<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 11:45:29 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Space Marine 2 February update brings the Datavault & Tyranid Biovore]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/01/30/space-marine-2-february-update-brings-the-datavault-tyranid-biovore/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/space-marine-2-february-update-brings-the-datavault-tyranid-biovore.1095738/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/01/30/space-marine-2-february-update-brings-the-datavault-tyranid-biovore/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>The next big <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/space-marine-2">Space Marine 2</a> update has been previewed ahead of its February release, with Patch 6.0 set to introduce a new PvP map, Datavault, Tyranid Biovore and more.</p>
<p>There’s also the dangled thread that support for <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/warhammer-40000-space-marine-2">Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine 2</a> could continue after the end of the current roadmap. As we head into Season 3 of content for Winter 2025, there’s just Season 4 and Spring 2025 left to come, but the team writes, “Worry not, even if this roadmap ends in 2025, that doesn’t mean the game will not receive new content after that!”</p>


<p>But back to the (almost) here and now, the 6.0 update has got a fresh batch of new content for players to take on:</p>
<ul>
<li>New PvP Map – Tomb</li>
<li>New PvE Enemy – Tyranid Biovore</li>
<li>New Battle Barge Feature – Datavault</li>
<li>Aboslute Difficulty</li>
<li>Perks Rework</li>
<li>FoV Slider for PC</li>
<li>Season Pass Cosmetics – Salamander Champion</li>
<li>Season Pass Cosmetics – Raven Guard Pack</li>
</ul>
<p>Let’s dig in a little deeper.</p>


<p>The new PvP map, Tomb, takes place under the surface of Demerium, digging into the creepy environs of a Necron tomb. It’s a map that is closed off with narrow passages, so there’s plenty of blind spots to be aware of, though there is also a more open arena for a change of combat range.</p>
<p>In PvE, the Tyranid Biovore can now appear in all Operations featuring the Tyranids. This is an Extremis enemy that shoots out Spore Mines that you need to dodge and destroy before they impact, but it can also be deadly at close range.</p>

<p>The Datavault on the Battle Barge is a new area to give unlockable information on different parts of the game and cosmetic rewards. You’ll nead to earn special currency from completing the in-game Ordeals achievements across all modes. These could be thinks like making a Carnifex stun itself, knocking back Spore Mines to kill Tyranids, or completing missions in Operations at specific threat levels.</p>
<p>Through the rest of the update, there will be a perks rework, though Saber didn’t go into details here, an FOV slider on PC – useful for ultra-wide monitors – an Absolute difficulty level, and the following smaller improvements and additions:</p>
<ul>
<li>New finisher animations on Zoanthropes, Scarab Occult Terminators and Rubric Marines.</li>
<li>A new functionality will be added, allowing you to upgrade your Master-Crafted and Artificer Armoury Data to Relic by trading them. You can also sell your Armoury Data to get Requisition Points.</li>
<li>Absolute Difficulty (unlocked after completing 1 Operation in Lethal Difficulty) will unlock a bloodstained Knife Combat and a new pauldron.</li>
<li>Base Decals available for Right Pauldrons</li>
<li>A new option to share your skin between PvE and PvP modes will be added. This option also allows you to share your patterns between classes.</li>
<li>PvP Crossplay Toggle On/Off: allows console players to play with PC players. You now have the option to be matched with either PC players or Console players independently.</li>
<li>New Emotes – Strengthen the bond with your fellow Brothers with the new emotes! So go ahead and use them without moderation.</li>
</ul>
<p>Rounding things out for Season Pass holders, the Salamanders Champion will be available for the Sniper class, and the Ravens Guard cosmetic pack will bring the classic MK VI ‘Corvus’ helmet design, a fan-favourite beaky look that dates back to the earliest versions of Warhammer 40,000.</p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://community.focus-entmt.com/focus-entertainment/space-marine-2/blogs/145-january-community-update">Focus Entertainment</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Grand Theft Auto VI and Grand Theft Auto Online Could Be Sold Separately; Rockstar Is Targeting Solid 30 FPS on Consoles, According to Former Animator]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/grand-theft-auto-vi-online-sold-separately-30-fps-target/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/grand-theft-auto-vi-and-grand-theft-auto-online-could-be-sold-separately-rockstar-is-targeting-solid-30-fps-on-consoles-according-to-former-animator.1095735/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/grand-theft-auto-vi-online-sold-separately-30-fps-target/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Grand Theft Auto VI and Grand Theft Auto Online will be sold separately at launch, with a potential upgrade for the full game available for those who only purchase the online component of the next entry in the Rockstar series, according to rumors circulating online.</p>
<p>On the <a href="https://gtaforums.com/topic/1000113-gta-vi-speculation-discussion-part-%E2%88%9E-the-leonida-drought/page/73/#findComment-1072491760" target="_blank" rel="noopener">GTA Forums</a>, known Rockstar leaker Tez2 said that the release of the sixth main entry in the series will coincide with the first time the full package and the online component will be sold separately at launch. According to the leaker, Rockstar Games will have to factor the price of the online component into the total cost of the game, but could benefit from pricing the online standalone lower to provide access to players who cannot afford the full price, who could, eventually, upgrade to the full game including the main story campaign. At the same time, if the online component is priced low, it could help Rockstar Games keep the price of the full experience low, which is something many in the industry wouldn't want to see, as there are expectations that a potential $80 price tag for Grand Theft Auto VI could <a href="https://wccftech.com/grand-theft-auto-6-growth-engine-pricing/">normalize video game pricing</a>, which hasn't increased much in the past few years despite rising costs.</p>
<p>The rumors of Grand Theft Auto Online possibly being sold separately from the full Grand Theft Auto VI package isn't the only news related to the highly-anticipated game that's come in the past few hours.&nbsp;<span>As reported by&nbsp;<a href="https://www.gamesradar.com/games/grand-theft-auto/gta-6-will-run-at-30fps-on-console-former-gta-5-and-red-dead-redemption-2-animator-expects-and-your-best-shot-at-60fps-may-be-hoping-for-pc/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">GamesRadar</a>, former Rockstar Games animator, Mike York commented on what console players should expect in terms of performance, saying that the developer is likely going to go for a steady 30 FPS, optimizing the game as much as possible to make sure it will never dip below the target.</span> On PlayStation 5 Pro, using the PlayStation Spectral Super Resolution upscaler, the game could hit 60 FPS, according to the former Rockstar developer, but 60 FPS shouldn't be expected on base hardware at launch. From their experience, the former animator is sure Rockstar is going to squeeze as much performance from consoles as possible to make the game run at 30 FPS, and then later optimize for 60 FPS, as the higher framerate is not as important as making the game amazing at 30.</p>
<p>Grand Theft Auto VI launches on PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X|S later this year. A precise release date has yet to be confirmed.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PlayStation finally drop the PSN account requirement that annoyed every PC player]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/playstation-finally-drop-the-psn-account-requirement-that-annoyed-every-pc-player</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/playstation-finally-drop-the-psn-account-requirement-that-annoyed-every-pc-player.1095729/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/playstation-finally-drop-the-psn-account-requirement-that-annoyed-every-pc-player<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div>
  

        <p>The mandatory becomes optional</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/last-of-us-part-2-playstation-psn-requirement-dropped-1.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>PlayStation / Naughty Dog</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Looks like they finally got the message. "An account for PlayStation Network will become optional for these titles on PC," said PlayStation in <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2025/01/29/new-in-game-content-incentives-coming-to-playstation-games-on-pc/">a short and quiet blog post</a> that includes the upcoming PC release for <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/marvels-spider-man-2">Spider-Man 2</a>, and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/the-last-of-us-part-ii-remastered">The Last Of Us Part II</a>. It's been eight months since PlayStation provoked mass annoyance among PC players by making a PSN account mandatory to play <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/helldivers-2">Helldivers 2</a>, and later <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/horizon-zero-dawn">Horizon Zero Dawn Remastered</a>. They soon walked back the decision for Helldivers 2 after <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/helldivers-2-has-received-100000-negative-reviews-since-announcing-players-must-link-steam-to-a-psn-account">a rough review-bombing</a> but the company didn't seem to fully take the hint. It looks like they've now conceded that, yes, the obligatory sign-up was an unpopular move.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>The post itself is brief and plain, and spins the decision as a way for PlayStation to offer "in-game content incentives" to any PC player who decides to sign in not as a requirement but as an option. "Players who still opt to sign into a PlayStation Network account will also enjoy added benefits like trophies and friend management," they say, before showing a table of the extra goodies account linkers will get for each game.</p>
<p>This is similar to what the company did for open world sequel <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/horizon-forbidden-west">Horizon Zero Dawn: Forbidden West</a>, which offered players a bonus outfit and spear for protagonist Aloy if they linked their Steam and PSN accounts. It looks like that may be the approach from now on. Although PlayStation don't explicitly say so outright. They only say that all the games which so far required the account are having that requirement dropped. I guess we'll see when <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/death-stranding-2">Death Stranding 2</a> comes out. </p>
<p>The whole saga has been quite stupid. PlayStation <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/helldivers-2-drops-psn-account-linking-requirement-for-steam-players-after-widespread-backlash">dropped the requirement for Helldivers 2</a> after players (and the game's developers) got supremely annoyed with the decision, but the hullaballoo resulted in a community manager <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/disgruntled-helldivers-2-fans-start-petition-to-bring-back-fired-community-manager">losing his job</a>. Following that, the account requirement was instituted on the above mentioned games, which many players pointed out were single player adventures, with no requirement to be online (aside from unspoken DRM reasons, that is). </p><p>The decision made the games unavailable to PC players in over 100 countries where it is currently not possible to sign up for Sony's service (not to mention slightly annoying anyone else who doesn't even own a PlayStation console). Most recently, they said the account <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-last-of-us-part-ii-will-require-a-psn-account-to-play-on-pc-making-it-unplayable-in-over-100-countries">would be required on the upcoming PC release of Last Of Us Part II</a>, due out in April. But now that too won't need a PSN account. Instead, if you sign on optionally, you'll get an in-game jacket inspired by Naughty Dog's new upcoming sci-fi adventure <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/intergalactic-the-heretic-prophet">Intergalactic: The Heretic Prophet</a>. </p>
<p>God, let this be the end of it. It was a stupid decision, irritated a ton of players, and probably only benefited some number crunchers in a department buried deep in Sony's corporate bowels. Now that it's just an option, we can all get back to deciding if the games are actually good or not.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marvel’s Spider-Man 2 PC System Requirements Detailed; RTX 4090 Recommended For Ultimate Ray Tracing, 4K@60FPS]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/marvels-spider-man-2-pc-system-requirements/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/marvel%E2%80%99s-spider-man-2-pc-system-requirements-detailed-rtx-4090-recommended-for-ultimate-ray-tracing-4k-60fps.1095723/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/marvels-spider-man-2-pc-system-requirements/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The Marvel's Spider-Man 2 PC system requirements have been confirmed ahead of today's launch, detailing what system configuration the user will need to achieve certain resolution and performance targets.</p>
<p>Unlike some other recent games, the PC version of the second entry in the series developed by Insomniac Games will not require a ray tracing capable GPU to run even at the lowest resolution and frame rate, as old GPUs like the NVIDIA GTX 1650 or AMD Radeon RX 5500 XT will be able to run the game at 720p, 30 frames per second with the very low graphics preset. To enjoy the game at its very best at 4K resolution, 60 frames per second, and Ultimate Ray Tracing, however, an RTX 4090 will be required. The full requirements for other resolutions and frame rate targets can be found below.</p>
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td data-align="center"><strong>Minimum</strong></td>
<td data-align="center"><strong>Recommended</strong></td>
<td data-align="center"><strong>High</strong></td>
<td data-align="center"><strong>High Ray Tracing</strong></td>
<td data-align="center"><strong>Very High Ray Tracing</strong></td>
<td data-align="center"><strong>Ultimate Ray Tracing</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Avg. Performance</strong></td>
<td data-align="center">720P @ 30 FPS</td>
<td data-align="center">1080P @ 60 FPS</td>
<td data-align="center">1440P @ 60 FPS</td>
<td data-align="center">1440p @ 60 FPS</td>
<td data-align="center">1440p @ 60 FPS</td>
<td data-align="center">4K @ 60 FPS</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Graphics Presets</strong></td>
<td data-align="center">Very Low</td>
<td data-align="center">Medium</td>
<td data-align="center">High</td>
<td data-align="center">High<br>
Ray Tracing High</td>
<td data-align="center">High<br>
Ray Tracing Very High</td>
<td data-align="center">Very High<br>
Ray Tracing Ultimate</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>GPU</strong></td>
<td data-align="center">NVIDIA GeForce GTX 1650<br>
AMD Radeon RX 5500 XT</td>
<td data-align="center">NVIDIA GeForce RTX 3060<br>
AMD Radeon RX 5700</td>
<td data-align="center">NVIDIA GeForce RTX 3070<br>
AMD Radeon RX 6800</td>
<td data-align="center">NVIDIA GeForce RTX 4070<br>
AMD Radeon RX 7900 XT</td>
<td data-align="center">NVIDIA GeForce RTX 4080<br>
AMD Radeon RX 7900 XTX</td>
<td data-align="center">NVIDIA&nbsp;GeForce RTX&nbsp;4090</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>CPU</strong></td>
<td data-align="center">Intel Core i3-8100<br>
AMD Ryzen 3 3100</td>
<td data-align="center">Intel Core i5-8400<br>
AMD Ryzen 5 3600</td>
<td data-align="center">Intel Core i5-11400<br>
AMD Ryzen 5 5600</td>
<td data-align="center">Intel Core i5-11600K<br>
AMD Ryzen 5 5600X</td>
<td data-align="center">Intel Core i7-12700K<br>
AMD Ryzen 9 5900X</td>
<td data-align="center">Intel Core i9-12900K<br>
AMD Ryzen 7 7800X3D</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>RAM</strong></td>
<td data-align="center">16 GB</td>
<td data-align="center">16 GB</td>
<td data-align="center">16 GB</td>
<td data-align="center">16 GB</td>
<td data-align="center">16 GB</td>
<td data-align="center">32 GB</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>OS</strong></td>
<td data-align="center">Windows 10/11 64-bit<br>
(version 1909 or higher)</td>
<td data-align="center">Windows 10/11 64-bit<br>
(version 1909 or higher)</td>
<td data-align="center">Windows 10/11 64-bit<br>
(version 1909 or higher)</td>
<td data-align="center">Windows 10/11 64-bit<br>
(version 1909 or higher)</td>
<td data-align="center">Windows 10/11 64-bit<br>
(version 1909 or higher)</td>
<td data-align="center">Windows 10/11 64-bit<br>
(version 1909 or higher)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>SSD Storage</strong></td>
<td data-align="center">140 GB</td>
<td data-align="center">140 GB</td>
<td data-align="center">140 GB</td>
<td data-align="center">140 GB</td>
<td data-align="center">140 GB</td>
<td data-align="center">140 GB</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>Marvel's Spider-Man 2 will launch with plenty of PC-exclusive features, as has been the case for PlayStation PC ports for a while. Among these features are NVIDIA DLSS 3, including Frame Generation and Ray Reconstruction, AMD FSR 3.1, including Frame Generation, and Intel XeSS support, ultra-wide support, increased ray tracing geometry detail setting, and more. Additional information on the game's PC-exclusive features can be found on the <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2025/01/29/marvels-spider-man-2-pc-features-and-ray-tracing-options-detailed-out-tomorrow/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">official PlayStation blog.</a></p>
<p>Marvel's Spider-Man 2 is now available on<a href="https://wccftech.com/review/marvels-spider-man-2-ultimate-incarnation/"> PlayStation 5</a>. The game will launch on PC later today.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 "the top-selling game on Xbox and PlayStation" last quarter]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-the-top-selling-game-on-xbox-and-playstation-last-quarter</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-the-top-selling-game-on-xbox-and-playstation-last-quarter.1095714/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-the-top-selling-game-on-xbox-and-playstation-last-quarter<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div>
        

        <p>Four million players dipped their toes in Indiana Jones' Great Circle.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Untitled-1_Cd7mrvo.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Activision / Eurogamer</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Microsoft is celebrating having the best-selling game on both Xbox and PlayStation platforms over the last quarter, thanks to its new ownership of the Call of Duty franchise.
</p>
<p>
<a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/call-of-duty-2024">Call of Duty: Black Ops 6</a> launched last October and has been a success for Microsoft, which namechecked the title during its latest financial results.
</p>
<p>
"Black Ops 6... saw more players in its launch quarter than any other paid release in franchise history," Microsoft boss Satya Nadella boasted during a <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/investor/events/fy-2025/earnings-fy-2025-q2">call</a> with investors.
</p>
<figure><div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div><figcaption>Xbox Developer Direct - four promising games also coming to PlayStation.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=afaO_AuPw0o" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
"We also continue to see strong momentum for Xbox Cloud Gaming, with a record 140m hours streamed this quarter," he continued.
</p>
<p>
Nadella also called out the brilliant <a data-keyword="true" href="https://eurogamer.net/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-review">Indiana Jones and the Great Circle</a>, and gave our first indication of how well MachineGames' globe-trotting adventure is doing.
</p>
<p>
"We saw rave reviews of Indiana Jones and the Great Circle, which has already been played by more than four million people," Nadella said.
</p>
<p>
Both of these statistics will reflect players who bought either game outright, as well as those who have played via Game Pass on both PC and Xbox.
</p>
<p>
Additionally, of course, the PS5 launch of Indiana Jones and the Great Circle is still to come - sometime in the first half of this year.
</p>
<p>
Revenue for Xbox's gaming and content division, which includes Game Pass, rose two percent over three months of 2024 thanks to a surge of subscribers on PC. But <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/xbox-hardware-sales-slump-but-game-pass-is-surging">Microsoft's wider gaming revenue was still down year-on-year overall, offset by the continued slump of Xbox hardware sales</a>.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Meta's speculative Reality Labs division continues to excel at losing billions]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/meta-s-speculative-reality-labs-division-continues-to-excel-at-losing-billions</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/metas-speculative-reality-labs-division-continues-to-excel-at-losing-billions.1095705/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/meta-s-speculative-reality-labs-division-continues-to-excel-at-losing-billions<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Reality Labs, the division Facebook owner Meta hopes will eventually birth the metaverse, lost over $17.7 billion during the last fiscal year.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">According to the company's </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://s21.q4cdn.com/399680738/files/doc_financials/2024/q4/Meta-12-31-2024-Exhibit-99-1-FINAL.pdf">fiscal report</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> for the year ended December 31, 2024, the segment delivered a loss of $4.9 billion during Q4–an increase on the $4.6 billion loss posted in Q4 last year.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Similar performance across previous quarters resulted in Reality Labs delivering a full-year loss of more than $17.7 billion.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Q4 revenue within the segment rose by 1 percent year-on-year to $1.1 billion and was driven by hardware sales. Reality Labs expenses totalled $6 billion.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Reality Labs is the home of Meta's virtual, augmented, and mixed reality consumer hardware, software, and content initiatives. That includes the company's Quest headset business, formerly known as Oculus.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The division has become the standard bearer for obscene losses. It burned through </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/extended-reality/meta-lost-16-1-billion-on-its-big-metaverse-bet-during-2023">$16.1 billion</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/meta-lost-13-7-billion-on-reality-labs-in-2022">$13.7 billion</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> across 2023 and 2022, respectively, and continues to haemorrhage cash.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Zuckerberg says Quest headset usage is rising, reiterates that Reality Labs is a long-term bet">Zuckerberg says Quest headset usage is rising, reiterates that Reality Labs is a long-term bet</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Discussing the Quest business specifically, Meta CEO Mark Zuckerberg said the number of people using its headsets and Horizon metaverse software has been "steadily growing."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"This is the year when a number of the long-term investments that we've been working on that will make the metaverse more visually stunning and inspiring will really start to land. So I think we’re going to know a lot more about Horizon's trajectory by the end of this year," he added.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Last year, Meta CFO Susan Li indicated Reality Labs was "definitely part of the budget conversation" amid rising expenses and infrastructure costs.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Yet, Meta execs have repeatedly told investors to expect losses to increase year-over-year. It was more of the same this year.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"We do anticipate that operating losses in Reality Labs will increase in 2025 as they did in 2024," </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://s21.q4cdn.com/399680738/files/doc_financials/2024/q4/META-Q4-2024-Follow-Up-Call-Transcript.pdf">said Li during an investor call</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. "We expect our Wearables devices to be the primary driver of Reality Labs operating losses growing in 2025 across both cost revenue and operating expenses. And that really comes from our efforts to further accelerate the adoption of our AI glasses products."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Li described Meta's ongoing Reality Labs investments as "big product bets" but said the company is determined to bring scalable products to market.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">In the meantime, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/meta-cutting-5-percent-of-workforce-to-jettison-low-performers-">Meta plans to eliminate 5 percent of its workforce</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> to jettison people the company feels are "low performers."</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">News Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer news editor Chris Kerr is an award-winning journalist and reporter with over a decade of experience in the game industry. His byline has appeared in notable print and digital publications including Edge, Stuff, Wireframe, International Business Times, and&nbsp;</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="http://pocketgamer.biz/">PocketGamer.biz</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. Throughout his career, Chris has covered major industry events including GDC, PAX Australia, Gamescom, Paris Games Week, and Develop Brighton. He has featured on the judging panel at The Develop Star Awards on multiple occasions and appeared on BBC Radio 5 Live to discuss breaking news.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox hardware sales slump, but Game Pass is surging]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/xbox-hardware-sales-slump-but-game-pass-is-surging</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/xbox-hardware-sales-slump-but-game-pass-is-surging.1095702/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/xbox-hardware-sales-slump-but-game-pass-is-surging<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div>
        

        <p>Microsoft gaming revenue down year-on-year overall.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Untitled-1_ATRP1mG.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Microsoft</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Microsoft has announced mixed results for its latest financial quarter, with strong growth for Game Pass offset by the continued decline in Xbox hardware sales. 
</p>
<p>
Overall, revenue for Microsoft's gaming division was down seven percent year-on-year for the three months ending 31st December 2024, with a 29 percent drop in Xbox console sales largely to blame. 
</p>
<p>
But the quarter also saw a significant boost to Game Pass, which made more money in the last three months of 2024 than in any previous quarter, and also saw a significant uptick to its subscribers on PC.
</p>
<figure><div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div><figcaption>Xbox Developer Direct - four promising games also coming to PlayStation.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=afaO_AuPw0o" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
"We are focused on improving the profitability of the business, in order to position it for long-term growth, driven by higher-margin content and platform services," Microsoft boss Satya Nadella said in a <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/investor/events/fy-2025/earnings-fy-2025-q2">call</a> with investors. "And we are delivering on this plan.
</p>
<p>
"All-up, Game Pass set a new quarterly record for revenue and grew its PC subscriber base by over 30 percent, as we focus on driving fully-paid subscribers across endpoints."
</p>
<p>
It's clear that Game Pass subscriptions will have been boosted by <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/call-of-duty-2024">Call of Duty: Black Ops 6</a>'s launch in October. The latest launch in Activision's long-running shooter franchise was the first to arrive on Game Pass on day one - provided you had PC Game Pass or Xbox Game Pass Ultimate on consoles.
</p>
<p>
Indeed, Black Ops 6 saw more players in its first couple of months than any other game in the series to date, Nadella said.
</p>
<p>
Its inclusion on Game Pass also does not appear to have dented its sales, either. Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 was "the top-selling game on Xbox and PlayStation" last quarter, Nadella said, before also <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-the-top-selling-game-on-xbox-and-playstation-last-quarter">revealing the number of people who have played the brilliant Indiana Jones and the Great Circle</a>.
</p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indiana Jones hits 4 million players, but Xbox revenue and hardware sales fall]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/01/30/indiana-jones-hits-4-million-players-but-xbox-revenue-and-hardware-sales-fall/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/indiana-jones-hits-4-million-players-but-xbox-revenue-and-hardware-sales-fall.1095687/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/01/30/indiana-jones-hits-4-million-players-but-xbox-revenue-and-hardware-sales-fall/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Microsoft’s Q2 earnings call has provided a number of highlights for the Xbox gaming division, including strong game and Xbox Game Pass performance, but the most important statistic is that the company saw a 7% revenue decline, year-on-year, in large part because of a huge 29% drop in Xbox hardware revenue through the final few months of 2024.</p>
<p>Let’s start with the good news. <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle">Indiana Jones and the Great Circle</a> has brought in over 4 million players across <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/xbox-series-x">Xbox Series X|S</a>, PC and through <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/xbox-game-pass">Xbox Game Pass</a> subscribers. We never get actual sales figures for Microsoft games anymore, but this is an encouraging amount of reach, and we’ll certainly see a big bump when the game arrives on PlayStation 5 in the first half of this year.</p>


<p>Microsoft CEO <a title="People > Satya Nadella [120 articles]" href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/people/satya-nadella/">Satya Nadella</a> also touted <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/call-of-duty-black-ops-6">Call of Duty: Black Ops 6</a> as having a record breaking launch quarter, as it topped sales charts for both Xbox and PlayStation, showing the value in multi-platform releases for Microsoft going forward.</p>
<p>Both of these launches fuelled a 30% growth in Game Pass subscribers on PC, which also indicates the potential of this subscription service, after a few years of slower growth than Microsoft had wanted. This helped Game Pass set a new quarterly revenue record, with the overall Xbox content and services revenue growing 2%.</p>
<p>However, in the quarter ending on 31st December 2024, the gaming division made $6.6 billion in revenue, which was a drop of $530 million year-over-year. That’s quite significant and revealing, as 2023’s figures had the massive bump of acquiring <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2023/10/13/microsoft-now-owns-activision-blizzard/">Activision Blizzard in October 2023</a>, flooding the financial report with all the sales of Call of Duty, World of Warcraft, Overwatch and Diablo revenue. That helped to mask whatever else was going on with Microsoft’s gaming business through 2024’s quarterly reports, but we’re now seeing a meaningful comparison once again.</p>

<p>It’s really looking like Xbox’s decline as a console manufacturer is now irreversible, and little in Microsoft’s new multiplatform release plan is going to arrest that slide. The company has a huge deficit to PlayStation this generation, without the impetus of exclusive games, there’s little reason for gamers to really consider jumping to Xbox in future. Things could slide even further as the <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/01/16/nintendo-switch-2-reveal-announcement/">Nintendo Switch 2 releases later this year</a>…</p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/Investor/earnings/FY-2025-Q2/press-release-webcast">Microsoft</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Microsoft Boasts Xbox Records, But Hardware Sales Collapse Drags Gaming Revenue Down]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/microsoft-boasts-xbox-records-but-hardware-sales-collapse-drags-gaming-revenue-down/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/microsoft-boasts-xbox-records-but-hardware-sales-collapse-drags-gaming-revenue-down.1095678/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/microsoft-boasts-xbox-records-but-hardware-sales-collapse-drags-gaming-revenue-down/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Just yesterday, it was <a href="https://wccftech.com/microsoft-top-publisher-december-2024/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reported</a> that Microsoft ranked as the top games publisher in the world last month. And yet, their <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/investor/earnings/fy-2025-q2/press-release-webcast" target="_blank" rel="noopener">second quarter, fiscal year 2025 financial report</a> doesn't exactly paint a rosy picture of the gaming division. Sure, CEO Satya Nadella boasted about a few records for Xbox Cloud Gaming, Game Pass, and successful games like <a href="https://wccftech.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-is-the-biggest-ever-says-activision/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Call of Duty: Black Ops 6</a> and <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-indiana-at-his-finest/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Indiana Jones and the Great Circle</a>:</p>
<p><em>We are focused on improving the profitability of the business in order to position it for long-term growth, driven by higher-margin content and platform services. </em><em>And we are delivering on this plan.</em></p>
<p><em>Black Ops 6 was the top-selling game on Xbox and PlayStation this quarter – and saw more players in its launch quarter than any other paid release in franchise history. </em><em>And we saw rave reviews of Indiana Jones and the Great Circle, which has already been played by more than 4 million people.</em></p>
<p><em>We also continue to see strong momentum for Xbox Cloud Gaming, with a record 140 million hours streamed this quarter. </em><em>All-up, Game Pass set a new quarterly record for revenue and grew its PC subscriber base by over 30%, as we focus on driving fully-paid subscribers across endpoints.</em></p>
<p>When you look closer at the numbers, though, overall Xbox content and services revenue increased only 2%, albeit Microsoft said that's above expectations thanks to higher-than-estimated performance from Activision Blizzard, chiefly Call of Duty: Black Ops 6. The growth was this small because gaming revenue specifically was down 7%, dragged by the collapse of Xbox hardware revenue (-29%). Microsoft Chief Financial Officer Amy Hood admitted in the earnings call:</p>
<p><em>In Gaming, revenue decreased 7% (8% in constant currency) as content and services growth continued to be offset by hardware declines.</em></p>
<p>There is seemingly no end in sight for these Xbox hardware declines, which have been constant for several quarters now. Partly, it might even be due to Microsoft's own multiplatform strategy. Some gamers undoubtedly see no reason to purchase an Xbox when they can get their games not only on PC but also on PlayStation or Nintendo platforms. Microsoft certainly believes the switch toward multiplatform, <a href="https://wccftech.com/spencer-keeping-games-off-other-platform-xbox-series-s-handheld/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">confirmed</a> yet again by gaming CEO Phil Spencer just a few days ago, will be worth it in the end; for now, however, the struggles continue. Could this lead to the abandonment of Xbox hardware as a whole? At the time being, Microsoft still believes it can turn this around by making its hardware more alluring on its own rather than relying on exclusive games. In a recent interview <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-KK8xil5Uy0" target="_blank" rel="noopener">with Destin Legarie</a>, Phil Spencer stated:</p>
<p><em>I want us to innovate and make hardware the differentiator. We've got into this space where the differentiation on the hardware has gone down, and it's really been 'locked games' that have become the identity of the hardware. I love when I see handhelds, when I see unique things that hardware manufacturers do. I want our hardware to compete on power and on innovation. So let's have our platform continue to innovate with services and the hardware work that we're doing — whether it's controller, power, or mobility.</em></p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Assetto Corsa Evo Early Access Review]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/assetto-corsa-evo-early-access-review</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/assetto-corsa-evo-early-access-review.1095675/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/assetto-corsa-evo-early-access-review<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Assetto Corsa Evo is easily one of the most exciting racing games of 2025. The huge open-world map of German countryside surrounding the famous Nürburgring Nordschleife that developer Kunos Simulazioni is currently crafting for it should make it one of the biggest in the genre. Literally, that is. The map is going to be 1,600 square kilometres in size. That’s about 15 Forza Horizon 5s. However, we’ll need to be patient for that, as the first chunk of it isn’t set to arrive in Evo’s evolving early access version until mid-year, and then grow from there. For now, at least, we get five tracks and 20 cars to noodle around in. The good news is that the driving feel is unsurprisingly fabulous, right out of the gate. At this point, however, that’s… essentially it. It’s hard to argue Evo makes a strong case as an immediately <em>crucial </em>purchase in this early state if you’re not especially keen on taking some warm-up laps before the main event kicks off.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">It’d be unfair to haul Assetto Corsa Evo over the coals too severely for its current technical blemishes. Yes, I’ve had it hitch up and drop frames occasionally and, yes, it’s crashed or frozen on me several times following its launch – although I’ve certainly had lengthy stints on-track where it’s been entirely cooperative on my current high-powered PC setup (RTX 4080, Intel Core Ultra 9 185H). Overall, it’s admittedly not running on all cylinders right now, but that’s the nature of ‘Early Access’ as a concept. We obviously need to be prepared for it to be a little more <em>Alpha</em> Romeo than Alfa Romeo at this point.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">And while five circuits and 20 available cars is modest, it does make for a decent amount of combinations to experiment with – and that’s without factoring in the adjustable wet weather options that obviously have very real effects on handling. If you think you’ll be happy to simply hotlap solo around the initial tracks (which include Mount Panorama, Brands Hatch, Imola, Laguna Seca, and Suzuka), Evo’s early access version may keep you busy for at least a few days. It’s certainly worth remembering the early access program for Evo’s immediate predecessor, Assetto Corsa Competizione, launched with just <em>a single car and a single track</em> – the Lamborghini Huracan GT3 race car and the Nürburgring GP circuit. By comparison, Evo’s launch is at least a considerably chunkier one.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>The first salvo of circuits includes a track from the US, Japan, the UK, continental Europe, and Australia. </p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Moreover, it’s a well-curated one. Notice, for instance, the first salvo of circuits includes a track from the US, Japan, the UK, continental Europe, and Australia. That’s a thoughtful mix that I don’t doubt was deliberate. Similarly, the short but sweet car list includes a spectrum of vehicles, ranging from front-wheel drive hatches to purpose-built race models. The feel of the cars I’ve tested so far has been top notch. I won’t pretend to be able to gauge the accuracy of the tyre model with the kind of insight you might glean from a professional racing driver, because I’m not one; I’m a car nerd journalist with a handful of trackdays in my past that I’m skeptical I’ll ever be able to afford to repeat. What I can say is the sensation of grip is excellent and I was instantly confident to push hard across the top of the mountain at Bathurst. Things always get a little murky when I’m comparing experiences gleaned many years ago using totally different racing setups (I personally migrated from a Thrustmaster TS-XW racing wheel to a direct drive Moza R12 some years ago), but Evo already seems to have nailed that feeling of being able to overdrive a car but still snap it back under control, because the grip will return as long as you wrestle it back into the window. That always suits me, as I’m a bit more of a butcher than a surgeon when it comes to racing sims these days. Forget the whole world turning into ice the second you slip into a slide; Evo is wonderfully intuitive.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Compared to ACC, race cars also feel a little less punishingly stiff and cling to the track more tenaciously, even while clattering over bumps or kerbs. In ACC, I generally felt like I was going as fast as I could without losing control. In Evo, I’ve found I feel like I <em>could </em>probably push faster. If I had the skill, that is.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">There’s also a really great feeling of balance, especially as cars squirm under braking, and the feel of the front end becoming lighter and heavier based on elevation changes is nice and pronounced. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">So yes, in the tradition of the original Assetto Corsa and ACC before it, Evo is already a genuinely terrific driving experience. But does that make this first taste a must-play?</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Right now, no. Not really. If you get it today you’re essentially just pre-ordering the final game at a slightly discounted price. That alone could be reason enough for you to grab it, and it’s a totally fair argument. However, other than confirming it feels good, there’s just not really much more joy to extract from Evo for the time being. As a man who peeled countless demo discs from the front of magazines back in ’90s, I’ve certainly got nothing against what’s essentially a hefty demo, but it’s not one I really want to keep playing anymore after seeing all of its tracks. But I’ll definitely be back for more when it’s available and some of the more annoying aspects have been resolved. </p><div id="rank-todays-top-racing-simulators" data-cy="tierlist-view-trigger"><p><h3 data-cy="title3">Rank today's top racing simulators</h3><h3>Rank today's top racing simulators</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Simply put, the racing itself just isn’t that robust at the moment, and it’s tedious being punted off track by computer-controlled opponents who simply try to drive through you around corners. I don’t know what the answer is, but the AI certainly still needs work. There have definitely been times when other cars seemed to be deliberately giving me racing room, and others where they’ve made unscripted mistakes. That’s good, because it creates the illusion they’re not just machines. It’s also true that getting speared into from behind is an unfortunate reality in real racing. Incidents happen, sure. But it’d be something that would happen to you quite irregularly in reality, whereas it’s far too common in Evo for racing to remain fun. If I wanted to get rear-ended for kicks, I’d brake-check Lance Stroll in a drive-thru.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>If I wanted to get rear-ended for kicks, I’d brake-check Lance Stroll in a drive-thru.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">That’s a pretty big problem when these races are largely all Evo offers in its current condition. There were supposed to be some other modes available, based on what was announced when the early access version launched, but ever since I started playing Evo has been stuck in ‘Offline’ mode. Evo’s Driving Academy mode and Special Events are currently inaccessible to me. All I can do is generate custom practice or race sessions. Tying functionality to an always-online caveat is very concerning, and I cannot fathom why it’s necessary for single-player content. Fortunately, there’s still plenty of time for Kunos to tweak that on the road map ahead.</p></section><div data-cy="verdict"><h3 data-cy="title3">Verdict</h3><p data-cy="article-verdict-paragraph">Assetto Corsa Evo already feels absolutely fantastic behind the wheel but, with aggravating AI opponents slamming into you every which way and hamstrung as it is by online-only features that are currently inaccessible, it doesn’t feel like an essential early access purchase. The handling may be excellent, but I’ll be parking it up and waiting for the finished product – including the promised epic-sized map of Germany – before I put the keys back in the ignition.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Snezhinka: Sentinel Girls 2 coming to PS5, Xbox Series, and Switch on February 13]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/01/snezhinka-sentinel-girls-2-coming-to-ps5-xbox-series-and-switch-on-february-13</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/snezhinka-sentinel-girls-2-coming-to-ps5-xbox-series-and-switch-on-february-13.1095672/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/01/snezhinka-sentinel-girls-2-coming-to-ps5-xbox-series-and-switch-on-february-13<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Currently available for PC.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > PLAYISM [292 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/playism">PLAYISM</a> and developer <a title="Companies > hinyari9 [4 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/hinyari9">hinyari9</a> will release <a title="Genres > Side-Scrolling [886 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/side-scrolling">side-scrolling</a> <a title="Genres > Shooter [3,984 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/shooter">shooter</a> <em><a title="Games > Snezhinka: Sentinel Girls 2 [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/snezhinka-sentinel-girls-2">Snezhinka: Sentinel Girls 2</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,726 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [6,620 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, and <a title="Platforms > Switch [16,560 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a> on February 13 for $11.99, the companies announced. <span id="more-941333"></span></p><p><em>Snezhinka: Sentinel Girls 2</em> first launched for PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2608350/SnezhinkaSentinel_Girls2/" target="_blank">Steam</a> on August 27, 2024.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via PLAYISM:</p><blockquote><p>This is the sequel to <em><a title="Games > Marfusha: Sentinel Girls [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/marfusha-sentinel-girls">Marfusha: Sentinel Girls</a></em>, the second entry in the series of high-tempo shooting game with simple controls.</p><p>Play as Snezhinka, an employee of a private military company in a dystopian world depicted in beautiful 2.5D pixel art. Go to various different battlefields and defend your objectives from the enemy’s onslaught.</p><p>Every day you manage to survive will net you a salary, but this goes through all sorts of tax deductions and other payments… and you’ll have to use your meager earnings left over to strengthen yourself, buy new equipment, and recruit coworkers.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>In Story Mode, the story changes based on which coworker you choose to fight with. Read every story to their ends over multiple playthroughs.</p><p>There are also two different Challenge Modes that both fully support online rankings, as well as a Collection where you can view all sorts of elements you obtain in-game.</p><p>The console version comes with the artbook included.</p></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Consoles Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><p><iframe title="Snezhinka - Console Release Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/k4XfbtbrsfU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe title="救国のスネジンカ | コンソール版のリリース PV" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/o_qk2KS5ZE8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EDEN.schemata(); launches this spring]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/01/eden-schemata-launches-this-spring</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/eden-schemata-launches-this-spring.1095666/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/01/eden-schemata-launches-this-spring<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Demo playable during Steam Next Fest: February 2025 Edition.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Science-fiction mystery <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,018 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure game</a> <em><a title="Games > EDEN.schemata(); [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/eden-schemata">EDEN.schemata();</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > PC [22,223 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2334170/" target="_blank">Steam</a> this spring, ublisher <a title="Companies > PLAYISM [292 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/playism">PLAYISM</a> will developers <a title="Companies > illuCalab. [14 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/illucalab">illuCalab.</a> and <a title="Companies > WSS playground [42 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/why-so-serious-inc/wss-playground">WSS playground</a> announced. A demo will be available during Steam Next Fest: February 2025 Edition, which will run from February 24 to March 3. <span id="more-941345"></span></p><p>Here is a brief overview of the game, via PLAYISM:</p><blockquote><p>You awaken in a dark, locked room, only to find a broken android and a headless body…</p><p>Investigate every corner of a lab isolated from the world to solve this strange murder mystery.</p><p>What you notice will reshape this world, from the premise of the story, to the game itself. Experience a narrative that can only be realized in video game format.</p></blockquote><p>Watch today’s PLAYISM Game Show mini featuring the announcement below.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <h2><span>PLAYISM Game Show mini: January 30, 2025</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><p><iframe title="PLAYISM GAME SHOW mini 2025.1.30 (English)" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/-TTq_dgr4-E?start=137&amp;feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe title="PLAYISM GAME SHOW mini 2025.1.30" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/hlHGrfMFPHQ?start=137&amp;feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Chinese</strong></p><p><iframe title="PLAYISM GAME SHOW mini 2025.1.30 (Chinese)" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/7fZm4vGiuNI?start=137&amp;feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BREAK ARTS III launches this spring]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/01/break-arts-iii-launches-this-spring</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/break-arts-iii-launches-this-spring.1095660/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/01/break-arts-iii-launches-this-spring<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Demo playable during Steam Next Fest: February 2025 Edition.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Battle <a title="Genres > Racing [221 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/racing">racing</a> and robot customization sequel <em><a title="Games > BREAK ARTS III [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/break-arts-iii">BREAK ARTS III</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > PC [22,223 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2522430/BREAK_ARTS_III/" target="_blank">Steam</a> this spring, publisher <a title="Companies > PLAYISM [292 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/playism">PLAYISM</a> and developer <a title="Companies > MercuryStudio [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/mercurystudio">MercuryStudio</a> announced. A demo will be available during Steam Next Fest: February 2025 Edition, which will run from February 24 to March 3. <span id="more-941342"></span></p><p>Here is a brief overview of the game, via PLAYISM:</p><blockquote><p>The beautiful battle racing game is back, deeper and with more freedom than ever.</p><p>Compete in all sorts of stages, each with varying terrain, gravity, and temperature. Achieve victory by designing appropriate machines and piloting them skillfully!</p><p>Choose from a wide variety of parts to create and compete with your very own unique machines… or simply admire your creations in Diorama Mode!</p><p>Build the fastest, most powerful, and most beautiful machines to compete in racing, battle, and battle racing competitions.</p></blockquote><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Watch today’s PLAYISM Game Show mini featuring the announcement below.</p><h2><span>PLAYISM Game Show mini: January 30, 2025</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><p><iframe title="PLAYISM GAME SHOW mini 2025.1.30 (English)" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/-TTq_dgr4-E?start=21&amp;feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe title="PLAYISM GAME SHOW mini 2025.1.30" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/hlHGrfMFPHQ?start=21&amp;feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Chinese</strong></p><p><iframe title="PLAYISM GAME SHOW mini 2025.1.30 (Chinese)" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/7fZm4vGiuNI?start=21&amp;feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sugoro Quest: Dice Heroes coming to PS5, Xbox Series, PS4, Xbox One, and Switch on February 7]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/01/sugoro-quest-dice-heroes-coming-to-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-xbox-one-and-switch-on-february-7</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sugoro-quest-dice-heroes-coming-to-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-xbox-one-and-switch-on-february-7.1095651/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/01/sugoro-quest-dice-heroes-coming-to-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-xbox-one-and-switch-on-february-7<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Technos Japan-developed board game-style turn-based RPG.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Ratalaika Games [35 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/ratalaika-games">Ratalaika Games</a> and <a title="Companies > Shinyuden [19 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/shinyuden">Shinyuden</a>, in cooperation with <a title="Companies > Arc System Works [1,286 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/arc-system-works">Arc System Works</a>, will release the <a title="Companies > Technos Japan" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/arc-system-works/technos-japan">Technos Japan</a>-developed <a title="Genres > Board Game [52 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/board-game">board game</a>-style <a title="Genres > Turn-Based RPG [1,098 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg/turn-based-rpg">turn-based RPG</a> <em><a title="Games > Sugoro Quest: Dice Heroes" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/sugoro-quest-dice-heroes">Sugoro Quest: Dice Heroes</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,726 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [6,620 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,631 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox One [13,724 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a>, and <a title="Platforms > Switch [16,560 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a> on February 7 for $5.99, the companies announced. <span id="more-941321"></span></p><p><em>Sugoro Quest: Dice Heroes</em> first launched for Famicom on June 28, 1991 in Japan. This re-release will mark the first-ever time the game will be available in the west, and it will be playable in English, Spanish, and Japanese.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/us/store/products/sugoro-quest-dice-heroes-switch/" target="_blank">Nintendo eShop</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Roll the dice and fight!</p><p><em>Sugoro Quest: Dice Heroes</em> comes to the west for the first time! This is a board game-style turn-based RPG where dice will decide your fate!</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>The story begins in the kingdom of Siland, where four <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,018 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a>rs set out to talk to the king in search of intrepid adventures. Each adventure is different, so be sure to choose the most suitable member for each journey.</p><p>A school of magic? An adventure at sea? It’s up to you(and luck, of course) to make sure the adventure has a good ending! But beware of the enemies, as they won’t make your path easy.</p><p>Luck will lead you to victory!</p><p><strong>Features:</strong></p><ul><li>Available in English for the first time!</li><li>Choose from four different heroes, each with their own unique abilities.</li><li>Explore six lands full of treasures and dangerous monsters.</li><li>Save state function: save wherever you want to in the game, and restart from that exact point.</li><li>Screen filters: select from several filters to modify how the game looks (retro-style monitor, black-and-white, etc.).</li><li>Gallery: view images from the original game’s manual and box design.</li><li>Cheats function: activate cheats that will make your mission a lot easier (infinite lives, invulnerability, etc.).</li></ul></blockquote></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[First Elminage port for modern consoles to be announced in mid to late February]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/01/first-elminage-port-for-modern-consoles-to-be-announced-in-mid-to-late-february</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/first-elminage-port-for-modern-consoles-to-be-announced-in-mid-to-late-february.1095645/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/01/first-elminage-port-for-modern-consoles-to-be-announced-in-mid-to-late-february<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
        </ul>

    
    <p><span>Elminage II possibly the first port in line.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Mebius [43 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/mebius">Mebius</a> will announce the first in a series of console ports for the <a title="Companies > STARFISH-SD [7 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/starfish-sd">STARFISH-SD</a>-developed <a title="Genres > Dungeon RPG [66 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg/dungeon-rpg">dungeon RPG</a> series <em>Elminage</em> in mid to late February, the company <a href="https://twitter.com/digitalmebius/status/1884742152586166664" target="_blank" rel="noopener">teased</a>. <span id="more-941315"></span></p><p>The <em>Elminage</em> series consists of the following titles:</p><ul><li><em>Elminage: Priestess of Darkness and The Ring of the Gods</em> (<a title="Platforms > PS2 [38 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps2">PS2</a>, 2008)<ul><li><em>Elminage <a title="Platforms > DS [55 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/ds">DS</a> Remix: Priestess of Darkness and The Ring of the Gods</em> (DS, 2008)</li><li><em>Elminage ORIGINAL: Priestess of Darkness and The Ring of the Gods</em> (<a title="Platforms > PSP [649 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/psp">PSP</a>, 2011)</li><li><em>Elminage ORIGINAL: Priestess of Darkness and The Ring of the Gods</em> (<a title="Platforms > 3DS [3,973 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/3ds">3DS</a>, 2016)</li><li><em>Elminage ORIGINAL: Priestess of Darkness and The Ring of the Gods</em> (<a title="Platforms > PC [22,223 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a>, 2017)</li></ul></li><li><em>Elminage II: Twin Goddesses and The Land of Destiny</em> (PSP, 2009)<ul><li><em>Elminage II DS Remix: Twin Goddesses and The Land of Destiny</em> (DS, 2010)</li><li><em>Elminage II: Twin Goddesses and The Land of Destiny</em> (3DS, 2017)</li></ul><!-- AD: content -->
        </li><li><em>Elminage III: Dark Apostle and The Palace of the Sun</em> (PSP, 2011)<ul><li><em>Elminage III: Dark Apostle and The Palace of the Sun</em> (3DS, 2017)</li></ul></li><li><em>Elminage Gothic</em> (PSP, 2012)<ul><li><em>Elminage Gothic 3D Remix</em> (3DS, 2013)</li><li><em>Elminage Gothic</em> (PC, 2014)</li></ul></li><li><em>Elminage <a title="Games > Ib [7 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/ib">Ib</a>un: Ame no Mihashira</em>&nbsp;(PSP, 2012)<ul><li><em>Elminage Ibun: Ame no Mihashira Kai</em> (3DS, 2014)</li></ul></li></ul><p>According to Mebius, the console ports of the numbered series will be based on the 3DS versions, with adjustments made for easier playability. The first title is scheduled for release in the early summer in Japan.</p><p>While Mebius did not announce which title it plans on porting first, the company <a href="https://twitter.com/digitalmebius/status/1795059051312611683" target="_blank" rel="noopener">held a poll</a> back in May 2024 asking users which&nbsp;<em>Elminage</em> game they would like to see brought back.&nbsp;<em>Elminage II</em> came out on top with an overwhelming 66.9 percent of the votes, followed by <em>Elminage III</em> at 14.4 percent,&nbsp;<em>Elminage Gothic</em> at 10 percent, and&nbsp;<em>Elminage Ibun: Ame no Mihashira</em> at 8.7 percent.</p><p>Then, in June 2024, Mebius <a href="https://twitter.com/digitalmebius/status/1805592403656818773" target="_blank">held another poll</a> asking users which platforms they would like to play <em>Elminage</em> on. Consoles won with 39.8 percent of the votes, followed by at 36.6 percent, and smartphones and handheld game devices at 23.7 percent.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Side Kicks! beyond launches June 5 in Japan]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/01/side-kicks-beyond-launches-june-5-in-japan</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/side-kicks-beyond-launches-june-5-in-japan.1095642/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/01/side-kicks-beyond-launches-june-5-in-japan<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Pre-orders open on February 1.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Genres > Otome [105 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/visual-novel/otome">Otome visual novel</a> <em><a title="Games > Side Kicks! beyond [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/side-kicks-beyond">Side Kicks! beyond</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > Switch [16,560 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>, iOS, and Android on June 5 in Japan, publisher <a title="Companies > eXtend [13 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/extend">eXtend</a> and developers <a title="Companies > Toybox Inc. [119 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/toybox-inc">Toybox Inc.</a> and <a title="Companies > Karakuri-ism [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/karakuri-ism">Karakuri-ism</a> <a href="https://prtimes.jp/main/html/rd/p/000000013.000035750.html" rel="noopener" target="_blank">announced</a>. Pre-orders will open on February 1. <span id="more-941327"></span></p><p><em>Side Kicks! beyond</em> is an enhanced port of <em>Side Kicks!</em>, which originally released for <a title="Platforms > PS Vita [7,378 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps-vita">PS Vita</a> in March 2017. It will add new episodes to the main story of <em>Side Kicks!</em>, as well as a crossover episode with otome murder mystery <a title="Genres > Visual Novel [519 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/visual-novel">visual novel</a> <em>BUSTAFELLOWS</em>, which is set in the same world.</p><p>In related news, eXtend announced that total sales for <em>BUSTAFELLOWS</em> have surpassed 150,000 copies.</p><p>Here is the <em>Side Kicks!</em> story synopsis, via <a href="https://vndb.org/v19743" rel="noopener" target="_blank">VNDB</a>:</p><blockquote><p>Side Kicks: a newly established special investigation bureau within the Sakrada Police Force, located in California, designed to heighten the security of Sakrada City with their unique style of thinking and individual skill. Currently seeking additional members.</p><p>A city in California, United States of America—Sakrada. In recent years, the spread of a highly addictive drug, Ripcord, has been causing several issues in the sunny, quiet city located on the West Coast. In order to control cases like this, the Sakrada Police Force established a new organization—a special investigation bureau made up of members with unique styles of thinking and their idiosyncratic skills, known as the Side Kicks.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Chika, who has exceptional athletic talent; Hibari, the profiler who possesses a way with words; Shishiba, the quiet hacker prodigy; Rico, gifted with photographic memory; and Tatewaki, the leader in charge of the four.</p><p>The special investigation bureau has become well-known in the city for its ground-breaking investigation methods that are unlike anything ever seen before.</p><p>One day, the heroine Inori is scouted as a new member of Side Kicks. The skill she possesses… is the mysterious ability of clairvoyant dreams.</p></blockquote></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Compile Heart 2025 lineup trailer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/01/compile-heart-2025-lineup-trailer</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/compile-heart-2025-lineup-trailer.1095612/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/01/compile-heart-2025-lineup-trailer<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div role="main">
  
  <article>

    
<header>

  <div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Scar-Lead Salvation, Todokero! Tatakae! Calamity Angels, Hyperdevotion Noire: Goddess Black Heart, Magical Librarian Ariana: The Book of Seven Heroes, and Zaleste.</span>
      </p></div>

  

</header>  

<!-- Moved from templates/posts/default.php -->

    <div><p><a title="Companies > Compile Heart [1,205 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/idea-factory/compile-heart">Compile Heart</a> has <a href="https://prtimes.jp/main/html/rd/p/000000745.000080401.html" target="_blank">released</a> a trailer showcasing its 2025 lineup, including third-person <a title="Genres > Shooter [3,984 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/shooter">shooter</a> <em><a title="Games > Scar-Lead Salvation [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/scar-lead-salvation">Scar-Lead Salvation</a></em>, <a title="Genres > RPG [16,954 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg">RPG</a> <em><a title="Games > Todokero! Tatakae! Calamity Angels [4 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/todokero-tatakae-calamity-angels">Todokero! Tatakae! Calamity Angels</a></em>, the <a title="Platforms > Switch [16,560 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a> version of strategy RPG <em>Hyperdevotion Noire: Goddess Black Heart</em>, 2D <a title="Genres > Action [2,448 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a> RPG <em><a title="Games > Magical Librarian Ariana: The Book of Seven Heroes [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/magical-librarian-ariana-the-book-of-seven-heroes">Magical Librarian Ariana: The Book of Seven Heroes</a></em>, and <a title="Genres > Shoot 'Em Up [760 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/shoot-em-up">shoot ’em up game</a> <em><a title="Games > Zaleste [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/zaleste">Zaleste</a></em>. <span id="more-941306"></span></p><p>Here is a brief overview of each game:</p><blockquote><p><strong><em>Scar-Lead Salvation</em></strong></p><ul><li><strong>Platforms:</strong> <a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,726 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,631 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > PC [22,223 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> (Steam)</li><li><strong>Release Date:</strong> May 29, 2025</li><li><strong>Genre:</strong> <a title="Genres > Third-Person Shooter [1,271 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/shooter/tps">Third-Person Shooter</a></li><li><strong>Developer:</strong> <a title="Companies > Neilo [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/neilo">Neilo</a></li></ul><p>Read more about the game <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2025/01/scar-lead-salvation-debut-trailer-gameplay-details-and-screenshots">here</a>.</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Compile-Heart-2025-Lineup_01-29-25_002.jpg"></a></figure><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong><em>Todokero! Tatakae! Calamity Angels</em></strong></p><ul><li><strong>Platforms:</strong> PlayStation 5, PlayStation 4, Switch</li><li><strong>Release Date:</strong> Summer 2025</li><li><strong>Genre:</strong> RPG</li><li><strong>Developer:</strong> Compile Heart</li></ul><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Compile-Heart-2025-Lineup_01-29-25_003.jpg"></a></figure><p><strong><em>Hyperdevotion Noire: Goddess Black Heart</em></strong></p><ul><li><strong>Platforms:</strong> Switch</li><li><strong>Release Date:</strong> February 13, 2025</li><li><strong>Genre:</strong> <a title="Genres > Strategy RPG [392 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg/strategy-rpg">Strategy RPG</a></li><li><strong>Developer:</strong> <a title="Companies > Sting [79 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sting">Sting</a></li></ul><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Compile-Heart-2025-Lineup_01-29-25_004.jpg"></a></figure><p><strong><em>Magical Librarian Ariana: The Book of Seven Heroes</em></strong></p><ul><li><strong>Platforms:</strong> PlayStation 5, PlayStation 4, Switch</li><li><strong>Release Date:</strong> Summer 2025</li><li><strong>Genre:</strong> 2D <a title="Genres > Action RPG [1,480 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg/action-rpg">Action RPG</a></li><li><strong>Developer:</strong> <a title="Companies > HYDE [20 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/hyde">HYDE</a></li></ul><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Compile-Heart-2025-Lineup_01-29-25_005.jpg"></a></figure><p><strong><em>Zaleste</em></strong></p><ul><li><strong>Platforms:</strong> PlayStation 5, PlayStation 4, Switch</li><li><strong>Release Date:</strong> 2025</li><li><strong>Genre:</strong> Shoot ‘Em Up</li><li><strong>Developer:</strong> <a title="Companies > M2 [85 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/m2">M2</a></li></ul><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Compile-Heart-2025-Lineup_01-29-25_006.jpg"></a></figure></blockquote><p>Watch the trailer below. Visit Compile Heart’s 2025 lineup website <a href="https://www.compileheart.com/ch_titlelineup2025/" target="_blank">here</a>.</p><h2><span>Compile Heart 2025 Lineup Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="『2025コンパイルハート タイトルラインナップ ！』" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/j3dlfpqGLIg?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div>

        
    
  </article>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tokyo Xtreme Racer Is Back After 20 (!!) Years, And It Rules]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/tokyo-xtreme-racer-impressions</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/tokyo-xtreme-racer-is-back-after-20-years-and-it-rules.1095603/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://aftermath.site/tokyo-xtreme-racer-impressions<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Back in the mid-90s, Japanese studio Genki were responsible for a series of games called <em>Shutokō Battle</em>, known (mostly) in the West as <em>Tokyo Xtreme Racer</em>. From 1994-2006 these games landed on the Super Famicom, PlayStation, Saturn, Dreamcast, PS2, Xbox 360, PC and even portable systems, then they just...disappeared.</p><p>The last main game in the series came out in 2006, and that seemed a pretty fitting time for it to bow out. In the West we were well into the age of <em>Forza</em>, <em>Project Gotham</em> and <em>Burnout</em>, and <em>Tokyo Xtreme's</em> obsession with hard numbers and grinding--not to mention its relatively limited roster of cars and locations--made it seem almost quaint by comparison.</p><p>But hey, times change! We're now in 2025, we're exhausted with AAA racing games, we're tired of the same old franchises doing the same old things, and it's time for something new! And by something new I mean something very old, because here comes a new <em>Tokyo Xtreme Racer </em>game like nothing happened.</p><p>Look at this series’ release timeline. This is the video game equivalent of a cat going missing for nine years then just walking back into your house like nothing happened. Only instead of nine years it's <em>19</em>. And instead of walking, the cat drifted in sideways like a sick, modified Subaru Impreza.</p><figure><figcaption><span>Wikipedia</span></figcaption></figure><p>This is great! This new game is, I'm told, largely unchanged in terms of structure from its decades-old predecessors; you drive around Japanese motorways challenging people to races, which are decided not by clocks or flags, but by a "spirit meter" that drains if you're behind your opponent. There's also loads of grinding and tinkering to do in order to level up your car and be able to defeat more powerful rivals. About the only thing that's changed significantly is that it looks nicer.</p><div><figure><p><iframe title="【Tokyo Xtreme Racer】#8：Full PV" width="710" height="399" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/umlztIQ7HeE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></figure></div><p>Which is fine, because going back to the well is maybe my favourite broad trend in video games right now.<a href="https://aftermath.site/video-games-palworld-helldivers-manor-lords-aaa" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> AAA gaming has gotten so risk averse, and its release calendar has become so sparse</a>, that these mid-tier kinds of games--once beloved by millions, but crowded out over the past decade by an industry that thought it was moving past them--are coming back.</p><p>Turns out we weren't moving past anything. We <em>thought </em>we were, but all we've ended up doing over the past two decades is see racing games--like so many other genres--become bloated beyond almost all recognition as they've chased realism, more cars, more features, bigger tracks, more, more more. Or, on the flipside, they've retreated the other direction and become incredibly simple, casual affairs (<a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/550320/art_of_rally/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">like the excellent <em>Art of Rally</em>!</a>)</p><p><em>Tokyo Xtreme Racer</em> (2025), then, is a welcome reminder that for many people racing video games were at their best when they were somewhere in between; when they were just video games about racing cars, not swollen attempts at simulating the act of driving. This is a game about menus, about tinkering with engine values, unlocking old Nissans and just driving around to have some fun. It's returning at a time when we've learned to appreciate that maybe we never had to move past these kinds of games at all.</p><p>Time now to confess that I'm a newcomer to the series, and one thing I love from playing this new release is the 1v1 aspect of the game. <em>Tokyo Xtreme Racer </em>works by just letting you drive around the motorway until you find a rival, then when you want to challenge them, you flash your headlights a couple of times and a race triggers.</p><figure><figcaption>Pictured: me coming up on my next opponent</figcaption></figure><p>You're supposed to challenge other drivers in fancy sports cars, who are clearly noted on the map as rivals, but turns out you can also just challenge <em>anyone </em>driving on the motorway. Guy driving a Dyna work truck? You can race them. Someone behind the wheel of a little Suzuki? Take them on. You don't get many points (needed to upgrade your car and buy stuff) for doing so, but it's <em>incredibly </em>funny the first 90-100 times you do it.</p><figure></figure><p>Being new, I was also unaware that the game, which mostly takes place with a very racing game tone and presentation, also has intros like this? I'm driving a Mazda on a motorway, but this looks like the intro to a game about mystical ninjas on PS2? Incredible stuff.</p><p>I'm glad this series is back, and I'm sad I missed it the first time around. We all need more video games in our lives where we can race against cab drivers in a 1987 Toyota Corolla, while a rousing eurobeat soundtrack plays in the background.&nbsp;</p></div><div><h2>Stay in touch</h2><p>Sign up for our free newsletter</p></div><div><h2><span>More from Aftermath</span></h2><div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/brownville-deer-pantry-youtube"><h3>Bad Day? Here’s A Deer Cam</h3></a><p>YouTube is full of horrors, but also a "food pantry" for deer</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/narrative-designer-job-description-video-games"><h3>Just What, Exactly, Does A Video Game’s Narrative Designer Do?</h3></a><p>'I think the largest&nbsp;misconception&nbsp;is that we're just writers'</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/ubisoft-phoenix-labs-layoffs-studio-closure-far-cry-dauntless"><h3>Another Big Day For Layoffs In Another Big Year For Layoffs</h3></a><p>Ubisoft is closing its third studio in two months, and Phoenix Labs is bidding farewell to "the majority" of its workforce</p></div></div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/all">See all posts<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="#000" stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round"><path d="M5 12h13m-6-7 7 7-7 7"></path></svg></a></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Scar-Lead Salvation debut trailer, gameplay, details, and screenshots]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/01/scar-lead-salvation-debut-trailer-gameplay-details-and-screenshots</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/scar-lead-salvation-debut-trailer-gameplay-details-and-screenshots.1095597/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/01/scar-lead-salvation-debut-trailer-gameplay-details-and-screenshots<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Returnal-like third-person shooter due out on May 29 in Japan.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Compile Heart [1,205 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/idea-factory/compile-heart">Compile Heart</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Neilo [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/neilo">Neilo</a> have released the first official trailer, gameplay videos, information, and screenshots for <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2025/01/compile-heart-and-neilo-announce-third-person-shooter-scar-lead-salvation-for-ps5-ps4-and-pc">newly announced</a> <a title="Genres > Third-Person Shooter [1,271 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/shooter/tps">third-person shooter</a> <em><a title="Games > Scar-Lead Salvation [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/scar-lead-salvation">Scar-Lead Salvation</a></em>, which is due out for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,726 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,631 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [22,223 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via Steam on May 29 in Japan. <span id="more-941277"></span></p><p>The PlayStation 5 version will be available both physically and digitally, while the PlayStation 4 and PC versions will be digital-only. The standard edition will cost 8,580 yen, while the Special Edition will cost 12,980 yen, and the Digital Deluxe Edition will cost 10,780 yen. The Special Edition includes a special box with ab illustration by marumoru, a visual art and setting materials book, the original soundtrack CD, a metal card case, a staff ID card, and two Willow serial number stickers. The Digital Deluxe Edition includes the digital art book and a digital soundtrack.</p><p>It is also worth noting that the PC version is noted as being distributed by <a title="Companies > Idea Factory International [391 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/idea-factory/idea-factory-international">Idea Factory International</a>, which could suggest <em>Scar-Lead Salvation</em> is planned for a simultaneous worldwide release on May 29. However, this has yet to be confirmed.</p><p>Get the first details below.</p><blockquote><p><strong>■ Story</strong></p><p>Willow Martin awakens in an unfamiliar room. She has no memory of her past, nor why she is here.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Who is she? Where did she come from? Is the AI offering her advice an ally or an enemy?</p><p>After surviving life-or-death battles against mechanical weapons, what lies ahead for Willow?</p><p><strong>■ Characters</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Willow Martin</strong> (voiced by Fairouz Ai) – The protagonist who has no memory of her past. Although she can’t remember anything, she gets caught up in battles against mechanical weapons. Her body moves instinctively, and she displays exceptional combat skills. Will she be able to escape her confined space and recover her lost memories?</li><li><strong>AI</strong> (voiced by Junichi Suwabe) – A mysterious entity that suddenly starts speaking to Willow through her intercom. Despite sensing some hidden agenda in the voice calling itself “AI,” Willow ends up hearing it out. Who is this being, and why is it helping Willow?</li></ul></blockquote><div id="carousel_941282"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div><blockquote><p><strong>■ System</strong></p><p>Escape from the loop of repeated death.</p><p>With a high difficulty that even advanced players will find challenging, death is not the end.</p><p><strong>Willow Awakens in a Mysterious Research Facility and is Attacked by Armed Machines</strong></p><p>When Willow dies, she loses her weapons and must restart the stage from the beginning. Evade the relentless bullet barrage, gather powerful weapons, and launch your counterattack.</p><p>Enemies are armed machines. Fight off the numerous mechanical weapons that attack you.</p><p>Each enemy has its own method of attack, so determine the right strategy to avoid taking hits.</p><p><strong>The Further You Progress, The Stronger the Enemies Become… Including Huge Biological Weapons</strong></p><p>Use actions to gain the upper hand:</p><ul><li><strong>Mirage Shift</strong> – An ability that breaks down the body into data and transports it to a separate space. In addition to passing through attacks, it can be used to quickly move short distances or through the air.</li><li><strong>Striker</strong> – A weapon mounted on your armor’s fist. Upon activation, it charges toward the target, dealing significant damage upon impact. It requires close proximity, making it risky, but the damage dealt is substantial.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch the announcement trailer and a set of gameplay videos below. View the screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/scar-lead-salvation/january-29-2025/">at the gallery</a>. Visit the official website <a href="https://www.compileheart.com/sls/" target="_blank">here</a>.</p><h2><span>Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="『スカーレッドサルベーション』アナウンストレーラー" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/1JfIneZTc-k?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><span>Gameplay Videos</span></h2><p><strong>System Video</strong></p><p><iframe title="『スカーレッドサルベーション』システム動画" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/QdBpDjhySc4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Enemy Video #1</strong></p><p><iframe title="『スカーレッドサルベーション』エネミー①" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/clgcpBIP01A?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Enemy Video #2</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="『スカーレッドサルベーション』エネミー②" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/636c-XpMKhs?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Enemy Video #3</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="『スカーレッドサルベーション』エネミー③" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rFPQ-cDYOyw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Battle Video #1: Powerful Enemy</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="『スカーレッドサルベーション』バトル①「強大な敵」" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/oBXP17OvO2g?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Battle Video #2: Various Weapons</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="『スカーレッドサルベーション』バトル②「様々な武器」" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Gxau7-ECaJM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Battle Video #3: <a title="Genres > Action [2,448 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">Action</a>s</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="『スカーレッドサルベーション』バトル③「アクション」" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/g1DKA6rBA2g?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Battle Video #4: Enemy’s Fierce Attack</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="『スカーレッドサルベーション』バトル④「敵の猛攻」" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/19XA8HfNhaU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Battle Video #5: Striker</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="『スカーレッドサルベーション』バトル⑤「アクション：ストライカー」" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/q1grgdchiRg?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Battle Video #6: Mirage Shift</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="『スカーレッドサルベーション』バトル⑥「アクション：ミラージュシフト」" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/v6PsyjiUuG0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox Game Pass Records Growth After Indiana Jones, Call of Duty, but Hardware Sales Drop]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/xbox-game-pass-growth-indiana-jones-great-circle-call-of-duty-hardware-falls</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/xbox-game-pass-records-growth-after-indiana-jones-call-of-duty-but-hardware-sales-drop.1095573/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/xbox-game-pass-growth-indiana-jones-great-circle-call-of-duty-hardware-falls<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Indiana Jones and the Great Circle records 4 million players.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">During today's Q2 investors call, Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella revealed that Indiana Jones and The Great Circle has reached 4 million players.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In an otherwise ho-hum earnings report for its gaming division, a bright spot appears to be MachineGames' newest release which has garnered critical acclaim, multiple awards, and now millions of players. While sales numbers are hard to pin down given its availability on Xbox Game Pass, 4 million is still an impressive number of players considering not many people knew exactly what to expect in a modern, AAA Indiana Jones game.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">We loved it ourselves, calling it an "irrestistable and immersive global treasure hunt," along with nominations for Game of the Year and Best Xbox game. You can read our <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-review">full review here</a>.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Elsewhere in Xbox land, Microsoft confirmed that Game Pass PC grew 30%  last quarter and set a new quarterly revenue record. On the cloud gaming side, 140 million hours of streaming has been logged. All this helped Xbox content and service revenue grow 2%.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">There's still work to be done however. While the Game Pass figures were stronger than expected, overall gaming revenue declined 7% and Xbox hardware revenue declined 29%.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">What does this all mean? Well, Microsoft still has ground to make up in the console and hardware space, but its continued investment into Game Pass appears to be paying off. Game Pass growth on PC makes sense given Xbox had a slate of big game releases last quarter that includes Indiana Jones but also Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 and Microsoft Flight Simulator. All of which were available on Game Pass day one for Ultimate subscribers.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Matt Kim is IGN's Senior Features Editor.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Capcom Spotlight + Monster Hunter Wilds Showcase set for February 4]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/01/capcom-spotlight-monster-hunter-wilds-showcase-set-for-february-4</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/capcom-spotlight-monster-hunter-wilds-showcase-set-for-february-4.1095555/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/01/capcom-spotlight-monster-hunter-wilds-showcase-set-for-february-4<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div role="main">
  
  <article>

    
<header>

  <div>

    <ul>
        </ul>

    
    <p><span>Featuring Monster Hunter Wilds, Onimusha: Way of the Sword, and Capcom fighting collections.</span>
      </p></div>

  

</header>  

<!-- Moved from templates/posts/default.php -->

    <div><p><a title="Companies > Capcom [2,554 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/capcom">Capcom</a> will host a <a href="https://www.capcom-games.com/showcase/spotlight/en-us/" target="_blank">Capcom Spotlight</a> broadcast followed directly by a <em><a title="Games > Monster Hunter Wilds [25 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/monster-hunter-wilds">Monster Hunter Wilds</a></em> Showcase on <a href="https://www.timeanddate.com/worldclock/fixedtime.html?iso=20250204T2200" target="_blank">February 4 at 2:00 p.m. PT / 5:00 p.m. ET / February 5 at 7:00 JST</a>, the company <a href="https://twitter.com/CapcomUSA_/status/1884769389930774934" target="_blank">announced</a>. You will be able to watch it on YouTube (<a href="https://www.youtube.com/@CapcomUSA" target="_blank">English</a>, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@capcom" target="_blank">Japanese</a>). <span id="more-941255"></span></p><p>The 35-minute broadcast will feature “back-to-back info about all that’s coming from Capcom,” including <em>Monster Hunter Wilds</em>, <em><a title="Games > Onimusha: Way of the Sword [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/onimusha-way-of-the-sword">Onimusha: Way of the Sword</a></em>, <em><a title="Games > Capcom Fighting Collection 2 [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/capcom-fighting-collection-2">Capcom Fighting Collection 2</a></em>, and <em><a title="Games > Marvel vs. Capcom Fighting Collection: Arcade Classics [4 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/marvel-vs-capcom-fighting-collection-arcade-classics">Marvel vs. Capcom Fighting Collection: Arcade Classics</a></em>, followed by further information on <em>Monster Hunter Wilds</em> with producer Ryozo Tsujimoto, including the latest trailer and details about the <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2025/01/monster-hunter-wilds-second-open-beta-test-set-for-february-6-to-9-february-13-to-16">second open beta test</a>.</p><p>Watch a teaser trailer below.</p><h2><span>Teaser Trailer</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><p><iframe title="[Teaser] Capcom Spotlight + Monster Hunter Wilds Showcase - Feb 2025" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/82iI8NfT7d8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe title="カプコンの最新情報をお届けするデジタルイベント「カプコンスポットライト」と「モンスターハンターワイルズ ショーケース」2本立ての番組が2月5日（水）朝7時より配信！" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/dp2LEWIU_RA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div>

        
    
  </article>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No Man’s Sky update adds ‘trillions’ of planets]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/599537/no-mans-sky-worlds-2-update</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/no-man%E2%80%99s-sky-update-adds-%E2%80%98trillions%E2%80%99-of-planets.1095543/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/news/599537/no-mans-sky-worlds-2-update<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/andrew-webster">Andrew Webster</a> <span>is an entertainment editor covering streaming, virtual worlds, and every single Pokémon video game. Andrew joined The Verge in 2012, writing over 4,000 stories.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/8/12/12454434/no-mans-sky-diaries"><em>No Man’s Sky</em> has always been big</a>, but the game’s newest update sounds like it will expand things considerably. According to developer Hello Games, the update will introduce “billions of new solar systems and trillions of new planets.”</p><p>The update is called <em>Worlds Part II</em>; <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/7/17/24200072/no-mans-sky-next-update-worlds-part-1">it follows <em>Worlds Part I </em>from last year</a>, which made the game’s planets more detailed and realistic. In addition to increasing the sheer scale of planets and systems available to explore, the new update also adds more biomes and terrain types. Here are some of the highlights, via Hello Games cofounder Sean Murray:</p><div><ul><li><span>“Terrain is more detailed and far more varied with huge mountains and these massive features.”</span></li><li><span>“Gas giants are truly epic, ten times bigger than our biggest planet. It’s truly end-game stuff to explore them with huge storms that rage across the surface.”</span></li><li><span>“New tech allows oceans that can be several kilometers deep. A new lighting system makes them look so different. New caustics, light shafts and the deeper that you explore the darker it gets.”</span></li></ul></div><p>There are also new alien creatures, about which Murray says, “I think we’ve gone probably weirder than ever before.” <em>Worlds Part II</em> sounds like it would be a huge update for any release, let alone one that’s approaching its 10th anniversary. As with all of <em>No Man’s Sky</em>’s many previous updates, it will be free for all players — and you can download it today. Check out the full patch notes <a href="https://www.nomanssky.com/worlds-part-ii-update">right here</a>.</p><p>According to Murray, some of these features come from tech that was created for the studio’s next game, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23990841/hello-games-light-no-fire-trailer">the fantasy adventure <em>Light No Fire</em></a>. “The team is extremely busy on <em>Light No Fire</em>,” he explains. “Each time we push our engine to new places though we have this urge to share it with the community, with <em>No Man’s Sky</em>.”</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shikhondo: Youkai Rampage coming to Switch on May 29]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/01/shikhondo-youkai-rampage-coming-to-switch-on-may-29</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/shikhondo-youkai-rampage-coming-to-switch-on-may-29.1095537/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/01/shikhondo-youkai-rampage-coming-to-switch-on-may-29<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Shoot 'em up currently available for PC.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > CFK [74 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/cfk">CFK</a> and developer <a title="Companies > DeerFarm" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/deerfarm">DeerFarm</a> will release a <a title="Platforms > Switch [16,560 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a> version of <a title="Genres > Shoot 'Em Up [760 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/shoot-em-up">shoot ’em up game</a> <em><a title="Games > Shikhondo: Youkai Rampage" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/shikhondo-youkai-rampage">Shikhondo: Youkai Rampage</a></em> on May 29, the companies announced. <span id="more-941249"></span></p><p><em>Shikhondo: Youkai Rampage</em> first launched for PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2712480/Shikhondo_Youkai_Rampage/" target="_blank">Steam</a> on April 18, 2024.</p><p>In Japan, the Switch version will be available both physically and digitally. The standard physical edition will cost 5,478 yen, while the first-print limited edition will cost 8,778 yen. The latter includes a special box, art book, 10-track original soundtrack CD, and a diorama acrylic stand.</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Shikhondo-Youkai-Rampage-Switch_01-29-25_NSW-CE.jpg"></a></figure><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its Steam page:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Popular vertically scrolling shoot’em up game <em>Shikhondo</em> is back and powered up! One day, the soul-starved Youkai escape from the depths of hell. Now, the story of the Grim Reaper and the girl who has fallen into this land begins!</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Continuing the Long Line of Shoot’em Up Classics</strong> – Boasts unique and charming protagonists, a variety of bosses with bizarre and fantastical designs, and waves upon waves of enemies to keep players on their toes!</li><li><strong>The Charm of Eastern Fantasy</strong> – In reimagining the Youkai from Korean folktales and historical records from a new perspective, the game features inventive original characters drawn in an elegant fashion and a gripping story fully-voiced by professional voice actresses.</li><li><strong>Soul Collection System</strong> – <em>Shikhondo: Youkai Rampage</em> features a unique system called ‘Soul Collect’, where players can charge their ‘Soul Gauge’ as they avoid enemy bullets. It’s perilous, but the closer players stay to bullets, the faster their gauges charge! Then, players can use their dodge to evade bullets for a moment! Nullify enemy attacks and shoot for a new high score!</li><li><strong>Various Game Modes</strong> – Play through the main story in <a title="Platforms > Arcade [375 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/arcade">Arcade</a> mode, focus down the bosses in Boss Rush mode, or get double souls but lose in a single hit in Hardcore mode. <em>Shikhondo: Youkai Rampage</em> also features a new Dual mode, a strategic single-player mode that allows switching between the two protagonists to match the circumstances players face! In addition, the game has been reworked, adding new optional features and even a new stage!</li></ul><p><strong>Characters</strong></p><ul><li><strong>The Girl</strong> – One day, the girl falls into this world, losing even the memory of her own name. She begins her harrowing journey to fight the youkai in search of her memories, her hometown, and her family.</li><li><strong>Grim Reaper</strong> – Death’s emissary who must face the begrudged souls-turned-Youkai and perform her given duties. She happens upon the girl, teaming up to help her.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Switch Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><p><iframe title="Nintendo Switch |『Shikhondo: Youkai Rampage』Official Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/KeZcRxbLt2M?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe title="Nintendo Switch |『食魂徒 ~百花妖乱~』公式プロモーションムービー" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Rkkazfej51w?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Korean</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Nintendo Switch |『식혼도 ~백화요란~』공식 프로모션 무비" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/xjwDOKciO3w?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Korean (with Japanese Voice-Overs)</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Nintendo Switch |『식혼도 ~백화요란~』공식 프로모션 무비 (일본어 음성 ver.)" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/X3s0XxGl_jM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Piczle Cross: Rune Factory launches February 20]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/01/piczle-cross-rune-factory-launches-february-20</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/piczle-cross-rune-factory-launches-february-20.1095534/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/01/piczle-cross-rune-factory-launches-february-20<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Solve nonogram puzzles in the world of Rune Factory.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Nonogram puzzle game <em><a title="Games > Piczle Cross: Rune Factory [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/piczle-cross-rune-factory">Piczle Cross: Rune Factory</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > Switch [16,560 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a> and <a title="Platforms > PC [22,223 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3134280/Piczle_Cross_Rune_Factory/" target="_blank">Steam</a> on February 20, publisher <a title="Companies > Rainy Frog [19 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/rainy-frog">Rainy Frog</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Score Studios [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/score-studios">Score Studios</a> announced. It will support English, French, Italian, German, Spanish, Japanese, Korean, Simplified Chinese, and Traditional Chinese language options. <span id="more-941245"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3134280/Piczle_Cross_Rune_Factory/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam page</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>From the creator of the <em>Piczle</em> series comes the latest nonogram experience.</p><p><a title="Companies > Experience [210 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/experience">Experience</a> the characters, monsters, and world of the <em><a title="Series > Rune Factory [20 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/series/rune-factory">Rune Factory</a></em> series through addictive nonogram logic-puzzles!</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <ul><li>300 nonogram puzzles with both classic and color variations!</li><li>20 collage puzzles, made up of many smaller puzzles, both in classic and color variations!</li><li>Fight and capture monsters!</li><li>Uncover villagers and bachelors!</li><li>Customize your farm, pick your spouse and choose your weapons!</li><li>Unlock entries in the in-game Compendium and learn about the characters in <em>Rune Factory</em>!</li><li>Unlock entries in the in-game Bestiary and learn more about the beasts of Rigbarth!</li><li>The most feature-rich nonogram experience available!</li><li>Dozens of Quality of Life features, as well as aides for newcomers and a challenge mode for experts</li><li>Challenge yourself… or don’t! There is no wrong way to play!</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe title="ピクセルクロス　ルーンファクトリーエディション (Switch/Steam)" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/l35do8W3FxU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Does Kingdom Come Deliverance 2 Have Early Access?]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/does-kingdom-come-deliverance-2-have-early-access/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/does-kingdom-come-deliverance-2-have-early-access.1095516/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/does-kingdom-come-deliverance-2-have-early-access/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Kingdom Come Deliverance 2 having Early Access would go a long way to shortening the seven-year wait for a sequel. The first game was a blockbuster success and has kept fans entertained for years. The time has come for a new title though, but you want to know if you can play it early, and we know.</p>



<p>Warhorse Studios believes in the “bigger is better ideology.” The sequel is bigger, the development team working on the game is bigger, and it has a bigger weapon pool. It’s just <em>bigger</em>. The first game has <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/kingdom-come-deliverance-sales/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sold over 8 million units</a>, so it’s obvious the interest is there—hence the Early Access discussion.</p>



<p>Early Access is all the rage. Everyone wants everything now. Let’s see if you can have <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-release-date-platforms/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Kingdom Come Deliverance 2</a>. </p>



<h2 id="h-can-you-play-kingdom-come-deliverance-2-early-access">Can You Play Kingdom Come Deliverance 2 Early Access?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>We’ll have to pass on that drink for now. Credit to Warhorse Studios</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Kingdom Come Deliverance 2 doesn’t feature any form of Early Access, meaning the only way to play KC2 is to wait for the worldwide launch.</strong></p>



<p>Warhorse Studios hasn’t commented on Early Access, which isn’t ideal. Worse still, we’ve seen every Kingdom Come Deliverance 2 edition, and while they come with a whole host of luxurious benefits for launch and after KC2’s release, <strong>there’s no Early Access</strong>.</p>



<p>Why is this? I don’t know. There does seem to be a trend of games with close communities and titles geared toward players (and not microtransactions) foregoing modern-day business practices—Early Access being one. The developer has opted not to have Early Access, and potentially use the benefit as a way to flog more expensive editions.</p>



<p>Lots of this is speculation on my part. However, one thing not up for debate is there is no Early Access.  </p>



<h2 id="h-kingdom-come-deliverance-2-editions">Kingdom Come Deliverance 2 Editions</h2>



<p><strong>There is a Standard Edition, Gold Edition, and Collector’s Edition for Kingdom Come Deliverance 2 if you want more out of the experience.</strong></p>



<p>Each one ramps up the price, but also the content included. To iterate, none of them have Early Access. But you can check out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/all-kingdom-come-deliverance-2-editions-collectors-edition-gold-edition/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">every Kingdom Come Deliverance 2 edition</a> to see if any catch your eye. </p>



<p>Plus, securing your copy early is a surefire way to guarantee the inviting <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/all-kingdom-come-deliverance-2-editions-collectors-edition-gold-edition/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">pre-order bonus</a> too.</p>



<hr>



<p>I’m sorry if you were hoping for better news. At least it isn’t long now until the February 4 release date, and you can make the Kingdom of Bohemia your own. Let us know the first thing you’re going to do in Kingdom Come Deliverance 2 in the comments below.</p>



<p>We’ve answered many other questions about the sequel too including if it’s coming to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/is-kingdom-come-deliverance-2-coming-game-pass/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Xbox Game Pass</a>, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-big-is-kingdom-come-deliverance-2-map/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">how big the map is</a>, and what the game’s <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-post-launch-roadmap/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">post-launch roadmap</a> plans are looking like.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Game Pass "Doesn't Hurt Game Companies," Says Doom Co-Creator]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/game-pass-doesnt-hurt-game-companies-says-doom-co-creator/1100-6529136/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/game-pass-doesnt-hurt-game-companies-says-doom-co-creator.1095513/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/game-pass-doesnt-hurt-game-companies-says-doom-co-creator/1100-6529136/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529136">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>There's an ongoing debate as to whether Microsoft's Game Pass hurts or helps sales of titles that are available on the service. But as far as id Software co-founder and Doom co-creator John Romero is concerned, Game Pass is beneficial to the video game industry.</p><p>Via <a href="https://www.trueachievements.com/news/doom-creator-loves-xbox-game-pass" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">True Achievements</a>, Romero was recently interviewed by <a href="https://youtu.be/sBOMxyuyQeQ" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Xbox Expansion Pass</a>, and he was effusive with his praise for Game Pass.</p><p>"I love it," said Romero. "I mean, who doesn't love Game Pass? It's Netflix for games; who doesn't want that? It's great because it's try before you buy... one thing after another thing. Really the barrier for people to play games is just access to those games. Even free-to-play games, it's like, knowing that those games exist, and Game Pass is like 'Here they are!'"</p><p>Romero went on to add that Game Pass "doesn't hurt the game companies that made those games," because players get to experience titles more quickly even if they don't keep them. It's unclear if Romero feels this way even about games that launch on Game Pass at the same time that they hit stores. <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-campaign-review/1900-6418306/" data-ref-id="1900-6418306">Call of Duty: Black Ops 6</a> was seemingly unaffected by its availability on Game Pass, and it was <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/2024s-best-selling-games-in-the-us/2900-5106/" data-ref-id="2900-5106">the top-selling game in America for 2024</a>. Conversely, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-review-im-making-this-up-as-i-go/1900-6418322/" data-ref-id="1900-6418322">Indiana Jones and the Great Circle</a> only debuted at No. 14 on <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/indiana-jones-enters-the-20-best-selling-games-in-the-us-for-december-but-black-ops-6-is-still-no-1/2900-6157/" data-ref-id="2900-6157">December 2024's list of best-selling games</a>. That game may have also been hampered by the fact that its PlayStation 5 port won't arrive until later this spring.</p><p>Although Romero didn't work on <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/doom-the-dark-ages-release-date-trailer-story/1100-6526483/" data-ref-id="1100-6526483">Doom: The Dark Ages</a>, that title will be a day-one release on Game Pass when it arrives on May 15. And unlike Indiana Jones and the Great Circle, it will also be hitting PlayStation 5 at the same time as its debut on Xbox Series X|S.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>