<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 15:35:55 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What We Played – Star Wars Outlaws, Concord & everything at Gamescom]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/08/23/what-we-played-star-wars-outlaws-concord-everything-at-gamescom/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/what-we-played-%E2%80%93-star-wars-outlaws-concord-everything-at-gamescom.962088/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/08/23/what-we-played-star-wars-outlaws-concord-everything-at-gamescom/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>It’s been a busy old week in video games, and so the fitting way to spend my Friday afternoon is to tap out a quick catch up on What We Played, which travelling on a very delayed, very diverted train to escape Cologne. Wish me luck in my continuing adventures!</p>
<p>But train travails is now what we’re really here to talk about, and Dom and I had a jam-packed week of previewing games at Gamescom 2024. We’ve played and seen around 40 games between us, both big and small, and we’ll be churning out our features and write ups over the coming fortnight. But what have we enjoyed seeing the most?</p>

<p>For me, the three games that I’d pick out as highlights were <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/06/09/rebellion-reveal-atomfall-which-looks-a-bit-like-fallout-goes-british/">Atomfall</a> by those folks at Rebellion, a game which is probably a good bit different to what you think, <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/08/20/civilization-vii-gameplay-revealed-with-february-release-date/">Civilization VII</a>, which is exploring some fascinating ideas for the 4X genre, and <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/08/22/rogue-waters-sails-the-turn-based-tactical-roguelite-seas-in-september/">Rogue Waters</a>, which has a really fun take on turn-based tactical gameplay that’s a lot about positioning and cascading abilities.</p>
<p>As for <strong>Dom</strong>, <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/07/07/metaphor-refantazio-trailer-showcases-why-you-should-get-excited-for-this-rpg/">Metaphor: ReFantazio</a> was one game that really stood out, and he rather enjoyed how very British is felt, Dying Light: The Beast with the return of Kyle Crane, and then the musical RPG of Fretless.</p>

<p>On to everyone else, and<strong> Nic B</strong> has continued to enjoy his time with MTG Arena, exploring the online-only pre-con decks, and a smidgeon of Monster Hunter Now.</p>
<p><strong>Jim’s</strong> continuing adventures in Fallout: New Vegas have taken him into the Lonesome Road DLC, which has been a nice narrative detour (with a big difficulty spike). He’s also tried out Rise of Ronin using his PS Portal, which wasn’t quite conducive to the split-second reflexes needed. And most significantly, he’s been playing <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/concord">Concord</a> for our review, “As a lapsed Overwatch addict, it’s definitely hitting that hero shooter sweet spot, with a vibrant catch of heroes who each tout markedly different playstyles.”</p>

<p><strong>Ade</strong> has been on the review train with an eclectic mix of Truck racing with Monster Jam Showdown, old-school Zelda-ing with Crypt Custodian, and a spot of retro 2D shoot ’em up-ing with Shadow of the Ninja Reborn. <strong>Aran</strong> in the same carriage, playing Gori: Cuddly Carnage for review and Beyond Galaxyland for a preview.</p>
<p>The re-release of the TimeSplitters trilogy on PS5 had <strong>Miguel</strong> diving back into these FPS classics, but he’s still spent most of his time with Ace Combat 5. From there, “a really wild racing game kick” bounced him between&nbsp;Ride Ridge 2, Ridge Racer 6, F1 2023, Split/Second and Midnight Club Los Angeles.</p>

<p>And finally, we come to <strong>Gamoc</strong>. He’s been playing <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/star-wars-outlaws">Star Wars Outlaws</a>. The review embargo isn’t up until Monday at 2PM, so keep an eye out for something around about then!</p>
<p><em>Now, what have you been playing this week?</em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Avowed Developers Confirm 30 FPS Was The Target In Development]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/avowed-developers-confirm-30-fps-was-the-target/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/avowed-developers-confirm-30-fps-was-the-target-in-development.962085/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/avowed-developers-confirm-30-fps-was-the-target/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>In an interview with members of the Iron Lords Podcast, Matt Hansen, Art Director, and Ryan Warden, Production Director, sat down to talk about Avowed and what players can expect from the game. One of the most surprising things from <a href="https://x.com/GPTGamingNews/status/1826920564700631363" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the interview</a> was that their target during development for Avowed was 30 FPS across the board. Considering Avowed is a first-person action RPG, this number surprises quite a few people. While many are defending their statement, saying that you don't necessarily need 60 FPS for a game like this, some wholeheartedly believe that 60 FPS should be the bare minimum.</p>
<p><iframe title="Exclusive Avowed Interview Ft @MrMattyPlays | Gameplay Q&amp;A | Xbox Consoles 30FPS? | Gamescom 2024" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/AxBL4jTHs5w?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>At the moment, they haven't explicitly said whether the game will be able to run at 60 FPS or not, but they have expressed that Avowed will hit 30 FPS with plenty of flashy effects in place to make the game more desirable.</p>
<p>Much like in <a href="https://wccftech.com/avowed-possible-endings-now-reach-into-double-digits/">another post</a> we wrote about Avowed, there are macro and micro endings for players to achieve. Those excited to get into the game now know that the ending slides have reached double digits. However, how many are macro endings remains to be confirmed, with multiple variations. According to the interview, though, there are well over 50 variations for players to encounter.</p>
<p>In Avowed, players will play as the Envoy from the Aedyrian Empire, where they are then sent on a mission to the Living Lands to investigate the Soul Plague. While this game does take place in the same universe as Pillars of Eternity, the two stories are not directly connected. However, playing Pillars of Eternity does offer the opportunity to get some additional context for Avowed.</p>
<p>The interview with the developers dove into some other essential details for Avowed, such as the lack of a traditional class system. Instead, players are given full authority to explore abilities as they wish, mixing and matching abilities from classes to create the hybrid class that works for them. This helps contribute to the many different ways players can play the game, allowing them as much freedom as they want to create their playstyle that suits them for the journey through Avowed.</p>
<p>The full interview is over thirty minutes long, and they break down plenty of important factors of Avowed, such as the delays that the game experienced, the world-building, and trying to make it seem as dense and populated as possible.</p>
<p>It remains to be seen whether the developers of Avowed will see the mixed opinions on the 30 FPS choice for the game or not, but there is the possibility that they will later make a statement about it or begin to tailor the game to run at a higher FPS for those who want a smoother experience.</p>


				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Black Myth: Wukong Sales Top 10 Million Just Three Days After Release]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/black-myth-wukong-sales-10-million</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/black-myth-wukong-sales-top-10-million-just-three-days-after-release.962082/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/black-myth-wukong-sales-10-million<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Black Myth: Wukong&nbsp;</em>sales have reached a frankly insane milestone just three days after the game's release, developer and publisher GameScience has announced.</p>
<p>Per <a href="https://x.com/BlackMythGame/status/1826985302592049599" rel="noopener" target="_blank">a post on the game's official X (formerly Twitter) account</a>,&nbsp;<em>Black Myth: Wukong&nbsp;</em>has sold 10 million copies since launch. As a reminder, the game was released on August 20th, which was just three days ago.</p>
<p>GameScience thanks players for their "support and love" for the game, wishing everyone a "great gaming weekend" in the post. The developer also includes some artwork of the player character clutching his healing gourd.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/black-myth-wukong-sales-10-million-artwork.jpg?itok=O4uKjVkD 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/black-myth-wukong-sales-10-million-artwork.jpg?itok=bioaCDcX 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Black Myth: Wukong&nbsp;</em>has done some serious numbers.</figcaption></figure><p>Not only has the game reached 10 million sales, but it's also managed to achieve a total of three million concurrent players across both platforms on which it's currently available (PC and PlayStation 5, in case you're wondering).</p>
<p>It's fair to say the rise of&nbsp;<em>Black Myth: Wukong&nbsp;</em>has been meteoric, to say the least. Since being announced back in 2020, hype for the game has built and built, resulting in&nbsp;<em>Wukong&nbsp;</em>being the most-wishlisted game on Steam prior to its release.</p>
<p>After its launch, the game quickly began to climb the Steam charts, topping the 24-hour concurrent player count list <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/black-myth-wukong-24-hour-player-count">within just a handful of hours</a>. Further success seemed inevitable, and, indeed, so it has proven.</p>
<p>The rapidity of&nbsp;<em>Wukong</em>'s rise can, it seems, largely be attributed to Chinese players. As <a href="https://newsletter.gamediscover.co/p/black-myth-wukong-behind-the-numbers" rel="noopener" target="_blank">this (paywalled) article from GameDiscoverCo</a> points out, around 88% of the game's player base is based in China, and 94% of&nbsp;<em>Wukong</em>'s Steam reviews are in simplified Chinese.</p>

<p>Given that&nbsp;<em>Black Myth: Wukong</em>'s developer is Chinese, it perhaps stands to reason that the majority of the game's players would be in the studio's native country. Still, it demonstrates the power of China as a demographic when it comes to gaming.</p>
<p><em>Black Myth: Wukong&nbsp;</em>is available right now on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2358720/Black_Myth_Wukong/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor">PC</a> and <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-gb/games/black-myth-wukong/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">PlayStation 5</a>, with an Xbox Series X|S version planned for later down the line. You can <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/black-myth-wukong-review-serious-monkey-business">read my review here</a> if you want to know why I think it deserves its immense success.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How Long Does Silent Hill 2 Remake Take To Beat?]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/how-long-silent-hill-2-remake/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/how-long-does-silent-hill-2-remake-take-to-beat.962076/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/how-long-silent-hill-2-remake/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Silent Hill 2 Remake launches in October, and many fans have wondered about game length and how long it’ll take to beat the game. Now, thanks to the game’s creative director, we have an answer.</p>



<p>In responding to <a href="https://x.com/Mateusz_Lenart_/status/1825636867900838162" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">questions on Twitter</a>, creative director Mateusz Lenart says that Silent Hill 2 remake should take between 16-18 hours to beat on the first playthrough. He then added that it could taken even longer than that depending on how you play.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Silent Hill 2 - Story Trailer | PS5 Games" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/CMvrMTmuJuA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>“If you like to spent your time searching for everything that we put into the game and things we’ve hidden for you, it will take you more than 20 [hours] for sure,” he said. “I’m not counting the new game plus and all endings of course. </p>



<p>“I’m curious how fast will you get all of them.”</p>



<p>As far as the time length goes, a 16- to 18-hour playthrough puts the remake ahead of <a href="https://howlongtobeat.com/game/8523" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">what the completionist time</a> is for the original Silent Hill 2 from 2001. And, for the most part, fans seem excited about the extended time to play the game.</p>



<p>“That is some very pleasantly surprising news,” <a href="https://x.com/Micahmakefunny/status/1826753846447894726" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">one user said</a>.</p>



<p>Said <a href="https://x.com/LukeCastles1/status/1826699655495000315" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">another</a>, “That’s a lot longer than the original, I’m very excited for this.”</p>



<p>Silent Hill 2 Remake releases October 8 for PlayStation 5 and PC. The game is a PS5 console exclusive for at least a year, according to reports. After which, it will be able to come to Xbox Series X|S.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, check out the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-myth-wukong-sold-10-million-copies/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">latest milestone reached by Black Myth: Wukong</a> in its first week.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>
    
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[gamescom 2024 Award Winners Revealed: Monster Hunter Wilds Wins Big]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/gamescom-2024-award-winners-revealed</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gamescom-2024-award-winners-revealed-monster-hunter-wilds-wins-big.962073/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/gamescom-2024-award-winners-revealed<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Capcom's next won every category it was nominated for.</h2></div><section><p>gamescom 2024 has come and gone, and as the annual event ends, now comes the time for awards to games that appeared this year. With categories, such as best visuals and audio to more platform-specific ones (excluding Nintendo this year), like best Xbox games, this list provides every gamescom 2024 award and this year's recipient.</p><p>Of this year's recipients, Capcom's upcoming project, <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/monster-hunter-wilds">Monster Hunter Wilds</a>, won the most awards, winning in every single category it was nominated in, such as Most Entertaining and Most Epic. Supermassive Games and Bandai Namco's upcoming project, <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/little-nightmares-iii">Little Nightmares 3</a>, also won multiple accolades, winning three out of the four categories it was nominated for, such as Best Visuals and Best Audio. </p><p>If you want to know more, <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/gamescom-2024-announcements">check out the biggest announcements at this year's gamescom</a>. If you want to know what was specifically <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/gamescom-opening-night-live-2024-everything-announced">unveiled at Opening Night Live earlier this week</a>, check out our roundup.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3>Gamescom 2024 Show Floor Photos</h3></div></output><p>The full list of winners for the gamescom 2023 awards are as follows:</p><h2><strong>gamescom Awards 2024 Winners: </strong></h2><h3><strong>Best Trailer</strong></h3><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Monster Hunter Wilds [Winner]</strong></li></ul><h3><strong>Best of Show Floor</strong></h3><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>WINNER: Microsoft / Xbox / Bethesda / Blizzard</strong></li></ul><h3><strong>Visuals</strong></h3><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>WINNER: Little Nightmares 3</strong></li><li>Crimson Desert</li><li>Dune: Awakening</li><li>Empire of the Ants</li><li>Star Wars Outlaws</li></ul><h3><strong>Audio</strong></h3><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>WINNER: Little Nightmares 3</strong></li><li>Dune: Awakening</li><li>Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2</li><li>Nine Sols</li><li>Star Wars Outlaws</li></ul><h3><strong>Gameplay</strong></h3><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>WINNER: Frostpunk 2</strong></li><li>Blue Prince</li><li>Empire of the Ants</li><li>PVKK: Planetenverteidigungskanonenkommandant</li><li>The Alters</li></ul><h3><strong>Most Entertaining</strong></h3><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>WINNER: Monster Hunter Wilds</strong></li><li>inZoi</li><li>Palworld</li><li>PVKK: Planetenverteidigungskanonenkommandant</li><li>Star Wars Outlaws</li></ul><h3><strong>Most Epic</strong></h3><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>WINNER: Monster Hunter Wilds</strong></li><li>Crimson Desert</li><li>Dune: Awakening</li><li>Kingdom Come Deliverance 2</li><li>Star Wars Outlaws</li></ul><h3><strong>Most Wholesome</strong></h3><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>WINNER: Tavern Talk</strong></li><li>Creatures of Ava</li><li>Tiny Bookshop</li><li>Urban Jungle</li><li>Woodo</li></ul><h3><strong>Games for Impact</strong></h3><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>WINNER: Creatures of Ava</strong></li><li>GreenGuardiansVR</li><li>Out &amp; About</li><li>REKA</li><li>Tiny Bookshop</li></ul><h3><strong>Best Xbox Game</strong></h3><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>WINNER: Little Nightmares 3</strong></li><li>Age of Mythology: Retold</li><li>Creatures of Ava</li><li>Star Wars Outlaws</li><li>The Alters</li></ul><h3><strong>Best PC Game</strong></h3><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>WINNER: Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2</strong></li><li>Dune Awakening</li><li>Empire of the Ants</li><li>Frostpunk 2</li><li>The Alters</li></ul><h3><strong>Best PlayStation Game</strong></h3><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>WINNER: Monster Hunter Wilds</strong></li><li>Dragon Ball: Sparking! Zero</li><li>Little Nightmares 3</li><li>The First Berserker: Khazan</li><li>Unknown 9: Awakening</li></ul><h3><strong>Best Mobile Game</strong></h3><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>WINNER: Genshin Impact</strong></li><li>Digital Animals Game</li><li>Dungeons of Dreadlock 2 - The Dead King's Secret</li><li>Monster Hunter Now</li><li>Zenless Zone Zero</li></ul><p><em>Taylor is a Reporter at IGN. You can follow her on Twitter </em><a href="https://twitter.com/TayNixster" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>@TayNixster.</em></a></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokémon Trading Card Shop Allegedly Contained $1 Million Worth of Meth]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/pokmon-trading-card-shop-allegedly-contained-1-million-worth-of-meth</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pok%C3%A9mon-trading-card-shop-allegedly-contained-1-million-worth-of-meth.962067/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/pokmon-trading-card-shop-allegedly-contained-1-million-worth-of-meth<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>A Pokémon Trading Card Game shop in Hong Kong allegedly had more than $1 million worth of Schedule 2 drug methamphetamine, commonly known as crystal meth, hidden in the back.</p><p>As reported by <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/pokemon-card-shop-had-over-1-million-in-meth-police-say/1100-6526063/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">GameSpot</a>, the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/law-and-crime/article/3275171/hong-kong-police-raid-pokemon-card-shop-used-drug-front-seize-hk10-million-ice" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">South China Morning Post</a> revealed a 28-year-old man had been arrested following the discovery of what is alleged to be 5 kilograms of crystal meth in a "staff only area" of the Pokémon card shop.</p><p>Located in the residential district of Hung Hom, the shop held Pokémon card tournaments that teenagers and children would attend to play the Pokémon TCG with friends. Police confirmed no child or teenager was involved in the purchasing the crystal meth, however.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>"Storing such a large quantity of narcotics in a place where teenagers and children can visit is irresponsible and disgraceful behavior that also heightens the possible risk of teenagers and children mistakenly encountering illegal drugs," Hong Kong Narcotics Bureau inspector Liong Chun-Hin said.</p><p>Perhaps inspired by Team Rocket, Pokémon cards have long been the target of criminal endeavors but usually with thieves trying to steal them.</p><p><a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokmon-and-other-trading-cards-targets-of-unprecedent-number-of-robberies-in-japan">Tokyo police reported an unprecedented number of trading card thefts</a> in the latter half of 2022, while <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/thousands-dollars-pokmon-merch-reportedly-stolen-after-thief-breaks-through-a-store-wall">an independent gaming store in Minnesota reportedly had around $250,000 worth of Pokémon</a> merchandise stolen in February of that year. One month later, again in Tokyo, <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/man-arrested-after-literal-pokemon-card-heist">a man was arrested for allegedly launching a literal heist</a> in order to steal the treasured cards.</p><p>Making the most of a bad situation, a trading card shop in California posted a video of thieves who stole 35,000 Pokémon cards from them in January 2024 and <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/thieves-caught-on-camera-stealing-35000-pokmon-cards-get-mocked-by-store-staff">mocked them for not knowing what to take</a>.</p><p><em>Ryan Dinsdale is an IGN freelance reporter. He'll talk about The Witcher all day.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Star Wars Outlaws Spoilers Have Leaked Online]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/star-wars-outlaws-spoilers-have-leaked-online</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/star-wars-outlaws-spoilers-have-leaked-online.962064/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/star-wars-outlaws-spoilers-have-leaked-online<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">The Dark Side is in our nature.</h2></div><section><p>Star Wars fans beware: Spoilers for Ubisoft's upcoming open world game Star Wars Outlaws have leaked online.</p><p>As reported by <a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/a-week-before-its-full-release-star-wars-outlaws-is-being-livestreamed-on-kick/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">VGC</a>, a user on live streaming platform Kick has been streaming Star Wars Outlaws a full four days before its release date, though it's unclear how they came to acquire a copy. Footage from the stream has naturally spread far and wide across the internet, potentially spoiling the highly anticipated game for many.</p><p>Star Wars Outlaws launches <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/star-wars-outlaws-release-date-revealed-alongside-a-story-trailer-teasing-the-underworlds-golden-age">August 27, 2024 for PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X and S, and PC</a> for those willing to spend <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/star-wars-outlaws-release-date-special-editions">$109.99 on the Gold Edition</a>, $129.99 on the Ultimate Edition, or $17.99 a month for <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ubisoft-multi-access-and-pc-access-become-ubisoft-premium-cheaper-tier-ubisoft-classics-available">the Ubisoft Plus subscription service</a>. The $69.99 Standard Edition arrives three days later on August 30.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>Falling more in line with the <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/star-wars-jedi-survivor-review">Star Wars Jedi</a> series compared to the likes of <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2019/12/17/star-wars-battlefront-2-review-2019">Star Wars Battlefront</a> or <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/star-wars-squadrons-multiplayer-review">Star Wars Squadrons</a>, Star Wars Outlaws is a solely single player experience that puts players in the shoes of wannabe scoundrel Kay Vess as she looks to make her mark on the galaxy far, far away.</p><p>Players can explore five different planets from Star Wars lore new and old, including Tatooine, a Toshara moon, Akiva, Kijimi, and Cantonica. All open worlds of their own, these are <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/star-wars-outlaws-isnt-going-down-the-procedurally-generated-worlds-route">around the size of two or three zones in Assassin's Creed Odyssey</a> and <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/some-star-wars-outlaws-planets-can-be-crossed-in-4-or-5-minutes-on-a-speeder">some can be crossed in four or five minutes on a speeder</a>.</p><p>It's not the first time Star Wars Outlaws has suffered from leaks, as <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ubisoft-battles-fresh-star-wars-outlaws-gameplay-leaks">a 13 minute string of gameplay hit the internet in July 2024</a>. Those looking forward to the game may want to take precautions while scrolling social media in the coming days.</p><p><em>Ryan Dinsdale is an IGN freelance reporter. He'll talk about The Witcher all day.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tails of Iron II: Whiskers of Winter delayed to February 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/tails-of-iron-ii-whiskers-of-winter-delayed-to-february-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/tails-of-iron-ii-whiskers-of-winter-delayed-to-february-2025.962061/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/tails-of-iron-ii-whiskers-of-winter-delayed-to-february-2025<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > United Label [23 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/ci-games/united-label">United Label</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Odd Bug Studio [8 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/odd-bug-studio">Odd Bug Studio</a> have delayed medieval <a title="Genres > Adventure [1,702 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a> <a title="Genres > RPG [16,546 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg">RPG</a> sequel <em><a title="Games > Tails of Iron II: Whiskers of Winter [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/tails-of-iron-ii-whiskers-of-winter">Tails of Iron II: Whiskers of Winter</a></em> from its <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2024/03/tails-of-iron-ii-whiskers-of-winter-announced-for-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-xbox-one-switch-and-pc">previously planned</a> 2024 release window to February 2025. It will be available for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [7,777 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [5,965 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,099 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox One [13,421 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch [15,832 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [21,054 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2473480/Tails_of_Iron_2_Whiskers_of_Winter/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a>. <span id="more-909565"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via United Label:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>A new and violent “tail” begins…</p><p>Set after the bloody conclusion of the original, <em>Whiskers of Winter</em> sees Arlo embark on a violent quest of ruthless revenge against the Dark Wings’ onslaught, while introducing new fearsome monster-hunting sidequests against gigantic beasts. The young rat can also imbue his weapons with a range of new elemental effects and abilities, helping him slaughter foes standing in his way. <a title="Companies > Enhance [31 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/enhance">Enhance</a>d settlement mechanics allows Arlo to rebuild the Rats’ northern garrison of Winter’s Edge, while its new protector explores new and distinct areas of the frontier home to a cast of critters, some to ally with… others to vanquish.</p><p>Odd Bug Studio has also confirmed that multi-award-winning voice actor, Doug Cockle (<em>The Witcher 3</em>, <em><a title="Games > Baldur's Gate III [24 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/baldurs-gate-iii">Baldur’s Gate III</a></em>, <em><a title="Games > Alan Wake II [13 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/alan-wake-ii">Alan Wake II</a></em>) returns to the world of <em><a title="Games > Tails of Iron [6 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/tails-of-iron">Tails of Iron</a></em> to provide his immediately distinct gruff and foreboding tones to Arlo’s bloody crusade of retribution.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>An Expanded Campaign of Violence and Revenge</strong> – <em>Whiskers of Winter</em>‘s “tail” of Arlo’s fight against the ferocious Dark Wing Bats is an intense experience, featuring a semi-open RPG world set across six varied biomes to explore, and new animal factions to discover.</li><li><strong>Challenging Combat</strong> – Building upon the series’ trademark hardcore combat, Tails of Iron 2 features enhanced weapons gameplay, including four elemental effects (fire, ice, electricity, and poison) to imbue Arlo’s arsenal with unique abilities to use against foes.</li><li><strong>New Monster Hunting Gameplay</strong> – To tip the balance against the new fanged army of Dark Wing Bats, Arlo can track down and overcome 15 gigantic and challenging beasts to harvest their cadavers for rare upgrade materials.</li><li><strong>Improved Base Building</strong> – Construct and upgrade the devastated settlement of Winter’s Edge to gain access to more powerful items from the smithy, tastier meals at the kitchen, a wider range of powerful traps from the shoppe, and more!</li><li><strong>New Day and Night System</strong> – Arlo will face different foes depending on the time of day, with more enemy types added as additional monsters are hunted down and vanquished.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Release Window Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Tails of Iron 2 | Release Date Gameplay Trailer | Wishlist - PC, Playstation, Xbox &amp; Nintendo Switch" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Sg5FBayiuWc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[7 Best Wireless Gaming Headsets In 2024]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/best-wireless-gaming-headset/1100-6525389/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/7-best-wireless-gaming-headsets-in-2024.962058/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/best-wireless-gaming-headset/1100-6525389/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6525389">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>We're big proponents of gaming headsets. They create a private, immersive listening experience that can make games more engrossing. Some games even encourage you to wear one to get the best audio experience. Gaming headsets are integral to the online multiplayer experience, not just for chatting with friends, but because it's often easier to pinpoint audio cues while wearing one. <span>While some may prefer the immediacy and simplicity of wired headsets, the freedom afforded by wireless headsets is unmatched. And thanks to low-latency 2.4GHz connections and modern Bluetooth technology, issues that plagued wireless headsets in the early gaming headset boom, like playback delay or lower audio quality, are virtually unheard of if you buy from a decent brand. Wireless headsets can sound as good and perform as reliably as their wired counterparts.</span></p><p>For anyone out there looking for a new gaming headset, we've put together this list of the best wireless gaming headsets you can buy in 2024. If you've read any of our other headset roundups, you won't be surprised to see the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/SteelSeries-Arctis-Wireless-Multi-Platform-Headset/dp/B0B15QM5LL?tag=gamespot-wirelessheadsets-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">SteelSeries Arctis Nova 7</a> in the top slot as the best wireless gaming headset in 2024. We simply haven't found any competitors that can match its blend of high quality audio, comfort, and price. That said, it's not our only recommendation. Some users will want something more affordable, while others may be able to splurge on higher-end models that offer even more features. So, we've made sure to include picks from a variety of price points, features, and styles--including a couple of wireless earbud options, led by <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Sony-Wireless-Cancelling-Earbuds-WF-G700N/dp/B0CJH6NV38?tag=gamespot-wirelessheadsets-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Sony's Inzone Buds</a>.</p><p>If you're looking for more recommendations, including wired models, be sure to check out our lists of the best headsets for <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/best-ps5-headset/1100-6482578/" data-ref-id="1100-6482578">PS5</a>, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/best-xbox-headset/1100-6485694/" data-ref-id="1100-6485694">Xbox</a>, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/best-pc-headset/1100-6486018/" data-ref-id="1100-6486018">PC</a>, and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/best-nintendo-switch-mic-headset/1100-6497491/" data-ref-id="1100-6497491">Nintendo Switch</a>.</p><div title="6525389 - Best Wireless gaming headsets" data-embed-type="buylink" data-ref-id="2534" data-template="4" data-size="buylink__listicle" data-title="6525389 - Best Wireless gaming headsets" data-collection="">                                                                     <div>             <h2>                    <a href="https://www.amazon.com/SteelSeries-Arctis-Multi-Platform-Gaming-Mobile-Headset/dp/B0B8QP5BGD?tag=gamespot-wirelessheadsets-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/SteelSeries-Arctis-Multi-Platform-Gaming-Mobile-Headset\/dp\/B0B8QP5BGD?tag=gamespot-wirelessheadsets-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/SteelSeries-Arctis-Multi-Platform-Gaming-Mobile-Headset/dp/B0B8QP5BGD?tag=gamespot-wirelessheadsets-20">Best Wireless Gaming Headset</a>       </h2>                                   <h3>                      <a href="https://www.amazon.com/SteelSeries-Arctis-Multi-Platform-Gaming-Mobile-Headset/dp/B0B8QP5BGD?tag=gamespot-wirelessheadsets-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/SteelSeries-Arctis-Multi-Platform-Gaming-Mobile-Headset\/dp\/B0B8QP5BGD?tag=gamespot-wirelessheadsets-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/SteelSeries-Arctis-Multi-Platform-Gaming-Mobile-Headset/dp/B0B8QP5BGD?tag=gamespot-wirelessheadsets-20">SteelSeries Arctis Nova 7</a>         </h3>                                                                                                                      <div><ul><li dir="ltr"><strong>Battery life</strong>: 38 hours</li><li dir="ltr"><strong>Connectivity: </strong>2.4GHz; Bluetooth</li><li dir="ltr"><strong>Spatial audio:</strong> Yes (Tempest 3D Audio, 360 Spatial Audio)</li><li dir="ltr"><strong>Noise-canceling: </strong>No</li><li dir="ltr"><strong>Mic style:</strong> Retractable noise-canceling boom mic</li><li dir="ltr"><strong>Supported Devices:</strong> PlayStation, Xbox, PC, Switch, Steam Deck, Mobile</li></ul><p dir="ltr">The Arctis Nova 7 (and its console-specific variants the 7X and 7P) take the top slots in our best headsets lists for each console and PC, so its ranking as our favorite wireless headset overall should be no surprise. Every model in SteelSeries Arctis Nova line is an excellent choice, but the Nova 7 offers the best mix of sound quality, features, and comfort without pushing into luxury-tier prices.</p><p dir="ltr">The Nova 7 shares its best feature with the rest of the Arctis Nova lineup: The ComfortMax system. This ingenious adjustable suspension design gently supports the lightweight--but durable--rubber-coated steel headband above your head rather than memory foam padding like other headsets. The headband design coupled with SteelSeries' breathable AirWeave ear cushions makes the Nova 7 comfortable for long gaming sessions. However, what makes the Nova 7 stand out among its Arctis peers is its sound quality, which is second only to the high-end--and much pricier--Nova Pro. It supports 3D spatial audio and works on a wide range of devices via Bluetooth or 2.4GHz wireless.</p><p dir="ltr">The Nova 7 comes in three versions: The standard Nova 7 works on PC, Switch, and mobile. The 7P supports all those devices, plus PS5. Meanwhile, the 7X works on Xbox and all the aforementioned devices, including PS5 with Tempest 3D Audio. The lone difference in features between the headsets is the wheel on the right earcup: The Nova 7 and 7P are equipped with a sidetone dial for microphone monitoring, while the 7X has a Chatmix dial for party chat. PC users get the most customization features thanks to the SteelSeries desktop app.</p><p dir="ltr">It's worth mentioning that SteelSeries sells accessories to help you <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fgo.skimresources.com%3Fid%3D225336X1707200%26xs%3D1%26xcust%3Dsubid_value%26url%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fsteelseries.com%2Fgaming-accessories%2Fheadset-accessories%3Fin_stock%3Don&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fbest-wireless-gaming-headset%2F1100-6525389%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">customize your Nova 7 headset</a>, should you ever want to switch up its look, The earcup faceplates and elastic headband are swappable. And although the AirWeave ear cushions are great, you can swap them out for leatherette cushions--the same ones found in the premium Nova Pro.</p></div>                      </div>                                                                     <div>             <h2>                    <a href="https://www.amazon.com/SteelSeries-Arctis-Wireless-Multi-System-Headset/dp/B09ZWKD9TF?tag=gamespot-wirelessheadsets-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/SteelSeries-Arctis-Wireless-Multi-System-Headset\/dp\/B09ZWKD9TF?tag=gamespot-wirelessheadsets-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/SteelSeries-Arctis-Wireless-Multi-System-Headset/dp/B09ZWKD9TF?tag=gamespot-wirelessheadsets-20">Best Premium Wireless Gaming Headset</a>       </h2>                                   <h3>                      <a href="https://www.amazon.com/SteelSeries-Arctis-Wireless-Multi-System-Headset/dp/B09ZWKD9TF?tag=gamespot-wirelessheadsets-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/SteelSeries-Arctis-Wireless-Multi-System-Headset\/dp\/B09ZWKD9TF?tag=gamespot-wirelessheadsets-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/SteelSeries-Arctis-Wireless-Multi-System-Headset/dp/B09ZWKD9TF?tag=gamespot-wirelessheadsets-20">SteelSeries Arctis Nova Pro</a>         </h3>                                                                                                                      <div><ul><li dir="ltr"><strong>Battery life: </strong>Up to 22 hours per swappable battery pack</li><li dir="ltr"><strong>Connectivity: </strong>2.4GHz; Bluetooth</li><li dir="ltr"><strong>Spatial audio: </strong>Yes (Tempest 3D Audio, Microsoft Spatial Audio)</li><li dir="ltr"><strong>Noise-canceling:</strong> Yes</li><li dir="ltr"><strong>Mic style:</strong> Retractable ClearCast Gen 2 mic</li><li dir="ltr"><strong>Supported Devices:</strong> PlayStation, Xbox, PC, Nintendo Switch, Steam Deck, Mobile</li></ul><p dir="ltr">While the Nova 7 is a great headset that should meet the needs of most players, the Nova Pro is the model to pick if you're looking for a high-end, luxury-class wireless model. The Nova Pro looks like the other headsets in SteelSeries' Arctis Nova line and shares the same super-comfortable headband design, but there are some major differences that justify its higher price tag. It has a better build quality with a more robust steel-reinforced design and leatherette earcups.</p><p dir="ltr">The Nova Pro connects to your PC or console wirelessly via the included base station that can be linked to two devices at once. The base station includes an OLED and a simple dial-based controls you can use to navigate the Nova Pro's many settings, including EQ, mic mix, active noise canceling, and more. Normally, features like EQ balancing would require a PC or mobile app, but since everything is handled within the base station, all of those features are available regardless of the device you're connected to. That said, PC players can use SteelSeries' Sonar software to access even more granular controls and pre-made audio profiles for specific games.</p><p dir="ltr">Another great feature of the Nova Pro is its dual-audio input support. This means you can connect to one device through the base station and another via Bluetooth and listen to both at the same time. This is great for anyone who likes to listen to podcasts or music on their mobile devices while they game on their consoles.</p><p dir="ltr">To top it all off, the Nova Pro comes with two rechargeable, hot-swappable batteries that you charge in the base station. That means you essentially have endless battery life as long as you make sure one pack is always charging. That said, the headset does allow for wired 3.5mm connections if you're in a pinch. It's also worth noting there's a <a href="https://www.amazon.com/SteelSeries-Arctis-Multi-System-Gaming-Headset/dp/B09ZWF9BCJ?tag=gamespot-wirelessheadsets-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">superb wired model</a> that will save you a decent amount of cash, but you'll be missing out on some of the wireless features. Additionally, the wired version connects to SteelSeries' GameDAC, which makes it better for those who play at their desk as opposed to on the couch.</p><p>Just like with the Nova 7 series, you'll need the Xbox version of the Nova Pro for support across all consoles and PC. The Nova 7 and 7P will work with all of your consoles and PC except for Xbox.</p></div>                      </div>                                                                     <div>             <h2>                    <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Stealth-Multiplatform-Wireless-Noise-Cancelling-Xbox-X/dp/B0BX77C1LD?tag=gamespot-wirelessheadsets-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/Stealth-Multiplatform-Wireless-Noise-Cancelling-Xbox-X\/dp\/B0BX77C1LD?tag=gamespot-wirelessheadsets-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/Stealth-Multiplatform-Wireless-Noise-Cancelling-Xbox-X/dp/B0BX77C1LD?tag=gamespot-wirelessheadsets-20">Best Premium Wireless Gaming Headset (Runner-up)</a>       </h2>                                   <h3>                      <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Stealth-Multiplatform-Wireless-Noise-Cancelling-Xbox-X/dp/B0BX77C1LD?tag=gamespot-wirelessheadsets-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/Stealth-Multiplatform-Wireless-Noise-Cancelling-Xbox-X\/dp\/B0BX77C1LD?tag=gamespot-wirelessheadsets-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/Stealth-Multiplatform-Wireless-Noise-Cancelling-Xbox-X/dp/B0BX77C1LD?tag=gamespot-wirelessheadsets-20">Turtle Beach Stealth Pro</a>         </h3>                                                                                                                      <div><ul><li dir="ltr"><strong>Battery life:</strong> 12+ hours (per swappable battery pack)</li><li dir="ltr"><strong>Connectivity: </strong>2.4GHz; Bluetooth</li><li dir="ltr"><strong>Spatial audio: </strong>Yes (Windows Sonic, PS5 3D Audio, Dolby Atmos, DTS Headphone: X)</li><li dir="ltr"><strong>Noise-canceling:</strong> Yes</li><li dir="ltr"><strong>Mic style:</strong> Removable noise-canceling boom, plus integrated mics</li><li dir="ltr"><strong>Supported Devices: </strong>Xbox, PlayStation, PC, Switch, Steam Deck, Mobile</li></ul><p dir="ltr">The Turtle Beach Stealth Pro is another high-end alternative to the SteelSeries Arctis Nova Pro. One of its coolest feature is an integrated DAC (digital audio converter), which can enhance the audio quality beyond what its already excellent 50mm Nanoclear drivers would normally achieve. The only drawback to this is that it adds more internal hardware, making for a bulkier design, especially the earcups.</p><p dir="ltr">The larger design is one of the Stealth Pro's few downsides, and the rest of the headset is excellent. It features multiple mics for clear audio pickup, supports various spatial audio formats, and connects to a wide range of devices via 2.4GHz wireless and Bluetooth 5.1. Its active noise-canceling tech is fantastic for a gaming headset--perhaps even slightly better than what's found in the Nova Pro.</p><p dir="ltr">Like the Nova Pro, the Turtle beach also uses dual, hot-swappable battery packs. Each pack holds up to 12 hours of battery life, and features quick charging, so you can effectively keep playing indefinitely as long as you keep the extra pack charged up so you can swap them out when needed.</p><p dir="ltr">The Xbox version of the Stealth Pro works wirelessly on all platforms, whereas the PlayStation edition is compatible with everything except Xbox.</p></div>                      </div>                                                                     <div>             <h2>                    <a href="https://www.amazon.com/SteelSeries-Arctis-Wireless-Multi-System-Gaming-Headset/dp/B0D2YC9GM9?tag=gamespot-wirelessheadsets-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/SteelSeries-Arctis-Wireless-Multi-System-Gaming-Headset\/dp\/B0D2YC9GM9?tag=gamespot-wirelessheadsets-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/SteelSeries-Arctis-Wireless-Multi-System-Gaming-Headset/dp/B0D2YC9GM9?tag=gamespot-wirelessheadsets-20">Best Budget Wireless Headset</a>       </h2>                                   <h3>                      <a href="https://www.amazon.com/SteelSeries-Arctis-Wireless-Multi-System-Gaming-Headset/dp/B0D2YC9GM9?tag=gamespot-wirelessheadsets-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/SteelSeries-Arctis-Wireless-Multi-System-Gaming-Headset\/dp\/B0D2YC9GM9?tag=gamespot-wirelessheadsets-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/SteelSeries-Arctis-Wireless-Multi-System-Gaming-Headset/dp/B0D2YC9GM9?tag=gamespot-wirelessheadsets-20">SteelSeries Arctis Nova 5</a>         </h3>                                                                                                                      <div><ul><li><strong>Battery life: </strong>60 hours</li><li dir="ltr"><strong>Connectivity: </strong>2.4GHz, Bluetooth</li><li dir="ltr"><strong>Spatial audio: </strong>Yes</li><li dir="ltr"><strong>Noise-canceling: </strong>No</li><li dir="ltr"><strong>Mic style: </strong>Retractable noise-canceling boom mic</li><li dir="ltr"><strong>Supported Devices:</strong> PlayStation, Xbox, Switch, PC, Steam Deck, Mobile</li></ul><p dir="ltr">Yep, we've got one more Arctis Nova model for this list. If the Nova 7 and Pro are out of your price range, the Nova 5 is the option for you. It's more affordable than its siblings but still sounds great. The Nova 5 uses the ingenious headband strap design we love about the other models. It's also a touch lighter than the rest, making it even more comfortable for long-term use.</p><p dir="ltr">The Nova 5 isn't just a lighter and more affordable version of the other Arctis models, however. It also has its own unique capabilities, namely an exclusive mobile companion app available for iOS and Android that includes over 100 EQ presets for popular games like Call of Duty, Destiny, and Minecraft. The headset lets you connect to your phone via Bluetooth while also connected to a console or PC over 2.4GHz so you can swap EQs in the app on the fly. Unfortunately, you cannot listen to both sources with simultaneous connection, but that's one of our few misgivings about the Nova 5.</p><p dir="ltr">Along with the app and multiple connection options, the Nova 5 also has a noise-canceling microphone that fully retracts into the left earcup, sports up to 60 hours of battery life, and has fast charging via the included USB-C cable.</p><p dir="ltr">The Arctis Nova 5 headset is available in three different models: the all-black Nova 5, the blue and black Nova 5P, and green and black Nova 5X. All three models support PC, PlayStation, Nintendo Switch, and mobile, but only the 5X supports Xbox consoles. They also support spatial audio on PS5, Xbox Series X|S, and PC.</p></div>                      </div>                                                                     <div>             <h2>                    <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Razer-BlackShark-Wireless-Xbox-Gaming-Headset/dp/B0CXGL6G6N?tag=gamespot-wirelessheadsets-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/Razer-BlackShark-Wireless-Xbox-Gaming-Headset\/dp\/B0CXGL6G6N?tag=gamespot-wirelessheadsets-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/Razer-BlackShark-Wireless-Xbox-Gaming-Headset/dp/B0CXGL6G6N?tag=gamespot-wirelessheadsets-20">Best Wireless Headset (Runner-Up)</a>       </h2>                                   <h3>                      <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Razer-BlackShark-Wireless-Xbox-Gaming-Headset/dp/B0CXGL6G6N?tag=gamespot-wirelessheadsets-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/Razer-BlackShark-Wireless-Xbox-Gaming-Headset\/dp\/B0CXGL6G6N?tag=gamespot-wirelessheadsets-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/Razer-BlackShark-Wireless-Xbox-Gaming-Headset/dp/B0CXGL6G6N?tag=gamespot-wirelessheadsets-20">Razer BlackShark V2 Pro</a>         </h3>                                                                                                                      <div><ul><li dir="ltr"><strong>Battery life: </strong>70 hours</li><li dir="ltr"><strong>Connectivity: </strong>2.4GHz; Bluetooth</li><li dir="ltr"><strong>Spatial audio: </strong>Yes</li><li dir="ltr"><strong>Noise-canceling: </strong>No</li><li dir="ltr"><strong>Mic style: </strong>Detachable wideband boom mic</li><li dir="ltr"><strong>Supported Devices: </strong>PlayStation, Xbox, Switch, PC, Mobile, Steam Deck</li></ul><p dir="ltr">While we might prefer the look and feel of the Nova headsets, the BlackShark V2 Pro puts up strong competition and easily ranks as one of the most comfortable headsets out there. Not only is it comfortable for long play sessions, it also sports a 70-hour battery life, which is the highest on this list.</p><p dir="ltr">Most importantly, the BlackShark V2 Pro sounds incredible, and thanks to the recent 2024 model refresh, the headset now supports 3D spatial audio on PC, PS5, and Xbox. It supports wireless connections via Bluetooth or Razer's low-latency 2.4GHz HyperSpeed tech. The only real downside is that it lacks true active noise-canceling tech, but otherwise, this is one of the best headsets out there, and a great alternative to SteelSeries' Arctis Nova line.</p><p dir="ltr">It's a theme on this list, but yet again, you'll need the Xbox edition for wireless support across all devices, while the PlayStation and PC editions support everything besides Xbox consoles.</p></div>                      </div>                                                                     <div>             <h2>                    <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Sony-Wireless-Cancelling-Earbuds-WF-G700N/dp/B0CJH6NV38?tag=gamespot-wirelessheadsets-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/Sony-Wireless-Cancelling-Earbuds-WF-G700N\/dp\/B0CJH6NV38?tag=gamespot-wirelessheadsets-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/Sony-Wireless-Cancelling-Earbuds-WF-G700N/dp/B0CJH6NV38?tag=gamespot-wirelessheadsets-20">Best Wireless Gaming Earbuds</a>       </h2>                                   <h3>                      <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Sony-Wireless-Cancelling-Earbuds-WF-G700N/dp/B0CJH6NV38?tag=gamespot-wirelessheadsets-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/Sony-Wireless-Cancelling-Earbuds-WF-G700N\/dp\/B0CJH6NV38?tag=gamespot-wirelessheadsets-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/Sony-Wireless-Cancelling-Earbuds-WF-G700N/dp/B0CJH6NV38?tag=gamespot-wirelessheadsets-20">Sony Inzone Buds</a>         </h3>                                                                                                                      <div><ul><li dir="ltr"><strong>Battery life: </strong>12 hours</li><li dir="ltr"><strong>Connectivity: </strong>2.4 GHz; Bluetooth LE</li><li dir="ltr"><strong>Spatial audio: </strong>Yes (Tempest 3D Audio, 360 Spatial Audio)</li><li dir="ltr"><strong>Noise-canceling: </strong>Yes</li><li dir="ltr"><strong>Mic style:</strong> Multiple integrated mics</li><li dir="ltr"><strong>Supported Devices: </strong>PS5, PC, Switch, Steam Deck, Android, iPhone 15 (older iPhones with adapter)</li></ul><p dir="ltr">So far, we've covered standard gaming headsets, but wireless earbuds are another great option for cordless audio while gaming, and the best choice is Sony's Inzone Buds. These true wireless earbuds were designed with gaming in mind with support for 360 Spatial Audio on PC and Tempest 3D Audio on PS5. The Inzone Buds also implement some of the audio giant's best tech to help them thrive beyond gaming, too.</p><p dir="ltr">From a noise-canceling standpoint, the Inzone Buds are the best option on this list. Sony is well-known as one of the best in the business for ANC, and that is on display with the manufacturer's first pair of gaming earbuds. The Inzone Buds also utilize the same drivers found in Sony's flagship WF-1000XM5 Bluetooth earbuds.</p><p dir="ltr">The Sony Inzone Buds last up to 12 hours on a single charge, which is pretty decent for a pair of wireless earbuds. Their design minimizes ear contact, which makes for a more comfortable wear.</p><p dir="ltr">Like other Inzone gaming gear--Sony also has over-ear headphones, including the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Sony-INZONE-Wireless-Canceling-Over-ear-Headphones/dp/B0B1TDHLPT?tag=gamespot-wirelessheadsets-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">high-end Inzone H9</a> that <em>just </em>missed the cut on this list--the Inzone Buds were designed with PC gaming in mind. With the Inzone Hub Windows app, you can customize your audio experience and save your settings to the earbuds.</p><p dir="ltr">Though best suited for PC gamers, these earbuds fully support the PS5's suite of audio features. It connects to both PC and PS5 via the included USB-C dongle. You can also use the Inzone Buds on other devices with audio-supported USB-C ports, including Nintendo Switch and Steam Deck.</p><p dir="ltr">On mobile, however, things are a bit different than usual for wireless earbuds. Android users with a newer phone equipped with Bluetooth LE can ditch the dongle if they so choose, but since Apple hasn't implemented Bluetooth LE in its devices, you'll need to use the dongle. For iPhone 15 users, this isn't a big issue--unless you have a bulky case, which may require a USB-C extender to attach the dongle. Those with iPhones with legacy Lightning ports will need a Lightning to USB-C adapter that supports audio output.</p><p dir="ltr">To clear up any confusion: Inzone Buds are manufactured by Sony Electronics and released before <a href="https://www.amazon.com/PULSE-Explore-Wireless-Earbuds-PlayStation-5/dp/B0CMDFSB89?tag=gamespot-wirelessheadsets-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">PlayStation's Pulse Explore earbuds</a>. Sony Inzone Buds cost the same and have noise-canceling tech as well as better audio and overall design. Pulse Explore earbuds do, however, support standard Bluetooth.</p></div>                      </div>                                                                     <div>             <h2>                    <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-Generation-Cancelling-Transparency-Personalized/dp/B0D1XD1ZV3?tag=gamespot-wirelessheadsets-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/Apple-Generation-Cancelling-Transparency-Personalized\/dp\/B0D1XD1ZV3?tag=gamespot-wirelessheadsets-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-Generation-Cancelling-Transparency-Personalized/dp/B0D1XD1ZV3?tag=gamespot-wirelessheadsets-20">Best Bluetooth Gaming Earbuds</a>       </h2>                                   <h3>                      <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-Generation-Cancelling-Transparency-Personalized/dp/B0D1XD1ZV3?tag=gamespot-wirelessheadsets-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/Apple-Generation-Cancelling-Transparency-Personalized\/dp\/B0D1XD1ZV3?tag=gamespot-wirelessheadsets-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-Generation-Cancelling-Transparency-Personalized/dp/B0D1XD1ZV3?tag=gamespot-wirelessheadsets-20">Apple AirPods and AirPods Pro</a>         </h3>                                                                                                                      <div><ul><li dir="ltr"><strong>Battery life: </strong>24-30 hours with charging case (varies by model)</li><li dir="ltr"><strong>Connectivity: </strong>Bluetooth</li><li dir="ltr"><strong>Spatial audio: </strong>No</li><li dir="ltr"><strong>Noise-canceling: </strong>AirPods Pro only</li><li dir="ltr"><strong>Mic style:</strong> Multiple hidden noise-cancelling mics</li><li dir="ltr"><strong>Supported Devices: </strong>PS5, Nintendo Switch, Steam Deck, Mobile, PC, Xbox with Bluetooth adapter.</li></ul><p dir="ltr">While not traditionally thought of as a gaming peripheral, Apple's AirPods are great for gaming simply because of their ubiquity. Chances are, if you own an iPhone, you have a pair of these lying around <em>or </em>you have thought about buying a pair. Since they can pair up with any Bluetooth-supported device, you can quickly sync them to PS5, Nintendo Switch, Steam Deck, or any other mobile device you're using for games. They work on PCs, too, provided you have integrated Bluetooth or a USB Bluetooth dongle. And for Xbox, you'll need to pick up an <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Skull-Co-AudioBox-Transmitter-Controllers/dp/B09NMP462M?tag=gamespot-wirelessheadsets-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Xbox-specific Bluetooth converter</a> like this one from Skull &amp; Co.</p><p dir="ltr">AirPods won't outclass a gaming headset or a pair of good headphones, but they sound pretty good, and their integrated mics mean they can work like a headset in a pinch. We recommend going with the AirPods Pro since they have better overall sound quality and active noise cancellation. For a cheaper but still solid option, the 3rd Gen standard AirPods are worth a look, but the 2nd Gen AirPods are still available and work great, too--especially for the price.</p></div>                      </div>   </div><div data-embed-type="pinbox" data-ref-id="4304">  <ul>                              <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/buy-two-get-one-free-nintendo-switch-games-and-preorders-my-best-buy-members/1100-6525928/">B2G1 Free All Nintendo Switch Games - Zelda: Echoes Of Wisdom, Mario &amp; Luigi, And More Preorders</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/dragon-age-the-veilguard-preorder-guide/1100-6525830/">Dragon Age: The Veilguard Collector's Edition Preorders Live Now</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/doom-anthology-preorders-quakecon-2024/1100-6525656/">Doom Anthology Preorders Are Live - Comes With 6 Games, Steelbook Case, And Replica BFG</a></li>                          <li>         <span>+ Show More More Gaming, Tech, and Entertainment Deals &amp; Preorders Links (5)</span>       </li>          <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/retrorealms-halloween-ash-vs-evil-dead-retro-game-preorder-guide/1100-6525752/">Halloween And Ash Vs. Evil Dead Retro Games Revealed - Collector's Bundle Preorders Live</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/amiibo-nintendo-switch-restocks-reprints-2024/2900-5671/">Rare Nintendo Amiibo Figures Restocked - Ness, Mr. Game &amp; Watch, ROB, Charizard, And More</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/final-fantasy-i-vi-pixel-remaster-collection-north-america-release/1100-6525641/">Final Fantasy Pixel Remaster Collection Anniversary Edition Preorders Live At Amazon</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/retro-pokemon-brick-sets-in-stock-at-target-pixel-art-mew-pikachu-charmander-and-more/1100-6525719/">Retro Pokemon Brick Sets In Stock At Target - Pixel Art Mew, Pikachu, Charmander, And More</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/best-nintendo-switch-deals-games-controllers-nintendo-consoles/1100-6525715/">Best Nintendo Switch Game Deals This Week - Zelda And Mario Games For Big Discounts</a></li>   </ul> </div>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/104300651635509044736?rel=author">Brendan Hesse</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Black Myth: Wukong Is Now One Of The Fastest-Selling Games Ever]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/black-myth-wukong-is-now-one-of-the-fastest-selling-games-ever/1100-6526082/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/black-myth-wukong-is-now-one-of-the-fastest-selling-games-ever.962052/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/black-myth-wukong-is-now-one-of-the-fastest-selling-games-ever/1100-6526082/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6526082">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/black-myth-wukong/" data-ref-id="5000-599537">Black Myth: Wukong</a> released on August 20 and had a massive debut, selling 10 million copies between launch and August 23, making it one of the fastest-selling video games of all time.</p><p>The game has surpassed the sales of Elden Ring and Hogwarts Legacy in the same timeframe, <a href="https://x.com/ZhugeEX/status/1826993907172782265" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">according to analyst Daniel Ahmad.</a> The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-legend-of-zelda-tears-of-the-kingdom-sold-over-10-million-copies-in-first-three-days/1100-6514264/" data-ref-id="1100-6514264">also sold 10 million copies in about three days.</a></p><p>"Thanks to all players worldwide for your support and love. Have a great gaming weekend!" the developers said. The game is currently available on PC and PS5, and is coming to Xbox Series X|S later, so the game's sales numbers will no doubt continue to climb over time.</p><div data-embed-type="tweet" data-src="https://x.com/BlackMythGame/status/1826985302592049599" data-has-image="true"><blockquote data-conversation="none" data-mce-disable-toolbar="true"><p dir="ltr">Black Myth: Wukong has sold 10 million copies across all platforms.<br>(Data as of 21:00 Beijing time, August 23, 2024)<br>Thanks to all players worldwide for your support and love.<br>Have a great gaming weekend!<a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/BlackMythWukong?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#BlackMythWukong</a> <a href="https://t.co/mp3mk9JxrX" rel="nofollow ">pic.twitter.com/mp3mk9JxrX</a></p>  — Black Myth: Wukong (@BlackMythGame) <a href="https://twitter.com/BlackMythGame/status/1826985302592049599?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 23, 2024</a></blockquote>              </div><p>Black Myth: Wukong is the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/black-myth-wukong-becomes-steams-no-2-most-popular-game-of-all-time-after-less-than-24-hours/1100-6525956/" data-ref-id="1100-6525956">No. 2 game of all time on Steam</a> based on concurrent players, <a href="https://steamdb.info/charts/?sort=peak" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">exceeding 2.4 million players at its peak</a>. The record-holder is PUBG (3.2 million).</p><p>According to a report, the early launch data for Black Myth: Wukong showed that more than 88% of sales on Steam came from China, where its developer, Game Science, is based. China is an absolutely massive market for games, with the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-number-of-chinese-gamers-surpasses-the-number-of-american-citizens/1100-6419166/" data-ref-id="1100-6419166">number of gamers in China exceeding the total US population.</a></p><p>Black Myth: Wukong has been controversial in some circles. Game Science's guidelines for content creators ask them to avoid discussing <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/black-myth-wukong-guidelines-ask-content-creators-not-to-discuss-feminist-propaganda-covid-and-more/1100-6525951/" data-ref-id="1100-6525951">"feminist propaganda" and COVID.</a> A <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/how-black-myth-wukong-developers-history-of-sexism-is-complicating-its-journey-to-the-west" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">report from IGN in 2023</a> documented the alleged sexist and misogynist commentary from the development team.</p><p>If you're just getting started with Black Myth, you can check out <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/black-myth-wukong-tips-beginners-guide/2900-5688/" data-ref-id="2900-5688">GameSpot's Black Myth: Wukong guide that runs through 20 things to know before you jump in.</a> We also have a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/black-myth-wukong-guides-hub/1100-6525898/" data-ref-id="1100-6525898">dedicated guides hub</a> where you can get all the key info you need. GameSpot's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/black-myth-wukong-review-monkey-business/1900-6418269/" data-ref-id="1900-6418269">Black Myth: Wukong review</a> scored the game an 8/10.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Avowed currently targeting baseline of 30fps on Xbox consoles to make way for "juicier" VFX]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/avowed-currently-targeting-baseline-of-30fps-on-xbox-consoles-to-make-way-for-juicier-vfx</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/avowed-currently-targeting-baseline-of-30fps-on-xbox-consoles-to-make-way-for-juicier-vfx.962049/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/avowed-currently-targeting-baseline-of-30fps-on-xbox-consoles-to-make-way-for-juicier-vfx<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>"You don't necessarily need that 60 frames."</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Avowed-header_rJMLGAl.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Obsidian</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>Obsidian is targeting 30fps on Xbox consoles for its fantasy RPG, Avowed.</p>
<p>In conversation with the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AxBL4jTHs5w">Iron Lords podcast</a>, Obsidian art director Matt Hansen said the studio is "core targeting 30 frames per second, bare minimum" for the upcoming release, adding since "it's a first-person, single-player game, you don't necessarily need that 60 frames".</p>
<p>Explaining further, Hansen said this will allow the Avowed team to "get a lot juicier with VFX and lighting and all this other stuff".</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Avowed Story Trailer - Xbox Games Showcase 2024" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/WxRHlKtvRp4?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Avowed Story Trailer - Xbox Games Showcase 2024</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/WxRHlKtvRp4?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/WxRHlKtvRp4?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Here's Avowed's story trailer, which debuted at the Xbox Games Showcase earlier this year. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WxRHlKtvRp4" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>"It's a trade-off we opted to make relatively early, and we're really happy with that," the art director continued. "The game's running pretty smooth for, you know, how visually dense it is, and that was always our goal."</p>
<p>He did note, however, the team is still hashing out some of the final performance bits and pieces. "It's one of the last things you do," Hansen said.</p>
<p>(As a general point, earlier this year the game's director confirmed <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/avowed-can-be-played-in-third-person-obsidian-confirms">Avowed could also be played in third-person</a>, however Hansen did not mention this during the podcast.)</p>
<p>Avowed is currently set to <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/obsidians-avowed-reportedly-delayed-from-2024-to-early-next-year">release across Xbox and PC on 18th February next year</a>.</p>
<p>Our Tom went hands on with the fantasy RPG earlier this week. "I'm more intrigued than I was, certainly, now I have a novice understanding of its playstyle and story," he wrote in <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/avowed-plays-like-a-funny-obsidian-role-player-where-you-buddy-up-with-the-voice-of-mass-effects-garrus">Eurogamer's Avowed preview</a>. "If you're after a fresh Obsidian hit... Avowed is one to keep an eye on."</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Black Myth: Wukong continues its dominance with new milestone]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/black-myth-wukong-continues-its-dominance-with-new-milestone</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/black-myth-wukong-continues-its-dominance-with-new-milestone.962046/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/black-myth-wukong-continues-its-dominance-with-new-milestone<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/black-myth-wukong-review-header.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Eurogamer / Game Science</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p><a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/black-myth-wukong">Black Myth: Wukong</a> has sold 10,000,000 copies across all platforms since it released on PC and PS5 just three days ago (20th August).</p>
<p>As we reported yesterday, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/black-myth-wukong-continues-to-attract-record-breaking-numbers-of-players">Black Myth: Wukong continues to attract record-breaking numbers of players</a>, establishing itself as the most-viewed game on Chinese livestreaming platforms on its first day of release.</p>
<p>This additional 10m milestone now cements Black Myth: Wukong as one of the most successful video game launches of all time.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Black Myth: Wukong - PC Tech Review - The High-End Graphics Experience" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/OItx2QHZt68?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Black Myth: Wukong - PC Tech Review - The High-End Graphics Experience</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/OItx2QHZt68?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/OItx2QHZt68?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Our experience on PC was mostly free from any technical problems, but our friends at Digital Foundry have the full low-down on Black Myth: Wukong's PC version.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OItx2QHZt68" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>Developer Game Science thanked players for their "support and love", and wished them "a great gaming weekend".</p> <div>
<div data-domain="twitter.com"><blockquote><div dir="ltr" lang="en"><p>Black Myth: Wukong has sold 10 million copies across all platforms.<br>(Data as of 21:00 Beijing time, August 23, 2024)</p><p>Thanks to all players worldwide for your support and love.<br>Have a great gaming weekend!<a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/BlackMythWukong?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#BlackMythWukong</a> <a href="https://t.co/mp3mk9JxrX">pic.twitter.com/mp3mk9JxrX</a></p></div>— Black Myth: Wukong (@BlackMythGame) <a href="https://twitter.com/BlackMythGame/status/1826985302592049599?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 23, 2024</a></blockquote></div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>According to Niko Partners analyst Daniel Ahmad, "this makes it one of the fastest-selling games of all time, surpassing <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/elden-ring-walkthrough-8042">Elden Ring</a> and <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/hogwarts-legacy">Hogwarts Legacy</a> in the same timeframe".</p> <div>

<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>This latest achievement joins Black Myth: Wukong newly-minted accolade of being <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/black-myth-wukong-already-steams-most-played-single-player-game-of-all-time">the most popular single-player game by peak concurrent users (PCCU) in Steam history</a>. In fact, the game is so successful in China, sales of Sony's system are currently twice that of the same period last year.</p>
<p>Black Myth: Wukong secured three out of five stars in <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/black-myth-wukong-review">Eurogamer's Black Myth: Wukong review</a>.</p>
<p>"Wukong's glitz and glamour can only paste over its cracks for so long, as behind all that razmataz is a hollowness it never quite shakes," we said. "Its unpleasant (and badly lip-synced) supporting cast also do little to make it feel more inviting as you go along, and by the end you'll wonder whether this journey was even worth making in the first place."</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Phil Spencer Speaks on Changes for Microsoft and Xbox Exclusives]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/phil-spencer-speaks-on-changes-for-microsoft-and-xbox-exclusives/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/phil-spencer-speaks-on-changes-for-microsoft-and-xbox-exclusives.962007/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/phil-spencer-speaks-on-changes-for-microsoft-and-xbox-exclusives/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Indiana Jones and The Great Circle was previously slated to be an Xbox exclusive. However, that idea has since been scrapped, and the game will also be coming to PlayStation 5. Xbox confirmed this on Tuesday at Gamescom Opening Night Live, where it was revealed that the game will be swinging onto PS5 in early 2025. However, those on PC and Xbox Series X|S will experience the adventure on 9 December, 2024. Today, Phil Spencer spoke about upcoming changes for Microsoft.</p>
<p>This announcement spells out a huge change happening at Xbox, as this is the latest first-party Xbox game to be announced on PS5. This year has already seen some significant announcements for Xbox, including DOOM: The Dark Ages, Sea of Thieves, and Pentiment, which will also be coming to alternative platforms, such as PlayStation 5 and Nintendo Switch.</p>
<p>During an<a href="https://x.com/Knoebelbroet/status/1826246589977153723?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1826246589977153723%7Ctwgr%5Efee93a41b2c89426528ec32cc9492cfb3045d0a1%7Ctwcon%5Es1_&amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.videogameschronicle.com%2Fnews%2Ftheres-going-to-be-more-change-phil-spencer-speaks-on-indy-ps5-news%2F" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> interview today</a> at Gamescom, Phil Spencer was asked to comment on Xbox's latest announcement and the stark change from their previous statement regarding Indiana Jones in February.</p>
<p>"Going to the PlayStation announcement, obviously, last spring we launched four games- two of them on the Switch, four on PlayStation - and we said we are going to learn." Looking at the statistics side, having the games launch on multiple platforms other than being an Xbox exclusive greatly benefits Microsoft.</p>
<p>"What I see when I look is that our franchise are getting stronger, our Xbox console players this year are as high as they've ever been, so I look at it and I say, our player numbers are going up for the console platform, our franchise are as strong as they've ever been... and we run a business," says Phil Spencer at Gamescom.</p>
<p>At the end of the interview, Phil Spencer spoke up about the changes in the gaming industry and the pressure it's facing as a whole. This year alone has seen thousands of layoffs across all types of companies in the games industry, with Microsoft included in that statistic. Spencer claimed that traditional ways of distributing games would continue to change.</p>
<p>"The last thing that I'll say is I think as an industry right now, there's a lot of pressure on the industry. It's been growing for a long time and now people are looking for ways to grow." Which, when looking at the statistics of all major gaming consoles and sales, that doesn't strictly feel true. <a href="https://wccftech.com/xbox-series-sales-down-52-year-on-year-in-europe-while-ps5-sales-are-up-143/">Xbox in particular</a> has sold the least amount of units, particularly in Europe. In addition, they've also been dealing with a <a href="https://wccftech.com/ftc-files-complaint-against-microsoft-following-game-pass-price-hike/">complaint filed by the FTC</a> regarding their Game Pass price hike, which doesn't exactly spell good news for Microsoft.</p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Avowed Will Run at 30FPS on Xbox Series X|S]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/avowed-30fps-xbox-target</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/avowed-will-run-at-30fps-on-xbox-series-x-s.962004/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/avowed-30fps-xbox-target<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Obsidian has revealed that upcoming action RPG&nbsp;<em>Avowed&nbsp;</em>will target a 30fps frame rate on Xbox Series X|S, so if you're a frame rate fanatic, you might want to pick this one up on PC.</p>
<p>This information comes via Obsidian's Matt Hansen, who's serving as art director on the RPG (<a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/avowed-runs-at-30fps-on-xbox-series-x-and-s-obsidian-confirms" rel="noopener" target="_blank">thanks, IGN</a>). In a recent podcast interview, Hansen told the hosts that Obsidian would target a "baseline" of 30fps, and he doesn't draw any kind of distinction between the Series S and the Series X on that front.</p>
<p>Hansen says that 60fps isn't necessary for a "first-person, single-player game", and that dropping the frame rate target allows him and his studio to "get a lot juicier with VFX and lighting and all this other stuff".</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/avowed-30fps-console-lizard.jpg?itok=-dmqQUaJ 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/avowed-30fps-console-lizard.jpg?itok=-G_4I7KK 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Avowed won't have a high frame rate, but it will have some fancy visual effects.</figcaption></figure><p>According to Hansen, the trade-off that sacrifices a higher frame rate for nicer graphics is one he and the team decided to make "relatively early", and Obsidian is "really happy" with the call it's made.</p>
<p>Despite the relatively low frame rate target, Hansen says that&nbsp;<em>Avowed&nbsp;</em>is "running pretty smooth" considering its visual density, and that the finer points of performance are still being worked out, as they're "one of the last things" developers address.</p>
<p>As IGN points out, there's a history of developers targeting 30fps on launch, only to introduce a 60fps performance mode later. Games like&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/redfall-will-launch-with-30-fps-quality-mode-only-on-xbox-series-xs"><em>Redfall</em></a>,&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/plague-tale-requiem-60-fps-mode-added-for-ps5-and-xbox-series-x-in-new-patch"><em>A Plague Tale: Requiem</em></a>, and&nbsp;<em>Starfield&nbsp;</em>all launched without 60fps modes, only to have performance-based options added in later.</p>
<p>There's every chance&nbsp;<em>Avowed&nbsp;</em>will go through the same process, but for now, if you're picking the game up on Xbox, you're going to have to cope with a lower frame rate.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/avowed-30fps-console-bear.jpg?itok=EUzQkdsy 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/avowed-30fps-console-bear.jpg?itok=SSijJxgb 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>This bear won't be moving at a silky-smooth 60fps, at least at launch.</figcaption></figure><p>If you're wondering what&nbsp;<em>Avowed&nbsp;</em>is, it's an upcoming fantasy RPG from&nbsp;<em><a href="https://techraptor.net/games/fallout-new-vegas">Fallout: New Vegas</a>&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em><a href="https://techraptor.net/games/outer-worlds">The Outer Worlds</a>&nbsp;</em>developer Obsidian.</p>
<p>Set in the same world as the developer's&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/games/pillars-of-eternity"><em>Pillars of Eternity</em></a>,&nbsp;<em>Avowed&nbsp;</em>is a first-person action RPG akin to something like&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/games/elder-scrolls-v-skyrim"><em>Skyrim</em></a>, albeit hopefully with less bugs and jank on launch. It's heading to <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2457220/Avowed/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor">PC</a> and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/avowed/9nhrdqvfpq34" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Xbox Series X|S</a> on February 18th.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Turn-based strategy game Bonaparte wants to redo the French Revolution, but this time with mechs]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/turn-based-strategy-game-bonaparte-wants-to-redo-the-french-revolution-but-this-time-with-mechs</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/turn-based-strategy-game-bonaparte-wants-to-redo-the-french-revolution-but-this-time-with-mechs.962001/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/turn-based-strategy-game-bonaparte-wants-to-redo-the-french-revolution-but-this-time-with-mechs<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/1_fu0qPpW.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Studio Imugi</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>Everything I know about the French Revolution has hitherto come from two literary works: Hilary Mantel's excellent doorstopper <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/A_Place_of_Greater_Safety">A Place Of Greater Safety</a>, and <a href="http://www.harkavagrant.com/index.php?id=321">Kate Beaton's webcomics</a>. Neither Mantel nor Beaton mention mechs, which are a core feature of Studio Imugi's new "ideology driven" turn-based strategy game <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/bonaparte-a-mechanized-revolution">Bonaparte: A Mechanized Revolution</a>. I, for one, feel like I've been grossly ill-informed. Kate, Hilary - I've been quoting you for years at parties and it seems like all this time, people have been silently judging me for my ignorance of the role giant clockwork soldiers played in the fall of the Bastille.</p><!--more-->
<p>Studio Imugi are made up of veterans of prolific Canadian indie publisher Kitfox Games and Sea Of Stars devs Sabotage. This is their debut game, and it very much looks like a Kitfox production - a nerdy, narrative-led alt-historical sandbox. Here's the announcement trailer...</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Bonaparte: A Mechanized Revolution announcement trailer  |  Strategy &amp; turn based tactical game" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9iaQevmLL7k?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Bonaparte: A Mechanized Revolution announcement trailer  |  Strategy &amp; turn based tactical game</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9iaQevmLL7k?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/9iaQevmLL7k?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9iaQevmLL7k" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>...and here's some background from <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2560340/Bonaparte__A_Mechanized_Revolution/">the Steam page</a>. The game begins in 1789 and casts you as either Céline or César Bonaparte - two seemingly fictional variations upon noted megalomaniac Napoleon. The game keeps some foothold in historical record, but lets you pick your own path through the events of the Revolution. There doesn't have to be a Revolution, for starters. Guillotines are so <em>gauche</em>, after all.  You might choose to defend Marie Antoinette and her ilk against the mob, sending your troops to force-feed the peasants rhetorical cake. Or you could side with the moderates and try to reform the system somehow. Hey, it worked out so well for us British!</p>
<p>Apparently, players will be able to "see policy play out in real time on the battlefield", but it's not really clear what that amounts to from the trailer. It looks like a game of two halves: hex and turn-based battles featuring the aforesaid mechanical Colossi, and tense branching dialogue with period luminaries such as Robespierre. There's also a papery world map with army figurines which looks very Paradox Interactive.</p>
<p>It's out in early 2025, and has <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2560340/Bonaparte__A_Mechanized_Revolution/">a Steam page</a>. I get a faint whiff of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/suzerain">Suzerain</a> from the presentation, which is promising, but I'm a little concerned about the mechs, who do feel like an afterthought, skulking furtively behind the colon in the title. Or worse, a publicity gimmick. This doesn't seem to be a steampunk world in other respects. Perhaps Mantel and Beaton were in the right of things, after all.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Black Myth: Wukong Secret Lets You Summon One Rock Boss To Beat The Crap Out Of Another Rock Boss]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/black-myth-wukong-buddha-eyeball-shigandang-stone-cliff-1851630113</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/black-myth-wukong-secret-lets-you-summon-one-rock-boss-to-beat-the-crap-out-of-another-rock-boss.961995/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/black-myth-wukong-buddha-eyeball-shigandang-stone-cliff-1851630113<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="36ded8229de21eecedf76a64772f2fd4" data-recommend-id="image://36ded8229de21eecedf76a64772f2fd4" data-format="gif" data-width="800" data-height="450" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A GIF shows two bosses fighting in Black Myth: Wukong." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A GIF shows two bosses fighting in Black Myth: Wukong." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Gif<!-- -->: <!-- -->Game Science / YouTube / JVGS / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="36ded8229de21eecedf76a64772f2fd4" data-recommend-id="image://36ded8229de21eecedf76a64772f2fd4" data-format="gif" data-width="800" data-height="450" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A GIF shows two bosses fighting in Black Myth: Wukong." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/black-myth-wukong-how-long-1851625314&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/black-myth-wukong-how-long-1851625314"><em>Black Myth: Wukong</em></a></span> isn’t a Souls-like but it is full of boss fights. Some of them are really tough and will beat you to a pulp, so it’s extra cool that there’s at least one secret encounter where you get to watch the bosses beat the crap out of each other instead. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="195386" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Cyberpunk 2077's Phantom Liberty DLC Probably Won’t Change V’s Fate" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="157" data-playlist="195386,196251,195805" data-current="195386"><div><p>Cyberpunk 2077's Phantom Liberty DLC Probably Won’t Change V’s Fate</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195386/195386_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195386/195386_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195386/195386_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195386/195386_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/20852.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>This hidden detail is found in chapter 2 (via <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.ign.com/articles/in-black-myth-wukong-you-can-summon-one-boss-to-beat-another-boss-while-basically-doing-nothing&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/in-black-myth-wukong-you-can-summon-one-boss-to-beat-another-boss-while-basically-doing-nothing" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>IGN</em></a></span>) and requires some finesse to pull off, but if done correctly gives you a brief breather from getting crushed. While many players have defeated the Stone Vanguard, a required boss near the Fright Cliff area, fewer have discovered Shigandang, an optional boss fight that first requires finding the six Buddha’s Eyeballs. But the real hidden secret is that you can actually get Shigandang and the Stone Vanguard to fight if you go about this area in the correct way. </p><p>There are a bunch of <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dVT-Nmb420U&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dVT-Nmb420U" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">YouTube videos</a></span> showing how to find all of the eyeballs and defeat Shigandang, but the key is to do that <em>before</em> fighting the Stone Vanguard. As one player points out, in order to do that, it seems like you need to arrive in the Fright Cliffs through the Squall Hideout rather than the bridge and cave most players are likely to enter from.  you need to have not come into this area via the bridge and cave. Otherwise, it sounds like the Stone Vanguard will be blocking the way to finish getting all of the Buddha’s Eyeballs. </p><p>Once Shigandang and the Stone Vanguard are fighting each other you can either watch from the sidelines or start waling one them yourself like an<em> Elden Ring</em> boss fight where the enemy is distracted by a summoned NPC. Shigandang will eventually destroy the Stone Vanguard for you, at which point you’ll need to finish the job. But it’s neat that the required boss fight is finished for you and a cool scene to watch given how one of <em>Black Myth: Wukong</em>’s strong points are its visual designs and cinematic animations. </p><p>You can read more about the game’s strengths and weaknesses in <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/black-myth-wukong-review-soulslike-pc-ps5-1851629456&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/black-myth-wukong-review-soulslike-pc-ps5-1851629456"><em>Kotaku</em>’s review</a></span>. <em>Black Myth: Wukong</em> <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/black-myth-wukong-steam-game-pass-cyberpunk-elden-ring-1851626674&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/black-myth-wukong-steam-game-pass-cyberpunk-elden-ring-1851626674">flew to the top of the Steam Charts</a></span> hours after coming out this week, beating out records set by other single-player games like <em>Elden Ring</em> and <em>Cyberpunk 2077</em>. That massive launch was propelled in part by players in China where the game is so popular PS5s <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://twitter.com/DanielOlimac/status/1826904414751436848?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1826904414751436848%7Ctwgr%5E20368b9d246fb50bd735817c604f99c3da047413%7Ctwcon%5Es1_&amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fnews.instant-gaming.com%2Fen%2Farticles%2F7985-black-myth-wukong-causes-ps5-stock-outs-in-china&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://twitter.com/DanielOlimac/status/1826904414751436848?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1826904414751436848%7Ctwgr%5E20368b9d246fb50bd735817c604f99c3da047413%7Ctwcon%5Es1_&amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fnews.instant-gaming.com%2Fen%2Farticles%2F7985-black-myth-wukong-causes-ps5-stock-outs-in-china" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">are apparently going out of stock</a></span>. </p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Black Myth: Wukong Has Already Sold 10 Million Copies]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/black-myth-wukong-sold-10-million-copies/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/black-myth-wukong-has-already-sold-10-million-copies.961992/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/black-myth-wukong-sold-10-million-copies/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-54314">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>Game Science has just confirmed that Black Myth: Wukong has sold 10 million copies since its release on August 20. That makes it one of the fastest-selling games in years, and the numbers outside of the overall sales figure represent the rampant popularity of this title. It has topped streaming charts and the player count is breaking records on some platforms.</p>



<p>With 10 million copies old and no sign of slowing down, this monumental title is shaping up to be the talk of the town for quite some time.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-10-million-and-counting">10 Million and Counting</h2>



<p>Black Myth: Wukong broke peak player count records on Steam, storming above Counter-Strike and securing the top spot as the most-played single-player game in the platform’s history. It hit almost half a million concurrent viewers on Twitch, but it likely dominated Chinese streaming platforms much more effectively – we just don’t have the numbers at present.</p>



<p>For a while, the game was shaken by a slight scandal that surfaced. It was revealed that Game Science issued ‘guidelines’ to influencers that prohibited them from streaming the game and talking about topics like feminism and COVID-19. This was enough to rile some in the gaming community, but it did nothing to slow down the overall impact of the game. </p>



<figure><div>
<blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>Black Myth: Wukong has sold 10 million copies across all platforms.<br>(Data as of 21:00 Beijing time, August 23, 2024)</p><p>Thanks to all players worldwide for your support and love.<br>Have a great gaming weekend!<a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/BlackMythWukong?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#BlackMythWukong</a> <a href="https://t.co/mp3mk9JxrX">pic.twitter.com/mp3mk9JxrX</a></p></div>— Black Myth: Wukong (@BlackMythGame) <a href="https://twitter.com/BlackMythGame/status/1826985302592049599?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 23, 2024</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>



<p>Some players have reported difficulties beating certain bosses, but that’s the nature of the game. It’s another entry in a long line of ‘soulslike’ games that many refer to as ‘Boss Simulators’. However, the enemies in Black Myth: Wukong are innovative and unique enough to stand apart from the competition, even if the general vibe isn’t too dissimilar from top titles like Elden Ring.</p>



<p>Have you played Black Myth: Wukong yet? Let us know in the comments.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news regarding <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-multiplayer-gameplay-leaked/">the Black Ops 6 multiplayer leaks</a> </p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>
    
	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-multiplayer-gameplay-leaked/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-multiplayer-gameplay-leaked/">Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 Multiplayer Gameplay Leaked</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Ahead of the game’s open beta on August 30 starting, multiplayer gameplay has been leaked online for Call of Duty: Black Ops 6.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/squirrel-with-a-gun-gets-october-2024-release-date-for-xbox-playstation/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/squirrel-with-a-gun-gets-october-2024-release-date-for-xbox-playstation/">Squirrel With a Gun Gets October 2024 Release Date For Xbox &amp; PlayStation</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>A new console release date trailer confirms that Squirrel with a Gun is coming to PlayStation and Xbox in mid-October 2024.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/playstation-teases-death-stranding-2-event-more-for-tokyo-game-show-2024/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/playstation-teases-death-stranding-2-event-more-for-tokyo-game-show-2024/">PlayStation Teases Death Stranding 2 Event &amp; More For Tokyo Game Show 2024</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>PlayStation has confirmed some of its plans for Tokyo Game Show 2024, including a Death Stranding 2 stage event and more.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/avowed-doesnt-need-60-fps-mode-says-obsidian/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/avowed-doesnt-need-60-fps-mode-says-obsidian/">Avowed ‘Doesn’t Need 60 FPS Mode’ Says Obsidian</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Obsidian has confirmed that Avowed does not need 60 fps on Xbox Series X/S consoles. Here are more details. </p>
                    </div>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[World of Warcraft boss: "I think we should have listened more to the player base"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/world-of-warcraft-boss-i-think-we-should-have-listened-more-to-the-player-base</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/world-of-warcraft-boss-i-think-we-should-have-listened-more-to-the-player-base.961989/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/world-of-warcraft-boss-i-think-we-should-have-listened-more-to-the-player-base<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>Team says it still looks to the mistakes of Shadowlands "as guidance for where we're going".</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/WoW_The_War_Within_Anduin_FCs0TH2.jpg?width=1200&amp;height=1200&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Eurogamer / Blizzard</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p><a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/world-of-warcraft">World of Warcraft</a> boss Holly Longdale says Blizzard has learned from its controversial Shadowlands launch, acknowledging the expansion "wasn't enough" and "wasn't the right stuff", admitting the team should have "listened more" to its community.</p>
<p>Talking to <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/world-of-warcraft/warcraft-vp-on-what-blizzard-should-have-done-differently-over-the-game-s-20-years-we-should-have-listened-more/">PC Gamer</a>, Longdale reflected back over World of Warcraft's storied 20 years, partly as a player, and "as a very humble and lucky leader on this team".</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Official Trailer: Powers Within | World of Warcraft | The War Within" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Jw47XzJw-2Q?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Official Trailer: Powers Within | World of Warcraft | The War Within</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Jw47XzJw-2Q?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/Jw47XzJw-2Q?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Official Trailer: Powers Within | World of Warcraft | The War Within.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Jw47XzJw-2Q" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>"I think we should have listened more to the player base," Longdale said. "I think quite often in earlier times, game design wasn't even a job, really," she said. "It was a bunch of super incredibly passionate geeks figuring out how to make tabletop gaming into 3D. So, I think there was a lot of going on their best instincts."</p>
<p>Acknowledging the changing shape of social media and community management, Longdale said the development team at the time "wasn't really reflective", so the team has learned to "listen more and observe".</p>
<p>"So listening to the community, and being able to verify the discussions - now we have the technology and the data to be able to map those two, "Longdale explained. "Like, whoa, did we really miss something? And then checking to verify that, oh yeah, this is an issue."</p>
<p>Talking specifically about class balancing, she said: "Like, oh, my class is a disaster. And you get a wealth of commentary and support for those ideas, and then you make a change and then it breaks everything else. Balance is a big example.</p>
<p>"It took longer to make [Shadowlands] content than we would've liked. We remained committed to get it out there, but it wasn't enough, and it wasn't the right stuff. And we looked at that very deeply and we still do to use it as guidance for where we're going."</p>
<p>World of Warcraft's new expansion, The War Within, is now available in early access. For everyone else, the long-running MMORPG will launch soon, on 26th August.</p>
<p>Did you know that the entirety of Blizzard's 500-strong World of Warcraft development team <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/blizzards-world-of-warcraft-team-forms-500-stong-union">have unionised</a>, making it the largest group within Microsoft's gaming teams to do so thus far?</p>
<p>Around 1750 employees within Microsoft's gaming teams are now unionised, including those working on Blizzard's veteran MMO.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Steam update lets patrons know if a game review has been played "primarily" on Steam Deck]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/steam-update-lets-patrons-know-if-a-game-review-has-been-played-primarily-on-steam-deck</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/steam-update-lets-patrons-know-if-a-game-review-has-been-played-primarily-on-steam-deck.961986/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/steam-update-lets-patrons-know-if-a-game-review-has-been-played-primarily-on-steam-deck<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>



            <p>There is a new update on Steam which informs other players if a review left on a game's page was primarily played on Valve's handheld Steam Deck.</p>
<p>The news was shared via the Steam Deck's social media team on <a href="https://x.com/OnDeck/status/1826673475119186082/photo/1">X</a>, with the straight to the point wording: "We've just shipped a new feature on Steam that shows when a customer review was written by someone who played primarily on Steam Deck."</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Steam Deck Launch Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/pHHgA4tZtkE?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Steam Deck Launch Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/pHHgA4tZtkE?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/pHHgA4tZtkE?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Here's the Steam Deck's launch trailer. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pHHgA4tZtkE" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>Valve asks that patrons look out for the Deck icon, to "see how these players reviewed the game". It shared an example of how this icon looks on a review, with a little Deck outline displayed in the upper right corner of the screen.</p>
<p>Response to this update has been positive, with many other X users sharing their appreciation. Several messages such as "fantastic idea" and "that'll be extremely helpful" have popped up in the replies since Valve made the announcement. </p>
<p>What do you think of this new Steam update?</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Steam-Deck-icon-on-the-side-of-a-Steam-review.png?width=1200&amp;height=1200&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption>You can see the little Steam Deck icon in the upper right hand corner of this review on Valve's platform.  | <span>Image credit: <cite>Valve</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>As for the Steam Deck itself, back in May, Digital Foundry said <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/digitalfoundry-2024-steam-deck-rt-tested-vs-rog-ally">Valve's portable PC had "quietly become a reasonably capable ray tracing handheld"</a>.</p>
<p>Elsewhere in Valve-related news, its <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/valve-hero-shooter-deadlock-still-hasnt-been-announced-but-had-16k-steam-concurrent-players-this-weekend">hero shooter known as Deadlock</a> and which the company still hasn't actually announced has welcomed quite the number of players over the last few weeks.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PlayStation MENA Hero Project Announced for Middle East and North Africa Devs]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/playstation-mena-hero-project</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/playstation-mena-hero-project-announced-for-middle-east-and-north-africa-devs.961962/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/playstation-mena-hero-project<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Sony has announced the PlayStation MENA Hero Project, a new incubator program aimed at finding and supporting developers based in the Middle East and North Africa.</p>
<p>Previous Hero Projects have focused on areas like <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/sonys-china-hero-project-shows-off-five-upcoming-chinese-indie-games">China</a> and <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/playstation-india-hero-project">India</a>, but this one focuses on eleven specific countries within the MENA regions, aiming to support companies through "mentorship, training, and project-based investment".</p>
<p>According to Sony, the MENA Hero Project is part of "identifying new and diverse developers worldwide" and showcasing "the most incredible talents" the region has to offer. Looks like we might be about to see a whole lot more games from Middle Eastern and North African developers.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/convallaria-sony-china-hero-project.jpg?itok=bEhtBEai 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/convallaria-sony-china-hero-project.jpg?itok=4m18Dxdp 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Sony's previous Hero Project initiatives have been focused around China and India.</figcaption></figure><p>Here's a full list of the eleven countries that will fall under the purview of the MENA Hero Project.</p>
<ul><li>Saudi Arabia</li>
<li>United Arab Emirates</li>
<li>Bahrain</li>
<li>Iraq</li>
<li>Kuwait</li>
<li>Oman</li>
<li>Qatar</li>
<li>Jordan</li>
<li>Egypt</li>
<li>Morocco</li>
<li>Tunisia</li>
</ul><p>If you happen to belong to a studio that's from one of these countries and you want to apply for the PlayStation MENA Hero Project, then you can apparently <a href="https://www.playstation.com/global/mena-hero-project/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">do so via this link</a>.</p>
<p>I should point out that the link doesn't appear to work for me, but that might be because I'm based in the UK, and the link only works for those who are operating from one of the above countries.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/ayo-a-rain-tale-sony-mena-hero-project.jpg?itok=ULFZ80Qq 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/ayo-a-rain-tale-sony-mena-hero-project.jpg?itok=MtwbLX4m 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>We might be about to see a whole lot more games from the MENA region.</figcaption></figure><p>Presumably, if you are, you'll find an FAQ that explains the MENA Hero Project further, as well as an application form you can use to put your studio forward for funding and mentorship via the new program.</p>
<p>Of course, it's also possible that the link is just broken right now and that the page will go live at some point in the near future. If that's the case, you might want to bookmark it so that you can check whether it's working later down the line. Stay tuned for more on this and all other things PlayStation.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Your Lord Of The Rings: The Rings Of Power Refresher Ahead Of Season 2]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/the-lord-of-the-rings-rings-of-power-season-1-recap-1851630074</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/your-lord-of-the-rings-the-rings-of-power-refresher-ahead-of-season-2.961953/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/the-lord-of-the-rings-rings-of-power-season-1-recap-1851630074<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><figure id="" data-id="7301df36590a296eff245811a9085d60" data-recommend-id="image://7301df36590a296eff245811a9085d60" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Galadriel wields a bow. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Galadriel wields a bow. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Amazon Studios</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="7301df36590a296eff245811a9085d60" data-recommend-id="image://7301df36590a296eff245811a9085d60" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Galadriel wields a bow. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>Amazon’s massive fantasy series, <em>The Lord of the Rings: The Rings of Power</em> is set to kick off its second season on the streaming service on August 29. The prequel takes place thousands of years before the events of the J. R. R. Tolkien novels <em>The Hobbit</em> and <em>The Lord of the Rings</em>, though there are some familiar faces, including Sauron, Galadriel, Elrond, and even an unnamed character who is most likely (definitely) Gandalf.<br></p><p>The series follows the stories of several different important characters as they deal with a rapidly changing Middle-earth<em>. A lot</em> of stuff went down in the first season, from fiery volcanic explosions to the reveal of a big bad lurking in the body of a big hottie. But since it’s been two full years since <em>The Rings of Power</em> season one aired, you probably need a refresher on what went down in Middle-earth before you settle in to watch the first episode of season two in a few days. Don’t worry, we’ve got you covered.<br></p><p>Click through for a thorough <em>Lord of the Rings: The Rings of Power </em>season one recap. Spoilers, obviously.</p><figure id="" data-id="afpvuwnfoibrncd6upmy" data-recommend-id="image://afpvuwnfoibrncd6upmy" data-format="png" data-width="800" data-height="88" data-lightbox="false" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><span data-id="afpvuwnfoibrncd6upmy" data-recommend-id="image://afpvuwnfoibrncd6upmy" data-format="png" data-width="800" data-height="88" data-lightbox="false" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure></div></div><div><figure id="" data-id="09d5b6120bf59401e53815a31c8def7e" data-recommend-id="image://09d5b6120bf59401e53815a31c8def7e" data-format="jpg" data-width="4000" data-height="2594" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Durin walks past two guards." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Durin walks past two guards." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Amazon Studios</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="09d5b6120bf59401e53815a31c8def7e" data-recommend-id="image://09d5b6120bf59401e53815a31c8def7e" data-format="jpg" data-width="4000" data-height="2594" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Durin walks past two guards." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>In season one, Elrond (Robert Aramayo) returns to visit his old friend Prince Durin IV (Owain Arthur) in Khazad-dum, requesting that the dwarf help him mine mithril, which the dwarves have discovered in their kingdom. The powerful material is needed by the elves, but the dwarves stopped mining it because of how dangerous it was. It took nearly an entire season of convincing, but Elrond managed to get Durin to help him get some mithril—however, just as they’re about to start mining again, Durin’s father (the king) stops them. He strips Durin of his title and banishes Elrond from Khazad-dum.<br></p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="85605b9c9aca17e486c5fcac6c1a0d2e" data-recommend-id="image://85605b9c9aca17e486c5fcac6c1a0d2e" data-format="jpg" data-width="5000" data-height="3332" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Nori looks towards the sky." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Nori looks towards the sky." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Amazon Studios</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="85605b9c9aca17e486c5fcac6c1a0d2e" data-recommend-id="image://85605b9c9aca17e486c5fcac6c1a0d2e" data-format="jpg" data-width="5000" data-height="3332" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Nori looks towards the sky." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Early on in season one, a Stranger (David Weyman) falls from the sky and lands in the land of the Harfoots, who are one of three breeds of Hobbits. Small in stature, brown-haired, and big-footed, the Harfoots are a migratory species, avoiding conflict and relying on nature to keep themselves safe and well-fed. One Harfoot, named Nori (Markella Kavenagh), discovers the Stranger after he crash-lands nearby, and the two forge a bond as he travels with the Harfoots. The Stranger is a wizard (everyone knows it’s Gandalf even though the show hasn’t said it outright yet) who appears to have lost his memory and is struggling to regain the use of his powers. When he leaves to go on an adventure to discover his identity, Nori agrees to go with him, leaving her family behind.<br></p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="52b0e734149754f86a6c42765a0a7c16" data-recommend-id="image://52b0e734149754f86a6c42765a0a7c16" data-format="jpg" data-width="3000" data-height="1688" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="The three rings of power." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="The three rings of power." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Amazon Studios</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="52b0e734149754f86a6c42765a0a7c16" data-recommend-id="image://52b0e734149754f86a6c42765a0a7c16" data-format="jpg" data-width="3000" data-height="1688" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="The three rings of power." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>The rings of power are magical artifacts bestowed upon men, elves, and dwarves that highlight and enhance the user’s innate abilities. However, these rings can easily be corrupted by the wearer—hence the One Ring that’s at the center of <em>The Lord of the Rings</em> storyline, the one that Frodo must destroy in order to restore peace in Middle-earth. During <em>The Rings of Power</em> season one, we learn that the Elven smith Celebrimbor (Charles Edwards), is forging these rings with a small amount of mithril. He gives these first three rings to the elves: Galadriel (Morfydd Clark), Cirdan (Ben Daniels), and King Gil-galad (Benjamin Walker).<br></p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="dbdcd7fc2817e9446f56c21c781faeec" data-recommend-id="image://dbdcd7fc2817e9446f56c21c781faeec" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Galadriel and Theo walk through an ash-covered forest. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Galadriel and Theo walk through an ash-covered forest. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Amazon Studios</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="dbdcd7fc2817e9446f56c21c781faeec" data-recommend-id="image://dbdcd7fc2817e9446f56c21c781faeec" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Galadriel and Theo walk through an ash-covered forest. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Towards the end of <em>The Rings of Power </em>season one, we learn exactly why the orcs were doing all that construction: to trigger a massive volcanic eruption in the Southlands, covering the beautiful, verdant land in flame and thus creating Mordor, the realm of Sauron. <br></p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="07271921c282f8de646e62f193ff4b34" data-recommend-id="image://07271921c282f8de646e62f193ff4b34" data-format="jpg" data-width="5000" data-height="3332" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Bronwyn, Arondir, and Theo stand together." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Bronwyn, Arondir, and Theo stand together." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Amazon Studios</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="07271921c282f8de646e62f193ff4b34" data-recommend-id="image://07271921c282f8de646e62f193ff4b34" data-format="jpg" data-width="5000" data-height="3332" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Bronwyn, Arondir, and Theo stand together." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>We first meet the elf Arondir (Ismael Cruz Córdova) on patrol in the Southlands, where he’s remained for nearly 80 years after being placed there to ensure the humans did not turn to evil again (pesky humans). Much to the chagrin of the humans, who distrust the elves, Arondir has fallen in love with Bronwyn (Nazanin Boniadi), and the feeling is mutual. Throughout the season, their bond grows stronger, even after he’s captured by Orcs and forced to work on their dam. Arondir and Bronwyn help defend the Southlands against the Orcs, and are saved at the last minute by Galadriel and the Númenóreans. Bronwyn plans to lead her people, who are now without a home, to the port of Gondor. <br></p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="d7a6ef68bb6d0c29ebb3ede58fd33664" data-recommend-id="image://d7a6ef68bb6d0c29ebb3ede58fd33664" data-format="jpg" data-width="3000" data-height="2000" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Adar walks behind Orcs." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Adar walks behind Orcs." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Amazon Studios</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="d7a6ef68bb6d0c29ebb3ede58fd33664" data-recommend-id="image://d7a6ef68bb6d0c29ebb3ede58fd33664" data-format="jpg" data-width="3000" data-height="2000" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Adar walks behind Orcs." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Adar (played by Joseph Mawle in season one, and Sam Hazeldine in season two), is a fallen elf who became leader of the Orcs. He oversees their work to create Mordor, torturing the people of the Southlands, but he soon becomes disillusioned by Sauron’s plans and his treatment of the Orcs and decides to seek a magical sword hilt that can bestow great power upon him. That sword hilt, first found and stolen by Bronwyn’s son, Theo, is believed to have been forged by Morgoth (the big bad before Sauron) and will lengthen into a full sword if imbued with someone’s blood. In the final episode of season one, Adar is captured after the Númenóreans and Galadriel come to the rescue of the people of the Southlands, and it’s believed he leaves the sword hilt behind. But he escapes, and we discover that he switched out the sword hilt for a decoy—now he has the sword and Mordor.<br></p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="fe34c8a6990fc02b561d6450308425c1" data-recommend-id="image://fe34c8a6990fc02b561d6450308425c1" data-format="jpg" data-width="3000" data-height="1999" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Miriel stands at court." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Miriel stands at court." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Amazon Studios</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="fe34c8a6990fc02b561d6450308425c1" data-recommend-id="image://fe34c8a6990fc02b561d6450308425c1" data-format="jpg" data-width="3000" data-height="1999" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Miriel stands at court." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>A huge focus of <em>The Rings of Power</em> season one is the tension between races, especially men and elves. In Númenor, Galadriel is treated like a prisoner until she convinces Queen Regent Miriel (Cynthia Addai-Robinson) to team up and head to the mainland to retake the Southlands. But some Númenórean senators are unhappy with this decision, and by the end of season one, it’s clear that this is going to become a problem for Miriel going forward. After the horrific battle at Mordor, Elendil (Lloyd Owen) thinks his son Isildur (Maxim Baldry), the very same Isildur who eventually is corrupted by a ring of power, is dead, and Miriel is blind. The future of Númenor and the relationship between men and elves hangs in the balance.<br></p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="db58b9c00f6226ac251037ea03f7f34b" data-recommend-id="image://db58b9c00f6226ac251037ea03f7f34b" data-format="jpg" data-width="2999" data-height="2001" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Halbrand captured." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Halbrand captured." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Amazon Studios</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="db58b9c00f6226ac251037ea03f7f34b" data-recommend-id="image://db58b9c00f6226ac251037ea03f7f34b" data-format="jpg" data-width="2999" data-height="2001" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Halbrand captured." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>For much of season one, Galadriel is hanging out with a hottie known as Halbrand (Charlie Vickers) in Númenor, the great island civilization of man. Halbrand was once, supposedly, the king of the Southlands before he was driven out of his home by Orcs and forced to set sail on the Sundering Seas—this is where he finds Galadriel, and the two are eventually rescued by captain Elendil of Númenor. After spending some time there (Galadriel was not allowed to leave at first), she convinces Halbrand to join her in the fight to reclaim the Southlands, and the two defeat Adar, the leader of the Orcs. However, Halbrand is wounded when the massive volcano erupts, and must be healed with elven magic in the city of Ost-in-Edhil—it’s there that he meets Celebrimbor and helps convince him to create the rings of power with mithril.<br></p><p>But while Halbrand is helping Celebrimbor, Galadriel discovers that the last king of the Southlands died ages ago with no heir. It’s then that Halbrand reveals himself to be Sauron in disguise and, after a brief fight with Galadriel, flees to Mordor—his new home. <br></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 Multiplayer Gameplay Leaked]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-multiplayer-gameplay-leaked/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-multiplayer-gameplay-leaked.961950/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-multiplayer-gameplay-leaked/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-54307">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>Ahead of the early access beta that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-6-beta-dates-revealed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">begins on August 30</a>, new Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 multiplayer gameplay has been leaked online. </p>



<p>The <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=itZM2m74VHE" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">nearly eight-minute</a> gameplay, which you can check out below if you’d like before it likely gets removed, gives a look at Team Deathmatch on Protocol. The weapon of choice for the match? The AK 74.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Black Ops 6 Leaked Gameplay - Protocol Team Deathmatch - AK 74" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/itZM2m74VHE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>Since it’s reveal earlier this summer, leaks for Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 have <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-6-leaks-running-wild/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">been happening quite regularly</a>. Over the last few weeks alone, the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-6-achievements-how-to-unlock-them/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">game’s achievements</a> have leaked along with <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-6-mutliplayer-maps-leaked/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">all of the multiplayer maps</a> and more. It’s the first Call of Duty to launch since Microsoft officially acquired Activision Blizzard. It’s also become the most leaked Call of Duty game ever.</p>







<p>Black Ops 6 launches October 25 for PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X|S, PC, Xbox One, and PlayStation 4. It’ll also be the first Call of Duty to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-confirms-call-of-duty-black-ops-6-for-game-pass-on-day-one/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">launch day one on Xbox Game Pass</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>What do you think of the multiplayer gameplay for Black Ops 6? Does it get you more or less excited for the release of the game in October? For more Insider Gaming, read why Obsidian <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/avowed-doesnt-need-60-fps-mode-says-obsidian/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">doesn’t think Avowed needs 60 frames</a> per second.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>
    
	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/squirrel-with-a-gun-gets-october-2024-release-date-for-xbox-playstation/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/squirrel-with-a-gun-gets-october-2024-release-date-for-xbox-playstation/">Squirrel With a Gun Gets October 2024 Release Date For Xbox &amp; PlayStation</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>A new console release date trailer confirms that Squirrel with a Gun is coming to PlayStation and Xbox in mid-October 2024.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/playstation-teases-death-stranding-2-event-more-for-tokyo-game-show-2024/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/playstation-teases-death-stranding-2-event-more-for-tokyo-game-show-2024/">PlayStation Teases Death Stranding 2 Event &amp; More For Tokyo Game Show 2024</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>PlayStation has confirmed some of its plans for Tokyo Game Show 2024, including a Death Stranding 2 stage event and more.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/avowed-doesnt-need-60-fps-mode-says-obsidian/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/avowed-doesnt-need-60-fps-mode-says-obsidian/">Avowed ‘Doesn’t Need 60 FPS Mode’ Says Obsidian</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Obsidian has confirmed that Avowed does not need 60 fps on Xbox Series X/S consoles. Here are more details. </p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-first-descendant-season-1-updates-adjusted-for-new-2-part-structure/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-first-descendant-season-1-updates-adjusted-for-new-2-part-structure/">The First Descendant Season 1 Updates Adjusted For New 2-Part Structure</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>The First Descendant producer Lee Beom-jun has announced a new 2-part structure for Season 1, merging its fall updates.</p>
                    </div>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Squirrel With a Gun Gets October 2024 Release Date For Xbox & PlayStation]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/squirrel-with-a-gun-gets-october-2024-release-date-for-xbox-playstation/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/squirrel-with-a-gun-gets-october-2024-release-date-for-xbox-playstation.961947/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/squirrel-with-a-gun-gets-october-2024-release-date-for-xbox-playstation/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>In a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UeAQ9zpZg8I" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">new trailer</a> released today, Maximum Entertainment confirmed that Squirrel with a Gun will launch on Xbox Series X|S and PlayStation 5 on October 15, 2024.</p>



<p>Until now, those platforms only had a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/squirrel-with-a-gun-release-date-window-announced/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">release window for fall 2024</a>, and today’s announcement coincides with day three of Gamescom. The new console release trailer showcases vehicle and drone gameplay, a wide range of shooting, platforming, and more. </p>



<p>Ahead of the Xbox and PlayStation releases, Maximum Entertainment <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/squirrel-with-a-gun-release-date/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">previously announced</a> that Squirrel with a Gun will launch on PC via Steam and the Epic Games Store on August 19, 2024.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Squirrel with a Gun - Console Release Date Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/UeAQ9zpZg8I?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>







<p>Just this week, Insider Gaming also revealed reactions after a hands-on experience with the game, deeming Squirrel with a Gun <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/squirrel-with-a-gun-hands-on-another-indie-must-buy/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">another Indie Must Buy</a>. There is currently no plan to release the game on last-gen consoles. </p>



<p>Today’s trailer also shows off the central objective of the sandbox game, which is to collect golden acorns by any means necessary. </p>



<p>Earlier this month, the devs shared a post-release roadmap on the official <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2067050/Squirrel_with_a_Gun/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Steam page</a>, including content coming through August 2025. This September, the game will add a Photo Mode. A new Super Platforming Challenge level and a new rival are both coming in December 2024.</p>



<p>Some fans compare Squirrel with a Gun to hit sandbox action games like Goat Simulator 3 from Coffee Stain, who <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/goat-simulator-remastered-revealed-at-gamescom-2024/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">announced a Remastered version</a> during Gamescom.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more of the latest Insider Gaming news, you can read about PlayStation announcing that its <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/playstation-teases-death-stranding-2-event-more-for-tokyo-game-show-2024/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">plans for Tokyo Game Show 2024</a> include a Death Stranding 2 event and more, and sign up for <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/newsletter/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">our official newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>
    
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Victory Heat Rally launches October 3 for PC, iOS, and Android; later for Switch]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/victory-heat-rally-launches-october-3-for-pc-ios-and-android-later-for-switch</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/victory-heat-rally-launches-october-3-for-pc-ios-and-android-later-for-switch.961944/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/victory-heat-rally-launches-october-3-for-pc-ios-and-android-later-for-switch<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/mobile/smartphone">Smartphone</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>PC demo now available.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Genres > Arcade [59 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/arcade">Arcade</a> <a title="Genres > Racing [200 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/racing">racing</a> game <em><a title="Games > Victory Heat Rally" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/victory-heat-rally">Victory Heat Rally</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > PC [21,054 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1594060/Victory_Heat_Rally/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a>, and iOS and Android via <a href="https://www.crunchyroll.com/games/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Crunchyroll Game Vault</a> on October 3, followed by Switch at a later date, publisher <a title="Companies > Playtonic Friends [24 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/playtonic-games/playtonic-friends">Playtonic Friends</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Skydevilpalm [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/skydevilpalm">Skydevilpalm</a> announced. <span id="more-891411"></span></p><p>“Our hope was always to launch simultaneously on all platforms,” Playtonic Friends said in a press release. “Unfortunately, due to some unforeseen difficulties with development we made the decision to move ahead with launching on PC and mobile with a launch on <a title="Platforms > Switch [15,832 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Nintendo Switch</a> to follow at a later date. But worry not! We will have news about the Switch launch very soon! It’s not far behind!”</p><p>While the <a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/skydevilpalm/victory-heat-rally/description" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Kickstarter campaign</a> for <em>Victory Heat Rally</em> also targeted PlayStation 4 and Xbox One versions, and still lists those versions today, a Playtonic Friends representative told <a title="Companies > Gematsu" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/gematsu">Gematsu</a> there are currently no plans to release <em>Victory Heat Rally</em> for those platforms, as it only signed Switch, PC, and mobile releases with the developer, and is not associated with the Kickstarter campaign.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Playtonic Friends:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Harkening back to the age of <em>Power Drift</em>, <em>Out Run</em>, and <em>Ridge Racer</em>, <em>Victory Heat Rally</em> will be delivering the turbocharged Neo-SuperScaler arcade racing experience unlike any other!</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Power slide at breakneck speeds through a dynamic &amp; vibrant 2.5D world, brought to life with pixel perfect visuals. Crank up the volume with a soundtrack featuring banging beats, scorching guitar solos, and high octane energy that really bring the heat to <em>Victory Heat Rally</em>.</p><p>Select your star driver and become one with your machine. Challenge yourself and friends-turned-rivals across a variety of game modes. <a title="Companies > Experience [210 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/experience">Experience</a> the high speed <a title="Genres > Action [2,115 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a> and non-stop drifting thrills either solo or in up to four-player split screen.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Select Your Superstar</strong> – With 12 super-star drivers &amp; their machines to choose from, who will you blaze a path to victory with?</li><li><strong>Solo or Against Friends</strong> – Go for the gold in the extensive single player championship, jump in for a quick-fire Arcade Grand Prix, race against up to three friends, or take on the time trial mode and set some new world records.</li><li><strong>World Tour</strong> – Victory Heat Rally features dozens of stages across 12 unique environments. From the sun-drenched beaches of Baytona Beach to the glacial tundras of Frostbite Harbor, you’ll be breaking speed limits across the globe.</li><li><strong>Style Meets Performance</strong> – Express your personal style with exchangeable performance parts &amp; paint jobs, assemble a ride that feels your own!</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Victory Heat Rally | Release Date Trailer!" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9ytHkOlwTLA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Black Myth: Wukong sales top 10 million]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/black-myth-wukong-sales-top-10-million</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/black-myth-wukong-sales-top-10-million.961941/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/black-myth-wukong-sales-top-10-million<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Massive milestone achieved in just three days.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Total sales for Chinese <a title="Genres > Action RPG [1,314 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg/action-rpg">action RPG</a> <em><a title="Games > Black Myth: Wukong [10 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/black-myth-wukong">Black Myth: Wukong</a></em> have surpassed 10 million units, developer <a title="Companies > Game Science [9 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/game-science">Game Science</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/BlackMythGame/status/1826985302592049599" rel="noopener" target="_blank">announced</a>. <span id="more-907331"></span></p><p><em>Black Myth: Wukong</em> launched for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [7,777 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a> and <a title="Platforms > PC [21,054 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2358720/Black_Myth_Wukong/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> and <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/p/black-myth-wukong-87a72b" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Epic Games Store</a>, as well as via the WeGame platform in China, on August 20 worldwide. The sales milestone was achieved in three days.</p><p>The game also achieved a total of three million concurrently players across all platforms. On Steam alone, it achieved <a href="https://steamdb.info/charts/?sort=peak" rel="noopener" target="_blank">all-time and 24-hour peaks</a> of 2,415,714 players, making it the highest ever concurrently played game within 24 hours of launch on Steam, and the second highest concurrently played game ever on Steam following <em><a title="Games > PUBG: Battlegrounds [15 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/pubg-battlegrounds">PUBG: Battlegrounds</a></em>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Firaxis' big swing with Civilization VII? Convincing players to actually finish their games]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/firaxis-big-swing-with-civilization-vii-convincing-players-to-actually-finish-their-games</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/firaxis-big-swing-with-civilization-vii-convincing-players-to-actually-finish-their-games.961935/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/firaxis-big-swing-with-civilization-vii-convincing-players-to-actually-finish-their-games<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">It has been eight years since Firaxis launched </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Civilization VI</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, but creative director Ed Beach hasn't stopped ruminating on what the studio might have done differently.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"</span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Civilization VI</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> was very successful," he says, speaking to Game Developer at Gamescom 2024, "but it didn't mean the design team loved it by the time we were finished. We are self critical, and we're happy to dissect and pick apart our own creation and see its flaws."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Beach was looking to the past to explain how Firaxis is approaching the future, which is important to understand given it has just unveiled </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Civilization VII</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">. He explains Firaxis uses a formula that requires each new entry in the franchise to incorporate equal parts new content, updated content, and existing content.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">It's a rule of thirds that enables the studio to innovate without completely alienating players—while also avoiding scope creep. Digging into how that equation influenced production on </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Civilization VII</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, which is slated to launch in February 2025, Beach says the headline issue was the fact players simply weren't finishing games.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"The number [of people who completed a game of </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Civ VI</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">] was surprisingly, depressingly—whatever adjective you want to put in there—low. It was less than 50 percent. So, why is that happening?," he asks.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The short answer is 'pacing.' He says your average Civilization player might spend 15 to 20 hours completing a single game. As the hours pass and empires grow, the managerial elements become more pronounced, leaving players needing to complete a exponentially growing list of tasks just to get through a turn.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Beach claims players "hated" the pacing of </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Civilization VI</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">. It's an admission that resulted in Firaxis&nbsp;conducting individual postmortems of each system to learn when they pushed "important, strategic decisions you don't have to make more than every five to 10 minutes," and when they demanded players make "tiresome 'click here, click here, click, here' decisions that just aren't very interesting."</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="A sequel for the ages">A sequel for the ages</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">That inquisition saw Firaxis reconfigure </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Civilization VII</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> to ensure more people felt capable of crossing the finish line. "The number one thing we wanted to do was break the game up into chapters," Beach explains. "We're calling them 'ages' this time. We're only at three ages to get through the game, because there's a lot of restructuring around the map that happens between the two age transitions. We wanted to make it so we could reset the board a little bit and simplify things out and change up the rules. [For instance], our trade system works differently in each age."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Exploration has also been tweaked to preserve the sense of fun sparked by discovery. "I think a core pillar of 4X games is exploration, and that's one reason players wouldn't go all the way through the game and restart. It's because that first 50 turns of figuring out where you are on the map and who's around you is innately fun. We have done some things [this time] to bottle up that fun and spread it throughout the game," says Beach.</span></p><p><iframe title="Embedded content" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/kK_JrrP9m2U?si=Yi1_1aiiNZ7TuO6w" height="315px" width="100%" allowfullscreen="" data-testid="iframe-video"></iframe></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Elaborating, he explains </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Civilization VII</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> is broken into chapters, beginning with the 'Antiquity Age.' During that age, players will only be allowed to explore the landmass they start on. "Even if you invest in a lot of naval technology, we won't let you go across the ocean," adds Beach.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">When asked how the team will essentially restrict players without causing frustration, he explains the technique was used in past titles across 70 to 80 percent of maps. Now, it's being enforced without exception.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Again referencing the formula we mentioned earlier, Beach says the team wasn't shy when it came to pitching new ideas—but sometimes you have to cut your coat according to your cloth.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"The design team were so self-critical," he says. "They were like 'we want to change this, and this, and this.' So, I would bring up that rule of thumb and say 'you want to do something entirely different here, Another thing entirely different here. These two areas—the foundations are the same but they're falling into our 'one third modified'. There were times I could see the trajectory was radically different enough that it was violating that formula."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Beach created a spreadsheet that he whipped out during two design meetings to prove his colleagues were over-indexing and breaking the formula. "[I said] basically you get 33 percent total change, and then another 33 percent you can modify," he adds. "So you've got a 50 percent budget for changing the game, and you're all at 60 percent—and we haven't even finished all of this."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">When deciding which aspects of the franchise to alter, Firaxis uses a technique called 'ripples.' It's a process that requires the team to understand "the minimum viable amount of implementation you need to get to the core idea of something you can then experiment with." Testing is a fundamental part of that process.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"We have single player playtests and multiplayer playtests on a scheduled cadence," continues Beach. "So, whatever is ready to try out in the next playtest session [is included]. Then the whole design team gets together and discusses [the feedback]."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Underlining the importance of variety when playtesting, he notes combat becomes more visible in multiplayer tests because people "like to bash on each other." Conversely, single player tests are better for appraising systems like building and diplomacy.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Looking towards launch, Beach explains Firaxis currently has hundreds of developers working on </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Civilization VII</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and is "taking full responsibility for shipping to all the platforms in house." That decision was made to ensure all versions of the title, which is built on a proprietary engine, work as intended. He says it's a choice that has left the studio in a "more comfortable place" as it attempts to wrap production.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">News Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer news editor Chris Kerr is an award-winning journalist and reporter with over a decade of experience in the game industry. His byline has appeared in notable print and digital publications including Edge, Stuff, Wireframe, International Business Times, and&nbsp;</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="http://pocketgamer.biz/">PocketGamer.biz</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. Throughout his career, Chris has covered major industry events including GDC, PAX Australia, Gamescom, Paris Games Week, and Develop Brighton. He has featured on the judging panel at The Develop Star Awards on multiple occasions and appeared on BBC Radio 5 Live to discuss breaking news.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Glamtime never ends in Infinity Nikki, the open world dress-up game from Zelda talent]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/glamtime-never-ends-in-infinity-nikki-the-open-world-dress-up-game-from-zelda-talent</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/glamtime-never-ends-in-infinity-nikki-the-open-world-dress-up-game-from-zelda-talent.961926/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/glamtime-never-ends-in-infinity-nikki-the-open-world-dress-up-game-from-zelda-talent<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Infinity-Nikki-jpg.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Infold Games</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
Take the ballroom scene from Disney's Beauty And The Beast, swap the wailing utensils for an army of chibi cats, endow Belle with low-key Doctor Manhattan-grade powers of matter transformation, and you're perhaps <em>beginning</em> to approximate the experience of Infinity Nikki - an <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-best-open-world-games">open world</a> dress-up adventure from Singapore-based Infold and former Legend of Zelda: Breath Of The Wild developer Kentaro Tominaga.</p>
<p>Trailered this week at <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/events/gamescom-2024">Gamescom 2024</a>, it's the fifth installment in the hitherto mobile-focussed Nikki series and it's seemingly going down a storm, with over 12 million pre-registrations so far (albeit, many of them motivated by the prospect of collectively unlocked in-game bonuses). It's also a free-to-play game, and I have the usual unanswered questions about currencies and gacha, but I'm willing to give it the benefit of the doubt for the minute, because I have not spent nearly enough of my life considering the tactical applications of ballgowns. Here's that trailer.
</p><!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Infinity Nikki - Gamescom 2024 Trailer | PS5 Games" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6YI7sR97kzI?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Infinity Nikki - Gamescom 2024 Trailer | PS5 Games</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6YI7sR97kzI?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/6YI7sR97kzI?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6YI7sR97kzI" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>
Some plot gleaned from <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/infinity-nikki-the-first-hands-on-preview">a recent Ian Games preview</a>: princess or princess-adjacent heroine Nikki is rifling through her wardrobe for an outfit when she discovers an enchanted dress. The dress promptly abducts her, yanking her through a portal into the sparkling Narnified Hyrule that is Miraland. Here she meets a cursed goddess, Ena, who tasks her with saving the world from evil using the power of the lost Miracle Outfits.</p>
<p>Along the way, she'll snatch up a bazillion other fresh looks that bestow various powers and skills - fishing, stealthy movement, mastery of electronics, bug-catching, shrinking yourself so you can ride around on your pet <del>Moogle</del> cat's head. It's the costume-based verbing of Final Fantasy X-2, applied to open worlding. Do not despair of the absence of expressly warlike elements, for war is but fear cloaked in taffeta, and the hem is mightier than the sword.
</p>
<p>
There <em>is</em> combat, aka monster purification, but it's played light. Enemies have names like Bouldy and sometimes literally consist of materials for posh frocks. The land appears to be populated chiefly by tailors and stylists, rather than the usual brooding blacksmiths and arms dealers. Zeldary touches abound: you get a Pear-Pal tablet akin to Breath Of The Wild's Sheikah Slate, which is used principally for photoshoots, and one of the dresses lets you glide. There are also dungeons of a sort with platforming sequences: one of them consists of a Dream Warehouse full of paper cranes that represent wishes. Complete it, and you'll get to fly away on one. Some other things you can ride on: magic trains, bicycles, minecarts in wine cellars, and a bloody great bird that follows a fixed route around the map.
</p>
<p>
I'm fairly charmed? I am firmly expecting the so-far-unspecified monetisation elements to be as savage as the visuals are saccharine - this feels like it's aimed squarely at magpie children with unregulated access to their parent's bank cards. But I dig the idea of an open world explicitly built around gladragging, inasmuch as playing dress-up is secretly the best part of many games - including games which ostensibly frown upon such frivolous distractions because Look Here, I Am A Serious Artform or Dress-Up Is For Girls. Put it this way: Dark Souls has a fashion scene. Anyway, you can read more of Nikki and her doings on <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/en-US/p/infinity-nikki-71fc64?lang=en-US">the Epic Game Store</a>.</p>
<hr>
<p><em>For more of the latest news and previews from Gamescom 2024, head to our <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/events/gamescom-2024">Gamescom 2024 hub</a>.</em></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>