<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 14:11:10 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[IO Interactive Co-Founder Opens New Studio Wombo Games, New Rogue-Lite Raiders Of Blackveil To Be Debut Project]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/io-interactive-co-founder-opens-new-studio-wombo-games-new-rogue-lite-raiders-of-blackveil-to-be-debut-project/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/io-interactive-co-founder-opens-new-studio-wombo-games-new-rogue-lite-raiders-of-blackveil-to-be-debut-project.1172532/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/io-interactive-co-founder-opens-new-studio-wombo-games-new-rogue-lite-raiders-of-blackveil-to-be-debut-project/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The co-founder of <a href="https://wccftech.com/io-interactive-wants-to-create-a-007-gaming-franchise-will-publish-mindseye-from-rocket-boy/">IO Interactive</a> and former chief creative officer at Square Enix,&nbsp; <strong><span data-olk-copy-source="MessageBody">Janos Flösser, </span></strong>has started a new studio based in Copenhagen called <a href="https://www.wombogames.com/">Wombo Games</a>. Alongside the new studio announcement, Flösser has also announced the studio's debut project, a new roguge-lite called <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3352240/Raiders_of_Blackveil/">Raiders of Blackveil</a>.</p>

<figure></figure>

<p>Raiders of Blackveil is currently set to arrive on Steam in Early Access sometime this summer, and is described as an "<em><span data-olk-copy-source="MessageBody">action-packed</span></em> <em>rogue-lite</em>" that looks to "<em><span data-olk-copy-source="MessageBody">blend MOBA-inspired champions, RPG-style loot and PVE extraction gameplay to create a deeply strategic game filled with challenging, fun encounters that can be experienced alone or with friends</span></em>," according to a press release.</p>
<p>The setting is a dystopian fantasy world where you'll fight against an evil corporation run by humans named Blackveil. The human part is important because you're part of an animal rebellion against Blackveil, and either on your own or alongside two other animal friends in groups of three, you'll raid and plunder Blackveil in the fight to end the corporation's evil dominance.</p>

<figure></figure>

<p>Flösser describes Wombo Games as a mixture of industry veterans who have worked on games like Hitman, Tomb Raider, and Deus Ex, paired with young, talented developers looking to make their mark on the video game industry.</p>
<p><span data-olk-copy-source="MessageBody">"<em>Wombo Games has been developing Raiders of Blackveil for nearly two years so it's surreal to finally be able to announce it, and Wombo Games, to the world,</em></span>" said Flösser. "<span data-olk-copy-source="MessageBody"><em>Raiders of Blackveil is our first title so it's very special to us. It is a blueprint of our studio because every person at Wombo has contributed directly to its development. At Wombo, we make decisions by consensus, and plan to continue that with feedback from our players once we launch in early access later this year...</em>"</span></p>

<figure></figure>


<p>With summer just around the corner, hopefully we'll hear more about Raiders of Blackveil soon.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokemon TCG Pocket Celestial Guardians Set Revealed for Next Week]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/pokemon-tcg-pocket-celestial-guardians-set</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pokemon-tcg-pocket-celestial-guardians-set-revealed-for-next-week.1172526/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/pokemon-tcg-pocket-celestial-guardians-set<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>DeNA and The Pokemon Company have announced a brand new&nbsp;<em>Pokemon TCG Pocket&nbsp;</em>set in the form of&nbsp;<em>Celestial Guardians</em>, a major expansion that brings hundreds of new cards to the game.</p>

<p>As revealed in an announcement <a href="https://www.pokemon.com/uk/pokemon-news/look-to-the-skies-with-pokemon-tcg-pockets-upcoming-expansion-celestial-guardians" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">post</a>,&nbsp;<em>Celestial Guardians&nbsp;</em>is the next mainline expansion for&nbsp;<em>Pokemon TCG Pocket</em>, and it's coming on April 29th at 11pm Pacific (that's April 30th at 2am Eastern).</p>

<p><em>Celestial Guardians </em>isn't a mini-expansion like&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/pokemon-tcg-pocket-mythical-island-expansion" rel="nofollow"><em>Mythical Island</em></a>; it's the real deal, and it&nbsp;follows on from previous expansions like&nbsp;<em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/pokemon-tcg-pocket-expansion-shining-revelry" rel="nofollow">Shining Revelry</a>&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/pokemon-tcg-pocket-trading-update-new-expansion-release-date" rel="nofollow"><em>Space-Time Smackdown</em></a>, bringing over 200 new cards for you to collect, including "the first immersive Supporter card".</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/pokemon-tcg-pocket-celestial-guardians-lillie.jpg?itok=9Ey2g9nY 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/pokemon-tcg-pocket-celestial-guardians-lillie.jpg?itok=SNcMfneb 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Pokemon TCG Pocket</em>'s&nbsp;<em>Celestial Guardians&nbsp;</em>set will feature the game's first immersive Supporter card.</figcaption></figure><p>This new set will feature the debut of a number of Alolan Pokemon, including starters Rowlet, Popplio, and Litten, as well as the banner legendaries Lunala and Solgaleo.</p>

<p>Both legendaries will be getting ex cards, of course, along with the likes of Alolan Raichu. The trailer also gives us a glimpse of a rather beautiful full art Alolan Marowak card, as well as a number of new basic cards, item cards, and more.</p>

<p><em>Celestial Guardians&nbsp;</em>is arriving as&nbsp;<em>Pokemon TCG Pocket&nbsp;</em>prepares to celebrate its six-month anniversary (which is, according to DeNA and The Pokemon Company, a thing).</p>

<p>As part of that celebration, a new series of battles and missions will be available at the same time as&nbsp;<em>Celestial Guardians</em>. Taking them on will give you the chance to earn promo cards, including a gorgeous Rayquaza ex card, as well as other goodies.</p>




<p>If you're wondering what&nbsp;<em>Pokemon TCG Pocket&nbsp;</em>is, the clue's in the name; it's a mobile version of the&nbsp;<em>Pokemon&nbsp;</em>trading card game, in which you can collect cards, battle opponents, and trade with your friends (<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/pokemon-tcg-pocket-trade-tokens" rel="nofollow">to a certain degree, anyway</a>).</p>

<p>Despite criticisms of some of its systems and monetization elements,&nbsp;<em>Pokemon TCG Pocket&nbsp;</em>has proven <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/pokemon-tcg-pocket-dena-revenue" rel="nofollow">phenomenally successful</a> for its developers, so you can expect to see new expansions appearing well into the future.</p>

<p><em>Pokemon TCG Pocket&nbsp;</em>is available now for <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=jp.pokemon.pokemontcgp&amp;hl=en_GB" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Android</a> and <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/pok%C3%A9mon-tcg-pocket/id6479970832" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">iOS</a> devices.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Don't Leave Sinners Before You See The Post-Credit Scenes]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/sinners-post-credit-scenes-1851777646</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dont-leave-sinners-before-you-see-the-post-credit-scenes.1172520/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/sinners-post-credit-scenes-1851777646<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>“Sinners” is one of the earliest blockbusters of 2025, and for good reason. The fifth collaboration between director Ryan Coogler and actor Michael B Jordan is also their most ambitious yet, as the ladder plays a pair of twin brothers who battle supernatural forces while opening up a new juke joint in Jim Crow era Mississippi. Below, see five spoiler-free reasons why you should see the movie (and don’t leave until the screen is completely Black).</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196566" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Please, Game Developers, Stop It With The Killmonger Swoop Already" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="196" data-playlist="196566,197541,197533" data-current="196566"><div><p>Please, Game Developers, Stop It With The Killmonger Swoop Already</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196566/196566_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196566/196566_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196566/196566_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196566/196566_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/22120.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p><strong>It’s Three Movies In One</strong></p><p>“Sinners” is essentially three genres in one, and if you leave early, you’ll miss the brilliant way that director Ryan Coogler brings everything together. The first half of the film is essentially a Jim Crow era western, a period piece that finds twin brothers Smoke and Stack bustling around the Mississippi Delta to plan the grand opening for their juke joint. But in the time that follows, the movie blooms into even more: it’s a supernatural horror film, with characters wielding wooden stakes and garlic to fight bloodthirsty vampires, and a musical, with the blues working as both a narrative motif and as the film’s sonic heartbeat. </p><p><strong>That incredible ode to Black music</strong></p><p>In the trailer for “Sinners,” a voiceover of one its characters describes a legend of musicians’ whose gifts are so powerful that they can “conjure spirits from the past and future.” In this film, those capabilities are bestowed to Sammie, the son of a preacher who leads a small church in Mississippi. He has a stirring voice, no doubt – and there’s one moment where viewers get to see his celestial talents at work. It’s one of the biggest surprises in a film that’s full of them: a wonderful showcase of Sammie’s voice, an impressive display of expert editing and cinematography, and a beautiful ode to to the intergenerational power of music. </p><p><strong>The ambitious usage of IMAX cameras</strong></p><p>Ahead of the theatrical release of “Sinners,” a video was released online that gave Ryan Coogler a chance to break down the different types of film that were used in the creation of the movie. The video is admittedly a little inside baseball, but long story short, “Sinners” is the first movie that’s shot in two different camera systems – a creative approach that particularly shines in IMAX theaters. The screen expands vertically for the film’s most scenic moments, while it narrows into a wide screen for its most intense, intimate scenes. The result is a film that feels technically adventurous, and seeing the aspect ratios change in real time offers a sense of anticipation for what’s next.</p><p><strong>Give the movie the consideration it deserves</strong></p><p>“Sinners” is lots of fun its share of laughs, lust, and action to keep viewers on the edges of their seats. But it’s also sure to send viewers home with things to think about. The film and its characters have a lot to say about Black creativity, spirituality, allyship, freedom, and individuality. Its themes have had viewers’ group chats and social media feeds buzzing nonstop since opening night, and that’ll remain the case for a while. </p><p><strong>Post-credit scenes</strong></p><p>This isn’t a superhero movie, but Coogler still has a couple of tricks up his sleeve to reveal as the credits roll. So if you haven’t seen it yet, sit tight; and if you haven’t, it might be time to head back to the theatre for a second viewing. There’s a satisfying mid-credits scene that takes place 60 years after the events of the film, reuniting some of its characters for an epilogue that brings satisfying closure to its story. There’s also a post-credits scene at the very end that showcases Sammie playing a song on his beloved guitar, a moment that has deeper meaning after all that transpired in the film beforehand. </p><p><em>This story originally appeared on The Root, our sister site, on Tuesday, April 22.</em></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[After The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion Remastered’s Success, Ex-Bethesda Dev Expects a Fallout 3 Remaster Would Significantly Improve the ‘Not Good’ Gun]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/after-the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-remastereds-success-ex-bethesda-dev-expects-a-fallout-3-remaster-would-significantly-improve-the-not-good-gun-combat</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/after-the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-remastered%E2%80%99s-success-ex-bethesda-dev-expects-a-fallout-3-remaster-would-significantly-improve-the-%E2%80%98not-good%E2%80%99-gun.1172511/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/after-the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-remastereds-success-ex-bethesda-dev-expects-a-fallout-3-remaster-would-significantly-improve-the-not-good-gun-combat<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">With <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-remastered">The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion Remastered</a> going down well with fans, thoughts are now turning to which Bethesda game is set for the remaster treatment next. And with many speculating <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/fallout-3">Fallout 3</a> is coming (<a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/oblivion-remaster-fallout-3-remaster-and-more-leaked-from-microsoft-document">it was leaked back in 2023</a>), how might Bethesda improve upon its 2008 post-apocalyptic role-playing game?</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Bruce Nesmith, one of Fallout 3’s designers, has pointed to the game’s “not good” gun combat, which he expects Bethesda would improve significantly for a remaster.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Speaking to <a href="https://www.videogamer.com/news/fallout-3-designer-expects-remaster-to-heavily-revise-gunplay/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">VideoGamer</a>, Nesmith said Fallout 3 Remastered would have shooting more in-line with that of Fallout 4.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“What did you see in Fallout 4? That will tell you what they felt was necessary to change from Fallout 3,” Nesmith said.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“I know in Fallout 4 there was a lot of work done on the gun combat, because Fallout 3 is the first time they ever tried to do a shooter-style game. And, well, I think the work that was done was amazing.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Oblivion Remastered, developed by remake specialist Virtuos using Unreal Engine 5, has a long list of visual and feature improvements. It runs at 4K resolution and 60 frames per second, as you'd expect, but other changes are more meaningful. Everything from the leveling systems to character creation, and combat animations to in-game menus have been improved. Meanwhile, there's lots of new dialogue, a proper third-person view, and new lip sync technology. The changes are going down well with fans, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-elder-scrolls-4-oblivion-remastered-fans-react-to-all-the-biggest-changes-say-its-good-enough-to-be-called-a-remake"><u>some of whom believe Oblivion Remastered would be more accurately described as a remake</u></a>. Bethesda, however, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/bethesda-comments-on-the-elder-scrolls-4-oblivion-remastered-changes-we-never-wanted-to-remake-it"><u>has explained why it went down the remaster route</u></a>.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Nesmith said Fallout 3 Remastered would probably include improvements and changes along similar lines to Oblivion Remastered.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“[Fallout 3 combat] didn’t hold up to shooters at the time,” he said. “Also, it’s an RPG shooter, it’s not a run-and-gun shooter. But a lot of work was done on that for Fallout 4. So I anticipate seeing a lot of that work go into it, assuming they’re doing the same thing.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Oblivion wasn’t just brought up to the 2011 version of Skyrim,” he added. “It was brought up to something that, at least on the surface, looks like it exceeds the most recent graphics update in Skyrim.” Nesmith has said <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/original-the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-designer-says-bethesdas-remaster-is-so-impressive-it-could-be-called-oblivion-20">The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion Remastered is so impressive it could be called “Oblivion 2.0.”</a></p><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s a busy time for Bethesda, which is working on <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/the-elder-scrolls-vi">The Elder Scrolls VI</a> and, maybe, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/playstation-logo-pops-up-on-work-in-progress-starfield-creation-sparking-ps5-release-speculation">more Starfield</a>. Throw in remasters and ongoing work on Fallout 76 and the Fallout TV show, which is heading to New Vegas for Season 2, and fans are in for a treat in the coming years.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">We've got a comprehensive guide to everything you'll find in Oblivion Remastered, including an expansive <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/maps/the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion/cyrodiil">Interactive Map</a>, complete Walkthroughs for the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion/Main_Quest_Walkthrough">Main Questline</a> and every <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion/Guilds">Guild Quest</a>, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion/Character_Building_Guide">How to Build the Perfect Character</a>, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion/Things_to_Do_First_in_Oblivion">Things to Do First</a>, every <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion/PC_Cheats_and_Console_Commands">PC Cheat Code</a>, and much more.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Quietly Confirms Cost of Switch 2 Upgrades for Kirby and the Forgotten Land and Super Mario Party Jamboree — and They're Not Cheap]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-quietly-confirms-cost-of-switch-2-upgrades-for-kirby-and-the-forgotten-land-and-super-mario-party-jamboree-and-theyre-not-cheap</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-quietly-confirms-cost-of-switch-2-upgrades-for-kirby-and-the-forgotten-land-and-super-mario-party-jamboree-%E2%80%94-and-theyre-not-cheap.1172508/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-quietly-confirms-cost-of-switch-2-upgrades-for-kirby-and-the-forgotten-land-and-super-mario-party-jamboree-and-theyre-not-cheap<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">UK eShop suggests upgrades in the U.S. could cost $20.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Nintendo has confirmed the cost of upgrading two more Switch games from the OG Switch edition to the Switch 2 Edition, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/kirby-and-the-forgotten-land"><u>Kirby and the Forgotten Land</u></a> and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/super-mario-party-jamboree"><u>Super Mario Party Jamboree</u></a> — and it's not cheap.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/the-legend-of-zelda-breath-of-the-wild"><u>The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild</u></a> and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/the-legend-of-zelda-tears-of-the-kingdom"><u>The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom</u></a> cost $9.99 each to upgrade from the original Switch 1 game to the Switch 2 Edition, but <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/04/nintendo-confirms-upgrade-pack-price-for-two-more-switch-2-edition-titles" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>NintendoLife</u></a> spotted that both the Kirby and the Forgotten Land and Super Mario Party Jamboree upgrades cost more than double that each.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/how-nintendo-switch-2-will-improve-switch-1-games"><u>Nintendo Switch 2 Enhanced Edition of Breath of the Wild</u></a> comes with <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/videos/zelda-breath-of-the-wild-nintendo-switch-2-edition-graphical-comparison-treehouse-live"><u>improved visuals and performance</u></a>, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-legend-of-zelda-breath-of-the-wild-and-tears-of-the-kingdom-are-getting-achievements-on-nintendo-switch-2"><u>achievements</u></a>, as well as support for the new "Zelda Notes" service in the Nintendo Switch Online app. If you already own Breath of the Wild on the Switch, you won't get those features automatically, but you can purchase an "upgrade pack" for $10 to access them.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The Switch 2 Edition of Kirby and the Forgotten Land’s Star-Crossed World has new story content. Super Mario Party Jamboree’s Switch 2 Edition comes with a new suite of content called Jamboree TV that takes advantage of the Joy-Con 2 mouse controls, Switch 2 microphone, and the Switch 2 USB-C camera that will be sold separately. Along with upgraded resolution up to 1440p in TV mode and better frame rate, there are new minigames and online functions as well.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">While we don't yet have U.S. prices on the <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/us/gaming-systems/switch-2/featured-games/switch-2-edition/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>American Nintendo eShop</u></a> — possibly <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/trumps-tariffs-hit-pc-hardware-razer-gaming-laptop-removed-from-sale"><u>due to the uncertainty with President Trump's tariffs</u></a> — the <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/en-gb/Games/Nintendo-Switch-2-Edition/Kirby-and-the-Forgotten-Land-Nintendo-Switch-2-Edition-Star-Crossed-World-2787773.html" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>UK Nintendo eShop shows the Kirby and the Forgotten Land upgrade pack</u></a> on sale for £16.99 / €19.99, more than twice the £7.99 / €9.99 charged to upgrade either Breath of the Wild and Tears of the Kingdom.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It's the same price for <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/en-gb/Games/Nintendo-Switch-2-Edition/Super-Mario-Party-Jamboree-Nintendo-Switch-2-Edition-Jamboree-TV-2785806.html" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">the Super Mario Party Jamboree – Nintendo Switch 2 Edition ＋ Jamboree TV upgrade</a>. That suggests the price will be $19.99 in the U.S.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">A $20 upgrade price for both games may have to do with the shock $80 cost of both Kirby and The Forgotten Land - Nintendo Switch 2 Edition + Star Crossed World, and Super Mario Party Jamboree - Nintendo Switch 2 Edition + Jamboree TV. Both games' OG Switch versions are $20 cheaper, priced $59.99 each.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Here's how much Nintendo Switch 2 Edition games cost in the U.S. for those not upgrading:</h2><ul data-cy="list"><li><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/kirby-and-the-forgotten-land-nintendo-switch-2-edition-star-crossed-world">Kirby and The Forgotten Land - Nintendo Switch 2 Edition + Star Crossed World</a> - $79.99</li><li><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/the-legend-of-zelda-breath-of-the-wild-nintendo-switch-2-edition">The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild – Nintendo Switch 2 Edition</a> - $69.99</li><li><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/super-mario-party-jamboree-nintendo-switch-2-edition-jamboree-tv">Super Mario Party Jamboree - Nintendo Switch 2 Edition + Jamboree TV</a> - $79.99</li><li><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/the-legend-of-zelda-tears-of-the-kingdom-nintendo-switch-2-edition">The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom – Nintendo Switch 2 Edition</a> - $79.99</li></ul><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">As a reminder, both Breath of the Wild and Tears of the Kingdom upgrade packs are also available for no extra cost to Nintendo Switch Online and Expansion Pack subscribers. At the time of writing, however, there is no similar offer for players hoping to upgrade Kirby or Party Jamboree.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Nintendo Switch 2 pre-orders went live earlier today, April 24, with the price still fixed at $449.99 — <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-pre-orders-went-live-and-were-predictably-a-mess"><u>and they went about as well as you'd expect</u></a>. Meanwhile, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-issues-inevitable-switch-2-my-nintendo-store-warning-to-us-customers-says-release-date-delivery-not-guaranteed-due-to-very-high-demand">Nintendo has just issued a warning to U.S. customers who applied for a Switch 2 pre-order from the My Nintendo Store</a>, saying release date delivery was not guaranteed due to very high demand.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Check out IGN's <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-preorder-guide"><u>Nintendo Switch 2 pre-order guide</u></a> for more.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Vikki Blake is a reporter, critic, columnist, and consultant. She's also a Guardian, Spartan, Silent Hillian, Legend, and perpetually High Chaos. Find her at </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vixx.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>BlueSky</em></a><em>.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Low-poly cozy driving game Easy Delivery Co. announced for PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/low-poly-cozy-driving-game-easy-delivery-co-announced-for-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/low-poly-cozy-driving-game-easy-delivery-co-announced-for-pc.1172505/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/low-poly-cozy-driving-game-easy-delivery-co-announced-for-pc<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Due out in 2025. Demo available now.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Oro Interactive" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/oro-interactive">Oro Interactive</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Sam C" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sam-c">Sam C</a> have announced <em><a title="Games > Easy Delivery Co." href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/easy-delivery-co">Easy Delivery Co.</a></em>, a driving game set in a quiet mountain town “where something feels just a little… off.” It will launch for <a title="Platforms > PC [22,979 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3293010/Easy_Delivery_Co/" target="_blank">Steam</a> in 2025. A demo is available now. <span id="more-961092"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3293010/Easy_Delivery_Co/" target="_blank">Steam page</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>Easy Delivery Co.</em> is a relaxing driving game, with definitely no secrets. You’ve been hired as a delivery driver in a once-lively scenic mountain town now plagued with inhospitable weather. Make deliveries and uncover the story of the town’s not-at-all mysterious residents, all while earning well below minimum wage.</p><p>Pick Up. Drive. Deliver. Dream of escaping.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <ul><li>Earn a “living” by delivering packages with your kei truck.</li><li>Take in the atmospheric scenery or blitz through (road safety not required).</li><li>Buy drastically overpriced gas and get to know the locals.</li><li>Simple controls and retro graphics.</li><li>Listen to cool beats while driving.</li><li>Split-screen race mode with up to four players.</li><li>Nothing strange going on, no lore, nothing at all, we promise.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch the announcement trailer below.</p><h2><span>Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Easy Delivery Co. | Official Reveal Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_hTyizqcLV8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[RoboCop: Rogue City – Unfinished Business will launch in July]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/04/24/robocop-rogue-city-unfinished-business-will-launch-in-july/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/robocop-rogue-city-%E2%80%93-unfinished-business-will-launch-in-july.1172496/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/04/24/robocop-rogue-city-unfinished-business-will-launch-in-july/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>RoboCop: Rogue City – Unfinished Business will lay down the law when this standalone expansion launches for PC, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series X|S on 17th July,</p>
<p><iframe title="RoboCop: Rogue City - Unfinished Business | Story Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/7ykC7btuV6Y?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>OCP’s plan to create a centralised control centre for all their law delivering robots has been thrown into disarray when&nbsp;Omni Tower has been overrun by mercenaries. RoboCop will have to fight his way up the tower, taking on a menagerie of classic goons, fan-favourite bots and flying drones and mercenaries along the way.</p>
<p>Thankfully there’s some new weapons and more brutal finishers to help mix things up as you make your way up the tower, as well as some new allies to work alongside. Inevitably, RoboCop will take one heck of a beating as he goes up floor-by-floor.</p>
<p>But there’s also special missions that will take players into flashback sequences to a time before RoboCop, giving the chance to play as Alex Murphy for the first time and reveal some about the game’s antagonist. It will be interesting to see how different that is compared to the rather stompy FPS action of the main game.</p>

<p>RoboCop: Rogue City is Teyon’s latest FPS based on an 80’s film franchise. Set between the second and third films, RoboCop methodically stomps around town on the trail of a new drug gang and peel back a new mystery while blasting everything in sight into smithereens. The game has passed a significant milestone with Nacon proudly touting over 1 million players since launch.</p>
<p>It’s also a game that’s divided opinion a little amongst our writers. A few of us have had a great time with it, getting exactly what they want out of a RoboCop game – one-note bipedal cop-bot action – while others were a little less enthused.&nbsp;<a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2023/10/31/robocop-rogue-city-review/">Ade handled our RoboCop review</a>, and sadly did not have the best of times, awarding it a 4/10 for some technical flaws, as well as a monotonous plodding pace to story and combat.</p>
<p><em>Source: press release</em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GeForce NOW Adds Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 and Oblivion Remastered This Week]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/geforce-now-adds-clair-obscur-expedition-33-and-oblivion-remastered-this-week/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/geforce-now-adds-clair-obscur-expedition-33-and-oblivion-remastered-this-week.1172493/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/geforce-now-adds-clair-obscur-expedition-33-and-oblivion-remastered-this-week/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>GeForce NOW users who love roleplaying games have plenty to do this week with the launches of <a href="https://wccftech.com/the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-remastered-looks-gorgeous-and-its-out-now/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion Remastered</a> and <a href="https://wccftech.com/clair-obscur-expedition-33-launches-on-april-24th-on-pc-and-consoles-new-trailer-released/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</a>. The games may differ heavily when it comes to RPG design (the former is a classic Western open world action RPG with real-time combat, whereas Clair Obscur is a linear JRPG-inspired turn-based game with some innovative real-time elements). Still, they have a few things in common: they're both powered by Unreal Engine 5, available on Game Pass, and can now be played on NVIDIA's cloud platform if you don't have the required PC hardware.</p>
<p>Both games&nbsp;<span><a href="https://wccftech.com/tempest-rising-clair-obscur-expedition-33-and-more-add-support-for-nvidia-dlss-super-resolution/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">support</a></span><a href="https://wccftech.com/tempest-rising-clair-obscur-expedition-33-and-more-add-support-for-nvidia-dlss-super-resolution/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&nbsp;NVIDIA DLSS Super Resolution upscaling</a>, which can be enabled by any GeForce NOW user with a Priority or Ultimate subscription. Oblivion Remastered takes it one step further with DLSS Frame Generation and hardware-accelerated Lumen ray-traced global illumination, both of which can be activated by GFN players with an Ultimate subscription.</p>
<p>We've covered Oblivion Remastered a lot in the past few days, but Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 is also exciting. Critics have raved about it in their reviews, <a href="https://www.metacritic.com/game/clair-obscur-expedition-33/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">averaging over 90 in the Metacritic scores</a> across all platforms. You'll have to wait a bit longer to read our review, as Wccftech was not provided with an advance code and has only been able to access the game today with everyone else.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, here's the full list of weekly GeForce NOW additions:</p>
<p><em>● The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion Remastered (New release on Steam and Xbox, available on PC Game</em><br>
<em>Pass, April 22)</em><br>
<em>● Sunderfolk (New release on Steam, April 23)</em><br>
<em>● Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 (New release on Steam and Xbox, available on PC Game Pass, April</em><br>
<em>24)</em><br>
<em>● Ace Attorney Investigations Collection (Steam and Xbox, available on the Microsoft Store)</em><br>
<em>● Ace Attorney Investigations Collection Demo (Steam and Xbox, available on the Microsoft Store)</em><br>
<em>● Dead Rising Deluxe Remaster Demo (Steam)</em><br>
<em>● EXFIL (Steam)</em><br>
<em>● Sands of Aura (Epic Games Store)</em></p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Until Dawn Dev Supermassive Reportedly Cancels Blade Runner Game]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/supermassive-blade-runner-game-canceled-report</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/until-dawn-dev-supermassive-reportedly-cancels-blade-runner-game.1172490/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/supermassive-blade-runner-game-canceled-report<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Until Dawn&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>The Quarry&nbsp;</em>developer Supermassive Games has reportedly canceled an in-development&nbsp;<em>Blade Runner&nbsp;</em>game that was set to release some time in 2027.</p>

<p>That's according to an Insider Gaming report, which cites anonymous sources that supposedly worked on the project. According to Insider's report,&nbsp;<em>Blade Runner: Time to Live&nbsp;</em>was a "character-focused, cinematic action-adventure" game that would have run around 10-12 hours.</p>

<p>The game would have featured the four key pillars of "stealth, combat, exploration, and investigation", which would have set it apart from Supermassive's usual fare; the developer is mostly known for <a href="https://techraptor.net/games/quarry" rel="nofollow">movie-style adventure games</a> that <a href="https://techraptor.net/games/dark-pictures-anthology-little-hope" rel="nofollow">don't usually feature much</a> in the <a href="https://techraptor.net/games/dark-pictures-anthology-man-of-medan" rel="nofollow">way of gameplay</a>.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/blade-runner-enhanced-edition-supermassive-games-canceled-project-rumor.jpg?itok=yly1jTn2 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/blade-runner-enhanced-edition-supermassive-games-canceled-project-rumor.jpg?itok=Bwf_bVCX 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Until Dawn&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>The Quarry&nbsp;</em>developer Supermassive Games has reportedly canceled a&nbsp;<em>Blade Runner&nbsp;</em>game.</figcaption></figure><p>According to Insider Games, you'd have access to various skills and abilities that you could upgrade in&nbsp;<em>Blade Runner: Time to Live</em>, and you'd also be able to use "past memories to figure out the story", as well as using "in-game technology to complete your investigations".</p>

<p>It sounds like the game would have been a pretty ambitious one, and it sounds pretty far out of Supermassive's usual wheelhouse as well; it puts me in mind of The Chinese Room's work on <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/vampire-masquerade-bloodlines-2-delayed-october-2025" rel="nofollow">the upcoming&nbsp;<em>Vampire: The Masquerade - Bloodlines 2</em></a>.</p>

<p>Supposedly,&nbsp;<em>Blade Runner: Time to Live&nbsp;</em>would have arrived in 2027 across PC and current-gen machines, as well as the next generation of PlayStation and Xbox consoles (<a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/full-next-gen-xbox-reportedly-set-for-2027-xbox-branded-gaming-handheld-due-out-later-in-2025" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">assuming there is one</a> where Xbox is concerned, of course).</p>

<p>Insider's report says that the project would have cost around $45 million before music, testing, and other expenses, and that&nbsp;<em>Blade Runner&nbsp;</em>rights holder Alcon Entertainment is the reason the game was canceled, although the report doesn't go into specifics "to protect the sources of the information".</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/supermassive-games-directive-8020.jpg?itok=HU0M9uON 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/supermassive-games-directive-8020.jpg?itok=LVIo0EiG 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Supermassive Games is currently working on sci-fi adventure&nbsp;<em>Directive 8020</em>.</figcaption></figure><p>As for what's next for Supermassive Games, the studio is currently working on the sci-fi adventure&nbsp;<em>Directive 8020</em>, which looks closer to the studio's traditional output, although it will also feature stealth sections and other more interactive gameplay trappings.</p>

<p>Supermassive is also the developer on <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/little-nightmares-3-delayed" rel="nofollow">Bandai Namco's&nbsp;<em>Little Nightmares 3</em></a>, which will be the first game in the series not to be developed by original studio Tarsier.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Very Best Cosplay From WonderCon 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/wondercon-cosplay-gallery-arcane-marvel-rivals-1851777633</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-very-best-cosplay-from-wondercon-2025.1172487/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/wondercon-cosplay-gallery-arcane-marvel-rivals-1851777633<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><figure id="" data-id="34fda6aec1aaddf7fc3ac1ab7398c4b4" data-recommend-id="image://34fda6aec1aaddf7fc3ac1ab7398c4b4" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Three cosplayers from Wondercon 2025." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Three cosplayers from Wondercon 2025." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Photo<!-- -->: <!-- -->Mineralblu / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="34fda6aec1aaddf7fc3ac1ab7398c4b4" data-recommend-id="image://34fda6aec1aaddf7fc3ac1ab7398c4b4" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Three cosplayers from Wondercon 2025." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>The comic, sci-fi and movie convention WonderCon has been running since 1987, an extraordinary 37 years of gathering in various cities of California—currently Anaheim—celebrating the best of nerd culture.</p><p>As ever, photographer and filmmaker Mineralblu was there for <em>Kotaku</em>, taking stunning photographs of the best cosplay on the show floor. These galleries provide such an excellent insight into what’s dominating the zeitgeist, and this collection suggests that <em>Elden Ring</em> is finally loosening its grip. <em>Marvel Rivals</em> is represented once again, while <em>Arcane</em> still isn’t going anywhere. And it’s brilliant to see some left-field inclusions, especially <em>Severance</em> and <em>Skeleton Crew</em>.</p><p>Take a look at the video below to see even more of the most impressive cosplay from the convention, and then click on to our gallery of 20 of the best.</p></div></div><div><figure id="" data-id="8cba6a130cdf24bf963c60f09a016e5b" data-recommend-id="image://8cba6a130cdf24bf963c60f09a016e5b" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A cosplayer at Wondercon 2025." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A cosplayer at Wondercon 2025." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Photo<!-- -->: <!-- -->Mineralblu / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="8cba6a130cdf24bf963c60f09a016e5b" data-recommend-id="image://8cba6a130cdf24bf963c60f09a016e5b" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A cosplayer at Wondercon 2025." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure></div><div><figure id="" data-id="92a12f4bf805c020bdaf8ee486820e9b" data-recommend-id="image://92a12f4bf805c020bdaf8ee486820e9b" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A cosplayer at Wondercon 2025." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A cosplayer at Wondercon 2025." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Photo<!-- -->: <!-- -->Mineralblu / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="92a12f4bf805c020bdaf8ee486820e9b" data-recommend-id="image://92a12f4bf805c020bdaf8ee486820e9b" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A cosplayer at Wondercon 2025." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure></div><div><figure id="" data-id="a81bfbf2d4f3a05d2ee2fc0cf1e6f515" data-recommend-id="image://a81bfbf2d4f3a05d2ee2fc0cf1e6f515" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A cosplayer at Wondercon 2025." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A cosplayer at Wondercon 2025." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Photo<!-- -->: <!-- -->Mineralblu / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="a81bfbf2d4f3a05d2ee2fc0cf1e6f515" data-recommend-id="image://a81bfbf2d4f3a05d2ee2fc0cf1e6f515" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A cosplayer at Wondercon 2025." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure></div><div><figure id="" data-id="82b4af7a2715250d6a4ad772ed7c0ad8" data-recommend-id="image://82b4af7a2715250d6a4ad772ed7c0ad8" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A cosplayer at Wondercon 2025." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A cosplayer at Wondercon 2025." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Photo<!-- -->: <!-- -->Mineralblu / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="82b4af7a2715250d6a4ad772ed7c0ad8" data-recommend-id="image://82b4af7a2715250d6a4ad772ed7c0ad8" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A cosplayer at Wondercon 2025." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure></div><div><figure id="" data-id="735255574d663151faa78a907444d6c2" data-recommend-id="image://735255574d663151faa78a907444d6c2" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A cosplayer at Wondercon 2025." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A cosplayer at Wondercon 2025." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Photo<!-- -->: <!-- -->Mineralblu / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="735255574d663151faa78a907444d6c2" data-recommend-id="image://735255574d663151faa78a907444d6c2" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A cosplayer at Wondercon 2025." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure></div><div><figure id="" data-id="2faa34838ed944e5ad4bcbe324a6a767" data-recommend-id="image://2faa34838ed944e5ad4bcbe324a6a767" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A cosplayer at Wondercon 2025." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A cosplayer at Wondercon 2025." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Photo<!-- -->: <!-- -->Mineralblu / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="2faa34838ed944e5ad4bcbe324a6a767" data-recommend-id="image://2faa34838ed944e5ad4bcbe324a6a767" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A cosplayer at Wondercon 2025." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure></div><div><figure id="" data-id="1da4eea6847b4b7ba787ae2b94c3eb31" data-recommend-id="image://1da4eea6847b4b7ba787ae2b94c3eb31" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A cosplayer at Wondercon 2025." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A cosplayer at Wondercon 2025." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Photo<!-- -->: <!-- -->Mineralblu / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="1da4eea6847b4b7ba787ae2b94c3eb31" data-recommend-id="image://1da4eea6847b4b7ba787ae2b94c3eb31" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A cosplayer at Wondercon 2025." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure></div><div><figure id="" data-id="c3abe2657d49d1585d528d1493281f23" data-recommend-id="image://c3abe2657d49d1585d528d1493281f23" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A cosplayer at Wondercon 2025." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A cosplayer at Wondercon 2025." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Photo<!-- -->: <!-- -->Mineralblu / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="c3abe2657d49d1585d528d1493281f23" data-recommend-id="image://c3abe2657d49d1585d528d1493281f23" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A cosplayer at Wondercon 2025." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure></div><div><figure id="" data-id="de52857940afa17fe2469448dde270c7" data-recommend-id="image://de52857940afa17fe2469448dde270c7" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A cosplayer at Wondercon 2025." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A cosplayer at Wondercon 2025." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Photo<!-- -->: <!-- -->Mineralblu / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="de52857940afa17fe2469448dde270c7" data-recommend-id="image://de52857940afa17fe2469448dde270c7" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A cosplayer at Wondercon 2025." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure></div><div><figure id="" data-id="49bec8220559234de6abd74f2cc99c61" data-recommend-id="image://49bec8220559234de6abd74f2cc99c61" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A cosplayer at Wondercon 2025." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A cosplayer at Wondercon 2025." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Photo<!-- -->: <!-- -->Mineralblu / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="49bec8220559234de6abd74f2cc99c61" data-recommend-id="image://49bec8220559234de6abd74f2cc99c61" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A cosplayer at Wondercon 2025." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure></div><div><figure id="" data-id="5cb08dae90493ecea719f5a0c9006c4c" data-recommend-id="image://5cb08dae90493ecea719f5a0c9006c4c" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A cosplayer at Wondercon 2025." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A cosplayer at Wondercon 2025." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Photo<!-- -->: <!-- -->Mineralblu / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="5cb08dae90493ecea719f5a0c9006c4c" data-recommend-id="image://5cb08dae90493ecea719f5a0c9006c4c" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A cosplayer at Wondercon 2025." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure></div><div><figure id="" data-id="a30b9c9b8df8386efd56ae1cf273f82f" data-recommend-id="image://a30b9c9b8df8386efd56ae1cf273f82f" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A cosplayer at Wondercon 2025." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A cosplayer at Wondercon 2025." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Photo<!-- -->: <!-- -->Mineralblu / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="a30b9c9b8df8386efd56ae1cf273f82f" data-recommend-id="image://a30b9c9b8df8386efd56ae1cf273f82f" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A cosplayer at Wondercon 2025." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure></div><div><figure id="" data-id="f8e8a4f147a1426b13f86bf81ff12cbb" data-recommend-id="image://f8e8a4f147a1426b13f86bf81ff12cbb" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A cosplayer at Wondercon 2025." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A cosplayer at Wondercon 2025." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Photo<!-- -->: <!-- -->Mineralblu / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="f8e8a4f147a1426b13f86bf81ff12cbb" data-recommend-id="image://f8e8a4f147a1426b13f86bf81ff12cbb" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A cosplayer at Wondercon 2025." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure></div><div><figure id="" data-id="8c82d0b5196bb97666a86fc577256565" data-recommend-id="image://8c82d0b5196bb97666a86fc577256565" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A cosplayer at Wondercon 2025." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A cosplayer at Wondercon 2025." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Photo<!-- -->: <!-- -->Mineralblu / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="8c82d0b5196bb97666a86fc577256565" data-recommend-id="image://8c82d0b5196bb97666a86fc577256565" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A cosplayer at Wondercon 2025." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure></div><div><figure id="" data-id="f44d6fd3e9d3f3249a4dafdc8af1d04a" data-recommend-id="image://f44d6fd3e9d3f3249a4dafdc8af1d04a" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A cosplayer at Wondercon 2025." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A cosplayer at Wondercon 2025." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Photo<!-- -->: <!-- -->Mineralblu / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="f44d6fd3e9d3f3249a4dafdc8af1d04a" data-recommend-id="image://f44d6fd3e9d3f3249a4dafdc8af1d04a" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A cosplayer at Wondercon 2025." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure></div><div><figure id="" data-id="a3042e5e620315a893b5bc47823dffd5" data-recommend-id="image://a3042e5e620315a893b5bc47823dffd5" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A cosplayer at Wondercon 2025." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A cosplayer at Wondercon 2025." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Photo<!-- -->: <!-- -->Mineralblu / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="a3042e5e620315a893b5bc47823dffd5" data-recommend-id="image://a3042e5e620315a893b5bc47823dffd5" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A cosplayer at Wondercon 2025." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure></div><div><figure id="" data-id="e8145623b0405d13960a93ceb30166cf" data-recommend-id="image://e8145623b0405d13960a93ceb30166cf" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A cosplayer at Wondercon 2025." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A cosplayer at Wondercon 2025." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Photo<!-- -->: <!-- -->Mineralblu / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="e8145623b0405d13960a93ceb30166cf" data-recommend-id="image://e8145623b0405d13960a93ceb30166cf" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A cosplayer at Wondercon 2025." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure></div><div><figure id="" data-id="9559806263e4f4a5e5528c56ed58cafc" data-recommend-id="image://9559806263e4f4a5e5528c56ed58cafc" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A cosplayer at Wondercon 2025." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A cosplayer at Wondercon 2025." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Photo<!-- -->: <!-- -->Mineralblu / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="9559806263e4f4a5e5528c56ed58cafc" data-recommend-id="image://9559806263e4f4a5e5528c56ed58cafc" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A cosplayer at Wondercon 2025." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokemon Trading Card Game Pocket ‘Celestial Guardians’ expansion launches April 30]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/pokemon-trading-card-game-pocket-celestial-guardians-expansion-launches-april-30</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pokemon-trading-card-game-pocket-%E2%80%98celestial-guardians%E2%80%99-expansion-launches-april-30.1172475/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/pokemon-trading-card-game-pocket-celestial-guardians-expansion-launches-april-30<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/mobile/smartphone">Smartphone</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Featuring Solgaleo, Lunala, Rowlet, Litten, Popplio, and more.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><em><a title="Games > Pokemon Trading Card Game Pocket [6 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/pokemon-trading-card-game-pocket">Pokemon Trading Card Game Pocket</a></em> expansion “Celestial Guardians” will launch on <a href="https://www.timeanddate.com/worldclock/fixedtime.html?iso=20250430T0600" target="_blank">April 29 at 11:00 p.m. PT / April 30 at 2:00 a.m. ET</a>, <a title="Companies > The Pokemon Company [411 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/the-pokemon-company">The Pokemon Company</a> announced. <span id="more-961078"></span></p><p>The description reads: “In Celestial Guardians, players can discover Pokémon as seen in the <em><a title="Series > Pokemon [44 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/series/pokemon">Pokemon</a> Sun</em> and <em>Pokemon Moon</em> video games, including the Alola region’s first partner Pokemon: Rowlet, Litten, and Popplio. ‘Celestial Guardians’ will feature two new digital booster packs spotlighting the Legendary Pokemon Solgaleo and <a title="Platforms > Luna [60 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/cloud/luna">Luna</a>la. In addition to the new expansion, players can look forward to a new drop event, special missions, and new accessories to flaunt their favorite cards.”</p><p><em>Pokemon Trading Card Game Pocket</em> is available now for iOS via <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/pok%C3%A9mon-tcg-pocket/id6479970832" rel="noopener" target="_blank">App Store</a> and Android via <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=jp.pokemon.pokemontcgp" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Google Play</a>.</p><p>Watch a trailer for the expansion below.</p><h2><span>Expansion “Celestial Guardians” Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><iframe title="Pokémon TCG Pocket: Celestial Guardians | Coming April 30!" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/szw-wAp7irI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe title="【公式】『ポケポケ』拡張パック「双天の守護者」" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9uzlnIjaLdA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hotel Architect launches in Early Access on May 20]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/hotel-architect-launches-in-early-access-on-may-20</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hotel-architect-launches-in-early-access-on-may-20.1172469/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/hotel-architect-launches-in-early-access-on-may-20<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Hotel construction and <a title="Genres > Management [28 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/management">management</a> <a title="Genres > Simulation [720 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/simulation">simulation game</a> <em><a title="Games > Hotel Architect [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/hotel-architect">Hotel Architect</a></em> will launch in Early Access for <a title="Platforms > PC [22,979 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1602000/Hotel_Architect/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> on May 20, publisher <a title="Companies > Wired Productions [88 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/wired-productions">Wired Productions</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Pathos Interactive [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/pathos-interactive">Pathos Interactive</a> announced. It will be priced at $19.99 / £15.99 / €19.99 with a 20 percent discount running for the first two weeks of release. The final pre-launch playtest is available now. <span id="more-960751"></span></p><p>Here at the latest details:</p><blockquote><p>The creatively chaotic <em>Hotel Architect</em> is ready to invite players to design and manage their dream hotels when it enters Early Access. Published by Wired Productions and developed by Pathos Interactive, discover what it takes to step into the shoes of a hotel owner—juggling an array of tasks and responsibilities to meet the needs of demanding guests.</p><p><em>Hotel Architect</em> invites players to unleash their creative freedom in the ultimate hotel construction and management simulation game.</p><p>Key Features coming to Early Access include:</p><ul><li>Expand across multiple locations each with their own scenario and sandbox modes.</li><li>A wide variety of staff to manage, each with their own unique set of attributes.</li><li>Up to six guest types, with diverse preferences, available to welcome into your hotel.</li><li>Freely select from several zones to design exquisite hotels to impress guests and critics.</li><li>Design a detailed layout and watch as your construction workers lay the foundations to bring your dream hotel to life.</li><li>Create your own characters and watch as they appear in-game using the “character creator” tool. Choose from any role including the guests, staff and service workers.</li></ul><!-- AD: content -->
        </blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Early Access Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Hotel Architect | Release Date Announcement Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/tSDVDdtusZ8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Until Dawn developer reportedly cancels Blade Runner game set for PS6, next Xbox]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/until-dawn-developer-reportedly-cancels-blade-runner-game-set-for-ps6-next-xbox</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/until-dawn-developer-reportedly-cancels-blade-runner-game-set-for-ps6-next-xbox.1172463/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/until-dawn-developer-reportedly-cancels-blade-runner-game-set-for-ps6-next-xbox<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Blade-Runner-cover.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Warner Bros</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Supermassive Games - known for releases such as Until Dawn and <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/the-quarry">The Quarry</a> - has reportedly cancelled an unannounced <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/blade-runner">Blade Runner</a> game.</p>
<p>The project was titled Blade Runner: Time To Live, and according to <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WPUISqX5T6E">Insider Gaming</a>, it was going to be a "character focused, cinematic, action adventure" release, poised to be launched across PC, PS5 and Xbox Series X/S, as well as on next generation Xbox and PlayStation systems. Reportedly, it was a single-player game, slated for a 2027 debut.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="The 7 Best Game Franchise Revivals Ever" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/B1XHifp5_Ao?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>The 7 Best Game Franchise Revivals Ever</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/B1XHifp5_Ao?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/B1XHifp5_Ao?autoplay=1" title="The 7 Best Game Franchise Revivals Ever">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>The 7 Best Game Franchise Revivals Ever. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=B1XHifp5_Ao" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>The report claims the player would be the only Blade Runner in 2065, and the game's campaign would feature a 10-12 hour "compelling" story, which would blend "the philosophical themes of Blade Runner with kinetic action-adventure gameplay".</p>
<p>This story would see players taking on the role of So-Lange, the report states. So-Lange is a vintage model Nexus-6 "inexplicably still alive well beyond your limited lifespan".</p>
<p>Documentation seen by Insider Gaming reads: "Journey from the teeming undercity of New Zurich 2065 to the eerie remnants of the forgotten world beyond... Under orders to retire Rev, the mysterious and ruthless leader of an underground replicant network, you are betrayed and left for dead in a brutally hostile environment."</p>
<p>Blade Runner: Time to Live was said to have entered pre-production in September 2024, with pre-production then expected to wrap up in March 2025. The end of prototyping, meanwhile, was set for this September.</p>
<p>On the cost side of things, Blade Runner: Time to Live's development budget was reported to be in the region of $45m, with $9m of this expected to cover external performance capture and acting talent.</p>
<p>The game was ultimately cancelled, reportedly towards the end of last year. As to why, that's allegedly due to Alcon Entertainment, who is the owner of the Blade Runner rights, although no further details were provided at this time.</p>
<p>While we may never know what could have been, according to one source, Blade Runner: Time to Live was "rather impressive".</p>
<p>Next up from Supermassive Games will be the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/directive-8020-is-a-notable-upgrade-to-the-dark-pictures-anthologys-formula">long-awaited next Dark Pictures Anthology game, Directive 8020</a>. This one's set in space, features Bond and Marvel star Lashana Lynch, and has been in development for some time.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Unreal Engine 5 Zorah Tech Demo NvRTX Branch Pushes the RTX 5090 to Its Limits, Dropping to 13 FPS at Native 4K Resolution in Certain Scenarios]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/unreal-engine-5-zorah-tech-demo-13-fps-rtx-5090/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/unreal-engine-5-zorah-tech-demo-nvrtx-branch-pushes-the-rtx-5090-to-its-limits-dropping-to-13-fps-at-native-4k-resolution-in-certain-scenarios.1172451/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/unreal-engine-5-zorah-tech-demo-13-fps-rtx-5090/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The NvRTX branch of the impressive Unreal Engine 5 Zorah tech demo sports some advanced features that even the most powerful GPU on the market cannot handle at native 4K resolution properly.</p>
<p>As shown in a new test video shared by Compusemble, advanced features like Mega Geometry, ReSTiR Global Illumination and Path Tracing and more can tank performance at native 4K resolution even on an<a href="https://wccftech.com/review/geforce-rtx-5090-founders-edition-gamers-pricey-dream/"> RTX 5090 GPU,</a> the most powerful GPU currently available on the market. In some scenarios, the demo runs at a whopping 13 FPS, proving how gaming hardware still isn't ready for some of the advanced RTX features NVIDIA has been working on. Things get slightly better with NVIDIA DLSS, and it's only in Performance mode that the RTX 5090 can run the demo at above 30 FPS in the same scenario that tanked performance at native 4K resolution.</p>
<p><iframe title="Zorah Demo: NvRTX Branch vs Stock UE5 - NvRTX Can Run As Low As 13FPS on 5090 Depending on the Scene" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/zdbjsO8k8mM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Even though the Unreal Engine 5 Zorah demo cannot be run at acceptable performance at native 4K resolution, there's no denying that some of the technology is impressive. Among the new features that have yet to be implemented in games is RTX Neural Rendering, which can quickly create a neural representation of thousands of textures to save VRAM and RAM much more than the currently used compression tech. More information on Neural Rendering can be found on NVIDIA's <a href="https://developer.nvidia.com/blog/get-started-with-neural-rendering-using-nvidia-rtx-kit/">official website.</a></p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[11 bit studios Announces Frostpunk Remake Frostpunk: 1886 for 2027]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/frostpunk-1886-announced-2027</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/11-bit-studios-announces-frostpunk-remake-frostpunk-1886-for-2027.1172448/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/frostpunk-1886-announced-2027<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Developer and publisher 11 bit studios has announced&nbsp;<em>Frostpunk: 1886</em>, a remake of the original&nbsp;<em>Frostpunk&nbsp;</em>in Unreal Engine 5 (and, despite what the title suggests, nothing to do with&nbsp;<em>The Order: 1886</em>).</p>

<p>In an announcement <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/3645160/view/545607485799530656" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">post</a> on Steam, 11 bit says the aim with&nbsp;<em>Frostpunk: 1886&nbsp;</em>is to "recreate the experience of the original game in [Unreal Engine 5]", and that the project is part of an effort to "further expand upon&nbsp;<em>Frostpunk</em>" away from the original game's now-defunct Liquid Engine.</p>

<p>This is almost certainly the new&nbsp;<em>Frostpunk&nbsp;</em>game to which 11 bit referred in its <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/new-frostpunk-game-2027-11-bit-studios" rel="nofollow">most recent financial summary</a>; the studio already confirmed a 2027 release for that project, so unless there's another one in the works for the same year, it's most probably&nbsp;<em>Frostpunk: 1886</em>.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/frostpunk-1886-remake-original-game-city-view.jpg?itok=R2Vt-VH2 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/frostpunk-1886-remake-original-game-city-view.jpg?itok=jiUQUZya 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Frostpunk: 1886&nbsp;</em>aims to reimagine the original (pictured here) with new visuals and gameplay mechanics.</figcaption></figure><p>According to 11 bit,&nbsp;<em>Frostpunk: 1886&nbsp;</em>will feature "improved visuals, higher resolution, and all the other possibilities Unreal has to offer", serving as a "great introduction to the world of&nbsp;<em>Frostpunk</em>" but also the perfect game for "die-hard fans".</p>

<p>However, the project won't just be a rebuilt version of&nbsp;<em>Frostpunk</em>. Instead, it'll feature "tons of new content, new mechanics, new events, technologies, and buildings", as well as a totally new path, Purpose, to go alongside Faith and Order.</p>

<p>In addition,&nbsp;<em>Frostpunk: 1886&nbsp;</em>will support expansion via DLC in future, as well as official modding support, which is something that's <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/frostpunk-2-modding-tool-at-launch" rel="nofollow">available for the second</a>&nbsp;<em>Frostpunk&nbsp;</em>but not for the first due to engine limitations.</p>

<p>You can check out the very brief teaser trailer for&nbsp;<em>Frostpunk: 1886&nbsp;</em>below. It doesn't give very much away, and it's really more of a mood piece than a full trailer, but hey, it might help you to get excited for the game.</p>




<p><em>Frostpunk: 1886&nbsp;</em>is due to land on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3645160/Frostpunk_1886/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC via Steam</a> sometime in 2027. No console release has been announced yet.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GALIX: New Horizons ‘Gameplay’ trailer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/galix-new-horizons-gameplay-trailer</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/galix-new-horizons-%E2%80%98gameplay%E2%80%99-trailer.1172442/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/galix-new-horizons-gameplay-trailer<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div role="main">
  
  <article>

    
<header>

  <div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Uncover the secrets of a world struggling to rebuild after catastrophe.</span>
      </p></div>

  

</header>  

<!-- Moved from templates/posts/default.php -->

    <div><p><a title="Companies > Magicfish Games [12 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/magicfish-games">Magicfish Games</a> has released a new gameplay trailer for science-fiction <a title="Genres > Open-World [618 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/open-world">open-world</a> <a title="Genres > Action RPG [1,589 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg/action-rpg">action RPG</a> <em><a title="Games > GALIX: New Horizons [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/galix-new-horizons">GALIX: New Horizons</a></em>. <span id="more-961062"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2862770/GALIX_NewHorizons/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam page</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>In a distant future where human civilization has crumbled, Earth has become a pristine new world teeming with life. In this open-world ARPG, play as the the courageous Hailey and set out on a journey filled with mystery and <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,229 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a>. Begin your own fantastical journey as you chase the unknown.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Setting Out on a Fantastical Journey With a Mission</strong> – Billions of years later, humanity’s advanced civilization lies in ruins, and Earth has transformed into a pristine world with new ecosystems. In this mysterious and ever-changing world, a courageous girl sets out on an exciting adventure to find a lost friend from the old world.</li><li><strong>Explore the Vast World</strong> – In the game, you’ll explore a vast world filled with diverse landscapes. From rejuvenated lands pulsing with ancient cosmic energy, to the stunning Rainbow Mountains, and onward to the mystical <a title="Companies > crim [23 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/crim">Crim</a>son Realms sustained by elemental energies, you’ll encounter a wide variety of ecosystems to marvel at.</li><li><strong>A Rich Gaming <a title="Companies > Experience [211 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/experience">Experience</a></strong> – Players will delve into several unique biomes, reveal the legends hidden in NPCs around the world, and work side-by-side with the inhabitants to build a thriving new world and bring the planet back to life.</li><li><strong><a title="Series > Persona [88 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/series/persona">Persona</a>lized Gameplay</strong> – In the game, you will have the opportunity to deeply explore the vast world, from the land of rebirth containing the original divine power of the universe, to the magnificent and gorgeous mountains of ten thousand colors, to the Underworld Crimson Realm, which nourishes the divine power of the meta-world to nurture, and enjoy the diversity of ecological environments.</li><li><strong>Experience Intense and Thrilling Battles Firsthand</strong> – Players have the freedom to switch between different long-range or close-combat weapons, demonstrating their prowess in tough and ever-changing fights. Specially designed combat techniques for each boss offer players diverse challenges and a rewarding feeling of success.</li></ul><!-- AD: content -->
        </blockquote><p><em>GALIX: New Horizons</em> will be available for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [9,331 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a> and <a title="Platforms > PC [22,979 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2862770/GALIX_NewHorizons/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a>. A release date has yet to be announced.</p><p>Watch the trailer below.</p><h2><span>Gameplay Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="GALIX: New Horizons Trailer【ARPG】『星の旅：億万年の絆』PV公開🌌 Steamウィッシュリスト募集中！" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/TaNGUf4I474?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div>

        
    
  </article>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[FANTASY LIFE i: The Girl Who Steals Time ‘Paladin Life Trial’ gameplay]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/fantasy-life-i-the-girl-who-steals-time-paladin-life-trial-gameplay</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fantasy-life-i-the-girl-who-steals-time-%E2%80%98paladin-life-trial%E2%80%99-gameplay.1172436/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/fantasy-life-i-the-girl-who-steals-time-paladin-life-trial-gameplay<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>12 minutes of new footage, this time in French.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > LEVEL-5 [770 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/level-5">LEVEL-5</a> and developer <a title="Companies > LEVEL-5 Osaka Office [20 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/level-5/level-5-osaka-office">LEVEL-5 Osaka Office</a> have released a 12-minute gameplay video for social slow-life <a title="Genres > RPG [17,187 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg">RPG</a> <em><a title="Games > FANTASY LIFE i: The Girl Who Steals Time [20 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/fantasy-life-i-the-girl-who-steals-time">FANTASY LIFE i: The Girl Who Steals Time</a></em> dubbed “Paladin Life Trial.” <span id="more-961059"></span></p><p><em>FANTASY LIFE i: The Girl Who Steals Time</em> is due out for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [9,331 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [7,098 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,930 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch [16,996 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [22,979 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2993780/FANTASY_LIFE_i_The_Girl_Who_Steals_Time/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> on May 21. It will support English, Japanese, Korean, Traditional Chinese, Simplified Chinese, French, Italian, German, and Spanish language options. Digital pre-orders opened <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2025/03/fantasy-life-i-the-girl-who-steals-time-digital-pre-orders-now-available-for-ps5-ps4-xbox-series-and-pc">earlier today</a>. Read more about the game <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2025/02/fantasy-life-i-the-girl-who-steals-time-launches-may-21-for-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-switch-and-pc">here</a>.</p><p>Watch the footage below.</p><h2><span>Paladin Life Trial Gameplay</span></h2><p><iframe title="Gameplay d'entraînement des carrières (Paladin) - FANTASY LIFE i : La voleuse de temps" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/KOYLafoEmMI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Discord names former Activision Blizzard and King exec as its new CEO]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/discord-names-former-activision-blizzard-and-king-exec-as-its-new-ceo</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/discord-names-former-activision-blizzard-and-king-exec-as-its-new-ceo.1172433/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/discord-names-former-activision-blizzard-and-king-exec-as-its-new-ceo<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Former Activision Blizzard vice chairman and King Digital Entertainment president, Humam Sakhnini, has been named the new CEO of Discord.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">It's a notable shift for the voice, video, and text communication platform, which is used by over 200 million monthly active users—including a litany of video game developers and communities.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Sakhnini has been appointed to eventually turn Discord into a public company. He'll also help the platform continue refocusing on its "gaming roots" while exploring the opportunities presented by "advertising, micro-transactions, and providing social infrastructure to game developers."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Sakhnini will officially step into the role on April 28, 2025. His soon-to-be predecessor, Discord co-founder and long-serving CEO Jason Citron, will remain on the company's board of directors and become an advisor to the CEO.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Citron's fellow Discord co-founder Stanislav Vishnevskiy will remain chief technology officer.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://discord.com/blog/passing-the-torch">In a lengthy message shared with Discord workers</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, Citron said it was essential the company appoint a new leader from a "position of strength."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"I am thrilled to welcome Humam Sakhnini as the next CEO of Discord.&nbsp;After spending significant time together, I have complete confidence in his ability to lead us into the future alongside Stan and the rest of our executive team," he wrote.</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/nintendo-tells-customers-in-japan-to-expect-switch-2-hardware-shortage" target="_self" data-discover="true">Nintendo tells customers in Japan to expect Switch 2 hardware shortage at launch</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Humam brings more than 15 years of experience in the gaming industry, including at Activision Blizzard where he served as Chief Strategy Officer helping guide franchises like World of Warcraft and Call of Duty. He later took over from the founders of King to delight the players of their live service games while substantially growing the King business in the public market."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">That latter detail feels particularly notable given Citron explained Sakhnini was hired to "someday" take Discord public.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Outlining his vision for the platform, Sakhnini described Discord as a "foundational part of the gaming ecosystem" and pledged to scale the business while remaining true to the company's core vision.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"What Jason and Discord co-founder and CTO Stan Vishnevskiy have built is truly remarkable — a platform with an undeniable product-market fit where hundreds of millions of people connect around their passion for gaming and shared interests," </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://discord.com/blog/discord-appoints-new-ceo-humam-sakhnini">he added in a separate announcement</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"I look forward to working with Stan and Discord's talented team to scale our business while staying true to the company's core mission and the special connection it has with player communities. We're still at the beginning of gaming's impact on entertainment and culture, and Discord is perfectly positioned to play a central role in that future."</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/devolver-cuts-40-percent-of-workforce-at-reigns-developer-nerial" target="_self" data-discover="true">Devolver cuts 40 percent of workforce at Reigns developer Nerial</a></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">News Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer news editor Chris Kerr is an award-winning journalist and reporter with over a decade of experience in the game industry. His byline has appeared in notable print and digital publications including Edge, Stuff, Wireframe, International Business Times, and&nbsp;</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="http://pocketgamer.biz/">PocketGamer.biz</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. Throughout his career, Chris has covered major industry events including GDC, PAX Australia, Gamescom, Paris Games Week, and Develop Brighton. He has featured on the judging panel at The Develop Star Awards on multiple occasions and appeared on BBC Radio 5 Live to discuss breaking news.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch 2 Pre-Order Demand Outpaces Nintendo's Expectations And Supply]]></title>
            <link>https://gameinformer.com/2025/04/23/nintendo-switch-2-pre-order-demand-outpaces-nintendos-expectations-and-supply</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-switch-2-pre-order-demand-outpaces-nintendos-expectations-and-supply.1172430/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://gameinformer.com/2025/04/23/nintendo-switch-2-pre-order-demand-outpaces-nintendos-expectations-and-supply<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p>After a <a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="884f35ab-23fc-4898-a479-26bb82edbd6b" href="https://gameinformer.com/2025/04/04/trump-tariff-plans-delay-nintendo-switch-2-pre-order-date">several-week delay</a>, Nintendo Switch 2 pre-orders are <a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="0dea30b2-7e9b-43f4-a82e-9a35679b42ca" href="https://gameinformer.com/2025/04/18/nintendo-switch-2-pre-orders-begin-april-24-in-us-with-updated-pricing-for-certain">set to kick off tonight in the United States</a>. While hundreds of thousands of hopeful gamers will likely be refreshing the websites of <a href="https://buff.ly/340n4Ou">Best Buy</a>, <a href="https://buff.ly/BCrRzOM">Target</a>, and <a href="https://buff.ly/dfdT51Z">Walmart</a>, hoping to be lucky enough to successfully push an order through and secure their piece of the first Switch 2 wave, Nintendo also <a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="0c942683-aa0d-42df-b11a-12e2b25a91dd" href="https://gameinformer.com/nintendo-direct/2025/04/02/heres-how-to-pre-order-a-nintendo-switch-2">asked interested players to register their My Nintendo accounts</a> as interested in pre-ordering the upcoming system to enter into a lottery. However, Nintendo President Shuntaro Furukawa took to Nintendo's Japanese social media accounts to share some bad news regarding the lottery system.</p>

<p>According to a post shared on Nintendo's Japanese X account, Nintendo received 2.2 million interested players in Japan alone. If that number is truly representative of the number of players who want to purchase a Switch 2 in Japan, it would far exceed the initial Japanese sales numbers of the Switch 1, which, according to <a href="https://venturebeat.com/games/nintendo-sells-313700-switch-consoles-in-japan-over-launch-weekend/"><em>VentureBeat,</em></a> reached just over 313,000 units in its first weekend. In the console's first month, Nintendo sold 2.74 million units worldwide, meaning that the 2.2 million Japanese registrations nearly reaches that number on its own.</p>

<p><iframe allow="autoplay" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/jqQG2xco8eI" width="640"></iframe></p>

<p>According to Furukawa, Nintendo cannot fulfill all of those requests at launch. However, if you register through the My Nintendo Store and are not selected to purchase during the first wave, you will have another chance once the company can replenish its supply.&nbsp;</p>

<p>You can see the full translation of Furukawa's post from X below.</p>

<div>
<p>Hello, this is Furukawa. We have been procuring many materials and proceeding with production in advance so that we can deliver the Nintendo Switch 2 to you. On April 2nd, we announced details about the Nintendo Switch 2 and started accepting applications for the lottery sale on the My Nintendo Store. As a result, we received an extremely large number of applications, approximately 2.2 million people in Japan alone. However, this number far exceeds our expectations, and far exceeds the number of Nintendo Switch 2 consoles that can be delivered from the My Nintendo Store on June 5th. Therefore, unfortunately, we expect that a significant number of customers will not be selected when the winners are announced tomorrow, April 24th.</p>

<p>In order to avoid the trouble of those who were not selected in the first lottery sale having to reapply, My Nintendo Store will automatically carry over those who were not selected in the first lottery sale to the second lottery sale. However, even including the quantity for the second lottery sale, we cannot fulfill all of the applications we received. We deeply apologize for not being able to meet your expectations despite our prior preparations.</p>

<p>In response to this demand, we are currently working on further strengthening our production system. In addition, starting tomorrow, April 24th, game retailers and online stores nationwide will begin accepting pre-orders or lottery sales for the Nintendo Switch 2 console (please check the information of each retailer for details). The console will also continue to be sold at the My Nintendo Store after the release date (more details will be announced at a later date). With the cooperation of retailers, we will continue to ship the console and make efforts to get as many Nintendo Switch 2 consoles as possible into your hands.</p>

<p>We plan to continue producing and shipping a considerable number of Nintendo Switch 2 units in the future. We apologize for the delay in our ability to meet your expectations, and we appreciate your understanding.</p>
</div>

<p>Though Furukawa alludes to it, he doesn't directly say that Nintendo will be unable to fulfill demand through its retail partners. Still, with the company seeing such increased demand in its home country, players worldwide will likely encounter fierce competition and, more than likely, frustration while trying to get their hands on a launch model Switch 2. Nintendo Switch 2 arrives on June 5. For more on the console, you can read our hands-on impressions <a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="2bca940b-8846-4536-bd3c-87ddd37f9549" href="https://gameinformer.com/preview/2025/04/03/hands-on-with-nintendos-next-console">here</a>.</p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ghost Of Yōtei Release Date Set For October, Collector's Edition Revealed]]></title>
            <link>https://gameinformer.com/2025/04/23/ghost-of-yotei-release-date-set-for-october-collectors-edition-revealed</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ghost-of-y%C5%8Dtei-release-date-set-for-october-collectors-edition-revealed.1172424/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://gameinformer.com/2025/04/23/ghost-of-yotei-release-date-set-for-october-collectors-edition-revealed<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p>The follow-up to 2020's <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/review/ghost-of-tsushima/ghost-of-tsushima-review-a-most-honorable-epic">acclaimed Ghost of Tsushima</a>, Ghost of&nbsp;Yōtei has garnered a lot of excitement following its announcement during a PlayStation State of Play livestream last September. The open-world adventure places players in the boots of a new samurai named Atsu 300 years after the events of Ghost of Tsushima. However, developer Sucker Punch Productions largely went quiet following the surprise reveal last year. That changed today, as the studio revealed additional details about Ghost of&nbsp;Yōtei, including the release date.</p>

<p>Players who have been waiting a half-decade to continue exploring Sucker Punch's stunning recreation of feudal Japan can now circle October 2 on their calendars. The game is available in the standard edition for $70, but if you're excited enough to want some bonuses, Sony is also offering a Digital Deluxe Edition as well as a physical Collector's Edition. The Digital Deluxe Edition costs $80 and includes in-game Snake Armor, exclusive armor dye and horse with saddle, a charm, an early unlock of the Traveller's Map, and a sword kit. Meanwhile, the Collector's Edition costs $250 and offers all the Digital Deluxe content (including a digital copy of the game), plus physical items like a sash, a tsuba, art cards, a papercraft ginkgo tree, and a zeni hajiki coin game with pouch.&nbsp;</p>












<article data-embed-button="image_browser_uploader" data-entity-embed-display="view_mode:file.body_default_rendered" data-entity-type="file" data-entity-uuid="b6d2ec8d-f4d7-42fc-b908-5d222cbc6185" data-langcode="en" data-entity-embed-display-settings="[]">





</article><p>The final inclusion of today's Ghost of&nbsp;Yōtei announcements is a trailer called "The Onryō's List." The story goes that 16 years prior to the events of the game, a gang called The&nbsp;Yōtei Six killed her family and pinned her to a burning ginkgo tree, leaving her for dead. She somehow survived the ordeal and what appeared to be a death sentence from the gang of outlaws and she harnessed that strength and motivation to learn how to fight, kill, and hunt. In Ghost of&nbsp;Yōtei, Atsu returns home with a list of the six names of those in The&nbsp;Yōtei Six, with eyes toward vengeance.</p>

<p>Using the same katana that pinned her to the tree, Atsu embarks on a mission to avenge her family. The story plays out in Ezo, which is known as Hokkaido today. New gameplay mechanics will allow the player to understand Atsu's past to fully come to know how much was truly stolen from her by The&nbsp;Yōtei Six. Sucker Punch claims it has built upon and evolved the way players can explore the massive open world, with more freedom and variety on offer than in Ghost of Tsushima. Atsu can choose which member of The&nbsp;Yōtei Six she wants to pursue first, while also claiming bounties, learning new skills, and exploring the natural beauty of northern Japan.</p>

<p>You can see the new trailer released by Sucker Punch Productions below.</p>

<p><iframe allow="autoplay" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/PVBLJYjSAhg" width="640"></iframe></p>

<p>Ghost of&nbsp;Yōtei arrives exclusively on PlayStation 5 on October 2. If you're hungry for more information surrounding the highly anticipated follow-up, Sucker Punch promises to show more in the approach to that date.</p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[F1 25’s Braking Point 3 aims to tell motorsports’ most impactful story]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/04/24/f1-25s-braking-point-3-aims-to-tell-motorsports-most-impactful-story/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/f1-25%E2%80%99s-braking-point-3-aims-to-tell-motorsports%E2%80%99-most-impactful-story.1172418/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/04/24/f1-25s-braking-point-3-aims-to-tell-motorsports-most-impactful-story/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="gp-content-wrapper">

	<article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/Article">

		<meta itemprop="mainEntityOfPage" itemtype="https://schema.org/WebPage" itemscope="" content="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/04/24/f1-25s-braking-point-3-aims-to-tell-motorsports-most-impactful-story/">
		<meta itemprop="headline" content="F1 25’s Braking Point 3 aims to tell motorsports’ most impactful story">			
		
		<meta itemprop="author" content="Dominic L">			
		<meta itemprop="datePublished" content="2025-04-24">
		<meta itemprop="dateModified" content="2025-04-24">
		
		
		
		
											
																		
		<div itemprop="text">
			
			<p>F1 25 is just around the corner – OK, maybe it’s a chicane or chicken – with the latest entry in Codemasters’ long-running motorsport series set to arrive on the 30th of May for PS5, XSX|S and PC. While there are improvements over last year’s entry across the board, from extensive visual updates through to new systems and features that aim to bring the digital version of the sport closer than ever to the real thing, today’s focus is on the returning Braking Point, the F1 series’ central narrative mode, that drops you into the endless drama surrounding the fictional Konnersport team.</p>
<p><iframe title="F1 25 Braking Point 3 Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/D52QfcK9qJc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>A dramatic event sees the Konnersport team thrown into chaos this time around, and given the real-world drama that surrounds F1, they’ve got plenty to draw from, whether its the loss of sponsorship, drivers moving to another team, rookies nope-ing out of contracts on social media, or some wide-reaching breach of the extensive rules and regulations. Either way, things aren’t looking good at Konnersport, and you’re stepping in here to steady the ship.</p>


<p>New to this year’s entry is branching or alternative storylines, and you can decide which of the Konnersport drivers you’re going to take control of, leading to bespoke objectives for that driver, and a unique storyline conclusion. Whether that means there’s a minimum of two endings, or even more, we’re excited to find out, but it’s great to see Codemasters heaping new content into a mode that’s well-liked, but previously hasn’t had the same mileage as the others. It looks as though you’ll want to play through it multiple times to see all of the possibilities, and that’s a great option for those who tire of the long seasons or the high adrenaline and inevitable crashes of competitive online racing.</p>
<p>That’s not where the story ends though, as once you’ve finished with Braking Point you can take your driver into Driver Career or take the position as their Team Principal in My Team, making them the 11th team on the grid. I especially like this, giving the whole storyline some serious longevity and impact, and there’s also some mirroring of Brad Pitt’s forthcoming F1 movie or upcoming Cadillac team, where they will take this 11th spot.</p>


<p>While the on-screen action is at the heart of Braking Point, the team has made some welcome changes to various technical aspects of the mode, including the appearance of an all-new Hard mode to ramp up the challenge, and updating and revising the facial capture for the drivers using Nvidia’s Audio-to-Face technology through the returning interview sequences, making sure that the drama and high-tension moments look better than ever before. It’ll also benefit from all of the other improvements across the board, making it feel as though this is an essential part of the F1 25 experience.</p>
<p>2025 looks to be an amazing year for F1 storylines, and F1 25 hopes to put itself at the centre of that with Braking Point. We can’t wait to finally get our hands on it in the near future.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

			
		</div>

				
		

					
	
			
			

			
						
		<div>

			<h3>Related stories from TSA			
			</h3>
			
				
				
		</div>

	
		
					
 
	
	
				
	</article>

</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Oblivion Remastered New Mods Introduce Stability and Performance Improvements]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/oblivion-remastered-stability-performance-improvements-mods/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/oblivion-remastered-new-mods-introduce-stability-and-performance-improvements.1172415/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/oblivion-remastered-stability-performance-improvements-mods/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>A couple of Oblivion Remastered mods shared online a few hours ago introduce stability and performance improvements to the game, allowing those with more dated systems to run the game with fewer technical issues.</p>
<p>The No More VRAM Leaks Crashes mod, which was released today by SmokerNaruto on <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/oblivionremastered/mods/399?tab=description" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nexus Mods</a>, is a modified Unreal Engine 5 configuration file that caps texture streaming to the user's GPU VRAM and disables ray tracing and Lumen to prevent crashes on GPUs with lower VRAM capacity, like 4 and 6 GB. However, improvements for 8 GB VRAM GPUs are also expected, so this mod is definitely worth a try for those who are having trouble running the game properly.</p>
<p>Much like stability, performance in Oblivion Remastered is not particularly solid on anything&nbsp;<span>other than a top-end machine. As such, the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/oblivionremastered/mods/280?tab=description" target="_blank" rel="noopener">LEGEND FPS patch</a> by NBCoo is another mod that is more than worth a try. It</span> introduces some tweaks that can improve performance without significantly impacting the visuals, such as turning off motion blur, bloom, film grain, and even improving water. Some users, however, have experienced slightly worse performance with this mod, so the experience may vary depending on the system configuration.</p>
<p>After months of rumors and speculation, the Oblivion Remastered was finally confirmed to be real this week with a highly anticipated reveal, which came shortly before the game<a href="https://wccftech.com/the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-remastered-looks-gorgeous-and-its-out-now/"> launched</a> on PC, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series X|S. Developed by Virtuos, the game uses Unreal Engine 5's latest version to deliver improved visuals while keeping the Gamebryo engine for its underlying logic to offer gameplay mostly in line with the original, complete with some choice improvements such as revamped UI and more.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Frostpunk 1886 Is an Unreal Engine 5 Reimagining of the Original Game]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/frostpunk-1886-is-an-unreal-engine-5-reimagining-of-the-original-game/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/frostpunk-1886-is-an-unreal-engine-5-reimagining-of-the-original-game.1172412/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/frostpunk-1886-is-an-unreal-engine-5-reimagining-of-the-original-game/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Today, Polish developer 11 bit studios announced <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3645160/Frostpunk_1886/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Frostpunk 1886</a>, a reimagining of the original Frostpunk game powered by Unreal Engine 5 technology. The game is currently slated to launch at some point in 2027.</p>
<p>11 bit studios plan to provide a much improved visual experience, but they won't stop there. Fans can expect a lot of new content, mechanics, events, technologies, and buildings. There will even be an entirely new Purpose path in addition to the existing Faith and Order paths. Additionally, the switch from the original game's proprietary Liquid Engine to Epic's Unreal Engine 5 will also bring mod support, a feature that franchise fans have requested for years, to Frostpunk 1886.</p>
<p>Interestingly, the studio also expressed a desire to continue making content for both <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/frostpunk-2-day-after-tomorrow/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Frostpunk 2</a> and this reimagining of the original, keeping both updated for a long time.</p>
<p><iframe title="Frostpunk 1886 | New Game Announcement" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/q9fw6_MvSss?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>The studio didn't share any further specifics, but there'll be time for that, given that we will have to wait for a couple of years. Meanwhile, you can refer to <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/frostpunk-chilling-good-stuff/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">our original Frostpunk review</a> (scored 8.5/10 back then):</p>
<p><em>Frostpunk is unforgiving and punishing but that’s why you’ll invest more and more time into it. It takes what you know about city builders and turns it on heads. It’s bleak, and the beautiful design brings life to an otherwise frozen hellscape. The race against the clock is stressful as you try to make sure everyone is alive while the weather gets colder and colder and materials become more and more scarce. Frostpunk is a pleasant surprise that is definitely worth your time if you’re looking for something different and brutally challenging.</em></p>
<p><em>Frostpunk is a challenging city builder where your decisions have dramatic repercussions on the citizens you’re tasked with looking after in a wintery apocalypse. It's a pleasant surprise that is definitely worth your time if you’re looking for something different and brutally challenging.</em></p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>