<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 12:52:47 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sexy Brutale and Rime Developer Tequila Works Cancels Game and Lays Off Staff]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/tequila-works-rime-sexy-brutale-layoffs</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sexy-brutale-and-rime-developer-tequila-works-cancels-game-and-lays-off-staff.1003542/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/tequila-works-rime-sexy-brutale-layoffs<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Rime&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>The Sexy Brutale&nbsp;</em>developer Tequila Works has announced that it's laying off an unspecified number of staff and cancelling an unannounced game.</p>
<p>In <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/tequilaworks_with-deep-regret-we-must-inform-activity-7249379290159452160-vRKo/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">a post on LinkedIn</a>, the studio says it's "restructuring" (which is a pretty common refrain when it comes to layoffs), and that this restructuring operation will "impact...a small number of roles at the studio".</p>
<p>Additionally, Tequila says it's made "the decision to cancel an unannounced game", although naturally, the studio doesn't specify exactly what the game was, so we don't know whether it was a sequel to an existing Tequila Works game or a new IP.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/tequila-works-layoffs-cancellation-the-sexy-brutale.jpg?itok=zME4DD0B 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/tequila-works-layoffs-cancellation-the-sexy-brutale.jpg?itok=7E8iz1cm 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Tequila Works is known for games like&nbsp;<em>The Sexy Brutale&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>Rime</em>.</figcaption></figure><p>Tequila Works closes its brief statement on LinkedIn by saying that it intends to "provide support and guidance to those affected" in what it describes as an "incredibly difficult time".</p>
<p>If you're not familiar with Tequila Works, it's a studio that was founded back in 2009 in Madrid. Its debut game was the side-scrolling zombie cinematic platformer&nbsp;<em>Deadlight</em>, and it followed this up with time loop murder mystery&nbsp;<em>The Sexy Brutale&nbsp;</em>and <i>Ico</i>-style adventure game&nbsp;<em>Rime</em>&nbsp;in 2017.</p>
<p>Following these games, the studio released&nbsp;<em>Gylt&nbsp;</em>in 2020. It was initially a Google Stadia exclusive, but following the untimely (or perhaps that should be timely) <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/google-stadia-shutting-down-in-january">demise of that platform</a>,&nbsp;<em>Gylt&nbsp;</em>eventually <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/gylt-pc-console-release-date">found its way to other platforms</a>.</p>
<p>Tequila's most recent game is the puzzle adventure&nbsp;<em>Song of Nunu: A League of Legends Story</em>, released under the <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/league-of-legends-developer-riot-games-laying-off-530-employees-riot-forge-will-cease">now-sadly-defunct Riot Forge label</a>. It's still got one project in the works; in fact, one of the goals of today's layoffs and cancellation was to "concentrate on the development of only one game".</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/song-of-nunu-tequila-works.jpg?itok=j11mN4To 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/song-of-nunu-tequila-works.jpg?itok=V9Ezaj5Y 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>You may also know Tequila Works' name from&nbsp;<em>Song of Nunu: A League of Legends Story</em>.</figcaption></figure><p>News of these Tequila Works layoffs comes at a <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/this-week-in-gaming-business-june-14th">particularly brutal time</a> for the industry, with many studios experiencing layoffs, project cancellations, and studio closures.</p>
<p>Studios as big as <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/microsoft-gaming-layoffs-september" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Microsoft</a>, <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/playstation-layoffs">Sony</a>, and <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/take-two-interactive-layoffs">Take-Two</a> have laid off hundreds of staff in recent months, and smaller indie outfits like&nbsp;<em>Palia</em>'s <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/palia-developer-singularity-6-layoffs">Singularity 6</a>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<em>Disco Elysium&nbsp;</em>developer <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/disco-elysium-developer-zaum-confirms-game-cancellation-and-layoffs">ZA/UM</a> have also been affected.</p>
<p>Of course, this hasn't prevented C-suite execs at companies like EA <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/ea-ceo-25-million-income-layoffs">raking in huge amounts of cash</a>, nor has it stopped certain ex-industry personnel from making some <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/ex-sony-boss-chris-deering-comments">pretty silly-sounding suggestions</a>.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Every Star Wars TV Show, Ranked From Worst To Best]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/star-wars-tv-show-ranked-disney-plus-mandalorian-1851667009</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/every-star-wars-tv-show-ranked-from-worst-to-best.1003536/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/star-wars-tv-show-ranked-disney-plus-mandalorian-1851667009<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><figure id="" data-id="12aed86ac2c745b93553a08cdb6c8d71" data-recommend-id="image://12aed86ac2c745b93553a08cdb6c8d71" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="An assortment of characters from Star Wars TV shows, including Cassian Andor, Ahsoka, and Darth Maul, are seen against a starry background. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="An assortment of characters from Star Wars TV shows, including Cassian Andor, Ahsoka, and Darth Maul, are seen against a starry background. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="false" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Disney / Lucasfilm / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="12aed86ac2c745b93553a08cdb6c8d71" data-recommend-id="image://12aed86ac2c745b93553a08cdb6c8d71" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="An assortment of characters from Star Wars TV shows, including Cassian Andor, Ahsoka, and Darth Maul, are seen against a starry background. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>Ever since <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/disney-buys-lucasfilm-star-wars-episode-7-coming-in-20-5957508&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/disney-buys-lucasfilm-star-wars-episode-7-coming-in-20-5957508">Disney bought Lucasfilm</a></span> back in 2012, there’s been a steady drip feed of <em>Star Wars</em> television shows airing on Disney+. Before that, we had a few shows set in George Lucas’ space opera universe, but they were only animated series (mostly) geared towards children. Since the Disney deluge, Disney has released 15 different <em>Star Wars</em> series, one a continuation of <em>The Clone Wars </em>animated show; the rest all brand-new.</p><p> Some of them, like 2022’s brilliant <em>Star Wars</em> spy thriller <em>Andor</em> (a prequel to <em>Rogue One</em> starring Diego Luna) are excellent. Some, like <em>The Book of Boba Fett</em>, a limited series that tried to make an exciting show out of everyone’s favorite mostly-silent bounty hunter, feel more like Disney taking action figures and smashing them together on a soundstage. When <em>Star Wars</em> TV is good, it’s whip-smart and inspiring, but when it’s bad it’s like that muck at the bottom of the trash compactor in <em>A New Hope</em>.</p><p>So, we ranked the 15 <em>Star Wars</em> TV shows (not including the ‘80s animated series, sorry), from worst to best. Click through to see how everything shook out. </p></div></div><div><p>The pitch for <em>The Book of Boba Fett </em>was incredible: a big-budget live-action spin-off of <em>The Mandalorian</em> starring Boba Fett as he takes over Tatooine and becomes a powerful criminal kingpin following the death of Jabba the Hutt. That sounds amazing. Sadly, there wasn’t much story to tell, and the show meandered around for a few hours while tossing in some fan service to hide how empty it was. It’s telling that the best part of <em>The Book of Boba Fett</em> is the two <em>Mandalorian </em>episodes shoved in the middle of the short season.—Zack Zwiezen</p></div><div><p>Unfortunately, <em>Young Jedi Adventures</em> is so far down on this list because of ageism—kind of. This series is the most geared-towards-children of any <em>Star Wars</em> show—it’s on Disney Junior, which means it’s aimed at really young kids (like 2-7 young), so it’s pretty tough to watch if you’re a childless 34-year-old woman. It’s a weird little kids show that I’d guess is easy to throw on when your toddler is pitching a fit so they can be distracted by whooshing lightsabers and spaceship sounds, and the animation is pretty cute, but there’s not much else to be said about a show that none of us here are the target audience for. — Alyssa Mercante</p></div><div><p>Poor<em> Star Wars: Resistance</em>. It could have been something special, but instead, it got saddled with the unfortunate task of trying to exist within the, at the time, still-being-developed sequel trilogy timeline. So it felt like it could never push too far or take too many big swings with its cast of lovable hotshot pilots living on a giant oil rig-like platform. Poe Dameron, voiced by Oscar Isaac, shows up a few times and that’s cool. But it’s not enough to make <em>Resistance </em>more than a colorful but empty side-story that feels even less important in 2024 than it did back in 2018. — ZZ<br></p></div><div><p>I desperately wanted the <em>Obi-Wan Kenobi</em> series to be good, as it promised to reunite actors Hayden Christensen and Ewan McGregor and to bridge a gap that was, for nearly two decades, only ever broached by the<em> Clone Wars</em> animated series. I had hoped that <em>Kenobi</em> would flesh out the Anakin/Obi-Wan dynamic in live-action and show us how their relationship was much more akin to that of brothers, rather than just merely master and apprentice, and that it would give Christensen a chance to enjoy some proper <em>Star Wars</em> love after he’d been the subject of so much ire as the prequels were released in the late ‘90s/early aughts.<br></p><p>But, alas, <em>Obi-Wan Kenobi </em>focused far too much on a young Leia and her relationship with Obi-Wan, bizarrely retreading tired characters and tropes while also trying to create new problems and plot points when there’s been a good story to be told sitting right there (Anakin and Obi-Wan’s bond during the Clone Wars), waiting patiently, for years.<br></p><p>Though McGregor deftly portrays an Obi-Wan so destroyed by the events of Episode 3 that he’s fully withdrawn from society, so scarred by the loss of his “brother” and his fellow Jedi that he can’t successfully keep his emotions from overwhelming him, we just don’t get enough of that. The show incessantly trots out child Leia (Vivien Lyra Blair, who is great) like a prized pony. “Look, remember her? She’s a kid now!” Yawn.<br></p><p>The brief scenes of Anakin and Obi-Wan together start to paint a clearer picture of their dynamic, but we never get a chance to see the finished painting. Instead we are repeatedly pulled back to young Leia and to a new Inquisitor struggling under the weight of Sith pressure (Reva, played by Moses Ingram), and told we should care about this, not that.<br></p><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/star-wars-obi-wan-season-2-clone-wars-armor-ewan-1851666770&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/star-wars-obi-wan-season-2-clone-wars-armor-ewan-1851666770">McGregor’s recent comments gave me some hope</a></span> that a potential second season of the series could provide the live-action <em>Clone Wars </em>we’ve been searching for, but I won’t hold my breath. — AM<br></p></div><div><p><em>Ahsoka </em>has potential. It picks up where animated series <em>Star Wars: Rebels</em> left off and switches over to live-action to give us our first-ever look at beloved characters in a different medium (Rosario Dawson as Ashoka Tano, Mary Elizabeth Winstead as Hera Syndulla, Natasha Liu Borduzzo as Sabine Wren, Eman Esfandi as Ezra Bridger). But that potential, like so many <em>Star Wars</em> projects, is only half-realized. </p><p>There are shining moments in the first season, like when Ahsoka meets Anakin (<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/star-wars-anakin-skywalker-hayden-christensen-ahsoka-1850403820&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/star-wars-anakin-skywalker-hayden-christensen-ahsoka-1850403820">the Hayden renaissance is upon us</a></span>) in the World Between Worlds, or whenever Shin Hati (Ivanna Sakhno) is on-screen. There are some great lightsaber fights, too, and David Tennant’s return as a sarcastic droid is perfection. But <em>Ahsoka</em> eventually falls victim to the persistent <em>Star Wars</em> curse, curling in on itself and the franchise’s established lore like a big nostalgia ouroboros. There are moments of delicious nostalgia for us <em>Clone Wars</em> and <em>Rebels</em> sickos, don’t get me wrong, but by the end of the first season it feels like <em>Ahsoka</em> is running on fumes.</p><p>A second season unburdened by the connective threads of <em>Rebels</em> could propel this series higher up the list. Stay tuned. — AM</p></div><div><p>Genndy Tartakovsky’s<em> Clone Wars</em> is just plain cool. I wasn’t actually a S<em>tar Wars</em> fan for a large chunk of my youth and found the milieu of the prequels pretty off-putting and boring. I didn’t want to hear about blockades or embargoes, and the inner workings of the galactic senate put me to sleep. </p><p>I wanted more action, more style, more <em>flair</em>, and I only really got that in the brief, 2D-animated minisodes of Tartakovsky’s <em>Clone Wars </em>that aired between shows on Cartoon Network. There was no better creative force to stick on the job either, considering Tartakovsky’s work on <em>Samurai Jack</em> had already impressed and enraptured me. This <em>Clone Wars</em> series is action-packed, stylish, and economic in its storytelling, and that is largely thanks to the vision of Tartakovsky.</p><p><em>Clone Wars</em> still kind of feels like the template for some of <em>Star Wars’ </em>best material. The mainline film saga has always painted in broad strokes, rarely affording time to dig into characters and moments across its vast timeline. This <em>Clone Wars </em>show was one of the first times I could remember the franchise carving out the time to make a bigger deal of the actual war that is supposed to be raging in the background of the prequels. It’s intimate in a way the movies rarely are—when <em>Star Wars</em> narrows its focus to hone in on a set of characters for an extended amount of time, rather than treat them like a cog in a big-ass storytelling machine, you get stuff like <em>Andor</em>, <em>The Acolyte</em>, or even the follow-up <em>Clone Wars</em> show that is now championed as some of the best work in the whole franchise. </p><p>I simply don’t believe we would have much of <em>Star Wars</em>’ best stuff if this early animated series hadn’t shown the value in the series pumping the brakes on the larger movements of its sweeping epic and taking its time to focus on some key players and a handful of pivotal moments. — Moises Tavares</p></div><div><p>As the first live-action <em>Star Wars</em> show,<em> </em>there was a lot of hype and eyeballs on <em>The Mandalorian. </em>And thankfully, it mostly succeeds at taking the big, campy adventurous spirit of live-action <em>Star Wars</em> films and squeezing it into weekly episodes of a TV show. It also introduced Grogu aka Baby Yoda, a small child-like example of the alien race known only as Yoda’s species. Grogu became an overnight pop culture icon and helped make <em>The Mandalorian </em>even bigger. </p><p>The show is pure <em>Star Wars </em>fan service, but it’s big-budgeted and fun fan service delivered in a weekly package with guest stars like Jack Black and interesting bits of post-<em>Return of the Jedi</em> lore sprinkled in to keep super fans excited. It’s not high art, but it’s entertaining sci-fi and that’s really all <em>Star Wars </em>needs to be most of the time to work. — ZZ<br></p></div><div><p>The <em>Tales of the Jedi </em>anthology<em>&nbsp;</em>is very good (you’ll see why on the next slide), so it makes sense that Disney would try and milk the cash cow some more with <em>Tales of the Empire</em>. Though it <em>looks</em> just as good as its benevolent predecessor, <em>Empire</em> is less consistent, with really good episodes (the first and third episodes in each arc) and some bad ones (the middle episodes in each arc). Morgan Elsbeth and fan-favorite Barriss Offee are the central characters in <em>Empire</em>, and their stories are solid—it’s just both of their damn middle episodes, which feel like unnecessary filler thrown in to make sure <em>Empire</em> wasn’t a shorter series. Gotta love Disney logic. — AM </p></div><div><p>Any series that features <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/it-took-you-cowards-long-enough-to-add-yaddle-to-a-vide-1843245709&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/it-took-you-cowards-long-enough-to-add-yaddle-to-a-vide-1843245709">Yaddle</a></span> is good in my book. But even without Jedi Master Yaddle, <em>Tales of the Jedi</em> is some wonderful <em>Star Wars</em> storytelling. It follows Ahsoka Tano and Count Dooku, showing us previously unseen moments from their lives. With Ahsoka, we see her as a baby, a teenager fighting in the Clone Wars, and an adult living out on her own after leaving the Order. Meanwhile, we watch how a noble and trusted Jedi, Dooku, could become disillusioned with the Jedi order and fall to the Dark Side. </p><p>While Ahsoka’s episodes are great—the highlight being an episode that shows her training endlessly against the Clone Troopers, which gave her the skills to survive the Purge—the real highlight of<em> Tales of the Jedi</em> is Dooku.<br></p><p>We get to see how he fell to darkness and joined up with the Emperor, and witness the big revelation that the Emperor didn’t have to promise him power or money or anything like that. Instead, Dooku watched people suffer and die while the Jedi, in his opinion, didn’t do enough to stop it or investigate. After that, all it took was a bit of a push to convince him to turn on the Jedi and the Republic. Watching him kill Yaddle (RIP) makes it clear that he’s conflicted, but convinced that this is the right path. A sad end for a once-noble Jedi, but a hell of an anthology series. — ZZ</p></div><div><p>When it was announced back in 2021 I was very excited for <em>Star Wars: Visions</em>, an anime anthology of original stories from iconic Japanese animation studios. The two seasons we’ve gotten so far have more than lived up to expectations, offering up beautifully realized, endlessly creative, and fantastically hopeful <em>Star Wars</em> stories across its 18 episodes. <em>Visions </em>is proof of the creative potential of opening up major IPs like <em>Star Wars</em> as a sandbox for more people to play in, and not setting restrictions on what those new visitors create.<br></p><p>From<em> “</em>Screecher’s Reach,” a beautiful retelling of Irish folklore in which the banshee is instead a Sith Mother, to “The Village Bride,” a fascinating, Kurosawa-esque tale of a Jedi on the run who is pulled into the bizarre but beautiful ways of a remote village’s wedding preparations, <em>Visions</em> is, well, visionary. Disney and Lucasfilm should aim for more <em>Star Wars</em> media to be like this, not less. — AM</p></div><div><p>Oh, <em>The Acolyte</em>, you were too pure for this world. How dare you tell a brand-new <em>Star Wars</em> story during a never-before-seen-in-live-action era starring several actors of color that lambastes the small-mindedness of the Jedi Order and has an enemies-to-lovers plot point? Notoriously close-minded sects of the <em>Star Wars</em> community hated <em>The Acolyte</em> before it even aired, and relished in its cancellation. But <em>The Acolyte</em> isn’t a bad <em>Star Wars</em> show, it’s just <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/star-wars-the-acolyte-canceled-season-2-1851627217&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/star-wars-the-acolyte-canceled-season-2-1851627217">a victim of modern television and ballooning budgets</a></span>. </p><p>Though it tripped on its own two feet midway through the first (and now seemingly only) season, <em>The Acolyte</em> gave us the best live-action lightsaber fight since Duel of the Fates, a deliciously deviant villain in Manny Jacinto’s Qimir, a pointed critique of the pointless rigidity of the Jedi Order, and new characters who immediately endeared themselves to us. It’s an inspiring show that’s fresher than drinking Bantha milk out of the damn bucket, with great performances from Jacinto, Lee Jung-jae, Amandla Stenberg, Carrie-Anne Moss, and Dafne Keen. It has a tactility to its set and costume design reminiscent of old-school <em>Star Wars</em>. It lovingly embraces what makes the franchise special while turning its back on what makes it reductive.</p><p>Perhaps <em>Star Wars</em> didn’t deserve <em>The Acolyte</em>, but <em>The Acolyte</em> deserved better. — AM</p></div><div><p><em>Star Wars </em>has long been about ragtag groups coming together to form found families as they fight back forces more powerful than themselves in a desperate effort to save the galaxy, or at least survive for one more day. And <em>Star Wars: The Bad Batch</em>, a spin-off of<em> Clone Wars</em> starring a squad of “defective” elite troopers, follows that classic <em>Star Wars</em> playbook perfectly.</p><p>At first I was worried the series, set shortly after the events of <em>Episode III</em>, would feel too by the numbers. But as it progresses, <em>Bad Batch</em> uses the<em> Star Wars</em> formula to tell a story of loyal soldiers now faced with the fact that their side is the bad side and the galaxy is a worse place because of them. It’s a dark time in <em>Star Wars</em>, and <em>Bad Batch</em> doesn’t shy away from sad or mature moments. It’s not quite <em>Andor</em>, but this is a series that’s not afraid to kill characters or show how defeated the galaxy is post-<em>Episode III’</em>s Jedi Purge and the rise of the Empire.</p><p>What could have been a silly show about weird Clone Troopers getting into random adventures each week is actually a series about betrayal, destruction, hope, and perseverance that also helps fill in some lore gaps in this era of the franchise. In other words, you should probably watch <em>Bad Batch</em>! — ZZ</p></div><div><p>I remember when <em>Rebels </em>was first announced and the reaction from <em>Star Wars</em> fans was, unsurprisingly, very negative. People complained that it didn’t look good, they were upset that it seemingly killed <em>The Clone Wars</em>, and as the first new <em>Star Wars</em> series from Disney, a subset of fans assumed it would be a terrible thing designed to rewrite lore and erase past<em> Star Wars</em> adventures. </p><p>All of these complaints and fears would end up being completely wrong. For one thing, <em>Rebels’ </em>art style was directly inspired by original concept art for the old <em>Star Wars</em> movies and as the series continued, its animation got better. It’s now considered one of the best-looking <em>Star Wars</em> shows around. It also didn’t kill <em>The</em>&nbsp;<em>Clone Wars</em>; instead, it was a sequel to that series. But before revealing that to fans, it introduces a new cast of plucky-but-flawed scoundrels, including a former Jedi, and slowly turns them into fan-favorites as they take on Thrawn, a character from the EU brought into canon via <em>Rebels</em>.<br></p><p>Then, once series supervising director Dave Filoni and Lucasfilm had introduced new characters and developed them into fully fleshed-out heroes worth caring about on their own, they revealed that <em>Rebels </em>was a continuation of <em>Clone Wars</em>. Ashoka and Rex were back. Hondo was here. Darth Maul returned. Story threads and lore first featured in <em>Clone Wars</em> got picked up in <em>Rebels</em>, like the Dark Saber and the fate of Mandalore. And then Lucasfilm ended the series on a cliffhanger, and all those fans who complained about <em>Rebels </em>were begging for a resolution that wouldn’t come until the live-action <em>Ahsoka </em>series in 2023. Now that’s how you run a large franchise TV series. — ZZ</p></div><div><p>Maybe my most successful tweet ever was <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/carolynmichelle/status/1577808668254507009&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/carolynmichelle/status/1577808668254507009" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">this one</a></span>, four images from episode five of <em>Andor </em>accompanied by my reaction: “Whoa.” In those images, young Karis Nemik, the most intellectually engaged member of the small band on Aldhani planning a massive heist of Imperial wealth, passionately imparts some of his ideas to Cassian Andor, who is undergoing his own reluctant political awakening. “So much going wrong,” Karis says, “so much to say, and all of it happening so quickly. The pace of repression outstrips our ability to understand it. And that is the real trick of the Imperial thought machine. It’s easier to hide behind 40 atrocities than a single incident.” </p><p>My hair stood on end upon hearing those words, a clear, truthful insight into how systems of oppression maintain their dominance, not just in that galaxy far, far away, but here in our world, too. For me, this conversation marked one of the most exciting moments in all of <em>Star Wars</em>, more thrilling than many of the franchise’s space battles and lightsaber clashes: here was a bold, unapologetic staking of ideological ground, a dazzling reminder that <em>Star Wars </em>could be, and should be, <em>about </em>something.</p><p>And this isn’t, as some may claim, <em>Andor </em>coming along and needlessly making <em>Star Wars </em>political. It’s a bold reclaiming of the political heart that was always there. Just watch <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://youtu.be/fv9Jq_mCJEo?si=rc8T1j-l-vDlkvvs&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://youtu.be/fv9Jq_mCJEo?si=rc8T1j-l-vDlkvvs" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">this excerpt from an interview</a></span> between George Lucas and James Cameron, in which Lucas asserts that his focus, as a student of anthropology, is “social systems.” Cameron then observes how interesting it is that in <em>Star Wars</em>, “the good guys are the Rebels, they’re using asymmetric warfare against a highly organized Empire. I think we call those guys terrorists today.” Lucas responds, “When I did it, they were Viet Cong,” which makes the Empire of the original 1977 film—dun dun DUN!!!!!!!—the good ol’ U.S. of A. </p><p>Of course, over the decades, there have been many real-life Empires and many real-life Rebellions, and sadly, those core political themes of oppression and resistance at the heart of <em>Star Wars </em>have never been made obsolete. If anything, they feel more urgently relevant today than ever. But what makes <em>Andor </em>so extraordinary isn’t just the fact that it unabashedly and explicitly reclaims this radical, anti-fascist political ground for the colossal franchise. Of course it’s possible to write a story with radical politics that’s clunky and boring, that feels more driven by ideology than by characters with real desires and convictions. But <em>Andor </em>is extraordinarily successful on this level, too. In the hands of showrunner Tony Gilroy, who also wrote and directed the exceptionally smart and thrilling 2007 film <em>Michael Clayton</em>, <em>Andor</em>’s characters and themes are organically fused, with its fascists as complex and believable as its anti-fascists, and with every rousing speech—like <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://youtu.be/GQMDmb3mOY8&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://youtu.be/GQMDmb3mOY8" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">the one Stellan Skarsgård stirringly delivers</a></span> as Luthen Rael, revealing all the things he has sacrificed in pursuit of liberation, and<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://youtu.be/TaKrm5txGCQ?si=fXTyR-Yu0LslXcvb&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://youtu.be/TaKrm5txGCQ?si=fXTyR-Yu0LslXcvb" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"> the one Fiona Shaw’s Maarva Andor delivers</a></span> from beyond the grave, urging those she’s left behind to “fight the Empire!”—feeling not like a bad writer heavy-handedly working some ideological message into a story where it doesn’t belong, but rather like a wholly believable and necessary expression of that character’s convictions.<br></p><p>Every day now—every tragic, horrible day—it feels more and more plainly true that Karis was right: there’s so much going wrong, and all of it’s happening so quickly, and that the sheer number of atrocities being funded and committed only makes it easier for the governments doing so to hide behind them. <em>Andor </em>is full of thrilling action and wonderful characters, all of the things we’ve always come to <em>Star Wars </em>for. But it’s also an urgent reminder of what <em>Star Wars </em>has always really been about. Know an evil empire when you see one. — Carolyn Petit</p></div><div><p>The animated <em>Clone Wars</em> series started off as an okay-but-not-great show that filled in the gap between the prequel movies of <em>Episode II</em> and <em>Episode III</em>. But as the series continued, it quickly became  fantastic, not only filling in the gaps left by the films, but providing us something they didn’t: Chemistry between Anakin and Obi-Wan.</p><p>If you just watch the prequels, Anakin and Obi-Wan barely seem close, let alone like brothers, and the actual Clone Wars are a background detail that feels far away and weirdly not all that dangerous. The animated series fixes this, providing us with an action-packed and well-written series of arcs that not only show us what happened during the Clone Wars but also how Anakin slowly moves toward the dark side, the things that push him there (the Jedi, mostly), and his inevitable fall to Darth Vader.</p><p>Most of <em>Star Wars</em> outside the movies can be skipped unless you love the franchise and want more of it. <em>Clone Wars</em> is the big exception. So much of <em>Clone Wars</em> has continued to appear in books, comics, games, movies, and other TV shows. Ahsoka’s arc starts here. It’s where we meet Hondo Ohnaka. And it’s the series that <em>Rebels </em>builds off of which itself has become a backbone of modern <em>Star Wars</em>. <em>Clone Wars</em> is a key piece in all of this and essential viewing if you want to understand the <em>Star Wars</em> universe. And lucky for you, (most  of) the show is really good. — ZZ</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Until Dawn PS5 and PC Remake Suffers a Rough Launch]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/until-dawn-ps5-and-pc-remake-suffers-a-rough-launch</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/until-dawn-ps5-and-pc-remake-suffers-a-rough-launch.1003533/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/until-dawn-ps5-and-pc-remake-suffers-a-rough-launch<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>Sony's Until Dawn remake for PlayStation 5 and PC is having a rough launch, with not just technical issues but low player numbers too.</p><p>The remake of the 2015 horror game — <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/until-dawn-comes-to-playstation-5-and-pc-in-october-2024">which comes with updated graphics, technical improvements, and minor story changes</a> — launched October 4 with <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/until-dawn-on-ps5s-60-pricetag-reignites-remake-price-debate">a full price tag of $59.99</a> and no cheaper upgrade option for those who own the original.</p><p>This seemingly wasn't too appealing for PC players, as Until Dawn has debuted to a peak concurrent player count of just 2,607 players on Steam, according to tracking website <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/2172010/charts/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">SteamDB</a>. Other single-player PlayStation games performed much better when making the jump to PC, with Ghost of Tsushima reaching 77,154 concurrent players, God of War reaching 73,529, and Spider-Man reaching 66,436 on Valve's platform. Until Dawn's Steam launch is the worst Sony debut on Steam since the ill-fated <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/concord">Concord</a> and <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/sackboy-a-big-adventure">Sackboy: A Big Adventure</a>.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>This small player base is reporting myriad issues too. Until Dawn currently has a "mixed" user review rating on Steam with just 69% of reviews being positive. The review deemed most helpful recommends the game but complains about <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pc-gamers-in-countries-without-psn-hit-out-at-sony-for-blocking-sale-of-single-player-games-god-of-war-ragnarok-and-until-dawn-on-steam">the required PlayStation Network account</a>, poor optimisation, music changes from the original, bugs, and poor controls at times.</p><p>Other reviews also comment on ray tracing and DLSS not working alongside graphical issues which "destroy immersion." Others comment on the full price tag for the originally nine-year-old game and it still launching with issues.</p><p>Developer Ballistic Moon, which <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/until-dawn-remake-developer-ballistic-moon-lays-off-several-staff">suffered a "significant" round of lay-offs</a> even before the Until Dawn remake launched, has acknowledged the problems in an <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2172010/Until_Dawn/#app_reviews_hash" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">post</a> released today, October 8. "We understand that some of you may have encountered some technical issues or bugs, and we’d love to hear from you so we can address these concerns," it said.</p><p>"We are also aware of a couple of recurring issues, such as HDR and AMD FSR frame generation settings not functioning as intended, and issues with save/load. We hear you and we're actively testing fixes for these issues (and more). We will provide further information with our next patch update."</p><p>Issues are not exclusive to the PC version of the game, however. The tech experts at <a href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/gxwB2f5s850?autoplay=1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Digital Foundry</a> noted that the PS5 version has frame pacing or frame ordering issues, 30 frames per second and 1440p output with significant aliasing on high contrast edges, and break up when there's motion on-screen.</p><p>Ballistic Moon has at least said updates are coming, but these may be too little, too late for those who've already spent $59.99 on the remake. No release dates or windows have been shared for these fixes.</p><p>Until Dawn fans otherwise got a kick out of story changes in the remake (<a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/until-dawn-remake-leak-reveals-revamped-intro-in-3-hours-of-ps5-gameplay">when it all leaked ahead of launch</a>) with <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/why-until-dawn-ps5-and-pc-remake-leaks-have-sparked-until-dawn-2-speculation">some even thinking a sequel is on the way</a>. The universe is expanding elsewhere too, as <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/sonys-until-dawn-film-has-already-wrapped-filming">filming wrapped on the Until Dawn movie adaptation</a> earlier in October.</p><p><em>Ryan Dinsdale is an IGN freelance reporter. He'll talk about The Witcher all day.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A Space for the Unbound coming to iOS]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/10/a-space-for-the-unbound-coming-to-ios</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/a-space-for-the-unbound-coming-to-ios.1003527/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/10/a-space-for-the-unbound-coming-to-ios<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/mobile/smartphone">Smartphone</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>The heartwarming story on mobile.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publishers <a title="Companies > Toge Productions [41 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/toge-productions">Toge Productions</a> and <a title="Companies > Chorus Worldwide [63 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/chorus-worldwide">Chorus Worldwide</a>, and developer <a title="Companies > Mojiken Studio [13 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/toge-productions/mojiken-studio">Mojiken Studio</a> will release slice-of-life narrative <a title="Genres > Adventure [1,802 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure game</a> <em><a title="Games > A Space for the Unbound [6 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/a-space-for-the-unbound">A Space for the Unbound</a></em> for iOS via <a href="https://apps.apple.com/th/app/a-space-for-the-unbound/id6544796348" rel="noopener" target="_blank">App Store</a>, the companies announced. A release date was not announced.</p><p><em>A Space for the Unbound</em> first launched for PlayStation 5, Xbox Series, PlayStation 4, Xbox One, Switch, and PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1201270/A_Space_For_The_Unbound/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a>, <a title="Companies > Epic Games [340 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/epic-games">Epic Games</a> Store, and <a href="https://www.gog.com/en/game/a_space_for_the_unbound" target="_blank" rel="noopener">GOG</a> on January 19, 2023.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via <a href="https://apps.apple.com/th/app/a-space-for-the-unbound/id6544796348" rel="noopener" target="_blank">App Store</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>A magical adventure about two high school sweethearts set at the end of their school days—and the end of the world.</p><p>This free version of the <em>A Space for the Unbound</em> contains the first Prologue Chapter that can be played for free. You will need to purchase an In App Purchase to unlock the full game.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong>High School is Ending and the World is Ending With It</strong></p><p><em>A Space for the Unbound</em> is a slice-of-life adventure game with beautiful pixel art set in the late 90s rural Indonesia that tells a story about overcoming anxiety, depression, and the relationship between a boy and a girl with supernatural powers.</p><p>Follow two high school sweethearts, Atma and Raya, on a journey of self-discovery at the end of their high school years. When a mysteriously supernatural power is suddenly unleashed threatening their existence, they must explore and investigate their town to uncover hidden secrets, face the end of the world, and perhaps learn more about each other.</p><p>Set in a small town inspired by 90s era rural Indonesia, <em>A Space for the Unbound</em> presents an endearing story-driven experience with a vibrant environment waiting to be explored.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li>Throwback to the 90s! Let us take you to Indonesia in the late 90s.</li><li>Explore rural Indonesia and enjoy its relaxing atmosphere with a hint of supernatural events.</li><li>Chat and interact with other townfolks and listen to their personal stories.</li><li>Dive into people’s minds Inception-style.</li><li>Listen to beautiful music composed by Masdito “Ittou” Bachtiar.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch the iOS announcement trailer below.</p><h2><span>iOS Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="A Space for the Unbound | Coming Soon to App Store" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/60M43B_-GwQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Llamalandia Preview – Live, llama, love]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/10/08/llamalandia-preview-live-llama-love/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/llamalandia-preview-%E2%80%93-live-llama-love.1003521/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/10/08/llamalandia-preview-live-llama-love/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Who wouldn’t want to a be llama? You’d quite possibly get to live in South America, graze in the sun, spend time with your family, and just spit at things that annoy you. Let’s forget about the whole being reared for meat bit, or the odds of ending up in a UK llama farm. Llamalandia does, instead having you play as a llama, leading your llama family, and building a little llama town while going on adventures.</p>
<p><iframe title="Llamalandia Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/G29JoWELESc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>The demo for Llamalandia is relatively short, but it shows the basics of what to expect whenever the full game is eventually released. The opening scene shows the llamas sleeping out in the wild until a few wake up and wander off. You have to go off and find them. It’s a relatively simple set up and the opening introduces elements of platforming, command management, and puzzles.</p>


<p>When you find the llamas you recruit them to your side, with the options to get them following you or to wait for you. The puzzles in the demo require doors to be opened, using weight-activated switches. Some of the switches require two llamas to stand on them, so you all wander over, or you might have to split the herd to activate multiple switches. The platforming is prominent in these sections, and I would say the animation is rather stiff when jumping.</p>


<p>Before you get to the sanctuary there is a bit of combat as snakes and a big cat come for the llamas. Snakes can be knocked out with a single headbutt, so they are not that dangerous, but the big cat is more of a danger and can knock out your llamas, and does not go down even with multiple hits. It will instead run away and come back to attack again later. You can revive your llamas, but on the final stretch to the sanctuary I did leave a llama behind because the big cat kept attacking, so it was just easier to get to the sanctuary with the remaining llamas. Don’t worry, this is a child friendly game, and the llama that was left behind did appear in the sanctuary too, albeit bandaged up.</p>
<p>In addition to the platforming and combat, Llamalandia does have resource collection too, though the only resources that I was collecting was plants that restored health. You can given these plants to other llamas to hold and use if they get injured. I also found a hat and poncho for my llama to wear. Other resources that look like will be collectable are wood and stone, with these being necessary to build your llama town at the sanctuary.</p>

<p>The Llamaland demo gives a couple of places to build for your town, with the help of the the llama architect and the llama gardener. First is the town hall which acts as an information hub, showing how many llamas are in your town. You can then build the llama homes for them to live in, a watering hole for them to drink from, and crop fields to grow food so they can eat and stay at full health. The llama town has life to it in the early stages with adult and baby llamas wandering around. The game says you have to be stronger to order around the baby llamas, which really adds realism to the game since babies are notoriously bad at following instructions.</p>
<p>What I really like about Llamalandia is its visual design. It has bright colours that make it stand out, while the character models come across as something you would see in a cartoon. The building designs also make them easy to differentiate. The demo also gives the impression that the full release will be easy to pick up and play, while there will be some challenges, overall Llamalandia could be a really chill game to relax to.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch SUPER7 Screen Mod Will Put the Vanilla OLED Screen to Shame]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-screen-mod-oled/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-switch-super7-screen-mod-will-put-the-vanilla-oled-screen-to-shame.1003518/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-screen-mod-oled/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The original Nintendo Switch will soon get a screen mod that will put the vanilla OLED screen featured in the console's second version to shame.</p>
<p>Well-known modder <a href="https://x.com/TakiUdon_" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Taki Udon</a>, who recently released a <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-lite-oled-release-date/">Nintendo Switch Lite OLED screen mod</a> that looks incredible, revealed a few days ago that a SUPER7 mod for the V1/V2 Switch is in the works. This screen will be bigger than the vanilla screen of the console, 7 inches instead of 6.2, and its quality will put the vanilla OLED screen to shame, as effectively showcased in a comparison picture. The upgrade will be a simple PCB swap, so even those who never attempted to mod any of their systems should have no problem installing this mod.</p>
<blockquote>
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">I've been getting questions about upgrades for the V1 or V2 Switch all year.</p>
<p>I can confirm SUPER7 exists, it improves everything in the V1/V2 Switch, and it puts the OLED Switch to shame. An IPS upgrade also exists.</p>
<p>SUPER5 OLED Deep Dive: <a href="https://t.co/y7cq5L5aGU">https://t.co/y7cq5L5aGU</a> <a href="https://t.co/CWeRz8MvON">pic.twitter.com/CWeRz8MvON</a></p>
<p>— Taki Udon (@TakiUdon_) <a href="https://twitter.com/TakiUdon_/status/1842109903101735064?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 4, 2024</a></p></blockquote>

<p>On a related note, Taki Udon also shared a new video a few days ago showcasing the Ultimate Nintendo Switch Lite OLED. The system was upgraded with the SUPER5 OLED Kit, a 5,000 mAh battery, and hall effect sticks, and almost looks like an official premium upgrade of the handheld only version of the system. You can check out the video below.</p>
<p><iframe title="Building the Ultimate OLED Switch Lite" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/BU6mKBRExjk?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>More information on the amazing work Taki Udon is doing to improve the current Nintendo Switch models can be found <a href="https://retroremake.co/products/super5-oled-diy-screen-mod-kit" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here.</a></p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mass Effect: The Board Game Review – Back To The Reaper War]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/mass-effect-board-game-review-back-to-reaper-war</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mass-effect-the-board-game-review-%E2%80%93-back-to-the-reaper-war.1003515/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/mass-effect-board-game-review-back-to-reaper-war<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Mass Effect: The Board Game</em> is a wonderful licensed board game experience that is few and far between. A game that doesn't lean on imitation of its source material, but adds to it. On top of that, it pulls off the task of presenting a complex board game experience in a relatively compact package, making it a must-have board game experience.</p>

<p><em>Mass Effect: The Board Game</em> is a cooperative narrative-driven tactical skirmish board game. You and up to three friends play as Commander Shepard, Liara, Garrus, Tali, or Wrex. The board game is set during the events of <a href="https://techraptor.net/games/mass-effect-3" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><em>Mass Effect 3</em></a>, with Shepard and their crew infiltrating a Cerberus outpost on the planet Hagalaz.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/mass-effect-the-board-game-mission-map.jpg?itok=bWzyBtzH 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/mass-effect-the-board-game-mission-map.jpg?itok=e-pocTCQ 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Alright, where we dropping?</figcaption></figure><p>The game is broken up into several branching missions. Depending on their choices, players will deploy into different hex-based battle maps and take turns fighting enemies and clearing objectives, all the way to the end. As characters defeat enemies and complete missions, they slowly unlock new abilities to help them against escalating threats.</p>
<p>There are even Loyalty Missions unique to each character. These optional missions will unlock even more potent abilities designed to give you an edge in the next mission.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/mass-effect-the-board-game-miniatures.jpg?itok=lZGagxJs 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/mass-effect-the-board-game-miniatures.jpg?itok=lF7sDuHo 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Still looking great, team.</figcaption></figure><h2>What is in Mass Effect: The Board Game?</h2>
<p><em>Mass Effect: The Board Game</em> packs a lot into a single box. This is thanks to a combination of smart packaging and meticulously curated storage. A single copy of the game contains a narrative book, a rulebook, a large binder book full of skirmish maps and mission objectives, a mission overview sheet, five character sheets, a set of 12 skill dice and 2 paragon dice, two decks of cards that determine the enemy AI, three token sheets, a token bag, a dry erase marker, and six miniatures.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/mass-effect-the-board-game-game-books.jpg?itok=uLQqX3_6 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/mass-effect-the-board-game-game-books.jpg?itok=lRIJevTa 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Your choices have consequences, Commander.</figcaption></figure><h2>How Do You Play Mass Effect: The Board Game?</h2>
<p>The first major accomplishment of <em>Mass Effect: The Board Game</em> is that it captures the spirit of the <a href="https://techraptor.net/games/mass-effect-legendary-edition" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><em>Mass Effect</em></a> trilogy.</p>
<p>Each mission is broken into several steps. First, you roll your skill dice. Each die has a symbol on it for movement, a character's ability, or attacking. You then pick three of those dice, place them on your sheet, then hand the remaining dice to a teammate. Once this is all done, those dice act as your action pool, letting you move, shoot, interact, or use a unique power like Liara's biotics or Tali's tech powers.</p>
<p>Once your turn is complete, you must resolve a card from a deck of cards. This either spawns new enemies on the map, has existing enemies attack anyone in range, or adds a complication like a door locking or a trap turning on.</p>
<p>After everyone has gone, the enemy advances or attacks anyone in range. Then you break out the skill dice and repeat the process until either Shepard dies and the mission fails or you complete</p>
<p>Ranged combat is simple compared to other skirmish games. You can only fire on something in a direct line from you and on the same level of elevation. The closest thing to cover in this game is getting out of the enemy's line of sight and shields. It's not as complex as <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/games/warhammer-40000-kill-team" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><em>Warhammer 40,000 Kill Team</em></a>, but it gets the job done.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/mass-effect-the-board-game-mission-objectives.jpg?itok=PYKHns-E 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/mass-effect-the-board-game-mission-objectives.jpg?itok=zGLq0FMb 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Be a hero, or be efficient. Choice is yours.</figcaption></figure><p>This is good because <em>Mass Effect: The Board Game</em> encourages you to fight through. Defeating enemies will cause characters to level up, providing new options on the battlefield. Not to mention certain maps contain useful inventory pick-ups like grenades or medi-gel.</p>
<p>Lastly, each mission in <em>Mass Effect: The Board Game</em> has a Paragon ending and a Renegade ending. Getting a Paragon ending lets you add a Paragon die to the dice pool, giving you more options each turn. Getting the Renegade ending gives you a token. You can spend this token once per mission to just get a certain die result. Both are great expressions of the series' themes of idealism vs. pragmatism.</p>
<h2>How Does Mass Effect: The Board Game Feel To Play?</h2>
<p>If you are planning on picking up <em>Mass Effect: The Board Game</em> and enjoy miniatures, temper your expectations. While the six miniatures included represent the Normandy crew admirably, enemy units just use cardboard tokens.</p>
<p>Personally, I am okay with this since it reduces clutter and helps streamline board set-up. But if you have been clamoring for your own Cerberus troopers or Reaper husks, you may want to wait.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/mass-effect-the-board-game-board-set-up.jpg?itok=D8o0fU7M 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/mass-effect-the-board-game-board-set-up.jpg?itok=W_EKzAHo 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>I am honestly impressed this fits on a medium-sized table.</figcaption></figure><p>From a gameplay perspective, <em>Mass Effect: The Board Game</em> does a decent job of mixing branching narrative choices with miniature combat.</p>
<p>Generally, the skirmish combat is light and quick. Each character has a unique ability that they utilize during a mission. Wrex has his Blood Rage, which grants bonus damage on attacks. Tali has a combat drone. And Shepard can temporarily enhance their squad mate's attacks, playing into their leader role.</p>
<p>The weak link in the bunch may be Liara. This is mostly due to how scaled-back biotic abilities are. Combos take a little too long to set up and don't have the same payoff as concentrated gunfire.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/mass-effect-the-board-game-miniature-combat.jpg?itok=EXN06jbd 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/mass-effect-the-board-game-miniature-combat.jpg?itok=z51AXuQV 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Alright, Wrex should keep them busy, someone get those doors open.</figcaption></figure><p>As for the narrative, it is clear that&nbsp; Eric Lang (<a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/bloodborne-board-game-review" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><em>Bloodborne: The Board Game</em></a>) and Calvin Wong Tze Loon understood the assignment. Every narrative choice, branching path, and character dialogue feels like something straight from the original trilogy.</p>
<p>The only real issue is that the game's narrative feels like a cut mission from <em>Mass Effect 3</em>. One that wasn't cut for character inconsistency or overambitious scale, but for pacing. There isn't any real embellishments or major revelations to the established canon here. Shepard and the crew are on just another mission fighting Cerberus and The Reapers and that's about it.</p>
<h2>Should I Pick Up Mass Effect: The Board Game?</h2>
<p>Despite some minor stumbles, <em>Mass Effect: The Board Game</em> is an absolute treat for both diehard fans and co-op miniature game enthusiasts. While there are more robust dedicated skirmish games on the market, the mix of branching player choice and alternate win conditions makes this game highly replayable.</p>
<hr><p><em>The copy of <strong>Mass Effect: The Board Game</strong> used in this review was provided by the publisher - all screenshots were taken during the process of review. </em></p>
</div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Ever since he was small, Tyler Chancey has had a deep, abiding love for video games and a tendency to think and overanalyze everything he enjoyed. This… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/tyler-chancey">More about Tyler</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Epic Scores Victory as Judge Rules Google Must Open Up the Play Store]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/epic-google-victory-play-store</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/epic-scores-victory-as-judge-rules-google-must-open-up-the-play-store.1003512/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/epic-google-victory-play-store<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>A judge has issued his final ruling in an ongoing lawsuit between&nbsp;<em>Fortnite&nbsp;</em>developer Epic Games and Android owner Google, and the ruling will no doubt be music to Epic's ears.</p>
<p>According <a href="https://www.theverge.com/policy/2024/10/7/24243316/epic-google-permanent-injunction-ruling-third-party-stores" rel="noopener" target="_blank">to The Verge</a>, Judge James Donato has ruled that Google must now open up its Play Store on Android devices to third-party app stores such as the Epic Games Store, and it must, in The Verge's words, give "rival third-party app stores access to the full catalog of Google Play apps".</p>
<p>Additionally, Google must stop requiring apps to use its Google Play Billing payment system, since the jury in the lawsuit found that the tying of this system to the Play Store was illegal. Given that that's <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/epic-sues-google-over-fortnites-removal-from-play-store">arguably where this whole mess began</a>, that's likely to please Epic.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/epic-games-store-mobile-google-lawsuit.jpg?itok=ajwAm3I4 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/epic-games-store-mobile-google-lawsuit.jpg?itok=3tnGM595 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>A judge has ruled that Google must allow the Epic Games Store to be downloaded via its own Play Store on Android.</figcaption></figure><p>Google must also allow developers to tell users about different payment methods, link to alternative app download sources, and set their own price for apps "irrespective of Play Billing", as The Verge puts it.</p>
<p>However, it hasn't all gone down in Epic's favor. Judge Donato ruled that Google must open up the Play Store for three years, but Epic wanted six, and it also wanted users to be able to sideload apps with just one tap, which hasn't been included in Judge Donato's ruling.</p>
<p>Still, Judge Donato says that his ruling will give other app stores "a fighting chance" of competing with the Play Store, and Epic's own Tim Sweeney is <a href="https://x.com/TimSweeneyEpic/status/1843394692551192972" rel="noopener" target="_blank">chalking this one up as a win</a> as well.</p>
<p>Naturally, Google isn't pleased with the changes. It says it plans to appeal the Epic verdict, stating that the changes will "cause a range of unintended consequences that will harm American consumers, developers, and device makers". Ominous.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/fall-guys-epic-games-store-google.jpg?itok=20sZcLAQ 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/fall-guys-epic-games-store-google.jpg?itok=KGtOvMvm 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>You'll soon be able to download the Epic mobile store on the Play Store and enjoy games like&nbsp;<em>Fall Guys&nbsp;</em>(although you technically already can).</figcaption></figure><p>Epic's battle against Google started at around the same time as its <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/35-us-states-back-epic-in-ongoing-epic-vs-apple-antitrust-case">legal beef with Apple</a>, and the grounds of both lawsuits were roughly the same; Apple and Google have a mobile duopoly and no other entity can compete with them.</p>
<p>As The Verge points out, that particular battle went worse for Epic, since the company's final appeal against the decision that Apple doesn't have a monopoly (a stance with which the <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/house-antitrust-committee-says-apple-has-ios-distribution-monopoly">House Antitrust Committee disagreed in 2020</a>) was rejected in January.</p>
<p>Still, Tim Sweeney's studio can enjoy this victory against Google, at least until the appeal begins. We'll bring you more on this as soon as we get it.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon Hails Success of MMO Throne and Liberty After 3 Million Players in a Week]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/amazon-hails-success-of-mmo-throne-and-liberty-after-3-million-players-in-a-week</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/amazon-hails-success-of-mmo-throne-and-liberty-after-3-million-players-in-a-week.1003491/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/amazon-hails-success-of-mmo-throne-and-liberty-after-3-million-players-in-a-week<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p><a href="https://www.ign.com/games/throne-and-liberty">Throne and Liberty</a>, the free-to-play massively multiplayer online role-playing game developed by NCSoft and published by Amazon Games, has seen more than three million players in just a week.</p><p>Originally billed as a Lineage sequel, Throne and Liberty is an MMO with PvE and PvP set in a dynamic and seamless world. It suffered numerous delays over the course of a development cycle spanning several years.</p><p>Throne and Liberty finally launched on October 1 across PC, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series X and S, and soon proved a hit on Steam with an impressive player concurrent peak of 336,300. That’s enough to make Throne and Liberty one of the most-played games on Valve’s platform right now. Neither Sony nor Microsoft make player numbers public.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>Amazon added that Throne and Liberty players had amassed 24 million hours in the game, with more than 11 million hours watched on Twitch.</p><p>“Bringing Throne and Liberty to players around the world has been a huge shared undertaking by our team and our friends at NCSoft, and we’re so pleased to see the results as players join the game,” said Christoph Hartmann, VP, Amazon Games.</p><p>“We’re only getting started, and we have a series of updates planned including our first castle siege coming soon.”</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3>The Best PC Games</h3></div></output><p>Throne and Liberty’s early performance is all the more impressive in light of its ‘mixed’ user review rating on Steam, with most of the negative reviews about server issues and the typical monetization you get from these sorts of F2P MMOs. IGN’s impressions of <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/throne-and-libertys-beta-is-fun-but-doesnt-do-enough-to-stand-out"><u>Throne and Liberty during its beta</u></a> said the game “is fun but doesn’t do enough to stand out.”</p><p>For Amazon Games, Throne and Liberty’s success comes as it continues to support its own developed MMO, <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/new-world">New World</a>, and Smilegate’s action role-playing game <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/lost-ark">Lost Ark</a>, which it published in 2022. Amazon is also publishing <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/tomb-raider-next">Crystal Dynamics’ next Tomb Raider game</a>, and has a <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/the-lord-of-the-rings-mmo">The Lord of the Rings MMORPG</a> in the works, among other projects.</p><p>In August, <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/amazon-games-still-seeking-lord-of-the-rings-mmo-christoph-hartmann-interview">Hartmann told IGN</a> the Lord of the rings MMO was "still early," and the next Tomb Raider a "huge, huge task."</p><p><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[There’s never been a better time to play Diablo IV]]></title>
            <link>https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2024/10/diablo-iv-is-in-a-great-place-whether-you-buy-vessel-of-hatred-or-not/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/there%E2%80%99s-never-been-a-better-time-to-play-diablo-iv.1003488/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2024/10/diablo-iv-is-in-a-great-place-whether-you-buy-vessel-of-hatred-or-not/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="main">
            <article data-id="2054701">
  
  <header>
  <div>
      

      

      <p>
        Review: new expansion adds to an already vastly improved game.
      </p>

      
    </div>
</header>

  

  
      
    
    <div>
                      
                      
          
<p>When we reviewed <em>Diablo IV</em>, the latest installment in the long-running action roleplaying game series last year, we said it was <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2023/05/diablo-4-review-off-to-a-hell-of-a-good-start/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">off to a hell of a good start</a>. But ARPGs live and die by their endgame loops, and it was far too early at the time to accurately assess the game’s true staying power.</p>
<p>Sadly, after that confident first step, like so many loot-hunting games before it, <em>Diablo IV</em> fell flat on its face. I’ve seen plenty of boneheaded updates to live-service games, but <em>Diablo IV</em>’s first major patch, released a couple of months after the game’s release, was still pretty shocking. By that point, a consensus had emerged that the endgame was a bit barren, and getting to the game’s level cap of 100 was a tedious slog. But that’s the great thing about live-service games, right? Tweak some numbers, throw in a couple of fun high-level activities, and, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Sr2PlqXw03Y" target="_blank" rel="noopener">baby, you’ve got a stew going</a>.</p>
<p>Sadly, the game’s developers at Blizzard had other plans. The patch notes for that first update read like someone had systematically gone through the game and <a href="https://www.polygon.com/23801426/diablo-4s-season-1-patch-1-1-nerfs-community-reaction" target="_blank" rel="noopener">removed anything that could be considered fun</a>. Almost every character build had been mercilessly nerfed, and worst of all, the game became even slower. <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/diablo4/comments/1534z13/patch_11_is_essentially_a_slowdown_to_every/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Fans were incensed</a>, and <em>Diablo IV</em> floundered like this for its first three <a href="https://diablo.fandom.com/wiki/Season_(Diablo_IV)">seasons</a>. I mostly lost interest.</p>
<p>On the release of the game's first expansion, <em>Vessel of Hatred</em>, we're checking in on the state of the game—and we're pretty happy with what we've found.<br>
</p>
<h2>Game details</h2>
<p><strong>Developer:</strong> Blizzard<br>
<strong>Publisher:</strong> Blizzard<br>
<strong>Platform:</strong> <a href="https://diablo4.blizzard.com/en-us/vessel-of-hatred">Battlenet</a>, <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3043530/Diablo_IV_Vessel_of_Hatred/">Steam</a>, <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/product/UP0002-PPSA02442_00-D4VOHSTANDARD000/">Playstation 4|5</a>, <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/diablo-iv-vessel-of-hatred-standard-edition/9N9H2HMFZKLM">Xbox Series X|S and Xbox One</a><br>
<strong>Release Date:</strong> Oct. 8, 2024<br>
<strong>Price:</strong> $39.99

</p>
<h2>Loot reborn</h2>
<p>There were many problems with <em>Diablo IV</em>'s endgame, but the most pressing concern was the loot. There were too many possible “affixes”—random properties on pieces of gear—and they were way too specific. You’d have a sword that gave you, like, an extra critical hit chance to enemies below a certain health threshold or a helm that gave you a chance (of a chance) of healing on hit. Players started calling these hyper-conditional affixes "damage on Tuesdays" effects.</p>

          
                      
                  </div>
                    
        
          
    
    <div>
          
          
<p>And because any rare item—a misnomer, as they’re very common—could be converted into a legendary (the items you actually want), you had to pore over every stat on every piece of gear to avoid missing an upgrade. Believe it or not, that was the tip of the iceberg—I’ll spare you an explanation of the game’s strange and infuriating implementation of “legendary aspects.”</p>
<p>It was all so confusing and tedious that looking through loot—what should mark a nice break in the action as you see if you got an exciting upgrade—became an impediment to playing the game. Often, when faced with a full bag of loot to sort through after some adventuring, I’d let out an exhausted sigh and log off.</p>
<p>Thankfully, <em>Diablo IV</em> got its “loot 2.0” update in season 4. (If you're remembering <i>Diablo III</i>’s <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2014/03/two-years-later-reaper-of-souls-is-the-diablo-iii-we-always-wanted/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><em>Reaper of Souls</em> expansion</a> and feeling déjà vu, yeah, it was like that.) That season was focused entirely on fixing the loot situation, and… it actually worked.</p>
<p>Affixes were pared down to an understandable and easily scannable minimum, and the game added some light but engaging crafting systems to let players further customize their gear. It’s impossible to overstate how much the loot changes improved the game.</p>
<p>There were plenty of other updates, too. Endgame activities were added and tweaked (we saw a return of <em>Diablo III</em>'s Greater Rifts in the form of "the Pit"), and the game generally found its footing. Now, Blizzard is going further.</p>

<h2>Haters welcome</h2>


<p>The cheerily named <em>Vessel of Hatred</em> picks up where the base game lets off. The story, told through the usual combination of cutscenes (both breathtaking and pedestrian) and fairly standard “go here and kill monsters” questing, is on par with that of the base game, which is to say it’s atmospheric and engaging enough, but you’ll probably play it once and then skip it in future seasons to focus on the monster slaughtering. I’ll be frank: I don’t care a whit about the story content of ARPGs, and I’d recommend looking elsewhere if that’s all you’re interested in. But it’s fine.</p>

          
                  </div>
                    
        
          
    
    <div>
          
          
<p>The new Amazonian-themed region of Nahantu brings a bit of color to <em>Diablo IV</em>’s intentionally drab and dreary map. As much as I enjoy the muddy fields and desolate wastelands of the base game, I’ll admit that a splash of color really livens things up. It still feels like Diablo, though, which is great.</p>
<div>
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 40 40"><defs><clipPath id="arrow-blocks-right_svg__a"><path fill="none" d="M0 0h40v40H0z"></path></clipPath></defs><g fill="currentColor" clip-path="url(#arrow-blocks-right_svg__a)"><path d="M32 16h8v8h-8zm-8 8h8v8h-8zm-8 8h8v8h-8zm8-24h8v8h-8zm-8-8h8v8h-8zM0 16h16v8H0z"></path></g></svg>

    <p><span>The expansion's new Nahantu region has great art direction.</span>
                </p>
  </div>

<p>Easily my favorite part of the expansion is the new class, the dexterity-based Spiritborn. The Spiritborn calls on the spirits of four creatures—jaguar, gorilla, eagle, and centipede—to rain down destruction on its foes. Any worries I had that the class would be too similar to the base game's animal-centric Druid class were dispelled when I actually got my hands on it. I didn't have time to try out all of its archetypes, but I specced into the fiery jaguar and poison-spreading centipede trees and found a lot to love.</p>
<p>There's a level of thoughtfulness and polish to the class that shows Blizzard really took its time in designing it. I'd love to see the company give all the classes some similar love—and while I'm wishing, I hope the next big thing Blizzard tackles is all of the game's skill trees. There are some mild tweaks in the new update, but the trees still feel a bit simplistic overall.</p>
<div>
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 40 40"><defs><clipPath id="arrow-blocks-right_svg__a"><path fill="none" d="M0 0h40v40H0z"></path></clipPath></defs><g fill="currentColor" clip-path="url(#arrow-blocks-right_svg__a)"><path d="M32 16h8v8h-8zm-8 8h8v8h-8zm-8 8h8v8h-8zm8-24h8v8h-8zm-8-8h8v8h-8zM0 16h16v8H0z"></path></g></svg>

    <p><span>The new Spiritborn class harnesses the power of creatures to do damage.</span>
                </p>
  </div>

<p>Also new in the expansion are mercenaries, a return of sorts of the "follower" system we had in <em>Diablo III</em>. Choose from four NPC mercs—a tank, a fighter, an archer, and a fire-wielding demon—to fight by your side, and level them up to unlock abilities and a new bartering system. I generally prefer a more lone-wolf style of gameplay in these types of games, but the mercenaries seem helpful, and they don't get in the way too much. I'll take their help.</p>

          
                  </div>
                    
        
          
    
    <div>
          
          
<figure>
    <div>
              <p>
                The mercenaries.
                              </p>
            </div>
                  <figcaption>
          <div>
    
    <p>
      The mercenaries.

          </p>
  </div>
        </figcaption>
            </figure>


<h2>Room for activities</h2>
<p><em>Diablo IV</em>'s endgame activities had already reached a much healthier state before the new update, but <em>Vessel of Hatred</em> adds even more ways to get sucked in.</p>
<p>The Kurast Undercity, a new multi-stage time-attack dungeon, was a big standout for me. You start with a timer of 100 seconds or so, and you fight through several levels of a dungeon, killing specific elite monsters along the way to extend your timer and enhance your rewards. There are several ways to tailor the rewards to your liking, and the whole thing feels like a healthy burst of adrenaline.</p>
<div>
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 40 40"><defs><clipPath id="arrow-blocks-right_svg__a"><path fill="none" d="M0 0h40v40H0z"></path></clipPath></defs><g fill="currentColor" clip-path="url(#arrow-blocks-right_svg__a)"><path d="M32 16h8v8h-8zm-8 8h8v8h-8zm-8 8h8v8h-8zm8-24h8v8h-8zm-8-8h8v8h-8zM0 16h16v8H0z"></path></g></svg>

    <p><span>The Kurast Undercity is a new multi-stage time-attack dungeon.</span>
                </p>
  </div>

<p>I didn't get a chance to test the Dark Citadel, the Diablo franchise's first multiplayer "raid" experience, but it's a big leap for the series. There are three "wings" to the dungeon, each culminating in a boss fight, and you can complete a wing and come back later for the others if you want. But you <em>will</em> need a party to play—at least two people are required, and four are strongly recommended. Teamwork mechanics, the hallmark of any raid, are a big part of the experience.</p>
<figure>
    <div>
              <p>
                The citadel is a new endgame raid.
                              </p>
            </div>
                  <figcaption>
          <div>
    
    <p>
      The citadel is a new endgame raid.

          </p>
  </div>
        </figcaption>
            </figure>

<p><em>Diablo</em> is a distinctly single-player experience for many players, so this mode may fall flat with a large part of the audience. If you want to play with others, though, the game's new party finder will help you group up with fellow adventurers, and not just for the raid. You can specify activities, though this isn't automatic matchmaking; the finder just helps you find a group of like-minded players. Regardless of your thoughts on raiding (I'm generally not a fan), the party finder is something people have been asking for since the game's launch, and I'm glad to see it finally arrive.</p>

          
                  </div>
                    
        
          
    
    <div>
          
          
<figure>
    <div>
              <p>
                There's a new party finder, and I hear some of you grumbling already.
                              </p>
            </div>
                  <figcaption>
          <div>
    
    <p>
      There's a new party finder, and I hear some of you grumbling already.

          </p>
  </div>
        </figcaption>
            </figure>


<h2>2.0</h2>
<figure>
    <div>
              <p>
                Eight new difficulties replace the previous four "world tiers."
                              </p>
            </div>
                  <figcaption>
          <div>
    
    <p>
      Eight new difficulties replace the previous four "world tiers."

          </p>
  </div>
        </figcaption>
            </figure><p>
The new version of <em>Diablo IV</em> is essentially a rework of the entire game, including progression and difficulty systems. The game now has eight difficulty levels (four standard and four unlockable "torment" difficulties), allowing for more granular control over your experience while giving you milestones to shoot for. It's a much better system than the convoluted "world tier" system we had previously.</p>
<p>The level cap has been lowered from 100 to 60, but there are now more points available for the Paragon system, which lets you continue leveling in the endgame. The Paragon system still feels a bit unwieldy to me, so hopefully Blizzard can continue to refine it in the future.</p>
<p><em>Vessel of Hatred</em> also brings back&nbsp;<em>Diablo II</em>'s "<a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2024/02/diablo-ii-streamer-finds-1-in-3-million-item-drop-instantly-sells-it-for-laughs/">runewords</a>," though the system is different in <em>Diablo IV. </em>Essentially, you can now slot two runes into any piece of gear that supports them, with one (a "rune of ritual") being a condition you need to meet to get a resource called "offering" and the other (a rune of invocation) determining the effect you'll get when you spend that resource. It's essentially a way to create your own skills. Cast a skill or travel a certain distance, for instance, to increase your critical hit chance or even get access to other classes' skills. The system seems fairly barebones at the moment, but there's plenty of room for expansion here, especially if Blizzard can balance all the effects.</p>
<p>Because Blizzard is once again shaking up several core systems, and because the community needs time to chew up and spit out the endgame, I can’t guarantee that hidden issues won’t start cropping up. I'm especially concerned about the fact that the game's pinnacle "ancestral" legendary gear seems to be a bit rarer than one would hope. Progression speed needs to stay snappy; <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2024/06/are-diablo-fans-getting-too-old-for-the-old-school-item-grind/">no one wants a return to tedious grinds</a>.</p>

          
                  </div>
                    
        
          
    
    <div>
        
        
        
        <div>
          
          
<p>What I <em>can</em> say is that Blizzard’s launch-era “we know best” attitude has given way to a much more open and community-centric position. The developer has introduced “public test realms” to the game, pre-season servers that let players test new updates before they go live. They're available for anyone to play and give feedback on, and Blizzard has shown it's listening—most of the complaints that arose during the past two PTRs were addressed by the time their seasons launched. This, more than anything else, gives me confidence in the game's future.</p>
<figure>
    <div>
              <p>
                Unfortunately, there's still plenty of this. Fortunately, none of it affects gameplay.
                              </p>
            </div>
                  <figcaption>
          <div>
    
    <p>
      Unfortunately, there's still plenty of this. Fortunately, none of it affects gameplay.

          </p>
  </div>
        </figcaption>
            </figure>

<p>Cosmetic microtransactions are still a thing, and they’re still the worst part of the game. You can ignore them completely, but designing a game around selling skins has unfortunate knock-on effects, as <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2022/09/im-still-worried-about-diablo-ivs-cosmetic-only-microtransactions/">I’ve complained about before</a>. If you’ll brook no microtransactions in your full-priced game (though the standard price for the base game has dropped from $70 to $50), you can safely move on with your life—nothing here will change your mind.</p>
<p>The expansion will get you the new class, new region (including new dungeons), new campaign, mercenaries, the raid, the Kurast Undercity, and the runewords system. Everyone who owns the base game will get all the new systems updates, including the new difficulty system and new gear.</p>
<p>Here’s my recommendation: If you bought the game and dropped off at some point, or if you were waiting for Blizzard to iron out the kinks, there’s never been a better time to check out the base game. If you find yourself enjoying it and want more,&nbsp;<em>Vessel of Hatred</em> is here and waiting for you.</p>
<p>With the impending Early Access release of the much-anticipated<em> <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2694490/Path_of_Exile_2/">Path of Exile 2</a>&nbsp;</em>coming in November, Blizzard needed to nail this. <em>Diablo</em> fans can rest assured that it did.</p>


          
                  </div>

                  
          <div>
    

    <p>
      Aaron is Ars Technica's Copy Chief. He has worked as an editor for over 17 years. In addition to editing features at Ars, he occasionally reviews board and video games. He lives in Chicago.
    </p>
  </div>


  


  


  
              </div>
  </article>


<div>
    <header>
      <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 40 26"><defs><clipPath id="most-read_svg__a"><path fill="none" d="M0 0h40v26H0z"></path></clipPath><clipPath id="most-read_svg__b"><path fill="none" d="M0 0h40v26H0z"></path></clipPath></defs><g clip-path="url(#most-read_svg__a)"><g fill="none" clip-path="url(#most-read_svg__b)"><path fill="currentColor" d="M20 2h.8q1.5 0 3 .6c.6.2 1.1.4 1.7.6 1.3.5 2.6 1.3 3.9 2.1.6.4 1.2.8 1.8 1.3 2.9 2.3 5.1 4.9 6.3 6.4-1.1 1.5-3.4 4-6.3 6.4-.6.5-1.2.9-1.8 1.3q-1.95 1.35-3.9 2.1c-.6.2-1.1.4-1.7.6q-1.5.45-3 .6h-1.6q-1.5 0-3-.6c-.6-.2-1.1-.4-1.7-.6-1.3-.5-2.6-1.3-3.9-2.1-.6-.4-1.2-.8-1.8-1.3-2.9-2.3-5.1-4.9-6.3-6.4 1.1-1.5 3.4-4 6.3-6.4.6-.5 1.2-.9 1.8-1.3q1.95-1.35 3.9-2.1c.6-.2 1.1-.4 1.7-.6q1.5-.45 3-.6zm0-2h-1c-1.2 0-2.3.3-3.4.6-.6.2-1.3.4-1.9.7-1.5.6-2.9 1.4-4.3 2.3-.7.5-1.3.9-1.9 1.4C2.9 8.7 0 13 0 13s2.9 4.3 7.5 7.9c.6.5 1.3 1 1.9 1.4 1.3.9 2.7 1.7 4.3 2.3.6.3 1.3.5 1.9.7 1.1.3 2.3.6 3.4.6h2c1.2 0 2.3-.3 3.4-.6.6-.2 1.3-.4 1.9-.7 1.5-.6 2.9-1.4 4.3-2.3.7-.5 1.3-.9 1.9-1.4C37.1 17.3 40 13 40 13s-2.9-4.3-7.5-7.9c-.6-.5-1.3-1-1.9-1.4-1.3-.9-2.8-1.7-4.3-2.3-.6-.3-1.3-.5-1.9-.7C23.3.4 22.1.1 21 .1h-1"></path><path fill="#ff4e00" d="M20 5c-4.4 0-8 3.6-8 8s3.6 8 8 8 8-3.6 8-8-3.6-8-8-8m0 11c-1.7 0-3-1.3-3-3s1.3-3 3-3 3 1.3 3 3-1.3 3-3 3"></path></g></g></svg>
      
    </header>
    <ol>
              <li>
                      
                    <div>
                          
              <p><span>
                <span>1.</span>
                <span>Teen achieves first NES Tetris “rebirth,” proves endless play is possible</span>
              </span>
                      </p></div>
          <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2024/10/nes-tetris-first-ever-rebirth-loops-past-level-255-and-back-to-zero/?itm_source=parsely-api" aria-label="Read Teen achieves first NES Tetris “rebirth,” proves endless play is possible">
          </a>
        </li>
                    <li>
                    <div>
                          
              <p><span>
                <span>2.</span>
                <span>Artist appeals copyright denial for prize-winning AI-generated work</span>
              </span>
                      </p></div>
          <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2024/10/artist-appeals-copyright-denial-for-prize-winning-ai-generated-work/?itm_source=parsely-api" aria-label="Read Artist appeals copyright denial for prize-winning AI-generated work">
          </a>
        </li>
                    <li>
                    <div>
                          
              <p><span>
                <span>3.</span>
                <span>Smart TVs are like “a digital Trojan Horse” in people’s homes</span>
              </span>
                      </p></div>
          <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2024/10/streaming-industry-has-unprecedented-surveillance-manipulation-capabilities/?itm_source=parsely-api" aria-label="Read Smart TVs are like “a digital Trojan Horse” in people’s homes">
          </a>
        </li>
                    <li>
                    <div>
                          
              <p><span>
                <span>4.</span>
                <span>Reports: China hacked Verizon and AT&amp;T, may have accessed US wiretap systems</span>
              </span>
                      </p></div>
          <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2024/10/reports-china-hacked-verizon-and-att-may-have-accessed-us-wiretap-systems/?itm_source=parsely-api" aria-label="Read Reports: China hacked Verizon and AT&amp;T, may have accessed US wiretap systems">
          </a>
        </li>
                    <li>
                    <div>
                          
              <p><span>
                <span>5.</span>
                <span>Hurricane Milton becomes second-fastest storm to reach Category 5 status</span>
              </span>
                      </p></div>
          <a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2024/10/hurricane-milton-becomes-second-fastest-storm-to-reach-category-5-status/?itm_source=parsely-api" aria-label="Read Hurricane Milton becomes second-fastest storm to reach Category 5 status">
          </a>
        </li>
                  </ol>
</div>


  

  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Assassin's Creed Valhalla finally gets Steam Achievements, two years later]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/assassins-creed-valhalla-finally-gets-steam-achievements-two-years-later</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/assassins-creed-valhalla-finally-gets-steam-achievements-two-years-later.1003485/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/assassins-creed-valhalla-finally-gets-steam-achievements-two-years-later<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>



            <p>A little under two years since it first debuted on Valve's PC storefront, <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/assassins-creed-valhalla">Assassin's Creed Valhalla</a> has finally got itself those lovely Steam Achievements.</p>
<p>Back in December 2022, Ubisoft confirmed that <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/ubisoft-confirms-assassins-creed-valhalla-wont-get-steam-achievements">Assassin's Creed Valhalla wouldn't be getting Achievements on Steam</a>. This led to a certain amount of upset from the community, which argued Achievements were a key feature of Steam.</p>
<p>However, fast-forward to today, and those Achievements are now there.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Assassin’s Creed Valhalla Review - ASSASSIN’S CREED VALHALLA XBOX ONE GAMEPLAY" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9I1fWPUQpZU?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Assassin’s Creed Valhalla Review - ASSASSIN’S CREED VALHALLA XBOX ONE GAMEPLAY</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9I1fWPUQpZU?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/9I1fWPUQpZU?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Our Zoe's review of Assassin's Creed Valhalla. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9I1fWPUQpZU" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>As shown on Assassin's Creed Valhalla's <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/2208920/history/">SteamDB</a> page, the team added in Achievements for the game last night.</p>
<p>The addition of Steam Achievements in Assassin's Creed Valhalla marks another step forward in Ubisoft's full return to the PC storefront. Last month, Ubisoft announced its <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/all-new-ubisoft-games-to-release-day-one-on-steam-starting-next-february">new releases are set to launch day one on Steam</a>, something the company has eschewed for a while now.</p>
<p>This will all begin with <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/assassins-creed-codename-red">Assassin's Creed Shadows</a>, which is set to release on 14th February next year. Meanwhile, Ubisoft recently announced last year's <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/assassins-creed-mirage-comes-to-steam-this-month-as-ubisoft-returns-to-valves-storefront">Assassin's Creed Mirage will also be coming to Steam</a> later this month.</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/image-(398)_8oXJ7Oj.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>SteamDB/Eurogamer</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>For more on Assassin's Creed, a recent report suggested <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/assassins-creed-shadows-co-op-mode-in-development-report">Ubisoft is working on a co-op mode for Shadows</a>. Should this report prove accurate, it would mark the studio's first foray back to Assassin's Creed co-op gameplay in over a decade.</p>
<p>As for Steam, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/steam-families-officially-launches-out-of-beta">Valve opened up Steam Families to the wider public</a> last month. Steam Families replaces both Steam Family Sharing and Steam Family View, giving users a one stop shop to manage who can access what and when.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch 2 Will Support Every Unreal Engine 5 Feature, Possibly Even MegaLights; Performance Differences With the Steam Deck Won’t Matter]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-unreal-engine-5-support-megalights/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-switch-2-will-support-every-unreal-engine-5-feature-possibly-even-megalights-performance-differences-with-the-steam-deck-won%E2%80%99t-matter.1003473/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-unreal-engine-5-support-megalights/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>While the <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-design-pictures-specs/">Nintendo Switch 2</a> won't be as powerful as the current generation consoles from Sony and Microsoft, the upcoming system will support every Unreal Engine 5 feature, possibly even the recently revealed <a href="https://wccftech.com/epic-games-unreal-fest-showcases-new-features-for-unreal-engine-5/">MegaLights</a>, although with some caveats.</p>
<p>Speaking during the latest episode of their weekly podcast, the tech experts at Digital Foundry replied to a fan question asking if the next Nintendo console will support the latest UE5 features, saying that features like Lumen, Nanite, and Virtual Shadows Maps will surely be supported by virtue of the architecture of the system alone. Even MegaLights could be supported, as all that matters are the performance targets. In addition, there could be some Nintendo Switch 2-specific versions of all these technologies that will allow them to run decently on the system with some obvious trade-offs, and if they are not too memory intensive. Even hardware Lumen could run on the system with the proper tweaks.</p>
<p>Given how much third-party support the original Switch received, something that was made possible by the system supporting the Unreal Engine, and that most of these developers are moving onto the new version of the engine, there's no doubt that the Nintendo Switch 2 will support the vast majority of the Unreal Engine 5 features. Not every game will scale well, and some will have some compromises, but looking at what has been accomplished on its predecessor, there's no doubt that we will see some impressive showcases for a mobile platform on it.</p>
<p>Digital Foundry also commented on how the Nintendo Switch 2 handheld mode performance differences with the Steam Deck could impact the platform. According to the tech experts, there won't be much of an impact, as the two platforms offer substantially different experiences. The Steam Deck is a little clunkier to use and, most of all, lacks the Nintendo games that drive the sales of its platforms. On the other hand, developers aren't targeting the Steam Deck specifically, while Nintendo Switch 2 games will be optimized to run on the system and take advantage of its feature set, which is said to include the <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-custom-dlss/">NVIDIA DLSS upscaler</a>. The only scenario where a difference in performance could matter is in a drought situation where multiplatform games fill in the gap left by the lack of first-party releases</p>
<p><iframe title="DF Direct Weekly #183: Until Dawn Has Issues, Nintendo Ryujinx Takedown, UE5 MegaLights, FF16 Xbox?" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/gxwB2f5s850?start=5704&amp;feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>The Nintendo Switch 2 has yet to be officially revealed. We will keep you updated on the system as soon as possible, so stay tuned for all the latest news.</p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stylish menus in Persona and Metaphor: ReFantazio "really annoying to do", says director]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/stylish-menus-in-persona-and-metaphor-refantazio-really-annoying-to-do-says-director</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/stylish-menus-in-persona-and-metaphor-refantazio-really-annoying-to-do-says-director.1003467/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/stylish-menus-in-persona-and-metaphor-refantazio-really-annoying-to-do-says-director<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>"It takes a lot of time."</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Metaphor_-ReFantazio_20240927102632.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Atlus</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>Atlus' RPGs - the likes of the Persona series and this week's <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/metaphor-refantazio">Metaphor: ReFantazio</a> - are well known for their stylish menus, but it turns out they're "really annoying to do".</p>
<p>That's according to director Katsura Hashino who discussed the menu design with <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/7/24262357/persona-metaphor-menu-design">The Verge</a>.</p>
<p>"In general, the way most game developers make UI is very simple. That’s what we try to do as well - we try to keep things simple, practical, and usable," said Hashino.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Metaphor: ReFantazio Review" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ct98clbQw5k?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Metaphor: ReFantazio Review</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ct98clbQw5k?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/ct98clbQw5k?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Metaphor: ReFantazio video review<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ct98clbQw5k" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>"But maybe the reason that we’ve achieved both [functionality and beauty] is that we have unique designs that we make for each and every menu. This is actually really annoying to do. We have separate programs running for each of them as well. Whether it’s the shop menu or the main menu, when you open them up there’s a whole separate program running and a separate design that goes into making it. It takes a lot of time."</p><p>From selecting options in battle to evolving Persona or Archetypes, the menu designs in Atlus' games have been praised for their balance of flashiness and usability, so perhaps that annoyance is all worth it. On the other hand, some players are put-off by how busy they are.</p>
<p>Over time, Atlus has evolved its menu style to achieve that balance. "How we achieve both of them together is by the know-how that we built up over years," said Hashino.</p>
<p>For instance, there were angular elements in <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/persona-5">Persona 5</a>'s menus that hindered legibility. "It was impossible to read at first," he said, "so we did lots of tweaking and adjusting so it became legible."</p>
<figure data-count="2" role="group">
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Metaphor_-ReFantazio_20240915184032.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Atlus / Eurogamer</cite></span></figcaption></figure>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Metaphor_-ReFantazio_20240914113719.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Atlus</cite></span></figcaption></figure>
<figcaption>From menus to battle, Metapho: ReFantazio exemplifies Atlus' style</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Metaphor: ReFantazio is the latest RPG from Atlus, building upon the systems and style of the Persona games.</p>
<p>"Persona veteran Atlus flexes its expertise with a fresh take on high fantasy. What it lacks in subtlety, it makes up for in grandeur and heart," reads our <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/metaphor-refantazio-review">Eurogamer Metaphor: ReFantazio review</a>.</p>
<p>Metaphor: ReFantazio will be released on 11th October across PS4, PS5, Xbox Series X/S, and PC.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Traveller's Hymn is a free open-world grid-based RPG, and it's out today]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/travellers-hymn-is-a-free-open-world-grid-based-rpg-and-its-out-today</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/travellers-hymn-is-a-free-open-world-grid-based-rpg-and-its-out-today.1003458/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/travellers-hymn-is-a-free-open-world-grid-based-rpg-and-its-out-today<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/travellers-hymn-header.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Aquatic Ranger Studio</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p><a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/travellers-hymn">Traveller's Hymn</a> is a top-down, grid-based, open-world adventure game (and breathe), set in a dark fantasy land. The tileset is lovely, as are the little dialogue boxes and menus and the gentle bob of your backpack-ridden character as they walk. Basically, it looks like it's worth everyone's time, particularly because there's one big twist here - it's entirely free.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>Developers Aquatic Ranger Studio were asked over on <a href="https://x.com/AquaticRangerGS/status/1842763992659304902">Xwitter</a> why the game was free, considering people likely would've paid good money for something that looks so breezy. They said that it's their "first attempt at gamedev", and that "we've only spent 4 months on it because it started as an experimental project". Essentially, they felt like the game was good enough to publish, but the "contents are a bit lacking", so didn't want to charge for it.</p>
 <p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span></p><p>The devs say the game clocks in roughly at "4-5 hours" and it'll see you explore, battle, and loot for some nice rewards. What's staggering is that there are over 20 unique locations, over 100 enemies and NPCs, and over 100 items. All from a three-person team in the space of a few months? Outrageous. Apparently there's also a hunger system but we can pretend that doesn't exist.</p><p>There aren't any plans outlined right now for further development, but presumably, they're going to see how it does and decide whether it's worth investing the time to turn it into an actual, full fledged release, perhaps over Steam early access. We'll just have to wait and see.</p>
<p>If you want to give it a try, Traveller's Hymn is out sometime today over on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3249180/Travellers_Hymn/">Steam</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Epic wins major Google lawsuit, further opening up Android phones to third-party stores]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/epic-wins-major-google-lawsuit-further-opening-up-android-phones-to-third-party-stores</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/epic-wins-major-google-lawsuit-further-opening-up-android-phones-to-third-party-stores.1003449/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/epic-wins-major-google-lawsuit-further-opening-up-android-phones-to-third-party-stores<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Untitled-1_rjzeYkS.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Epic Games / Pexels / Eurogamer</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
Epic Games has won a major victory in its ongoing legal battle against Google, which a US judge has now ruled operates an illegal monopoly via its smartphone app store. 
</p>
<p>
Google - which is appealing the verdict - has been ordered to allow third-party storefront apps such as the Epic Games Store to be made available from the Google Play Store in the US next year. 
</p>
<p>
For at least the next three years, Google will also be forced to allow users to pay via alternate means, rather than just Google Play Billing, from which Google takes a 30 percent cut. 
</p>
<p>
In a <a href="https://blog.google/outreach-initiatives/public-policy/epic-games-verdict-appeal/">statement</a> released in response to the verdict, Google said it would push back against the ruling and request a pause on its required changes "to maintain a consistent and safe experience for users and developers".
</p>
<p>
Google has argued the verdict should be reviewed as it appears to <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/apple-trumpets-resounding-victory-in-epic-anti-trust-lawsuit-appeal">contradict the ruling of Epic's less-successful Apple trial</a> - and that because it exists in competition to Apple, it does not have a monopoly either.
</p>
<p>
"The Epic verdict missed the obvious," Google spokesperson Lee-Anne Mulholland wrote. "Apple and Android clearly compete."
</p>
<p>Epic Games boss Tim Sweeney, meanwhile, had this pithy pun:</p> <div>

<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>
Google has pointed to Android already being "open" - and more so than iOS - as it allows side-loading and lets users download the Epic Games Store currently. 
</p>
<p>
This is true, of course, though Epic Games' fight here has been to streamline the process of getting to the Epic Games Store - which currently requires a fiddly process where users see various "scare screens" designed to put them off. 
</p>
<p>
Indeed, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/epic-launches-major-new-lawsuit-in-app-store-fight-this-time-against-samsung-and-google">Epic Games has already launched a fresh lawsuit against both Google and former partner Samsung</a> for, it says, pre-emptively making the process to download the Epic Game Store on Android phones more difficult.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Best SSD for Gaming Is on Sale for Prime Day]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/samsung-990-pro-ps5-ssd-deal-amazon-prime-day</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-best-ssd-for-gaming-is-on-sale-for-prime-day.1003440/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/samsung-990-pro-ps5-ssd-deal-amazon-prime-day<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">The Samsung 990 Pro is the fastest PCIe M.2 SSD on the market.</h2></div><div><section><p>For <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/amazon-october-prime-day-2024">October Prime Day</a>, Amazon is offering an excellent deal on the <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-ssd">best gaming SSD</a>. Right now you can get the blazing fast <a href="https://zdcs.link/KJnKY?object_uuid=0fc2eead-2f22-49cc-b896-b7d5fefe55ca&amp;t=article" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Samsung 990 Pro 2TB</a> PCIe 4.0 M.2 solid state drive (SSD) for only $139.99. This is the lowest price we've seen this year and $10 less than the previous Prime Day deal back in July. <a href="https://zdcs.link/aeppoA?object_uuid=0fc2eead-2f22-49cc-b896-b7d5fefe55ca&amp;t=article" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">4TB</a> and <a href="https://zdcs.link/QLnnE4?object_uuid=0fc2eead-2f22-49cc-b896-b7d5fefe55ca&amp;t=article" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">1TB</a> models are also on sale. The 990 Pro is still considered one of the fastest PCIe 4.0 SSDs on the market. It's also compatible with the PlayStation 5 console right out of the box, especially since it's pre-equipped with a low-profile heatsink.</p><h2>Prime Day Deal: Samsung 990 Pro PS5 SSD with Heatsink</h2><div><div id="188080" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p><h3>Samsung 990 Pro 2TB PCIe Gen4 SSD with Heatsink</h3></p></div><div id="208332" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p><h3>Samsung 990 Pro 4TB PCIe Gen4 SSD with Heatsink</h3></p></div><div id="208333" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p><h3>Samsung 990 Pro 1TB PCIe Gen4 SSD with Heatsink</h3></p></div></div><p>The <a href="https://zdcs.link/eBo3X?object_uuid=0fc2eead-2f22-49cc-b896-b7d5fefe55ca&amp;t=article" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">990 Pro</a> is the successor to the venerable 980 Pro and is Samsung's flagship SSD. The 990 Pro has been updated with Samsung's newest Pascal controller and 7th gen TLC NAND flash chips which are manufactured in-house. It boasts sequential speeds of 7,450MB/s read and 6,900MB/s write and random speeds of 1400K read and 1550K IOPS write, which is up to 50% faster per watt than the 980 Pro. This is absolutely the best boot drive you can get for your gaming PC, especially since 2TB is currently the best compromise between capacity and price point.</p><p>For console gamers, the Samsung 990 Pro also happens to be one of the <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-ps5-ssd">best SSDs for the PlayStation 5</a>. In fact, performance-wise, it's overkill since the stock PS5 SSD only has speeds of up to 5,600MB/s. This 990 Pro  comes pre-equipped with a low-profile aluminum heatsink that's guaranteed to fit in both the PS5 and PS5 Slim consoles. It also back by a 5 year warranty; by the time your warranty runs out, you might have already moved onto the PS6.</p><p>If you want to compare this deal with other PlayStation 5 compatible options, here's a list of <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-ps5-ssd">our favorite PS5 SSDs</a>. If you're looking for deals on other PS5 accessories, check out the <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-playstation-ps5-deals">best PS5 deals</a> going on right now (we update it often). If you don't yet own a PS5 console, you're in luck. The <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ps5-slim-october-prime-day-2024">PS5 Slim</a> is currently on sale for Prime Day, and Sony recently announced a more powerful <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/where-to-buy-ps5-pro">PS5 Pro</a> that is currently up for preorder and ships out next month. For all other deals, head over to our <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/amazon-october-prime-day-2024">Prime Day megapost</a> to see our cherry-picked list of the best deals we've found.</p><h3>Are October Prime Day Deals as good as Black Friday?</h3><p>Although Black Friday is still the overall best time to buy just about anything every year, <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/prime-day-vs-black-friday-deals">October Prime Day is just as good as Black Friday</a> for many different items. Amazon's own devices that are currently on sale likely won't go much lower in price. The same goes for most of the deals we've featured on this list, which are at some of their lowest prices of the year so far. If you are unsure whether or not you're getting a good deal on anything, you can reference specific products on the <a href="https://camelcamelcamel.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">CamelCamelCamel website</a> to see historical Amazon pricing.</p><h2>More Prime Day Deals on Console Storage Upgrades</h2><div data-cy="catalog-view-trigger"><div><div><p>PS5, PC Compatible (DRAM)</p></div><p><h3>Samsung 990 PRO 2TB NVMe M.2 SSD (7450MB/s) with Heatsink</h3></p></div><div><div><p>PS5, PC Compatible (DRAM)</p></div><p><h3>WD Black SN850X 2TB NVMe M.2 SSD (7300MB/s)</h3></p></div><div><p><h3>WD Black C50 1TB Storage Expansion Card</h3></p></div><div><p><h3>Seagate 1TB Storage Expansion Card</h3></p></div><div><div><p>Nintendo Switch Compatible</p></div><p><h3>SanDisk Ultra 1.5TB Micro SDXC Card</h3></p></div><div><div><p>Nintendo Switch Compatible</p></div><p><h3>Teamgroup A2 Pro Plus 1TB U3 A2 V30 Micro SDXC Card</h3></p></div><div><div><p>Nintendo Switch Compatible</p></div><p><h3>Silicon Power 512GB U3 A1 V30 Micro SDXC Card</h3></p></div><div><div><p>PS5, PC Compatible (DRAM)</p></div><p><h3>XPG Gammix S70 Blade 2TB NVMe M.2 SSD (7400MB/s)</h3></p></div><div><div><p>PS5, PC Compatible (DRAM-Less)</p></div><p><h3>Nextorage 2TB NVMe M.2 SSD (7400MB/s)</h3></p></div><div><div><p>PS5, PC Compatible (DRAM)</p></div><p><h3>Lexar NM790 2TB NVMe M.2 SSD (74000MB/s) with Heatsink</h3></p></div></div><p><em>Eric Song is the IGN commerce manager in charge of finding the best gaming and tech deals every day. When Eric isn't hunting for deals for other people at work, he's hunting for deals for himself during his free time.</em></p></section><div><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Oct 8, 2024 8:55 am</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Detroit: Become Human Shoots Through 10 Million Sold 6 Years After Launch]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/detroit-become-human-shoots-through-10-million-sold-6-years-after-launch</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/detroit-become-human-shoots-through-10-million-sold-6-years-after-launch.1003434/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/detroit-become-human-shoots-through-10-million-sold-6-years-after-launch<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p><a href="https://www.ign.com/games/detroit-become-human">Detroit: Become Human</a> has sold over 10 million copies, developer Quantic Dream has announced.</p><p>That’s 10 million paid units across PlayStation and PC, Quantic Dream qualified. Given Detroit: Become Human is on-and-off a part of various subscription services such as PS Plus, its total number of players will be much higher.</p><p>"We are extremely grateful to each and everyone out there who played the game," Quantic Dream CEO Guillaume de Fondaumière <a href="https://x.com/GdeFondaumiere/status/1843335782947532811" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">tweeted</a>. "You mean the world to us and we couldn't have achieved this incredible milestone without every single one of you!"</p><p>Detroit: Become Human is a sci-fi thriller that first launched on PlayStation 4 in May 2018, before launching on PC in December 2019, and followed Quantic Dream’s other PlayStation interactive thrillers Heavy Rain and Beyond: Two Souls. IGN’s <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2018/05/24/detroit-become-human-review">Detroit: Become Human review</a> returned an 8/10. We said: “Detroit: Become Human is a wonderfully silly interactive drama that meaningfully bends to your will.”</p><p>Since going on sale, <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/detroit-become-human-manga">Detroit: Become Human was turned into a manga</a>, but there’s been no mention of a sequel, a remaster, a full-blown remake, or even a native PS5 version. On the PS5, Detroit: Become Human runs via backwards compatibility using the PS4 Pro version of the game.</p><p>As for Quantic Dream, it’s still working on <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/star-wars-eclipse">Star Wars Eclipse</a>, a new action adventure game set in the High Republic era of Star Wars, although we haven’t heard a peep out of the game in years. Last year, the studio told IGN that <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/star-wars-eclipse-still-alive-quantic-dream-insists-its-simmering">Star Wars Eclipse development was “simmering.”</a></p><p><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sonic Rumble won't include gacha mechanics as Sega says they're "shunned" in West]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/sonic-rumble-wont-include-gacha-mechanics-as-sega-says-theyre-shunned-in-west</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sonic-rumble-wont-include-gacha-mechanics-as-sega-says-theyre-shunned-in-west.1003428/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/sonic-rumble-wont-include-gacha-mechanics-as-sega-says-theyre-shunned-in-west<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>"The monetisation model was designed from the beginning based on global standards."</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Sonic-Rumble---Announce-Trailer-0-19-screenshot-(1).png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Sega</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>Sonic Rumble, Sega's forthcoming mobile and PC game, won't have gacha mechanics because they're not popular in the west.</p>
<p>The 32-player battle royale will be free-to-play but won't be pay-to-win, with a season pass as its main monetisation.</p>
<p>"We're aiming for a casual system that allows you to just buy what you want quickly for a small, fixed amount, rather than a gacha system that gives you a certain probability of obtaining items," game director Makoto Tase told <a href="https://automaton-media.com/en/news/sega-avoided-gacha-and-pay-to-win-mechanics-in-sonic-rumble-because-they-know-overseas-players-dont-like-them/">Automaton</a>.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Sonic Rumble - Announce Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Em6-SjjaYQE?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Sonic Rumble - Announce Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Em6-SjjaYQE?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/Em6-SjjaYQE?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Sonic Rumble - Announce Trailer<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Em6-SjjaYQE" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>Added Sonic franchise lead Takashi Iizuka: "In the Japanese and Asian markets, it's common to have to spend tens of thousands of yen [in a game] until you draw a rare character and finally get to move on. But this is not the case in the global market, especially for an action game like Sonic Rumble, where players should be able to enjoy the game on an equal footing. The starting point of this project itself was to make it a mobile game that would sell globally. Therefore, the monetisation model was designed from the beginning based on global standards."</p>
<p>Instead, players will spend in-game Rings on cosmetics, which will be updated daily. Rings are obtained through play to raise your score and double as in-game currency.</p>
<p>Monetisation through gacha mechanics - that is, spending money for a random item - have "not been very successful when it comes to games targeted towards worldwide audiences of all ages," said Tase. "Also, such mechanics tend to be shunned overseas, so we didn’t think it was the right choice for this project."</p>
<p>Sonic Rumble has been developed with <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/angry-birds">Angry Birds</a> studio Rovio, which Sega acquired in 2023. Company profits have <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/segas-acquisition-of-angry-birds-maker-rovio-helps-boost-profits-by-1815">since been boosted significantly</a>.</p>
<p>The game is a <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/fall-guys">Fall Guys</a>-esque battle royale with multiple modes for players to race through or battle for Rings. It's set for <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/sega-announces-sonic-and-dc-comic-collaboration-at-sonic-central-stream">release across mobile and PC this winter</a>.</p>
<p>The gacha comments are certainly interesting when compared to the likes of <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/companies/square-enix">Square Enix</a>. Its <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/final-fantasy-7-ever-crisis-turns-square-enixs-best-into-an-avalanche-of-money-grabbing-tactics">Final Fantasy 7: Ever Crisis</a> game is rife with money-grabbing tactics, although the company's <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/square-enix-sales-drop-year-on-year-despite-release-of-final-fantasy-7-rebirth">latest financial report</a> states its mobile games have seen declining sales "due to weak sales of existing titles".</p>
<p>The company has recently closed a number of mobile games in the west, including <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/another-final-fantasy-mobile-game-ends-global-service-this-time-the-one-with-ariana-grande">Final Fantasy: Brave Exvius</a>, which included gacha mechanics - notably the Japanese version will remain in service.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Combo Critters is a free, crunchy creature collecting deck builder from the Shotgun King devs]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/combo-critters-is-a-free-crunchy-creature-collecting-deck-builder-from-the-shotgun-king-devs</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/combo-critters-is-a-free-crunchy-creature-collecting-deck-builder-from-the-shotgun-king-devs.1003416/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/combo-critters-is-a-free-crunchy-creature-collecting-deck-builder-from-the-shotgun-king-devs<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
  

        <p>A nutritious start to the day</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/combo-critters.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>PUNKCAKE Délicieux/Rock Paper Shotgun</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>Tiny deck builder Combo Critters exhibits the winning combination common to both small games and radical breakfast cereals - it’s very crunchy, but also bright, sugary and moreish. If <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2024/feb/27/kelloggs-ceo-cereal-for-dinner">Thaddius Cornflakes</a> had recommended struggling families play Combo Critters instead of eating Cookie Crisp for dinner, I imagine the backlash would have been far more reserved. Cookie Crisp tastes like like someone poured Splenda on a packing peanut fished out from a puddle. Combo Critters, though? Pretty tasty, and also <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-best-free-pc-games">free</a> from <a href="https://punkcake.itch.io/combo-critters">Itch here</a>.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>Combo Critters is the latest from PUNKCAKE Délicieux, of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/shotgun-king-is-roguelike-chess-with-a-shotgun">Shotgun King</a> and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/this-mathematical-tactics-rpg-is-like-the-countdown-numbers-round-with-added-violence">Super Algebrawl</a> fame. Each level, you form a team of six critters by drawing and discarding, then try to beat your opponent’s score. Each critter has a score, an alignment, and a special effect. Some critters play nice with each other, some don’t. I currently have an ice cream in my hand that adds fifteen to its score if paired with another critter called Cloud, but I also need at least one other ‘sugar’ type critter to score at all. Here's the description:</p>
<blockquote>Welcome to Combo Critters, a unique strategy game where the smallest creatures pack the biggest punch! Build a team of tiny yet powerful critters, each with unique abilities and traits. Maximize their interactions and synergies to achieve the highest possible score and outwit your opponents.</blockquote>
<p>Also, get this: It’s not a bloody roguelike. You get to a NEW stage and if you FAIL the stage you just START that stage over and TRY AGAIN. Is this legal, I ask?</p>
<p>I do have to whine briefly though: Combo Critters refuses to explain itself whatsoever, including what certain status effects and other terms mean. This feels like such an obvious oversight that I’m wondering if it’s a deliberate choice - the proverbial dump in the cereal. Perhaps it’s a ploy to command your full attention and teach you an important lesson - for how many people do we look at, but never really see? A lesson on empathy? Pretty rich coming from the bastards who couldn’t even empathise with my need for a tutorial, that. Anyway - cool game, lovely soundtrack, very free. Enjoy!</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Throne and Liberty Already Had 3 Million Players in Its Debut Week, Says Amazon]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/throne-and-liberty-already-had-3-million-players-in-its-debut-week-says-amazon/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/throne-and-liberty-already-had-3-million-players-in-its-debut-week-says-amazon.1003398/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/throne-and-liberty-already-had-3-million-players-in-its-debut-week-says-amazon/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>It's been a week since the free-to-play Unreal Engine 4-powered MMORPG Throne and Liberty launched globally on PC, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series S|X, and publisher Amazon Games has now shared the first promising figures on player numbers. According to Amazon, over three million players have ventured into the world of Solisium during the first seven days of availability. Altogether, they have spent more than 24 million hours in the game, an average of eight each. The game fared well on Twitch, too, with more than 11 million hours watched on the streaming platform.</p>
<p>Christoph Hartmann, VP at Amazon Games, said in a statement:</p>
<p><em>Bringing Throne and Liberty to players around the world has been a huge shared undertaking by our team and our friends at NCSOFT, and we’re so pleased to see the results as players join the game. We’re only getting started, and we have a series of updates planned including our first castle siege coming soon.</em></p>
<p>We recently <a href="https://wccftech.com/throne-and-liberty-pre-launch-qa-new-weapons-and-pvp-modes-coming-soon/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">interviewed</a> Daniel Lafuente (Globalization Design Manager at Amazon Games), who teased some of the upcoming updates for the MMORPG. According to the official roadmap, November will see the first major guild events in the form of the first Tax Delivery Event and Castle Sieges. Amazon Games is also planning to launch Arena Season 1 for the 3v3 mode and possibly the two-star co-op dungeons as well.</p>
<p>The Korean version of Throne and Liberty already saw the introduction of a whole new mountainous region called Talandre, where players can even exploit water currents to get an advantage during conquest battles. In Talandre, players will find four new field bosses and two new arch-bosses to defeat. There are also new systems called Runes and Trait Resonance. All of these things will be added in due time to the global version.</p>
<p>Amazon Games isn't new to big launches, with <a href="https://wccftech.com/new-world-had-over-1-million-players-on-day-one-character-transfers-coming-next-week/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">New World</a> and <a href="https://wccftech.com/lost-ark-had-over-4-7-million-players-says-amazon-who-wants-to-be-the-most-customer-obsessed-company-in-games/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Lost Ark</a> both setting records right away. However, both games saw massive reductions in the respective player bases over time, especially New World. Still, the latter game largely suffered because of a lack of content, and this likely won't be an issue with Throne and Liberty, as noted above.</p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Commandos: Origins Demo Released for PC and Xbox Series S|X]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/commandos-origins-demo-released-for-pc-and-xbox-series-sx/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/commandos-origins-demo-released-for-pc-and-xbox-series-s-x.1003392/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/commandos-origins-demo-released-for-pc-and-xbox-series-sx/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Kalypso Media and Claymore Game Studios announced the release of a demo for the upcoming real-time tactics game <a href="https://wccftech.com/commandos-origins-gets-new-trailer-ahead-of-gamescom/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Commandos: Origins</a>. The demo is available only on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3137720/Commandos_Origins__Demo/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PC</a> and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/commandos-origins-demo/9nq8p31k009d" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Xbox Series S|X</a>, although the full game is also launching on Xbox One, PlayStation 4, and PlayStation 5.</p>
<p>In this test mission, players will step into the iconic boots of the Green Beret and Marine and be immersed in the heart of tactical warfare. They have to sabotage a cutting-edge German radar system responsible for a shocking surge in RAF casualties. The Green Beret is adept with both his combat knife and his Colt M1911. However, sometimes, it's just more effective to use a sound decoy to distract the soldiers and slip past unnoticed. The Marine, on the other hand, uses his throwing knives with deadly precision and is an expert at throwing a simple rock to distract guards.</p>
<p>Set against the backdrop of the Channel Islands during World War II, the Commandos will use their unique skills to sabotage a German radar system, showcasing the exciting gameplay that Commandos: Origins promises.&nbsp;This demo-exclusive test mission, Operation: Prelude, is a sneak peek at the intricate gameplay mechanics and stealth tactics that await players in the full release.</p>
<p>The full game will include fourteen missions set in authentic World War II environments, ranging from the barren Arctic to the African desert. Players will be able to select six Commandos: Jack O’Hara “the Green Beret”, Thomas “the Sapper” Hancock, Francis T. “the Sniper” Woolridge, Samuel “the Driver” Brooklyn, James “the Marine” Blackwood, and Rene “the Spy” Duchamp.</p>
<p>Commandos: Origins is still scheduled to launch in 2024, even though there's only a couple and a half months left before the end of the year. It will be added to Game Pass PC and console on day one.</p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fallout: Nuevo México Trailer Eliminates Concerns of Cancellation]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/fallout-nuevo-mexico-new-trailer/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fallout-nuevo-m%C3%A9xico-trailer-eliminates-concerns-of-cancellation.1003386/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/fallout-nuevo-mexico-new-trailer/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Rejoice, Fallout fans – there’s a new trailer for Fallout: Nuevo México, and it comes months after concerns surfaced that the project was going to be cancelled. In the latest trailer, which is a meaty three minutes long, we get a new look at the game-sized mod that promises to breathe a fresh lease of life into Fallout: New Vegas.</p>



<p>It’s potentially more ambitious than Fallout: London, which was released recently on the Fallout 4 platform. Building Fallout: Nuevo México in Fallout: New Vegas’ engine has proven to be a trifle tougher than manipulating the tools available in Fallout 4.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-viva-mexico">Viva México</h2>



<p>Earlier this year, concerns surfaced regarding <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fallout-nuevo-mexico-on-hold/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the future of Nuevo México</a>, a game-sized Fallout: New Vegas mod with huge potential. It was announced that the project was on an ‘indefinite hold’ following the departure of Zapshock, the mod’s lead developer. It came mere weeks after the indefinite cancellation of Fallout: London, a similarly ambitious mod for Fallout 4.</p>



<p>However, Fallout: London would go on to be released weeks later, while Fallout: Nuevo México has been shrouded in silence for months.</p>



<p>This latest trailer helps to dispel fears that it’ll never make it to the market:</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Fallout: México - Official Reveal Trailer | 🇲🇽" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/zoh5HxjV81M?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>







<p>Per the mod’s synopsis on YouTube:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>Mexico City is the largest city in North America and serves as the biggest hub in Fallout: Nuevo México. While still largely under development, we are thrilled to finally reveal this iconic wasteland. </p>



<p>Once the vibrant heart of a massive metropolis, Mexico City now lies in ruin, a battleground for factions struggling for dominance and survival. From the decaying colonia of Chapultepec to the submerged canals of Xochimilco, the city is a haunting blend of beauty and brutality.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>The update doesn’t mention the recent hold, nor does it address the radio silence that has been in place for the last few months. It’s just solid news that the mod is moving forward once again, and not only that but it looks brilliant on-screen.</p>



<p>Are you excited about Fallout: Nuevo México? Let us know on the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/detroit-become-human-10-million-copies/">Detroit: Become Human has sold 10 million copies</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Detroit: Become Human Has Sold 10 Million Copies]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/detroit-become-human-10-million-copies/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/detroit-become-human-has-sold-10-million-copies.1003383/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/detroit-become-human-10-million-copies/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>In 2018, Detroit: Become Human hit the market and delivered an emotional, heart-wrenching experience to fans worldwide. As one of the best ‘choice-and-consequence’ games out there,e Detroit: Become Human puts players in control of several characters, all of whom can ultimately become intertwined through a dramatic and immersive story.</p>



<p>It was remarkably well received, and to this day, people are still raving about it. Recently, the team at Quantic Dream revealed that the game has officially hit 10 million (paid) copies sold across PlayStation and PC.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-just-a-little-while-longer">Just a Little While Longer</h2>



<p>Detroit: Become Human offers one of the most engaging stories you’ll ever play. From the perspective of several characters, you’ll embark on an intense journey that details the uprising of ‘synths’ or ‘androids’ against human oppressors and masters. </p>



<p>Whether you’re playing as Kara, a protective housekeeper, or Connor, a conflicted investigator who must align closely with human law enforcement officers, you’ll be exploring multiple angles of a story where one wrong choice could mean the irrevocable death of a character.</p>



<p>Think Beyond Two Souls or Heavy Rain but in a universe that could one day be our reality.</p>



<p>In a recent post on X, Guillaume de Fondaumière, the CEO of Quantic Dream, said:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>The entire Quantic Dream team is joining me to proudly announce that (Detroit: Become Human) has now sold in excess of 10 million (paid) units on PlayStation and PC. </p>



<p>We are extremely grateful to each and everyone out there who played the game. You mean the world to us and we couldn’t have achieved this incredible milestone without every single one of you!</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Around the time that Detroit: Become Human was released, Quantic Dream came under fire for allegedly fostering a toxic working environment, which forced a reform at the studio. Despite that, fans were – and still are – hungry for a follow-up title to Detroit: Become Human, which would perfectly translate into a live-action adaptation at any time.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the latest results from the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/epic-v-google-play-store-third-party/">Epic v. Google court case</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Epic v. Google: Tech Titan Must Open Google Play Store to Rival Apps, Judge Rules]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/epic-v-google-play-store-third-party/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/epic-v-google-tech-titan-must-open-google-play-store-to-rival-apps-judge-rules.1003377/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/epic-v-google-play-store-third-party/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-60111">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>The ongoing Epic v. Google debacle continues to unfold. In the latest development, a judge has ruled that Google must open up the Google Play store to rival third-party applications for the next three years. This means that Google Play will be <strong>mandated </strong>to offer platforms like Epic Games to users worldwide. </p>



<p>Not only that but the tech titan must also give third-party app stores access to every application housed in Google Play – unless the developers themselves opt out of that mechanic. </p>



<h2 id="h-monumental-victory">Monumental Victory</h2>



<p>Epic Games has taken Google to court and historically schooled the gargantuan tech firm. Recently, Judge Donato, who has been presiding over the case, decreed it that Google has eight months to piece together a system governed by a three-person technical committee.</p>



<p>This system will need to figure out how these new arrangements will work in the best interests of everyone involved.</p>



<p>Here’s the full list of changes that have surfaced as a result of these legal proceedings:</p>



<ul>
<li>Google must <strong>stop </strong>requiring Google Play Billing for apps distributed on the Google Play store</li>



<li>Google <strong>must </strong>allow Android developers to offer other ways to pay within the Play Store</li>



<li>Google <strong>must </strong>let Android developers link to ways to download outside of the Play Store</li>



<li>Google <strong>must </strong>let developers arrange their own pricing structure irrespective of Play Billing</li>



<li>Google <strong>must not </strong>share app revenue with ‘any person or entity that distributes Android apps’ or plans to launch their own app store</li>



<li>Google <strong>must not offer </strong>developers money to launch their apps exclusively on the Play Store. Similarly, Google cannot offer money to developers to have them <strong>not </strong>launch on a rival platform.</li>



<li>Google <strong>must not </strong>offer manufacturers incentives to pre-install the Play Store on their devices</li>
</ul>



<p>This ruling also eradicates Google’s 30% ‘app tax’. Speaking on the proceedings, Judge Donato said:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>We’re going to tear the barriers down, it’s just the way it’s going to happen.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Fast-forward to today, and those barriers have well and truly been decimated. Google’s monopoly on the Android application market has been irrevocably changed — but we’ll see what happens when the three-year window is up.</p>



<p>What do you think about the implications of this settlement? Let us know on the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-6-trailer-launch-gameplay/">Black Ops 6 has a new launch trailer</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-6-trailer-launch-gameplay/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-6-trailer-launch-gameplay/">Black Ops 6 Global Launch Gameplay Trailer Released</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Activision has published a stunning but short trailer giving us another glimpse at the upcoming story in Black Ops 6.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/diablo-4-vessel-of-hatred-release-delayed-due-to-technical-issues/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/diablo-4-vessel-of-hatred-release-delayed-due-to-technical-issues/">UPDATE: Diablo 4 Vessel of Hatred Is Finally Available After Release Delayed Due To Technical Issues</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Diablo 4 Vessel of Hatred, the first expansion for the 2023 release from Blizzard, saw its launch delayed due to technical issues.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/activision-releases-call-of-duty-black-ops-6-launch-trailer/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/activision-releases-call-of-duty-black-ops-6-launch-trailer/">Activision Releases Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 Launch Trailer</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Activision has released the Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 launch trailer, just weeks before the game’s scheduled release on PC and Console.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nvidia-ces-2025-keynote-will-happen-on-january-6/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nvidia-ces-2025-keynote-will-happen-on-january-6/">Nvidia CES 2025 Keynote Will Happen On January 6</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>It’s been revealed that Nvidia will hold its annual keynote at CES 2025 on January 6. The company is expected to announce new GPUs.</p>
                    </div>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>