<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 16:23:20 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Practice makes perfects in Forestrike’s martial arts brawler]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/03/24/practice-makes-perfects-in-forestrikes-martial-arts-brawler/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/practice-makes-perfects-in-forestrike%E2%80%99s-martial-arts-brawler.1143297/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/03/24/practice-makes-perfects-in-forestrikes-martial-arts-brawler/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>The Empire is under threat from within, and only the Order of Foresight has a chance to save it. The latest game from <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2021/01/28/olija-review/">Olija</a> developer Skeleton Crew, Forestrike is a martial arts brawler where you can see the future… kind of. Coming to Switch and PC later this year, <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2325930/Forestrike_Demo/">a demo is now available on Steam</a> to try and we’ve been hands on.</p>
<p><iframe title="Forestrike | Leaf School Combat Overview | Play the First Demo on Steam" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/DQvhBv8kTlc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>You see, the power of Foresight is bestowed upon a select few, including our apprentice protagonist, Yu. When faced with a clutch of bad dudes that need defeating, Yu can only take a couple hits, but can enter into Foresight and unpick the chain of events that’s going to occur and how to turn it around in his favour. It’s a bit like he’s borrowed Doctor Strange’s time stone to have a peep at all the possibilities.</p>


<p>Foresight is basically a trial run, a practice arena where you can figure out the attacks coming your way and how to use your limited dodge, pickups and standard light and heavy attacks to defeat them. You’ll see what enemies emerge to surround you, and then learn to pick them apart one-by-one until you stand victorious.</p>


<p>If an enemy comes charging at Yu, he can engage a dodge mode that will pass that charing enemy straight through you and see them barrel into someone stood on the other side, dealing damage to both. Similarly, an enemy that is able to dodge can be tricked into using that either by a bullrushing enemy you’ve evaded or by triggering them with an attack for your own, opening themselves up for attack immediately after.</p>
<p>It’s essentially an action puzzle game where you need to try and figure out a path through and then execute your plan. Get it wrong and you’ll lose health pips or even die, sending you right back to the start of the game’s roguelite form.</p>
<p>The demo does a good job of slowly introducing you to these concepts before letting you go on a run and see the roguelite structure. Working your way from the countryside, through the mountains, the city and into the inner court of the Emperor, you’ll have a choice of levels to take on, many of which come with rewards and fresh abilities.</p>

<p>For example, one could make your light attacks spin enemies around, potentially disorient them to then turn and attack their allies. Or you could gain health from instances of friendly fire amongst them, or cancel out and steal their weapons. Levels that reward you with a new abilities present you with three to choose from, but others can also upgrade abilities – that turn-about ability can then stun enemies, if upgraded. There’s also a shop to spend coins – if not using those to open up a further path.</p>
<p>It comes to a head when facing a boss. Larger health bars, quickly recharging dodge abilities, and some audacious attacks – Master Ogai in the demo can tumble into one of his allies and just fling them at you – makes them a real task to figure out, come up with a plan and then pull it off. It’s not something that I managed in my exploratory run, despite well over a dozen efforts in Foresight.</p>

<p>The demo has one of Yu’s potential mentors, the old Master Talgun who pops up in your Foresight like a Jedi ghost and gives a little guidance. He rejects violence typically, but even he pushes for an attack-first principle in certain situations. He’s just one of a handful of masters that you’ll be able to choose from at the start of a run, each of which has a different school of combat, which you can master and ultimately combine.</p>
<p>For now, the demo provides a tasty morsel of the action that Forestrike will offer when it launches later this year. Unpicking the combat puzzles is sure to prove delectable to a particular cachet of players, ramping up to those ‘real’ battles where you have only one shot to pull off what you’ve been practicing, and leading to some gloriously slick combat sequences that would fit right into a martial arts movie.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch 2, PlayStation 5 Will Get a Lot More Xbox Games in 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-playstation-5-more-xbox-games/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-switch-2-playstation-5-will-get-a-lot-more-xbox-games-in-2025.1143294/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-playstation-5-more-xbox-games/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Multiple Xbox games will hit the Nintendo Switch 2 and PlayStation 5 consoles this year besides those that have already been announced, according to a new report shared online today.</p>
<p>Commenting on the release date announcement for the <a href="https://wccftech.com/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-is-out-on-april-17-for-ps5/">PlayStation 5 version of Indiana Jones and the Great Circle</a>, The Verge's Tom Warren <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/610817/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-ps5-release-date">stated</a> that 2025 will include a lot more titles appearing on PlayStation 5 and the next-generation Nintendo console. Which former Xbox console exclusives will make the jump has yet to be seen, but it wouldn't be surprising to see any of these games make an appearance during the Nintendo Switch 2 Direct scheduled for next week.</p>
<p>While Microsoft has yet to reveal which games will hit rival formats next, there's a very good chance that Starfield will be among the next to release at least on PlayStation 5. <a href="https://wccftech.com/starfield-playstation-5-release-imminent/">Earlier this month</a>, the console's logo appeared on Creation listings, suggesting that the game's announcement and release could be imminent.</p>
<p>The next entry in the Fable series could be a <a href="https://wccftech.com/fable-starfield-playstation-5-nintendo-switch-2/">multiplatform release</a> right from launch, as work on other console versions of the game has reportedly already begun. With the game having been <a href="https://wccftech.com/fable-delayed-2026-stunning-gameplay/">delayed</a> to 2026, a multiplatform launch has become even more likely, although it remains to be seen how the Nintendo Switch 2 will be able to handle the game, given its lower specs compared to the other current-generation systems.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marvel Rivals Esports is Already Building Strong Rivalries and Solid Viewership]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-esports-is-already-building-strong-rivalries-and-solid-viewership/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/marvel-rivals-esports-is-already-building-strong-rivalries-and-solid-viewership.1143285/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-esports-is-already-building-strong-rivalries-and-solid-viewership/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>The Marvel Rivals esports scene is still in its very early days, but the early results have been very positive. The fledgling scene is attracting numerous organizations, strong viewership numbers (thanks to co-streaming), and some exciting rivalries.</p>



<p>The first competitive tournaments have featured plenty of highlights and trash talking, and there’s nowhere to go but up for Marvel Rivals esports.</p>



<h2 id="h-marvel-rivals-esports-is-heating-up-quickly">Marvel Rivals Esports is Heating Up Quickly</h2>



<p>After a month of action across the world, the Marvel Rivals Invitational series has ended, crowning five champions across each of the main regions. Arguably the most interest in Marvel Rivals esports has been in North America, which has attracted the most viewership and the most interest from established organizations.</p>



<p>Excluding the streamer-focused events like Creator Cup and Twitch Rivals, the Marvel Rivals event with the highest viewership peak was the NA Invitational that just concluded yesterday. The event <a href="https://escharts.com/tournaments/mr/marvel-rivals-invitational-north-america-2" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">reached 71,099 concurrent viewers at its peak</a>, according to Esports Charts. This number was aided by co-streamers like Shroud, who has become so interested in Marvel Rivals that he <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/shroud-marvel-rivals-esports-roster-reveal/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">founded a team that competed in the event: Shroud-X</a>. But the event included a trove of larger organizations with dedicated fanbases: Sentinels, Envy, FlyQuest, and 100 Thieves.</p>



<p>100 Thieves have been dominating the competition in North America. Since the squad formerly known as Mutants signed with Nadeshot’s brand, they haven’t lost a single match, thanks in part to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/one-of-marvel-rivals-best-pro-tank-players-plays-on-controller/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">one of the few Vanguard players playing (and winning) on controller</a>. The rivalry between Sentinels and 100 Thieves in VALORANT has carried over to Marvel Rivals, complete with the<a href="https://x.com/MRivalsEsports/status/1903651194196676821" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> expected amount of social media back-and-forth</a>. The trash talk is at the perfect level: not too far to be deemed personal or inappropriate, but above the basic level of normal banter.</p>



<p>There’s still plenty of room for Marvel Rivals to grow, but NetEase has committed to investing in the game itself for “10 years and beyond.” And with seasonal tournaments baked into the game’s competitive mode itself, that implies that esports will be a priority for years to come.</p>



<p>What do you make of Marvel Rivals’ aspirations in esports? Let us know in the comments or on our&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-releases-on-ps5-next-month/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Indiana Jones and The Great Circle’s PS5 announcement</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The First Berserker: Khazan Review In Progress]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/the-first-berserker-khazan-review</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-first-berserker-khazan-review-in-progress.1143279/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/the-first-berserker-khazan-review<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">I’m exhausted after playing The First Berserker: Khazan over the past week and a half. My hands ache, my brain is fried, and I’ve often had to step away in frustration. It’s a brutally difficult game, one often expecting near-perfection in its toughest encounters. I’m slowly working my way through this Soulslike extension of developer Neople’s Dungeon &amp; Fighter universe, and it’s an understatement to say it’s given me trouble – which is part of why I still have a bit more to go before I’m able to call this review finished. But like a new military recruit, it’s broken me down and, over time, built me into a lethal weapon that’s prepared to take on whatever hellish nightmares wait ahead. Even though I’ve hit seemingly insurmountable roadblocks for hours at a time, I’ve somehow found myself enjoying and reveling in the battles that take me to the brink of my abilities.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The First Berserker: Khazan is a classic revenge tale. Khazan, a celebrated general, is betrayed by his empire and labeled a traitor. After being gravely injured while apprehended, he is revived and possessed by a melded legion of vicious warrior spirits who antagonize him into doing their bidding. The Blade Phantom, as the ethereal symbiote is known, is more concerned with advancing the objectives of the underworld from which it hails, while Khazan is out for the blood of those who wronged him. The setup provides plenty to build on, tying grounded medieval politics to the occult forces leeching their way into the world, but the story after has mostly been thin and underwhelming beyond that.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Khazan meets various characters as he ventures forth into the world, but besides adding some minor connective tissue to the ongoing plot, they don’t contribute to the story in a way that makes me care about really anything that’s happening. Distressed villagers, otherworldly advisors, former military cohorts, and more start to fill out a sparse hub area known as The Crevice. Outside of being visually interesting as a floating stone sanctuary with mysterious broken staircases and far-off platforms that I’d like to get to and explore, there’s not a lot to do in The Crevice apart from managing my inventory from time to time or pressing onto the next mission area. There’s shockingly little to glean from the greater world despite being the perfect place to slow things down and foster an environment for further flavor. Instead, it’s more a mechanical necessity to pick up optional quests or craft, upgrade, and augment gear for Khazan than an area to explore and enhance the overall story.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Being a well-honed instrument of war, Khazan has a handful of tools at his disposal to slaughter his enemies – although it took a long time before I felt like I was on his perceived level of capability. An early mission introduced me to The First Berserker’s three types of weaponry: You can choose to use the powerful but slow and defensive greatsword, a nimble stamina-draining spear, or the whirling assault of the dual blades. I enjoy how unique each weapon type is from the others, offering transformative move sets ranging from defensive and methodical to all-out aggressive. </p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>Khazan feels way different than he did at the start roughly 40 hours ago. </p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Each weapon is further expanded with a full skill tree that enhances Khazan’s effectiveness in battle. Nodes on these trees modify your basic attacks, like altering how your charged Potent Blow (or heavy attack) works, changing the stamina depletion for actions like dodging and blocking, or providing new moves entirely by spending a resource called Spirit Points in combat. My Khazan currently feels way different to play than he did at the start roughly 40 hours ago. There are a lot of options to kit out Khazan with as you level him up, and it’s been rather fun to figure out which moves and perks contour best to my playstyle to help me slice my way out of its hardening conflicts.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The First Berserker lets you swap between your three weapons freely, but with little overlap between their various abilities, what’s normally a quick switch is actually a dramatic change and a hassle. For instance, in <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2011/09/30/dark-souls-review">Dark Souls</a>, most weapons boil down to having light and heavy attacks, with maybe a special ability available when switching to a two-handed grip. Weapons in The First Berserker, on the other hand, allow for up to six of the previously mentioned Spirit attacks and further optimization of the skill tree. It’s a lot to deal with when equipping what is essentially a bespoke class. That’s why I’ve dedicated myself to the dual blades during my playthrough, which I’m still tweaking and learning about with every big fight I pick. Thankfully, If I ever wanted to make the big jump to the greatsword or spear, you can reallocate skill points freely. However, the process is <em>just </em>obtuse and annoying enough to do on the fly that I’ve stuck with one kind of weapon throughout.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Upon embarking on The First Berserker’s mainline missions, the structure is extremely similar to what’s expected in a soulslike. Each level involves slaying dangerous enemies patrolling the area, figuring out how to survive with limited healing items, collecting spoils of the dead, and using them to level up at this game’s version of a bonfire, called a Blade Nexus. It’s an overly familiar formula that’s certainly inoffensive in its design, with levels smartly built to weave back to prior respites via shortcuts. The First Berserker unfortunately doesn’t add anything that you haven’t already seen in FromSoftware’s games, but it recreates that loop well enough.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Capping off each mission is a tooth-and-nail fight with that area’s boss, each of which represents a potentially substantial roadblock before you can continue to enjoy The First Berserker, but these encounters have begun to win me over. The first big encounter I struggled with was the end boss of Mission 2, a manifestation of souls like the ones inhabiting our newly possessed hero. Its aggressive melee attacks would quickly kill me, and after several unsuccessful attempts and unforeseen weapon swaps from my adversary, I needed to try another strategy to finally break through. Another early boss, a bipedal goat demon wielding a flaming spike and hammer, caused plenty of grief by hitting hard and often, occasionally lighting the battlefield ablaze with a carpet of flames. At first, I tried to grind weaker enemies around the level to collect Khazan’s version of souls, called Lacrima, to boost my stats and give myself a better chance of living. It helped, but ultimately didn’t do enough to tip the scales. I then took a close look at my gear and opted for a tankier build. Still no dice. </p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>What was once a peak point of frustration has become my favorite part of The First Berserker.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Khazan’s bosses are just painfully tough, and the early ones are like a brick wall. Some of the smaller enemies leading up to a boss will somewhat teach you how to deal with certain aspects of them, but there’s little to ramp you into what is continually asked of you moving forward. There’s no easy way to smash your way through these walls in The First Berserker, like finding an overpowered item or excessively juicing your stats. Even in a brutal game like <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/elden-ring-review">Elden Ring</a>, a notorious early boss like <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/elden-ring/Margit_the_Fell_Omen"><u>Margit</u></a> can be overcome more easily if you spend some time getting stronger in the areas before him, but that’s not really an option here. In turn, this immediate difficulty spike genuinely made me want to stop playing after the first few levels – but I’m glad I stuck with it.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The process of learning each oppressive bosses’ moves and tells, figuring out when it’s ideal to dodge or block, is extra important in The First Berserker. It’s how I ultimately figured out how to enjoy the experience in the face of overwhelming odds. Honing these abilities was mind-numbing and shredded my will to play early on. There’s no way around the need to execute well-timed damage blocks or rolls and then strike back at opportune moments. Some bosses in the first half of the campaign burned upwards of five hours of my time alone, often leaving me wondering if <em>maybe </em>I should just consider dropping down from the default Normal difficulty to Easy to save myself the stress. These enemies tested my patience, but after overcoming that initial barrier,  building the foundation of my reaction options, and adapting my plan of attack, I became much more successful at figuring out the ones that followed.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">What was once a peak point of frustration has become my favorite part of The First Berserker; the bosses are ultimately what make it worth playing. While they are incredibly hard to take down, every one can eventually be read like a book, telegraphing the moves they’re about to make and predictable strategies they’ll use throughout the fight. Every death that was once met with confusion and irritation has become a learning experience I look forward to absorbing. Every restart is a renewed chance to land my attacks and survive with newfound knowledge. Yes, there are plenty of cheap attacks, one-hit kills, and groan-inducing mistakes, but I’ve been enjoying studying each big boss I come across as much as the catharsis of finally taking them down.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">The First Berserker: Khazan Screenshots</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">I’ve also been able to achieve these insurmountable feats thanks to two great quality-of-life decisions Neople has implemented into The First Berserker. First, dying repeatedly at a boss isn’t for nothing, but rather grants precious Lacrima based on how far you took their life down. Each upgrade that helps you afford gets you a little bit further the next time, and gaining levels by grinding the boss you need to beat is far more valuable than breaking away to farm elsewhere. Second, skill points are awarded separately from the levels you get from cashing in Lacrima, and are instead earned through a more traditional experience bar that is filled simply by being in battle. While not necessarily an increase in stats, unlocking new moves to use or enhancing your favorites can be just the thing needed to beat a stubborn encounter.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">After finally finding my footing with what’s being asked of me at the conclusion of each mission and gaining abilities that make me feel like I can stand a chance against anything, I’ve come to enjoy Khazan’s devastating bosses. They’re what’s keeping me trudging through largely uninteresting levels and hordes of enemies. It’s been a steep and sometimes demoralizing climb to feel effective with my skills and stats – but there’s also the exhilaration of executing split-second guards and dodges to escape relentless attacks and hit my foes with my own flurry of steel. If I weren’t reviewing it, there’s a very good chance I would have taken a long break early on, and who knows if I would ever go back. But now that I know I’m capable of taking on the worst Khazan has thrown at me (so far), I’m looking forward to seeing it to the end.</p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Forestrike Demands Absolute, Unconditional Kung Fu Pixel-Art Perfection – Hands-on Preview]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/forestrike-demands-absolute-unconditional-kung-fu-pixel-art-perfection-hands-on-preview</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/forestrike-demands-absolute-unconditional-kung-fu-pixel-art-perfection-%E2%80%93-hands-on-preview.1143273/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/forestrike-demands-absolute-unconditional-kung-fu-pixel-art-perfection-hands-on-preview<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">If at first you don’t succeed, try, try again.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Like a demanding, wizened kung fu master insisting you repeat a training exercise until you’ve gotten it exactly right, Forestrike shows no mercy, absolutely insisting you achieve perfection before proceeding to the next level. Despite being squarely centered on martial arts mastery, this pixelated 2D roguelike has more in common with a chess match than an action game, as you repeat encounters until you’ve perfected them in one of the most satisfying, unique, and immediately compelling brawlers I’ve played in a very long time.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">If you’ve ever wanted to live out your most epic kung fu fantasies where every moment plays out like you can see into the future, Forestrike very well might fill that need unlike any game has so far. The premise is simple: you’re a martial arts master who can enter your mind palace and practice each combat encounter as many times as you want before heading into battle for real. After a dozen or more rehearsals, even the most seemingly insurmountable scenarios went off without a hitch as I moved with the precision and speed of someone who knew every enemy’s move before they made it – because I quite literally had. And since this is a roguelike where just one or two mistakes will send you all the way back to the beginning, having that handicap is extremely important to success.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Forestrike Screens</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">In one level, I practiced again and again to resolve an encounter where I had to protect a traveling merchant from a band of ne’er-do-wells, and in another I challenged an extremely tricky boss who was annoyingly good at dodging, eventually beating him by getting his henchmen to accidentally hit him with friendly fire. Each level is its own miniature puzzle that must be solved and practiced before you try it for real, and even after all that, there’s always a chance your nerves will get to you and you won’t pull things off quite right, resulting in an untimely end to your journey.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>When you’ve got unlimited time to practice walloping the enemy in clever and creative ways, why not go beyond simply achieving victory and aim for a bit of flourish?</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">But sometimes beating your opponents isn’t enough – after all, when you’ve got unlimited time to practice walloping the enemy in clever and creative ways, why not go beyond simply achieving victory and aim for a bit of flourish? Sometimes this is incentivized via optional missions, like one where you’re encouraged to knock the hat off an enemy’s head, have it land on your own, then don’t let it get knocked off of your head for the rest of the encounter; those can be a great way to earn some extra gold for upgrades (like armor that will allow you to take one additional hit without ending your run) when you next find yourself at the shop. But if you’re like me, you also just might find it funny to see if you can get through an entire fight only using misdirection and dodging to get the enemy to kill one another.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The really crazy thing is I only played a little beyond the first of five regions, where encounters were still mostly on the simpler side, the number of unique enemies was fairly low, and I didn’t get to try out any of the other four fighting styles. Having gotten just a peek beyond that, it seems there’s a whole lot more in store, including some absolutely nutty looking encounters – like creepy banshee monsters that were introduced at the tail end and charged at me with reckless abandon. The demo I played also focused on the School of the Leaf fighting style, the first of five total schools you’ll be able to unlock and incorporate into your build, each of which has their own flavor and abilities you unlock on each run. The Leaf style is all about evasion and misdirecting enemy attacks to encourage friendly fire, and some of the abilities shown in the sizzle trailer that played at the end of the demo looked like they extended that idea to its logical conclusion – like by linking yourself to an enemy, then magically switching places with them when you take a hit. In a game that was already impressively clever in a short hour-long demo, I’m extremely excited to see what else the developers have got up their sleeves.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Finally, I have to mention just how beautiful and stylish Forestrike looks. Don’t be fooled by the pixel art simplicity! Animations are charming and detailed, character art during dialogue makes you forget they’re represented by pixels to begin with, and the music, sound effects, and overall presentation are absolutely unforgettable. I’m telling you, friends: this is one to watch!</p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ex-Warner Bros. Exec Reveals the Real Reason Shadow of Mordor's Much-Loved Nemesis System Was Created]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/ex-warner-bros-exec-reveals-the-real-reason-shadow-of-mordors-much-loved-nemesis-system-was-created</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ex-warner-bros-exec-reveals-the-real-reason-shadow-of-mordors-much-loved-nemesis-system-was-created.1143267/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/ex-warner-bros-exec-reveals-the-real-reason-shadow-of-mordors-much-loved-nemesis-system-was-created<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Remembering your actions.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/middle-earth-shadow-of-mordor">Middle-Earth: Shadow of Mordor</a> is remembered for many reasons, but perhaps best of all for its Nemesis system, an incredible mechanic for generating memorable Orc encounters. According to a former executive, the Nemesis system came about from trying to solve a different problem: secondhand sales.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=r5f65WksXqA" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">new video</a>, Laura Fryer — former vice president of WB Games who oversaw the publisher's Seattle studios at the time — talked about her time with Monolith. While discussing the way trend-chasing affects the industry, Fryer mentioned that chasing trends is what "literally led to the Nemesis system."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">At the time, used game sales were a hot-button topic. Companies like <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2010/05/10/ea-sports-locks-out-multiplayer-modes-on-used-sales">Electronic Arts</a> and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2010/05/18/ubisoft-to-tackle-used-game-sales">Ubisoft</a> were taking measures such as selling season passes to counteract an active used game market. Fryer said a sales drop-off for Rocksteady's Arkham Asylum was attributed, by analytics, to a theory that people would play the game, then return the disc to a retailer.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"This was great for gamers, because they could buy the game and then sell it back to a company like GameStop and buy something else," Fryer said. "It was great for GameStop, because then they sold that used game for a discount and they pocketed the money. For game developers, though, it was a disaster, because they weren't getting paid for every game. They were only getting paid for the first copy sold. They lost millions of dollars."</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">This is where the Nemesis system, according to Fryer, came about. Faced with secondhand game sales and potential losses, how does a studio encourage players to hold onto their game? Memorable experiences, it seems.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"With Shadow, we faced the same problem," Fryer said. "How do we create a single-player game that is so compelling, that people keep the disc in their library forever? We knew Monolith's game engine wasn't yet capable of having a fully open world like a GTA, and this team wasn't interested in going the multiplayer route. But we still had to solve for the constraint. And this thinking is what led to the Nemesis system, arguably one of the most creative and coolest game features in recent memory."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Solving for this constraint would, as it turns out, lead to an incredibly memorable system of named Orc rivals, who would remember your actions and previous encounters, developing stories out of the action combat. It's often the best-remembered part of Monolith's Lord of the Rings duology, Middle-Earth: Shadow of Mordor and its sequel, Shadow of War.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Yet <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/warner-bros-cancels-wonder-woman-game-closes-three-studios">with the sudden closure of Monolith Productions</a> and cancellation of its Wonder Woman project, that particular success seems doomed to life in the vault. Though the Nemesis system was due to be implemented in the Wonder Woman game, Warner Bros. still owns the patent for the system, which <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/shadow-of-mordors-brilliant-nemesis-system-is-locked-away-by-a-warner-bros-patent-until-2036-despite-studio-shutdown" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">stands with an expiration date in 2036</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It's fascinating to hear more about how the Nemesis system came together, even if it means <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/after-warner-bros-shut-down-shadow-of-mordor-developer-monolith-and-canceled-wonder-woman-fans-lament-the-wasted-potential-of-its-nemesis-system">further lamenting</a> the fact that it will gather dust for the forseeable future.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Eric is a freelance writer for IGN.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Real-Life Japanese Shrine That Appeared in Ghost of Tsushima Bans All Tourists After 'Grave and Unforgivable Act of Disrespect']]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/real-life-japanese-shrine-that-appeared-in-ghost-of-tsushima-bans-all-tourists-after-grave-and-unforgivable-act-of-disrespect</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/real-life-japanese-shrine-that-appeared-in-ghost-of-tsushima-bans-all-tourists-after-grave-and-unforgivable-act-of-disrespect.1143264/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/real-life-japanese-shrine-that-appeared-in-ghost-of-tsushima-bans-all-tourists-after-grave-and-unforgivable-act-of-disrespect<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">"... nothing less than the destruction of Japanese culture."</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">After Japan’s Prime Minister responded to questions around <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/assassins-creed-shadows">Assassin’s Creed: Shadows</a> and the risk of copycat "defacing" of shrines, the shrine linked to <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/ghost-of-tsushima">Ghost of Tsushima</a> has banned all tourists after an "unforgivable act of disrespect."</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://automaton-media.com/en/news/japanese-shrine-once-repaired-thanks-to-ghost-of-tsushima-fans-bans-all-tourists-after-unforgivable-act-of-disrespect/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Automaton</a> reported on the Watazumi Shrine, a real-life Shinto shrine located on Japan’s Tsushima Island, which announced it had banned entry to anyone other than congregants and worshippers after what it called “a grave and unforgivable act of disrespect committed by foreigner(s).” </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Ghost of Tsushima brought worldwide attention upon the Watazumi Shrine upon its release in 2020, as it is thought to have inspired the in-game <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/ghost-of-tsushima/Scarlet_Rock_Shrine">Scarlet Rock Shrine</a>. As Automaton reported, Ghost of Tsushima fans launched a successful crowdfunding campaign to help raise money to repair damages suffered by the shrine during a typhoon.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/03/24/ghost-of-tsushima-scarletrock4-1742826050850.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">The Scarlet Rock Shrine in Ghost of Tsushima.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Officials didn’t go into detail on this latest incident, but mentioned having to call the police to deal with vandalism and the physical and verbal abuse of staff. “Inbound tourism’s destruction of places, things, and people cherished by the Japanese is nothing less than the destruction of Japanese culture,” Automaton quoted shrine officials as saying.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The incident comes hot on the heels of the controversial launch of Assassin’s Creed: Shadows in Japan. Shadows, which like Ghost of Tsushima is set in Feudal Japan, launched last week <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/amid-japan-concern-about-assassins-creed-shadows-ubisoft-confirms-day-one-patch-that-makes-tables-and-racks-in-temples-and-shrines-indestructible">alongside a day-one patch that quietly made a number of important changes, including to temples and shrines</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The update made tables and racks in temples and shrines indestructible, and changed citizens without weapons so they no longer bleed when attacked and thus reduce blood spill in temples and shrines.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Ubisoft told IGN the day-one patch was for all players and not Japan-specific, but was hard to see the changes as anything but a response to the controversy surrounding the game in the country.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">That controversy even reached the upper echelons of Japanese politics. Last week, Shigeru Ishiba, the Prime Minister of Japan, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-prime-minister-of-japan-responded-to-a-question-about-assassins-creed-shadows-today-heres-whats-actually-going-on"><u>responded to a question about Assassin’s Creed Shadows during an official government conference meeting</u></a>.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The Assassin’s Creed Shadows question was asked by Japanese politician and member of the House of Councillors of Japan, Hiroyuki Kada. Kada, who will campaign for re-election this summer, said:</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“I fear that allowing players to attack and destroy real-world locations in the game without permission could encourage similar behavior in real life. Shrine officials and local residents are also worried about this. Of course, freedom of expression must be respected, but acts that demean local cultures should be avoided.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Prime Minister Ishiba responded:</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“How to address this legally is something we need to discuss with the Ministry of Economy, Trade and Industry, the Ministry of Education, Culture, Sports, Science, and Technology, and the Ministry of Foreign Affairs.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Defacing a shrine is out of the question - it is an insult to the nation itself. When the Self-Defense Forces were deployed to Samawah, Iraq, we ensured they studied Islamic customs beforehand. Respecting the culture and religion of a country is fundamental, and we must make it clear that we will not simply accept acts that disregard them.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The shrine being “defaced” in pre-release Assassin's Creed Shadows gameplay videos was the Itatehyozu Shrine in Himeji, Hyogo Prefecture, which is within Kada’s constituency. He said that he had consulted with representatives of the shrine, who confirmed that Ubisoft did not seek their permission to show the shrine and use its name in the game.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As our colleagues at IGN Japan explained to us last week, Japan has seen record numbers of overseas visitors in the wake of the country reopening its borders after the pandemic and the lure of the weak yen. In this government budget meeting the politician Hiroyuki Kada twinned his complaints against Shadows with the controversial subject of what he called “over tourism” and an attendant perceived rise in vandalism and graffiti in Japan.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">His argument was that if players were able to deface a temple or harm individuals with a katana in the game, they may be inspired to do it in real life when they visit Japan, similar to the age-old argument that Call of Duty or Grand Theft Auto inspire copycat violence.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Prime Minister Shigeru Ishiba responded that if such actions were taken in real life, he would oppose them. His comments were aimed at theoretical real-life copycat actions rather than at the game itself.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indiana Jones and the Great Circle PS5 release date confirmed]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-ps5-release-date-confirmed</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-ps5-release-date-confirmed.1143261/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-ps5-release-date-confirmed<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>In skit featuring crossover with Uncharted's Nolan North.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/PS5-Date-Reveal---Indiana-Jones-and-the-Great-Circle-1-5-screenshot.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Bethesda</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Prepare your best shocked face - <a data-keyword="true" href="https://eurogamer.net/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-review">Indiana Jones and the Great Circle</a> will launch for PlayStation 5 on 17th April.
</p>
<p>
The <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circles-ps5-release-date-will-be-announced-tomorrow-leaker-suggests">announcement today might have leaked</a>, but here's something you perhaps were not expecting - a skit featuring video game Indiana Jones Troy Baker, and Uncharted lead actor Nolan North.
</p>
<p>
Together, the two do their best to wring out 90 seconds of content from, well, the date written above. If you're a fan of Uncharted, or Trey, sorry, Troy Baker, this will likely raise a smile or two:
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="PS5 Date Reveal - Indiana Jones and the Great Circle" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/0VdnmreE1X0?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>PS5 Date Reveal - Indiana Jones and the Great Circle</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/0VdnmreE1X0?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/0VdnmreE1X0?autoplay=1" title="PS5 Date Reveal - Indiana Jones and the Great Circle">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle PS5 date reveal.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0VdnmreE1X0" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
Alongside the game, a Collector's Bundle will be available with a physical game case (though you'll still need to download the game), an adventure journal book, a stone tablet replica, a globe (with hidden storage) and up to two days early access to the upcoming The Order of the Giants story DLC. Also included is a Temple of Doom outfit, and The Last Crusade travelling suit and lion tamer whip.
</p>
<p>Quite simply, PS5 owners are in for a treat - Indiana Jones was one of the best games of 2024, a brilliant and authentic-feeling adventure from Wolfenstein developer MachineGames, and probably the best Indiana Jones video game ever made.</p>
<p>"Smart, fun and so very Indiana Jones, The Great Circle is a stealth action tour de force that marks a bold new era for MachineGames," Katharine wrote in <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-review">Eurogamer's Indiana Jones and the Great Circle review</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indiana Jones and the Great Circle Is Out on April 17 for PS5]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-is-out-on-april-17-for-ps5/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-is-out-on-april-17-for-ps5.1143240/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-is-out-on-april-17-for-ps5/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Yesterday, leaker billbil-kun said the release date announcement for the PlayStation 5 version of Indiana Jones and the Great Circle would take place today. Indeed, a few minutes ago, publisher Bethesda Softworks revealed that the acclaimed first-person adventure/action game released in December by MachineGames will debut on Sony's console in less than a month, on April 17.</p>
<p>Digital pre-orders are <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-us/games/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle/?country-selector=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">now open</a>, and physical pre-orders, depending on your region, are expected to be available soon. Users can choose from three options: the Standard Edition, available both digitally and physically; the Premium Edition, also available in both formats; and the retail-only Collector's Bundle.</p>
<p>All pre-orders will reward players with The Last Crusade Pack, which includes the Traveling Suit Outfit and the Lion Tamer Whip in-game items. The pricier Premium Edition also adds a Temple of Doom Outfit, a digital artbook, and access to the story DLC The Order of Giants, which has been confirmed to launch in 2025. The Premium Edition, just like the Collector's Edition, also provides two days of early access, allowing Indiana Jones fans to start playing on April 15.</p>

<p>The $199 Collector's bundle adds the following physical items to everything mentioned above:</p>
<ul>
<li>An 11” Great Circle globe with a puzzle mechanic that unlocks a hidden storage compartment when solved</li>
<li>Allmaker Relic replica</li>
<li>Adventure Journal</li>
<li>Jumbo SteelBook display case</li>
</ul>

<p>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle has been 'visually optimized' for the PS5 Pro, said Bethesda without going into further details. That info will likely be shared in the few remaining weeks ahead of the launch. By the way, the developers are also adding new whip abilities to the game, regardless of the platform you play on, with an upcoming free update. With “Open Season”, whip-cracking an enemy will temporarily cause them to take more damage from subsequent attacks, while when using “Sleight of Hand,” players can disarm an enemy and cause their weapon to fly Indy's way.</p>
<p><iframe title="PS5 Date Reveal - Indiana Jones and the Great Circle" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/0VdnmreE1X0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>I found Indiana Jones and the Great Circle to be fantastic, as outlined in <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-indiana-at-his-finest/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">my review (9/10)</a> on PC:</p>
<p><em>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle is an excellent adventure/action game that features one of the best Indiana Jones stories, great level design that rewards exploration, and awesome ray traced visuals. This might just be the best game dedicated to Dr. Henry Walton we've ever seen.</em></p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indiana Jones and the Great Circle arrives on PS5 in April]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/610817/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-ps5-release-date</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-arrives-on-ps5-in-april.1143237/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/news/610817/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-ps5-release-date<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="__next"><p><a href="#content"><span>Skip to main content</span></a></p><nav aria-label="Sticky Nav"></nav><div><main id="content"><article><div><div><div><p><span><ul><li><a href="https://www.theverge.com/news">News</a></li></ul></span></p></div><div><p>Bethesda’s Indiana Jones game first debuted on Xbox and PC in December.</p></div></div><div><div><p>Bethesda’s Indiana Jones game first debuted on Xbox and PC in December.</p><div><p><span><time datetime="2025-03-24T15:02:34+00:00">Mar 24, 2025, 3:02 PM UTC</time></span></p></div></div><div><p><cite>Image: Bethesda Softworks</cite></p></div></div></div><div><div><div><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/tom-warren">Tom Warren</a> <span>is a senior editor and author of <a href="https://www.theverge.com/notepad-microsoft-newsletter"><i>Notepad</i></a>, who has been covering all things Microsoft, PC, and tech for over 20 years.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Microsoft and Bethesda are bringing <em>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle</em> to PS5 on April 17th. The game first debuted on Xbox and PC on December 9th, with Microsoft promising a PS5 release this spring.</p><p>Bethesda is selling standard and premium versions of <em>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle</em> on PS5, and the premium version provides two days of early access starting April 15th. Preorders begin today, ahead of <em>Indiana Jones</em>’ debut on PS5 next month.</p><p>I originally <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/2/4/24057433/microsoft-bethesda-indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-ps5-release">revealed last year</a> that Microsoft was considering a PS5 release of <em>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle</em>, ahead of Bethesda’s announcement during Gamescom Opening Night Live in August. <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/8/20/24224284/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-ps5-release-date">I also reported</a> that Bethesda was targeting April 2025 for <em>Indiana Jones</em> on PS5.</p><p><em>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle</em>’s release on PS5 is part of a broader effort from Microsoft to bring more Xbox games to rival platforms. Microsoft first started launching previous Xbox-exclusive titles like <em>Hi-Fi Rush</em>, <em>Pentiment</em>, <em>Sea of Thieves</em>, and <em>Grounded </em>on PS5 last year, and 2025 will include a lot more titles appearing on both PS5 and Nintendo’s Switch 2.</p><div><p><em><a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/620993/forzas-on-ps5s-horizon">Forza Horizon 5</a></em> is coming to Sony’s rival console on April 29th, shortly after <em><a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/606102/xbox-ps5-age-of-empires">Age of Empires II: Definitive Edition</a></em> and the <em>Age of Mythology: Retold</em> released on PS5 earlier this month. <em><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/23/24349379/doom-the-dark-ages-release-date-trailer-xbox-pc-ps5">Doom: The Dark Ages</a></em> is also arriving on Xbox and PS5 on May 15th.</p></div></div></div><div><form><div><h2>Installer</h2><p><span>A weekly newsletter by David Pierce designed to tell you everything you need to download, watch, read, listen to, and explore that fits in The Verge’s universe.</span></p></div></form></div></div></article></main></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indiana Jones and The Great Circle Releases on PS5 Next Month]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-releases-on-ps5-next-month/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-releases-on-ps5-next-month.1143231/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-releases-on-ps5-next-month/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Indiana Jones and The Great Circle finally has a PS5 release date: April 17, 2025.</p>



<p>The official PlayStation account on <a href="https://x.com/playstation/status/1904186452851994817?s=46" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">X</a> has finally provided Indy fans with what they have been waiting for: a release date for Indiana Jones and the Great Circle. After months of <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-receives-esrb-rating-for-ps5/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">speculation</a>, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-ps5-release-date-leaked/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">leaks</a> and rumours, we now know that MachineGames’ latest action-adventure will be available on a new platform in less than a month.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 id="h-indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-ps5-editions-and-pre-order-details">Indiana Jones and the Great Circle PS5 Editions and Pre-order Details</h2>



<p>A report by <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2025/03/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-for-ps5-launches-april-17" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Gematsu</a> reveals that there are three editions of Indiana Jones and the Great Circle Up for grabs on the PS5. The standard edition, priced at ($69.99 / £69.99 / €79.99) will provide players with just the base game. The Premium edition will cost players ($99.99 / £99.99 / €109.99) and provides players with two days of early access, a digital art book, the ‘Temple of Doom’ outfit and access to story DLC, “The Order of the Giants”, once it releases.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle’s release on the PS5 is also celebrated with a Collector’s Bundle. It will feature all the Premium Edition content along with a Jump SteelBook display case, The Great Circle globe with Hidden Storage, Allmaker Relic and The Adventure Journal.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Players who pre-order any edition of Indiana Jones and the Great Circle on the PlayStation Store will receive ‘The Last Crusade Pack’, which includes the “Traveling Suit” outfit and the “Lion Tamer” whip.&nbsp;</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Official Launch Trailer: Indiana Jones and the Great Circle" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/sq97d1RkdRM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>In other news, more Indiana Jones games <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/more-indiana-jones-games/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">are being developed</a>. What are your thoughts on Indiana Jones and the Great Circle releasing on PS5 next month?&nbsp;Let us know in the comments or on our&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-legends-z-a-will-bring-27-new-mega-evolutions-its-claimed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a new claim stating that Pokemon Legends Z-A will introduce 27 new mega-evolutions</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indiana Jones and the Great Circle for PS5 launches April 17]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/03/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-for-ps5-launches-april-17</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-for-ps5-launches-april-17.1143228/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/03/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-for-ps5-launches-april-17<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Available in standard, Premium, and Collector's editions.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>The <a title="Platforms > PS5 [9,120 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a> version of first-person action <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,144 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure game</a> <em><a title="Games > Indiana Jones and the Great Circle [9 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle">Indiana Jones and the Great Circle</a></em> will launch on April 17, publisher <a title="Companies > Bethesda Softworks [785 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/zenimax-media/bethesda-softworks">Bethesda Softworks</a> and developer <a title="Companies > MachineGames [47 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/zenimax-media/bethesda-softworks/machinegames">MachineGames</a> announced. <span id="more-943146"></span></p><p>The game will be available both physically and digitally in the following editions:</p><blockquote><p><strong>Standard Edition</strong> ($69.99 / £69.99 / €79.99)</p><ul><li>A copy of the game</li></ul><p><strong>Premium Edition</strong> ($99.99 / £99.99 / €109.99)</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Indy-PS5_03-24-25_Premium.jpg"></a></figure><!-- AD: content -->
        <ul><li>A copy of the game</li><li>Up to two days of early access starting April 15</li><li>Digital art book</li><li>“Temple of Doom” outfit</li><li>Access to the story downloadable content “The Order of Giants” when it launches</li></ul><p><strong>Collector’s Bundle</strong></p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Indy-PS5_03-24-25_Collectors.jpg"></a></figure><ul><li>Premium Edition content</li><li>Jump SteelBook display case</li><li>The Great Circle globe with hidden storage</li><li>Allmaker Relic</li><li>The Adventure Journal</li></ul></blockquote><p>Pre-orders for all editions include the downloadable content “The Last Crusade Pack,” Which features the “Traveling Suit” outfit and “Lion Tamer” whip.</p><p>Additionally, <em>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle</em> has been visually optimized for PlayStation 5 Pro. The PlayStation 5 launch will also bring two new whip abilities—“Open Season” and “<a title="Games > Sleight of Hand [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/sleight-of-hand">Sleight of Hand</a>“—which will be available for all platforms by April 15. With ​”Open Season​,”​ whip-cracking an enemy will temporarily cause them to take more damage from subsequent attacks, while “Sleight of Hand” will disarm an enemy and cause their weapon to fly Indy’s way.</p><p><em>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle</em> first launched for Xbox Series and PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2677660/Indiana_Jones_and_the_Great_Circle/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> and <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/store/p/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle/9n8fq28z6qx3" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Microsoft Store</a> on December 9, 2024.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Bethesda Softworks:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Uncover one of history’s greatest mysteries in <em>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle</em>, a first-person, single-player adventure set between the events of <em>Raiders of the <a title="Games > Lost Ark [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/lost-ark">Lost Ark</a></em> and <em>The Last Crusade</em>. The year is 1937, sinister forces are scouring the globe for the secret to an ancient power connected to the Great Circle, and only one person can stop them—Indiana Jones. You’ll become the legendary archaeologist in this cinematic action-adventure game from MachineGames, the award-winning studio behind the recent Wolfenstein series, and executive produced by Hall of Fame game designer Todd Howard.</p><p><strong>You Are Indiana Jones</strong></p><p>Live the adventure as Indy in a thrilling story full of exploration, immersive action, and intriguing puzzles. As the brilliant archaeologist—famed for his keen intellect, cunning resourcefulness, and trademark humor—you will travel the world in a race against enemy forces to discover the secrets to one of the greatest mysteries of all time.</p><p><strong>A World of <a title="Games > Myst (2020) [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/myst-2020">Myst</a>ery Awaits</strong></p><p>Travel from the halls of Marshall College to the heart of the Vatican, the pyramids of Egypt, the sunken temples of Sukhothai, and beyond. When a break-in in the dead of night ends in a confrontation with a mysterious colossal man, you must set out to discover the world-shattering secret behind the theft of a seemingly unimportant artifact. Forging new alliances and facing familiar enemies, you’ll engage with intriguing characters, use guile and wits to solve ancient riddles, and survive intense set-pieces.</p><p><strong>Whip-Cracking <a title="Genres > Action [2,592 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">Action</a></strong></p><p>Indiana’s trademark whip remains at the heart of his gear and can be used to distract, disarm, and attack enemies. But the whip isn’t just a weapon, it’s Indy’s most valuable tool for navigating the environment. Swing over unsuspecting patrols and scale walls as you make your way through a striking world. Combine <a title="Genres > Stealth [79 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/stealth">stealth</a> infiltration, melee combat, and gunplay to combat the enemy threat and unravel the mystery.</p><p><strong>The Spirit of Discovery</strong></p><p>Venture through a dynamic mix of linear, narrative-driven gameplay and open-area maps. Indulge your inner explorer and unearth a world of fascinating secrets, deadly traps and fiendish puzzles, where anything could potentially hide the next piece of the mystery—or snakes. Why did it have to be snakes?</p></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>PlayStation 5 Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="PS5 Date Reveal - Indiana Jones and the Great Circle" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/0VdnmreE1X0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indiana Jones And The Great Circle Launches In April On PS5]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-launches-in-april-on-ps5/1100-6530308/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-launches-in-april-on-ps5.1143222/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-launches-in-april-on-ps5/1100-6530308/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6530308">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Bethesda and MachineGames have announced that Indiana Jones and the Great Circle will launch for PS5 on April 17. They also released a new trailer featuring voice actors Troy Baker and Nolan North opening up a box containing a glowing blue hue, referring to PlayStation's primary color.</p><p>Those who preorder the game will receive the Last Crusade pack, which includes a Traveling Suit outfit for Indy as well as a Lion Tamer whip. The Premium Edition comes with a digital artbook and a Temple of Doom outfit, as well as a copy of the game in either digital or physical formats. It also includes up to two days of early access and the upcoming The Order of the Giants story DLC.</p><p>The Collector's Bundle is available too. It contains the Premium Edition, a steelbook case, an adventure journal, an Allmaker replica, and a globe with hidden storage.</p><p>Earlier this month, an <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circles-esrb-rating-for-ps5-may-imply-launch-is-near/1100-6530005/" data-ref-id="1100-6530005">ESRB rating</a> for Indiana Jones and the Great Circle popped up, indicating that a release date could possibly be revealed soon. The game also racked up <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-whips-up-4-million-players-before-ps5-debut/1100-6529145/" data-ref-id="1100-6529145">four million players on Xbox and PC</a> since its debut back in December before the PS5 release.</p><p>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle has won several awards, including Outstanding Achievement in Character, Outstanding Achievement in Story, and Adventure Game of the Year at the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/28th-annual-dice-awards-nominees-revealed/2900-6116/" data-ref-id="2900-6116">2025 Dice Awards</a>. It also won the Best Acting award for Troy Baker's performance as Indy at the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/new-york-game-awards-2025-all-nominees/2900-6106/" data-ref-id="2900-6106">New York Game Awards 2025</a>.</p><p>In GameSpot's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-review-im-making-this-up-as-i-go/1900-6418322/" data-ref-id="1900-6418322">Indiana Jones and the Great Circle review</a>, we said, "Indiana Jones and The Great Circle takes an unexpectedly stealthy and freeform approach, making for a faithful, rip-roaring adventure in which you truly embody the famous archeologist."</p><p>The next Bethesda game that could be making its way over to PS5 is Starfield, as it was <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/starfield-on-ps5-still-not-confirmed-but-new-evidence-emerges/1100-6530141/" data-ref-id="1100-6530141">recently discovered</a> that the Bethesda Creation Kit website for the game was updated with the PlayStation logo.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/115776530127739146123?rel=author">George Yang</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The First Berserker: Khazan Review]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/03/24/the-first-berserker-khazan-review/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-first-berserker-khazan-review.1143192/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/03/24/the-first-berserker-khazan-review/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="gp-content-wrapper">

	<article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/Article">

		<meta itemprop="mainEntityOfPage" itemtype="https://schema.org/WebPage" itemscope="" content="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/03/24/the-first-berserker-khazan-review/">
		<meta itemprop="headline" content="The First Berserker: Khazan Review">			
		
		<meta itemprop="author" content="Jason Coles">			
		<meta itemprop="datePublished" content="2025-03-24">
		<meta itemprop="dateModified" content="2025-03-24">
		
		
			
		
								
		
			

																		
		<div itemprop="text">
			
			<p>I love a good action game. Heck, I love a lot of middling action games so long as they’ve got one or two really cool things about them. The First Berserker: Khazan is definitely not a middling action game though, and has a lot of style along with a lot of substance that makes it a blast to play from start to finish, along with a gorgeous art style and some very edgy but entertaining writing.</p>
<p><iframe title="The First Berserker: Khazan | Demo Accolades Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/aU6bt8ArKY8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Khazan describes itself as a “hardcore action RPG,” which is a fun way to say that while it definitely evokes the Soulslike subgenre, it’s not quite a Soulslike. I actually really like that it’s not gunning to be a Soulslike, because while the weighty combat and the checkpoint system definitely mean a lot of players will be reminded of ye olde Dark Souls, it’s got a lot more in common with action games in general. It feels a bit more like a slower-paced Nioh, and that’s wonderful.</p>


<p>The main distinction here, for me at least, is that it’s just a little bit more easygoing in terms of difficulty, but also that there’s a lot more loot. Outside of the three main weapon categories, which are dual blades, big old sword, and spear, you’ve then got loads of armour sets to muck around with that have unique stats and properties, as well as set bonuses. It means there are a lot of ways to upgrade Khazan as he marches down the path of revenge and anime.</p>


<p>There are a load of little touches that allow the game to be a little more chilled too. While it’s always challenging, there’s little touches like gaining experience just from hitting bosses, skills unlocking as you play instead of at set points, and also an easy difficulty if you just want to smash things up. It all adds up to make a game that’s not holding your hand, but also isn’t actively trying to shoot you in the foot.</p>
<p>Wrapped around the gameplay is an art style that I absolutely adore. A lot of games go for an anime look using cel shading, but there’s plenty examples where that doesn’t work out. The style of The First Berserker: Khazan, both visually and in terms of the setting and story, means it all feels a lot more cohesive. This is an over-the-top story of revenge and battling through the underworld, and the visuals that render the regions you visit and the beasts and enemies you battle just help sell the whole thing.</p>

<p>The story kicks off in a fun way too – well, not “fun”, but certainly interesting. Khazan is a heroic character, that’s for sure, but he’s been condemned to death. You get to not only uncover why as you play through, but also see Khazan grow into something a bit different as he’s warped by the spirit possessing him and by the world around him. It’s just different enough to actually be worth paying attention too.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

			
		</div>

		
				
	<div id="gp-summary">
		<p>Summary</p><p>
		The First Berserker: Khazan is a great action game that's not reinventing anything by any means, but is consistently fun to play. The visuals are lovely, the action is a lot of fun thanks to ever-evolving skill trees, and the boss designs are great too. If you're after a Soulslike challenge, it can fit that bill in some ways, but it should also have a broader appeal thanks to the easy mode and more.	</p></div>
		

	<div id="gp-review-results">

									<div id="gp-good-points">
						<p>Good</p>
						<ul>
														
								<li><i></i>Great quality of life features</li>
														
								<li><i></i>Beautiful visuals</li>
														
								<li><i></i>Combat that builds on itself well</li>
													</ul>
					</div>
				
									<div id="gp-bad-points">
						<p>Bad</p>
						<ul>
														
								<li><i></i>Some fights can feel a bit uninspiring at times</li>
														
								<li><i></i>More weapon variety would have been nice</li>
													</ul>
					</div>
							
			</div>

					
	
						
			
			

			
						
		<div>

			<h3>Related stories from TSA			
			</h3>
			
				
				
		</div>

	
		
					
 
	
	
				
	</article>

</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The First Berserker: Khazan Review – Stranger of Pell Los]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/review/the-first-berserker-khazan-review-stranger-of-pell-los/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-first-berserker-khazan-review-%E2%80%93-stranger-of-pell-los.1143189/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/review/the-first-berserker-khazan-review-stranger-of-pell-los/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			<div><header>Game Info</header><div><div>
						<h5>The First Berserker: Khazan</h5><p><span>March 27th, 2025</span>
					</p></div><div>
							<h5>Platform</h5><p><span>PC (Steam), PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X, Xbox Series S</span>
						</p></div></div></div>			
			<p>Dungeon &amp; Fighter, or Dungeon Fighter Online, is one of the most played video games of all time, having managed to even surpass massively popular games like League of Legends in terms of gross revenues at times, but it is not a well-known game in the West. Starting with the fighting game <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/dnf-duel-broken-but-in-a-fun-way/">DNF Duel</a>, Korean developer Neople, however, has decided to try and bring in more people to their franchise with multiple titles set in the Dungeon &amp; Fighter Universe, such as The First Berserker: Khazan, an extremely competent action role-playing heavily inspired by the first few entries in FromSoftware's Souls series and Team NINJA's most recent ARPGs like the <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/nioh-2-the-complete-edition-grave-no-bar/">Nioh series</a> and <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/stranger-of-paradise-final-fantasy-origin/">Stranger of Paradise: Final Fantasy Origin.</a></p>
<p>As I was told a few months back during <a href="https://wccftech.com/the-first-berserker-khazan-interview-discussing-setting-gameplay-pc-features/">Gamescom</a> by game director JunHo Lee, The First Berserker: Khazan has been created as a starting point for newcomers to the Dungeon &amp; Fighter universe, and in this regard, the game does an excellent job making players interested in the harsh world where the MMO is set. The First Berserker: Khazan stars the titular Khazan, once the Great General of the Pell Los Empire who, in the 89th year of the Empire, is accused of treason and exiled to the Stru Mountains to live out his days in shame. The war-hardened veteran, however, is not an easy man to kill, as he manages to survive an avalanche that struck the carriage that was carrying him into exile. A fateful meeting with a crazed spirit called the Blade Phantom completely heals the Great General, whose tendons were severed as punishment for his treason, and grants him the power to exact vengeance on the emperor that exiled him. Power, however, comes at a heavy price, and Khazan will have to help this emissary of Charon restore balance in the universe by banishing the undead back to the Netherworld and finding the reason for this unbalance, all the while furthering his own vengeance. A bloody journey that will eventually turn him into the first Berserker of the Dungeon Fighter Online world.</p>
<p>The First Berserker: Khazan's story isn't particularly deep or anything, but it does its job of getting players interested in the Dungeon &amp; Fighter universe rather well, introducing the setting slowly without overpowering newcomers with terms and convoluted concepts. It also does a great job keeping players engaged, with some unexpected twists here and there and multiple endings that provide more information on the events that led to Khazan being branded a traitor and some of the game's central characters. The way the story is delivered, much like the gameplay, is definitely in the Souls series fashion, with some nicely choreographed short cutscenes, environmental storytelling, and dialogues with characters met during missions in The Crevice, the main hub, which is very reminiscent of Demon's Souls' The Nexus. All in all, the story provides a decent backdrop for all the action, of which the game features quite a bit.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/20250315120822_1-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>

<p>Right from the very first mission, it's very clear how The First Berserker: Khazan is a Soulslike through and through. The game ticks all the boxes of the ARPG subgenre spawned by FromSoftware's series; stamina-based combat with light and heavy attacks, dodging and blocking, hard-hitting enemies, and tricky enemy configurations scattered all over a multitude of different locations sporting a few secrets, shortcuts and bonfire-like checkpoints, Lacrima experience points that can be used to level up Khazan's stats but also craft and purchase gear and consumable items and so on. When the game doesn't tick the Souls series boxes, it more closely resembles Team NINJA's Nioh series, <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/wo-long-fallen-dynasty-shadows-dont-die-twice/">Wo Long: Fallen Dynasty</a> and Final Fantasy series spin-off Stranger of Paradise: Final Fantasy Origin with its focus on parrying, enemy stamina depletion and more complex moveset, which is expanded via different skill trees, for a limited number of weapon types that seem more to act as different playable characters with plenty of nuance and depth, rather than weapons with similar movesets and only a few remarkable differences like in FromSoftware's games. Level and world design are also closer to Team NINJA's games rather than FromSoftware's, as the game is comprised of a variety of main and side missions set in linear stages which are accessed via a main hub, and each location is a separate stage with no direct connection to the others. The ability to fight Spirits using Khazan's moveset and the ability to summon a Spirit of Assistance before boss battles, and the Phantom System, which allows Khazan to equip one among many different Phantoms that provide beneficial effects like increased stamina recovery, Spirit regeneration to allow the Great General to use powerful skills more often, have also been clearly lifted from the Nioh series.</p>
<p>Considering how The First Berserker: Khazan doesn't even attempt to try something different in an established gameplay formula, is it a game worth playing? It most definitely is, in my opinion, as I have found the game to be one of the most accomplished recent soulslike, alongside <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/lies-of-p-review/">Lies of P</a>. For starters, Khazan feels very good to control, thanks to amazing animation work and very responsive controls. The three weapon types available - Dual Blades, Greatsword, and Spear - all have some very different movesets and heavily determine how the player should approach combat, and all feel very satisfying to use. The defensive options, which include blocking, evading, and their perfect forms, a parry called Reflection with very strict timing and a Counterattack that can be unleashed when stronger enemies are about to use some powerful attacks, similar to Nioh 2's Burst Counters, not only all have their uses, but synergize well with some passive skills and attributes attached to gear, providing plenty of depth to the combat experience while also giving players a reason to go with gear other than the one providing the highest defense or stat increase.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/20250317192310_1-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>

<p>All of the offensive and defensive mechanics The First Berserker: Khazan offers wouldn't mean much with bad or average enemy design, but that is not the case here, as the game fully delivers in this regard, sporting a decent amount of regular enemies sporting different movesets and weapons, including plenty of ranged fighters, more powerful enemies that require a bit more effort to take down, Elite enemies that essentially function as mini-bosses, and proper bosses located at the end of each mission. Unsurprisingly, bosses are the stars of the show in The First Berserker: Khazan, coming with memorable visual and combat designs, effective movesets, and multiple phases that require players to always be on their toes to win. Unlike the current tendency FromSoftware has shown in its boss designs, with movesets with absurd range and areas of effect that are extremely unfair, I have found The First Berserker: Khazan's bosses to be quite challenging but also very fair. If you know when to attack and how to properly defend against their varied movesets, fighting bosses will be, for the most part, a frustration-free experience. In addition, every time Khazan dies while attempting to take down any of the bosses, the game not only rewards the player with some Lacrima but also allows the lost experience points to be recovered before entering the boss arena once again, which is a nice touch that reduces the need for grinding for Lacrima, although dying in the game is most often due to having used the wrong strategy, rather than being underleveled.</p>
<p>Even so, if anyone finds The First Berserker: Khazan too difficult but still wants to play through the game to experience the Great General's tale, they can decide to play the game in Easy Mode, which is considerably more approachable than the regular difficulty setting. Once Easy Mode is selected, however, there's no turning back, and some achievements will no longer be unloackable, so think hard before making the jump to the reduced difficult mode the game offers. While not as effective as picking the easier difficulty mode, it is possible to make The First Berserker: Khazan slightly easier by taking full advantage of the gear system. Like in more traditional action role-playing games and the Team NINJA Souls series-inspired games, gear comes in different rarity levels, which determine their stats, and has different random attributes and set bonuses, which not only grant significant advantages but also include skills not available on the regular skill trees. A few hours into the adventure, it becomes possible to increase the level of gear and alter its random attributes, so the game definitely provides everything a player may need to bring difficulty down a bit. Make no mistake, however. As much as the developer says that they didn't want to make a challenging game just for the sake of it, The First Berserker: Khazan is still a challenging game. Perhaps not when fighting the vast majority of mobs, but when fighting bosses, you will probably die a lot as you try to figure out their attack patterns and how best to deal with them using any of the numerous defensive options available.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/20250319181545_1-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>

<p>With its well-animated cel-shaded character models, detailed environments featuring a rather oppressive atmosphere that well suits the game's story, and all sorts of flashy special effects for even regular combat maneuvers, The First Berserker: Khazan is as great to look at as it is a joy to play. Performance is solid on PC, as the game had no trouble running at high framerates on my machine (i7-13700F, RTX 4080, 32 GB RAM). Locking the game to my monitor's max refresh rate, 120 Hz, the game had no trouble running at solid 120 FPS most of the time at 4K resolution with NVIDIA DLSS in Quality mode and max setting. A system configuration like mine can even push beyond the 120 FPS cap, as the game ran at an average of 152 FPS, 85 1% low during a benchmark session conducted in the Nadin Quarry stage. These numbers, however, don't tell the whole story, as there's some light traversal stuttering in certain areas, but thankfully it is not major. Before the release of the latest patch during the review period, the game also suffered from some massive shader compilation stutters during boss battles every time the enemy performed a special move for the first time, but the issue seems to have been fixed, as I have not experienced it again after the game was updated.</p>
<p>The First Berserker: Khazan is one of those games that gets better and better the more you play it. What in the beginning feels only like another Soulslike becomes a very engaging experience with deep combat, lots of complementary gameplay systems, and a great visual style that make it a game worth playing for all those who are looking for an engaging, combat-focused action role-playing game and are not too bothered by the almost complete lack of innovation. In the 40 or so hours required to complete the main campaign once, I know I wasn't.</p>
<p><em>PC version tested. Review code provided by the publisher.</em></p>

				

						<div>
					
					
					<h2>The First Berserker: Khazan</h2>
				</div>
			
						<section>
				<p>With its excellent combat system, complementary mechanics, solid level and enemy design, and engaging story, The First Berserker: Khazan stands out as one of the best action RPGs in recent years. While its heavy inspiration from FromSoftware and Team NINJA’s latest titles is a little too evident, and PC performance issues occasionally impact the experience, the tale of Great General Khazan is a compelling one that makes for a great game and the perfect introduction to the world of Dungeon Fighter Online.</p>
				<div>
												<ul>
							<h6>Pros</h6>
							<li>Interesting setting
</li><li>Engaging enough story
</li><li>Excellent combat mechanics with plenty of depth enhanced by solid complementary mechanics
</li><li>Amazing boss design
</li><li>Good amount of content
</li><li>Great cel-shaded character models and visuals</li>						</ul>
																		<ul>
							<h6>Cons</h6>
							<li>Not particularly original or innovative
</li><li>Minor stuttering issues</li>						</ul>
										</div>
				<a rel="sponsored nofollow noskim" href="">Buy for  from Amazon</a>
				<span>The links above are affiliate links. As an Amazon Associate, Wccftech.com may
					earn from qualifying purchases.</span>
			</section>
			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Assassin's Creed Shadows Debuts to Series' Highest Steam Player Count]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/assassins-creed-shadows-steam-player-count</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/assassins-creed-shadows-debuts-to-series-highest-steam-player-count.1143183/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/assassins-creed-shadows-steam-player-count<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Assassin's Creed Shadows</em>, the latest game in the long-running&nbsp;<em>Assassin's Creed&nbsp;</em>series of stealth action-adventure games, has launched to the franchise's highest Steam player count of all time.</p>

<p>As spotted by the folks at <a href="https://www.dexerto.com/assassins-creed/assassins-creed-shadows-sets-huge-franchise-record-with-growing-player-count-3168000/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Dexerto</a>,&nbsp;<em>Shadows</em>' peak player count on Steam <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/3159330/charts/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">hit 64,825</a> over the weekend. At time of writing, that's still the game's peak; 43,263 players are currently enjoying&nbsp;<em>Shadows</em>, which still isn't bad considering today is a Monday.</p>

<p>That figure puts&nbsp;<em>Assassin's Creed Shadows&nbsp;</em>slightly ahead of Greek epic&nbsp;<em>Assassin's Creed Odyssey</em>, which managed to achieve a peak player count of 62,069 around the time of its release. There's not much in it, but&nbsp;<em>Assassin's Creed Shadows&nbsp;</em>is officially the series' biggest Steam launch.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/assassins-creed-shadows-steam-player-count-sneaking.jpg?itok=4STrPyMk 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/assassins-creed-shadows-steam-player-count-sneaking.jpg?itok=kuspaO07 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Assassin's Creed Shadows&nbsp;</em>is officially the franchise's biggest Steam launch.</figcaption></figure><p>If you're wondering how the game stacks up against other Ubisoft releases, it still can't quite hold a candle to the publisher's biggest Steam launches ever, at least not according to <a href="https://steamdb.info/publisher/Ubisoft/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">SteamDB's numbers</a>.</p>

<p>Ubisoft's biggest Steam launch ever was the crunchy melee brawler&nbsp;<em>For Honor</em>, which achieved an impressive 225,831 peak player count in August 2018. It's followed by&nbsp;<em>Tom Clancy's Rainbow Six Siege</em>'s peak of 201,933, with&nbsp;<em>The Division</em>'s 114,228 (a very satisfying number) putting it in a comfortable third.</p>

<p>Despite the fact that&nbsp;<em>Assassin's Creed Shadows&nbsp;</em>can't reach those lofty heights, its success will doubtless come as a relief to Ubisoft, given that the game hasn't exactly had an easy time of it in recent months.</p>

<p>Announced last year,&nbsp;<em>Shadows&nbsp;</em>was originally set to launch in November, but was <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/assassins-creed-shadows-delayed-february" rel="nofollow">subsequently delayed to February</a> as Ubisoft announced it would rethink some of its business practices (including releasing PC games on Steam on day one in future).</p>




<p>The game was <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/assassins-creed-shadows-delayed-again-march" rel="nofollow">then delayed again</a>, with publisher Ubisoft <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/xdefiant-shutting-down-ubisoft-studios-closing" rel="nofollow">closing down</a> three of its <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/ubisoft-layoffs-leamington-closure" rel="nofollow">locations</a>&nbsp;and revealing its intention to pursue <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/ubisoft-financials-cost-cutting-q3" rel="nofollow">further cost-cutting measures</a> after a pretty dire third-quarter performance.</p>

<p>It remains to be seen whether&nbsp;<em>Assassin's Creed Shadows&nbsp;</em>can single-handedly turn Ubisoft's fortunes around, but the game is available right now for <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3159330/Assassins_Creed_Shadows/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC</a>, <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-gb/games/assassins-creed-shadows/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PlayStation 5</a>, and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-GB/games/assassins-creed-shadows" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Xbox Series X|S</a>. You can read our Andrew's <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/assassins-creed-shadows-story-attempting-to-hit-word-limit" rel="nofollow">review of the game here</a>.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Playable GTA 6 map mod Project Vice is no more following Take-Two copyright strike]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/playable-gta-6-map-mod-project-vice-is-no-more-following-take-two-copyright-strike</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/playable-gta-6-map-mod-project-vice-is-no-more-following-take-two-copyright-strike.1143180/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/playable-gta-6-map-mod-project-vice-is-no-more-following-take-two-copyright-strike<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Next up, fresh GTA 6 conspiracy theories</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/1_h9LRI0U.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Dark Space</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>A <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/grand-theft-auto-v">GTA 5</a> mod that aims to recreate the entirety of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/gta-6-everything-we-know">GTA 6</a>'s map based on "leaked" data and guesswork is no longer in development, after Rockstar parent company Take-Two had videos of the project banished from Youtube.</p>
<p>Titled Project Vice and <a href="https://x.com/Dark_SpaceYT/status/1902865326804701386">released</a> to the public on 20th March, the playable GTA 6 map mock-up in question is the work of Youtuber Dark Space. In a <a href="https://youtu.be/7LmLfJAuR_U?feature=shared">response video published yesterday</a>, Dark Space says Take-Two sent him a copyright removal request over his Youtube videos of the mod last week. He's now removed all download links to the mod, without any further prompting from Take-Two, and says he's no longer working on the project.</p>
<p>"I spent months building a fan-made GTA 6-inspired map inside GTA 5--something purely made out of passion, not profit," reads the intro to the response video. "But shortly after uploading a video showcasing the project, Take-Two Interactive took it down. No warning. No conversation. Just gone."</p>
<p>Dark Space has since been chatting to <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/gta-6-map-in-gta-5-mod-suffers-inevitable-take-two-takedown-creator-believes-it-was-probably-a-little-too-accurate-and-could-have-ruined-the-surprise">IGN</a> about this reversal, which he says wasn't unexpected (an unsympathetic soul might ask why, given that knowledge, he decided to work on it in the first place). "I expected this would happen based on their past takedowns," he said. "I went into this project knowing it was a possibility, and the fact that it happened does not surprise me." </p>
<p>Take-Two have yet to share their reasoning for the takedown request, so we're left with Dark Space's own explanation for events. The mod forms part of a loose community GTA 6 mapmaking initiative, largely operating out of Reddit, which deploys a bunch of speculation and alleged leaked information to plot out the game's geography. That said, Dark Space claims that "most" of his map is based simply on shots from <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/gta-6-first-trailer-reactions">the first GTA 6 trailer</a> from back in 2023.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Grand Theft Auto VI Trailer 1" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZvqP6ziEQ3Y?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Grand Theft Auto VI Trailer 1</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZvqP6ziEQ3Y?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/ZvqP6ziEQ3Y?autoplay=1" title="Grand Theft Auto VI Trailer 1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZvqP6ziEQ3Y" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>"I think my map could have ruined the surprise of their map, which I get," he told Ian Games. "If you spent years building out this amazing game world just to have some YouTuber spoil the experience of the map's shape, size, and vibe... I'd want it removed too."</p>
<p>As for why he's decided to junk the whole thing despite not being commanded to by our insect overlords at Take-Two, Dark Space observed that "well they clearly do not want this project to exist. So it's not just under threat, it's eliminated. There's no point putting more time into something that goes directly against what they're willing to allow."</p>
<p>All of this naturally makes me much more curious about Project Vice. Is this just a corporation's lawyers auto-firing at anything that smells remotely like an infringement, or is the mod, as Dark Space suggests, "a little too accurate" in its portrayal of GTA 6? I mean, it's probably the former, but please don't let my growing deficiency of wonder ruin an <a href="https://x.com/zapactugta6/status/1904151003290566681">emerging conspiracy theory</a>. I've dug up a bunch of screenshots of Project Vice for your eyeballs and insights.</p>
<figure data-count="4" role="group">
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/3_HFXfVI8.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
</figure>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/4_BuI11wf.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
</figure>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/1_h9LRI0U.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
</figure>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/2_nEoVab4.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
</figure>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Dark Space</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>All of this continues Rockstar and Take-Two's rather torrid relationship with the GTA modding scene, which has seen them <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/gta-5-ai-mod-shot-down-by-take-two-even-as-rockstar-relax-policy-on-modding">recruit some modders</a> to work on the series while <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/gta-v-and-rdr2-vr-modder-receives-dmca-takedown-from-take-two-interactive">giving others the ole DMCA blunderbuss</a>. It'll be intriguing to see how things change or don't change after the release of GTA 6, given that the game is <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/gta-6-may-let-you-modify-its-own-map-using-roblox-style-user-creation-features-claims-report">rumoured to let you modify its own map using Roblox-style features</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Minecraft Is Getting A Major Visual Upgrade, Flying Mounts, And My Favorite Quality Of Life Feature In Years]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/minecraft-vibrant-visuals-ghasts-bedrock-edition-1851771891</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/minecraft-is-getting-a-major-visual-upgrade-flying-mounts-and-my-favorite-quality-of-life-feature-in-years.1143168/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/minecraft-vibrant-visuals-ghasts-bedrock-edition-1851771891<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>2025 is going to be <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/the-unending-appeal-of-minecraft-1795549429?_gl=1*hthy9t*_ga*MTg4NjY0MzM1NS4xNzM5NDU1MDcz*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTc0MjgyMjEwMi4zMS4xLjE3NDI4MjYyMzguNjAuMC4w&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/the-unending-appeal-of-minecraft-1795549429?_gl=1*hthy9t*_ga*MTg4NjY0MzM1NS4xNzM5NDU1MDcz*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTc0MjgyMjEwMi4zMS4xLjE3NDI4MjYyMzguNjAuMC4w">a neat year for <em>Minecraft</em></a></span>. Not only is the survival crafting game moving to more frequent feature drops, it’s also getting flying mounts and a big boost to its more than  decade-old graphics. Revealed during a special Minecraft Live, Vibrant Visuals will make every pixelated world full of new life and possibilities thanks to the power of better lighting and reflections.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196049" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="This Modern Warfare 3 Gameplay Feature Spices Up A Weak Campaign" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="134" data-playlist="196049,196653,196307" data-current="196049"><div><p>This Modern Warfare 3 Gameplay Feature Spices Up A Weak Campaign</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196049/196049_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196049/196049_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196049/196049_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196049/196049_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21580.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>The additions to Mojang’s 3D sandbox that first officially debuted back in 2011 were on display at March 2025's edition of Minecraft Live, a presentation that will now take place two times a year to match the faster cadence of smaller but more impactful feature drops arriving alongside them. The first of these is Vibrant Visuals, a visual overhaul coming the the Bedrock edition of Minecraft this year on Xbox Series X/S, PlayStation 5, and PC. </p><p>The developers say the update adds “thousands of individually crafted elements while preserving what makes Minecraft unique.” Alongside the tweaked appearance, volumetric lighting is the other key feature of Vibrant Visuals. Instead of the world looking flat, the new lighting will bring more depth and also improve reflections. Water shimmers and cast shadows look more stark. It all makes <em>Minecraft</em> look a lot more appealing, especially at sunset. </p><p>Happy Ghasts are another big deal. They’ll be able to carry small groups of players through the world, making survival mode more accessible. Players will find dried ghasts in the netherworld, bring them back to the overworld, re-hydrate them, and then poof: a cute, cloud-like chariot awaits. My kids are going to love it, until they start fighting over them. </p><p>What they won’t be fighting over is the new  Player Locator bar that Mojang also briefly touched on during the event. Announced earlier this month, the new UI feature will make it easier for players to find one another across the map. No more looking around for striking landscape features and going, “I’m kinda, sorta, maybe 100 yards Northeast of the oak tree by the beach.” Instead, players will appear as color-coded blips on a horizontal bar near the bottom of the screen. This one is gonna save me a ton of time. </p><p>As with all of the other features, there no specific release date for this, but all of them should be coming in the next few months. Maybe by then we’ll also hear about any upgrades coming to a Switch 2 version of <em>Minecraft</em>. The <em>Minecraft Movie</em> is also out April 4, just two days after the Switch 2 Nintendo Direct. </p><p>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hollow Knight Silksong Steam Metadata Change Has Fans Ready To Get Hurt Again]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/hollow-knight-silksong-steam-metadata-change-has-fans-ready-to-get-hurt-again/1100-6530313/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hollow-knight-silksong-steam-metadata-change-has-fans-ready-to-get-hurt-again.1143162/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/hollow-knight-silksong-steam-metadata-change-has-fans-ready-to-get-hurt-again/1100-6530313/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6530313">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">Of all of the video games announced or released in the last decade, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/hollow-knight-silksong-everything-we-know-about-team-cherrys-metroidvania/1100-6520282/" data-ref-id="1100-6520282">Hollow Knight Silksong</a> ranks among the most torturous to follow. First announced in 2019 and last seen in 2022, Silksong fans are starved for more information--and a recent change to the game's SteamDB profile is providing a temporary snack.</p><p dir="ltr">The <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/1030300/history/" rel="nofollow ">Silksong SteamDB</a> page is now reflecting a change made to the game's Steam metadata made on March 24. Specifically, the game's bio now includes an opt-in option for the Nvidia GeForce Now service--and, more importantly, a change in the store page's fine print that changes the copyright date from 2019 to 2025.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/3/37852/4464116-hollow-knight-silksong-metadata.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4464116" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/3/37852/4464116-hollow-knight-silksong-metadata.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4464116"></a><figcaption>Hornet from Hollow Knight Silksong</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/3/37852/4464116-hollow-knight-silksong-metadata.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">The change has resurrected hopes of a Silksong appearance at the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/switch-2-release-date-specs-display-price/1100-6520278/" data-ref-id="1100-6520278">Nintendo Switch 2</a> Direct livestream scheduled for April 2, as rumors swirled of the game's involvement with the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/hollow-knight-silksong-creator-drops-clues-of-switch-2-version/1100-6528880/">Switch 2 announcement</a> back in January. One month later, fans were alerted when<a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/hollow-knight-silksong-page-removed-from-nintendo-store-remains-elsewhere/1100-6529560/"> the game's eShop page mysteriously disappeared</a>, only for it to reappear later.</p><p dir="ltr">Hollow Knight Silksong's debut trailer came during the E3 2019 Nintendo Direct, where it was announced for Nintendo Switch and PC. Since then, the game featured in the Xbox Showcase--where it was confirmed to be part of Xbox Game Pass--in June 2022, while official<a href="https://x.com/PlayStation/status/1570797280063627264" rel="nofollow "> PlayStation social media accounts confirmed</a> it would also launch on PlayStation consoles.</p><p dir="ltr">The Nintendo Switch 2 Direct is currently scheduled to kick off April 2 at 6 AM PT / 9 AM ET. There has been no official word from Team Cherry or Nintendo regarding Silksong's involvement as of this writing.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/115235460361630065469?rel=author">Jason Fanelli</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Crimson Desert’s BlackSpace Engine Showcase Demonstrates Big Tech Advancements]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/crimson-desert-blackspace-engine-showcase-demonstrates-big-tech-advancements/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/crimson-desert%E2%80%99s-blackspace-engine-showcase-demonstrates-big-tech-advancements.1143129/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/crimson-desert-blackspace-engine-showcase-demonstrates-big-tech-advancements/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>As we <a href="https://wccftech.com/crimson-desert-to-launch-in-fall-2025-pc-requirements-revealed/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">learned</a> at The Game Awards 2024, Korean developer Pearl Abyss finally nailed down a release window for Crimson Desert. The game was first <a href="https://wccftech.com/pearl-abyss-showcases-stunning-debut-trailers-for-crimson-desert-plan-8-and-dokev-mmo-games/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">unveiled</a> at G-Star 2019, and back then, it was still billed as an MMO that was not too dissimilar from the studio's premiere game, Black Desert. Not long afterward, the developer <a href="https://wccftech.com/crimson-desert-shifts-from-mmo-to-open-world-action-adventure-with-multiplayer-support-launch-set-for-winter-2021/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced</a> a genre change from MMO to single-player open-world action/adventure, albeit still with optional multiplayer support. Back then, the game was still tentatively headed toward a Winter 2021 launch, but in July 2021, Pearl Abyss <a href="https://wccftech.com/crimson-desert-open-world-multiplayer-game-delayed-indefinitely-by-pearl-abyss/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">said</a> the project had been indefinitely delayed.</p>
<p><iframe title="Crimson Desert Time of Day Timelapse" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/BrtH_Kwto94?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Crimson Desert only <a href="https://wccftech.com/crimson-desert-gets-new-gameplay-trailer-at-gamescom-2023/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">resurfaced</a> at Gamescom 2023 with a gameplay trailer. Multiplayer appears to have been silently cut, but other than that, communication has been constant, and there have even been limited hands-on opportunities at various conventions. At the recent Game Developers Conference 2025 in San Francisco, Pearl Abyss put the spotlight on the game's BlackSpace Engine. According to the team, the proprietary technology can render vast, sprawling, and seamless open worlds with great detail. In the game, Kliff and his fellow Greymanes will traverse a variety of landscapes, including lush forests, medieval-inspired cities, snow-capped mountains, and vast deserts.</p>
<p><iframe title="Crimson Desert GPU based Cloth and Hair Simulation" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/HcY56F6o1V0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>The simulations running under the hood of the BlackSpace Engine augment the realism of the environments: trees, grass, cloth, and hair are all naturally affected by wind movement. The environments featured in Crimson Desert also support real-time physics and destructibility, not to mention volumetric fog, real-time lighting, detailed atmospheric scattering effects, and dynamic weather. Optionally, ray tracing can further enhance visual realism. The engine also supports highly realistic water effects thanks to the usage of FFT Ocean simulation and Shallow Water simulation, creating realistic waves, currents, and ripples.</p>
<p><iframe title="Crimson Desert Fluid Simulation" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/i48sVUmiuuU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Lastly, the BlackSpace engine also improves combat encounters thanks to the detailed hit reactions and physics-based interactions.&nbsp;Object destruction can vary depending on the force applied, and enemies can dynamically collide with the environment, adding depth to combat. Pearl Abyss has shared several brief videos of the technology. You can find them embedded throughout this article.</p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Crimson Desert Shallow Water" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/T-2oZNnKRmI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Gameplay-wise, Crimson Desert promises a great variety of traditional content (quests, puzzles, dungeons), 'life' content (cooking, hunting, mining, gathering, fishing, crafting, horse taming), and a fairly complex combat system that combines parrying, blocking, dodging, jumping, and even some wrestling moves. The players will create their own unique combos.</p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Crimson Desert Raytracing" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/cWwwDgDPU8s?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Crimson Desert is slated to launch this Fall on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3321460/Crimson_Desert/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PC</a> and Mac, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series S|X.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>