<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 20:57:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Runescape's Future May Be Radically Reshaped After Fan Vote]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/runescapes-future-may-be-radically-reshaped-after-fan-vote/1100-6535811/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/runescapes-future-may-be-radically-reshaped-after-fan-vote.1338694/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6535811">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>The daily Treasure Hunter has been a part of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/runescape/" data-ref-id="5000-5022">Runescape</a> since 2014, and some of the game's players openly resent it as a pay-to-win feature that diminishes the experience for fans who don't utilize it. Jagex has been exploring its options for the feature, and now the developer is leaving Treasure Hunter's fate in the hands of the fans.</p><p>Jagex has started <a href="https://secure.runescape.com/m=poll/treasure-hunter-poll" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">an online poll</a> that will determine if Treasure Hunter will stay in Runescape. If 100,000 players vote to remove Treasure Hunter, it will be completely deleted from the game alongside 225 direct XP and skilling items that are related to it. That would leave the game with only two purchasable items: Bonus XP with capped storable limits per skill and cosmetics "with a more grounded visual identity."</p><p>"Today marks one of the most important moments in Runescape history," reads a statement on the site. "We are proposing a new future for the game led by integrity, where your achievements are based on merit, and the vast experiences offered within Gielinor can truly shine.This is an era-defining shift for Runescape where YOU will cast the deciding vote--just as we did for the birth of Old School."</p><p>Jagex has previously laid out <a href="https://secure.runescape.com/m=news/mtx-experiments-what-weve-learned" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">the results of its experiments with Treasure Hunter</a>, and earlier polling that indicated it was a valuable resource for "time-poor" players. To appeal to those players, Bonus XP will remain in the store, but the new skill caps for storable XP are meant to encourage players to engage in the regular gameplay rather than simply buying all of their experience.</p><p>If the vote goes forward to remove Treasure Hunter, Jagex stated that it will "invest in a year-long Integrity Roadmap that addresses the heart of issues that have long held Runescape back--from UI, to onboarding, to dailyscape, revisiting the combat status quo and beyond. We'll also be looking at the balance of our XP progression too, ensuring each skill is still a satisfying experience to level up with a significant reduction in MTX-relative skilling items."</p><p>To place a vote, players will have to be logged in as their Runescape characters. The voting period will run until November 12, and nearly 40,000 players have already voted in favor of removing Treasure Hunter.</p><p>Outside of the main game, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/old-school-runescape/" data-ref-id="5000-486787">Old School Runescape</a> recently <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/old-school-runescape-is-more-popular-than-ever-breaks-concurrent-player-record/1100-6533697/" data-ref-id="1100-6533697">broke its concurrent-user record</a> with 241,016 players.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/runescapes-future-may-be-radically-reshaped-after-fan-vote/1100-6535811/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[CEO of GTA 6 publisher Take-Two is surprisingly hesitant about AI usage for entirely unsurprising reasons]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/ceo-of-gta-6-publisher-take-two-is-surprisingly-hesitant-about-ai-usage-for-entirely-unsurprising-reasons</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ceo-of-gta-6-publisher-take-two-is-surprisingly-hesitant-about-ai-usage-for-entirely-unsurprising-reasons.1338664/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/gta-6-grand-theft-auto-6-main-characters-hot-7.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/gta-6-grand-theft-auto-6-main-characters-hot-7.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/gta-6-grand-theft-auto-6-main-characters-hot-7.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/gta-6-grand-theft-auto-6-main-characters-hot-7.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/gta-6-grand-theft-auto-6-main-characters-hot-7.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/gta-6-grand-theft-auto-6-main-characters-hot-7.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/gta-6-grand-theft-auto-6-main-characters-hot-7.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/gta-6-grand-theft-auto-6-main-characters-hot-7.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/gta-6-grand-theft-auto-6-main-characters-hot-7.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Rockstar Games / Take-Two Interactive</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Because that sacred line called profit must always go up, we are seeing more and more game studios announce their intention to incorporate various forms of AI tech. PUBG publisher Krafton just recently referred to themselves as an <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/pubg-and-inzoi-publisher-krafton-declares-itself-an-ai-first-company-placing-ai-at-the-centre-of-problem-solving">AI-first company</a>, the big wigs up top at EA are <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/inside-ai-divide-roiling-video-game-giant-electronic-arts-2025-10">reportedly pushing for it hard</a>, it is, seemingly, unfortunately, inevitable. Which makes Take-Two CEO Strauss Zelnick's comments on it ever so slightly surprising - but only slightly, we'll get back to that.
</p>
<p>
Zelnick made an appearance at <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2025/10/28/can-ai-create-next-grand-theft-auto-take-two-interactive-ceo-says-no.html">CNBC's</a> Technology Executive Council Summit on Tuesday, where he was asked about his thoughts on the "promise" of AI in game development. Right off the bat, the CEO reminds us that he is still the CEO of publicly-traded company, as he did make it clear he's not a "naysayer" of AI. But he does actually seem to understand how limited it currently is, and crucially, for him and Take-Two, how risky it is for their intellectual property.
</p>
<p>
"We have to be really careful not to step on other people's intellectual property, and we don't ours stepped on," Zelnick explained. "As you know, if you create intellectual property with AI, you can't protect it. We're in the intellectual property business, we care about our rights, we care about other people's rights, and we have to protect what we make."
</p>
<p>
That's where the comments aren't very surprising, as it just seems like Zelnick is the very rare CEO that doesn't want to force AI right this very second because it risks their precious IP, IP that includes giants like <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/grand-theft-auto-vi">GTA</a> and NBA, as well as still very popular series like Borderlands.
</p><p>
This is where the surprising element comes in! Zelnick went on to note how in the event that AI has no constraints, he thinks whatever you'd make wouldn't be very good. "Could we push a button tomorrow and create an equivalent to the ‘<a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/grand-theft-auto">Grand Theft Auto</a>’, and the marketing plan, and here it is? The answer is no. A, you can’t do that yet, and B, I am of the view that you wouldn’t end up with anything very good. You end up with something pretty derivative."
</p>
<p>
Zelnick goes on to say how AI is just big datasets, and defines them as "backward-looking," as in it's always working off of something else that's already been made rather than looking forward. Perhaps his most surprising line is this one: "there is no creativity that can exist, by definition, in any AI model, because it is data driven."
</p>
<p>
I'd like to be very clear that I really do think Zelnick is currently only hesitant about implementing the use of AI at scale because of his aforementioned concerns over IP. I'm just hoping (yes, a useless thing to do here) that maybe some other CEOs and shareholders might see the GTA guys holding off and think maybe we should too. Can't wait for that to not happen!

</p>

        </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/ceo-of-gta-6-publisher-take-two-is-surprisingly-hesitant-about-ai-usage-for-entirely-unsurprising-reasons]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Arc Raiders: Everything You Need To Know Before Launch]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/arc-raiders-pvpve-extraction-maps-embark-studios-2000639945</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/arc-raiders-everything-you-need-to-know-before-launch.1338658/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><i>Arc Raiders</i>, the next game from <i>The Finals </i>developer Embark Studios, launches on October 30, 2025 on PS5, Xbox Series X/S, and PC.</p> <p><b>Read More:</b> <a href="https://kotaku.com/ark-raiders-embark-studios-server-slam-2000637325"><i>Arc Raiders</i> Is So Good I’m Worried It Will Completely Take Over My Life</a></p> <p>As a PvPvE extraction shooter, <a href="https://kotaku.com/ark-raiders-embark-studios-server-slam-2000637325"><i>Arc Raiders</i></a> sees you setting out to explore and loot the remains of a fallen civilization still under control of a lethal artificial intelligence system known as “Arc.”</p> <p>The game has already been in the hands of players via a few technical tests and the reaction has been overwhelmingly positive. Still, you might not know much about <i>Arc Raiders</i> or extraction shooters as a genre, and as someone who’s pretty excited about the game, I’d like to do what I can to make it as approachable as possible for potential players. So let’s break down everything you need to know about this game ahead of its release, from how many maps the game provides to the overall flow of your average match.</p>

  <h2>It’s you versus them, and also <i>them</i></h2> <p><i>Arc Raiders</i> is a PvPvE extraction shooter. That means you and a team of up to three are fighting real humans as well as the game’s computer-controlled bots, but your main “goal” is to leave the map alive within a certain time–which in theory you could do without firing a single shot. You can leave via multiple elevators on the map, each of which have a timer on them. You can also find or buy keys to escape hatches that make for an even speedier getaway.</p>

 <p><b>Read More:</b> <a href="https://kotaku.com/arc-raiders-leaper-server-slam-pvpve-extraction-2000637774">Check Out This Really Awesome Moment From <i>Arc Raiders</i>’ Server Slam</a></p> <p>With both people and patrolling enemy AI in the mix, there are a wide variety of emergent possibilities as different players, each with their own playstyles and agendas, intersect with the threats on the map. It makes for an intense game in which you need to think a few steps ahead of each action you take, and always keep an escape route in mind should you realize you’ve gotten yourself in over your head.</p>

   <p>Get out alive, and you keep everything you came in with, plus whatever you found. Die, and you’ll lose everything. You do have access to a “safe pocket” in your inventory, however, where you can stash a lone precious item to make it to the other side should you perish.</p>

 <p>As you explore the maps, you’ll find countless places to loot. Abandoned cars, file cabinets and desk drawers from empty offices and facilities, storage containers, and much more.</p> <figure id="attachment_2000639951" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000639951"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000639951">© Screenshot: Embark Studios / Kotaku</figcaption></figure> <p>You’ll also have a variety of quests you can take on, some of which ask you to loot specific items, while others ask you to take down some of the game’s bots, or “Arc” as they’re referred to in-universe. Quest progress is maintained even if you die, and you’ll earn XP after each match which can be used to improve your character’s stats, so death is not a total loss.</p>

 <p><b>Read More:</b> <a href="https://kotaku.com/arc-raiders-server-slam-embark-studios-ferro-2000638324"><i>Arc Raiders’</i> Dev Addresses Graphics Downgrade, Enemy Difficulty, And More Ahead Of Release</a></p> <p>When you’re not out on the field scavenging for parts from a fallen world, you’ll be at home in “Speranza,” your hub for launching games, crafting, and trading. <i>Arc Raiders</i> has a thorough crafting system; you can build weapons, gadgets, restorative items such as shield rechargers and bandages, and more. You can also trade with a variety of NPCs.</p>

 <p>You als0 have a pet rooster named Scrappy who’s always happy to see you after a match, giving you some minor crafting supplies when you return. If you’ve had a bad streak of losses, Scrappy will give you extra crafting materials as a consolation for your repeat losses.</p> <p>Zoom out, and we see the loop of the game: Venture out onto the maps, find what you can, avoid or engage in battles with humans or machines, return home and build better gear for your next run.</p> <h2>A closer look at <i>Arc Raiders</i>’ maps on launch</h2> <p><i>Arc Raiders</i> launches with four main maps, each set in a post-apocalyptic Italy with their own unique difficulty levels and points-of-interest. These maps are: Dam Battlegrounds, Buried City, the Spaceport, and the Blue Gate. There’s also a practice range and a mysterious location called “Stella Montis” which we don’t know a whole lot about ahead of release.</p>

 <p>The maps offer up a nice level of variety. Dam Battlegrounds, with its thick swamps and forests, makes for some brutal, <i>Predator</i>-esque battles and chase scenarios.</p> <figure id="attachment_2000639952" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000639952"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000639952">© Screenshot: Embark Studios / Kotaku</figcaption></figure> <p>Buried City is a smaller, more urban setting with some excellent sightlines across the tops of its roofs (there are going to be some intense sniper battles here, I can already tell).</p> <figure id="attachment_2000639946" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000639946"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000639946">© Screenshot: Embark Studios / Kotaku</figcaption></figure> <p>The Spaceport is another large map. My time on this map during a preview event was cut short due to, well, some very aggressive players. It’s very pretty though!</p>

 <p>Lastly, the Blue Gate is a gorgeous, mountainous map with tons of rolling hills that makes for some excellent battles with other players. It’s easily the toughest map, however, with aggressive Arc presence. There are also some lovely, labyrinthine mazes of steel and concrete under the surface to get lost in.</p> <figure id="attachment_2000639947" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000639947"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000639947">© Screenshot: Embark Studios / Kotaku</figcaption></figure> <p>Dam Battlegrounds is perhaps my favorite at the moment. As someone who prefers stealthy tactics, having bushes and trees to fall back to and hide in works well with my style. But I’d be lying if I said hunting down other players in the mountainous terrain of the Blue Gate didn’t give me a rush.</p> <h2>Which is worse, machines or other players?</h2> <p>The titular “Arc” come in <a href="https://arcraiders.wiki/wiki/ARC">a variety of forms</a>. With threats ranging from the different drone types who survey the ground below for human threats, to smaller patrolling orbs and little spiders (or “Ticks” as the game calls them) that monitor the insides of abandoned buildings, you’ll have to keep your eyes peeled. And they’re not afraid to just insert themselves into a skirmish with players, so don’t be surprised if you get swarmed by some once they see or hear you trading shots.</p>

   <p>There are also larger threats. The spider-like Leapers can, as the name implies, leap across incredible distances in their pursuit. There’s also the Queen, which often guards precious loot, particularly on the Dam Battlegrounds map.</p>   <p>These machines are resilient and aggressive in their desire to eliminate human threats, and you’ll have to place your shots well to destroy vulnerable parts and take them down.</p> <figure id="attachment_2000639950" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000639950"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000639950">© Gif: Embark Studios / Kotaku</figcaption></figure> <p>Speaking of those human threats, you also have other players to contend with, who pose a challenge equal to their skills with the game and the quality of their gear. Kill a human and a flare launches up into the air, letting just about anyone nearby know that a fight just went down and there’s gear for the taking.</p> <p>Without universal objectives for every player, extraction shooters can make for some truly unexpected encounters with other humans. And admittedly, it can feel a little unfair when someone kills you from an unexpected hiding place.</p>

 <p><b>Read More:</b> <a href="https://kotaku.com/arc-raiders-embark-extraction-virgil-watkins-interview-2000639879">I Asked <i>Arc Raiders</i>’ Design Director If Camping Makes Me A Bad Person</a></p> <p><a href="https://kotaku.com/arc-raiders-embark-extraction-virgil-watkins-interview-2000639879">Speaking with <i>Kotaku</i></a>, <i>Arc Raiders</i>’ design director Virgil Watkins said that the game is designed in such a way that “you should always have time to understand and react to what is happening to you.” With a longer time-to-kill (TTK) than most games in the genre, the game is designed to give you time to react. On combat with other players, Watkins said:</p> <blockquote><p>On even footing, the way TTK is balanced, if you’re full health and full shields, and so am I, and you attack me first, there’s a very solid chance that I will probably be able to back away, disengage, and do something to mitigate that situation. We really like when our fights have a lot of back and forth rather than just instantaneous [death].</p></blockquote> <p>Each map is also full of opportunities to hear other players nearby. Players make noticeable sounds not only while walking or running, but also when breaking into loot caches, tripping security cameras and metal detectors in abandoned interiors, scaring birds in the wild who take flight, and attracting attention from Arc. All of these can signal to you that another player is nearby, or give your presence away to someone else.</p>

 <p>This all complicates any approach to stealthily moving through a map. But it also means that you can set up some solid ambush opportunities by keeping your ears open for nearby threats, especially with the generous hiding spots on the game’s maps.</p> <h2>Is <i>Arc Raiders</i> too hardcore?</h2> <figure id="attachment_2000639896" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000639896"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000639896">© Screenshot: Embark Studios / Kotaku</figcaption></figure> <p>I’ve long been <a href="https://kotaku.com/extraction-shooter-dmz-tarkov-cycle-battle-royale-1850287778">a fan of the extraction shooter genre</a>. It brings together a variety of different game systems in a unique way that makes for an unpredictable and irresistible experience. But I get that the genre is not everyone’s cup of tea, especially given how lethal and mean it can be. Losing all of your gear can be a painful setback that isn’t easy to bounce back from. Embark Studios is aware of this and has built <i>Arc Raiders</i> to be a more approachable take on an otherwise hardcore genre.</p>

 <p>“Approachability was a key design tenet,” Watkins told me during our interview. Maintaining quest progress even after defeat, earning crafting supplies from Scrappy, and having multiple ways to extract means that it’s very doable to plan your way to victory at your own pace while also having a solid safety net to fall back on should you lose.</p> <hr> <p>Defeat is a crushing experience in an extraction shooter. But <a href="https://kotaku.com/ark-raiders-embark-studios-server-slam-2000637325">as I’ve said before</a>, those deep lows make for exhilarating highs when you come out alive from a tense battle or manage to get away with a sweet amount of loot.</p> <p>Ahead of release, however, we’ve only gotten a taste of <i>Arc Raiders</i>’ maps, its arsenal, and its threats. How the full experience will evolve over time remains to be seen, but based on my time with the game during its technical previews, I’m eager to see what wild, unexpected moments will happen out there in post-apocalyptic Italy.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/arc-raiders-pvpve-extraction-maps-embark-studios-2000639945]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Worst COD League Game Mode is Finally Being Removed]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/worst-cod-league-mode-finally-removed/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-worst-cod-league-game-mode-is-finally-being-removed.1338655/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>The Call of Duty League 2026 season is shaping up nicely now that the full schedule and running order have been revealed. Next year, the Call of Duty League will go to <strong>three countries</strong> in an unprecedented global tour that takes the CDL further than ever. It was also revealed that, <strong>thankfully</strong>, Control is being removed from the CDL rotation and will be replaced with an all-new mode.</p>



<p>Control was never awful, but the slow tempo, limited map pool, and tricky mechanics have long stood in the way of the mode being a complete success with fans of the COD League. It became suffocating during the 2025 CDL season when it was confined to just <strong>two maps</strong>.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-what-mode-is-replacing-control-in-the-cdl">What Mode is Replacing Control in the CDL?</h2>



<p>Control is officially being replaced after <strong>many years </strong>by Overload, a brand-new mode released alongside Call of Duty: Black Ops 7. In Overload, players are forced to contend with dynamic objectives, rapid respawn timers, wider map compatibility, and much clearer win conditions, all wrapped up in a mode that’s not too different from Capture the Flag.</p>



<p>The 2025 CDL season wrapped a few months ago, and now that it is dead and gone, so too is Control.</p>



<p>Despite being a staple of the COD League since 2018, the popularity of the mode declined, and quite drastically so in recent years. It was a mode that didn’t accommodate too much strategy, and it was ultimately something too repetitive to be hugely enjoyable</p>



<p>Overload goes the other way entirely, revealing positive results in tests and drawing nice feedback from the fans that’s sure to make it a winning formula when the CDL 2026 season goes live on December 5.</p>



<p>In some social circles, Overload has been dubbed ‘the most CDL-ready mode in years’, given that it perfectly accommodates the competitive flow that users expect from the COD League.</p>



<p>Do you think Overload will be a nice reset to the COD League formula going into the CDL 2026 season? Let me know what you’re thinking on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-league-2026-going-to-eu-uk-usa/">CDL is headed back to the UK and France</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/worst-cod-league-mode-finally-removed/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rare NES Platformer 'Little Samson' Is Coming To Switch In 2026]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/10/rare-nes-platformer-little-samson-is-coming-to-switch-in-2026</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/rare-nes-platformer-little-samson-is-coming-to-switch-in-2026.1338646/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>"The Wildest Adventure of Them All!" returns</p>
</section></header><section>

<p>Limited Run Games has announced that it's bringing NES side-scrolling platformer <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nes/little_samson">Little Samson</a> to the Switch in 2026. The reveal took place during the company's <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QK5Ow9zHA4U">10th anniversary stream</a>.</p>
<p>Originally released in 1992 for the NES and directed by former Capcom designer Shinichi Yoshimoto (<a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nes/strider">Strider</a>, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/megadrive/ghouls_n_ghosts">Ghouls 'n Ghosts</a>), Little Samson sees you controlling one of four characters — the eponymous Samson, a dragon called Kikira, the golem Gamm, or a mouse called K.O.</p>
<p>Each character controls a little differently and has different abilities — Kikira can breathe fire, for example, while Samson can climb walls and throw bells. Outside of the first four stages, which act like tutorials, you can swap which character you control at any point during the game. There are 20 stages to beat, with a true final boss that's only accessible if you beat the game on Normal difficulty.</p>

<p>In more recent years, Little Samson has become something of a collector's item. It's infamously one of the more-expensive NES games out there, with copies going for hundreds (if not thousands) of dollars online.</p>
<p>Well, now that won't be a problem, as Limited Run Games' Carbon Engine port will make it more accessible to all. Amazingly, we actually asked LRG's Josh Fairhurst about Little Samson when <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/features/how-limited-runs-new-engine-respects-the-legacy-of-classic-games">we interviewed them way back in 2022</a>, and here's what he had to say then:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"It’s super high on games I want to do but no one knows where the rights are. We reached out to Taito and they said “They might be with the owner.” So we found the owner (who was really hard to find) and he said “I don’t know who has the rights.” So now we’re basically at a dead end. Who has the rights to Little Samson? No idea."</p>
</blockquote>
<p>We're glad the team made something work!</p>
<p>Though it's worth highlighting that Limited Run Games has come under fire in recent months due to delays on physical products, some items being below-standard, and NES cartridges that may damage your console. Josh also spoke to our sister site <a href="https://www.timeextension.com/features/interview-werve-certainly-made-mistakes-limited-runs-boss-on-winning-back-the-trust-of-the-community">Time Extension more recently about those issues</a>.</p>
<hr>
<p><em>Are you looking forward to Little Samson on Switch? Ever played it before? Let us know in the comments</em>.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-articles:130013,181825,178795 @ 1761770708 --></section></article><div><p>Alana has been with Nintendo Life since 2022, and while RPGs are her first love, Nintendo is a close second. She enjoys nothing more than overthinking battle strategies, characters, and stories. She also wishes she was a Sega air pirate.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/AlanaHagues"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/alanahagues.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('AlanaHagues');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/10/rare-nes-platformer-little-samson-is-coming-to-switch-in-2026]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Team Behind One Of 2017’s Most Underrated Games Is Back With Another Banger]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/battle-suit-aces-review-impressions-chef-brigade-trinket-2000639931</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-team-behind-one-of-2017%E2%80%99s-most-underrated-games-is-back-with-another-banger.1338640/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><span>2017 was one of the all-time great years for video games, with major tentpole games like </span><i><span>Super Mario Odyssey</span></i><span>, </span><i><span>The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild</span></i><span>, and </span><i><span>Persona 5 </span></i><span>dominating GOTY conversations. So if you missed out on some of the hidden gems of that year, I wouldn’t blame you. </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/battle-chef-brigade-the-kotaku-review-1820617722"><i><span>Battle Chef Brigade</span></i></a><span> is one of those precious games that might have gotten lost in the shuffle, and Trinket Studios’ match-three/brawler/cooking game still holds up in 2025. However, the studio didn’t just try and make lighting strike twice with its latest project that’s out now on PC, PS5, and Switch. </span><i><span>Battle Suit Aces </span></i><span>is a much different game than its predecessor, but it’s no less stylish, endearing, and compelling.</span></p> <p><span>I want to rely on some easy lexicon to describe </span><i><span>Battle Suit Aces</span></i><span>, but I fear calling it a deckbuilder might give you the wrong impression. The game’s strategic battles are played with a deck of cards, each representing a different member of its mech-piloting crew, but these conflicts are less about getting mired in the mechanical complexities of individual cards than they are solving a puzzle with a randomized set of tools. Each card pulls from a different set of colored energies that replenish each turn to unleash attacks on the opposing team, and they all have different attack patterns on the game’s 5v5 field. So card placement on the board is just as important as your deck composition, and can be the difference between gaining the upper hand in a match or being outplayed.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <p><span>Firepower isn’t enough to win every time, though, and that’s where secondary effects and synergy come into play. Each pilot has additional perks, such as how Felix, the carefree white-haired hottie whom I’ve been lusting after my whole playthrough, is able to unleash a more powerful attack after his teammates destroy a certain number of enemy units. Yan’s mech is able to pierce through enemies, meaning it can fire a beam through an opposing card while also directly hitting their ship, which is similar to attacking your foe’s Life Points directly in a game of </span><i><span>Yu-Gi-Oh</span></i><span>. If you can destroy an enemy ship, you automatically win a duel. You don’t need a piercing ability to do it, as leaving any of the five spaces on the field empty leaves you and your enemies vulnerable to a direct attack. So, having units that can attack multiple spaces or really take advantage of an opening is a pretty reliable strategy, but more often than not, your foes will have more cannon fodder to put between your crew and their ship.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <figure id="attachment_2000639933" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000639933"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000639933">© Trinket Studios / Kotaku</figcaption></figure> <p><span>At first, I didn’t quite see the depth of </span><i><span>Battle Suit Aces</span></i><span> until I started playing around in the simulations on my ship that would give me only a few cards and challenge me with something like winning the fight it set up in one turn. These typically required me to take advantage of passive perks in order to set off a chain of attacks that relied on precise positioning and an order of operations to activate. I could read the card descriptions, such as the explanation of Daciana’s passive ability to proc a free attack every time one of her allies destroyed an enemy, but seeing the cards in action is what made the game click for me. These plays are why I’m more inclined to describe </span><i><span>Battle Suit Aces</span></i><span> as a turn-based strategy game rather than a deck builder, because you only have a handful of units, and the game doesn’t make you create decks of dozens of cards with a ton of minutiae to memorize. Once you see a lot of these characters playing off each other on the field, those bespoke mechanics naturally weave themselves into your strategies without the game becoming too overwhelming.</span></p>

 <p><span>In the five or so hours I’ve put into </span><i><span>Battle Suit Aces</span></i><span> so far, the game has pretty gently eased me into its whole deal, and the simple but satisfying card battles are only one slice of it. Those cards have names and faces, and the crew you’ll recruit into your deck is a big reason the game is so breezy. </span><i><span>Battle Suit Aces </span></i><span>stars Heathcliff, the captain of a starcraft called the USS Zephyr. In his spaceflight adventures, he and his crew meet several other mech pilots who are all typically game to join their cause as they investigate ancient cosmic secrets. Recruiting these characters gets you a new card for your deck, but it also puts another misfit on your ship. They chat with you, but also with each other, so there’s a constant sense of camaraderie and community between the group. Thus far, everyone’s pretty likable, and I’m interested to see their relationships grow not only with me as the player, but with each other, as well.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <figure id="attachment_2000639932" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000639932"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000639932">© Trinket Studios / Kotaku</figcaption></figure> <p><span>These relationships are elevated by </span><i><span>Battle Suit Aces</span></i><span>’ incredible character art and best-in-class voice acting. The anime-inspired art style looks straight out of classic mech anime like </span><i><span>Gundam </span></i><span>and </span><i><span>Evangelion</span></i><span>, though its chipper tone helps differentiate it from the latter. Everyone is hot and wearing a plug suit, so there’s something for everyone here. The game is full of memorable performances from some talented voice acting veterans, and I’ve really enjoyed listening to their interactions between duels, which help give the whole thing an authentic classic anime feel.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><i><span>Battle Suit Aces </span></i><span>has a lot to offer without ever getting too in the weeds that it becomes overwhelming. Much like </span><i><span>Battle Chef Brigade</span></i><span>, it manages to hit the sweet spot between tactical and approachable without ever veering too far into one or the other. Its skill expression is vast, its characters are easy to love, and it marries both sides of its world in a way that keeps me playing for just one more match. I’m looking forward to seeing where the USS Zephyr’s crew takes me as our journey through space continues.</span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/battle-suit-aces-review-impressions-chef-brigade-trinket-2000639931]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Call of Duty League 2026 is Going To Europe, UK, and USA with All-New Format]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-league-2026-going-to-eu-uk-usa/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/call-of-duty-league-2026-is-going-to-europe-uk-and-usa-with-all-new-format.1338637/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>The Call of Duty League’s grand reveal has just taken place for the 2026 season, and fans are immensely excited. The new season starts on December 5, and in the months that follow, the CDL 2026 season will greet fans in three countries. Majors are set to take place in the United States, England, and France, all wrapping up with a grand COD Champs event in <strong>Las Vegas</strong>.</p>



<p>Plenty of changes are coming for the new season, including the first 10-team Major, the return of Minor tournaments, and beefed-up Challengers opportunities at <strong>every LAN event in the season</strong>.</p>



<h2 id="h-cdl-2026-schedule-looks-insane">CDL 2026 Schedule Looks Insane</h2>



<p>The <a href="https://callofdutyleague.com/en-us/news/2026-season-announcement" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Call of Duty League 2026</a> schedule is already running wild. It confirms my <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-league-return-to-europe-and-uk-2026/">earlier exclusive reports</a> that the COD League is coming to the United Kingdom, as well as hosting a Major in Paris, France. It also confirms the placement of <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/cod-champs-2026-hosted-faze-las-vegas/">COD Champs in Las Vegas</a>, which I exclusively revealed earlier this year.</p>



<p>Here’s the schedule for the 2026 Call of Duty League:</p>



<ul>
<li>Opening Weekend: December 5 – 7</li>



<li>Major I (Dallas, Texas): January 29 – February 1</li>



<li>Major II (DreamHack UK): March 27 – 29</li>



<li>Minor I: April 24 – 26</li>



<li>Major III (DreamHack Atlanta): May TBC</li>



<li>Minor II: June 5 – 7</li>



<li>Major IV (Paris, France): June 25 – 28</li>



<li>COD Championship (Las Vegas, Nevada): July 16 – 19</li>
</ul>



<p>Major III at DreamHack Atlanta will be a Pro-Am event, and the Minor tournaments will feature teams <strong>outside </strong>the core CDL structure, as will Major II in Birmingham, UK.</p>



<p>It has already been too long since the end of the last season, during which OpTic Texas claimed the top spot and won the first back-to-back COD Champs in Call of Duty esports history. The team would then go on to win at the Esports World Cup in Riyadh, solidifying a spot in the history books.</p>



<p>The team is set to host Major I in Dallas, Texas, at the end of January – will the winning streak continue on home turf?</p>



<p>Let me know what you think about the CDL 2026 season schedule on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming esports, stay tuned to our <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/category/esports/">latest news feed</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-league-2026-going-to-eu-uk-usa/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Remedy CEO Steps Down Following FBC: Firebreak's Sales Flop]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/remedy-ceo-steps-down-following-fbc-firebreaks-sales-flop</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/remedy-ceo-steps-down-following-fbc-firebreaks-sales-flop.1338631/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">"Our first multiplayer product launch was technically successful."</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Remedy Entertainment's CEO has resigned, leaving the new CEO of the developer of Control and Alan Wake to reassure investors after weak sales of FBC: Firebreak left the company significantly lowering its revenue expectations for the year and writing off the game's development costs.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In its quarterly earnings report issued today, Remedy revealed that it recognized a €14.9 million ($17.4 million) impairment charge representing most of the development costs as well as purchased publishing and distribution rights for FBC: Firebreak.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">In total, Remedy's revenue decreased 32% year-over-year, to €12.2 million ($14.2 million). Remedy says this was largely driven by lower development fees coming in than last year at this time, during which it received revenue from Annapurna related to development work it did on Control 2. Remedy also revealed that it was revising its revenue expectations for the year: while previously Remedy expected revenue and operating profit to increase year-over-year and be positive, it now expects revenue to increase, but its operating profit to decrease and be negative. No exact numbers were shared.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Alongside this, CEO Tero Virtala has stepped down after nine years in the position. He is succeeded in the interim by board chairman Markus Mäki, who has stepped down from his chairman role and been replaced by Henri Österlund.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In comments by Mäki shared with investors, he stated that while Remedy would continue "working on features which enhance player value" and would keep true to its shared roadmap for Firebreak, the studio has moved development resources elsewhere going forward. Mäki also attempted to reassure investors that Firebreak was not a total loss:</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"We have also found positive sides from FBC: Firebreak," he said. "Our first multiplayer product launch was technically successful in a cross-platform environment, and our publishing team has built capabilities which support the releases of our future self-published titles."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">FBC: Firebreak was Remedy's first ever self-published game, and while the studio claims it technically succeeded, it also <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/remedy-admits-fbc-firebreak-underperformed-commercially-we-were-unsatisfied">admitted last quarter</a> that it "underperformed" on Steam and that the company was "unsatisfied" with its commercial reception. In today's earnings, Remedy stated that Breakpoint improved the game's sales only "marginally."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">We <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/fbc-firebreak-review">gave FBC: Firebreak a 6/10</a>, saying that it was a "compelling co-op shooter that, despite its good looks, doesn't have the depth to keep things interesting long-term."</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Rebekah Valentine is a senior reporter for IGN. You can find her posting on BlueSky @duckvalentine.bsky.social. Got a story tip? Send it to rvalentine@ign.com.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/remedy-ceo-steps-down-following-fbc-firebreaks-sales-flop]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battlefield REDSEC Launches to 'Mostly Negative' Steam Reviews as Battlefield 6 Players Push for Battle Pass Changes and Bigger Maps]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/battlefield-redsec-launches-to-mostly-negative-steam-reviews-as-battlefield-6-players-push-for-battle-pass-changes-and-bigger-maps</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/battlefield-redsec-launches-to-mostly-negative-steam-reviews-as-battlefield-6-players-push-for-battle-pass-changes-and-bigger-maps.1338628/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">“This is not why I bought Battlefield 6.”</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">EA just introduced its new, destructive take on battle royale with <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/battlefield-redsec">Battlefield REDSEC</a>, and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/battlefield-6">Battlefield 6</a> base game players are already slamming it with “Mostly Negative” Steam reviews.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">PC users who head to Steam to check out the standalone Battlefield experience, which <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/battlefield-redsec-launches-alongside-battlefield-6-season-1-with-battle-royale-gauntlet-and-portal-modes-heres-everything-you-need-to-know">launched across PC and consoles for free yesterday</a>, will be met with a flood of negative <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3028330/Battlefield_REDSEC/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Steam reviews</a> across the board. At the time of this piece’s publication, just 35% of REDSEC Steam user reviews were positive, with positive reviews in all languages fairing just slightly better at 39%. Both measurements result in a dark red, Mostly Negative label.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">A wave of negativity for Battlefield’s latest crack at battle royale arrives as Battlefield 6 players continue to express their dissatisfaction with the premium experience. Calls for changes to the base game reached a boiling point with <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/battlefield-6-season-1-trailer-highlights-blackwell-fields-and-eastwood-maps-ahead-of-next-weeks-launch">the launch of Season 1</a> yesterday, and now, criticism is spilling into REDSEC.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Although Battlefield 6 and REDSEC exist as separate multiplayer offerings, both EA and Battlefield Studios games share unlocks tied to many challenges, cosmetics, and battle pass unlocks. Where this has evolved into a problem is how one experience might affect another, with many Battlefield 6 players complaining of weekly challenges that require them to play battle royale.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“I wouldn't hate it so much if I wasn't forced to play it for challenges in the main game,” one <a href="https://steamcommunity.com/id/SirDoombox/recommended/3028330/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>negative Battlefield REDSEC Steam review</u></a> says. “But I am. So I do.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“This is not why I bought Battlefield 6,” they add.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"Oh, but you just can reroll the challenges!" another <a href="https://steamcommunity.com/profiles/76561197986653939/recommended/3028330/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">negative review</a> says. "Yeah and 3 of them are sill for the BR because they are pushing it hard on people that would not touch it even once..."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Other PC players agree that challenges granting large amounts of Battlefield 6 battle pass XP shouldn’t be tied to another experience, but dissonance isn’t the only thing tanking REDSEC Steam reviews. Some base game players are using Valve’s digital storefront to air out grievances related to multiplayer map sizes.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Battlefield REDSEC Launch Screenshots</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Early Battlefield 6 adopters have called for larger multiplayer maps as far back as the August beta tests, with the October 10 launch only adding fuel to the fire, as launch locations failed to live up to expectations for the community. At least a few negative Steam reviews even praise REDSEC’s exclusive battle royale map, Fort Lyndon, with their frustrations mostly summed up with one question: Why does the free-to-play game get the map sizes that premium players are asking for?</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Oh wow a nice big map with lots of POIs and flanks,” another <a href="https://steamcommunity.com/id/idiedonetime/recommended/3028330/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>negative REDSEC review</u></a> says. “If only we could get something like this for the main game.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“It's trying to be too much all at once,” another <a href="https://steamcommunity.com/id/JC_3223/recommended/3028330/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Steam user review</u></a> adds. “The map in this Battle Royale is so good it's criminal that it's not being used for Conquest right now.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As Battlefield 6 players aim to leave their mark with REDSEC Steam reviews, there are plenty of comments actually related to the new standalone experience itself, too. Many are positive, applauding how BF Studios blends classic Battlefield mechanics with other popular battle royale experiences, like Call of Duty: Warzone. Launch also ushered in a spike in activity, with <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/2807960/charts/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Steamdb</u></a> recording a 24-hour peak of 549,766 Battlefield 6 players yesterday.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">REDSEC, which encompasses Gauntlet and Portals modes in addition to its battle royale mode, is getting love in the Battlefield community, but there is still a general feeling that the experience is incomplete. Specifically, it’s the lack of a solo queue option and battle royale fatigue that many are calling out – both in negative and positive reviews.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“No solo Mode... When will they learn the overwhelming majority of players play solo?” one <a href="https://steamcommunity.com/id/koiruus/recommended/3028330/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>negative review</u></a> asks. “It doesn't feel good to play with randoms against premade coordinated squads.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Fun update, the battle pass is not half bad,” a <a href="https://steamcommunity.com/id/ZedAway/recommended/3028330/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>positive review</u></a> adds. “Only problem with me is not having a solo battle royal mode.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">REDSEC is just 24 hours into its time in the public’s hands. Seasonal updates will continue to offer shared experiences between REDSEC and Battlefield 6. Season 1 launched yesterday, introducing the new Blackwell Fields map for multiplayer, with more mid-season maps and guns set to follow in November and December.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">EA has <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/battlefield-6-recently-patched-conquest-mode-to-make-the-matches-shorter-the-community-complained-and-now-the-developers-have-reversed-the-decision">addressed fan feedback</a> in the past, with the latest update <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/we-won-battlefield-6-fans-rejoice-as-ea-tones-down-bright-colors-on-monster-energy-skin">introducing fixes for a controversial green skin</a> and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/flashbang-battlefield-6-lighting-is-so-bright-that-players-feel-like-they-have-to-fight-the-sun">some of the bothersome lighting effects</a> that have distracted players since launch. In the meantime, some players have been <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/battlefield-6-engineers-are-becoming-in-game-artists-instead-of-capturing-the-objective">content simply using their time to draw on walls with the Engineer repair tool</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Michael Cripe is a freelance writer with IGN. He's best known for his work at sites like The Pitch, The Escapist, and OnlySP. Be sure to give him a follow on Bluesky (@mikecripe.bsky.social) and Twitter (@MikeCripe).</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/battlefield-redsec-launches-to-mostly-negative-steam-reviews-as-battlefield-6-players-push-for-battle-pass-changes-and-bigger-maps]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Talking Point: When Did 'Good Enough' Become Good Enough For Pokémon?]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/features/talking-point-when-did-good-enough-become-good-enough-for-pokemon</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/talking-point-when-did-good-enough-become-good-enough-for-pok%C3%A9mon.1338610/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
<figure data-uuid="85a947ad7c8ab"><a title="Pokemon" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/85a947ad7c8ab/pokemon.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Gemma Smith / Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure><p>Over the weekend, we republished our reader-ranked list of <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/guides/best-pokemon-games-of-all-time">all the Pokémon games</a> after everyone had had a chance to spend some quality time with <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/pokemon-legends-z-a-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Legends: Z-A</a> and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/features/poll-what-review-score-would-you-give-pokemon-legends-z-a">vote accordingly</a>.</p>
<p>That's 22 mainline games by our count. The entries at the top of the table probably won't surprise you, as the inventiveness and sheer novelty (and nostalgia) of earlier entries dominate the higher ranks, although it may surprise you to see OG <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gameboy/pokemon_red_and_blue">Red/Blue</a>/<a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gameboy/pokemon_yellow_version_special_pikachu_edition">Yellow</a> outside the top 10.</p>
<p>However, scrolling down from low to high, one thing becomes immediately obvious: the Switch generation hasn't been a great one for Pokémon.</p><div><figure data-videoid="2LcP6TZzqhM" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/2LcP6TZzqhM?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><div><iframe title="YouTube Video" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/2LcP6TZzqhM?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/2LcP6TZzqhM?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed635c59whzjuq&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>837k</span></a></p>
</div></figure></div>
<p>The Pokémon Company's accountants would beg to differ, I'm sure. ZA <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/10/pokemon-legends-z-a-scored-us-biggest-physical-game-launch-since-totk">reportedly</a> turned in the biggest physical launch figures in the US since <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/legend_of_zelda_tears_of_the_kingdom">Tears of the Kingdom</a>, and it's gone down similarly well in Japan. The UK and European launches seem to have been <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/10/uk-charts-pokemon-legends-z-a-is-the-smallest-retail-launch-since-lets-go-in-europe">a mite less enthusiastic</a>, but <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/10/round-up-the-reviews-are-in-for-pokemon-legends-z-a">the critical reception</a> was positive, and the game is rocking a "Generally Favourable" Metascore of <a href="https://www.metacritic.com/game/pokemon-legends-z-a/">78</a> on Switch 2, <a href="https://www.metacritic.com/game/pokemon-legends-z-a/critic-reviews/?platform=nintendo-switch">76</a> on Switch 1.</p>
<p>And yet, with nearly 500 NL user ratings at the time of writing, there it languishes at the very bottom of our Pokémon list.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-articles:79484 @ 1761770851 -->
<figure data-uuid="61fc2aec9fbed"><a title="Pokemon" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/61fc2aec9fbed/pokemon.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Zion Grassl / Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>It's an odd one. Recency bias can present the opposite issue when a fervent fanbase is all-in on the new hotness, but after an initial period, we find things settle down nicely. Yes, it turns out <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/super_mario_odyssey">Mario Odyssey</a> and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/legend_of_zelda_breath_of_the_wild">BOTW</a> really are all-timers that deserve their spots at (or near) the very, very top of their rankings. We've had it so good with other Nintendo series since 2017, which makes all these Switch Pokémon games in the nosebleeds stand out all the more.</p>
<p>Naturally, you'll always have extremes with reader-voted polls: some will slap on an 'Outstanding' 10/10 to try and elevate their favourites; others will troll games they've taken against with a 1/10 to knock them down a peg. (Seriously, the five people currently rating <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/bokura-planet">BOKURA: planet</a> 'Abysmal' need to have a word with themselves, but that's another article.) But bombers and bootlickers and genuine outlier opinions aside, a good sample size soon balances things out and games settle into their groove.</p>
<p>And there's no getting around it: the consensus shows a paucity of truly great, recent Pokémon games. <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/pokemon_sword_and_shield">Sword and Shield</a> sits at #18, followed by <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/pokemon_lets_go_pikachu_and_lets_go_eevee">Let's Go, Pikachu and Eevee</a> at #19, the <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/pokemon_brilliant_diamond_and_shining_pearl">Diamond and Pearl</a> remakes at #20, and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/pokemon_scarlet_and_violet">Scarlet and Violet</a> slotting in just before ZA at the bottom.</p>
<p>The exception is <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/pokemon_legends_arceus">Pokémon Legends: Arceus</a> at #5; a game which dared to try something a <em>little</em> different, blending nostalgia for a past generation with some innovative touches — for Pokémon, at least — and hinting at a bright future if Game Freak dared to be different.</p>

<p>It's worth clarifying that none of the Switch Pokémon games are straight-up bad. The average score from nearly 500 NL readers currently stands at 7.0, coincidentally bang on with <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/nintendo-switch-2/pokemon-legends-z-a-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Alana's 7/10 review score</a>. As per our own scoring rubric, it's patently a 'Good' game.</p>
<p>But is 'Good' or 'Generally Favourable' sufficient for one of the most beloved series in all of video games? Imagine the headlines, the think pieces, the <em>confusion</em> if Nintendo fumbled the next 3D Mario and it settled on a Metascore in the late 70s. It's possible, but also, somehow, unthinkable. Would Koizumi even let it out the door if he thought someone could give it a 4 with a straight face? 'Good' doesn't cut it for the greatest series.</p>
<p>Yet it seems that, at some point, we've gotten used to 'good enough' from Pokémon, a sorry state for a series that fires up such formative passions. When did it happen?</p>
<p>I remember <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/3ds/pokemon_x_and_y">X &amp; Y</a> launching without support for the 3DS' namesake, flagship feature. Was that it? I don't think so. Rarely has a Pokémon game been a visual tour de force, and that game was genuinely great. No, that wasn't it.</p>
<figure data-uuid="6de7165e83781"><a title="Pokemon" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/6de7165e83781/pokemon.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Alex Olney / Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>Sword and Shield felt like a very safe first step into a new realm, although in that context, as the first home-console entry, Game Freak still had the benefit of the doubt. No, no, the <em>next</em> one will be the big one...</p>
<p>Not that one. Or that one. Hmm. Look, maybe Gen 10 is when they'll really bring out the big guns, Timmy.</p>
<p>The Pokémon fanbase extends far beyond the games, of course, so you're not relying on the near-annual mainline schedule for your Pokémon fix. However, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/features/pokemon-tcg-community-engulfed-in-potential-fraud-scandal">discord in the physical TCG sphere</a> and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/features/opinion-one-year-on-every-positive-pokemon-tcg-pocket-update-still-comes-with-a-catch">dissatisfaction</a> with the <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/mobile/pokemon_trading_card_game_pocket">Pocket</a> version, in particular, have seen the fanbase become more vocally unhappy than ever. Throw in major disappointment around Scarvi's performance (which, for the record, performs much better on Switch 2 - it only took two-and-a-half years and totally new hardware!) and it feels like Pokémon stories come in just four flavours: 'random 'mon distribution in Game X', '<em>OMG terrible tech!!1</em>', 'scandalous card-pack prices', and 'crossover merch'.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-articles:182656,161218 @ 1761768016 -->
<p>Given the series' success, the dev resources allocated are a popular discussion topic, too. If Pokémon is the biggest franchise on the planet, why isn't The Pokémon Company putting Naughty Dog-level budgets on these games? <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/10/pokemon-z-as-source-code-and-beta-builds-have-now-supposedly-leaked">A recent (still-unverified) leak</a> of various Pokémon-related material <a href="https://www.polygon.com/pokemon-franchise-budget-leak-game-freak-nintendo-switch-graphics/">reportedly suggests</a> that Scarlet and Violet's budget was $21.8 million.</p>
<figure data-uuid="4632c24f7ec23"><a title="Pokemon" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/4632c24f7ec23/pokemon.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Gemma Smith / Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>Now, many a small developer would kill for a budget like that, but for games that sell <em>this</em> well, a budget of $22 million is modest compared to many AAA games on other consoles. Perhaps there's something there: whatever triple-A means exactly in 2025, Pokémon...just isn't. Has it ever been?</p>
<p>Modern Pokémon's problem is a lack of ambition. Say what you like about <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/mobile/pokemon_go">Pokémon GO</a>, but it injected something totally fresh and captivating. And it did so nearly a decade ago, eight months before Switch launched. I gave myself an RSI playing that in Hong Kong, such was the curiosity and joy it inspired, the ol' surprise and delight. <em>[insert tasteless joke about more recent Pokémon games inspiring personal injury of a different nature here]</em></p>
<p>TPC giving the mainline series a breather last year felt like tacit acknowledgement that they'd made too many trips to the well and had come back with a muddy bucket. A year to regroup seemed prudent to prevent an MCU-style glut of product and waning enthusiasm.</p>
<figure data-uuid="634de2828d339"><a title="Pokemon" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/634de2828d339/pokemon.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: The Pokémon Company</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>But is enthusiasm <em>actually</em> waning for Pokémon? ZA's early sales figures suggest 'nope', although speaking to the NL team, there's a general sentiment which doesn't bode well. A sampling:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"Modern entries try to convey a sense of freedom, yet constantly stop you in your tracks to explain something excruciatingly simple step-by-step. They've lost that sense of discovery."</p>
<p>"I’m always more excited to boot up Ruby/Sapphire or Black/White than the latest entry — and I think that’s because I always need to clarify the newbies with a “Yeah, it’s pretty rough, <em>but</em>…” to justify my enjoyment."</p>
<p>"There are no surprises anymore."</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Then again, we're not kids anymore; naturally, they're the franchise focus. There's an influx of fresh players every generation, and no impetus for TPC to push the envelope when the base proposition of catching 'em all is still so addictive and profitable. Candy doesn't go out of fashion, does it? We're not kicking down doors at Cadbury's or Hershey's demanding they reinvent chocolate.</p>
<p>But just contrast this to Nintendo's own approach to Mario. Just the other day, we saw <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/10/shigeru-miyamoto-is-confident-mario-will-be-around-for-a-long-time-to-come">Nintendo luminaries stressing</a> that Mario will only survive if his games evolve and the developers continue to innovate. What's the last mainline Mario game that surprised me? <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/super_mario_bros_wonder">Wonder</a>, probably. The last one. Perhaps to a fault (<em>"Okay, what's <strong>this</strong> zany Wonder Flower going to do?"</em>), but who could deny being surprised and fairly delighted?</p>
<p>Looking further afield, I wonder (heh) if <a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/games/ps5/palworld">Palworld</a>'s success is partly attributable not to its 'Pokémon-with-guns' flavour — as if dropping a cache of firearms into Pokémon was the only way to appeal to adults — but its ambition to take the formula in a different direction. Looking like a proper next-(current-)gen game doesn't hurt, but at least Pocketpair is trying something, risking <em>something</em>.</p>
<figure data-uuid="1e2ce8caa2e05"><a title="Palworld" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/1e2ce8caa2e05/palworld.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Pocketpair</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>Likewise, with <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/cassette_beasts">Cassette Beasts</a>, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/temtem">Temtem</a>, and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/guides/best-pokemon-likes-on-nintendo-switch-games-to-play-after-youve-finished-pokemon">many other excellent monster catchers</a>, indie devs have picked up the <strong><a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/news/2023/06/chicory-team-is-making-a-turn-based-rpg-called-beastieball">Beastieball</a></strong> and run with it. I remember thinking that the brilliant <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/wii/okami">Okami</a> was a death knell for traditional Zelda in 2006. I've likened it in the past to outside devs finally mastering the grammar Nintendo established with <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/n64/legend_of_zelda_ocarina_of_time">Ocarina</a>. It took a decade, but Nintendo did finally respond - they <em>did</em> reinvent chocolate with BOTW. (Yes, I know a Toblerone and a video game are very different things; please let me have this laboured metaphor.)</p>
<p>It's worth acknowledging that Game Freak does try new things, too, even if the pace of progress is glacial. As Alana said, ZA's battle mechanics are the best thing about it, and while the many and various Pokémon spin-off games can feel like free-to-play potshots, or half-baked ideas not intriguing enough to sustain a whole game, TPC does experiment with Pokémon. <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/pokemon-pokopia">Pokopia</a> looks fun! If only the mainline series could inspire such excitement.</p>
<p>What does the future of Pokémon look like, then? Well, the leaks are out there if you're curious. But it feels to me that lapsed Trainers and uberfans alike are starting to align in their 'it is what it is' resignation. 'Phoned-in' isn't fair to the developers who work so hard on these games, but from the outside looking in, they deserve more time and resources.</p>
<p>That the games look like they'd run fine on a PS3 isn't the point; Pokémon conquered the world from a Game Boy in 1996. The real issue is that the series itself feels like a fund-sucking machine fuelled by 'that'll do' energy more than an endeavour to surprise and delight. It could — and really <em>should</em> — be so much more.</p>

<figure data-uuid="aa76bbfb98cab"><a title="Pokémon" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/aa76bbfb98cab/pokemon.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Gemma Smith / Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-articles:192371,188830,192851 @ 1761768016 --></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/features/talking-point-when-did-good-enough-become-good-enough-for-pokemon]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This magnetic controller brings Game Boy-style controls to your smartphone]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/809274/abxylute-m4-snap-on-mobile-wireless-smartphone-controller-magnetic-magsafe</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/this-magnetic-controller-brings-game-boy-style-controls-to-your-smartphone.1338607/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="__next"><p><a href="#content"><span>Skip to main content</span></a></p><nav aria-label="Sticky Nav"></nav><div><main id="content"><div><article><div><div><p>﻿The M4 Snap-On mobile controller is much smaller than clamp-on gamepads and easier to slip into a pocket.</p></div><div><p>﻿The M4 Snap-On mobile controller is much smaller than clamp-on gamepads and easier to slip into a pocket.</p><div><p><span><span>by</span> <!-- --> <span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"></span></span></p><p><span><time datetime="2025-10-29T18:37:08+00:00">Oct 29, 2025, 6:37 PM UTC</time></span></p></div></div></div><div><div><div><p><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span id="follow-author-standard_article_details-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTYw"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span></span><span>Andrew Liszewski</span></span></span></p> <p><span>is a senior reporter who’s been covering and reviewing the latest gadgets and tech since 2006, but has loved all things electronic since he was a kid.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><div><p>Abxylute, a company known for its <a href="https://www.theverge.com/report/763957/abxylute-will-actually-sell-intel-and-tencents-gigantic-glasses-free-3d-handheld">Android-based handhelds</a>, has announced a new compact mobile controller for smartphones. Unlike controllers from companies like <a href="https://www.theverge.com/games/661382/the-new-backbone-pro-could-be-the-one-controller-for-all-your-gaming">Backbone</a> and <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/25/24279435/8bitdo-ultimate-mobile-gaming-controller-android-hall-effect">8BitDo</a> that use an expanding mechanism to clamp onto phones, <a href="https://abxylute.com/products/abxylute-snap-on-mobile-gamepad">Abxylute’s smaller and lighter M4 Snap-On controller</a> uses a Q-shaped mount to magnetically attach to mobile devices that are compatible with Apple’s MagSafe or the Qi2 standard, which <a href="https://www.theverge.com/analysis/762711/pixel-10-qi2-magnets-pixelsense">now includes Google’s Pixel 10 series</a>.</p></div><p>Like clamp-on controllers, Abxylute’s new game pad is designed to be used with phones in a horizontal orientation, but it positions the controls beneath the screen, instead of splitting them up on either side. Those controls include a D-pad, ABXY action buttons, a pair of shoulder buttons, two tiny joysticks, and additional navigation buttons including quick access to a home screen.</p><p>Abxylute says the controller’s rechargeable battery will be good for up to 13 hours of use, and that magnetic mount can be removed entirely if you want to use the M4 as a standalone wireless controller with other devices. Exactly which devices and consoles the M4 will be compatible with aren’t known yet, but more details will be revealed when the company launches a <a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/1932181238/m4-snap-on-magnetic-phone-controller-for-anytime-pocket-play">Kickstarter crowdfunding campaign</a> in early November. Pricing for the earliest backers is expected to be as low as $39, <a href="https://www.notebookcheck.net/Abxylute-s-Snap-on-Controller-to-launch-on-Kickstarter-for-39-and-be-available-in-orange.1148691.0.html">according to <em>Notebookcheck</em></a>, but <em>The Verge</em> has reached out to Abxylute to confirm what pricing will be for those who’d rather wait until general availability, and will update this story accordingly.</p><div><p><span><strong>Follow topics and authors</strong> from this story to see more like this in your personalized homepage feed and to receive email updates.</span></p><ul><li id="follow-author-article_footer-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTYw"><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span><span>Andrew Liszewski</span></span></span></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li></ul></div></div></div><div><form><div><h2>The Verge Daily</h2><p><span>A free daily digest of the news that matters most.</span></p></div></form></div></div></article></div></main></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/news/809274/abxylute-m4-snap-on-mobile-wireless-smartphone-controller-magnetic-magsafe]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Microsoft Outage Temporarily Derails Outer Worlds 2 Launch]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/azure-outage-xbox-game-pass-outer-worlds-2-microsoft-2000639920</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/microsoft-outage-temporarily-derails-outer-worlds-2-launch.1338601/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><a href="https://kotaku.com/outer-worlds-2-review-rpg-xbox-ps5-2000638368"><em>The Outer Worlds 2</em></a> is out today and finally available to play for anyone who didn’t pay for the early access edition. That includes tons of <a href="https://kotaku.com/xbox-game-pass-october-november-2025-powerwash-sim-2-2000638198">Game Pass subscribers</a> across Xbox Series X/S and PC. There’s just one problem: A sudden Microsoft Azure outage is causing issues as another slice of the internet faces unexpected downtime.</p> <p>“Starting at approximately 16:00 UTC, we began experiencing Azure Front Door issues resulting in a loss of availability of some services,” the company <a href="https://azure.status.microsoft/en-us/status">announced on Wednesday</a>. “In addition, customers may experience issues accessing the Azure Portal.” Microsoft is currently blaming a “configuration change error” for the downtime.</p>

 <p>Customers impacted include Xbox and its first-party game studios, who rely on Azure systems to distribute their games digitally across console and PC.</p> <p>“Due to an ongoing Azure service outage, <em>The Outer Worlds 2</em> may be temporarily unavailable to purchase or install on Xbox Series X|S, the Xbox app on PC, and with Xbox Game Pass Ultimate or PC Game Pass,” developer Obsidian Entertainment <a href="https://x.com/OESupport/status/1983582678306975855">wrote on X</a>. “We’re working with Microsoft to resolve the issue and will update players when we have more information.”</p>

 <p>“The pre-installed game just vanished from my Xbox App today,” replied one fan. “How’s that even possible?” Another user on Steam wrote, “I can’t launch my copy on Game Pass. So it’s not working even if you have it installed. Just says something about not being able to sign you in.” Ahhh, the power of the cloud!</p> <p>This hiccup comes <a href="https://kotaku.com/robox-fortnite-outage-amazon-aws-explained-single-bug-god-of-war-xbox-forza-2000639249">a week after the major AWS outage</a> that briefly brought down major games like <em>Fortnite</em> and<em> Roblox</em>. It seems bad that just three companies are responsible for the modern infrastructure of the internet. Ah, well, nevertheless.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/azure-outage-xbox-game-pass-outer-worlds-2-microsoft-2000639920]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[AI Can’t Create Next Grand Theft Auto, Take-Two CEO Says]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/ai-cant-create-next-grand-theft-auto-take-two-ceo-says/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ai-can%E2%80%99t-create-next-grand-theft-auto-take-two-ceo-says.1338598/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Grand Theft Auto 6 hasn’t been released yet, but people are already asking about the franchise’s future. Specifically, how will AI change the development of Grand Theft Auto 7 and beyond?</p>



<p>During an interview this week in New York City, Take-Two Interactive CEO Strauss Zelnick was asked about AI and its place in game development. While he’s not fully against the idea of AI, Zelnick remains skeptical about just how much it can and will help game development and general production. That includes making sure that what his company builds remains with the company. </p>



<p><strong>“We have to protect our intellectual property, but more than that, we have to be mindful of others,” </strong>Strauss <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2025/10/28/can-ai-create-next-grand-theft-auto-take-two-interactive-ceo-says-no.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">told CNBC</a>. <strong>“If you create intellectual property with AI, it’s not protectable.”</strong></p>



<p>When talking specifically about Grand Theft Auto, Zelnick said even if there were no constraints on how AI can be used, it wouldn’t be able to produce what the team at Rockstar has been able to do.</p>



<p><strong>“Let’s say there were no constraints [on AI],”</strong> he said. <strong>“Could we push a button tomorrow and create an equivalent to the Grand Theft Auto marketing plan? The answer is no. </strong></p>



<p><strong>“A, you can’t do that yet, and B, I am of the view that you wouldn’t end up with anything very good. You end up with something pretty derivative.”</strong></p>



<p>As far as why, Zelnick said that AI is “backward looking”. AI productions, he said, can “feel new” because of the predictive models, and though there are things the data it’s built on can solve for, there are still areas that it simply can’t.</p>



<p><strong>“Anything that involves backward-looking data compute, it’s really good for that and that applies to lots of things,” </strong>Zelnick said. <strong>“What we do at Take-Two, anything that isn’t attached to that, it’s going to be really, really bad at.”</strong></p>



<p>Grand Theft Auto 6 is currently scheduled to launch on May 26, 2026, for Xbox Series X|S and PlayStation 5. </p>



<p>What do you think about AI being used to build games like Grand Theft Auto? Leave your thoughts down in the comments, and join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ea-employees-mock-company-mandate-to-use-ai/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">EA employees mocking the company’s mandate</a>&nbsp;to use AI tools for development and creative works. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/ai-cant-create-next-grand-theft-auto-take-two-ceo-says/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shujinkou Has Been Updated On Switch, Here Are The Patch Notes]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/10/shujinkou-has-been-updated-on-switch-here-are-the-patch-notes</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/shujinkou-has-been-updated-on-switch-here-are-the-patch-notes.1338571/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Even better visuals? Oof, yes please</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure data-uuid="9b4e55ffb85fd"><a title="Shujinkou" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/9b4e55ffb85fd/shujinkou.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Rice Games</em></figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/shujinkou">Shujinkou</a>, the DRPG that also offers up some excellent Japanese language-learning tools, has been <a href="https://ricegames.net/2025/10/30/shujinkou-nintendo-switch-1-0-2-patch-notes/">updated to version 1.0.2</a> on Switch.</p>
<p>The biggest improvement here is in the graphics. A new Visual Fidelity option has been added to the menu to enable the game to run at an even crisper resolution on Switch and Switch 2. Developer Rice Games has stated that this may result in some unsavoury frame drops on the original Switch, but those on Switch 2 can expect the same performance.</p>
<p>We've also got a whole bunch of bug fixes based on player feedback, so without further ado, let's get into it...</p><div><figure data-videoid="C1rrCdi_XjA" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><div><iframe title="YouTube Video" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed3be067iwnjyp&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>837k</span></a></p>
</div></figure></div>
<hr>
<h2>New Features</h2>
<ul>
<li>There is now a new “<strong><em>Visual Fidelity</em></strong>” setting in the Options Menu that improves visual graphics at the cost of performance on the Nintendo Switch. The performance is largely unaffected on stronger devices, and we strongly recommend enabling this setting on <em>Nintendo Switch 2</em>.</li>
<li>This is the best that we can do regarding improving graphic quality without a Nintendo Switch 2 development kit.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Bug Fixes</h2>
<ul>
<li>Fix issue where Kaifuku Ball could not be used outside of battle.</li>
<li>Fix a game softlock/freeze when approaching a certain boss battle from a certain position and angle in the final area of Labyrinth 2.</li>
<li>Fix an issue with button input sometimes not working smoothly when selecting party members for a special battle.</li>
<li>Fix an issue with button input in the Tsuri (fishing) minigame occasionally causing the game to stall after a completed reel.</li>
<li>Fix an issue with camera clipping in the Omikuji system.</li>
<li>Fixed a few typos and accidental usage of kanji in certain furigana-only fields.</li>
<li>Fix a rare bug where a character’s Onsen outfit could stay in place even in dialogue taking place outside of the Onsen.</li>
<li>Fix rare case of game freezing (harmless, but for too long) when saving the game.</li>
<li>Fix issue with being unable to interact with Kunihiko in Fuu Underground when playing Okkake no Osakenori.</li>
<li>Fix harmless error that may appear when a Yajuu joins a normal battle.</li>
<li>Fix input error that could take place when spamming inputs in the Fuu Underground.</li>
<li>Fix residual errors that may pop up when finishing Okkake no Osakenori.</li>
<li>Fix the equipment type of two late game equipment pieces.</li>
<li>Fix very small navigation issue with buttons and controllers for a couple dozen spots.</li>
<li>Fix typos and other issues found in a few dialogue scenes.</li>
<li>Fix a progression bug that only occurs for some players in Labyrinth 10.</li>
<li>Fix an equipment duplication error.</li>
<li>Fixed a few instances of graphical clipping in certain labyrinths.</li>
<li>Players can no longer access the Enemy View menu while the Kanakae UI is active.</li>
<li>Remove “No Extra Notes” text from Okkake no Osakenori to prevent text overflow.</li>
<li>Reduce special effects intensity of certain battles to improve overall performance.</li>
<li>Unity vulnerability fix has been implemented.</li>
<li><strong>Nintendo Switch-only Bug Fix</strong>: When pulling from the Omikuji, the camera will clip with a 3D model.</li>
<li><strong>Nintendo Switch-only Bug Fix</strong>: Some graphical clipping of some assets in the second area of Labyrinth 5.</li>
<li><strong>Nintendo Switch-only Bug Fix</strong>: Fishing minigame (Tsuri) can sometimes soft-lock due to button input navigation issues.</li>
<li><strong>Nintendo Switch-only Bug Fix</strong>: Game crashing in Labyrinth 7 due to memory management issues.</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<p>Shujinkou is available now via the Switch eShop for <strong>£26.99 / $29.99</strong>. Interestingly, Rice Games has confirmed that one player has already surpassed 200 hours of in-game time, which is quite the feat after under a month.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-articles:188940 @ 1761768378 -->
<p><em>Are you currently playing Shujinkou, or are you interested in picking it up? Let us know with a comment in the usual place.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://ricegames.net/2025/10/30/shujinkou-nintendo-switch-1-0-2-patch-notes/" rel="noopener" href="https://ricegames.net/2025/10/30/shujinkou-nintendo-switch-1-0-2-patch-notes/">ricegames.net</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-info/6b402343098e02c5ea2e57d784892b2b @ 1761770927 --></div></article><div><p>Nintendo Life’s resident horror fanatic, when he’s not knee-deep in Resident Evil and Silent Hill lore, Ollie likes to dive into a good horror book while nursing a lovely cup of tea. He also enjoys long walks and listens to everything from TOOL to Chuck Berry.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Olliemar28"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/ollie-nl.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Olliemar28');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/10/shujinkou-has-been-updated-on-switch-here-are-the-patch-notes]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Microsoft Azure Outage Is Affecting Xbox Game Downloads, Minecraft and More]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/microsoft-azure-outage-is-affecting-xbox-game-downloads-minecraft-and-more/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/microsoft-azure-outage-is-affecting-xbox-game-downloads-minecraft-and-more.1338568/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>Microsoft's Azure cloud service is experiencing a massive outage affecting multiple services, including Xbox game downloads and Minecraft.</p>



<p>Microsoft confirmed the cause in an <a data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-style-link dracula-processed" href="https://azure.status.microsoft/en-us/status">Azure status update</a>, stating the widespread connectivity issues began around 16:00 UTC. The company attributed the trigger event to <em data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed">"an inadvertent configuration change" </em>in the Azure Front Door (AFD) service.</p>



<p>Several concurrent actions are being taken to solve the issue, but the Azure outage is still ongoing at the time of writing, and Xbox game publishers have started warning users about potential problems. On <a data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-style-link dracula-processed" href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:h4x5o4kfgwgqm4enepisxtid/post/3m4dx2pwsik2j?ref_src=embed">Bluesky</a>, Obsidian Entertainment confirmed that due to the continuing outage, The Outer Worlds 2 may be temporarily unavailable for purchase or installation on Xbox consoles and PC. The publisher added that the issue is affecting all Xbox games, including online games such as Minecraft, whose down status is confirmed by <a data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-style-link dracula-processed" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Minecraft/comments/1ojbiqf/how_long_will_minecraft_be_down/">multiple online reports</a> as well as by <a data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" href="https://downdetector.com/status/minecraft/">Down Detector.</a> </p>



<p>Unfortunately, no estimation of when the services will return online has been provided. We will update this post once more information is available and when the outage has been resolved.</p>



<p>Today's Microsoft Azure cloud service outage follows last week's <a href="https://wccftech.com/aws-outage-snaps-chatgpt-fortnite-down/">massive AWS outage</a>, which took down almost half the internet, including PSN, Fortnite, and Roblox. The issues that led to the outage were resolved in a matter of hours, and <a href="https://wccftech.com/psn-fortnite-roblox-gaming-services-starting-to-recover-aws-outage/">all affected services were promptly brought back online</a>.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> or <a href="https://google.com/preferences/source?q=wccftech.com">add us as a preferred source</a>, to get our news coverage and reviews in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/microsoft-azure-outage-is-affecting-xbox-game-downloads-minecraft-and-more/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Outer Worlds 2’s satire has a Microsoft-shaped problem]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/entertainment/809022/the-outer-worlds-2-corporate-satire-interview-xbox</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-outer-worlds-2%E2%80%99s-satire-has-a-microsoft-shaped-problem.1338565/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Almost immediately in <em>The Outer Worlds 2</em>, the player receives news of a corporate shake-up: Auntie Cleo and Spacer’s Choice, two of the in-game retail brands, have merged to form Auntie’s Choice. Less a chain of stores and more a feudal power, Auntie’s Choice manages its employees — serfs, really — with the cruelty of the balance sheet, its military business far more important than the faux-cheery public-facing purveyor of somewhat-useful crap customers can’t get from anyone else.</p><p>The fictional business news parallels real-world business news. Right before developer Obsidian Entertainment began work on <em>The Outer Worlds 2</em> in 2019, the studio was acquired as part of Microsoft’s <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/11/10/18082922/microsoft-xbox-inxile-obsidian-entertainment-studio-acquisition">game developer shopping spree</a>. Less than a decade later, Microsoft’s gaming division doesn’t seem to be flourishing despite its incredibly deep bench of talent; in 2025, the company’s games efforts have largely been characterized by <a href="https://www.theverge.com/tech/790658/microsoft-xbox-game-pass-console-price-hikes-notepad">price hikes</a>, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/1/25/24049050/microsoft-activision-blizzard-layoffs">layoffs</a>, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/805280/microsoft-xbox-gaming-profit-targets-layoffs">lopsided priorities</a>, and an all-consuming interest from the company’s top brass in <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/799768/microsoft-windows-ai-copilot-voice-vision-launch">becoming an AI company</a>.</p><p>Yet Obsidian is still here, and it has something to say about this stuff. At least, its new role-playing game, which casts players as an agent in a cheerily fascist organization that becomes embroiled in a conflict between a megacorporation and a totalitarian government, might have a few things to say about it. The studio itself? It’s a little less clear.</p><p><em>The Outer Worlds 2</em> creative director Leonard Boyarsky and game director Brandon Adler are not in the business of making games that respond to any specific moment — games take so long to make, after all, and fun is their fixation. They do acknowledge that their game’s scenario can feel quite topical. “Tim [Cain, co-creator of the<em> Outer Worlds </em>franchise] and I have always made games that are about what happens when people get power,” Boyarsky told me in a Zoom interview alongside Adler. “We’re expanding on that continually.”</p><p>Boyarsky and Cain (who announced his “<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cdHqBi1IPOY">semi-retirement</a>” in 2023 but still does contract work for Obsidian) are co-creators of the <em>Fallout</em> franchise and have deep roots in the computer RPG scene, having worked on a string of cult classics like <em>Vampire: The Masquerade – Bloodlines</em> and the little-played but deeply beloved <em>Arcanum: Of Steamworks and Magick Obscura</em>. Their influence is everywhere, establishing modern RPG trends where factional conflicts and institutional mistrust are leveraged to generate interesting problems for players to solve.</p><p>The <em>Outer Worlds</em> games are best understood as another run at <em>Fallout</em>. Both franchises use a divergence in American history to spin out bizarre far futures defined by lopsided institutions. <em>Fallout</em> imagines a nuclear golden age post-World War II, where the science fiction of the ’50s became science fact, before a 21st-century thermonuclear war turns the world into <em>Mad Max</em>-style wasteland in which players eke out a mean, odd existence. In <em>The Outer Worlds</em>’ fictional history, President William McKinley is never assassinated, an antitrust movement never materializes, and the robber barons of the early 20th century run rampant for hundreds of years. Hence the heavy layer of corporate satire, which Obsidian expands in <em>Outer Worlds 2 </em>to become something darker.</p><p>In the first 15 minutes of the game, players are hit with:</p><div><ul><li><span>a glib conversation with a mascot for one of those retail companies owned by a defense contractor;</span></li><li><span>a TV show clip that suggests a level of <em>Starship Troopers</em>-esque propaganda;</span></li><li><span>an overt <em>Starship Troopers</em>-esque propaganda ad encouraging citizens to rat on each other.</span></li></ul></div><p>There’s a meaner undercurrent to the sequel’s iteration on <em>The Outer Worlds</em>’ corporate humor, one that tugs at a thread linking corporate overreach to fascism’s rise. At least, I think there is. Maybe Obsidian thinks so too?</p><p>“We don’t talk about the fascist aspect of it, but we all end up in situations where we don’t have control. Even people in power, whether it’s the real world or these games, I think people in power are as much victims of the system as anybody else,” Boyarsky said. “They think they’re in control of these things, but no one person can actually wield as much power as people want. Because you’re grown up in the system, you react based on how you were raised in the system, your beliefs that have come up through being told what’s right and wrong by your parents or society in general. So we all find ourselves in situations where it’s just like:<em> I have no idea how I got here. I guess I gotta make the best of it</em>.”</p><p>I tell Boyarsky that sounds like a very video game-y view of the world, and ask why he thinks games are an ideal medium to tackle these quandaries. He tells me that, at least when it comes to <em>The Outer Worlds</em>, the themes came from a convergence of his and Cain’s interests. Cain, he says, loved the idea of a <em>Futurama</em>-inspired setting, leaning into the silliness. Boyarsky says he wants this game to keep that, but push toward something more difficult and less goofy.</p><p>“My thing was always — and this is something that we really continue to dig into — we all tell ourselves stories,” Boyarsky said. “That’s how we cope with the world, with reality. That’s built by how you’re raised and what people tell you when you’re younger. But when people co-opt that story, they can control you very easily.”</p><p>These are all potent ideas, but they’re also thick with irony thanks to events largely out of Obsidian’s control. Some of them involve geopolitical issues well outside the games industry. But others lie closer to home for developers that are now owned by Microsoft.</p><p>“All I can say is that the irony was not lost on us when we were in the middle of making the first game. Railing against corporate power and all this stuff — and we were bought by Microsoft!” Boyarsky says. “But we’ve only had support from them. They liked what we were doing with the first <em>Outer Worlds</em>, and they support us making this game. We’ve had absolutely no pushback or messages from on high telling us <em>don’t do this</em>, or <em>make sure you do this</em>.”</p><p>While it may be true that Microsoft has not interfered with Obsidian’s creative processes on <em>The Outer Worlds 2</em>, the company certainly had preferences on how the leads at the studio discussed it. The game, with Boyarsky’s interests in exploring the plight of what happens to those who aren’t in power when people with base interests come into power, seemed particularly relevant to <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/785733/microsoft-block-israeli-military-cloud-ai-services-palestine-protests">Microsoft’s business entanglements with the Israeli Ministry of Defense</a>.</p><p>Before we get further, a Microsoft rep interrupts to note that the company’s latest statements on the matter <a href="https://blogs.microsoft.com/on-the-issues/2025/09/25/update-on-ongoing-microsoft-review/">can be found online</a>, and that they wanted to keep the conversation with Obsidian “focused on the game.”</p><p>So let’s focus on the game: Early on you can accept a quest that, depending on your choices, might send you to retrieve something from the Ministry of Accuracy. Like the name suggests, it’s a propaganda outfit. Read through the terminals found there and you’ll see how it works: Reports from all over the region are funneled through the Ministry, where workers “sanitize” them to make sure they align with the messaging of the space colony’s ruling power, The Protectorate. Art imitating life for Obsidian, once again. Or maybe it’s the other way around.</p><p><sub>The Outer Worlds 2 <em>is out now on the PS5, Xbox, and PC.</em></sub></p><div><p><span><strong>Follow topics and authors</strong> from this story to see more like this in your personalized homepage feed and to receive email updates.</span></p><ul><li id="follow-author-article_footer-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6Mzc2NDc="><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span><span>Joshua Rivera</span></span></span></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li></ul></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/entertainment/809022/the-outer-worlds-2-corporate-satire-interview-xbox]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[30 Years Ago, Homer Entered The Third Dimension]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/homer-cubed-3d-treehouse-horror-fox-30-years-ago-1995-2000639909</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/30-years-ago-homer-entered-the-third-dimension.1338559/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>On October 29, 1995, just over 12 million viewers tuned into the newest episode of Fox’s hit animated (and very 2D) comedy, <em>The Simpsons</em>, and were shocked to see Homer become 3D. Pulling this off was incredibly challenging, but the end result is a wonderful time capsule of early computer animation.</p> <p><em>The Simpsons Treehouse of Horror VI</em> is one of the best installments of the show’s annual Halloween special. In fact, <a href="https://kotaku.com/the-13-best-simpsons-treehouse-of-horror-segments-1850470445">two parts of the episode made our top 13 best <em>Treehouse of Horror</em> segments list</a>. One of those two segments is perhaps the most ambitious and wildest thing <a href="https://kotaku.com/the-simpsons-best-episodes-characters-top-to-watch-list-1850309544"><em>The Simpsons</em></a> has ever done. In the segment <em>Homer</em>³<em> (Homer Cubed),</em> we see the famous cartoon father and husband leave his 2D dimension via a portal behind a bookcase and enter a 3D computer-generated landscape. What follows is about four minutes of a 3D, computer-generated Homer exploring an odd world filled with simple objects, random pools of water, and even the library from the game <em>Myst</em>.</p>

  <p>At one point while exploring this bizarre 3D world, Homer says, “Man, this place looks expensive. I feel like I’m wasting a fortune just standing here.” And he wasn’t joking. As explained in the fantastic oral history of this segment, <a href="https://ew.com/tv/2018/10/19/the-simpsons-homer-cubed-treehouse-of-horror-vi/">written up by <em>Entertainment Weekly</em> in 2018</a>, it was estimated that the four minutes of 3D animation seen in <em>Treehouse of Horror VI</em> cost “hundreds of thousands of dollars.” However, Fox only paid <span>Pacific Data Images–the CG studio behind the animation–a measly $6,000 for the work.&nbsp;</span>Tim Johnson, the head of PDI’s character animation group, broke the news to the company’s founder, Carl Rosendahl.</p>

 <p>“Here’s the good news: <em>The Simpsons</em> has this amazing script, and we can participate,” said Johnson. “Carl just got up out of his chair and paced the room—he was so excited. I said, ‘Well, here’s the <em>bad</em> news: They don’t have any money to pay for it.’ So Carl sat back down and ran the numbers.”</p>

 <p>Ultimately, the company agreed to do the animation because it was seen as a big opportunity for the company. And it did pay off, in the end. Not long after this episode aired, Dreamworks bought up a big chunk of PDI, and Johnson would end up co-directing <em>Antz</em>. The company even helped on <em>Shrek</em>. PDI was still making CG shorts for Dreamworks up until it shut down in 2015.</p> <p>The end result was something that hadn’t really been seen on TV before, and it blew people’s minds. Today, this kind of thing could be created by a single person with one computer in a few days or hours. But back in October 1995, a month before <em>Toy Story</em> hit theaters, this kind of 3D animation was incredibly rare. And the only reason it happened was because PDI decided to do it basically for free. The end result is something very special. 30 years later, this segment is still great, even if the then-impressive tech has aged a lot since it first aired in the ’90s. Sure, it’s not the scariest or funniest segment in <em>The Simpsons’</em> long history, but it’s one of its most memorable, even three decades later. (<a href="https://ew.com/tv/2018/10/19/the-simpsons-homer-cubed-treehouse-of-horror-vi/">Oh, and you should totally read the full <em>EW</em> history of this segment if you are a Simpsons nerd. So much good stuff in there!</a>)</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/homer-cubed-3d-treehouse-horror-fox-30-years-ago-1995-2000639909]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[DHS will continue using game and pop culture iconography in messaging]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/dhs-will-continue-using-game-and-pop-culture-iconography-in-messaging</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dhs-will-continue-using-game-and-pop-culture-iconography-in-messaging.1338553/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="captioned-content" data-testid="featured-image"><p><span>Screenshot via Halo Studios/Microsoft. Logo via DHS.</span></p></div><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The United States Department of Homeland Security (DHS) is </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://bsky.app/profile/alyssamerc.bsky.social/post/3m4dt3spux22d">promising</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> to continue its campaign of posting memes and recruiting material based on pop-culture imagery, including those from the world of video games. This comes days after it and the White House promoted images on social media depicting </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://kotaku.com/donald-trump-halo-gamestop-console-wars-meme-ai-images-2000639237">President Trump as player character Master Chief</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, and recruitment ads </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://kotaku.com/department-homeland-security-halo-ice-pokemon-video-dhs-2000639308">encouraging would-be ICE agents to "Destroy the flood"</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> [sic] (a reference to the Flood, the zombie-like antagonists of the Halo series).</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">This promise suggests that more game developers and industry professionals may see the US government use the games they work on for recruitment purposes, or to push </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.npr.org/2024/03/08/1237103158/immigrants-are-less-likely-to-commit-crimes-than-us-born-americans-studies-find">unproven claims</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> of high crime rates driven by undocumented immigrants. Game File spoke with a number of former Halo franchise developers who </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamefile.news/p/halo-ice-developers-react?r=5i0nln">condemned the posts</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, with former series Jaime Griesemer calling the DHS ad "ought to offend every Halo fan, regardless of political orientation."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Word of DHS' plans comes from a comment sent to </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://bsky.app/profile/alyssamerc.bsky.social/post/3m4dt3spux22d">independent journalist Alyssa Mercante</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, who sought comment from the agency over its impromptu ad campaign. "We will reach people where they are with content they can relate to and understand, whether that be Halo, Pokémon, Lord of the Rings, or any other medium," an agency spokesperson stated, adding that it was "laser focused" on pushing messaging spotlighting the aforementioned unproven claims about immigrant crime rates.</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/amazon-is-ending-active-development-on-new-world" target="_self" data-discover="true">Amazon is ending active development on New World</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">According to Mercante and other journalists, Microsoft declined to comment on the Halo-themed posts.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="The Trump administration continues to embrace game-adjacent 'meme culture'">The Trump administration continues to embrace game-adjacent 'meme culture'</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Mercante had previously received comment from the White House celebrating the President's overseeing of the end of "the console wars," which was proclaimed by the </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://x.com/gamestop/status/1982213786221109263">GameStop X account</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> on Friday after Microsoft announced </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Halo: Campaign Evolved</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> would debut on the PlayStation 5 as well as Xbox Series X|S. GameStop posted a number of celebratory manipulated images of President Trump with the Master Chief in the hours afterward.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The DHS previously invoked the spirit of video games in </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.polygon.com/pokemon-ice-dhs-nintendo/">a number of social media messages in September 2025</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> drawing on imagery and slogans from the Pokémon franchise. The Pokémon Company (which is partially owned by Nintendo), distanced itself from these posts, saying that "it was not involved in the creation or distribution of this content, and permission was not granted for the use of our intellectual property."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">These posts followed</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.npr.org/2025/08/18/nx-s1-5482921/memes-white-house-dhs-social-media-trump">&nbsp;a number of promotional images earlier in 2025</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> promoting President Trump's agenda through the lens of </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.rollingstone.com/politics/politics-news/trump-star-wars-may-fourth-memes-1235331075/">Disney's Star Wars series</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, AI-generated images inspired by Studio Ghibli. Neither company issued any statement following these posts, though a number of </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.npr.org/2025/08/28/nx-s1-5506215/politicians-using-music-memes-issues">musicians</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> have consistently pushed back against their work being used by the Administration.</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/cwa-president-implores-u-s-regulators-to-scrutinise-ea-buyout-to-address-national-security-and-labor-concerns" target="_self" data-discover="true">CWA president implores U.S. regulators to scrutinize EA buyout to address national security and labor concerns</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Given the DHS' pattern of jumping from pop culture reference to pop culture reference, other developers may find their work used to promote its policies in the next few years.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Game Developer has reached out to Microsoft for comment on this story and will provide an update when the company responds.</span></span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Senior Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Bryant Francis is a writer, journalist, and narrative designer based in Boston, MA. He currently writes for Game Developer, a leading B2B publication for the video game industry. His credits include Proxy Studios' upcoming 4X strategy game Zephon and Amplitude Studio's 2017 game Endless Space 2.</span></p></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/dhs-will-continue-using-game-and-pop-culture-iconography-in-messaging]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Round Up: The Reviews Are In For Dragon Quest I & II HD-2D Remake]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/10/round-up-the-reviews-are-in-for-dragon-quest-i-and-ii-hd-2d-remake</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/round-up-the-reviews-are-in-for-dragon-quest-i-ii-hd-2d-remake.1338535/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
<figure data-uuid="1c2335ec82264"><a title="Dragon Quest II HD-2D Remake" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/1c2335ec82264/dragon-quest-ii-hd-2d-remake.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Square Enix</em></figcaption></figure><p>Tomorrow, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/dragon-quest-i-and-ii-hd-2d-remake">Dragon Quest I &amp; II HD-2D Remake</a> arrives on Switch 1 and Switch 2 — a package deal of remakes of the first two Dragon Quest (or Dragon Warrior) games from the NES era, and the final two games in the Erdrick Trilogy.</p>
<p>Following on from 2024's Dragon Quest III HD-2D Remake, expectations were high, particularly with the promise of new content, new story elements, and even a new playable character in II's case. And now that reviews are out there, guess what? Square Enix and Artdink have nailed it.</p><div><figure data-videoid="GReZx3uoZNA" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/GReZx3uoZNA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><div><iframe title="YouTube Video" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/GReZx3uoZNA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/GReZx3uoZNA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed640b4etrjmiv&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>837k</span></a></p>
</div></figure></div>
<p><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/nintendo-switch-2/dragon-quest-i-and-ii-hd-2d-remake">Our own 9/10 review</a> praises the whole package, singling out Dragon Quest II in particular: "The new work done on the characterisation really elevates the party, and the additional content doubles the original playtime and makes the experience much richer." But both games are absolutely worth playing, especially if you grabbed III last year.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-articles:192419 @ 1761768383 -->
<p>But what about other outlets? Well, let's start with our sister site <a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/">Push Squar</a>e, who scored the HD-2D Remake <a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/reviews/ps5/dragon-quest-i-and-ii-hd-2d-remake">an 8/10</a>, acknowledging the glow-up both games have received, but still noting their NES origins:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"Its offerings are traditional perhaps to a fault, and while modern conveniences have smoothed away some of its rougher edges, Dragon Quest I &amp; II HD-2D Remake does require a certain old-school mindset to be properly appreciated."</p>
</blockquote>
<p><a href="https://www.consolecreatures.com/">Console Creatures</a>' review is full of praise for the new content and modern adjustments, also giving the package an <a href="https://www.consolecreatures.com/dragon-quest-1-2-hd-2d-remake-review/">8/10</a>, noting some of those classic difficulty spikes and — once again — the NES caveats.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"You might ask why the Erdrick trilogy is the focus of its series over the last few years, and I can tell you it’s worth sticking through to the end. The trilogy reunites the scions of Erdrick for a new generation, delivering a simple tale with bells and whistles."</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Let's jump up a little, shall we? <a href="https://www.ign.com/">IGN</a> has scored the game a glowing <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/dragon-quest-i-ii-hd-2d-remake-review">9/10</a>, saying that the Remake "beautifully concludes" the trilogy. Again, RNG and difficulty does briefly come up, but this one's full of praise otherwise:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"Both games adhere to old-school turn-based combat that holds up despite being fairly simple, with the first offering a tightly focused solo adventure and the second being more expansive with its party-based structure – not to mention its stronger emphasis on storytelling and character development."</p>
</blockquote>
<p><a href="https://gameinformer.com/">Game Informer</a> is another site awarding the duology a <a href="https://gameinformer.com/review/dragon-quest-i-ii-hd-2d-remake/level-up-and-up">9/10</a> rounding out the review with a more than appropriate summary: "But it's good to know his Dragon Quest legacy is in fine form.<strong>" Yes, indeed.</strong></p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>"This collection is a treat for RPG freaks, but especially fans like me, who get to relish new content, stories, and a complete UI overhaul from two games they've loved since childhood."<br></strong></p>
</blockquote>
<p>Back to the 8/10 trail we have <a href="https://www.rpgfan.com/">RPGFan</a> (well, <a href="https://www.rpgfan.com/review/dragon-quest-i-ii-hd-2d-remake/">80/100</a> in this case), where praise and criticism is similarly dished out. Dragon Quest II is once again singled out here, with Dragon Quest I's frustrations becoming much more apparent in the remake <em>[Note: The author of this article is a former writer at RPGFan]</em>.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"[Dragon Quest II] might take over 40 hours to complete now, but the additional time feels organic and essential. Put simply, <em>Dragon Quest II</em> is the crown jewel of the two games here, and finally worth playing as more than just a history lesson."</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Lastly, on the lower end of the scale is <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/">GameSpot</a>, which scored the games a respectable <a href="http://gamespot.com/reviews/dragon-quest-1-2-hd-remake-review/1900-6418433/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f">7/10</a>. This is one of the few reviews that criticises some of the new narrative additions and padding, recommending last year's III remake over the upcoming one</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"The simple base narrative and lack of other party members makes little room to connect with these mostly forgettable characters with one-note personality traits, and the extra locations and quest objectives (with new boss fights) feels less like an expansion of the world and more like an attempt to pad out the game as much as possible."</p>
</blockquote>
<p>However you shake it, though, it sounds like DQ I &amp; II have been much improved on their NES — or even their Switch — counterparts. At the time of writing, on Switch 2, the game sits at an <a href="https://www.metacritic.com/game/dragon-quest-i-and-ii-hd-2d-remake/critic-reviews/?platform=nintendo-switch-2">85 average on Metacritic</a> (from 19 reviews) while OpenCritic's multi-console approach sits at an <a href="https://opencritic.com/game/19041/dragon-quest-i-ii-hd-2d-remake">average of 83</a> (after 41 reviews).</p>
<p><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/10/the-first-review-for-dragon-quest-i-and-ii-hd-2d-remake-is-in">Famitsu's review</a> from earlier today falls in line with many other critics, and Switch 1 impressions seem more limited at the time. But, basically, if you like Dragon Quest and like traditional RPGs, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/dragon_quest_i_and_ii_hd-2d_remake">Dragon Quest I &amp; II HD-2D Remake</a> is a no-brainer.</p>
<hr>
<p><em>Let us know if you're getting the game on Switch 1 or 2 tomorrow in the comments</em>.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-articles:192800,173714 @ 1761768057 --></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/10/round-up-the-reviews-are-in-for-dragon-quest-i-and-ii-hd-2d-remake]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Game Pass Used to Offer Business Class Experience at Economy Price, Says Analyst; New Segmented Formula Might Be the Right One]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/game-pass-new-segmented-formula-might-be-right-one-says-analyst/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/game-pass-used-to-offer-business-class-experience-at-economy-price-says-analyst-new-segmented-formula-might-be-the-right-one.1338532/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>On October 1, Microsoft shocked Game Pass subscribers by <a href="https://wccftech.com/xbox-game-pass-is-rumored-to-drop-pc-game-pass-get-cheaper-ad-supported-tier/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">announcing a substantial (+50%) price increase for the highest tier</a>, Ultimate, which jumped from $19.99 to $29.99 monthly. This led some users to <a href="https://wccftech.com/xbox-game-pass-subscription-cancel-page-overwhelmed-after-game-pass-price-hike/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">cancel their subscriptions in droves</a>, but did Microsoft really make a strategic mistake? </p>



<p>Veteran games analyst Joost van Dreunen, formerly founder of SuperData Research (acquired by Nielsen Media Research in 2018), offered a more nuanced analysis <a href="https://superjoost.substack.com/p/game-pass-or-fail?i" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">in his latest SuperJoost Playlist newsletter</a>.</p>



<p>To start with, van Dreunen relays a take from a former Xbox employee, who said that it's a case of 'bad optics'. Certainly, such a massive price increase doesn't look good from the point of view of consumers, but the analyst points out that Game Pass had so far offered a model that could be called airline economics in reverse. The analogy refers to the fact that, in air travel, premium passengers subsidize economy fares. On Microsoft's subscription service, though, for a long time, players got a business-class experience while paying economy prices. Indeed, there was a common saying that Game Pass was almost too good to be true for the library of games that it offered and the low barrier to entry.</p>



<p>For several years, Microsoft was trying to boost growth at all costs, but van Dreunen adds that this  created 'an inherently margin-thin model in which heavy users consumed disproportionate resources without proportional revenue.'</p>



<p>The publisher attempted to lure many more users by adding popular games to the subscription service, including last year's Call of Duty: Black Ops 6. That game's launch offered the largest weekly spike in Game Pass subscriptions, but other than that, the trend of new subscribers has gone downward, as shown in this chart based on data from Antenna, an analyst firm (of which van Dreunen is an investor) focused on the subscription economy.</p>



<figure><figcaption><em>New Game Pass subscribers in the United States. Source: Antenna</em></figcaption></figure>



<p>When Microsoft realized it couldn't easily get as many subscribers as it perhaps hoped (and <a href="https://wccftech.com/game-pass-to-reach-100-million-when-activision-games-are-added-says-pachter/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">some analysts believed</a>) even with relatively low pricing, the next step was to restructure the subscription service so that it would become sustainable on its own. This led to the new multi-tiered (Essential, Premium, and Ultimate) approach, which the analyst believes just might be the right formula:</p>



<p><em>The evidence suggests Microsoft isn’t abandoning Game Pass but transforming it. By shifting from a one-size-fits-all subscription to a segmented model that better aligns price with usage, Microsoft may have found the formula that eluded Stadia and others. It is here that Microsoft can lead: if this pivot from growth to profitability succeeds, it will determine both its own service’s future and whether gaming subscriptions can ever truly rival their entertainment counterparts.</em></p>



<p>Yesterday, Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella <a href="https://wccftech.com/microsoft-ceo-largest-gaming-publisher-want-to-be-everywhere-competition-tiktok/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">noted</a> that the acquisition of Activision Blizzard transformed the company into the largest gaming publisher, thus explaining the new multiplatform mandate to be 'everywhere', like with Office. Nadella did not talk about Game Pass, which he once described as Microsoft's attempt to create a Netflix-like experience for games. </p>



<p>Indeed, playing games is considerably different from watching TV shows or movies or even listening to songs. Many gamers focus on one big title at a time, so being able to access a vast game library is not necessarily of interest to them. Time will tell if the new approach will prove truly sustainable.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> or <a href="https://google.com/preferences/source?q=wccftech.com">add us as a preferred source</a>, to get our news coverage and reviews in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/game-pass-new-segmented-formula-might-be-right-one-says-analyst/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dispatch Episode 3 & 4 Impressions - Big Choices]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/dispatch-episode-3-4-impressions-big-choices</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dispatch-episode-3-4-impressions-big-choices.1338529/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Episodes 3 and 4 of <em>Dispatch </em>are a great pairing, both ratcheting up the player choice. Each episode does a good job of layering on some new gameplay elements that perfectly fit the story, too.</p>

<p>Be sure to check out my <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/dispatch-episode-1-2-impressions" rel="nofollow">preview of the first two episodes</a> to learn more about what <em>Dispatch </em>is.&nbsp;</p>

<h2>Episode 3 – Turnover&nbsp;</h2>

<p>This episode begins with Blonde Blazer explaining that a decision has been made to reduce the size of your squad by one. It's part to cut some that are underperforming, but also to show that SDN means business. Someone has to go, and at the end of the day, you’re making the decision.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Robert informs the team, and they are less than thrilled, obviously. Their performance has always been something public, though, as we get to see the "leaderboards" of heroes at SDN with some sort of point system. Z Team is, of course, all clumped at the bottom.</p>

<p>Immediately after, the workday starts, and calls come in that need heroes dispatched. Because their performance is being graded, they're all giving it their all, right?</p>



<p>Well, the chosen&nbsp;tactic by the Z Team is not to do their best but to sabotage their fellow teammates on the job. When you send off some heroes together, one of them is probably going to sabotage the other. These pop up like those emergencies you get to weigh in on in the previous episodes.</p>

<p>Here, you get some choices on how to get them out of that sabotaging situation. If they succeed, they avoid an injury. Either way, the sabotage takes them out of helping on a specific mission, so their stats aren't added to the potential success rate of that mission -- so expect a lot of failure.</p>

<p>I think it would be easy to take this sort of gameplay wrinkle and be frustrated by it. It’s going to make you fail way more missions than you would otherwise, and there’s nothing you can do about it.&nbsp;</p>

<p>But the gameplay marries so well with the story and the characters that I really love the choice. It’s simple but plays out exactly how it was intended, I’m sure, with the day being chaotic, filled with sabotage and failure, and shows the exact problem at the heart of Z Team that Robert has to solve.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Sabotaging drives home the personalities of these still villainous “heroes” who aren’t all that committed to the work they do. It’s a job and nothing more. It's like they got sentenced to some community service, and they just really need to put in some hours, not that they really want to be there.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/dispatch-team-z-heroes.jpg?itok=YB8rLh-e 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/dispatch-team-z-heroes.jpg?itok=0C_kY7ZL 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Some light does start to shine through, showing that Z Team is starting to get what SDN is all about though...</figcaption></figure><p>The episode ends with the choice of which hero you’re going to cut. It’s just between two, and I won’t say who, but the choice is a genuine one.&nbsp;</p>

<p>I can confirm that, at least through the next episode, that character is off the team and not in the episode. I can’t wait to see what future implications that may have, as none of the characters seem much of a “throwaway” and have a decent amount on offer. It's not just that they aren't around either, as some characters aren't exactly happy with your choice.</p>

<p>With how much of the game is bantering between the characters and their weird personalities colliding, this felt like a big choice. Will it hugely affect the plot? Obviously, I don’t know, but I doubt it. But it absolutely affects the interactions in the game, which is where <em>Dispatch </em>shines. &nbsp;</p>

<p>It's a game-changing choice that absolutely alters your experience with the game, which is really all you can ask for.</p>

<h2>Episode 4 – Restructure&nbsp;</h2>

<p>The episode opens with a nice scene with Royd, who is tasked with repairing and rebuilding the Mecha Man suit. It’s a quick reminder of that looming plot above all the dispatching that Robert really wants to be his own hero again and go after Shroud.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Where Episode 3 left us on a huge choice, Episode 4 also opens with a pretty monumental one. Now that there is a vacancy on the team, you get to choose who is going to fill it.</p>



<p>This time it’s not a reformed villain either, but someone who did get into the hero business with good intentions. I won’t spoil the choice, but they are wildly different people to choose from.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The Z Team may not be the nicest to the new member, which isn’t the most shocking thing. While they are all pretty selfish, villain-like people, they do have a sense of camaraderie in their situation. And we saw the team mentality start to shine last episode.</p>

<p>So, an outsider coming in is going to have a rough time.&nbsp;The dispatching experience reflects this again, with a lot of smack talk and making fun of the new member. Sometimes, without them even realizing. And the newest member will have some... issues that will affect how certain missions go.</p>

<p>The gameplay takes a bit of a backseat this episode, though. A lot of the focus is on relationships with people like Blonde Blazer, Invisigal, and you even get to spend time with Phenomaman, the sort of Superman of <em>Dispatch</em>.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Except, this is a very depressed Phenomaman who is in a very sad place. He's a powerful man whose emotions show up just as powerfully, and he's pretty self-absorbed. And he doesn't really understand our small human problems, so he's pretty out of touch. He has some wild comments and funny moments throughout the episode.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The end of Episode 4 has a monumental feeling. It’s a choice that seems like it will have significant effects on the rest of the game. Unfortunately, they’ve asked us not to spoil it, which I agree with, as it’s something worth seeing for yourself.&nbsp;</p>

<p>I may be repeating myself from the previous episode, but I am loving these big choices <em>Dispatch </em>tosses our way. So many games will set up choices that don’t really go anywhere or may let you see one small scene or dialogue later on.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Here, <em>Dispatch </em>is letting you change who you interact with and while I haven’t seen the effects of the choice at the end of this episode, it may fundamentally change Robert’s relationships with some characters.&nbsp;</p>

<p>This is what player agency looks like in a narrative-driven game like this. Character interactions and relationships are at the very heart of narrative, and choices that swing those one way or another are always going to be satisfying.</p>

<hr><p>Episode 3 and 4 continue the trend of adding new elements and wrinkles to the game, so each episode is not just more of the same. &nbsp;</p>

<p>I’m excited to see where it goes and just what sort of twists are in store for the second half of the game.&nbsp;</p>

<hr><p>Dispatch <em>was previewed on PC with a copy provided by the publisher.</em></p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Andrew is the Editor in Chief at TechRaptor. Conned into a love of gaming by Nintendo at a young age, Andrew has been&nbsp;chasing the dragon spawned by Super… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/andrew-otton">More about Andrew</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/dispatch-episode-3-4-impressions-big-choices]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dispatch Cast Interview - Carrying Telltale's Torch, Voicing Multiple Timelines, And Roleplaying Superheroes]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/interviews/dispatch-cast-interview</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dispatch-cast-interview-carrying-telltales-torch-voicing-multiple-timelines-and-roleplaying-superheroes.1338526/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Ahead of the release of <a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="0198afae-1a19-4ceb-8e96-ac07e2466b09" href="https://techraptor.net/games/dispatch" rel="nofollow"><em>Dispatch</em></a>, I had the chance to sit down with a number of the cast members to discuss how they came onto the project and about their characters, what it's like to voice characters across so many permutations, and what made AdHoc Studios the perfect pick for Critical Role's Exandria.</p>

<p>I sat down first with Travis Willingham (Phenomeman), Joel Haver (Waterboy), and comedian Fahim Anwar, who answered my questions in-universe as his character Lance Cantstopolis (Flambae). Additionally, I spoke with Laura Bailey (Invisigal) and Erin Yvette (Blonde Blazer) about the idea of good and bad powers.</p>

<p>You can check out my interviews back-to-back in the video below, or read on for the breakdown and highlights.</p>
<p><iframe allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed//DeOJgRvJdfI"></iframe></p>

<h2>Who Are the Heroes of the Superhero Dispatch Network?</h2>

<p>Willingham introduced me to Phenomeman, an alien with the powers of flight, speed, and strength. He's <em>Dispatch's </em>Superman analogue, though one big difference is that Phenomeman still doesn't quite understand what it is to be human leading him to be slightly weird no matter what situation he finds himself in.</p>

<p>Haver plays Waterboy, a down on himself guy with the ability to make things wet, who is hired to be the janitor at the Superhero Dispatch Network (SDN). "He's set to be the janitor, so a very important role, everyone needs one," Haver added.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/disaptch-waterboy.jpg?itok=aDuI7OhD 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/disaptch-waterboy.jpg?itok=eRVnDnXt 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>The question was a bit different for Cantstopolis, as I wanted to hear what led him to the change of heart, turning his back on his villainous ways and become a member of Z Team, a group of villains that SDN is looking to reform. "Change of pace, basically," Cantstopolis responded. "It seemed like a cool crew. Friendship and the benefits, like medical and dental."</p>

<p>The group broke out laughing at the idea of superhero medical benefits.</p>

<p>Yvette introduced her character, "I play Blonde Blazer, she hails from the ethos of Golden Age superheroes. She's got top-tier superstrength, flight, you know… everything that someone would want. She carries the mantle with grace and dignity, and I think she's unfulfilled by it and seeking a bit more.</p>

<p>"I think it's a surprising move for a superhero to end up at a desk job when they aren't forced to," Yvette dug deeper. "I think there's something exciting for Blazer in terms of the difference she can make reforming the Z Team, and I think she genuinely sees the good in people and wants to help nurture them."</p>

<blockquote>
<p>"Where you first meet [Blonde Blazer] in the game… she's saving Robert's ass, and it won't be the last time."</p>
</blockquote>

<p>"And I play Invisigal," Bailey explained. "Speaking of reforming, she is an ex-supervillain trying to be better and having a difficult go of it. The first time you meet her is in a moment where she's undermining [Blonde Blazer] and giving Robert Robertson a tough time."</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/disaptch-cutscene.jpg?itok=SkoOb8yM 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/disaptch-cutscene.jpg?itok=r5q227Ya 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>As a longtime fan of Haver's YouTube channel, where he creates comedic parodies with a unique rotoscoped style, I was interested to hear how he got involved with the project.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"It was Nick and Pierre, the director and writers of the game, who reached out to me via email because they'd seen some of my animations," Haver explained. "They liked what I did; they liked my awkward comedy. The strange and stilted dialogue felt very real, and it was a natural pairing for this game. It is grounded and real dialogue in a very fantastical setting, and they brought me on to play Waterboy, who is an awkward mess of a man. So maybe he'll clean himself up as part of the story."</p>

<p>Knowing that Cantstopolis started in such a different place as Robert Robertson, the main character of <em>Dispatch</em>, I asked how their relationship was now that they'd been working together. He started by talking about how their relationship began in a bar altercation, and where it went from there. "That was a very tense moment… to then have to be co-workers is tough. It's not just water under the bridge."</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/dispatch-mecha-man-and-blonde-blazer.jpg?itok=nYeNDSxA 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/dispatch-mecha-man-and-blonde-blazer.jpg?itok=BIcvMYgT 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>Haver jumped in, "It's really alcohol in the face."</p>

<p>Pondering it further Cantstopolis had to ask, "There's got to be a HR department that I can bring this up to? Then I'd just avoid his cube for a little while."</p>

<h2>How Do Powers Define You?</h2>

<p>There's a tense moment in the early episodes where Invisigal is down on herself due to her 'evil' powers of invisibility. I was interested to dive into what Bailey and Yvette thought of the idea of powers being defined that way.</p>

<p>"You know, we were talking about that earlier, If I had the ability to go invisible I think it might start in an altruistic way, but the temptation is so present, knowing you can get away with things, that you'd really have to have the strongest moral code to not slip into something nefarious," Bailey said, reflecting on her thought process about Invisigal's powers.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/dispatch-invisigal.jpg?itok=ANAgH9jo 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/dispatch-invisigal.jpg?itok=fjQzfiNd 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p><em>Dispatch </em>takes place in a world of superheroes and supercrime, but it's really more about the workplace drama and relationships of the party. I asked what about the story was it that made Yvette and Bailey want to be involved.</p>

<p>Yvette began, "Really, because of exactly what you pitched. The fresh perspective of, I think we can all say, a well-tread genre. There's so much more to mine out of it. <em>Dispatch </em>turns it on its head and explores, 'Do the supervillains really want to be supervillains? If they don't, how do they change that?'"</p>

<p>"It feels very grounded," Bailey added, "You've got this immense world, and these immense powers, but the story feels very intimate."&nbsp;</p>

<h2>A Story With Branching Paths</h2>

<p>Asking all about what it's like acting through a story with so many paths, I got a very concise answer from everyone. "It was just knowing I'm in the hands of a good director," Haver offered.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/dispatch-descisions.jpg?itok=VlJ-6NMF 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/dispatch-descisions.jpg?itok=0gvSfdHA 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>"They are the ones keeping track of the branching path, was this character betrayed in the previous scene? How should you play this moment? Fortunately they're really good at keeping track of this stuff so you just go with it. I trust that this scene I am not as sad, even though it's the same scene…"</p>

<p>"Yeah, the characters go through some crazy-ass twists and turns," Willingham added, throwing in some joking examples. "Is this the one where I've been romancing the elephant? Or is it the one where I'm in my crystal meth phase?"</p>

<p>Bailey confidently answered, "You've got to have a lot of trust. in your director, and writer, and the entire team to make sure that the performance that you're giving is going to be supported." Bailey talked about how a choice might have been made two episodes ago, that's going to pay off in a certain way and you've just got to trust you're getting the right information.</p>

<p>Bailey likened stepping into the booth to being an empty slate: "You're ready for the information."</p>

<p>Yvette also added that even as these choices are being made around the characters, "there's certain aspects of your character that remain the same. You have that foundation of the character you've explored and created together with your team, so that when you make these choices, all of them feel like they can coexist."</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/disaptch-phenomeman-and-blonde-blazer.jpg?itok=QqRS9qfz 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/disaptch-phenomeman-and-blonde-blazer.jpg?itok=v6i9l5WH 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><h2>Why Is AdHoc Studios the Place for Critical Role's Exandria?</h2>

<p>Asking Travis Willingham, not as the actor behind Phenomeman but as the CEO for Critical Role, I was curious what parts of <em>Dispatch </em>and the work AdHoc Studios was doing made it a perfect place for the first Critical Role video game.</p>

<p>"We had the great pleasure to work with Pierre Shorette and Nick Herman [AdHoc Studio founders] during their Telltale days for a number of games, but once we got our eyes on the demo scene from <em>Dispatch</em>, I was extremely hungry to learn as much as I could," Willingham began. "The more I learned, the more curious we became. I also think they've done an incredible job on the visuals, the animation is stellar.</p>

<p>"We also love people who are making their own IPs and making something from scratch, and at Critical Role we love to try and turn it into any other medium so you can find it in other audiences whether it's in books, animation, or a TTRPG. I think <em>Dispatch </em>would play great with rolling some dice in an actual-play setting."</p>

<p>Interestingly enough, since my conversation with Willingham, Critical Role has announced a <em>Dispatch</em>-themed <a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="951117a2-07e4-403b-b1c3-26041d599e45" href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/daggerheart-review-narrative-forward-yes-and-ttrpg-that-is-force-to-be-reckoned" rel="nofollow"><em>Daggerheart </em></a>one-shot Thursday Oct. 30, with cast members from the game along with some other faces familiar to Critical Role and actual play fans.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/wordless_dispatch_thumbnail_v1a.jpg?itok=b7N7ADQd 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/wordless_dispatch_thumbnail_v1a.jpg?itok=D1IndfiL 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>"It's just the beginning, and if we can help bring it to as many people as possible, then that's going to bring us a lot of joy in the interim."</p>

<blockquote>
<p>From here on there will be some spoilers for Episodes 3 and 4 of <em>Dispatch</em>. Be sure to play those episodes and then come back.</p>
</blockquote>

<h2>Stranger With A Broken Heart</h2>

<p>Knowing how odd Phenomeman was, I was interested in the approach Willingham took when having to play him while going through something as real as heartbreak. "It was fun from the start. It was great to see this big barrel-chested character with all of these amazing abilities, but when it gets down to it, he can't hold a normal conversation without confounding the people he's talking to."</p>

<blockquote>
<p>"You've gotta feel sorry for the guy, he's got the whole world at his fingertips and he can't even figure out the ladies." - Willingham</p>
</blockquote>

<p>"The great thing is being able to play someone all powerful like that, but they're not maligned, they're not trying to take over the world. It's not an Omni-Man character," Willingham did have to pause to give some respect to Phenomeman's mustache before continuing, "This guy is almost more childlike in a way. Love had him head over heels, he's trying his best to learn from anyone who will take a moment to sit with him."&nbsp;</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/disaptch-phenomeman.jpg?itok=8LoBRnZp 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/disaptch-phenomeman.jpg?itok=BF5TenZn 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><h2>Creating Deep Characters in the World of <em>Dispatch</em></h2>

<p>As we discussed the roles of Blonde Blazer and Invisigal in a game where choices are always being made to propel the characters in certain directions, it also offers up a lot of chances to see different sides of these characters.</p>

<p>Yvette began by explaining she was happy in this story that the 'will they, won't they' never defines any of the characters. "As an actor, that's really fulfilling to know that your character's worth isn't tied to their attractiveness or likability. If you're focused on 'I must be the most likable character,' it's going to be a rough room."</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/disaptch-z-team.jpg?itok=bMEdIvyz 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/disaptch-z-team.jpg?itok=t04ZUmHx 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>"I think I'm really attracted to scenes and characters where you get to have unexpected vulnerability, and as you pursue relationships with these characters and you find more of those interactions, as a performer, getting to peel back those layers and show those softer moments, I look forward to that so much that I would hope anybody that's playing the games takes the opportunity to play all aspects of the games so that they can see the scenes that they might miss out on." Bailey broke into a joking plea.</p>

<p>I took this moment to reveal I already had four save files, each with major changes, to experience the differences in the story.</p>

<p>If you're interested to learn more about how AdHoc came about <a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="516f8eb5-9839-41ae-b120-63ed11a9fa86" href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/features/dispatch-is-episodic-workplace-comedy-first-iterating-where-telltale-refused-to" rel="nofollow">creating the world of <em>Dispatch</em> then you can check out my interview with the development team</a>, and if you want to hear our thoughts on the game then <a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="cc726998-9269-443e-a9b7-85b760f056c8" href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/dispatch-episode-1-2-impressions" rel="nofollow">our preview of the first two episodes is available now</a>.</p>
</div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/interviews/dispatch-cast-interview]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Helldivers 2, Minecraft and Sea Of Thieves hit by connectivity issues following big Microsoft services outage]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/helldivers-2-minecraft-and-sea-of-thieves-hit-by-connectivity-issues-following-big-microsoft-services-outage</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/helldivers-2-minecraft-and-sea-of-thieves-hit-by-connectivity-issues-following-big-microsoft-services-outage.1338520/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Online things besides videogames probably having difficulty as well</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/helldivers-2-major-order-citizen-nightmares-arg-cape-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/helldivers-2-major-order-citizen-nightmares-arg-cape-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/helldivers-2-major-order-citizen-nightmares-arg-cape-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/helldivers-2-major-order-citizen-nightmares-arg-cape-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/helldivers-2-major-order-citizen-nightmares-arg-cape-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/helldivers-2-major-order-citizen-nightmares-arg-cape-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/helldivers-2-major-order-citizen-nightmares-arg-cape-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/helldivers-2-major-order-citizen-nightmares-arg-cape-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/helldivers-2-major-order-citizen-nightmares-arg-cape-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Arrowhead</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>If you're having trouble getting into Minecraft, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/helldivers-2">Helldivers 2</a> or Sea Of Thieves right now, it might have something to do with a Microsoft outage that has taken services such as Azure offline. All three of the aforesaid games are <a href="https://downdetector.com/status/helldivers-2/">experiencing</a> <a href="https://downdetector.com/status/sea-of-thieves/">spikes</a> <a href="https://downdetector.com/status/minecraft/">on</a> DownDetector.com, and there are reports of disconnections and failed logins on social media. The outage has also affected various possibly more consequential non-gaming things, such as airline bookings and banks. On the upside, it seems to have taken down Microsoft Outlook.
</p><!--more-->
<p>Microsoft appear to have identified what's broken. "We suspect that an inadvertent configuration change as the trigger event for this issue," notes an update, shared by <a href="https://www.techradar.com/pro/live/microsoft-down-major-outage-hits-azure-365-and-more-even-minecraft-affected">Techradar</a>, who have set up a very excited liveblog full of words I don't understand. "We are taking two concurrent actions where we are blocking all changes to the AFD services and disabling a problematic route that we found to be related to this, and at the same time rolling back to our last known good state.
</p>
<p>"We have failed the portal away from Azure Front Door (AFD) to mitigate the portal access issues," the note from MS continues, filling my head with fractal visions of doors peeling away from doors. "Customers should be able to access the Azure management portal directly. We do not have an ETA for when the rollback will be completed, but we will update this communication within 30 minutes or when we have an update."</p>
<p>That message was from about 45 minutes before this post was published. If you can't access your Minecraft server now, I believe it's company policy that you are allowed to sneeze on Satya Nadella's lunch. It seems likely other online videogames are struggling besides those mentioned above. Let us know if you're having difficulty entering your preferred corner of cyberspace. Let us fill the comments thread with woe.</p>

        </div>

      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/helldivers-2-minecraft-and-sea-of-thieves-hit-by-connectivity-issues-following-big-microsoft-services-outage]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>