<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 16:07:47 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Final Fantasy VII Remake Part 3 Story and Concept Have Been Completed; Devs Are Fully Committed to Deliver Freely Explorable Map With Airship]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/final-fantasy-vii-remake-part-3-story-completed/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/final-fantasy-vii-remake-part-3-story-and-concept-have-been-completed-devs-are-fully-committed-to-deliver-freely-explorable-map-with-airship.1036887/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/final-fantasy-vii-remake-part-3-story-completed/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The third and final entry in the Final Fantasy VII Remake trilogy will not shy away from the challenge of allowing players to fly freely around the map, according to the game's director.</p>
<p>Speaking during a panel today at G-Star 2024 going over the creation of the remake trilogy, the themes upon which each game was built, and more, as reported by <a href="https://www.4gamer.net/games/638/G063881/20241115058/">4Gamer</a>, Director Naoki Hamaguchi provided a small update on the third yet-to-be-named entry in the series. As far as development is concerned, the plot for the game has been completed, the concept decided, and the team is already working on it. The concept, in particular, is extremely important to the game but could not be revealed at the time.</p>
<p>The one thing about the third entry in the Final Fantasy VII Remake that Hamaguchi-san could talk about was the map. <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/final-fantasy-vii-rebirth/">Final Fantasy VII Rebirth</a> provided a big map to explore, but with the introduction of the Highwind airship, the development team needs to allow players to experience the world from a higher perspective. He also added that they will not take any shortcuts to achieve this and will take on the challenge of being able to fly freely around the map.</p>
<p>Considering the vast majority of the Final Fantasy VII world was recreated for Rebirth, it will be very interesting how the development team will overcome the challenge of recreating the entire world while allowing players to fly freely around it and make it interesting even when revisiting locations that were already explored in the second entry in the series. As the development team definitely exceeded expectations with Rebirth, in my opinion, there's little doubt they will be able to do so again with the third game that will conclude the story.</p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Remap Recommends, Volume II]]></title>
            <link>https://remapradio.com/articles/remap-recommends/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/remap-recommends-volume-ii.1036884/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://remapradio.com/articles/remap-recommends/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		<p><em>Remember when you’d walk into a local music, book, or video store and there’d be an adorable section where the employees would recommend what they were interested in that month? </em></p><p><em>Welcome to our little version of it, called Remap Recommends.&nbsp;</em></p><p><em>At the end of every month, we'll have an edition of Remap Recommends focused on video games. But in the middle of the month, we'll have an edition focused on...everything else. It's a chance for the staff at Remap to let you know what they've been reading, listening to, or watching.</em></p><hr><h3 id="patrick-recommends-arcane">Patrick Recommends... <em>Arcane</em></h3><figure></figure><p><strong>Streaming On:</strong> Netflix<br><strong>Number of Episodes:</strong> 18 (nine in season one, nine in season two)<br><strong>Hours I've Spent Playing <em>League of Legends</em>:</strong> 0<br><strong>Why Aren't We Getting More <em>Scavengers Reign</em>?:</strong> I don't know, man</p><p>Let me be clear: I do not care for MOBAs. In fact, they irritate me because it means there is time and money being spent on building MOBAs when those people could, in theory, be making anything else. But this is the world we live in. People deserve happiness, even if I question whether one should find salvation within a MOBA. </p><p>Jokes aside, do not let the<em> League of Legends</em> branding scare you off. I almost let that happen, but doing so would've robbed me of one of the best animated shows...<em>ever</em>? I feel comfortable saying that. <em>Arcane</em> does not require one drop of experience with its source material, and entirely succeeds on the merits of the storytelling happening in the show. I'm sure there are easter eggs about, but it never humiliates you for not knowing a lick about<em> League of Legends</em>, and delivers a gorgeous and heart-pounding mashup of steampunk and politics.</p><p><em>Arcane</em> is almost good enough to make me consider trying the game. Almost.</p><p>On, and like the<em> Spider-Verse </em>movies, <em>Arcane</em> suggests the Pixar and DreamWorks-ification of computer animation has been holding us back for decades. There's so much more than what we've seen so far.</p><hr><h3 id="rob-recommendsplus-one">Rob Recommends...<em>Plus One</em></h3><figure></figure><p><strong>Streaming On</strong>: Hulu<br><strong>Runtime:</strong> 1h38m<br><strong>Who It's For</strong>: People who loved <em>Before Midnight</em><br><strong>Cooter Status: </strong>Out</p><p>This flew under my radar until we we were at a loss for what to watch last month and just grabbed something Hulu was pushing on our home page. On the off chance you never heard of it, I'll give you my pitch for 2019's <em>Plus One</em>.</p><p><em>Plus One </em>is superficially about as by-the-numbers a romantic comedy as you can get. Two platonic friends are staring down the barrel of a wedding season from hell and decide to go as one another's dates for the entire year. Maya Erskine's Alice has just had a long relationship evaporate, and Jack Quaid's Matt is struggling with his fear that he will never meet anyone he can be confident in having a long, committed relationship with. You know what's going to happen next.</p><p>Except it happens about halfway through the film and most of the customary obstacles are dispensed with pretty quickly. An almost accidental casual hookup turns into a relationship with only a little tension and awkwardness... and then things go catastrophically and painfully wrong between Matt and Alice. Not in a cute way, not based on a simple misunderstanding that could cleared up with a conversation or a message. They go wrong because the ways Matt and Alice are messy and dysfunctional, though undeniably funny for much of the film, are neither harmless nor cute.</p><p>Most romantic comedies don't go this route. They keep their leads' flaws squarely in the relatable-but-harmless realm. The romantic pairing almost break-up because they just can't trust each other—and love itself—to open themselves up to embracing what is right in front of their eyes! The thing few of them get into is that love—or maybe the commitment part of it—really is scary. It can go bad. It <em>will </em>go bad. The question is what people decide to do next.</p><p><em>Plus One </em>gives us two characters who are protecting themselves and each other from a lot of pain and loneliness at the start of the movie, and almost against their will they open up to each other and in the process start handing the other person direct access to all their deepest fears and doubts... and almost immediately they devastate each other. For bad, self-sabotaging, but <em>entirely coherent and understandable </em>reasons. Matt and Alice might be characters in a comedy but the script from writer-directors Jeff Chan and Andrew Rhymer takes them very seriously <em>as people</em>. Erskine is, as always, sensational and absolutely nails both the broadest comedic moments of the film and the most painful dramatic ones, but Quaid is well-matched as a someone who is slowly revealed to be the the worst kind of man-child, convinced of his own kindness and maturity as he takes a nose-dive into his own hidden pathology. Understanding and self-knowledge arrive late for him in the form of a beautiful and hilarious scene with his father, played by Ed Begley, Jr. who deftly pivots his character from being the film's broadest source of comic relief to giving its thesis on what it really means for a relationship to succeed or fail.</p><p>The rest of the film is similarly iconoclastic. The photography (by Guy Godfree) and direction form eschew the saturated warm colors and aspirational sets of most contemporary romantic comedies and go for location shooting with a cooler and almost documentary feel. Matt and Alice spend time in shitty hotel rooms, dire motor courts, and empty parking lots and alleys. One of the big romantic breakthroughs takes place at a resort hotel perpetually blanketed by a cloying marine layer. The two characters are lunging for a relationship as the last light is fading. As funny and at times bawdy as <em>Plus One </em>is, it invites comparisons with Linklater's <em>Before </em>trilogy, and it's a good enough film that the comparison isn't an embarrassing one.</p><hr><h3 id="cado-recommends-mubi">Cado Recommends... Mubi</h3><figure><figcaption><span>The Substance, screenshot courtesy of Cannes</span></figcaption></figure><p><strong>Streaming On:</strong> Mubi<br><strong>Current Movies I've Watched on Mubi:</strong> 2<br><strong>Movies on Mubi That I've Added to My Watch List:</strong> 6<br><strong>La Jetée?:</strong> Yes</p><p>Me recommending Mubi is really a way to backdoor a recommendation for two movies that I think you should see if you haven't already because they both exist on Mubi, and as of this writing you can currently get a <a href="https://mubi.com/en/paste?ref=remapradio.com" rel="noreferrer">free month of the service thanks to the folks over at <em>Paste</em></a>.</p><p>And what should I do with that month you ask? First up, treat yourself to the aesthetic and emotional grandiosity of <em>The Fall, </em>which has just been remastered in 4k and screened at select theaters across the country. If you were unable to make one of these screenings, at least you've got Mubi as the (as of this writing) only place you can stream the 4k remaster at home. </p><p>Perhaps you're like me and are already missing the spooky vibes of an October that came and went too quickly. Well, Mubi's got you again with my personal favorite horror movie I watched this year, <em>The Substance.</em> Show up for the commentary on the treatment of women in Hollywood, stay for the absolutely wild body horror!</p><p>Aside from these two great films, I've also added a number of movies to my watch list to try and make the best out of this month of cinema. It's been too long since I've watched <em>La Jetée, </em>time for a refresher! Oops, I never saw <em>The Godfather</em>, might as well fix that! Who doesn't love a casual rewatch of <em>Stalker</em>? </p><p>Honestly, with the amount of interesting fresh-from-the-festival-circuit movies that exist, I'm already gearing up to need a little more Mubi in my life.</p>
		<p><em>Patrick Klepek (he/him) is an editor at Remap. In another life, he worked on horror movie sets, but instead, he also runs&nbsp;<a href="https://crossplay.news/?ref=remap.ghost.io" rel="noreferrer"><em>Crossplay</em></a>, a newsletter about parenting and video games. You can follow him on&nbsp;<a href="https://www.twitter.com/patrickklepek?ref=remap.ghost.io" rel="noreferrer"><em>Twitter</em></a>,&nbsp;<a href="https://www.threads.net/@patrickklepek?ref=remap.ghost.io" rel="noreferrer"><em>Threads</em></a>,&nbsp;<a href="https://mastodon.social/@patrickklepek?ref=remap.ghost.io" rel="noreferrer"><em>Mastodon</em></a>, and&nbsp;<a href="https://bsky.app/profile/patrickklepek.bsky.social?ref=remap.ghost.io" rel="noreferrer"><em>Bluesky</em></a>.</em></p>
		<p><em>Rob Zacny (he/him) is a cofounder and partner at Remap. In addition to his work at Remap, he is the host of <a href="https://amorecivilizedage.net/?ref=remapradio.com" rel="noreferrer">A More Civilized Age: A Star Wars Podcast</a> and a panelist on <a href="https://www.f1.cool/?ref=remapradio.com" rel="noreferrer">Shift+F1</a>, a Formula 1 racing podcast. You can follow his increasingly inactive social media presence on&nbsp;<a href="https://www.twitter.com/robzacny?ref=remapradio.com" rel="noreferrer"><em>Twitter</em></a>,&nbsp;and&nbsp;<a href="https://bsky.app/profile/robzacny.bsky.social?ref=remapradio.com" rel="noreferrer"><em>Bluesky</em></a>.</em></p>
		<p><em>Ricardo "Cado" Contreras (they/them) is a Livestream Producer, Podcast Editor, and (very rarely) Writer at Remap. They love card mechanics in video games and will teach you how to play Netrunner at the drop of a hat. You can follow them on&nbsp;<a href="https://www.twitter.com/a_cado_appears?ref=remap.ghost.io" rel="noreferrer"><em>Twitter</em></a>&nbsp;and <a href="https://cohost.org/cado?ref=remapradio.com" rel="noreferrer"><em>Cohost</em></a>.</em></p>
			</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Splinter Cell Movie Has Been Cancelled]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/the-splinter-cell-movie-has-been-cancelled/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-splinter-cell-movie-has-been-cancelled.1036881/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/the-splinter-cell-movie-has-been-cancelled/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>The Splinter Cell movie that was slated to star Tom Hardy has been cancelled, according to one of the film’s producers.</p>



<p>Twelve years after it was first reported as in development, producer Basil Iwanyk was asked about the state of the movie. In his response to <a href="https://thedirect.com/article/splinter-cell-tom-hardy-movie-exclusive" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">The Direct</a>, Iwanyk confirmed that the movie wasn’t happening due to not being able to “get it right”.</p>



<p>“That movie would have been awesome… Just couldn’t get it right, script-wise, budget-wise,” Iwanyk said. “But it was going to be great. We had a million different versions of it, but it was going to be hardcore and awesome. </p>



<p>“That’s one of the ones that got away, which is really sad.”</p>



<p>The news of the movie’s demise shouldn’t come as much of a surprise. Since being announced over a decade ago, there had been nary an update on it’s status. It’s likely that most fans that heard about it complete forgot by now.</p>



<p>If the cancellation of the Splinter Cell movie has you upset, however, don’t be too upset. Ubisoft is continuing work on its remake of the first Splinter Cell, which is <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/exclusive-update-on-splinter-cell-remakes-development/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">currently targeting for a 2026 release date</a>.</p>



<p>What do you think of the Splinter Cell movie being cancelled? Let us know below, and join the discussion in the official Insider Gaming forums.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read what Xbox boss Phil Spencer said about why <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/phil-spencer-reveals-why-xbox-isnt-doing-a-mid-gen-refresh/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Microsoft isn’t doing a mid-generation refresh</a> for the Xbox Series X|S. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Here’s Your Look at the Avowed System Requirements]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/heres-your-look-at-the-avowed-system-requirements/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/here%E2%80%99s-your-look-at-the-avowed-system-requirements.1036878/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/heres-your-look-at-the-avowed-system-requirements/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Obsidian Entertainment, known for fantastical RPGs like The Outer Worlds and Pillars of Eternity, returns in 2025 with a first-person RPG that many believe may rival The Elder Scrolls. That may feel a little generous, but if you’ve ever played Pillars of Eternity, then you know the team is adept at world-building and lore, making for a truly unique and captivating role-playing game experience. But for now, we must wait and prepare. To that end, here’s your first look at the Avowed system requirements!</p>



<h2 id="h-these-are-the-avowed-pc-system-requirements">These Are the Avowed PC System Requirements</h2>



<p>We’re still months from the release of Avowed, but Obsidian Entertainment finally unveiled the game’s system requirements ahead of time. Overall, they’re relatively approachable, especially on the low end, but man, storage space requirements have quickly ballooned in size in recent years. You’ll soon need an entire SSD for a single game, just you wait and see!</p>



<h3 id="h-minimum-system-requirements-nbsp">Minimum System Requirements&nbsp;</h3>



<ul>
<li><strong>OS</strong>: Windows 10/11 with updates</li>



<li><strong>Processor</strong>: AMD Ryzen 5 2600 / Intel i5-8400</li>



<li><strong>Memory</strong>: 16 GB RAM</li>



<li><strong>Graphics</strong>: AMD RX 5700 / Nvidia GTX 1070 / Intel Arc A580</li>



<li><strong>DirectX</strong>: Version 12</li>



<li><strong>Storage</strong>: 75 GB Available Space (SSD Recommended)</li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-recommended-system-requirements-nbsp">Recommended System Requirements&nbsp;</h3>



<ul>
<li><strong>OS</strong>: Windows 10/11 with updates</li>



<li><strong>Processor</strong>: AMD Ryzen 5 5600X / Intel i7-10700K</li>



<li><strong>Memory</strong>: 16 GB RAM</li>



<li><strong>Graphics</strong>: Graphics: AMD RX 6800 XT / Nvidia RTX 3080</li>



<li><strong>DirectX</strong>: Version 12</li>



<li><strong>Storage</strong>: 75 GB Available Space (SSD Recommended)</li>
</ul>



<h6 id="h-related-avowed-pre-order-details-and-game-editions-revealed">Related: <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/avowed-pre-order-details-and-game-editions-revealed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Avowed Pre-Order Details and Game Editions Revealed</a></h6>



<h2 id="h-what-to-play-while-we-wait-for-avowed">What to Play While We Wait for Avowed</h2>



<p>Seeing as Avowed doesn’t release until February 18, we still have a few months until we can dive into the fantasy world. That’s plenty of time to beat another large-scale RPG or two in the meantime. To help you prepare, we recommend the following RPGs:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Hogwarts Legacy</strong></li>



<li><strong>Baldur’s Gate 3</strong></li>



<li><strong>The Outer Worlds</strong></li>



<li><strong>Pillars of Eternity</strong></li>



<li><strong>Cyberpunk 2077</strong></li>



<li><strong>Dragon’s Dogma 2</strong></li>
</ul>



<p>The Outer Worlds doesn’t take too long to complete, but you can easily spend hundreds of hours exploring every nook and cranny in all of the other recommendations!</p>



<p>What other titles would you recommend while we wait for Avowed? Let us know in the comments below, or start a thread about the upcoming RPG in <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">our community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>Speaking of the upcoming RPG, according to Phil Spencer, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/avowed-delay-wasnt-due-to-game-quality-phil-spencer-says/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Avowed wasn’t delayed due to the game’s quality</a> but for other reasons instead!</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Real Heroes: Firefighter HD coming to PS5 on December 6]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/11/real-heroes-firefighter-hd-coming-to-ps5-on-december-6</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/real-heroes-firefighter-hd-coming-to-ps5-on-december-6.1036875/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/11/real-heroes-firefighter-hd-coming-to-ps5-on-december-6<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Currently available for Xbox One and PC.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Ziggurat Interactive [30 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/ziggurat-interactive">Ziggurat Interactive</a> will release a <a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,369 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a> version of first-person firefighting game <em><a title="Games > Real Heroes: Firefighter HD" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/real-heroes-firefighter-hd">Real Heroes: Firefighter HD</a></em> via <a title="Platforms > PlayStation [46,436 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation">PlayStation</a> Store on December 6, the company announced. <span id="more-928038"></span></p><p><em>Real Heroes: Firefighter HD</em> first launched for PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1333700/Real_Heroes_Firefighter_HD/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> and <a href="https://www.gog.com/en/game/real_heroes_firefighter" rel="noopener" target="_blank">GOG</a> on January 21, 2021, followed by Xbox One on March 30, 2022. It is a remastered version of <em><a title="Games > Real Heroes: Firefighter" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/real-heroes-firefighter">Real Heroes: Firefighter</a></em>, which first launched for <a title="Platforms > Wii [241 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/wii">Wii</a> on August 4, 2009, followed by <a title="Platforms > 3DS [3,973 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/3ds">3DS</a> on September 12, 2012, PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/549680/Real_Heroes_Firefighter/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> on March 14, 2017, Switch on November 27, 2019, and PlayStation 4 on March 10, 2020.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Ziggurat Interactive:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Don the soot-stained boots of an everyday hero as a newly graduated academy cadet getting their start in a big city fire station. Charging head-first into danger is all part of the job description!</p><p><em>Real Heroes: Firefighter HD</em> is a first-person firefighting and rescue <a title="Genres > Action [2,307 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action game</a> where players take on the heroic role of a real firefighter. Beginning their career at a fire station in Los Angeles, the game’s hero must learn the tools of the trade, battle massive blazes, and rescue citizens from deadly infernos. It’s time to put on a fresh pair of turnout pants, grab a Halligan, and take to the streets to battle man’s deadliest foe—fire!</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li>Realistic fire technology creates an incredible adversary that feels “alive” and dangerous</li><li>A career mode featuring more than nine levels and locations</li><li>Use real-life firefighting tools, including hoses, axes, hydraulic rescue tools, Halligans, and more</li><li>An all-star Hollywood voice cast including James Marsters (<em>Buffy: The Vampire Slayer</em>), Jack McGee (<em>Rescue Me</em>), Michael Jace (<em>The Shield</em>),</li><li>Jamie Kennedy (<em>Ghost Whisperer</em>), and Jenette Goldstein (<em>Aliens</em>).</li><li>PlayStation 5-exclusive haptic effects for DualSense gamepads.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>PlayStation 5 Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Real Heroes: Firefighter HD - PlayStation 5 Announce Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Wi0igBlUpUo?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I played Half-Life 2 for the first time this year—here’s how it went]]></title>
            <link>https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2024/11/i-played-half-life-2-for-the-first-time-this-year-heres-how-it-went/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/i-played-half-life-2-for-the-first-time-this-year%E2%80%94here%E2%80%99s-how-it-went.1036872/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2024/11/i-played-half-life-2-for-the-first-time-this-year-heres-how-it-went/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="main">
            <article data-id="2061537">
  
  <header>
  <div>
    <div>
      

      

      <p>
        Wake up and smell the ashes, Ms. Washenko.
      </p>

      
    </div>

    <div>
    
    <p>
      This article is part of our 20th anniversary of <em>Half-Life 2</em> series.

              <span>
          Credit:

          
          Aurich Lawson

                  </span>
          </p>
  </div>
  </div>
</header>


  

  
      
    
    <div>
                      
                      
          
<p><em>It's&nbsp;</em>Half-Life 2<em>&nbsp;week at Ars Technica! This Saturday, November 16, is the 20th anniversary of the release of&nbsp;</em>Half-Life 2<em>—a game of historical importance for the artistic medium and technology of computer games. Each day up through the 16th, we'll be running a new article looking back at the game and its impact.</em></p>
<p>The time has finally come to close one of the most notable gaps in my gaming history. Despite more than a decade of writing about video games and even more years enjoying them, I never got around to playing <em>Half-Life 2</em>.</p>
<p>Not only have I not played it, but I've managed to keep myself in the dark about pretty much everything to do with it. I always assumed that one day I would get around to playing this classic, and I wanted the experience to be as close as possible to it would have been back in 2004. So my only knowledge about <em>Half-Life 2</em> before starting this project was 1) the game is set in the same universe as <em>Portal</em>, a game I love, 2) the protagonist is named Gordon Freeman, and he looks uncannily like a silent, spectacled young Hugh Laurie, and 3) there's something called the Gravity Gun.</p>
<p>That's it. I didn't even know exactly what the Gravity Gun did, only that it existed.</p>
<p>So, the time has come for me to learn what the fuss is all about. I've cataloged my off-the-cuff reactions as well as my more analytical thoughts about <em>Half-Life 2</em>, both as a standalone project and as a catalyst for setting new standards in design. But if you're looking for the TL;DR of whether I think the game holds up, my answer is: it depends.</p>
<h2>Beginning a classic with a clunk</h2>
<p>A red letter day indeed! Time to experience this iconic piece of video game history. I spend most of the intro sequence in the train station soaking in the atmosphere of the dystopian City 17. A few minutes in, though, I think I'm supposed to sneak past a guard. Because I'm a fugitive trying to escape this freaky Big Brother building, and I swear Barney told me to avoid detection. Instead, the guard immediately sees me and whomps me on the head for not putting a bottle into the trash. Not an auspicious beginning.</p>

          
                      
                  </div>
                    
        
          
    
    <div>
          
          
<p>I make it to Dr. Kleiner's lab for a little bit of story exposition. I like this rag-tag group of geniuses and the whole vibe of a secret scientific rebellion. I also appreciate that it's not a static cutscene, so I can poke around the lab while I listen or observe the characters interacting.</p>
<p>After a failed teleport and getting a crowbar from Barney, I then spend a long time getting shot and dying in a train yard. Like, an embarrassingly long time. Perhaps I was assuming at this early stage that <em>Half-Life 2</em> would be like <em>Portal</em> with real guns, because I figured this area had to be a puzzle. I'm not sure how I missed the one portion of the environment that I could slip through, but I convinced myself that I was supposed to leap across the tops of the train cars, <em>Frogger</em> style. And Gordon might have many skills, but his jumping leaves something to be desired.</p>
<p>Finally, I realize that there's a gap in the cars, and I move along. This canal setting is striking, but I keep being unsure which areas of the map I can access. I've heard that the level design is one of the most lauded parts of <em>Half-Life 2</em>, but this is proving to be a genuine struggle with the game.</p>
<p>When I played <em>Portal</em>, I sometimes was unsure how to progress, but because that game is presented in the austere confines of a science experiment, I felt like I was supposed to be challenged. In <em>Half-Life 2</em>, though, where there are higher stakes and I'm running for my life, getting stuck just makes me feel dumb and annoyed. And I'm doubly annoyed because this escape sequence would probably feel amazing if I didn't keep getting lost. Again, not the thrilling start I was hoping for.</p>

          
                  </div>
                    
        
          
    
    <div>
          
          
<p>Killing a barnacle by feeding it an explosive barrel is a definite high point. I may have cackled. This is the sort of clever environmental interaction I expected to see from the minds that later made <em>Portal</em>.</p>
<p>Headcrabs, on the other hand, are just obnoxious. My dinky little pea shooter pistol doesn't feel like great protection. What's a rogue physicist gotta do to get a shotgun?</p>

<h2>From airboats to zombies</h2>
<p>After a break, I return armed with a renewed determination to grok this game and, more importantly, with an airboat. For 90 percent of the Water Hazard chapter, I am feeling like a badass. I'm cruising in my watery ride, flying over ramps, and watching a silo collapse overhead. Especially in those rare moments when the 2000s electro jams punctuate my fights, I feel like a true action hero.</p>
<figure>
    
          <figcaption>
        <div>
    
    <p>
      The airboat sequence was divisive in 2004, but this writer enjoyed it.

              <span>
          Credit:

          
          Anna Washenko

                  </span>
          </p>
  </div>
      </figcaption>
      </figure>

<p>Next I reach the Black Mesa East chapter, which is a perfect interlude. The game's approach to world-building is probably the area where my feelings align most closely with those of <em>Half-Life 2</em> veterans. It is spectacular. Heading down into the lab may be the best elevator ride I've taken in a game. Judith is talking science, and outside the shaft, I see humans and vortigaunts conducting fascinating experiments. Small vignettes like those are a perfect way to introduce more information about the rebellion. They give subtle context to a game that doesn't do much to explain itself and doesn't need to.</p>
<p>Also, Dog is the best boy. Seriously, I've seen modern games where the animations didn't have as much personality as when Alyx treats her robot protector like an actual dog, and he shakes in delight. My only sadness is that Dog doesn't accompany me to Ravenholm.</p>

          
                  </div>
                    
        
          
    
    <div>
          
          
<figure>
    
          <figcaption>
        <div>
    
    <p>
      Dog is, in fact, the best boy.

              <span>
          Credit:

          
          Valve

                  </span>
          </p>
  </div>
      </figcaption>
      </figure>

<p>I do wish Dog had come with me to Ravenholm. I learned after the fact that this chapter is one of the most iconic and beloved, but I had the opposite reaction. Survival horror is not my jam. These whirling death traps are sweet, but I hate jump scares, and I don't love any of my weapons for the encounters.</p>
<p>That brings me to something I don't want to say, but in the spirit of journalistic honesty, I must: I don't adore the Gravity Gun. Obviously it was the game's signature creation here and probably what most of you recall most fondly, but I did not fully grasp its potential immediately. Based on the tutorial in Black Mesa East, I assumed it would mostly be a component to puzzle-solving and traversal rather than a key part of combat. I only started using it as a weapon in Ravenholm because I ran out of ammo for everything else.</p>
<p>It's not that I don't get the appeal. Slicing zombies up with a saw blade or bashing them with paint cans is satisfying—no complaints there. But I found the tool inconsistent, which discouraged me from experimenting as much as the developers may have hoped. I'm pretty sure I do as much damage to myself as to enemies trying to lob exploding barrels. I want to be able to fling corpses around and can't (for reasons that became apparent later, but in the moment felt limiting). Later chapters reinforced my uncertainty, when I couldn't pull a car to me, yet a push blast had enough power to overturn the vehicle.</p>
<p>And once again, I had a rough time with navigation. Maybe I was missing what other people would have seen as obvious cues, the way I'm attuned to finding climbing paths marked by color in modern games—controversial as that yellow marking convention may be, its absence is noted when you're struggling to read the environment with a visual language for the game that emphasizes realism over readability. Or maybe I've gotten over-reliant on the tools of the sprawling RPGs I favor these days, where you have a mini-map and quest markers to help you manage all the threads. But for an agonizingly long time, I stared at an electrified fence and wires that seemed to lead to nowhere before realizing that I was supposed to enter the building where Father Grigori first appeared on the balcony. A giant bonfire of corpses out front seemed like a clear 'do not enter' sign, so it didn't occur to me that I could go inside. Alas.</p>

          
                  </div>
                    
        
          
    
    <div>
          
          
<p>Speaking of which, Father Grigori is the best part of the section. He's a total bro, giving me a shotgun at long last. I feel kind of bad when I just abandon him to his murderous flock at the end of the chapter. I hope he survives?</p>
<h2>Familiarity and finding my footing</h2>
<p>The new weapons are coming fast and furious now. I'm impressed at how good the combat feel is. I like the pulse rifle a lot, and that has become my go-to for most long-distance enemies. I wish I could aim down sights, but at least this feels impactful at range. Although I don't usually favor the slow cadence of a revolver in other games, I also enjoy the magnum. The SMG serves well as a workhorse, while the rocket launcher and crossbow are satisfying tools when the right situation arises.</p>
<p>But my favorite weapon, far more than the Gravity Gun, is the shotgun. Especially at point-blank range and into a fast zombie's head. Chef's kiss. Maybe it's my love of <em>Doom (2016)</em> peeking through, but any time I can go charging into a crowd with my shotgun, I'm a happy camper.</p>
<p>While the worldbuilding in <em>Half-Life 2</em> is stellar, I don't think the writing matches that high. Just about every brief encounter with allies starts with someone breathlessly gasping, "Gordon? Gordon Freeman?" It's the sort of repetition that would make for an effective and dangerous drinking game.</p>
<p>I was surprised when I entered another vehicle section. I liked the airboat, even though the chapter ran a touch long, but this dune buggy feels a lot jankier. At least it starts with a gun attached.</p>
<p>I love the idea of this magnet crane puzzle. I wish it didn't control like something from <em>Octodad</em>, but I do get my buggy up out of the sand.</p>

          
                  </div>
                    
        
          
    
    <div>
          
          
<figure>
    
          <figcaption>
        <div>
    
    <p>
      The "floor is lava" sequence involves placing objects with the Gravity Gun to avoid disturbing an army of angry antlions by stepping on the sand.

              <span>
          Credit:

          
          Anna Washenko

                  </span>
          </p>
  </div>
      </figcaption>
      </figure>

<p>Things start turning around for me once I reach the sandy version of 'the floor is lava.' That's a cute idea. Although I keep wanting to rotate objects and have a more controlled placement with the Gravity Gun like I could when I did these kinds of tasks with the Ultrahand ability during <em>The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom</em>. I understand that <em>Half-Life 2</em> crawled so <em>TotK</em> could run, but that knowledge doesn't mean I have a better time using the mechanic. Toward the end of the sequence, I got bored by the slow pace of creating a bridge and just barrelled ahead, willing to face a firefight just to move things along.</p>
<p>At this point, however, things take a decided turn for the better when I get my other favorite weapon of the game: My own antlion army! Commanding them is so fabulously ridiculous. The scene where hordes of antlions leap over high walls to attack gunmen on the towers leading into Nova Prospekt may be my favorite moment so far in the entire game. If this is how all of you felt flinging radiators around with the Gravity Gun back in the day, then I get why you love it so. I'm sure I won't be able to keep this glorious power indefinitely, but I would happily finish the rest of the story with just antlions and a shotgun if they'd let me.</p>
<p>The Nova Prospekt area is the first time I really see a clear line connecting <em>Half-Life 2</em> to <em>Portal</em>. None of the puzzles or characters thus far gave me <em>Portal</em> vibes, but I definitely get them here, especially once turrets come into play. By this point, I'm finally navigating the space with some confidence. That might be the result of logging enough hours or maybe it was just the sense that GLaDOS could start talking to me at any moment. Whatever the reason, I think I'm finding my groove at last.</p>

          
                  </div>
                    
        
          
    
    <div>
          
          
<figure>
    
          <figcaption>
        <div>
    
    <p>
      Nova Prospekt is one of the first areas Valve made when it developed <em>Half-Life 2</em>, so it's not surprising it bears a lot of similarity to environments and vibes in both the original <em>Half-Life</em> and in <em>Portal</em>.

              <span>
          Credit:

          
          Anna Washenko

                  </span>
          </p>
  </div>
      </figcaption>
      </figure>

<p>Somehow I am not surprised by Judith's sudden but inevitable betrayal in this chapter. Alyx not getting along with her in the Black Mesa East chapter felt pretty telling. But then she's just going to let Judith enter teleport coordinates unsupervised? Alyx, you're supposed to be smart!</p>
<p>What do you know—now Judith has re-kidnapped Eli. Color me shocked.</p>

<h2>Onward and upward to the end</h2>
<p>It's nice having human minions. They're no antlions, but I like how the world has shifted to a real uprising. It reminds me of the big charge at the end of <em>Mass Effect 3</em>, running and gunning through a bombed-out city with bug-like baddies overhead.</p>
<p>Snipers are not a welcome addition to the enemy roster. Not sure why Barney's whining so much. You could throw some grenades, too, my dude.</p>
<p>Barney tags along with my minions as we reach the Overwatch Nexus. Destroying floor turrets is probably the first time I've struggled with combat. These are the least precise grenades of all time. Once we make it through the interior sequence, it's time to face down the striders. I can't imagine how you'd play this section bringing down the swarm of them on a harder difficulty. My health takes a beating as I run around the wreckage desperately looking for ammo reloads and medkits. In theory, this is probably a great setpiece, but I'm just stressed out. Things go a little better once the combat is paired with traversal, and the final showdown on the roof does feel like a gratifying close to a boss fight.</p>
<p>On to the Citadel. Why on earth would I get into one of these pods? That's a terrible idea. But apparently that's what I'm going to do. I hope I'm not supposed to be navigating this pod in any way, because I'm just taking in the vibes. It's another transit moment with glimpses into what the enemies have been getting up to while the rebellion rages outside. It's eerie; I like it.</p>

          
                  </div>
                    
        
          
    
    <div>
          
          
<figure>
    
          <figcaption>
        <div>
    
    <p>
      Battling the striders as the game moves toward its finale.

              <span>
          Credit:

          
          Anna Washenko

                  </span>
          </p>
  </div>
      </figcaption>
      </figure>

<p>The Gravity Gun is the core of <em>Half-Life 2</em>, so it makes sense that a supercharged version is all I have for the final push. I appreciate that I can use it to fling bodies, but my reaction is a little muted since this was an idea I'd had from the start. But I do find the new angle of sucking up energy orbs to be pretty rad.</p>
<p>I arrive in Dr. Breen's office, and it looks grim for our heroes. Judith redeeming herself surprises me more than her betrayal, which is nice. When he runs off, I'm mentally preparing myself as I chase him for a final boss showdown. Surely, something extra bonkers with the Gravity Gun awaits me. I climb the teleportation tower, I pelt Breen's device with energy orbs, I'm waiting for the other shoe to drop, and…</p>
<p>Huh?</p>
<h2>Context is everything</h2>
<p>In the moment, I was torn between feeling that the opaque ending was genius and that it was an absolute cop-out. It was certainly not how I expected the game to end.</p>
<p>But on reflection, that wound up being a fitting final thought as the credits rolled, because I think 'expectations' were at the heart of my conflicted reactions to finally playing <em>Half-Life 2</em>. I've rarely felt so much pressure to have a particular response. I wanted to love this game. I wanted to share the awe that so many players feel for it. I wanted to have an epic experience that matched the epic legacy <em>Half-Life 2</em> has in gaming history.</p>
<p>I didn't.</p>
<p>Instead, I had whiplash, swinging between moments of delight and stretches of being stymied or even downright pissed off. I was tense, often dreading rather than eagerly awaiting each next twist. Aside from a handful of high points, I'm not sure I'd say playing <em>Half-Life 2</em> was fun.</p>

          
                  </div>
                    
        
          
    
    <div>

        
        <div>
          
          
<p>As I mentioned at the start, the big question I felt I had to answer was whether <em>Half-Life 2</em> felt relevant today or whether it only holds up under the rosy glow of nostalgia. And my answer is, "It depends." As an enigmatic person once said, "The right man in the wrong place can make all the difference in the world." It's all in the context.</p>
<p>Moments that were jaw-dropping in 2004 have less impact for someone like me who's played the many titles that copied, standardized, and perfected <em>Half-Life 2</em>'s revelations. Intellectually, I understand that the Gravity Gun was a literal game-changer and that a physics engine deployed at this scale was unheard of. But funnily enough, a modern player is even less likely to see those innovations as so, well, innovative when a game has as much polish as <em>Half-Life 2</em> does. <em>Half-Life 2</em> has almost no rough edges in the execution. Everything works the way it was intended.</p>
<p>Since that polish means the new ideas don't feel like experiments, and since I've seen them in other games in the intervening years, they don't register as notable.</p>
<p>Just as you don't need to be a fan of Aristotle's Poetics to appreciate drama, you don't need to love <em>Half-Life 2</em> to appreciate its legacy. As a fun game to play, whether it holds up will come down to you and your context. However, as a showcase of the technology of the time and a masterclass in world-building, yes, <em>Half-Life 2</em> holds up today.</p>


          
                  </div>

                  
          








  <p>
    <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2024/11/i-played-half-life-2-for-the-first-time-this-year-heres-how-it-went/#comments" title="51 comments">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 80 80"><defs><clipPath id="bubble-zero_svg__a"><path fill="none" stroke-width="0" d="M0 0h80v80H0z"></path></clipPath><clipPath id="bubble-zero_svg__b"><path fill="none" stroke-width="0" d="M0 0h80v80H0z"></path></clipPath></defs><g clip-path="url(#bubble-zero_svg__a)"><g fill="currentColor" clip-path="url(#bubble-zero_svg__b)"><path d="M80 40c0 22.09-17.91 40-40 40S0 62.09 0 40 17.91 0 40 0s40 17.91 40 40"></path><path d="M40 40 .59 76.58C-.67 77.84.22 80 2.01 80H40z"></path></g></g></svg>
    51 Comments
  </a>
      </p>





  
              </div>
  </article>


  


  

  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SteamWorld Creators Announce Incoming Layoffs And Focus On Third-Party Games]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/steamworld-creators-announce-incoming-layoffs-and-focus-on-third-party-games/1100-6527791/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/steamworld-creators-announce-incoming-layoffs-and-focus-on-third-party-games.1036869/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/steamworld-creators-announce-incoming-layoffs-and-focus-on-third-party-games/1100-6527791/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6527791">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Thunderful Games, the developer of the SteamWorld series, has announced 80-100 layoffs at the company and a reshifting focus for third-party games. In a <a href="https://thunderfulgroup.com/news-room/press-releases/2024-11-14-thunderful-group-implements-strategic-restructuring-program-doubling-down-on-third-party-game-publishing-and-scaling-back-internal-development-resulting-in-write-downs-of-220-240-msek" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">press release</a>, the company said the layoffs were part of a "restructuring." Along with the layoffs, an unspecified number of game projects were officially canceled.</p><p>CEO of Thunderful Martin Walfisz said that the decision came with regret, but this isn't the first time the company has seen layoffs this year. Back in January, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/indie-publisher-thunderful-to-lay-off-20-of-its-workforce/1100-6520404/" data-ref-id="1100-6520404">Thunderful saw 20% of the company's staff laid off</a> in a similar "restructuring," something that Walfisz acknowledges and saw as unavoidable.</p><p>"It is regrettable to announce a second restructuring of Thunderful in less than a year, but we unfortunately see no other alternatives in order to ensure the Group’s long-term sustainability and resilience," Walfisz said. "The strategic move towards publishing games from external partners allows us to reduce fixed costs, increase flexibility, and better control our cash flow. We have many talented and dedicated employees, and it is with great regret that we are forced to part ways."</p><p>According to the press release, the projections for money saved from these reductions will gain 80-90 MSEK (approximately $7.3-8.2 million), but it doesn't expect the majority of these savings to take effect until the first quarter of 2025. The restructuring program will be implemented immediately.</p><p>As for refocusing on external games, the company said that it hopes it will help reduce fixed costs and allow for a higher turnout rate, but still retain some internal development capacity, which includes games like the SteamWorld series and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/lost-in-random-review-six-appeal/1900-6417731/" data-ref-id="1900-6417731">Lost in Random</a>.</p><p>Thunderful's recent release, SteamWorld Heist 2, was released back in August and <a href="https://www.metacritic.com/search/steamworld%20heist%202/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">earned rather good reviews</a>, including at GameSpot where it received a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/steamworld-heist-2-review-like-clockwork/1900-6418264/" data-ref-id="1900-6418264">9/10</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Patch Notes #6: Pokemon TCG Pocket is my favorite gateway drug]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/mobile/patch-notes-6-pokemon-tcg-pocket-is-my-favorite-gateway-drug</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/patch-notes-6-pokemon-tcg-pocket-is-my-favorite-gateway-drug.1036866/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/mobile/patch-notes-6-pokemon-tcg-pocket-is-my-favorite-gateway-drug<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="captioned-content" data-testid="featured-image"><p><span>Pokemon TCG Pocket artwork via The Pokémon Company</span></p></div><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">I'm doing something a little bit different today. After vacationing in Japan for a couple of weeks and spending very little time thinking about video games or the wider world, I returned to an industry still besieged by rampant layoffs and CEO shithousery. It was a predictable and rather depressing plummet back towards reality. Combine that with the foul news that Hannibal Lecter's biggest sycophant will be returning to the White House in 2025, and, well, I didn't quite have the energy or motivation to write this column last week.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">My initial idea was to break down why the </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/production/netflix-games-exec-prepares-bowl-of-word-salad-to-announce-new-role-as-vp-of-genai-for-games">perpetual cacophony of generative AI word chunder</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> has filled me with despair, but I figured there's enough anger and frustration in the world right now. Instead, I want to talk about a wholesome series of events that shows how video games can send positivity rippling throughout the cosmos.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">But first, some quick context:</span><span data-testid="content-text"><span> </span></span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Pokemon TCG Pocket</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> is doing the business right now. The mobile card battler has </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/pokemon-tcg-pocket-has-topped-30-million-downloads-worldwide">surpassed 30 million downloads</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> in a couple of weeks and has likely earned a fair bit of brass by limiting people to a meager two free booster packs per day. I've yet to drop cash on the title, but I'm absolutely drinking the sugary sweet cool aid.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">To ward off the insatiable urge to rip open virtual boosters, I threw myself into </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>TCG Pocket's</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> multiplayer mode. After building my own custom decks (I'm running a fast-hitting Pikachu EX setup), I got stuck in and to my surprise began racking up plenty of wins. I was, in my humble opinion, a latent tactical genius who's calling in life was to become the ultimate Pokemon trainer. Unimpeded by self-doubt or any notion of reality, I decided my recent success within </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>TCG Pocket</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> would justify a splurge on the real thing: actual, tangible, mouth-watering Pokemon Cards.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">You see, in Japan, Pokemon cards were a dime a dozen. Pop into any konbini and you'll see booster packs loitering by the counter, begging to be taken home and tenderly torn asunder. Ideally while scoffing a custard bun and guzzling Pocari Sweat. I happily obliged. It's easy to succumb to such indulgent whims when you're half a world away.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Hard cut back to damp, miserable Blighty and I told myself it was over. I'd slide my Japanese cards in a binder and make a clean break. But before I could close the door on that fleeting fixation, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>TCG Pocket</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> quickly pulled me back in.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">And so, filled with purpose and a desire to see if I could replicate my </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>TCG Pocket</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> success in the real world, I ambled down to my local tabletop game store to ask for advice on how to start playing Pokemon TCG proper. I was told to pre-order a Surging Sparks Elite Trainer Box (which comes with competition-legal dice, a bunch of boosters, damage counters, and everything else you need to start battling) and the upcoming Charizard EX League Battle Deck. I was also told to head back down to the store on Monday evening to check out the weekly Pokemon League and learn the ropes. Good shouts all round.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Of course, inserting yourself into a new space without any kind of social support can be a nerve-wracking experience at the best of times. Would I fit in or immediately be outed as an upstart pretender. Fresh meat for the salivating, card-toting wolves. Eventually, I pushed my flickering anxieties aside and returned, but only after cobbling together a haphazard 60-card deck that I felt, at the very least, would be able to knock out a few 'mons before being overpowered.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">When I arrived (rather sheepishly) on Monday evening, the players were already downstairs excitedly discussing their latest pulls, searching for fabled illustration rares, and partaking in a few practice bouts in preparation for the real thing. I wondered how to go about introducing myself to what seemed like a rather tight-knit group, but before that thought could become even remotely corporeal I was excitedly ushered into the fold.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Within moments of being initiated, I was made to feel like a part of the furniture. It was as if I'd been going there for years. A veteran player insisted I take some of their cards to bolster my deck (a quick practice game unearthed more than a few deficiencies) and taught me how to hone my approach and practice good tournament etiquette. During the tournament, each opponent I sat opposite graciously answered my flurry of (no doubt rudimentary) questions and took the time to carefully explain the minutiae of certain plays.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">I was absolutely battered on occasion, but there are lessons in defeat and I was eager to learn. I played four games overall, losing two, drawing one, and winning another—with that victory coming at the very end of the evening. It was the perfect cap on a wholesome foray into the unknown. The small acts of kindness I experienced sent me home feeling marginally less cynical about the world, and that's a staggering achievement given just how utterly fucked everything is at the minute.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">In an industry that appears to be sinking under a tidal wave of corporate and neo-political bullshit, it can often feel like we're slipping under the surface while blindly scrambling for a life raft. There's a lot to be cynical about right now—and that skepticism is vital in the face of an industry that appears to grow more uncaring by the minute—but video games can still manifest positivity and foster real connections, sometimes just not in the ways you might expect.&nbsp;</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Status Report: The headlines that matter">Status Report: The headlines that matter</h2><div data-component="basic-list"><ul data-testid="basic-list-unordered"><li></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/production/zenimax-union-workers-strike-in-protest-of-microsoft-remote-work-and-outsourcing-policies">ZeniMax union workers strike in protest of Microsoft remote work and outsourcing policies </a></span><span data-testid="content-text">// A huge number of ZeniMax staffers aren't happy with some of the decisions being made by their parent company Microsoft. This week, hundreds of unionized staff staged a one-day strike to protest the Xbox maker's remote working policy and decision to continue outsourcing work on the down low. ZeniMax Workers United-CWA members hope the strike will convince Microsoft to return to the bargaining table with renewed focus.</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/thunderful-is-restructuring-its-publishing-division-and-cutting-even-more-jobs">Thunderful is restructuring its publishing division and cutting even more jobs</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> // Earlier this week, Swedish conglomerate Thunderful announced a second restructuring plan in the space of a year. This time, the company is cutting between 80 to 100 jobs and discounting some internal game projects so it can focus on third-party publishing. Last time around, it axed 20 percent of its workforce. Thunderful CEO said the group needs to downsized to deliver "sustainability and resilience." Now, where have we heard that before?&nbsp;</span></p></div></li></ul></div><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Feature Creep: Originals and interviews for the discerning reader">Feature Creep: Originals and interviews for the discerning reader</h2><div data-component="basic-list"><ul data-testid="basic-list-unordered"><li></li><li></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/what-finji-ceo-bekah-saltsman-would-update-about-her-gdc-talk-on-indie-pitching">Up-to-date indie pitching tips from Finji CEO Bekah Saltsman</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> // The game industry moves quickly. So much so that pitching advice that was dished out a few years ago can quickly become outdated. In service of keeping things fresh, then, we caught up with Finji CEO Bekah Saltsman to&nbsp; learn how indies should be pitching publishers in 2024. Her first piece of advice? Don't include your budget in your pitch document.</span></p></div></li></ul></div><div data-component="basic-list"><ul data-testid="basic-list-unordered"><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/audio/reflections-on-my-score-for-tactical-breach-wizards">Reflections on my score for Tactical Breach Wizards</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> // Composer Robert Arzola whips back the curtain to share an behind-the-scenes look at the creative process, inspirations, experiences, and challenges that shaped their score for Tactical Breach Wizards.</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/the-overdesign-trap-of-game-design">The overdesign trap of game design</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> // In this featured blog, Josh Bycer explains why over-designing your game can result in an "unfocused mess" and suggests designers need to dial in on two distinct areas.</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/designing-a-clunky-combat-system-on-purpose-in-crow-country">Designing a clunky combat system on purpose in Crow Country</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> // It might be considered barmy to pitch your own combat system as 'clunky,' but that's precisely what </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Crow Country</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> creative director Adam Vian set out to achieve. In his featured blog, Vian seeks to understand what the word 'clunky' actually means in the context of an old-school horror game and why he spend so much time attempting to replicate that very specific feeling.&nbsp;</span></p></div></li></ul></div></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">News Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer news editor Chris Kerr is an award-winning journalist and reporter with over a decade of experience in the game industry. His byline has appeared in notable print and digital publications including Edge, Stuff, Wireframe, International Business Times, and&nbsp;</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="http://pocketgamer.biz/">PocketGamer.biz</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. Throughout his career, Chris has covered major industry events including GDC, PAX Australia, Gamescom, Paris Games Week, and Develop Brighton. He has featured on the judging panel at The Develop Star Awards on multiple occasions and appeared on BBC Radio 5 Live to discuss breaking news.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lego teases new Horizon-themed set on the way]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/lego-teases-new-horizon-themed-set-on-the-way</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/lego-teases-new-horizon-themed-set-on-the-way.1036863/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/lego-teases-new-horizon-themed-set-on-the-way<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>Fresh Aloy minifig pops up in Lego Horizon Adventures video.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Screenshot-2024-11-15-at-15.03.57.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Guerrilla / Lego</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>Fans think they've spotted something exciting in the latest <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/lego-horizon-adventures">Lego Horizon Adventures</a> teaser, suggesting a new Horizon-themed set may be on the way.</p>
<p>In a new behind-the-scenes video in which Lego Horizon Adventures creators "share their experience of building Aloy's world brick by brick", eagle-eyed fans realised that the Aloy minifig shown right at the end of the teaser is not quite like any we've seen before.</p>
<p>You can see the minifig concerned at the nine-minute mark in the video embedded below:</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="LEGO Horizon Adventures - Building Aloy's World: Brick by Brick | PS5 &amp; PC Games" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/66-qPPjW-Ig?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>LEGO Horizon Adventures - Building Aloy's World: Brick by Brick | PS5 &amp; PC Games</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/66-qPPjW-Ig?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/66-qPPjW-Ig?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>LEGO Horizon Adventures - Building Aloy's World: Brick by Brick | PS5 &amp; PC Games.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=66-qPPjW-Ig" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>As posited by <a href="https://www.thebrickfan.com/lego-teases-future-lego-horizon-sets/">The Brick Fan</a>, this minifig appears to have an "updated printing" from the Aloy included in the Tallneck <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/horizon-forbidden-west">Horizon Forbidden West</a> Lego set released a couple of years ago.</p>
<p>Whilst this alone in no way implies a new Lego set is <em>definitely</em> on the way, the new Aloy variant isn't the only brick-shaped leak we've seen recently. Reliable Lego leaker Clay_Bricks goes even further, not only revealing that the set will feature Aloy &amp; Varl vs Shell-Walker &amp; Sawtooth, we've even got a kit number and a release date: 77037 and March 2025.</p>
<p>In the slideshow appended to the reddit post, we get another peek at that hitherto unknown Aloy minifig:</p>
<blockquote data-embed-height="740"><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Legoleak/comments/1grdiq9/horizon_77037_aloy_varl_vs_shellwalker_sawtooth/">Horizon: 77037 Aloy &amp; Varl vs Shell-Walker &amp; Sawtooth (from fateful_04, images from LEGO)</a><br> by<a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/Clay_Bricks/">u/Clay_Bricks</a> in<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Legoleak/">Legoleak</a></blockquote><p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span></p>
<p>"I don't <em>need</em> to buy every Horizon set I <em>don't</em> need to buy every Horizon set I don't need to buy <em>every</em> Horizon set I don't <em>need</em> to buy every Horizon set <em>I</em> don't need to buy every Horizon set…" said one particularly happy fan on the Lego leak <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Legoleak/comments/1grdiq9/comment/lx50rne/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button">subreddit</a>.</p>
<p>As for Lego Horizon Adventures, we just awarded the game two out of five stars.</p>
<p>"It's a decidedly joyless kind of game, the sort that's better to look at than actually play with, and one that does little to bridge the gap between its two main subjects," Katharine wrote in <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/lego-horizon-adventures-review">Eurogamer's Lego Horizon Adventures review</a>. "I still don't know why it exists or who it's for, and there's little evidence to suggest that Guerrilla or Gobo know the answer either."</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Star Wars: The Old Republic To Get Major Update Named Galactic Threads]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/star-wars-the-old-republic-to-get-major-update-named-galactic-threads/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/star-wars-the-old-republic-to-get-major-update-named-galactic-threads.1036839/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/star-wars-the-old-republic-to-get-major-update-named-galactic-threads/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>In a special developer live stream today, the <a href="https://wccftech.com/mass-effect-still-in-pre-production-bioware-passes-star-wars-the-old-republic-new-dev/">Star Wars: The Old Republic team</a> announced the next major update that will be arriving to the MMORPG, with the update being titled Game Update 7.6 - Galactic Threads. This is set to be a relatively significant update, as a lot of new features and content will be added, as well as character art modernization. The update will begin to roll out in December to players across the globe, with the story missions arriving in Star Wars: The Old Republic in 2025.</p>
<p>Star Wars: The Old Republic was first released in 2011, and since then has evolved a fair amount, with there being plenty of content for Star Wars fans to get stuck into. One of the most important features being added in the Galactic Threads update is the modernization of the character and planet art. This is something that has been in the works for a while, but updating all of the models and planets is very time consuming. While the updates on modernizing the graphics are slow, players will be able to see texture changes to models such as the Human, Chiss, Cyborg, and Miralukan, bringing improved fidelity to the game. To showcase the changes that have been made, the SWTOR team has released a YouTube video that shows off the graphical updates they have been working on.</p>
<p><iframe title="Planet and Character Model Modernization coming to Game Update 7.6" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/WN7JD4pTpks?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Of course, there is a ton more coming to the game aside from just this update. This includes new story missions that carry on straight from the Desperate Defiance storyline. Of course, these missions won't be rolled out until 2025, but players will at least be given time to get excited about them.</p>
<p>Additionally, the update will add a new boss fight called The Propagator Core XR-53, a new lair boss that will launch in Story and Veteran difficulties. Alongside this, there will be brand-new Dynamic Encounters, world content dedicated to immersing players in the exploration of the worlds they inhabit. The Dynamic Encounters will vary, depending on where you are and what you are doing. This could include having to take out Hidden Chain forces or herding together Banthas, who escaped. If you want to get stuck in, these encounters will first be arriving on Hoth and Tatooine, offering a bounty of rewards for players to earn.</p>
<p>If you want to know every last detail about what you can expect about the upcoming update to Star Wars: The Old Republic, <a href="https://www.swtor.com/info/news/article/20241114-0" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the website</a> has all of the info about what you can expect and some of the smaller features being added to the MMORPG.</p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GameMaker 25th Anniversary Celebrations Include Free Steam Game]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/gamemaker-25th-anniversary</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gamemaker-25th-anniversary-celebrations-include-free-steam-game.1036836/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/gamemaker-25th-anniversary<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Game creation engine GameMaker is 25 years old today, and to celebrate, the software suite's developers have released a free game that you can play on Steam right now.</p>

<p>As you might expect,&nbsp;<em>GameMaker 25th Anniversary&nbsp;</em>is a management sim in which you must manage the development house creating GameMaker. Whoa, recursive.</p>

<p>You'll have to keep your employees happy, choose which features to add to your game creation engine, and upgrade your office in order to keep worker productivity at a maximum. Along the way, you'll also collect "posters based on the history of GameMaker".</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/gamemaker-25th-anniversary-free-game-release.jpg?itok=H1djkgP1 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/gamemaker-25th-anniversary-free-game-release.jpg?itok=yitBjc2c 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>GameMaker 25th Anniversary&nbsp;</em>asks how you would do managing your very own game creation suite.</figcaption></figure><p>Creator YoYo Games (which is, believe it or not, also the company responsible for making GameMaker) describes&nbsp;<em>GameMaker 25th Anniversary&nbsp;</em>as a "minigame-filled, top-down management and strategy game".</p>

<p>The game has a lot in common with the likes of&nbsp;<em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/game-dev-story-other-kairosoft-games-now-on-steam" rel="nofollow">Game Dev Story</a>&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>Game Dev Tycoon</em>, although this one's based more around creating creation software itself rather than the games made with said software.</p>

<p>Of course,&nbsp;<em>GameMaker 25th Anniversary&nbsp;</em>was also made in GameMaker, and YoYo Games says it intends to make the source code assets and project files free to GameMaker users soon in the form of a template for the software kit.</p>

<p>It's all part of celebrating GameMaker's 25th year on our storied planet. You can read a blog post detailing what else YoYo has in the pipeline for GameMaker as part of these anniversary celebrations <a href="https://gamemaker.io/en/blog/gamemaker-25" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">right here if you're interested</a>.</p>




<p>If you're wondering exactly what GameMaker is, it's a game creation toolkit that specializes in creating 2D games across all current major platforms.</p>

<p>Some of the games that have been made using GameMaker include all-time classic&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/games/undertale" rel="nofollow"><em>Undertale</em></a>, cozy farming sim&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/games/fields-of-mistria" rel="nofollow"><em>Fields of Mistria</em></a>, and ultra-violent arcade action game&nbsp;<em>Hotline Miami</em>, to name but a few.</p>

<p>GameMaker is free to use on a non-commercial basis; the transition from paid to free was made last year, at which point YoYo <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/gamemaker-free-non-commercial-use" rel="nofollow">also seemingly took a swipe at Unity</a>, which was, at the time, going through a <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/unity-ceo-john-riccitiello-retiring-after-runtime-fee-controversy" rel="nofollow">major controversy surrounding a runtime fee</a> for developers.</p>

<p>You can download GameMaker and get started with it via the tool's <a href="https://gamemaker.io/en" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">official website</a>.&nbsp;<em>GameMaker 25th Anniversary&nbsp;</em>is currently available to play <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3219220/GameMaker_25th_Anniversary/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">for free on PC via Steam</a>.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox Promises More Gaming Consoles In The Future And Throws Shade At PS5 Pro]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/ps5-pro-xbox-microsoft-phil-spencer-new-console-1851700253</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/xbox-promises-more-gaming-consoles-in-the-future-and-throws-shade-at-ps5-pro.1036830/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/ps5-pro-xbox-microsoft-phil-spencer-new-console-1851700253<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Microsoft’s latest holiday <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2024/11/14/this-is-an-xbox/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2024/11/14/this-is-an-xbox/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">marketing campaign</a></span> is all about how you can play Xbox games even without the actual console. “<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.threads.net/@jeffgerstmann/post/DCW3Z2gu-wb/this-is-an-xbox&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.threads.net/@jeffgerstmann/post/DCW3Z2gu-wb/this-is-an-xbox" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">This is an Xbox</a></span>,” the slogan reads as it lists laptops, smartphones, VR headsets, and other platform-agnostic devices. But despite doubling-down on the virtues of “<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/starfield-xbox-series-x-s-pc-play-anywhere-game-pass-1850695407&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/starfield-xbox-series-x-s-pc-play-anywhere-game-pass-1850695407">play anywhere</a></span>,” the company is still committed to shipping new Xboxes in the future, even if it decided to skip the pricey PS5-Pro-style, mid-generation refresh. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196181" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="The Best Reveals From The Game Awards 2023" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="180" data-playlist="196181,196230,197298" data-current="196181"><div><p>The Best Reveals From The Game Awards 2023</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196181/196181_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196181/196181_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196181/196181_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196181/196181_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21718.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p> “We’ll definitely do more consoles in the future, and other devices,” Microsoft Gaming CEO Phil Spencer <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.rollingstone.com/culture/rs-gaming/xbox-console-future-cloud-ceo-phil-spencer-1235166597/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.rollingstone.com/culture/rs-gaming/xbox-console-future-cloud-ceo-phil-spencer-1235166597/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">told<em> Rolling Stone</em></a></span> in a new interview. While not shocking, the reassurance comes after this fall’s big holiday Xbox console exclusive, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/indiana-jones-great-circle-bethesda-footage-1851628386&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/indiana-jones-great-circle-bethesda-footage-1851628386"><em>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle</em></a></span>, announced a PS5 port coming just a few months later in the spring. The multiplatform push has had some fans  doubting the platform’s future, especially when Spencer says things like there’s “<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/xbox-boss-spencer-halo-ps5-switch-exclusive-no-red-line-1851697549&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/xbox-boss-spencer-halo-ps5-switch-exclusive-no-red-line-1851697549">no red line</a></span>” when it comes to bringing first-party games to rival consoles, including the next <em>Halo</em>. </p><p>Xbox president Sarah Bond <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/xbox-podcast-consoles-handheld-hardware-next-gen-1851261822&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/xbox-podcast-consoles-handheld-hardware-next-gen-1851261822">previously teased</a></span> that Microsoft’s next Xbox would be the “largest technical leap” players have ever seen in a console generation. And this week Spencer confirmed that the company is working on a dedicated PC gaming handheld, though it’s still a few years off. Previous leaks pegged a new Xbox console coming in late 2026, and while plans can always change, it certainly sounds like Microsoft remains all-in on hardware for the next 5-10 years, even if the success of those devices isn’t ultimately propelled first and foremost by exclusive franchises like <em>The Elder Scrolls </em>and <em>Gears of War</em>.</p><p>And what of Microsoft skipping the mid-cycle refresh? Unlike last time when its Xbox Series X and the PS4 Pro went head-to-head, Sony’s spiffed-up, $700 gaming rig has launched uncontested this year. Spencer’s answer is that the improvements just don’t warrant an incremental update this time around. “We think about hardware that can create unique value for our players or creators on our platform,” he told <em>Rolling Stone</em>. “We don’t need to do incremental hardware for our own benefit.”</p><p>He continued, “Does a new device really give you a unique experience onscreen in some way? [It’s] less like the old days, going from the original Xbox to 360; that was standard definition to high definition. Now, [it’s] harder to show the benefits.” That echoed a comment he made to <em>Bloomberg</em> this week as well about reaching new audiences. “We’re not going to grow the market with $1,000 consoles,” Spencer said. </p><p>Those implied shots at the PS5 Pro come after months of debate about whether Sony’s second-most-expensive console ever seems worth it for slightly better resolutions at higher framerates. While experts and diehard enthusiasts are <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/ps5-pro-who-is-it-for-review-worth-it-impressions-4k60-1851691112&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/ps5-pro-who-is-it-for-review-worth-it-impressions-4k60-1851691112">singing the praises</a></span> of the device for improving games like <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.eurogamer.net/digitalfoundry-2024-final-fantasy-7-rebirth-on-ps5-pro-delivers-huge-image-quality-improvements-at-60fps&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/digitalfoundry-2024-final-fantasy-7-rebirth-on-ps5-pro-delivers-huge-image-quality-improvements-at-60fps" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Final Fantasy VII Rebirth</em></a></span>, others have noted that even being a little too far away from the screen or dealing with daytime glare from windows all but cancels out that upgrade. </p><p>Of course, if Sony is struggling to showcase meaningful improvements with new hardware that’s $300 more than the all-digital PS5 was at launch, how exactly are we going to get the “largest technical leap you’ve ever seen” out of the next Xbox at an affordable price? Maybe machine learning, generative AI, and cloud computing, which Microsoft is currently all-in on, will provide a unique solution to that dilemma. </p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Blizzard Hiring For An Open-World Shooter Game]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/blizzard-hiring-for-an-open-world-shooter-game/1100-6527790/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/blizzard-hiring-for-an-open-world-shooter-game.1036827/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/blizzard-hiring-for-an-open-world-shooter-game/1100-6527790/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6527790">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Blizzard is hiring for an unannounced upcoming open-world shooter game. A job ad posted on November 13 revealed this, though the requisition doesn't have too many details about what the game is.</p><p>The<a href="https://careers.blizzard.com/global/en/job/R024230/Associate-Design-Director-Innovation-Unannounced-Game" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow"> job ad for the Associate Design Director, Innovation</a> says this person will be the "vision holder and owner of key strategic innovations" for the upcoming unannounced "open-world shooter game."</p><p>The job calls for someone to help implement strategies that have "shown potential but have not yet permeated the AAA space." The successful candidate will work with Blizzard's engineering, art, and audio teams to help guide the project from concept to release. This wording specifically suggests whatever this game is, it might be early in development.</p><p>According to the job listing (<a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/following-starcraft-reports-blizzard-is-hiring-for-an-open-world-shooter-game/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">via VGC</a>), a successful candidate can expect to earn a minimum annual salary of $124,400, with the potential of reaching $230,300.</p><p>This job ad was only posted this week, but journalist Jason Schreier's new book, Play Nice: The Rise, Fall, and Future of Blizzard Entertainment, contained a passage mentioning that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/blizzard-is-reportedly-trying-to-make-a-starcraft-shooter-again/1100-6526763/" data-ref-id="1100-6526763">a StarCraft shooter is, or was, in development at Blizzard</a>. Whether or not this newly posted job ad is connected to that is unknown.</p><p>The rumored StarCraft shooter was said to be led by Dan Hay, the former Ubisoft and Far Cry veteran who joined Blizzard as vice president and general manager in 2022.</p><p>As part of the iterative nature of game development, Blizzard <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/blizzard-cancels-new-game-in-development-for-two-y/1100-6467418/" data-ref-id="1100-6467418">cancels about 50% of the games it works on</a>, so whatever new Blizzard shooter is in development, it's not guaranteed to release. In January this year, Microsoft announced that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/blizzards-untitled-survival-game-has-been-canceled-after-president-leaves-report/1100-6520603/" data-ref-id="1100-6520603">Blizzard had canceled its survival game</a>, codenamed Odyssey, with some staffers <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/blizzard-is-reportedly-trying-to-make-a-starcraft-shooter-again/1100-6526763/" data-ref-id="1100-6526763">moving over to an incubation project that was said to be a StarCraft shooter.</a></p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What We Played – Lego Horizon Adventures, Max Mustard & Sorry, We’re Closed]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/11/15/what-we-played-lego-horizon-adventures-max-mustard-sorry-were-closed/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/what-we-played-%E2%80%93-lego-horizon-adventures-max-mustard-sorry-we%E2%80%99re-closed.1036812/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/11/15/what-we-played-lego-horizon-adventures-max-mustard-sorry-were-closed/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>It’s been slower going than I’d hoped with the <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/ps5-pro">PS5 Pro’s</a> enhanced lineup of games, as I wrangle together all the video clips and comparison points I need. I’m close to completing our Insomniac games round-up though, and I’m convinced that they’re the single best development studio out there this generation. Who else has managed to deliver three games in four years, pushing the boundaries for console graphics and world building each time, and reliably returned to previous releases to keep on delivering new tech options? They’re at it again with PS5 Pro, and long may it continue!</p>

<p>We’ll start off with <strong>Dom</strong>, who turned in our <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/11/13/lego-horizon-adventures-review/">review of Lego Horizon Adventures</a>, which wasn’t quite on the level of TT Games’ series, but certainly looks absolutely gorgeous. He’s joined that up with more Metaphor: Refantazio, and he’s been on a trip to play a mystery game. More on that soonish?</p>
<p><strong>Gamoc</strong> has spent this week playing the curiously titled <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/11/14/max-mustard-review/">Max Mustard</a> on PSVR 2, which is surprisingly not a game about a hotdog stall that’s run out of ketchup. He’s also played Phasmophobia with his sister, and found that he really likes it now that he’s figured out more about how it works.</p>


<p>It’s been most Black Ops 6 for <strong>Jim</strong>, now that Season One is live, and he’s still having a great time with it. He’s also returned to New World: Aeternum and is approaching the endgame and PvP content that waits after level 60 &nbsp;– “It’s the most fun I’ve had playing a console MMO since Final Fantasy XIV and it’s good to see just how populated the world is, even if it means getting my ass handed to me in PvP zones.”</p>
<p>3D Don’t Die Mr Robot is, according to <strong>Aran</strong>, exactly what it sounds like. “It is a 3D revision of the original Don’t Die Mr Robot, and my full review should be out next week.”</p>
<p>While <strong>Steve</strong> has also played some 3D Don’t Die Mr Robot, as well as an early build of Soulframe (from the makers of Warframe), Steve reviewed “the effortlessly cool and sexy <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/11/14/sorry-were-closed-review/">Sorry, We’re Closed</a>, a game that takes the bones of a survival horror and reinvigorates them into something that feels fresh.”</p>

<p>And finally, <strong>Tuffcub</strong> apologised for playing Destiny 2, while <strong>Ade’s</strong> real world gaming adventure of Moving House went very well, but he now has the&nbsp;unpacking, painting, and sorting DLC to do. Maybe not quite in that order.</p>
<p><em>Now then, what have you played?</em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Avowed PC Specs Revealed Ahead of February Release]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/avowed-pc-specs</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/avowed-pc-specs-revealed-ahead-of-february-release.1036809/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/avowed-pc-specs<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Obsidian and Xbox have quietly revealed the&nbsp;<em>Avowed&nbsp;</em>PC specs you'll need to run the upcoming first-person RPG, and they're relatively permissive, although it's likely you'll want a good rig to get the best out of this one.</p>

<p>The specs appeared yesterday on the game's Steam page without much fanfare from Obsidian itself, and since they're listed on Steam, you're only getting two presets: Minimum and Recommended, as is Steam's custom.</p>

<p>The minimum specs are pretty basic, but it's likely that you won't get much more than 30fps or so at 1080p resolution if you're running a rig with the minimum settings. Recommended users can likely expect a smoother experience, as usual.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/avowed-pc-specs-bear.jpg?itok=OB38gN88 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/avowed-pc-specs-bear.jpg?itok=UgWldcl9 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Avowed&nbsp;</em>will need a decent PC to run it at Recommended specs.</figcaption></figure><p>Both of&nbsp;<em>Avowed</em>'s spec presets on Steam will need 16GB of RAM, Windows 10 or 11 with updates installed, and at least 75GB of file space, which is <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-300gb" rel="nofollow">pretty reasonable</a> by modern game standards. You'll also want to install DirectX 12.</p>

<p>The game's Minimum settings will require either an Intel Core i5-8400 or an AMD Ryzen 5 2600 CPU. You'll also need an Nvidia GeForce GTX 1070, an AMD Radeon RX 5700, or an Intel Arc A580.</p>

<p>Moving up to Recommended, you'll need an Intel Core i7-10700K or AMD Ryzen 5 5600X processor, as well as an Nvidia RTX 3080 or AMD Radeon RX 6800 XT card.</p>

<p>It's not clear what exactly those specs will get you; we don't have one of those tables developers sometimes release that show what kind of resolution and frame rate you can expect with each preset, so try to clear the Recommended settings by some distance if you want the smoothest experience.</p>

<p>Hopefully, it'll be better than the Xbox Series X|S version, which will be <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/avowed-30fps-xbox-target" rel="nofollow">running at 30fps</a>. Console players can't simply upgrade their machines to help them run the game more smoothly, either.</p>




<p>These specs were revealed alongside&nbsp;<em>Avowed</em>'s Premium Edition, which grants two skin packs, access to a digital artbook and soundtrack, and "up to 5 days early access". Let's hope it goes better than&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/suicide-squad-early-access-bug" rel="nofollow"><em>Suicide Squad</em>'s early access period did</a>.</p>

<p>If you're not familiar with&nbsp;<em>Avowed</em>, it's a first-person RPG created by Obsidian, the makers of&nbsp;<em>Pillars of Eternity&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>Fallout: New Vegas</em>. Appropriately enough, the game looks to be a mixture of those games, with the fantasy setting of the former (the very same one, in fact) and the first-person gameplay of the latter, albeit without guns.</p>

<p><em>Avowed&nbsp;</em>launches on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2457220/Avowed/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC</a> and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-GB/games/avowed" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Xbox Series X|S</a> on February 18th, although you can play it early if you pre-order the Premium Edition. The game is also launching on day one across <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/xbox-game-pass-price-hike-new-tier" rel="nofollow">certain Game Pass tiers</a>.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ubisoft's Splinter Cell Movie Is Dead]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/ubisoft-splinter-cell-movie-tom-hardy-1851700151</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ubisofts-splinter-cell-movie-is-dead.1036806/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/ubisoft-splinter-cell-movie-tom-hardy-1851700151<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Despite a recent spate of successful games-to-screen transitions—such as <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/2024-emmy-nominations-fallout-walton-goggins-shogun-1851597281&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/2024-emmy-nominations-fallout-walton-goggins-shogun-1851597281"><em>Fallout</em></a></span>, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/super-mario-bros-movie-nintendo-chris-pratt-reviews-1850300138&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/super-mario-bros-movie-nintendo-chris-pratt-reviews-1850300138"><em>The Super Mario Bros. Movie</em></a></span>, and <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/arcane-season-1-recap-netflix-league-of-legends-1851689099&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/arcane-season-1-recap-netflix-league-of-legends-1851689099"><em>Arcane</em></a></span><em>—</em>publisher Ubisoft continues its endless run of cinematic misfortune. The latest blow comes in the form of the long-planned <em>Splinter Cell </em>movie, which is now not going to happen.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196345" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="The Week In Games: Pokémon With Guns And More New Releases" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="126" data-playlist="196345,196470,196299" data-current="196345"><div><p>The Week In Games: Pokémon With Guns And More New Releases</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196345/196345_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196345/196345_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196345/196345_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196345/196345_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21893.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>When it comes to movies, Ubisoft’s list of successes is one film long: 2021's deeply daft and very fun <em>Werewolves Within</em>. Before that, you’ve got the critically demolished <em>Assassin’s Creed </em>and <em>Prince of Persia: The Sands of Time</em>, preceded by Uwe Boll’s monstrously dreadful <em>Far Cry</em> in 2008. (To be fair, <em>Prince of Persia</em> at least squeaked a profit, albeit not enough to prevent planned sequels getting cancelled.) Scattered amongst them are many promised projects that never quite seem to reach our eyes.<br></p><p>One of those is now known  to be <em>Tom Clancy’s Splinter Cell</em>, which <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/splinter-cell-movie-is-happening-tom-hardy-starring-as-5960678&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/splinter-cell-movie-is-happening-tom-hardy-starring-as-5960678">was first confirmed as in development in 2012</a></span>. Set to star Tom Hardy (<em>Mad Max</em>) as ultra-spy Sam Fisher, be written by Eric Warren Singer (<em>Top Gun: Maverick</em>), and later attached to director Doug Liman (<em>Edge of Tomorrow</em>), it was announced at the same time as the Michael Fassbender-starring <em>Assassin’s Creed</em>, although only one of them ever made it to screen. The wrong one? We shall never know.</p><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://thedirect.com/article/splinter-cell-tom-hardy-movie-exclusive&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://thedirect.com/article/splinter-cell-tom-hardy-movie-exclusive" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">According to <em>The Direct</em></a></span>, producer Basil Iwanyk—while on some <em>John Wick</em>-related promotion—said that the movie is “now dead.”</p><p>“That movie would have been awesome,” the <em>Expendables </em>producer told the site. “Just couldn’t get it right, script-wise, budget-wise. But it was going to be great.” Mmm-hmm.</p><p>Admittedly, Clancy’s <em>Splinter Cell</em> conceit of a black-ops agent doing generic spy stuff should have been a fairly easy lift, it didn’t necessarily <em>have</em> to be dreadful. But in a producer’s imagination, it could have been perfection. “It was going to be hardcore and awesome,” he continued.</p><h2 id="h117402"><a id=""></a>Intellectual Propagation</h2><p>Ubisoft has, in fact, created a whole division devoted to the process of converting its IPs to non-interactive screens, called Ubisoft Film &amp; Television. It was one of the production companies behind that atrocious <em>Assassin’s Creed</em> movie, and indeed <em>Werewolves Within</em>, but is probably most successful with the Apple+ TV series <em>Mythic Quest</em>, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/apple-tv-mythic-quest-rob-mcelhenney-season-4-date-1851698983?_gl=1*rpmuw2*_ga*MzQzNjkwNDM2LjE2NDY2NjQ1NzQ.*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczMTYyNTIwMy4xMTUuMC4xNzMxNjI1MjA2LjU3LjAuMA..&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/apple-tv-mythic-quest-rob-mcelhenney-season-4-date-1851698983?_gl=1*rpmuw2*_ga*MzQzNjkwNDM2LjE2NDY2NjQ1NzQ.*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczMTYyNTIwMy4xMTUuMC4xNzMxNjI1MjA2LjU3LjAuMA..">which just announced a new season and a spin-off</a></span>.</p><p>The company also has just about every Ubisoft franchise you can think of in some stage of production, including <em>Far Cry</em> and <em>Splinter Cell</em> animated series for Netflix, a <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://news.ubisoft.com/en-us/article/6GCLknCe27aNmvECtOkIK7/watch-dogs-movie-starts-production-this-summer&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://news.ubisoft.com/en-us/article/6GCLknCe27aNmvECtOkIK7/watch-dogs-movie-starts-production-this-summer" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Watch Dogs</em> movie (with Sony) that is allegedly in production now</a></span>, and...oh gawd...<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://news.ubisoft.com/en-us/article/2u8UuwZsL8FTVCmHVWIz5y/just-dance-filmrights-acquired-by-sonys-screen-gems&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://news.ubisoft.com/en-us/article/2u8UuwZsL8FTVCmHVWIz5y/just-dance-filmrights-acquired-by-sonys-screen-gems" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">a <em>Just Dance</em></a></span> “feature film,” although that was announced in 2019, and further information has not been forthcoming. There are also claims of <em>Ghost Recon </em>(Warner), and <em>The Division</em> and <em>Beyond Good &amp; Evil</em> (both Netflix) at least optioned.</p><p>So sorry to those who were looking forward to one day seeing Tom Hardy as Sam Fisher. However, there’s compensation in the form of the upcoming Netflix animation <em>Splinter Cell: Deathwatch</em>, which <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gdVrikMkoNY&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gdVrikMkoNY" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">has proof of life and everything</a></span>.</p><p>Cancelling things is, of course, nothing new to Ubisoft, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/ubisoft-7-canceled-games-splinter-cell-assasin-s-creed-1849976552&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/ubisoft-7-canceled-games-splinter-cell-assasin-s-creed-1849976552">which makes a habit of killing many projects</a></span>, while allowing <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/beyond-good-evil-2-bg-e2-director-release-date-dead-1851679744&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/beyond-good-evil-2-bg-e2-director-release-date-dead-1851679744">vaporware dreams like <em>Beyond Good &amp; Evil 2</em></a></span> to continue demolishing money.</p><p>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GTA Trilogy Developers Respond to Credits Being Removed]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/gta-trilogy-developers-respond-to-credits-being-removed/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gta-trilogy-developers-respond-to-credits-being-removed.1036803/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/gta-trilogy-developers-respond-to-credits-being-removed/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-68848">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>Grove Street Games’ lead has addressed the removal of their name from the credits of the GTA Trilogy Definitive Edition. Fans pointed out that it was only partially removed.</p>



<p>Spotted by <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/boss-of-developer-behind-gta-trilogys-original-poorly-received-launch-laments-being-removed-from-games-credits-even-though-he-wasnt" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Eurogamer</a>, Thomas Williamson, the head of Grove Street Games, recently <a href="https://x.com/TSWilliamson/status/1857124999045222581" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">addressed</a> the removal of his company from the credits of the GTA Trilogy following the latest update. You can find his complete statement below.:&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote>
<p>“Speaking entire hypothetically: It’s a dick move to remove primary developers from credits in an update, especially when an update includes hundreds of fixes that were provided by those developers that stayed out of players’ hands for years.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p><a href="https://x.com/videotechuk_/status/1857196839713263958" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Several fans responded</a> to Williamson’s post, highlighting that Grove Street Games has not been entirely removed from the GTA Trilogy’s credits. They mentioned that the developers are still credited in the final credits but have been removed from the initial splash screen.</p>



<p>Recently, the GTA Trilogy <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/gta-trilogy-definitive-edition-receives-major-update-for-pc-and-consoles/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">received a significant update for both PC and consoles</a>, introducing new game features and enhancements. Key highlights of this update include a new “Classic Lighting” mode and improved animations, which greatly enhance the visual quality of the games. <span>This update removed Grove Street Games from GTA Trilogy’s </span>opening credits. </p>



<p>In other news, read about how <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/shawn-fonteno-franklin-clinton-almost-quit/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Shawn Fontenot almost quit the role of Franklin Clinton</a> in GTA 5. Also, Take Two isn’t worried about GTA 6’s <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/take-two-isnt-worried-about-gta-6-series-s-performance/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">performance on the Series S</a>. What are your thoughts on the GTA Trilogy developers’ response?&nbsp;What are your thoughts on GTA Trilogy Definitive Edition’s new update?&nbsp;Let us know in the comments or our new&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/phil-spencer-reveals-why-xbox-isnt-doing-a-mid-gen-refresh/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Phil Spencer revealing why Xbox isn’t working on a mid-gen refresh</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-list-of-known-issues/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-list-of-known-issues/">Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 List of Known Issues (UPDATED)</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Developers Treyarch and Raven Software have released a list of the known issues in Call of Duty: Black Ops 6.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/phil-spencer-reveals-why-xbox-isnt-doing-a-mid-gen-refresh/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/phil-spencer-reveals-why-xbox-isnt-doing-a-mid-gen-refresh/">Phil Spencer Reveals Why Xbox Isn’t Doing a Mid-Gen Refresh&nbsp;</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>During a recent interview, Phil Spencer stated that it has become “harder to show the benefits” of a mid-gen refresh console. </p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/uk-gaming-expo-scene-crumble-wasd/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/uk-gaming-expo-scene-crumble-wasd/">UK Gaming Expo Scene Crumbles As Another Event Disappears</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>As WASD London goes into liquidation, another blow is dealt to the UK’s gaming expo scene. Will EGX be the next event to go?</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/avowed-pc-system-requirements-revealed/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/avowed-pc-system-requirements-revealed/">Avowed System Requirements Revealed – What Do You Need To Run The Game on PC?</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Obsidian has revealed the minimum and recommended system requirements for Avowed. Here’s what you need to run the game on your PC. </p>
                    </div>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine 2 Players Are Using Its New Pistol to Turn the Game Into Ghostbusters 40k]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/warhammer-40000-space-marine-2-players-are-using-its-new-pistol-to-turn-the-game-into-ghostbusters-40k</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/warhammer-40-000-space-marine-2-players-are-using-its-new-pistol-to-turn-the-game-into-ghostbusters-40k.1036800/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/warhammer-40000-space-marine-2-players-are-using-its-new-pistol-to-turn-the-game-into-ghostbusters-40k<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">This week, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/warhammer-40000-space-marine-2-patch-45-adds-new-neo-volkite-pistol-buffs-various-weapons-and-squashes-bugs"><u>Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine 2</u> received a new update</a> (patch 4.5) and with it the hotly anticipated Neo-Volkite pistol.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The Neo-Volkite pistol is a powerful thermal ray weapon that shoots lethal beams that burn enemies to ash. It’s available for the Assault, Vanguard, and Bulwark classes and is limited to Operations, Space Marine 2’s three-player co-op focused PvE mode.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">And it’s there that Space Marine 2 players are teaming up to form a three-pronged Neo-Volkite pistol death stream, rekindling memories of all those moments when the Ghostbusters use their iconic Proton Packs to trap ghosts.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The Neo-Volkite pistol is unique among Space Marine 2’s armory in that it blasts a heat ray onto enemies, dealing accumulative thermal damage. Focusing on one enemy ramps up the damage until it generates a localized explosion for huge damage to your target and all nearby enemies.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Players have found that while the Neo-Volkite pistol is fun to use, it isn’t that effective especially on harder difficulties where ammo is scarce. At least, that’s the case in isolation. But what happens when all three players use the Neo-Volkite pistol to concentrate three heat rays onto the pesky Terminids? You get satisfying, Ghostbusters-style alien death, that’s what.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Redditor Crimsas demonstrated this in action, showing just how effective three Neo-Volkite pistols all trained on a single, powerful Termanid enemy (in this case a Carnifex) can be brought down to size.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">All we now need is a mod that replaces the Neo-Volkite pistol model with an actual Proton Pack and we’ve got Ghostbusters 40k edition.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Publisher <a href="https://community.focus-entmt.com/focus-entertainment/space-marine-2/blogs/109-patch-4-5-is-available" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Focus Entertainment has said</u></a> it’s limiting the Neo-Volkite pistol to Operations mode for now “as we continue to experiment with balancing in PvP.” It will be added to Eternal War mode in Space Marine 2’s next major update alongside a new Operations map, a new enemy, and the Dark Angels cosmetics. So, hopefully it won’t be long before even PvP is filled with a spot of Ghostbusters action.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In September, Saber Chief Creative Officer Tim Willits told IGN <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/success-of-warhammer-40000-space-marine-2-changes-everything-dev-says-and-yes-there-are-ideas-for-space-marine-3"><u>how the breakout success of Space Marine 2 had “changed everything” for the company</u></a>. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/eagle-eyed-warhammer-40000-space-marine-2-fans-spot-chapter-all-but-confirmed-to-get-cosmetic-pack-after-the-dark-angels"><u>Eagle-eyed fans have spotted the Space Marine chapter now all-but confirmed to get a cosmetic pack after the Dark Angels</u></a>, too.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Image credit: </em><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Spacemarine/comments/1grt0ik/neovolkite_my_beloved/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Crimsas / reddit</em></a><em>.</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[IGN UK Podcast 774: Ranking the 10 Best Netflix Original Series]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/ign-uk-podcast-774-ranking-the-10-best-netflix-original-series</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ign-uk-podcast-774-ranking-the-10-best-netflix-original-series.1036797/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/ign-uk-podcast-774-ranking-the-10-best-netflix-original-series<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="__next" tabindex="-1"><header></header><main data-cy="page-main-content" id="main-content"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Gladiator 2, Lego Horizon Adventures, The Rise of the Golden Idol, Arcane, and Netflix originals.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Cardy, Matt, and Dale are here for another dose of audio glory on this week's IGN UK Podcast. There are impressions of Gladiator 2, Lego Horizon Adventures, The Rise of the Golden Idol, and Arcane, all before the main event of ranking the 10 best Netflix original series. Squid Game, Mindhunter, Stranger Things. What will come out on top? Listen and find out, I guess.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Remember to send us your thoughts about all the new games, TV shows, and films you're enjoying or looking forward to: ign_ukfeedback@ign.com.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/pdst.fm/e/chrt.fm/track/FGADCC/traffic.megaphone.fm/SBP6141418733.mp3?updated=1731680313" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">IGN UK Podcast 774: Ranking the 10 Best Netflix Original Series</a></p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><ul data-cy="list"><li><a href="https://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/pdst.fm/e/chrt.fm/track/FGADCC/traffic.megaphone.fm/SBP6839139854.mp3?updated=1731078612" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">IGN UK Podcast 773: Don't Eat Play-Doh</a></li><li><a href="https://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/pdst.fm/e/chrt.fm/track/FGADCC/traffic.megaphone.fm/SBP7551969133.mp3?updated=1730477593" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">IGN UK Podcast 772: Breaking the Balls Meter</a></li><li><a href="https://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/pdst.fm/e/chrt.fm/track/FGADCC/traffic.megaphone.fm/SBP7016350553.mp3?updated=1730124578" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">IGN UK Podcast 771: Call of Duty: Tunnock's Teacakes 6</a></li><li><a href="https://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/pdst.fm/e/chrt.fm/track/FGADCC/traffic.megaphone.fm/SBP9450254244.mp3?updated=1729180114" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">IGN UK Podcast 770: The Horror, the Horror</a></li><li><a href="https://dcs-spotify.megaphone.fm/SBP9146547315.mp3?key=59ef77435bad4a80942dc3b5c0796e4d&amp;request_event_id=3ed02a4f-ab9d-4587-8e0e-3ca4c751bb40&amp;timetoken=1728663055_226AF6DCEC5182F8F6FC045E545958FF" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">IGN UK Podcast 769: They Pasteurise Mayonnaise, Don't They?</a></li></ul></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3><div data-cy="objectcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="article-subtitle">Not yet available for streaming.</p></div></div></main></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GTA Trilogy Studio Boss Says It’s a 'D**k Move' to Remove Developers From Game Credits After Long-Awaited Rockstar Update Goes Live]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/gta-trilogy-studio-boss-says-its-a-dk-move-to-remove-developers-from-game-credits-after-long-awaited-rockstar-update-goes-live</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gta-trilogy-studio-boss-says-it%E2%80%99s-a-d-k-move-to-remove-developers-from-game-credits-after-long-awaited-rockstar-update-goes-live.1036794/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/gta-trilogy-studio-boss-says-its-a-dk-move-to-remove-developers-from-game-credits-after-long-awaited-rockstar-update-goes-live<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">The boss of GTA Trilogy Definitive Edition has taken to social media to respond to recent changes made to the game by Rockstar.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">This week, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/gta-trilogy-definitive-edition-gets-surprise-update-on-console-and-pc-adds-visual-features-that-were-exclusive-to-mobile-versions">Rockstar issued a surprise update for the heavily criticized <u>GTA Trilogy Definitive Edition</u></a> on PC and console nearly two years after the last one. The patch added a number of visual features that were exclusive to the mobile versions, pleasing disgruntled fans of the groundbreaking open-world games.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">GTA Trilogy Definitive Edition, a compilation of 2001’s Grand Theft Auto 3, 2002’s Grand Theft Auto: Vice City, and 2004’s Grand Theft Auto: San Andreas, sparked a backlash upon its 2021 launch on PC and console. IGN’s <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/grand-theft-auto-the-trilogy-the-definitive-edition-review"><u>GTA Trilogy Definitive Edition review</u></a> returned a 5/10. We said: “GTA Trilogy Definitive Edition is defective, disappointing, and surprisingly disrespectful to three classic games and their many legions of fans.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">GTA Trilogy Definitive Edition was developed by Grove Street Games, which at the time came under fire for the poor quality of the release. The mobile versions were developed by Video Games Deluxe, the Australian studio behind <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/la-noire-the-vr-case-files"><u>L.A. Noire VR Case Files</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">After this week’s update went live, users noticed Grove Street Games and its logo were removed from GTA Trilogy’s main menu and splash screen. Now, the PC and console versions align with the mobile versions, showing Rockstar as GTA’s developer.</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr">Looks like mentions of Grove Street Games and their logos have been removed from the splash screen and main menu of the <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/GTA?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">#GTA</a> Definitive Editions as well. <a href="https://t.co/ZmXpccyiyS" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/ZmXpccyiyS</a></p>— TJGM (@TJGM_) <a href="https://twitter.com/TJGM_/status/1856316469954453783?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">November 12, 2024</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">It’s this removal that Thomas Williamson, boss of Grove Street Games, has clearly reacted to in a thinly-veiled tweet.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Speaking entire hypothetically: it's a dick move to remove primary developers from credits in an update, especially when an update includes hundreds of fixes that were provided by those developers that stayed out of players' hands for years,” Williamson <a href="https://x.com/TSWilliamson/status/1857124999045222581" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">tweeted</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">While Williamson’s displeasure at recent events is clear, Grove Street Games and Williamson himself remain in GTA Trilogy’s end credits, as many X/Twitter users have pointed out.</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr">PSA: Rumours being circulated by the community and even some news websites about Grove Street Games (GSG) having been removed from the <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/GTATrilogy?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">#GTATrilogy</a> entirely are unfounded. <br>Both GSG and Video Games Deluxe are in the final credits, only the initial splash screen was removed. <a href="https://t.co/MUkvgi2uZX" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/MUkvgi2uZX</a></p>— GTANet (@GTANet) <a href="https://twitter.com/GTANet/status/1857075030808461543?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">November 14, 2024</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">It’s a messy end for GTA Trilogy Definitive Edition, which has endured controversy ever since it came out. Rockstar was forced to apologize for the state of the collection at launch and even <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/gta-trilogy-free-game"><u>offered PC players free games</u></a> as recompense.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Still, the collection appeared to have <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/gta-remastered-trilogy-10-million-units-technical-issues"><u>sold very well despite the problems,</u></a> and Strauss Zelnick – CEO of Rockstar parent company Take-Two – eventually <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/take-two-ceo-gta-trilogy-launch-problems-glitch-been-resolved"><u>called those issues a “glitch” that was “resolved.</u></a><u>”</u></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Speaking Hypothetically, GTA Trilogy Dev Says "It's A D**k Move" To Remove Crediting]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/speaking-hypothetically-gta-trilogy-dev-says-its-a-dk-move-to-remove-crediting/1100-6527788/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/speaking-hypothetically-gta-trilogy-dev-says-its-a-d-k-move-to-remove-crediting.1036788/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/speaking-hypothetically-gta-trilogy-dev-says-its-a-dk-move-to-remove-crediting/1100-6527788/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6527788">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">Not everyone is happy about a recent update for Grand Theft Auto: The Trilogy - Definitive Edition. The CEO and co-founder for the developer behind the remake compilation seems particularly frustrated by the removal of his team's logo--Grove Street Games--from the game's splash screen. In fact, speaking in hypotheticals, Thomas Williamson said, "It's a dick move... "</p><p dir="ltr">Spotted by <a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/gta-trilogy-dev-calls-credits-removal-a-dick-move/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">VGC</a>, Williamson also insinuated <a href="https://x.com/TSWilliamson/status/1857124999045222581" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">on X</a> that Grove Street Games provided the fixes to <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/grand-theft-auto-the-trilogy-gets-long-overdue-console-patch/1100-6527714/" data-ref-id="1100-6527714">Grand Theft Auto: The Trilogy's long-overdue console patch</a> a while ago. "Speaking entire[ly] hypothetically: It's a dick move to remove primary developers from credits in an update, especially when an update includes hundreds of fixes that were provided by those developers that stayed out of players' hands for years," wrote Williamson.</p><div data-embed-type="tweet" data-src="https://x.com/TSWilliamson/status/1857124999045222581" data-has-image="false"><blockquote data-conversation="none" data-mce-disable-toolbar="true"><p dir="ltr">Speaking entire hypothetically: It's a dick move to remove primary developers from credits in an update, especially when an update includes hundreds of fixes that were provided by those developers that stayed out of players' hands for years.</p>  — Thomas Williamson (@TSWilliamson) <a href="https://twitter.com/TSWilliamson/status/1857124999045222581?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 14, 2024</a></blockquote>              </div><p dir="ltr">For clarity, Grove Street Games and its employees can still be found in the ending credits for Grand Theft Auto: The Trilogy after the recent patch. <a href="https://support.rockstargames.com/articles/35337378670739/Grand-Theft-Auto-The-Trilogy-The-Definitive-Edition-Title-Update-Notes-1-112-PlayStation-5-Xbox-Series-X-S-PC" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Rockstar Games released pretty vague notes</a> for the update, stating there are "numerous fixes and improvements" alongside the addition of classic lighting. When <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/grand-theft-auto-the-trilogy-definitive-edition-review-wasted/1900-6417791/" data-ref-id="1900-6417791">Grand Theft Auto: The Trilogy</a> launched in 2021, the game was criticized for its visual-upgrade choices and game-breaking bugs.</p><p dir="ltr">Interestingly enough, earlier this week, Williamson reposted <a href="https://x.com/SynthPotato/status/1856403271445033381" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">on X</a> a thread about all of the positive changes to Grand Theft Auto: The Trilogy. In addition to working on this game, <a href="https://grovestreetgames.com/games/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Grove Street</a> has assisted in developing Ark: Ultimate Survivor Edition on Switch and Ark: Survival Ascended on PC, PS5, and Xbox Series X|S.</p><p dir="ltr">This isn't the first big update for Grand Theft Auto: The Trilogy. In February 2022, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-trilogy-patch-notes-include-fixes-for-more-than-100-bugs/1100-6501098/" data-ref-id="1100-6501098">a patch offered fixes for more than 100 bugs</a>.</p><p dir="ltr">Looking ahead for the franchise, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/grand-theft-auto-6-is-still-on-track-for-fall-2025-release/1100-6527618/" data-ref-id="1100-6527618">Grant Theft Auto VI is still on track for a Fall 2025 launch</a>. Take-Two CEO Strauss Zelnick <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-6-on-xbox-series-s-im-not-really-worried-take-two-boss-says/1100-6527625/" data-ref-id="1100-6527625">isn't "really worried" about the game running on Xbox Series S</a>, while Digital Foundry previously reported that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/grand-theft-auto-6-might-not-benefit-from-ps5-pro-in-ways-that-you-expect/1100-6526459/" data-ref-id="1100-6526459">Grand Theft Auto VI might not benefit from PS5 Pro like people may think</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Phil Spencer Reveals Why Xbox Isn’t Doing a Mid-Gen Refresh]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/phil-spencer-reveals-why-xbox-isnt-doing-a-mid-gen-refresh/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/phil-spencer-reveals-why-xbox-isn%E2%80%99t-doing-a-mid-gen-refresh.1036767/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/phil-spencer-reveals-why-xbox-isnt-doing-a-mid-gen-refresh/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-68842">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>Phil Spencer recently discussed the reasons for not releasing a mid-gen refresh console for Xbox Series X/S like the PS5 Pro, stating it’s “harder to show the benefits” for such consoles.&nbsp;</p>



<p>During an interview with <a href="https://www.rollingstone.com/culture/rs-gaming/xbox-console-future-cloud-ceo-phil-spencer-1235166597/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Rolling Stone</a>, Phil Spencer was asked why Xbox wasn’t working on a mid-gen refresh like the PS5 Pro. In response, Spencer stated that Xbox thinks “about hardware that can create unique value” for the players or creators on its platform. The company doesn’t need to work on “incremental hardware” for its benefit.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Phil Spencer asked whether a new mid-gen device provides players with “a unique experience on screen in some way”. He stated that “it’s less like the old days” when going from the original Xbox to 360 meant moving from “standard definition to high definition”.” He concluded by stating, “Now, it’s harder to show the benefits” for mid-gen consoles.&nbsp;</p>



<p>During the same interview, Spencer also confirmed that Xbox would “definitely do more consoles in the future, and other devices”. Spencer means the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-handheld-confirmed-phil-spencer/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Xbox Handheld</a> by “other devices”, which was confirmed during another interview a few days ago. However, this console will not arrive for a few years.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In other news, Phil Spencer has stated that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/avowed-delay-wasnt-due-to-game-quality-phil-spencer-says/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Avowed wasn’t delayed due to game quality</a>. Also, check out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/is-stalker-2-on-xbox-game-pass/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">whether Stalker 2 is coming to Xbox Game Pass</a>. What are your thoughts on Phil Spencer’s reason for not creating a mid-gen refresh console?&nbsp;Let us know in the comments or our new&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/uk-gaming-expo-scene-crumble-wasd/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">WASD London entering liquidation as the UK gaming scene crumbles</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/uk-gaming-expo-scene-crumble-wasd/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/uk-gaming-expo-scene-crumble-wasd/">UK Gaming Expo Scene Crumbles As Another Event Disappears</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>As WASD London goes into liquidation, another blow is dealt to the UK’s gaming expo scene. Will EGX be the next event to go?</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/avowed-pc-system-requirements-revealed/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/avowed-pc-system-requirements-revealed/">Avowed System Requirements Revealed – What Do You Need To Run The Game on PC?</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Obsidian has revealed the minimum and recommended system requirements for Avowed. Here’s what you need to run the game on your PC. </p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/avowed-pre-order-details-and-game-editions-revealed/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/avowed-pre-order-details-and-game-editions-revealed/">Avowed Pre-Order Details and Game Editions Revealed &nbsp;</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Here’s everything you need to know about Avowed’s pre-order details and the different game editions available for sale. </p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/amazons-tomb-raider-series-might-feature-game-of-thrones-star/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/amazons-tomb-raider-series-might-feature-game-of-thrones-star/">Amazon’s Tomb Raider Series Might Feature Game of Thrones Star as Lara Croft</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Game of Thrones Star Sophie Turner is reportedly in talks to play Lara Croft in Amazon’s Tomb Raider series. </p>
                    </div>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[FATE: Reawakened adds PS5, Xbox Series, PS4, Xbox One, and Switch versions]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/11/fate-reawakened-adds-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-xbox-one-and-switch-versions</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fate-reawakened-adds-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-xbox-one-and-switch-versions.1036764/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/11/fate-reawakened-adds-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-xbox-one-and-switch-versions<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Remastered versions of all four FATE action RPGs.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publishers <a title="Companies > gamigo" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/gamigo">gamigo</a> and <a title="Companies > WildTangent" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/gamigo/wildtangent">WildTangent</a>, and developers gamigo and <a title="Companies > Tableflip Entertainment" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/tableflip-entertainment">Tableflip Entertainment</a> will release action <a title="Genres > RPG [16,789 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg">RPG</a> collection <em><a title="Games > FATE: Reawakened [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/fate-reawakened">FATE: Reawakened</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,369 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [6,364 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,436 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox One [13,626 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a>, and <a title="Platforms > Switch [16,308 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a> alongside its previously announced <a title="Platforms > PC [21,707 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> (<a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3030720/FATE_Reawakened/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a>, <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/p/fate-reawakened-dab2fa" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Epic Games Store</a>) versions, the companies announced. A release date is still to be announced. <span id="more-928012"></span></p><p><em>FATE: Reawakened</em> includes remastered versions of the <a title="Genres > Action RPG [1,401 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg/action-rpg">action RPGs</a> <em><a title="Series > Fate [64 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/series/fate">FATE</a></em> (2005), <em>FATE: Undiscovered Realms</em> (2008), <em>FATE: The Traitor Soul</em> (2009), and <em>FATE: The Cursed King</em> (2011), which were all released by WildTangent.</p><p>Here is an overview of the collection, via its store pages:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Reawaken the critically acclaimed <em>FATE</em> games like never before! Play all four classic dungeon crawler titles with enhanced graphics as you battle through challenging procedurally generated dungeons, learn powerful spells, and fish to your heart’s content. Are you up to the task? Your <em>FATE</em> awaits!</p><p>Revisit the quaint town of Grove and the realms beyond as you prepare to enter the Dungeon Gate once again! The award-winning <em>FATE</em> series has gotten a modern facelift while remaining true to the nostalgic dungeon crawler classic. Will you tempt fate on your journey to fame and fortune?</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong><a title="Companies > Enhance [31 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/enhance">Enhance</a>d for a New Generation</strong> – <a title="Companies > Experience [210 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/experience">Experience</a> everything you already love about the <em>FATE</em> series in higher definition. Enjoy higher poly counts, real-time directional lighting, ambient occlusion, additional languages with full localized voice-overs, and much more! The upgrades provide a deeper level of immersion all while staying faithful to what makes <em>FATE</em>… <em>FATE</em>.</li><li><strong>All Four Games, All Better than you Remember</strong> – Play (or replay) through all four <em>FATE</em> games in their reawakened greatness. <em>FATE</em>, <em>FATE: Undiscovered Realms</em>, <em>FATE: The Traitor Soul</em>, and <em>FATE: The Cursed King</em> are all included in this bundled release. No matter which game is your favorite, you’ll be able to dive back into all the dungeons and determine your <em>FATE</em>!</li><li><strong>Unique Procedurally Generated Playthroughs</strong> – Test your battle prowess in challenging procedurally generated dungeons! No playthrough is ever the same with randomized dungeon layouts, monster encounters, and loot drops.</li><li><strong><a title="Genres > Action [2,307 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">Action</a> Packed Real-time Combat</strong> – Step into the heart-pounding arena of real-time combat, where every moment counts. Armed with an arsenal of diverse weapons and skills, you’ll face off against relentless monsters that hunger for your defeat. Will you wield the thunderous fury of melee strikes, unleash deadly precision with ranged weaponry, or harness the arcane might of magic? Adapt, strategize, and master your chosen path to determine your <em>FATE</em>.</li><li><strong>Increase Your Fame and Power</strong> – Cater your character to your desired playstyle by utilizing a flexible skill point system. Gaining experience will allow you to level up, wield more powerful weapons, and develop proficiencies in different areas. Additionally, you can complete quests to raise your fame and unlock legendary gear.</li><li><strong>Aid in the Form of a Furry Friend</strong> – Choose from seven different pets to accompany you on your journey. This loyal companion will fight for you in combat, can hold onto various items, and even transform into powerful magical creatures to become the ultimate <a title="Genres > Adventure [1,867 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a>r’s sidekick.</li><li><strong>Reel in More than Just Fish</strong> – Gather your fishing supplies and head to the water to catch valuable items such as fish, artifacts, gems, rings, and more. Patient anglers might even be able to obtain rare items that will help them on their quest.</li><li><strong>Choose Your <em>FATE</em></strong> – When death beckons, choose from 3 distinct resurrection paths, each with its own cost. Decide wisely—your choices shape your <em>FATE</em>.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Consoles Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="FATE: Reawakened - Consoles Announce Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6h4FB-j2qSA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PS5 Pro Runs Max PC Settings in Lords of the Fallen, Says Dev; ‘A Comparable PC Would Be More Costly’]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/ps5-pro-runs-max-pc-settings-in-lords-of-the-fallen-says-dev-a-comparable-pc-would-be-more-costly/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ps5-pro-runs-max-pc-settings-in-lords-of-the-fallen-says-dev-%E2%80%98a-comparable-pc-would-be-more-costly%E2%80%99.1036740/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/ps5-pro-runs-max-pc-settings-in-lords-of-the-fallen-says-dev-a-comparable-pc-would-be-more-costly/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Spanish developer HEXWORKS was one of the first developers to <a href="https://wccftech.com/ps5-pro-lords-of-the-fallen-enhancements-revealed-more-updates-planned-sequel-teased/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">share</a> information on the graphics enhancements they had planned for their game's PS5 Pro version. As you might recall, HEXWORKS was founded in early 2020 specifically to make Lords of the Fallen, and they've got big plans for the <a href="https://wccftech.com/lords-of-the-fallen-2-gets-first-details-elevated-production-values-gameplay-improvements-and-more/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">sequel</a> tentatively slated for 2026. In the meantime, though, they're continuing to <a href="https://wccftech.com/new-lords-of-the-fallen-update-adds-better-umbral-exploration-and-gameplay-balancing/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">support</a> this game with patches and with the introduction of PS5 Pro support.</p>
<p>To delve into greater detail about their experience with Sony's new console, we interviewed Eduard Gonzalez, Principal Engine Programmer at HEXWORKS. Gonzalez lavished praise on the PS5 Pro hardware and revealed that this version actually runs on the highest PC settings available (though, of course, you can run Lords of the Fallen at higher frame rates on PC, provided you've got the significantly more expensive hardware to do it). Still, it's a major accomplishment that not many games achieve, and they did it without even using Sony's much-vaunted AI-powered PlayStation Spectral Super Resolution upscaling.</p>
<p><iframe title="Lords of the Fallen - PS5 Pro 4K 60FPS Gameplay" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/HtJD57wMtk4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p><strong>Unreal Engine 5 has been known to have spotty performance on PS5 (and Xbox Series S|X). Is the PS5 Pro a significant improvement in that regard?</strong></p>
<p>Unreal Engine 5 has empowered developers to increase triangle density in games by an order of magnitude. Achieving smooth framerates with this level of visual detail required several iterations of both the engine and content, but we’ve now reached a point where we can deliver a vastly enhanced experience showcasing the visual power of UE5. With this foundation, the PS5 Pro hardware upgrade marks a significant step forward. It enables further improvements to object visibility, texture density, and overall resolution, all while boosting framerates. The PS5 was solid, but the Pro is truly exceptional hardware.</p>
<p><strong>What is the single feature you were most impressed with after getting your hands on the hardware?</strong></p>
<p>The PS5 Pro enhances the PS5 base model in every aspect: a faster GPU, quicker CPU, upgraded raytracing units, additional memory, and custom machine learning hardware. If we had to highlight a single standout feature, it would be the GPU, which belongs to a hardware generation beyond the original.</p>
<p><strong>Compared to the jump between PS4 Pro and PS4, would you say the PS5 Pro-PS5 difference is similar or reduced (e.g., the advancement is more or less significant)?</strong></p>
<p>While the advancement is somewhat comparable, the PS5 Pro makes a more significant leap, especially with the introduction of custom machine learning hardware. This addition unlocks a whole new realm of possibilities for visual and performance enhancements.</p>
<p><strong>How much of an improvement is there between the PS5 and PS5 Pro versions of Lords of the Fallen?</strong></p>
<p>The improvement is noticeable, with a 40% increase in the game’s native rendering resolution. This enhancement makes a significant difference, especially on 4K screens, where details are far more visible, truly letting high-end TVs shine. In the PS5 Pro version of Lords of the Fallen, Performance Mode provides rich visual detail at 4K60 (upscaled from 1440p) with a fluid 60 frames per second, as well as sharper distant details and refined textures on characters and environments. For those playing in Quality Mode, this runs at a native 4K30, allowing up to showcase intricate visuals across the dual realms of Axiom and Umbral at a stable 30 FPS.</p>
<p><strong>Are you using PSSR? What do you think about it compared to established upscalers like NVIDIA DLSS, AMD FSR, and Intel XeSS?</strong></p>
<p>PSSR is an impressive technology, offering quality comparable to DLSS and Unreal Engine 5’s built-in upscaling, with the added benefit of being embedded directly in the console, making it compatible with any engine: PSSR is undeniably a valuable addition. After extensive testing, we found no visual differences compared to our custom version of UE5's upscaling, which is also highly robust. Therefore, we decided to continue using our own upscaling method.</p>
<p><strong>How does the PS5 Pro version stack with the maxed-out PC game? Will the PS5 Pro version feature the highest graphics settings available on PC?</strong></p>
<p>The game indeed utilizes the highest graphics settings available on PC. As I touched upon earlier, players can select between two graphics modes: Performance Mode and Quality Mode. Performance Mode is optimized for a smooth experience, while Quality Mode focuses on delivering the sharpest visuals. The primary distinction between these modes is the native rendering resolution, which dynamically adjusts to meet target frame rates - 60 FPS for Performance Mode and 30 FPS for Quality Mode. In short, you’ll enjoy top-tier PC graphics on the PS5 Pro, but you’ll need to choose between native 4K at 30 FPS or upscaled 4K at 60 FPS.</p>
<p><strong>The big <a href="https://wccftech.com/microsoft-gaming-ceo-gives-subtle-dig-at-ps5-pro-price-were-not-growing-the-market-with-1000-consoles/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">controversy</a> about Sony's new console is pricing. Based on the hardware, is it fair or excessive?</strong></p>
<p>Building a PC with comparable components - GPU, CPU, memory, and SSD - at a similar quality level would be significantly more costly, so it’s great to see Sony is bringing this high-end hardware to a wider audience. Rest assured, our game runs great on the standard PS5, so if the PS5 Pro is out of budget you will still enjoy Lords of the Fallen, but if you do have that extra budget, the PS5 Pro truly elevates the experience!</p>
<p><strong>Thank you for your time.</strong></p>

				

			
	<div>
		<h2>Products mentioned in this post</h2>
		
		<!--<p class="story-notice text-center">The links above are affiliate links. As an Amazon Associate, Wccftech.com may earn from qualifying purchases.</p>-->
	</div>

			
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Anti-Defamation League Says Steam "Rife with Extremism and Antisemitism"]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/anti-defamation-league-steam-extremism-report</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/anti-defamation-league-says-steam-rife-with-extremism-and-antisemitism.1036737/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/anti-defamation-league-steam-extremism-report<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>The Anti-Defamation League has released a new report which claims that digital distribution platform Steam is "rife with extremism and antisemitism", with the report also claiming it's identified "millions of examples" of content reflecting this problem.</p>

<p>According to the ADL, the report analyzed over 450 million Steam profiles, as well as more than 152 million "profile and group avatar images" and over 610 million comments on Steam user profiles and group pages.</p>

<p>Among the "millions of examples" of extremist content uncovered by the report were "explicit hate symbols" like the happy merchant figure and the sonnenrad, as well as "copypastas shaped into swastikas". We won't be showing any kind of images illustrating the ADL's points here, but you can imagine the kinds of things the report found.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/anti-defamation-league-steam-report-front-page.jpg?itok=EMHjKk6x 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/anti-defamation-league-steam-report-front-page.jpg?itok=rg51TLN6 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>The Anti-Defamation League says Steam is "rife" with extremist content.</figcaption></figure><p>In numbers terms, the ADL says it identified 1.83 million "unique pieces of extremist or hateful content", as well as 1.5 million users and over 73,000 groups "who used at least one potentially extremist or hateful symbol, copypasta, or keyword" on Steam.</p>

<p>1.18 million unique instances of extremist copypastas were identified, as well as over 820,000 avatars for users and groups containing extremist symbols. Additionally, the report found "thousands of profiles" glorifying violent extremists such as "white supremacist mass shooters".</p>

<p>The ADL blames Valve's "highly permissive approach to content policy" for this issue, stating that while Steam does occasionally remove high-profile extremist content, it has failed to "systematically address the issue of extremism and hate on the platform".</p>

<p>One such example of Valve banning extremist content on Steam was the <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/domina-removed-from-steam-after-devs-transphobic-rant" rel="nofollow">removal of gladiator game&nbsp;</a><em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/domina-removed-from-steam-after-devs-transphobic-rant" rel="nofollow">Domina</a>&nbsp;</em>following a transphobic rant on the part of its developer, but the ADL seems to be suggesting that this kind of action is the exception rather than the rule.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/anti-defamation-league-steam-report-profile.jpg?itok=n5mxcVLN 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/anti-defamation-league-steam-report-profile.jpg?itok=25U7Qwio 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>According to the ADL, many Steam profiles contain hateful or extremist content.</figcaption></figure><p>So, what does the ADL recommend Valve and Steam do about extremist and hateful content on the platform?</p>

<p>First, the ADL says Valve should adopt specific policies to prohibit extremism. There's currently no policy on Steam that specifically outlaws this kind of content, so the ADL wants to see one implemented.</p>

<p>Other recommendations include adopting policies "prohibiting hate", as well as enforcing policies "accurately at scale" and closing adult content moderation loopholes.</p>

<p>Lastly, the ADL says Valve should "engage with civil society, academics, and researchers" in order to shape its policies and prevent "vulnerable and marginalized groups" from being targeted on Steam.</p>

<p>You can read the ADL's full report, which contains numerous examples of the kind of content discovered on Steam during the course of the report's undertaking, <a href="https://www.adl.org/resources/report/steam-powered-hate-top-gaming-site-rife-extremism-antisemitism" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">right here</a>.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amerzone: The Explorer’s Legacy remake delayed to Q2 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/11/amerzone-the-explorers-legacy-remake-delayed-to-q2-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/amerzone-the-explorer%E2%80%99s-legacy-remake-delayed-to-q2-2025.1036734/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/11/amerzone-the-explorers-legacy-remake-delayed-to-q2-2025<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>No longer due out in November.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Microids [198 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/microids">Microids</a> has <a href="https://x.com/Microids_off/status/1857418031376298259" rel="noopener" target="_blank">delayed</a> the <em><a title="Games > Amerzone: The Explorer's Legacy (2025) [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/amerzone-the-explorers-legacy-2025">Amerzone: The Explorer’s Legacy</a></em> remake from its previously planned November 2024 release window to the second quarter of 2025 (between April and June 2025). It will be available for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,369 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [6,364 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [21,707 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2429190/Amerzone__The_Explorers_Legacy/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a>. <span id="more-927987"></span></p><p>“We made this decision in order to guarantee players an optimal gaming experience and complete immersion in this extraordinary <a title="Genres > Adventure [1,867 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a>,” Microids said in a message. “There is still some work to be done on our side to make the game the way we imagine it: a vibrant tribute to Benoit Sokal and his work, but also an initiatory journey that both new and initiated players will be able to (re)discover in the best possible conditions.”</p><p>Get the full message from Microids below.</p><blockquote><p>Dear <em>Amerzone</em> fans,</p><p>We would like to share important news with you regarding the release of <em>Amerzone: The Explorer’s Legacy</em>.</p><p>Originally to be released on November 2024, the game will be postponed for several months, planned for the second quarter of 2025.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>We made this decision in order to guarantee players an optimal gaming experience and complete immersion in this extraordinary adventure.</p><p>There is still some work to be done on our side to make the game the way we imagine it: a vibrant tribute to Benoit Sokal and his work, but also an initiatory journey that both new and initiated players will be able to (re)discover in the best possible conditions on PC, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series.</p><p>We will keep you regularly posted, stay tuned!</p><p>Our deepest apologies for this discrepancy.</p><p>—Microids</p></blockquote></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PQube to publish top-down shooter Kusan: City of Wolves for PS5, Xbox Series, Switch, and PC in early 2026]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/11/pqube-to-publish-top-down-shooter-kusan-city-of-wolves-for-ps5-xbox-series-switch-and-pc-in-early-2026</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pqube-to-publish-top-down-shooter-kusan-city-of-wolves-for-ps5-xbox-series-switch-and-pc-in-early-2026.1036731/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/11/pqube-to-publish-top-down-shooter-kusan-city-of-wolves-for-ps5-xbox-series-switch-and-pc-in-early-2026<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><a title="Companies > PQube [361 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/pqube">PQube</a> will publish <a title="Companies > CIRCLEfromDOT" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/circlefromdot">CIRCLEfromDOT</a>-developed fast-paced hardcore top-down <a title="Genres > Shooter [3,932 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/shooter">shooter</a> <em><a title="Games > Kusan: City of Wolves" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/kusan-city-of-wolves">Kusan: City of Wolves</a></em> when it launches for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,369 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [6,364 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch [16,308 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [21,707 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1714510/Kusan__City_of_Wolves/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> in early 2026, the companies announced. <span id="more-927982"></span></p><p>“I believe that our partnership with PQube will serve as a solid cornerstone for our studio’s successful debut on the global stage,” CIRCLEfromDOT CEO Jeong-gyu Yeom said in a press release.</p><p>PQUBE chief managing officer Andy Pearson added, “We are proud to work with CIRCLEfromDOT on Kusan: City of Wolves. Ever since we downloaded the first demo, we’ve been playing <em>Kusan</em> relentlessly internally—we can’t wait to introduce it to players.”</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1714510/Kusan__City_of_Wolves/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam page</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>Kusan: City of Wolves</em> is a hardcore top-down shooter set in the bloody Port City of the Asia in the near future. Protect the girl against the coup plan of an old comrades. Be an expert in combat skills, prosthetics, guns, and knife. The fiercest beast in the city, you are.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>You are a former soldier turned back-alley fixer, tasked with protecting a girl who possesses the power to endanger the city. With your military-grade combat prosthetic “War Hand,” the auto-targeting “Quantum Knife,” and your weapon of choice, eliminate enemies and safeguard the girl. Stand against the plan of your fallen comrade and crush his corrupted will. You are faster and stronger than any beast.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>It’s time to engage in the fastest and most intense battles.</strong><ul><li>Use your steel fist, “War Hand,” to obliterate obstacles and enemies blocking your path.</li><li>The auto-targeting “Quantum Knife” is a secret military weapon only you can wield. Be strategic in choosing your position when facing enemies.</li><li>With the steel fist “War Hand,” the auto-throwing dagger “Quantum Knife,” and firearms, your attacks are flawless. Unleash all your attacks at the right moments.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Collect bolts to upgrade your equipment and unlock powerful <a title="Genres > Action [2,307 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a>s.</strong><ul><li>Swiftly and stylishly dispatch enemies to earn more bolts.</li><li>Gather bolts to upgrade your gear and acquire new firearms.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Listen to the mysterious girl’s voice.</strong><ul><li>Discover the stories of the characters through comic-style cutscenes and pixel art. What is the truth behind the girl’s wish to find her father? What are the intentions of the government agent hiding behind sunglasses?</li></ul></li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Publisher Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Kusan: City of Wolves | Partnership Announcement Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/cGS4H46O1F4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Microsoft's PC-Only Games Are An "Anomaly," Says Phil Spencer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/microsofts-pc-only-games-are-an-anomaly-says-phil-spencer/1100-6527786/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/microsofts-pc-only-games-are-an-anomaly-says-phil-spencer.1036728/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/microsofts-pc-only-games-are-an-anomaly-says-phil-spencer/1100-6527786/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6527786">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Between <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/world-of-warcraft-the-war-within-review-stay-awhile-and-listen/1900-6418275/" data-ref-id="1900-6418275">World of Warcraft: The War Within</a>, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ara-history-untold-combines-civilization-with-an-unexpected-dash-of-battle-royale/1100-6526090/" data-ref-id="1100-6526090">Ara: History Untold</a>, and the early-access release of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/towerborne-uses-deep-combat-to-modernize-the-side-scrolling-brawler/1100-6526124/" data-ref-id="1100-6526124">Towerborne</a>, Microsoft has an unusually prominent slate of PC-only games this fall. Of those three titles, Towerborne will eventually make it to Xbox Series X|S, but don't get used to having Microsoft games skipping consoles. The company's gaming CEO, Phil Spencer, has indicated that this was "an anomaly" that's unlikely to be repeated.</p><p>"This is historical," Spencer told <a href="https://www.gamefile.news/p/xbox-phil-spencer-blizzard-avowed-south-of-midnight" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Game FIle</a>. "There might always be some anomalies, but I look at those three as an anomaly. We want our games playable across as many screens as possible. We think about the Xbox platform as the Xbox console, PC, and cloud. We want all the games playable across all of those. We want them to be Play Anywhere."</p><p>While there don't appear to be any plans to bring World of Warcraft to Xbox consoles, Spencer has been bullish about <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/microsoft-ceo-comments-on-xbox-games-coming-to-playstation/1100-6522971/" data-ref-id="1100-6522971">sharing select Microsoft-owned titles with Sony's PlayStation</a>. The most prominent example is <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-campaign-review/1900-6418306/" data-ref-id="1900-6418306">Call of Duty: Black Ops 6</a>, but even upcoming games like <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-hands-on-preview/1100-6527431/" data-ref-id="1100-6527431">Indiana Jones and the Great Circle</a> will get a PS5 release after an initial debut on Xbox consoles and PC. Spencer also mentioned his larger goal of allowing players to own a title regardless of where they're playing it.</p><p>"We want to get to the point where, when you buy, whether you're buying on cloud--which we're getting ready to introduce--buying on PC and buying on console, you own it across all of the Xbox ecosystem," said Spencer.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox, PlayStation, And Nintendo Console Market "Isn't Growing," Phil Spencer Says]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/xbox-playstation-and-nintendo-console-market-isnt-growing-phil-spencer-says/1100-6527787/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/xbox-playstation-and-nintendo-console-market-isnt-growing-phil-spencer-says.1036725/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/xbox-playstation-and-nintendo-console-market-isnt-growing-phil-spencer-says/1100-6527787/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6527787">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>The video game console market "isn't growing," Microsoft Gaming CEO Phil Spencer said in a new interview, and that's part of the reason why you <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/new-xbox-campaign-reminds-people-xbox-is-more-than-just-the-console/1100-6527759/" data-ref-id="1100-6527759">don't need an Xbox to play Xbox these days. </a></p><p>"The console space all up isn't growing, across all of them [Xbox, PlayStation, and Nintendo]. We love those customers, but in terms of continuing to expand and grow Xbox, it's about PC, it's about cloud, and it's about making our games more available in more places," Spencer told <a href="https://www.rollingstone.com/culture/rs-gaming/xbox-console-future-cloud-ceo-phil-spencer-1235166597/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Rolling Stone</a>.</p><p>Just because the console market isn't growing, that doesn't mean Microsoft is abandoning consoles. Spencer said Microsoft will "definitely do more consoles in the future," as well as "other devices."</p><p>None of this is a surprise, as Microsoft has already confirmed a next-gen Xbox that promises the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/next-xbox-release-date-specs-display-price/1100-6525379/" data-ref-id="1100-6525379">"largest technical leap" in Xbox history</a>. As for the "other devices," Spencer may be referring to the Xbox handheld device that is a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/xbox-handheld-device-is-a-few-years-out-apparently/1100-6527758/" data-ref-id="1100-6527758">"few years out."</a></p><p>Also in the interview, Spencer reiterated that Microsoft is probably not planning a mid-gen Xbox refresh, like Sony did with the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ps5-pro-review-powerful-on-paper-ordinary-in-action/1100-6527571/" data-ref-id="1100-6527571">PS5 Pro</a>. He said, "We don't need to do incremental hardware for our own benefit. Does a new device really give you a unique experience on screen in some way?"</p><p>Years ago, the leap between the original Xbox and Xbox 360 was significant in terms of graphics and performance, Spencer said, but these days "it's harder to show the benefits" of more powerful hardware alone.</p><p>A new <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/new-xbox-campaign-reminds-people-xbox-is-more-than-just-the-console/1100-6527759/" data-ref-id="1100-6527759">"This Is An Xbox" ad campaign</a> reminds people that Xbox is no longer limited to being a piece of plastic under your TV. Your phone is an Xbox, as is your TV, and any number of other devices, because Xbox games--and Game Pass--are available in those places. Spencer said he understands some part of the Xbox audience enjoys the "simplicity of a single box, single platform, single game." But the reality is that, "Today's largest games are bigger than any of the individual platforms."</p><p>He said the Xbox platform should be about games, characters, and worlds, as opposed to any one dedicated device. "That's how we think about Xbox today," he said.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>