<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 22:54:57 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Even Trump’s Pentagon Is Selling Rare Pokémon Cards Now]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/even-trumps-pentagon-is-selling-rare-pokemon-cards-now-2000661388</link>
            <guid>1411432</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><span>Rare </span><i><span>Pokémon </span></i><span>cards are locked up in one of the most secure locations in the United States. The Surging Sparks Pikachu, which includes a full art illustration of the little yellow guy adorned in a Stellar-type Tera crown, is sitting in a Lucky Box vending machine in the Pentagon food court. Good luck getting into that, </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-card-shops-robbed-100k-nyc-masked-thieves-anime-backpacks-recently-opened-2000660233"><span>card robbers</span></a><span>.</span></p> <p><a href="https://www.404media.co/theres-a-lootbox-with-rare-pokemon-cards-sitting-in-the-pentagon-food-court/?ref=aftermath.site"><i><span>404 Media</span></i></a><span> reports that the Lucky Box vending machine, which is essentially a gacha machine for rare, graded cards of both the sports and trading card game variety, was seemingly put up in the United States’ military headquarters </span><a href="https://taskandpurpose.com/news/pentagon-lucky-box/?ref=404media.co"><span>around Christmas Eve last month</span></a><span>.&nbsp;</span></p>

   <figure id="attachment_2000661404" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000661404"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000661404">© The Pokémon Company</figcaption></figure> <p><span>In a now-deleted Threads announcement, Lucky Box posted that it had set up one of its loot box machines in the Pentagon food court, and&nbsp; among the potential prizes which the machine’s display touts could be yours if you blindly give it some cash is the aforementioned Pikachu card. Based on photos posted on the </span><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/army/comments/1qbc0du/comment/nz9gcjz/?ref=404media.co"><span>Army subreddit</span></a><span>, the machine also has an image of a giant Charizard card on the side of it, but it’s unclear if that’s just decoration or if the original fire-breathing dragon card is also in that specific machine. Taking your chances at a Luck Box machine can cost anywhere from $100 to $200.</span></p> <p><span>Lucky Box’s </span><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DSf3_KvCWta/"><span>social media accounts</span></a><span> include photos of big winners, some of whom won rare </span><i><span>Pokémon </span></i><span>cards, while others won autographed jerseys from various sports teams. But it doesn’t look like they’ve posted anyone scoring something big in the middle of the Pentagon yet. In fact, most of its posts feature the boxes in Las Vegas, where </span><a href="https://luckyboxvending.com/pages/store-locator"><span>over 20 of the machines are found</span></a><span>. The winners that are featured are finding some pretty valuable </span><i><span>Pokémon </span></i><span>cards, though, from a rare Venusaur to the ancient Mew promo card from </span><i><span>Pokémon: The First Movie</span></i><span>’s theatrical run.</span></p>   <p><i><span>Pokémon </span></i><span>cards are already pretty much considered gambling by people who crack packs open by the dozens in the hopes of scoring a quick buck, but it’s still striking to see that concept&nbsp; demonstrated as blatantly as it is here, with valuable cards locked away in a machine that requires people to shell out hundreds of dollars for a small chance of scoring one.. Thank goodness the most powerful military in the world is keeping its eye on the machine until the lucky winner comes along. </span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/even-trumps-pentagon-is-selling-rare-pokemon-cards-now-2000661388]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Woman Creates Super Console Containing PS5, Xbox, And Switch 2]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/woman-creates-super-console-containing-ps5-xbox-and-switch-2-2000661391</link>
            <guid>1411429</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><a href="https://kotaku.com/console-wars-are-over-ps5-xbox-forza-switch-2-sony-1851752956">The console wars ended a while ago</a>, in case you didn’t know. But if they were still raging on, a talented hardware modder in China created a device that would force a lasting peace. It’s a massive and very cleverly designed triangular box that contains an Xbox, PlayStation, and Switch 2. They all work and can be easily swapped between with the press of a button.</p> <p><a href="https://www.tomshardware.com/video-games/console-gaming/modder-builds-all-in-one-console-with-ps5-xbox-series-x-and-switch-2-in-a-single-system-ningtendo-pxbox-5-powered-by-a-shared-250w-power-supply-mounted-inside-a-lost-wax-chassis">As first spotted by <em>Tom’s Hardware</em>,</a> Chinese tech and computer expert <em>小宁子 XNZ&nbsp;</em><a href="https://youtu.be/FAIqzpbv9Xw">has created an all-in-one mega console</a> which she anointed the “Ningtendo PXBOX 5,” a name that just rolls right off the tongue. According to XNZ, the idea behind this wild device came from her wanting to play various console-exclusive games without having to get up and manually power on and off each machine to switch between them.</p>

  <p>The design of the monster machine is inspired by the <a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/112025">2013 Apple Mac Pro, aka the one that looked like a trash can</a>. And while she didn’t use the actual innards of an old Mac, the inside of that strange computer was a triangular setup that ended up being the perfect design to house three disassembled gaming consoles. A fan at the bottom is then used to cool the consoles.</p> <p>But creating a triangular heatsink for that would be expensive, so XNZ used an ancient method known as lost-wax casting to create the high-end piece of tech. Essentially, you first create an object out of an easy-to-melt piece of material, like wax or plastic, and then coat it in a heat-resistant material. Then you heat the object and all the soft insides melt and you can pour molten metal inside, which hardens and cools into your desired shape. Nifty!</p>

 <p>The end product is an impressive device but it might not be the most practical. The power supply she used only allows one console at a time to play a game, though the others can idle in the background. A big button on top switches the HDMI input between the consoles. Probably easier and cheaper to just buy the consoles and an HDMI switcher with a remote, but that’s not nearly as cool as the Ningtendo PXBOX 5.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/woman-creates-super-console-containing-ps5-xbox-and-switch-2-2000661391]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[StarCraft II Won’t Be At EWC 2026, Nor Will Any Other RTS Title]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/starcraft-ii-wont-be-at-ewc-2026-nor-any-rts/</link>
            <guid>1411426</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>The recent announcement of the full Esports World Cup 2026 lineup has rattled RTS fans worldwide. The team at the Esports World Cup Foundation recently unveiled the <strong>last game </strong>in the roster, <strong>Trackmania</strong>, which is set to appear at the event in Riyadh for the first time.</p>



<p>However, this reveal means that StarCraft II, the beloved RTS game, <strong>will not </strong>surface at this year’s Esports World Cup, despite being present for the first two. It gets worse, as with the full lineup having been published, we know that <strong>no other RTS game </strong>will be there to replace it.</p>











<p>For the first time since the inaugural Esports World Cup in 2023, no RTS title will take to any stage at the event this year. The EWCF uncovered Trackmania as an unexpected final addition to the star-studded spread of titles gracing the Esports World Cup, and in that moment, RTS fans worldwide fell to their knees (metaphorically, of course).</p>



<p>Across social media, fans have voiced their displeasure at the snub. Kaelaris, a popular commentator and host with a penchant for StarCraft II, said:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>I was already having a rough day but no StarCraft at EWC hurts.</p>



<p>I suspect that also means I won’t be doing any SC2 in 2026 since that was the only place nowadays that fancies taking a desk host for the game.</p>



<p>Despite getting to do it at EWC last year, effectively to me it feels like a part of my life perished and I feel like I’m almost in mourning for that aspect of my world. It’s not been easy for my brain to get over it. That’s as best I can describe it at least.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>In another post, creator and commentator Simon ‘Lowko’ Heijnen wrote:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>Very sad to not have StarCraft 2 or any other RTS game at the EWC this year. Especially considering views and interest has been up noticeably compared to a few years ago.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Many were quick to point out that the Esports World Cup helped keep the competitive system afloat after waning interest and some tournament shutdowns. This is another major, international stage to be stripped from the RTS audience, and it’s a huge blow.</p>



<p>The Esports World Cup 2026 is shaping up to be the largest esports event ever held. But for many, it might be remembered as the year that the oldest competitive genre in esports was forgotten, pushed aside for an arcade racing game.</p>







<p>Do you think StarCraft II deserves a spot at the Esports World Cup? Let us know your thoughts on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming esports, check out the news that the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/esports-world-cup-2026-prize-pool-75-million/">Esports World Cup will boast a $75 million prize pool</a></p>


        <div>
                  <p>
                    Grant's passion for gaming started on the Amstrad CPC when he wasn't even old enough to walk properly. Now, he's a multi-platform expert gamer with an undying love for the…                  </p>
                  <p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/author/grant-taylor-hill/">
                    More from Grant Taylor-Hill                  </a>
                </p></div>
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/starcraft-ii-wont-be-at-ewc-2026-nor-any-rts/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Whiskerwood Is Already One Of The Finest City-Builders I Have Ever Played]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/whiskerwood-review-impressions-pc-city-builder-hooded-horse/</link>
            <guid>1411423</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
      <p><a href="https://aftermath.site/game-of-the-year-2025-aftermath-luke-plunkett/" rel="noreferrer">My 2025 obsession with city-builders</a> is running straight through into 2026 with <em>Whiskerwood</em>, which recently came out in Early Access and which, even unfinished, is legitimately one of the best and most interesting examples of the genre.</p><figure><a href="https://aftermath.site/game-of-the-year-2025-aftermath-luke-plunkett/"><div><p>Luke’s Favourite Video Games Of 2025</p><p>A year where indie city-builders carried the load following some big AAA disappointments</p><p><span>Luke Plunkett</span></p></div></a></figure><p>Set in the 1700s (though, not <em>our </em>1700s), you play as the leader of some little mice (<em>Redwall</em> fans, ahoy) who have been sent by their cat overlords to settle a distant (and importantly, unoccupied) land. Upon landing and picking out your settlement spot you begin a survival city-builder that appears to be quite conventional: you need to harvest timber and stone so you can build houses and farms, which you’ll need to support a growing population, while also keeping everyone fed and warm so they don't die during the depths of winter.&nbsp;</p><p>Were that all there was to this game, just a city-builder starring cute little mice, it would still be great. There's a staggering amount of tech and buildings to unlock, and a ton of resources to work with. What begins with picking berries and chopping down logs gets very quickly into pipe systems and mass transportation, and while early on you’re only building houses and docks, later you’ll need multiple buildings specialising in the inputs required for everything from tailored winter clothing to scissors.&nbsp;</p><figure><iframe width="200" height="113" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/X4VVSaG9WnE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen="" title="Whiskerwood - Launch Trailer | Cats &amp; Mice City-Builder Game"></iframe></figure><p><em>Whiskerwood</em> does a fantastic job of tracking the myriad of resources required to support this burgeoning commercial network. Click on a building and you’re instantly shown everything you need to know, like where the workers are right now on the map, what they’re doing, what the status of its current production is and what, if anything, is holding that up. Need to find a specific building, or a count of how much tea everyone has drunk today? It’s all 1-2 clicks away. I know this sounds like something all city-builders do and should do, but they don’t! Failing to tell the player all the information they need is where so many of them fall down!</p><p>The production chains, while appearing daunting at first glance, are also pretty fun to get going. <em>Whiskerwood</em> is packed with workshops that will turn something raw into something processed, then turn that processed thing into something else. Sometimes it’ll need more raw ingredients, sometimes it’ll need fresh water (requiring a piped water network) and often combinations of all of those. It’s very clear how to get these all up and running and to keep track of how they’re going, so from humble beginnings you can get some cool stuff going late-game, to the point it feels like <em>Factorio</em> in parts as you strive for the most economical way possible to move your resources from building to building (the developers’ last game went very hard on production).&nbsp;</p><p>It’s clear the team have put a <em>lot </em>of thought into what makes these games sing beyond the basics. You know everything you need to know at all times, thanks to the on-screen indicators and menus. The Interface is wonderful, and designed in a way that keeps you busy constantly; there’s always something broken or short on supply, which requires you to personally attend to it and generally make very precise orders, but rather than being an annoyance or something you wish could be automated, here it’s just an invitation to get creative. Mistakes in <em>Whiskerwood</em> are <em>fun</em>, a rarity in city-builders, but especially in survival ones.&nbsp;</p><figure></figure><p>The emphasis on logistics is also astounding in how thorough and robust it is, even at this Early Access stage. <em>Whiskerwood</em> runs on a day/night cycle, limiting the amount of work every mouse can do each day, so it's imperative to make sure your workers’ commutes are as short as possible, while also optimising the delivery of goods through first direct paths, then later on conveyer belts, elevators and even railways. Commutes even factor into a mouse’s happiness, so <em>Whiskerwood</em> is in effect asking you to build several 15-minute settlements across the map, then endlessly refine them in a way that’s so taxing, and rewarding, that it could have just been its own video game.</p><p>But that’s not all there is to it. Remarkably, <em>Whiskerwood</em> also has <a href="https://aftermath.site/sid-meiers-colonization-pc-windows-game/" rel="noreferrer">a whole <em>Sid Meier’s</em> <em>Colonization</em> thing going on as well</a>, set in a politically tumultuous time, and laced with secessionist possibilities. Just like in <em>Colonization</em> your overlords are assholes, and just like in <em>Colonization</em> they’re also necessary because they’re supplying you, so you pay your taxes (colonial ships arrive at your towns periodically and demand huge portions of your goods), you buy fancy gear from home and you will like it. And just like in <em>Colonization</em>, a big part of your workforce planning is defined by the skills and experience your colonists have when they land, making some much better suited to certain jobs than others.</p><figure><a href="https://aftermath.site/sid-meiers-colonization-pc-windows-game/"><div><p>Sid Meier’s Colonization Is The American Video Game - Aftermath</p><p>No game has told the American story better, whether intentionally or not</p><p><span>Aftermath</span><span>Luke Plunkett</span></p></div></a></figure><p>The bigger your colony gets, and the more self-sufficient it becomes, the more you can start to question that power balance, and maybe do something about it. Annoy the motherland enough and they’ll snap, cutting you off from vital supplies and sending warships to your harbour which bombard you, causing huge amounts of destruction which you need to repair.&nbsp;</p><p>There’s also…well actually that’s about it for the rebellion stuff, which is very much in an either unfinished or not-even-there-yet stage. You can see where the game’s going to try to go with it, but it’s clearly prioritising city-building at this stage of development over its political play.</p><p>I know I spent a lot of time in 2025 talking about city-building and resource management, so I'm sorry to begin 2026 doing exactly the same thing. But hey, it's not my fault the folks making cool games in this genre are getting so smart and making such interesting stuff. And <em>Whiskerwood</em> is one of the smartest I’ve played in a <em>long </em>time. </p>
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://aftermath.site/whiskerwood-review-impressions-pc-city-builder-hooded-horse/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[1047 Games Makes One (Final?) Bid to Keep Splitgate: Arena Reloaded Alive With New Arena Royale Mode]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/1047-games-makes-one-final-bid-splitgate-arena-reloaded-battle-royale-arena-royale/</link>
            <guid>1411411</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p><strong>1047 Games</strong> is making one, potentially final, bid to keep <strong>Splitgate: Arena Reloaded</strong> alive with a new battle royale mode called <strong>Arena Royale</strong>. If you weren't aware, Splitgate: Arena Reloaded is the new title for <strong>Splitgate 2</strong>, a name that emerged after <a href="https://wccftech.com/splitgate-2-back-to-beta-re-launch-2026-og-splitgate-servers-shutdown-1047-games-layoffs/">the maligned sequel was relaunched, and 1047 Games decided to shut down the OG Splitgate servers.</a> Arena Reloaded is meant to represent a combination of the best of both games, just like how its new Arena Royale mode is intended to be the best parts of a battle royale and an arena shooter in one.</p>



<p>That's the pitch made by 1047 Games design director <strong>Josh Watson</strong>, who breaks down what the team didn't like about current battle royales and how it let those feelings lead the design of Arena Royale to make a game mode that is still technically a battle royale mode, but in the most arena shooter way possible.</p>



<p>"<em>When we sat down to design Arena Royale, we knew we wanted to push it closer to that arena feel</em>," Watson begins. "<em>And we kept coming back to this core idea: <strong>less looting, more shooting</strong>. You see,</em> <em>traditional battle royales have long stretches where you're not really playing. You're staring at chests, traversing</em> <em>empty space, and waiting for your next fight."</em></p>



<p>"<em>Arena shooters are the opposite. They're about fast action and fast engagement. Arena Royale is the best of both worlds</em>."</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Introducing Arena Royale | SPLITGATE: Arena Reloaded" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/dvueCO7-ofo?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>Watson goes on to explain some of the core differences between the kind of battle royale you're already familiar with and the kind that 1047 Games has put together. You won't drop from a ship; you'll instead be dropped into a lobby ahead of every match, where you'll vote between one of the four available maps by standing in front of the one you want. </p>



<p>When the match begins, you'll instantly spawn in and go from there. The four available maps (or biomes, as Watson calls them) are <strong>Dought, Glacier, Fracture</strong>, and <strong>Outskirts</strong>, which is an entirely new biome that, frankly, at a quick glance, looks like a smaller knock-off of Kings Canyon from <strong>Apex Legends</strong>. That's not necessarily a bad thing; Kings Canyon is a pretty iconic map with some great POIs. If you're going to pull inspiration from anywhere, might as well pull it from what you know people already like.</p>



<p>Moving forward, other ways in which Arena Royale mixes an arena shooter and a battle royale is by doing away with any battle royale tropes that get in the way of fights. This manifests with chests opening instantly, a player's loot dropping in a big pile instantly when they die (no going through deathboxes), and most importantly, in its low player count, with only <strong>24 players to a match</strong>, in <strong>six teams of four</strong>.</p>



<p>You also won't find buy stations in any of Arena Royale's biomes, as you're able to upgrade equipment on the fly with money earned by doing damage, racking up kills, and completing events like Split Ball, Firecracker, and Hot Zone.</p>



<p><a href="https://wccftech.com/splitgate-2-relaunch-late-december-1047-games/">Since Splitgate 2 relaunched</a>, unfortunately for the team at 1047 Games, it doesn't seem to have taken off. The relaunch came and went without anyone really noticing. The last time we heard from the team ahead of this update was to try and grab some attention and press <a href="https://wccftech.com/splitgate-dev-responds-to-low-player-counts-steam-charts-dont-measure-fun/">by responding to claims that the game was dead/dying due to its poor concurrent player numbers on Steam</a>.</p>



<p>Making a big hullabaloo about its lacking Steam numbers did not, it may shock you to learn, <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/2918300/charts/">give it a boost in player numbers on Steam</a>. While Steam concurrent numbers are never the full picture, they're an indicator that, at least on one platform, Splitgate: Arena Reloaded has been unable to gain any serious traction. If that doesn't change, and if things aren't much better on Xbox or PlayStation, then the next time we see a major statement from the studio could very likely be about the studio and the game shutting down.</p>



<p>The Arena Royale mode and the rest of update 2.2 will arrive this Thursday, on <strong>January 22, 2026.</strong></p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/1047-games-makes-one-final-bid-splitgate-arena-reloaded-battle-royale-arena-royale/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Steam’s New Anime Animal Crossing Cozy Sim Gets Bullied Into Disclosing Gen AI]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/heartopia-ai-steam-animal-crossing-cozy-sim-2000661394</link>
            <guid>1411405</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><span>The </span><i><span>Animal Crossing</span></i><span>-like cozy life sim </span><i><span>Heartopia </span></i><span>is one of the biggest new games on Steam this month. It’s also made with AI-generated content according to a new disclosure by the developers.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><i><span>Heartopia</span></i><span> is developer and publisher XD International’s answer to the question, “What if </span><i><span>Animal Crossing</span></i><span> was a chibi anime?” It dropped on January 17 following a wave of closed betas in both November and December 2025. Concurrent players peaked at over 35,000.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><span>Reviews have been mixed, though. It currently sits at only a 66 percent positive rating on Steam. And many of the negative responses from players on Valve’s platform are taking issue with the developer not disclosing their use of AI-generated artwork in </span><i><span>Heartopia.</span></i></p>

 <figure id="attachment_2000661397" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000661397"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000661397">Discord</figcaption></figure> <p><span>“This game contains Generative AI (used to generate the puzzles), which they didn’t disclose until the accusations of it surfaced,” writes user </span><a href="https://steamcommunity.com/id/paruisfree/recommended/4025700/"><span>parupa206</span></a><span>. The use of AI wasn’t made public until </span><a href="https://www.gamingbible.com/news/new-cosy-animal-crossing-gen-ai-053843-20260120"><i><span>GAMINGbible’s</span></i><span> Richard Breslin</span></a><span> emailed </span><i><span>Heartopia’s </span></i><span>UK PR team earlier this week. A statement from the developer appeared on Discord not that long after.</span></p> <p><span>“Monetization Content in Heartopia does not include AI-generated materials,” read part of the message to fans. “Should any AI-assisted content be used in the game in the future, it will be announced in advance. Marketing materials produced outside the game, including those created in collaboration with third-party suppliers, are not covered by the scope of this disclosure.”</span></p>

 <p><span>Since then, </span><i><span>Heartopia’s</span></i><span> Steam page has been updated to include a newly added “AI Generated Content Disclosure” section, which states that “AI is used in the puzzle gameplay to reinterpret and redraw in-game snapshot images” and that AI is also “used in in-game chat to help players understand different languages.”</span></p>

 <p><span>The devs have seemingly not apologized for not disclosing their use of AI-generated assets on Steam in any of the official </span><i><span>Heartopia </span></i><span>channels that I could find, and, given how </span><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dZMFYb1_MWc"><span>blatantly obvious</span></a><span> its usage appears to be in its puzzle minigame, I’m not sure how they ever thought they’d get away with not disclosing this in the first place.</span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/heartopia-ai-steam-animal-crossing-cozy-sim-2000661394]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 Surpasses Elden Ring in All-Time GOTY Awards]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/clair-obscur-expedition-33-surpasses-elden-ring-in-all-time-goty-awards/</link>
            <guid>1411402</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 was undoubtedly the hottest game of 2025, and now, thanks to the tracking of <a href="https://www.resetera.com/threads/2025-video-game-awards-season-tracking-and-discussion-thread.1348411/">Rese</a><a href="https://www.resetera.com/threads/2025-video-game-awards-season-tracking-and-discussion-thread.1348411/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">t</a><a href="https://www.resetera.com/threads/2025-video-game-awards-season-tracking-and-discussion-thread.1348411/">Era, </a>it has been uncovered that the Sandfall Interactive-developed title has surpassed Elden Ring as the top game in history to win the most Game of the Year Awards. 436 outlets have awarded the title game of the year. Elden Ring previously had the record at 429 Game of the Year award wins.</p>



<p>Game of the Year Awards have been awarded to Expedition 33 by outlets such as Geoff Keighley’s Game Awards, Famitsu, GameSpot, IGN, Game Rant, GamesRadar+, and Esquire. Additionally, they were awarded Reader’s Choice Game of the Year awards by the readers here <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/clair-obscur-expedition-33-insider-gaming-community-2025-game-of-the-year/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">at Insider Gaming</a>, Destructoid, Game Informer, and more.</p>



<figure><div><blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 has overtaken Elden Ring for the most Game of the Year wins ever.</p><p>• Expedition 33 – 436<br>• Elden Ring – 429<br>• The Last of Us Part II – 326 <a href="https://t.co/hHHk1qL1Np">pic.twitter.com/hHHk1qL1Np</a></p></div>— KAMI (@Okami13_) <a href="https://twitter.com/Okami13_/status/2013695912447463740?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 20, 2026</a></blockquote></div></figure>







<h2 id="h-the-team-behind-clair-obscur-expedition-33-says-they-were-surprised-by-the-success-of-their-game">The Team Behind Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 Says They Were Surprised by the Success of Their Game</h2>



<p>As the awards keep rolling in for the game, the creative director behind the game, Guillaume Broche, said in a recent interview with Edge Magazine that the success of the game was a surprise to everyone on their team.</p>



<blockquote>
<p>“What really surprised us the most is how much the narrative and cinematics and story resonated with people. This is the thing that’s hardest to quantify, because it’s always something very personal. So the fact that this worked so well, pretty much instantly, this was the thing where we were like ‘Ok, this is one hundred times what we were expecting’,” he said <a href="https://www.gamesradar.com/games/rpg/clair-obscur-expedition-33-director-says-the-french-rpgs-success-was-completely-unexpected-from-pretty-much-everybody-at-the-studio/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">(via GamesRadar+)</a></p>
</blockquote>







<p>It hasn’t been all smooth sailing for RPG, however. The Indie Game Awards recently had to disqualify the game after discovering its use of generative AI. Learn more about that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/indie-game-awards-disqualifies-clair-obscur-expedition-33-gen-ai/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">here</a>. For additional information on Clair Obscur: Expedition 33, learn more the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/sandfall-reveals-budget-clair-obscur-expedition-33/">budget behind the game’s development.</a></p>



<hr>



<p>Do you think another game will ever reach the heights and critical acclaim of Clair Obscur: Expedition 33? Sound off in our official<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW"> Discord server.</a> Also, don’t forget to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;<br></p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/clair-obscur-expedition-33-surpasses-elden-ring-in-all-time-goty-awards/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fortnite Creators Are Using Women To Chase Clout And Make Money]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/fortnite-creators-are-using-women-to-chase-clout-and-make-money-2000661353</link>
            <guid>1411387</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Some of the most popular <em>Fortnite</em> custom content creators and studios are using young women in their ads, but not making it clear whether the woman made the map or is just a spokesperson. This is causing frustration among some female <em>Fortnite</em> creators trying to find success online with their own maps.</p> <p>User-generated content is becoming a bigger and bigger part of Epic’s online battle royale metaverse, <em>Fortnite</em>. Some popular maps have tens of thousands of players online at one time. Some user-created maps and modes can even <a href="https://kotaku.com/fortnite-only-up-steam-game-pc-uefn-epic-popular-1850615732">become more popular than <em>Fortnite’s</em> official modes.</a> And the creators and teams behind these maps can make a lot of money if one of their creations goes viral, thanks to Epic’s system for paying developers based on how long people play custom maps and how often they come back to them. Some creators are making millions of dollars from these maps.</p>

 <p>As you might expect, that amount of money floating around means there are people trying to gain any edge they can in the <em>Fortnite</em> clout economy, including misleading players about who is actually behind new user-generated content. <a href="https://gamesbeat.com/male-fortnite-creators-are-enlisting-young-women-to-market-their-maps-and-co-op-their-identities/">A new report from <em>GamesBeat</em></a> dives deep into the ongoing controversy around male <a href="https://fortnite.gg/creators"><em>Fortnite</em> creators</a> and large content studios primarily using young women in social videos and online posts without always disclosing how that woman is actually connected to the map or mode being advertised.</p> <p>Pandvil is one of the most followed and highest-earning <em>Fortnite</em> creators around. <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DSHB2XbEXF2/?igsh=NTc4MTIwNjQ2YQ%3D%3D&amp;img_index=4">And if you look at some</a> <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DSK2mtpjD1F/?hl=en">posts online,</a> you’d likely believe that Pandvil is a woman. There’s even a meme that references people discovering that the creator is a woman. However, that’s reportedly not the case. <em>GamesBeat</em> spoke to three individuals who have knowledge of the real-life creator’s identity and who claimed the woman seen in many of Pandvil’s videos isn’t the creator. Instead, she’s allegedly a social media manager employed by the creator’s studio, further blurring the lines between spokesperson and developer.</p>   <p>Pandvil seems to lean into the idea of him being a young woman, and he’s not alone. <em>GamesBeat</em> reports that <em>Fortnite</em> creators <a href="https://www.instagram.com/hivecr8/">Team Hive</a> and <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@unc.creative/video/7509941569529679126">UNC Creative</a> also post many videos online featuring women who aren’t the creators of the maps they’re promoting, though in Hive’s case, <a href="https://x.com/hivesisters/">they do openly employ women</a> who act as the studio’s social media and marketing team. And while women have been used to market products, including games, for a very long time, the parasocial nature of online creator spaces makes this different.</p>

 <p>If you’re just randomly scrolling through your feed and stumble upon one of these videos, you might assume the creator is the young woman in the video describing the new map or mode, not realizing she’s just a paid spokesperson or community manager. Other female island creators who spoke to <em>GamesBeat</em> shared frustrations and misgivings with this marketing strategy. They felt that it could hurt them financially by taking away possible media coverage and brand deals or siphoning away players.</p>

 <p>Mackenzie Bell, the co-founder of content studio <a href="https://www.instagram.com/fn_alliance/?hl=en">Alliance Studios</a>, didn’t blame creators for using women in ads, but instead wants Epic to improve the <em>Fortnite</em> creator ecosystem. “It’s less about calling out the individual creators or teams and more about addressing the overall systemic issues,” <a href="https://gamesbeat.com/male-fortnite-creators-are-enlisting-young-women-to-market-their-maps-and-co-op-their-identities/">Bell told <em>GamesBeat</em></a>. “If the platform and the creator economy balance itself better, with stronger discovery tools, more equitable payouts and support for diverse voices, I think creators wouldn’t feel as pressured to lean into potentially misleading marketing just to survive.”</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/fortnite-creators-are-using-women-to-chase-clout-and-make-money-2000661353]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fallout 3 and New Vegas Remakes Not Releasing Any Time Soon, It’s Claimed]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/fallout-3-and-new-vegas-remakes-not-releasing-any-time-soon-its-claimed/</link>
            <guid>1411384</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>If you were hoping to play the new remakes of either Fallout 3 or Fallout: New Vegas, don’t expect to play them anytime soon, according to a new report.</p>



<p><a href="https://www.windowscentral.com/gaming/no-bethesda-isnt-shadow-dropping-fallout-3-and-new-vegas-remasters-any-time-soon-heres-what-we-know" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Jez Corden of Windows Central </a>recently stated that while the sought-after remakes are on the way, they are not slated for an imminent release and should not be expected in the near future. However, Corden suggests that when the time comes for these releases, fans should expect to see the Fallout 3 remake before New Vegas.</p>







<h2 id="h-how-bethesda-feels-about-the-future-of-the-fallout-franchise">How Bethesda Feels About the Future of the Fallout Franchise</h2>



<p>It is known that Bethesda is working on Fallout 5 and would ideally like players to spend many hours, potentially 600, playing that future title. It’s also been confirmed by Todd Howard that the next game will be tied into the ongoing Fallout television show.</p>



<p>As for other Fallout games,<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fallout-4-patch/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow"> Fallout 4 recently received a major patch from Bethesda</a>. There are also impressive mods for the game, such as <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/todd-howard-no-interest-fallout-4-mod-london/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Fallout: London</a>, even though Todd Howard has said he personally has no interest in that. </p>



<p>Also, Fallout 76 is slated to get a current-gen upgrade this year, and there is <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fallout-76-burning-springs-release-notes-pts/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Fallout 76: Burning Springs that was recently released. </a>Howard recently claimed that Fallout 76 was the game Bethesda was currently putting the most work into.</p>







<p>Additionally, there is the aforementioned Fallout TV series, and there’s now a new Fallout Shelter reality series. To learn how to apply to that reality show, click <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/apply-for-fallout-shelter-reality-show-explained/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">here</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>Are you eagerly awaiting remakes of Fallout 3 and Fallout New Vegas? Sound off in our official<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW"> Discord server.</a> Also, don’t forget to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;<br></p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/fallout-3-and-new-vegas-remakes-not-releasing-any-time-soon-its-claimed/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Best Board Games That Channel the Spirit of Anime]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/best-anime-board-games</link>
            <guid>1411381</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle" data-autopogo="true"><p data-cy="paragraph">Anime is awesome. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-board-games-all-time">Board games</a> are also awesome. Put the two together, and you get tabletop fun that not only shows off some of the hottest anime series out there, but can also capture the wild nature of the animated media and their associated tropes. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">While there are plenty of games that have animed-themed versions like Naruto Monopoly or Dragonball Z Yahtzee, this list instead focuses on games that use the IPs they feature as a theme rather than simply being an anime reskin, and games that do a great job in replicating the look, feel, or tropes of this beloved art form. </p><p id="featured-in-this-article"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Featured in this article">Featured in this article</h2></p><p data-cy="paragraph">Just as a side note before we get into the list itself, this will only feature board games and won’t go into the plethora of solid anime TCGs that exist, like Digimon and One Piece, or TTRPGs either. Those are out there, and I recommend seeking those out, too, if that is more your style.</p><p id="react-the-arts-of-war"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Re;ACT - The Arts of War">Re;ACT - The Arts of War</h2></p><div id="234233"><div><p><span data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><div id="234233" data-cy="solo-product-card"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Re;ACT - The Arts of War</h3></p></div></span></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Fast-paced matches with hot-looking anime characters, each with dynamic and unique mechanics? Sign me up! Re;Act from Brother Ming Games puts players in the roles of artists who've been granted powers based on their respective art forms and are pitted against one another in a 1v1 showdown. Described as “Yugioh meets chess” by the creator Ming Yang Lu, where the importance of positioning from chess crosses over with the interrupts and actions of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/yu-gi-oh-tcg">Yugioh</a>, where you will declare your intentions by playing a card before allowing the opponent to play a reaction, acting akin to a trap card. From super-powered  Calligraphers to Dancers, Animators, and Painters, Re;Act: The Arts of War is shonen anime in a box and a blast to play.</p></div><p id="millennium-blades"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Millennium Blades">Millennium Blades</h2></p><div id="234398"><div><p><span data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><div id="234398" data-cy="solo-product-card"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Millennium Blades</h3></p></div></span></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Crack packs, build decks, and outfit yourself with the coolest deckbox out there in Millennium Blades – a board game about competing in a card game. Players are pro TCG players who are all vying to win the most points by doing well in the game’s three tournaments. Outside of the actual tournaments, which see you playing cards to score points, there are real-time trading and buying phases where you will trade cards with other players or the store, and buy packs of cards using Monopoly-esque money. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Just like the real world, the meta of the game will change as the game progresses and force you to adjust your approach and swap out cards. There are so many clever nods and homages to other games and anime that give Millennium Blades a wonderful identity, but don’t let its silliness fool you – it's a tense and highly strategic game with plenty of content, so you'll never play the same game twice. </p></div><p id="power-rangers-heroes-of-the-grid"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Power Rangers: Heroes of the Grid">Power Rangers: Heroes of the Grid</h2></p><div id="234399"><div><p><span data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><div id="234399" data-cy="solo-product-card"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Power Rangers: Heroes of the Grid</h3></p></div></span></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">This may be splitting hairs a bit since TECHNICALLY,  Power Rangers, aka Super Sentai, isn’t anime, but their motif and idea can be found in plenty of anime, and Super Sentai and its sibling Kamen Rider are just as much a part of Japan's entertainment history as anime, and so Power Rangers: Heroes of the Grid is on this list. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Heroes of the Grid is a cooperative boss battler in which the Ranger players attempt to take out the chosen monster of the week and big bad like Rita Repulsa before their forces overwhelm Angel Grove. Each Ranger has a unique deck and the respective zords they play with to get the job done, and with the plethora of expansions this game has, you can use your favorite ranger teams and villains. Heroes of the Grid is a great <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-cooperative-board-games">co-op board game</a> with teamwork and strategy being front and center. It's sure to delight Power Ranger fans.</p></div><p id="guilty-gear-strive-the-board-game"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Guilty Gear -Strive- The Board Game">Guilty Gear -Strive- The Board Game</h2></p><div id="234400"><div><p><span data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><div id="234400" data-cy="solo-product-card"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Guilty Gear -Strive- The Board Game</h3></p></div></span></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">One of the most stylish anime fighting games of the modern video game generation is the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/franchise/guilty-gear">Guilty Gear series</a> by Arc System Works. The same anime flair carries over into the board game adaptation, Guilty Gear Strive: The Board Game, which was released last year. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">This 1v1 dueling game features 20 characters from Strive, each with their own decks to play that highlight the styles and moves from the video game counterpart. It uses the Exceed card game system, so positioning of your character is crucial in Strive with attacks requiring different spacing to pull off and rewards keeping the momentum and pressure on. Set-up is fast and matches are over quickly, making this a great <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-best-quick-playing-board-games">quick board game</a> to act as a filler between bigger ones or playing a bunch of rounds. Like we said in our <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/guilty-gear-strive-the-board-game-review"><u>review</u></a>, this game captures not only the look of the source material but also what we love about fighting games. Fans of Guilty Gear or of fast-paced card games will find something to like with Guilty Gear Strive: The Board Game.</p></div><p id="one-piece-luffys-bento-panic"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="One Piece: Luffy’s Bento Panic">One Piece: Luffy’s Bento Panic</h2></p><div id="234401"><div><p><span data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><div id="234401" data-cy="solo-product-card"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>One Piece: Luffy’s Bento Panic</h3></p></div></span></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Perfect for anime conventions or parties with friends, One Piece: Luffy’s Bento Panic is a silly party game based on <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/one-piece-series-movies-in-order">the hit anime</a> featuring Luffy, Nami, Zoro, Sanji, and the rest of the Straw Hat Pirates. In Bento Panic, players take on the role of their favorite Straw Hat and celebrate a recent victory in the best way they know how – with a feast! Sitting in a circle, using their hands, all at once, players show a different gesture to declare their action from their turn, either pulling food tokens from the blind bag, stealing food from a neighbor, blocking a steal, or eating food. Points are scored by eating sets of food tokens, with the game only ending when Luffy wakes from his food coma a third time. Luffy’s Bento Panic makes a great <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-board-games-for-adults">party board game</a>, since everyone takes their turn at once. And like we mentioned in our <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/one-piece-luffys-bento-panic-board-game-review"><u>review</u></a>, even folks who aren’t necessarily fans of One Piece will have a good time with this one.</p></div><p id="aegis-combining-robots-second-ignit"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="AEGIS Combining Robots: Second Ignit">AEGIS Combining Robots: Second Ignition</h2></p><div id="234402"><div><p><span data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><div id="234402" data-cy="solo-product-card"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>AEGIS Combining Robots: Second Ignition</h3></p></div></span></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">For nearly as long as anime has existed, super robots and combining robots have been a part of it. AEGIS Combining Robots: Second Ignition lets players assemble teams, led by powerful Commanders with special abilities, of mecha from five different classes – Assault, Evasive, Guard, Intel and Support – and duke it out to try and be the team that comes out on top. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">While the mechs are strong by themselves, things really heat up when they start combining, turning the game from a strategic tactics game into something reminiscent of the fights out of GunBuster or GaoGaiGear. Manage your energy and pick the right time to combine your bots and grasp victory. For folks who prefer a more cooperative approach, additional modes are included, letting you and a friend take on buffed boss bots that will put your teamwork to the test. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">With 100+ mecha, each with its own skill loadout and standee, AEGIS gives you plenty of options for how to make your team, and Second Ignition is compatible with the first game, <a href="https://zdcs.link/QOj1N7?object_uuid=233a3f1d-a0c4-4fc0-be24-ccfe59a63870&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">AEGIS: Combining Robot Strategy Game</a>, which just saw a reprint, giving you even more options. Fans of mecha and tactic games should give AEGIS a look.</p></div><p id="cowboy-bebop-space-serenade"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Cowboy Bebop: Space Serenade">Cowboy Bebop: Space Serenade</h2></p><div id="234403"><div><p><span data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><div id="234403" data-cy="solo-product-card"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Cowboy Bebop: Space Serenade</h3></p></div></span></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">As crew members of the spaceship Bebop, in Cowboy Bebop: Space Serenade, you play as bounty hunters racing to take down nefarious criminals, all based on the legendary anime <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/tv/cowboy-bebop">Cowboy Bebop</a>. Space Serenade is a semi-cooperative <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-deck-building-board-games">deck builder</a> that's reminiscent of games like Star Realms, where you play cards for their resources and effects to buy new ones to add to your deck or to try and capture your targets. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Each of the four playable characters from the show – Spike, Ed, Faye, and Jet – comes with a set of cards special to them in addition to the generic ones that compose your starting hand. From there, it's a race to collect bounties and earn victory points to prove that you are the best bounty hunter in the galaxy. This game features plastic miniatures of your characters and cards depicting scenes from the anime, creating an authentic and fun deck builder for fans of the genre and source material.</p></div><p id="bullet-star-board-game"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Bullet Star Board Game">Bullet Star Board Game</h2></p><div id="234404"><div><p><span data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><div id="234404" data-cy="solo-product-card"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Bullet Star Board Game</h3></p></div></span></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Adopting the shoot-’em-up genre of video games for the tabletop, the Bullet series puts you in the role of different anime-like heroes as you avoid quickly approaching bullets and survive long enough to be the last one standing. The Bullet series is a real-time, pattern-matching puzzle game, and instead of shooting at the other players, you frantically attempt to remove the incoming bullets from reaching their own life points. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Over the course of three-minute rounds, players blindly pull bullet tokens from their bags and spend action points to help rearrange the tokens on their boards into patterns that allow bullets to be destroyed. At the end off each round, the destroyed bullets are moved to the player on their left to be added to the mix, similar to dropping Tetris blocks on your opponent. Bullet is a fast-paced game whose real-time countdown component and puzzle-based gameplay make it a refreshing anime addition to your board game shelf. </p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em> Scott White is a freelance contributor to IGN, assisting with tabletop games and guide coverage. Follow him on </em><a href="https://x.com/ProfessorRPG" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>X/Twitter</em></a><em> or </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/professorrpg.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Bluesky</em></a><em>.</em></p></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Jan 20, 2026 9:02 pm</p></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/best-anime-board-games]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Arc Raiders Update Targets Infamous Stella Montis Glitch – But Some Say ‘Rats’ Are Still in the Walls]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/arc-raiders-update-targets-infamous-stella-montis-glitch-but-some-say-rats-are-still-in-the-walls</link>
            <guid>1411378</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle" data-autopogo="true"><p data-cy="paragraph">Developer Embark Studios says <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/arc-raiders"><u>Arc Raiders</u></a> update 1.12.0 patched some infamous out-of-bounds exploits – but players say "rats" still live in the walls of Stella Montis.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Community lead Ossen took to the official website to publish <a href="https://arcraiders.com/news/patch-notes-1-12-0" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">full patch notes</a> for the January 20 adjustments, revealing a smaller set of targeted fixes for the massively popular extraction shooter. Exploits are in the line of fire this time, with the update said to fix glitches related to item and ammo duplication, the ability to damage other players from behind certain geometry, and a bug that let players reach out-of-bounds locations – specifically on Stella Montis.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The cold, labyrinthian halls of Stella Montis have already garnered a reputation for being perhaps the most cutthroat topside area Arc Raiders has to offer, and its abundance of cheaters isn’t helping. Streamers and everyday Raiders alike have reported dying to cheaters on the high-difficulty map for some time, with the out-of-bounds exploit proving to be especially problematic for months. The clip (above) showcases how the glitch has been used to steal some of the best Arc Raiders loot from players who are looking to extract back to Speranza or even just play some music.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Finally, update 1.12.0 is here to take care of what is maybe Embark’s most infamous exploit, but it sounds like it’s more of a speed bump than a stop sign. Just as the patch made its way to players across PC, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series X | S, Discord users began to report they were still losing runs to Raiders behind walls in Stella Montis. The developer’s patch notes do say that “various” – and not necessarily all – out-of-bounds map locations had been addressed, but that isn’t stopping fans from expressing their disappointment.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“There is still a wall glitch in Stella (somewhere in the lobby area),” one Discord user said. “Embark is incapable of fixing their game.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“So, I guess they didn’t fix wall glitches because I just got killed by 3 people inside the seed vault extract in Stella Montis,” another added.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“This patch notes seems like it only attracted rats into walls on Stella,” another player said.</p><span data-cy="poll-view-trigger"></span><p data-cy="paragraph">Disattisfaction with the update seems to stem from <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1808500/view/527614009105449109?l=english" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>a December 11 patch</u></a>, which was said to have tackled an out-of-bounds glitch related to zipline use on Stella Montis, only for players to find themselves still dealing with cheaters weeks later. Players have also shared reports of wall exploits at Dam Battlegrounds and Spaceport, with an ongoing issue related to an unopenable door in Stella Montis adding to the pile of glitches riling up the community.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Embark shared earlier this month that out-of-bounds glitches had been added to a list of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/arc-raiders-dev-promises-significant-changes-after-players-report-widespread-issues-with-cheaters"><u>anti-cheat fixes it hoped to implement</u></a> “over the next few weeks,” suggesting update 1.12.0 may be just one step in a larger plan. While players have waited weeks for exploit fixes, and Stella Montis may have a few holes to fill yet, some say they’re willing to give the studio more time to get Arc Raiders into shape.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“I don’t know much about game design, but I’m sure it takes a while to find and fix problems within coding,” one <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/ArcRaiders/comments/1qhx5zw/comment/o0n5ocv/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Reddit user argues</u></a>. “So I think people should be happy that they’ve fixed the exploits that have been such a source of complaints for so long.”</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Arc Raiders launched October 30, 2025, for PC, PS5, and Xbox Series X | S. Recent content updates include the introduction of Stella Montis November 13, as well as the limited-time <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/arc-raiders-cold-snap-update-goes-live-alongside-big-170-patch-notes"><u>Cold Snap event</u></a> December 16. While streamers and PvP fans both battle cheaters on and off stream, two <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/whoever-has-the-better-pc-wins-arc-raiders-players-second-guess-cheating-allegations-after-discovering-link-between-aim-assist-and-fps">content</a> <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/streamer-tfue-hit-with-30-day-arc-raiders-ban-amid-cheater-purge-then-immediately-unbanned">creators</a> have (temporarily) found themselves caught in the line of fire of Embark’s anti-cheat efforts. We'll have to wait and see just how long it takes for the studio to get wall exploits – and cheaters as a whole – under control.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Arc Raiders Update 1.12.0 Patch Notes</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Hey, Raiders!</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The store rotation is going live now and with it a few fixes:</p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Fixed an item duplication exploit.</li><li>Fixed an ammo duplication exploit.</li><li>Fixed some cases where players were able to damage others from behind geometry.</li><li>Fixed various out of bounds map locations on Stella Montis.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph">Restart your client to download.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Michael Cripe is a freelance writer with IGN. He's best known for his work at sites like The Pitch, The Escapist, and OnlySP. Be sure to give him a follow on Bluesky (@mikecripe.bsky.social) and Twitter (@MikeCripe).</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/arc-raiders-update-targets-infamous-stella-montis-glitch-but-some-say-rats-are-still-in-the-walls]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Might Have To Raise The Price Of The Switch 2 At The Worst Time]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/switch-2-price-increase-tariff-ai-ram-stock-price-2000661382</link>
            <guid>1411360</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><span>Nintendo may be about to “<a href="https://kotaku.com/ps5-gta-6-price-switch-2-trump-tariff-2000618881">follow in Sony and Microsoft’s footsteps</a>” and announce a Switch 2 price hike, according to a report from video game consumer insights firm Niko Partners. Although the new system is currently outselling the original Nintendo Switch by a wide margin in its first year, spiking RAM costs and ongoing tariffs could change all that.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><span>Niko Partners notes <a href="https://nikopartners.com/niko-partners-2026-predictions/">in a recent report</a> (</span><a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/nintendo-switch-2-faces-a-price-increase-in-2026-research-firm-predicts/"><span>via VGC</span><span>)</span></a><span> that</span> <span>Nintendo opted “to maintain [the Nintendo Switch 2’s] $449 entry price” when the system launched in June 2025, even as a trade war between the U.S. and China fueled price hikes on its competition. It now expects Nintendo to have to match those increases in 2026 due to high import taxes, increased memory costs, and other market conditions. <a href="https://gizmodo.com/amazon-ceo-says-tariff-price-increases-likely-to-hit-your-wallet-this-year-2000712020">Even Amazon’s CEO is warning</a>&nbsp;that this is the year companies start passing on more of the pain of tariffs to consumers.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <p><span>Nintendo President Shuntaro Furukawa </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/switch-2-price-hike-nintendo-sale-discount-2000642086"><span>previously told investors last November</span></a><span> that the company could keep the Switch 2 at $450 and “maintain the current level of profitability for hardware for the time being unless there are significant changes in external factors.” That time may have now passed. </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/switch-2-price-increase-nintendo-ram-shortage-2000658946"><span>Earlier this year</span></a><span>, he said the company was monitoring the current RAM situation and didn’t commit to not raising the price in the near future.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><span>These rumblings continue to suggest that anyone thinking of buying a Switch 2 in the next year might be better off doing it sooner rather than later, though Niko Partners notes that Nintendo might just start exclusively selling the $500 Switch 2 bundle rather than raising the price of the standalone SKU. In the meantime, the second half of the device’s launch year has been decidedly more uneven than the first.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <p><span>Despite having the </span><a href="https://www.nintendo.com/us/whatsnew/nintendo-switch-2-sets-record-selling-over-3-5-million-units-globally-in-first-four-days/"><span>fastest sales of any Nintendo console ever</span></a><span>, and </span><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/pierre485.bsky.social/post/3mbwj5lp24s2o"><span>currently outselling</span></a><span> the original Nintendo Switch in Japan by almost 2:1 in its first 30 weeks on the market, Nintendo’s stock has been tanking. </span><span>Switch 2 Christmas hardware sales were reportedly </span><a href="https://www.thegamebusiness.com/p/nintendo-switch-2-sales-stumble-over"><span>down by 35 percent</span></a><span> compared to hardware sales in 2017 (the Nintendo Switch’s release year). Hardware sales numbers might be strong overall, but </span><a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/newsletters/2025-11-11/nintendo-s-software-sales-aren-t-keeping-up-with-hardware-boom"><i><span>Bloomberg </span></i><span>reported</span></a><span> that game sales and attach rates were actually down compared to the first Switch’s debut.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <p><span>Meanwhile, Nintendo’s stock price has dipped </span><a href="https://www.tipranks.com/news/the-fly/game-on-nintendo-stock-drops-in-japan-over-past-five-months-thefly"><span>by a whopping 23.45 percent</span></a><span> over the last three months. With pressure mounting from the AI-driven RAM shortages and a weird holiday season for the Switch 2, Nintendo is in the awkward position of needing to maintain the existing launch-window sales momentum while also being expected to increase the hardware’s price tag. The only thing that could square that circle is a new </span><i><span>3D Mario</span></i><span> or </span><i><span>Zelda </span></i><span>adventure, but neither of those have been officially announced yet. </span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/switch-2-price-increase-tariff-ai-ram-stock-price-2000661382]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HItman: World of Assassination is getting cross-progression for its fifth birthday]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/01/20/hitman-world-of-assassination-is-getting-cross-progression-for-its-fifth-birthday/</link>
            <guid>1411351</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Five years on from the release of <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/hitman-3">Hitman 3</a>, IO Interactive has announced yet another impactful update and feature for their World of Assassination trilogy. Along with an overhauled IOI Account system, cross-progression will be added to Hitman WOA, letting you take your progress with your between platforms and storefronts.</p>
<p>Going live on 3rd February, enabling cross-progression will ask you to link platforms to your IOI Account and then choose one platform profile to become your primary account. All other linked platforms will then defer to this primary account, instead of having progress and achievements merged. It’s a shame, but it is understandable given the potential for problems that this would introduce.</p>


<p>The following progression data is shared across platforms:</p>
<ul>
<li data-list-item-id="ee883927197eb6b916f2a2ae0d01c6e6b"><strong>Experience</strong></li>
<li data-list-item-id="e9a47b05ccaa834fe2831a9defbc15d13"><strong>Player Level</strong></li>
<li data-list-item-id="e0c64bac2284521f595e3c0851665fc63"><strong>Challenges</strong></li>
<li data-list-item-id="eea2562a514f6a86df7d818fc8c4965f2"><strong>Location&nbsp;Mastery</strong></li>
<li data-list-item-id="e8c75d381f57c0f39239f67a720626804"><strong>Unlocks&nbsp;and Inventory</strong></li>
<li data-list-item-id="e99a35d8f441abc9ae2fdedbe00ca4e49"><strong>Achievements&nbsp;/&nbsp;Trophies</strong></li>
<li data-list-item-id="eeb408de67adb90ae6437e6603416ad47"><strong>Freelancer Mode Progression</strong></li>
<li data-list-item-id="ed0661519f1cc30d5c6f6892ac1f81ed2"><strong>Campaign&nbsp;Story Progress</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>Things that are not shared between platforms are any kind of purchases – game license, DLC license, and DLC-based unlocks – leaderboard scores and level saves (either offline or online). This means that, if you want to play some DLC levels on a system where you haven’t bought it, then you can’t.</p>
<p>The other major caveat is that the Hitman 2 to Hitman 3 progression carryover will now come to an end on 3rd February. This was created to enable the importing of Hitman 2 game progression into its sequel, but with this now being half a decade old compared to WOA, and again wanting to keep data integrity and prevent issues and conflicts, IO is bringing it to an end. You still have two weeks <a href="https://profile.hitman.com/">to do so here</a>.</p>

<p>For more details on everything this means for the game, head to <a href="https://ioisupport.zendesk.com/hc/en-us/articles/32645592211229-HITMAN-World-of-Assassination-Cross-Progression-Guide">IO Interactive’s FAQ here</a>.</p>
<p>In general, this is pretty great news. Again, it’s a shame that you can’t merge progression somehow, as my personal playtime has be spread across multiple systems, but the bulk of my time has been on PlayStation, so I can forego the loss.</p>
<p>Hitman 3 first launched back in early 2021, a concluding chapter to the ambitious trilogy that IO Interactive had started five years previous. In our <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2021/01/19/hitman-3-review-ps5-xbox-pc-switch-stadia/">Hitman 3 review</a>, Jim said, “Charting the series’ progress since that 2016 Paris debut has been a fascinating journey. IO have learned a lot over the past five years and that really shows in Hitman 3. It’s a flashier, more fluid evolution of IO’s original template – a rewarding conclusion to one of the most unique video game franchises around, and one we’ll continue playing for many weeks and months to come.”</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/01/20/hitman-world-of-assassination-is-getting-cross-progression-for-its-fifth-birthday/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[It Took Five Years For Forza Horizon 5 To Become My Antidote To Doomscrolling]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/forza-horizon-5-backlog-pulse-music-ps5-xbox-2000661365</link>
            <guid>1411345</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><span>2012’s </span><i><span>Forza Horizon </span></i><span>is one of my lifetime favorites. Earlier games like </span><i><span>Grand Theft Auto 3 </span></i><span>had shown me how much I could enjoy the simple experience of driving around a game’s world with a great song on the radio, but </span><i><span>Horizon </span></i><span>took it to the next level with its gorgeous Colorado setting, its impeccable driving model, and the relentless stream of exceptional pop tunes on Horizon Pulse, the game’s best radio station.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><span>And yet, despite loving the original, I’ve been largely uninterested in its many sequels. Whenever a new one has landed, I’ve spent a bit of time with it and then walked away, feeling like each one was a solid game but also just more </span><i><span>Horizon</span></i><span>, and that wasn’t enough to pull me back. </span><i><span>Forza Horizon 5 </span></i><span>came the closest, with its inviting slice of Mexico just calling out to be explored, but even then, cruising around an open world didn’t feel like an experience I needed to return to in 2021.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <p><span>And so the series has languished on my backlog, with me thinking that maybe someday I might find a reason to truly dive back in and rediscover the spark that made me fall in love with the original. At last, that time has come: I’m playing and enjoying </span><i><span>Forza Horizon 5 </span></i><span>every day, and the experience has taught me to think about my backlog in a different way. Rather than viewing it as a list of games that I really want to push myself to play and complete as soon as the opportunity arises, I’m coming to accept the idea that with some games, you just have to be in the right mindset. Maybe a game’s time will come and maybe it won’t, but you shouldn’t try to force it.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><span>Right now, my life feels like a game that mostly takes place in corridors. I get up in the morning, I walk down the same familiar streets to the same train line that takes the same route into the city each day, and at night, I make the same trip back home. Of course I’m aware that there’s a whole world beyond the confines of the narrow pathway I follow day in and day out, but the routine of my days remains pretty rigid. The constant barrage of political horrors and acts of evil, alongside the global embarrassments that come from having a raving lunatic as your president, only exacerbate the feeling that I need to escape, hit the open road without destination or obligation and focus more on the gorgeous scenery around me than I do on whatever nightmares are unfolding in the news and on my social media feeds.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <figure id="attachment_2000661368" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000661368"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000661368">When you’re playing an Xbox game on a PlayStation console, only one customized license plate will do.</figcaption></figure> <p><span>I bought </span><i><span>Forza Horizon 5 </span></i><span>on PlayStation 5 as part of the recent winter sale, not long after the news had broken that we’d attacked Venezuela. I’ve stress-eaten pints of ice cream before but this was, I think, my first time ever stress-buying a video game. I just wanted to be someplace else. Not fighting my way through the hostile world of some combat-heavy video game but someplace gorgeous and welcoming, where I was free to go anywhere and the scenery was full of rejuvenating natural beauty. And that’s exactly what </span><i><span>Forza Horizon 5 </span></i><span>is giving me.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <p><span>It’s probably not going to become lodged into my consciousness the way the first game did, both because the experience felt fresh and new back in 2012 and because </span><a href="https://youtu.be/RhJJjbLzfuk?si=PzZiYatJmI35xdav"><span>the original’s Horizon Pulse is still undefeated</span></a><span>, its shimmery pop bangers becoming fused with my sense memory of cruising around Colorado. There’s some decent tunes in </span><i><span>Horizon 5</span></i><span> but nothing that’s making the pilgrimage over to my own personal playlists the way so many songs from the original did.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><span>And yet, don’t get me wrong, I’m having a great time with </span><i><span>Horizon 5</span></i><span>. The racing in it is excellent, of course, but I actually bought a fairly ordinary car, a Nissan Skyline, so I could do my favorite thing: just drive around at a reasonable speed and take in the scenery. Sometimes when I’m on the subway on my way home from work, I close my eyes and see the game’s world, with those vast, breathtaking skies, already calling to me. And yes, of course getting home and diving into </span><i><span>Forza Horizon 5</span></i><span> is just me replacing one screen with another. I know that. But the screen that lets me escape into that gorgeous Mexican landscape isn’t going to fry my brain with a litany of all the latest horrors. It’s going to let me forget all that for a little while, savor the pleasure of hitting the open road, and remember why I think this world is worth fighting for.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <p><span>It’s also helping me make peace with my backlog. For years, games like </span><i><span>Returnal </span></i><span>and the </span><i><span>Demon’s Souls </span></i><span>remake have sat there, waiting patiently for my attention, and yet tackling them has just never felt right. I have little doubt that if and when I do play them, I’ll find a great deal to admire and I may even fall in love with them and wonder what took me so long, but I’ve just never yet felt them calling to me. Sometimes I’ve felt bad for not forcing myself to play them, telling myself that maybe if I just push myself over the initial hump of my indifference, everything would click and I’d be glad that I dove in.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><span>Maybe I would, but now I feel like maybe it’s okay to let go of that pressure, and to tell myself that if there comes a time in my life when </span><i><span>Returnal </span></i><span>is the game I need to play, the right game for where my mind and my heart are at in that moment, I’ll know it. For now, I have to go drive a car into a sandstorm.</span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/forza-horizon-5-backlog-pulse-music-ps5-xbox-2000661365]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Former Nintendo of America President Doug Bowser Joins Hasbro's Board of Directors]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/former-nintendo-of-america-president-doug-bowser-joins-hasbros-board-of-directors</link>
            <guid>1411333</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>A familiar face from Nintendo has joined Hasbro's board of directors. Former Nintendo of America President Doug Bowser will be lending his experience and consultation to the massive toy and tabletop company.</p><p>According to an <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ex-nintendo-of-america-boss-doug-bowser-joins-hasbro-owner-of-dungeons-dragons-and-magic-the-gathering" rel="nofollow">IGN report</a> by Tom Phillips, Doug Bowser is one of two newly-installed members of Hasbro's board. The second installed member is The Honest Company's CEO, Carla Vernon.&nbsp;</p><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/doug-bowser-with-plush-banner.jpg?itok=HlXMpqxZ 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="700" height="655">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/doug-bowser-with-plush-banner.jpg?itok=KVqUTF3D 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="700" height="655">
                  

  </picture><p>Doug Bowser <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/nintendo-of-america-doug-bowser-retiring" rel="nofollow">officially retired</a> from his position as President and COO of Nintendo of America on December 31, 2025, replaced by marketing executive VP Devon Pritchard.&nbsp;</p><p>In addition to having a delightful connection to the fire-breathing koopa king from S<em>uper Mario</em>, Bowser has overseen several of the gaming giant's recent successes since his time as president starting in 2019. The biggest one by far is the launch of the Nintendo Switch 2, which has currently sold over 10 million units.</p><blockquote><p>"We are delighted to have Doug and Carla join our seasoned and dynamic Board of Directors," said Rich Stoddart, Chair of Hasbro's Board of Directors. "Doug and Carla bring extensive leadership experience across consumer brands and franchise management. Their expertise and guidance will be invaluable as Hasbro continues to execute its long-term innovation and growth strategy."</p></blockquote><p>Doug Bowser's addition to the board adds invaluable insight to Hasbro. The company is a staple of both toys and tabletop entertainment. The company produces enduring toy lines like <em>Transformers</em> and <em>My Little Pony</em>, and iconic franchises like <a href="https://techraptor.net/games/magic-the-gathering" rel="nofollow"><em>Magic: The Gathering</em></a> and <a href="https://techraptor.net/games/dungeons-dragons" rel="nofollow"><em>Dungeons &amp; Dragons</em></a>.</p><p>It is also telling that both Magic and D&amp;D have only continued to grow in popularity. The iconic card game has been expanding thanks to recent crossover sets with Final Fantasy and Spider-Man. Whereas D&amp;D has gone mainstream thanks to Netflix's <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/dd-stranger-things-welcome-to-hellfire-club-review-starter-set-to-remember-eddie" rel="nofollow"><em>Stranger Things</em></a> and Larian Studio's critical masterpiece, <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/baldurs-gate-3-review" rel="nofollow"><em>Baldur's Gate 3</em></a>.</p><p>Given Bowser's work guiding and managing household names like Mario, Pokemon and Zelda, his skillset will come in handy for Hasbro's future.</p></div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Ever since he was small, Tyler Chancey has had a deep, abiding love for video games and a tendency to think and overanalyze everything he enjoyed. This… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/tyler-chancey">More about Tyler</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/former-nintendo-of-america-president-doug-bowser-joins-hasbros-board-of-directors]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Google has finally killed the Stadia Bluetooth tool — but this person rescued it]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/tech/864543/google-has-finally-killed-the-stadia-bluetooth-tool-but-this-person-rescued-it</link>
            <guid>1411330</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="__next"><p><a href="#content"><span>Skip to main content</span></a></p><nav aria-label="Sticky Nav"></nav><div><main id="content"><div><article><div><div><p>Stadia is now fully dead.</p></div><div><div><p>Stadia is now fully dead.</p><div><p><span><span>by</span> <!-- --> <span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"></span></span></p><p><span><time datetime="2026-01-20T19:50:46+00:00">Jan 20, 2026, 7:50 PM UTC</time></span></p></div></div><div><p><cite>Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge</cite></p></div></div></div><div><div><div><p><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span id="follow-author-standard_article_details-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MzQz"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span></span><span>Sean Hollister</span></span></span></p> <p><span>is a senior editor and founding member of The Verge who covers gadgets, games, and toys. He spent 15 years editing the likes of CNET, Gizmodo, and Engadget.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Did you save your Google Stadia controller <a href="https://www.theverge.com/games/829631/save-google-stadia-gamepad-steam-deadline">like I told you last month</a>? It’s <em>still </em>not too late. This week, Google has <a href="https://9to5google.com/2026/01/20/google-stadia-controller-conversion-tool-dead/">finally removed the tool</a> that converts the now-useless controller into a decent Bluetooth gamepad. But there’s another way.</p><p>Christopher Klay, who previously developed the Stadia Enhanced browser extension, is one of many who saved a copy of the tool to <a href="https://github.com/ChristopherKlay/stadiacontroller">a personal GitHub page</a>. What’s more, they’re hosting a working copy of that Google website <a href="https://christopherklay.github.io/stadiacontroller/">right here</a> to make it even easier.</p><div><p>I haven’t tried Klay’s mirror, as both of my gamepads are already converted, but <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=w-4yYrTyoiY">here’s my video</a> on how easy the process is. It’s worth doing now that the pads <a href="https://www.theverge.com/games/829631/save-google-stadia-gamepad-steam-deadline">work relatively well with Steam</a>! I maintain that while Google made a lot of mistakes, it’s <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23561541/google-stadia-shutdown-precedent-editorial">an amazing example of shutting down a service the right way</a>.</p></div><div><p><span><strong>Follow topics and authors</strong> from this story to see more like this in your personalized homepage feed and to receive email updates.</span></p><ul><li id="follow-author-article_footer-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MzQz"><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span><span>Sean Hollister</span></span></span></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li></ul></div></div></div><div><form><div><h2>The Verge Daily</h2><p><span>A free daily digest of the news that matters most.</span></p></div></form></div></div></article></div></main></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/tech/864543/google-has-finally-killed-the-stadia-bluetooth-tool-but-this-person-rescued-it]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Someone Already Brought Anthem Back To Life And Has It Running On A Private Server]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/anthem-revival-private-servers-shutdown-bioware-fan-2000661358</link>
            <guid>1411327</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><span>While ex-BioWare producer Mark Darrah </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/anthem-single-player-offline-mode-bioware-ea-mark-darrah-2000659773"><span>made a whole pitch</span></a><span> about how EA could still salvage </span><i><span>Anthem </span></i><span>for relatively cheap, it does seem more likely that BioWare and its parent company are going to let the game </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/anthem-server-shutdown-final-hours-videos-clips-stream-2000659367"><span>die a meaningless death</span></a><span>. However, some fans are looking into how the game could remain playable despite the servers being shut down, and one person has already managed to get it running on a P2P server.</span></p> <p><span>YouTuber And799 has posted a video of the game running on local servers. Though some of the online features, such as looking at your online profile, didn’t work, And799 was able to get the game running with two players in the same matchmaking space. According to the video description, this is all just for “research” and an “experiment,” and shouldn’t be considered indicative of any kind of </span><i><span>Anthem </span></i><span>revival process. However, it is exciting to see that a playable version of the game is still possible, even if EA and BioWare aren’t helming it themselves.</span></p>

  <p><span>If that’s already possible mere days after </span><i><span>Anthem </span></i><span>was shut down on January 12, hopefully fan efforts to preserve the game bear fruit in the coming months. Even if you </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/anthem-server-shutdown-bioware-dragon-age-mass-effect-1851786136"><span>didn’t like </span><i><span>Anthem </span></i></a><span>or thought BioWare </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/anthem-bioware-mark-darrah-interview-rpg-shutdown-2000661337"><span>shouldn’t have made it</span></a><span>, a game shouldn’t disappear without a trace afterpeople paid money for it and hundreds of developers spent years working on it. Fans may get the game’s unfinished campaign back up and running, but it’s unclear how much of the online experience they’ll be able to rebuild.</span></p> <p><i><span>Anthem</span></i><span>’s shutdown comes about a year after </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/dragon-age-the-veilguard-bioware-layoffs-mass-effect-1851784416"><span>BioWare was subject to significant downsizing</span></a><span> following the launch of </span><i><span>Dragon Age: The Veilguard</span></i><span>, with remaining developers all working on the next </span><i><span>Mass Effect</span></i><span>. The studio put out a </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/mass-effect-5-n7-day-bioware-blog-teaser-url-krogan-2000642122"><span>small tease for the game on N7 Day last year</span></a><span>, but was completely silent when </span><i><span>Dragon Age</span></i><span>’s equivalent fan day </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/dragon-age-the-veilguard-day-bioware-layoffs-december-4-2000650888"><span>came and went in December</span></a><span>.</span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/anthem-revival-private-servers-shutdown-bioware-fan-2000661358]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tainted Grail: The Fall of Avalon sales top one million]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/01/tainted-grail-the-fall-of-avalon-sales-top-one-million</link>
            <guid>1411324</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>PC version on sale for a limited time.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Total sales for <a title="Genres > Action RPG [1,934 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg/action-rpg">action RPG</a> <em><a title="Games > Tainted Grail: The Fall of Avalon [4 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/tainted-grail-the-fall-of-avalon">Tainted Grail: The Fall of Avalon</a></em> have surpassed one million units, publisher <a title="Companies > Awaken Realms [6 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/awaken-realms">Awaken Realms</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Awaken Realms Digital [5 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/awaken-realms/awaken-realms-digital">Awaken Realms Digital</a> <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1466060/view/198854507981966923" target="_blank">announced</a>. <span id="more-1020227"></span></p><p><em>Tainted Grail: The Fall of Avalon</em> first launched in Early Access for <a title="Platforms > PC [25,293 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1466060/Tainted_Grail_The_Fall_of_Avalon/" target="_blank">Steam</a> on March 30, 2023, followed by a full release across <a title="Platforms > PS5 [11,215 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [8,583 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, and PC on May 23, 2025. The expansion “<a title="Games > Sanctua" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/sanctua">Sanctua</a>ry of Sarras” launched on December 15, 2025.</p><p>To celebrate the milestone, the <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1466060/Tainted_Grail_The_Fall_of_Avalon/" target="_blank">Steam versions</a> of both the base game and expansion are currently available at a 20 percent-off discount price for a limited time.</p><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>One Million Copies Sold</span></h2><p><iframe title="Tainted Grail: The Fall of Avalon – 1 Million Copies Sold!" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/S10eIMFQQpY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><!-- AD: content -->
        </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/01/tainted-grail-the-fall-of-avalon-sales-top-one-million]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Square Enix Reveals Life Is Strange: Reunion Will Be the Series' Conclusion 'To the Max and Chloe Saga']]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/square-enix-reveals-life-is-strange-reunion-will-be-the-series-conclusion-to-the-max-and-chloe-saga</link>
            <guid>1411309</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><section data-cy="article-content" data-autopogo="true"><p data-cy="paragraph">After a decade of storytelling, Square Enix has decided to wrap up the story of Max Caulfield and Chloe Price in the newly-revealed Life is Strange: Reunion, which is set for launch on PC via Steam, PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X/S on March 26, 2026.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">A direct sequel to 2024's <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/life-is-strange-double-exposure">Life is Strange: Double Exposure</a>, featuring many of the same secondary characters, Reunion will also finally answer fan wishes by bringing back both beloved faces from the franchise's original 2015 game. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Max, who returned as the protagonist of Double Exposure, will reunite with her former lover/best friend Chloe for one final adventure — and for the first time in the same game, both characters will be playable.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Once again, there's a sci-fi mystery to solve and limited time to do so — this time, Max's Caledon University must be saved from a deadly fire — and once again, Max can rewind time to remake decisions, while Chloe can use her risk/reward "Backtalk" ability from 2017's Life is Strange: Before the Storm to provoke further responses from others.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">How is Chloe back, if players previously saw her demise? The story here seems to be that Chloe is now alive regardless after Max merged a pair of disparate timelines in Double Exposure's finale. Returned to life with memories of a past she never lived, Chloe is prompted to seek out Max for answers.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"This game builds on all the character-led, grounded storytelling for which the Life is Strange series is known, with meaningful choices that affect the outcome of a dramatic and surprising narrative – all culminating in an epic climax that serves as a finale to the Max and Chloe saga," Square Enix wrote today. </p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><span data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><div data-cy="slideshow-preview"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Life is Strange: Reunion Screenshots</h3></div></span></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Fans may be surprised to learn that Max and Chloe's stories will end here, but after a lengthy and often bumpy development road for the franchise, now perhaps feels a good point to ensure their tale gets a definitive ending, with both characters together one final time. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Remember that Don't Nod, the series' original developer, never planned for the characters' stories to continue beyond its initial hit game. Remember also that both Don't Nod and current maker Deck Nine have experienced mixed fortunes with the series since, with the original game's emotional climax still considered by many fans to be the franchise's high point. Finally, there are likely narrative advantages to letting players decide on a final outcome for the pair — something that doesn't need to be unpicked or worked around in any continuation.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Will Life is Strange continue without Max and Chloe? Square Enix doesn't go as far as stating that Reunion is the last Life is Strange game <em>ever </em>— though this feels an ending, for now. </p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2026/01/20/g-ibdyox0aeuhtr-1768932660114.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Farewell, Max and Chloe.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">"We couldn’t dismiss the tragedy at the heart of Max and Chloe," Life is Strange senior brand manager Andrew James said in an Xbox Wire blog post today. "Their reunion could be no quick fix. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">"Max and Chloe’s relationship is at the core of the story," James continued, "a relationship that YOU will choose how to develop over the course of the game. Whether Chloe lived or died in Arcadia Bay, and whether she and Max were friends or lovers — these choices are key not just to the <em>past</em> you’ll confirm as you play, but to the <em>future </em>you’ll fight for the chance to build."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Upon launch, Life is Strange: Reunion will be available for $40. There's also a $50 Deluxe edition featuring a digital soundtrack, art book and comic, and access to a behind-the-scenes documentary with returning Max Caulfield actress Hannah Telle, and Rhianna DeVries, Deck Nine's actress for Chloe Price. (Yes, thankfully there's no cat content sold separately this time around.)</p><p data-cy="paragraph">If you're yet to play Double Exposure, a double pack of both games will be available for $60. (It's a solid entry in the series that sets up a new cast of characters we'll see more of in Reunion — and one which Chloe fans may now enjoy more in retrospect.) Finally, a $100 Collector's Edition of Reunion will be available for die-hard fans, featuring a range of physical goods such as a 12" vinyl soundtrack.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Tom Phillips is IGN's News Editor. You can reach Tom at tom_phillips@ign.com or find him on Bluesky </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/tomphillipseg.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@tomphillipseg.bsky.social</a></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="title3"><svg data-cy="icon-logo" viewBox="0 0 76 24" title="IGN"><title>IGN Logo</title><path fill="currentColor" stroke="none" d="M5.38 7.65a7.85 7.85 0 0 1 2.26-2.26c.13-1.18.31-2.26.52-3.21a10.605 10.605 0 0 0-6 6c.95-.22 2.03-.39 3.21-.52M16.34 5.36v.02c.9.59 1.67 1.37 2.27 2.27 1.18.13 2.26.31 3.21.52a10.627 10.627 0 0 0-6.02-6.01c.22.95.4 2.02.54 3.2M7.64 18.62c-.9-.59-1.67-1.37-2.27-2.27h-.03c-1.19-.14-2.26-.32-3.19-.54 1.07 2.75 3.26 4.95 6.01 6.02-.22-.95-.39-2.03-.52-3.21M18.64 16.35h-.03c-.59.9-1.37 1.67-2.27 2.27v.03c-.14 1.17-.32 2.25-.54 3.19a10.59 10.59 0 0 0 6.03-6.03c-.94.22-2 .4-3.19.54M10.04 0h3.9c.85 1.85 1.2 4.59 1.3 5.52.04.22.06.43.06.63L12 9.11 8.7 6.15c0-.17.02-.35.05-.55.1-.95.43-3.75 1.29-5.61M8.7 17.83c0 .17.02.35.05.55.1.95.43 3.75 1.29 5.61h3.9c.85-1.84 1.2-4.59 1.3-5.52.04-.22.06-.43.06-.64L12 14.87l-3.3 2.96ZM6.16 8.68c-.17 0-.35.02-.55.05-.95.12-3.75.45-5.61 1.31v3.9c1.84.85 4.59 1.19 5.52 1.3.22.04.43.06.64.06L9.11 12 6.16 8.7ZM24 10.02c-1.86-.86-4.66-1.19-5.61-1.29-.2-.03-.38-.05-.55-.05l-2.96 3.3 2.96 3.3c.2 0 .41-.02.64-.06.93-.11 3.68-.45 5.52-1.3v-3.9Z"></path><path fill="currentColor" stroke="none" d="M42.83 13.9V10h10.45c1.06 0 1.93.86 1.93 1.92v4.63c0 2.38-1.91 4.36-4.33 4.36h-6.69c-4.96 0-8.97-4-8.97-8.94s4.04-8.95 8.98-8.95h10.36v4.11H44.2c-2.67 0-4.86 2.17-4.86 4.84s2.16 4.83 4.86 4.83h6.91v-2.91h-8.27ZM33.86 3h-4.07v16.02c0 1.05.86 1.91 1.91 1.91h2.15V3M74.37 3.01h-2.18v13.81s0 .08-.03.11a.29.29 0 0 1-.24.14c-.09 0-.16-.04-.25-.15L64.83 4.93a4.347 4.347 0 0 0-3.72-2.11h-.07c-2.39 0-4.32 1.93-4.32 4.32v11.88c0 1.05.86 1.91 1.91 1.91h2.17V7.14s.02-.09.04-.13a.29.29 0 0 1 .24-.14c.09 0 .18.03.24.14l6.88 12.07c.76 1.27 2.12 2.05 3.69 2.05h.07c2.39 0 4.32-1.93 4.32-4.32V4.92c0-1.05-.85-1.91-1.91-1.91"></path></svg>Recommends</h3></div></div><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/square-enix-reveals-life-is-strange-reunion-will-be-the-series-conclusion-to-the-max-and-chloe-saga]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokémon TCG: Full Release Schedule for 2026]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-full-release-schedule-2026</link>
            <guid>1411306</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle" data-autopogo="true"><p data-cy="paragraph">If 2025 felt busy, 2026 is already shaping up to be a big year for the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/pokemon-trading-card-game-tabletop"><u>Pokémon TCG</u></a> with the expansions it’s got coming up. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/tv/pokemon"><u>Pokémon</u></a> Trading Card Game is charging into its 30th anniversary year with the rest of the Pocket Monsters franchise, with a renewed focus on Mega Evolution, anniversary celebrations, and tightly curated sets designed to keep both collectors and competitive players fully locked in. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">While the full year’s roadmap hasn’t been revealed yet, three major products are already confirmed, and they give us a very clear idea of what kind of year we’re in for.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Here’s everything we know so far about the confirmed Pokémon TCG releases for 2026, including when they launch, what makes them special, and where you can actually buy them right now.</p><p id="ascended-heroes"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Ascended Heroes"><strong>Mega Evolution: Ascended Heroes – Releasing Jan. 30, 2026</strong></h2></p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2026/01/16/pokemon-tcg-ascended-heroes-cover-art-1768586008678.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Mega Evolution: Ascended Heroes - Credit: The Pokemon Company</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The 2026 TCG year officially kicks off with Ascended Heroes, the first English Mega Evolution expansion of the new era since the base set launched in September last year. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Ascended Heroes leans heavily into classic Mega Pokémon, new Tera cards, Team Rocket Pokémon, and even a Stadium card, with 290 cards coming to the set altogether. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Preorders have initially opened up, but availability has varied widely depending on the retailer — with <a href="https://zdcs.link/zJ8qdg?object_uuid=a4e67122-6c4e-4044-aa3f-fa1b60d0cb2d&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>Target</u></a> already sold out and <a href="https://zdcs.link/QPxYyV?object_uuid=a4e67122-6c4e-4044-aa3f-fa1b60d0cb2d&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>Best Buy’s</u></a> range listed as “Coming Soon”, both listing products at MSRP. The only options currently available are those not sold out due to being listed at prices higher than market value.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://zdcs.link/znB8o4?object_uuid=a4e67122-6c4e-4044-aa3f-fa1b60d0cb2d&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>Magic Madhouse</u></a> has announced it will be stocking Ascended Heroes, but it looks like it won’t be available there until launch. The big ticket item of any Pokémon TCG expansion, Ascended Heroes’ standard ETB (with nine booster packs, a promo card, and much more) is currently available at <a href="https://zdcs.link/QOjX3M?object_uuid=a4e67122-6c4e-4044-aa3f-fa1b60d0cb2d&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>TCGplayer</u></a> and <a href="https://zdcs.link/QpBeLg?object_uuid=a4e67122-6c4e-4044-aa3f-fa1b60d0cb2d&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>Walmart</u></a>: with TCGplayer’s being the best option at $119, with Walmart’s being distant backup at $178. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The next-most desirable product of an expansion, the six-pack booster bundle for Ascended Heroes is still way above MSRP, but is currently most affordable at <a href="https://zdcs.link/zj8Mbp?object_uuid=a4e67122-6c4e-4044-aa3f-fa1b60d0cb2d&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>Walmart</u></a> for around $79, followed by <a href="https://zdcs.link/QpBelg?object_uuid=a4e67122-6c4e-4044-aa3f-fa1b60d0cb2d&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>TCGplayer</u></a> at just over $82.  </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Both the Charmander and Ghastly Tech Sticker Collections (three booster packs, promo card, and stickers) are currently listed for the best prices at Amazon at just under $50 each — with TCGlayer offering much larger price points for now. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Meanwhile, the Heroes Collections around <a href="https://zdcs.link/a56y15?object_uuid=a4e67122-6c4e-4044-aa3f-fa1b60d0cb2d&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>Erika and Larry</u></a>, each with boosters and promo cards can be found cheapest at Walmart, and $10 more expensive, if you want the <a href="https://zdcs.link/zJ8qYq?object_uuid=a4e67122-6c4e-4044-aa3f-fa1b60d0cb2d&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>Larry</u></a> version as a guarantee. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Ascended Heroes will also have a variety of mini-tins featuring many key Pokémon — Clefairy &amp; Chikorita, Zorua &amp; Cramorant, Riolu &amp; Darumaka, etc — but these can currently cost upwards of $190 at TCGplayer. If you don’t mind getting a random tin, though, these are thankfully available for $29.99 at <a href="https://zdcs.link/aA8lrw?object_uuid=a4e67122-6c4e-4044-aa3f-fa1b60d0cb2d&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>Walmart</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Finally, each Premium Poster Collection (one for <a href="https://zdcs.link/z64qK3?object_uuid=a4e67122-6c4e-4044-aa3f-fa1b60d0cb2d&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>Mega Lucario</u></a> and another for <a href="https://zdcs.link/aA8lOw?object_uuid=a4e67122-6c4e-4044-aa3f-fa1b60d0cb2d&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>Mega Gardevoir</u></a>) can currently be found best at TCGplayer for just over $85 each — with Walmart’s sitting at $120. </p><p id="pokmon-day-2026-collection"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Pokémon Day 2026 Collection"><strong>Pokémon TCG: Pokémon Day 2026 Collection – Releasing Jan. 30, 2026</strong></h2></p><div id="234519"><div><p><span data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><div id="234519" data-cy="solo-product-card"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Pokémon TCG: Pokémon Day 2026 Collection</h3></p></div></span></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Pokémon’s 30th anniversary is on February 27, but you’ll be able to celebrate early when the commemorative Pokémon Day 2026 Collection also drops on January 30 with Ascended Heroes. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Announced back in December 2025, this is a very small release with one confirmed card: a unique stamped foil promo card of Pikachu looking cute as standard, along with a logo’d metallic coin, and a trio of TCG booster packs from different sets. Available imagery seems to show the packs being a mixture of one Phantasmal Flames and two Mega Evolution, but we like to warn that the contents may always differ from unit to unit. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The Pokémon Day 2026 Collection is currently marked as “Coming Soon” at <a href="https://zdcs.link/9gXe2D?object_uuid=a4e67122-6c4e-4044-aa3f-fa1b60d0cb2d&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>Best Buy</u></a>, but it can be bought now at <a href="https://zdcs.link/av8rDo?object_uuid=a4e67122-6c4e-4044-aa3f-fa1b60d0cb2d&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>Amazon</u></a> for $49.99, or from around $64 on <a href="https://zdcs.link/zE8lLG?object_uuid=a4e67122-6c4e-4044-aa3f-fa1b60d0cb2d&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>TCGplayer</u></a> if that sells out. </p></div><p id="perfect-order"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Perfect Order"><strong>Mega Evolution: Perfect Order – Releasing March 2026</strong></h2></p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2026/01/16/pokemon-tcg-perfect-order-mega-zygarde-ex-meowth-ex-1768585708494.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Mega Evolution: Perfect Order - Credit: The Pokemon Company</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">If Ascended Heroes is going to be setting the foundation of what the Mega Evolution set’s expansions are going to look like, Perfect Order’s going to kick things up a notch. Just announced this month and arriving in March, Perfect Order is going to be honing in on many of the Pokémon featured in the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/pokemon-legends-z-a"><u>Legends: Z-A game</u></a>. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Among the cards announced from the 120-card set so far, we know we’re going to be seeing many of the game’s starring Mega Pokémon; Mega Zygarde ex, Mega Starmie ex, and Mega Clefable ex; but also some surprising extra additions like Meowth ex.  </p><p data-cy="paragraph">At the time of writing, there are no pre-orders of Perfect Order products to buy, but we’ll be updating this article as soon as they are. </p><p id="2025-release-calendar-a-look-back"><h3 data-cy="title3" data-toc-title="2025 Release Calendar – A Look Back">Pokémon TCG: 2025 Release Calendar – A Look Back</h3></p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2026/01/19/pokemon-release-schedule-2025-ign-new-1761825918182-1768845525518.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Despite the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/pokemon-trading-card-game-tabletop">Pokemon TCG's</a> ongoing supply issues driving prices up, 2025 was one of the most packed years for the trading card game, both in expansions releases and just how expensive some products and chase cards have been worth. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Still, even for casual collectors, the hundreds of new cards released have had plenty that are still worth grabbing in 2026, if you can find a price you're happy with. Most notably, 2025 included the launch of the new Mega Evolution series, with the aptly named Mega Evolution set, and the final release of the year, Phantasmal Flames.</p><ul data-cy="list"><li><a href="https://zdcs.link/aoGXwL?object_uuid=a4e67122-6c4e-4044-aa3f-fa1b60d0cb2d&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><strong>Prismatic Evolutions</strong></a><strong>: Jan. 17, 2025</strong></li><li><a href="https://zdcs.link/QWYw3l?object_uuid=a4e67122-6c4e-4044-aa3f-fa1b60d0cb2d&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><strong>Journey Together</strong></a><strong>: Mar. 28, 2025</strong></li><li><a href="https://zdcs.link/Qr2XR8?object_uuid=a4e67122-6c4e-4044-aa3f-fa1b60d0cb2d&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><strong>Destined Rivals</strong></a><strong>: May 30, 2025</strong></li><li><strong></strong><a href="https://zdcs.link/QmnXj5?object_uuid=a4e67122-6c4e-4044-aa3f-fa1b60d0cb2d&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><strong>Black Bolt / White Flare</strong></a><strong>: Jul. 18, 2025</strong></li><li><a href="https://zdcs.link/ao6plm?object_uuid=a4e67122-6c4e-4044-aa3f-fa1b60d0cb2d&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><strong>Mega Evolution</strong></a><strong>: Sep. 26, 2025</strong></li><li><a href="https://zdcs.link/a01p0l?object_uuid=a4e67122-6c4e-4044-aa3f-fa1b60d0cb2d&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><strong>Phantasmal Flames</strong></a><strong>: Nov. 14, 2025</strong></li></ul><h2 data-cy="title2">Mega Evolution: Phantasmal Flames - Nov. 14, 2025</h2><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/09/04/pokemon-phantasmalflamesfeature-1-1756983518433.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Mega Evolution: Phantasmal Flames - Credit: The Pokemon Company</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The second expansion in <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/pokemon-trading-card-game-tabletop"><u>Pokémon TCG</u></a>'s Mega Evolution set was gearing up for quite some time. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-best-deals-today-september-3"><u>Phantasmal Flames</u></a> landed on 14 November 2025, and collectors were quickly scrambling to secure their <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-phantasmal-flames-where-to-buy">favourite sealed products before the inevitable shortages kicked in</a>. With headliners like <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-biggest-pokemon-card-crashers-and-climbers-this-week-september-5"><u>Mega Charizard X ex</u></a> taking centre stage, demand ran hot across every major retailer. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Featuring six booster bundles, there's still every chance that you'll pull a Mega Charizard X ex double rare, alt rare, or even Secret Art Rare or Gold Rare. I've pulled three normal 'Zard ex's so far, so no need to worry about deck building with Phantasmal Flames.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">They also had the <a href="https://zdcs.link/akwZV5?object_uuid=a4e67122-6c4e-4044-aa3f-fa1b60d0cb2d&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Phantasmal Flames Elite Trainer Box live</a>, which is actually available for $74.99 right now, though it's been going in and out of stock as the months have gone by. With that, I'd suggest keeping an eye on that too.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">What made this set even more exciting is its size, with about 90 cards before secret rares, which makes it the smallest English set in nearly a decade. For collectors like me, that usually means a much more manageable chase, while still packing in <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-biggest-pokemon-card-crashers-and-climbers-this-week-august-28">plenty of heavy hitters</a> for players.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The product lineup altogether for Phantasmal Flames was pretty stacked, too. We got the usual booster packs and booster box (36 packs), a 9-pack Elite Trainer Box featuring a shiny new Charcadet promo, and an Ultra-Premium Collection built around Mega Charizard X ex.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">On top of that, two theme decks for Mega Gengar ex and Mega Diancie ex arrived a few weeks early on October 24, which was a fun way to get a taste of the set before launch. If you’re like me and love cracking packs, the booster box was the way to go, but the UPC already looked like the big collector piece this time around.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">What tied it all together was the <a href="https://zdcs.link/ao6bvY?object_uuid=a4e67122-6c4e-4044-aa3f-fa1b60d0cb2d&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Japanese set Inferno X</a>, which hit shelves there in late September. That set had only 80 cards, and once you added in the Mega Gengar and Mega Diancie decks, you basically got the full Phantasmal Flames lineup. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">We'd already seen some killer reveals, including the Mega Charizard X ex secret rare previewed at Worlds, so I fully expected that to be the chase card when this launches. Between the smaller set size, Charizard hype, and some solid gameplay cards, I'm not surprised this one flew off the shelves and I’m definitely glad I locked in my preorder.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Mega Evolution - Released Sept. 26, 2025</h2><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/07/14/pokemon-tcg-mega-evolution-preorders-up-today-1752498558521.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Mega Evolution - Credit: The Pokémon Company</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Just when you thought the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/pokemon-trading-card-game-tabletop"><u>Pokémon TCG</u></a> had enough going on with <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-most-expensive-destined-rivals-cards"><u>Destined Rivals</u></a> and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-black-bolt-and-white-flare-revealed"><u>Black Bolt and White Flare</u></a>, in came a brand new series altogether with the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-mega-brave-mega-symphonia-sets-announced-for-2025">Mega Evolution sets</a>. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Announced at Japan's Championship tournament, the two new sets featuring Mega Lucario ex and Mega Gardevoir ex marked the popular trading card game stepping away from its Scarlet and Violet era.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Mega Evolution released on August 1, 2025, in Japan, and September 26 in English markets (<a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-mega-evolution-where-to-buy">with more preorders also supposedly taking place on September 13</a>). </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Finding sealed products like these at a fair price became a challenge very quickly. Some stores were holding MSRP, others were and still are inflating prices, and secondary marketplaces have had their own dynamics to keep in mind, too. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">But the gist is: collectors who must have the ETB, Best Buy and Walmart were worth constant refreshing. If reliability matters more, TCGplayer has been the most straightforward (though slighty more costly) option.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">While we can expect products from this set to be hopefully keep joining <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/deals-for-today-august-25"><u>Pokémon TCG deals</u></a> further down the line, huge initial demand will definitely see certain cards become price juggernauts among upcoming <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-biggest-pokemon-card-crashers-and-climbers-this-week-august-28"><u>crashers and climbers</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">2025 was shaped up to be a huge year at that point, sobut here’s everything else from the rest of the Pokémon TCG big releases last year. As always, IGN will keep tracking the buy links, both here and on socials at <a href="https://twitter.com/IGNDeals" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@IGNDeals</a>.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Pokémon TCG 2025 Holiday Calendar - Released Aug. 22, 2025</h2><div id="227412"><div><p><span data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><div id="227412" data-cy="solo-product-card"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Pokémon TCG: Holiday Calendar (2025)</h3></p></div></span></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">The Pokémon Company started releasing annual holiday calendars back in 2022, inspired by the <a href="https://bulbapedia.bulbagarden.net/wiki/Pok%C3%A9mon_Countdown_Calendar_(TCG)" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Pokémon Countdown Calendar</a> from 2008. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">These products are surprisingly good value in the current TCG market, as well as for casual fans of the series in other forms. You can see the listing <a href="https://zdcs.link/QObVLM?object_uuid=a4e67122-6c4e-4044-aa3f-fa1b60d0cb2d&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">here at Amazon</a> or scroll on for more details.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The 2025 Pokémon Holiday Calendar released on August 22 and initially retailed for $49.99 at Target before quicklly selling out. It's now available at Walmart for a pricier $64.99 or at Amazon for $69.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Black Bolt and White Flare - Released Jul. 18, 2025</h2><p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/05/08/gqyphggwqaac4ru-1746700735030.jfif" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Credit: The Pokemon Company / IGN</figcaption></figure></output></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://www.pokemon.com/us/pokemon-tcg/scarlet-violet-black-bolt" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Scarlet &amp; Violet: Black Bolt</a> and <a href="https://www.pokemon.com/us/pokemon-tcg/scarlet-violet-white-flare" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">White Flare</a> have been available since the summer, and can still be around at market price with enough luck at the right time, and if you know where to look. We previously <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokmon-tcg-black-bolt-and-white-flare-preview-why-this-dual-expansion-is-epic">previewed the new sets that brought 156 Unova Illustration cards to Pokémon TCG</a>, and it's altogether pretty good!</p><p data-cy="paragraph">If you haven't secured any boosters for Black Bolt and White Flare sealed products, you can still try your luck at local brick and mortar or online, or even online retailers like <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/deals-for-today-july-21">Amazon right now</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Alternatively, <a href="https://zdcs.link/QL8lMP?object_uuid=a4e67122-6c4e-4044-aa3f-fa1b60d0cb2d&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">TCGplayer</a> pricing for sealed product has occassionally been crashing, so I reckon we've well been seeing the usual price crash post-launch — as it what happens with some expansions.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">What do I think of the set? I think it's great and possibly the best opportunity to pull Illustration Rares in the Scarlet and Violet era, it's ending on a high note. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Personally I'm not a fan of stuffing the set with Pokéball and Masterball rares, but in terms of quality and presentation, they look cool. It would be grand to see Mega Evolution additionally double down on the dual format and loads of Illustration Rares going forward, but this is an encouraging sneek peek into what's next for Pokémon TCG.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Black Bolt and White Flare focus on the 156 Pokémon originally discovered in the Unova region. Each Unova Pokémon appear as either an illustration rare or a special illustration rare card, with different versions available in Black Bolt and White Flare products.</p><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>July 18, 2025:</strong> Scarlet &amp; Violet Black Bolt/White Flare ETBs (9 boosters, promo, accessories); Binder Collection (5 boosters, Zekrom/Reshiram album); Unova Poster Collection (6 boosters, Snivy/Tepig/Oshawott promos, poster); Unova Mini Tin (2 boosters, art/sticker card).</li><li><strong>August 1, 2025:</strong> Tech Sticker Collection (3 boosters, Reuniclus/Gothitelle promo, stickers); Unova Victini Illustration Collection (4 boosters, foil/parallel/oversized Victini).</li><li><strong>August 22, 2025:</strong> Booster Bundle (6 Black Bolt/White Flare boosters).</li></ul><h2 data-cy="title2">Destined Rivals - Released May. 30, 2025</h2><p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/03/24/pokemon-destined-rivals-ign-preorders-1742828696068.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Destined Rivals - Credit: The Pokémon Company</figcaption></figure></output></p><p data-cy="paragraph">Things really kicked off on <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-destined-rivals-preorder-guide-2025"><strong>May 30</strong> <strong>with Destined Rivals</strong></a>. This set brought back Trainer’s Pokémon, reintroduces Team Rocket for another round of villainous fun, and includes some of the best card art we’ve seen in ages. </p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-destined-rivals-preview">Destined Rivals</a> top chase card prices are also finally stabilizing, making it a great time to snap some up. Team Rocket's Mewtwo ex SIR has been going for anything over $450 since release, but is starting to settle on a more respectable $310. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">A while back, the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-destined-rivals-best-singles-to-chase-and-buy">Destined Rivals singles market</a> was bouncing all over the place. Some cards were doubling in price overnight and it was tough to tell what was hype and what would hold. Now, prices feel a lot more stable by comparison. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Some have dipped. Some <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-destined-rivals-best-singles-to-chase-and-buy">Destined Rivals</a> bangers are just cruising right at market. It feels like we’re finally seeing what these cards are actually worth.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Above are the ten of the most expensive cards you can find in the set right now. A couple of them are legit strong in decks. A few are pure collector bait. Team Rocket's Mewtwo ex was the hottest card in the set for a while and it’s still holding close to market. The artwork is what does it for me, personally. </p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://zdcs.link/z3GRqK?object_uuid=a4e67122-6c4e-4044-aa3f-fa1b60d0cb2d&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Mewtwo</a> looks like it's about to explode, floating in this dim lab setting with everything glowing around it. The ability makes it tough to use unless you’re running a full Rocket build, but once it's active, Erasure Ball gives you some serious power. Definitely still a top-tier pull even with the market calming down.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Journey Together - Released Mar. 28 2025</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s about time we got a set like this. Bringing back nostalgic Trainer’s Pokémon cards from the Gym Heroes era. N’s Zoroark ex and Lillie’s Clefairy ex end the chaos of endless secret arts for a more curated, collectible experience. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">With just 16 Pokémon ex, 11 illustration rares, and three hyper rare gold cards, it’s been easier to track what’s worth pulling without feeling like you need a PhD in pack odds. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Fancy snagging the Enhanced Booster Display Box with its bonus N’s Reshiram illustration rare or pull Iono’s Bellibolt ex? This set screams nostalgia with a new coat of paint.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Rare Cards and Collector’s Highlights</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">If you’re into collecting, this set hits the sweet spot. It’s got 16 Pokémon ex, six unique illustrations rares, and just three hyper rare gold cards, which means you won’t have to mortgage your house chasing every rarity. As for the artwork. illustrating rares like N’s Zoroark ex will look incredible in your binder.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Pokémon Center’s Enhanced Booster Display Box is the one to grab for preorder exclusives. It comes with a bonus N’s Reshiram illustration rare card — a little extra flex for your collection.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Prismatic Evolutions - Released Jan. 17 2025</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Prismatic Evolutions, kicked off 2025, and it’s all about Eevee and its many evolutions. This set is doing things differently, which is probably why stock sells out as soon as it comes in. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">This is another 151 situation, but there were plenty of stock refeshes coming throughout 2025, with hopefully more coming eventually in 2026. You won’t find these cards in the usual booster packs. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Instead, they’ve be released in boxed sets throughout last year, each packed full of exclusive cards celebrating Eevee and friends. With over 175 cards, including unique designs and new game mechanics, Prismatic Evolutions is shaping to be a hit with collectors and competitive players alike.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Rare Cards and Collector’s Highlights</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">For collectors, Prismatic Evolutions isn’t short on treasures. Each Eevee evolution has its special illustration and hyper-rare gold Pokémon ex card, making them must-haves for anyone building a showcase-worthy collection. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The set includes 32 illustration rares featuring detailed artwork for Pokémon ex and Supporter cards, so plenty of eye candy is here. With so many unique finishes and designs, it’s bound to make a few waves among fans.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Between the fresh artwork, inventive mechanics, and the undeniable charm of Eevee and friends, Prismatic Evolutions is set to be one of 2025's standout sets. Collectors and players alike will still find something to love here, from stunning illustration rares to powerful new game cards that can make a real difference in play.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Ben Williams</strong> – IGN freelance contributor with over 10 years of experience covering gaming, tech, film, TV, and anime. Follow him on Twitter/X <a href="https://x.com/BenLevelTen" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@BenLevelTen</a>.</p></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Jan 20, 2026 6:00 pm</p></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-full-release-schedule-2026]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[33 Immortals coming to Steam this summer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/01/33-immortals-coming-to-steam-this-summer</link>
            <guid>1411303</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Currently available via Epic Games Store and Microsoft Store.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Thunder Lotus Games [23 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/thunder-lotus-games">Thunder Lotus Games</a> will release the <a title="Platforms > PC [25,293 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> version of <a title="Genres > Co-Op [367 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer/co-op">cooperative</a> <a title="Genres > Roguelike [408 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/roguelike">roguelike</a> <a title="Genres > Action [3,333 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action game</a> <em><a title="Games > 33 Immortals [7 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/33-immortals">33 Immortals</a></em> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/958520/33_Immortals/" target="_blank">Steam</a> this summer, the developer <a href="https://thunderlotusgames.com/press-releases/33-immortals-2/" target="_blank">announced</a>. <span id="more-1020081"></span></p><p><em>33 Immortals</em> first launched in Early Access for Xbox Series and PC via <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/p/33-immortals-9873a2" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Epic Games Store</a> and <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/store/p/33-immortals/9p8lr42ptrgj" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Microsoft Store</a> on March 18, 2024. It is also available via Game Pass.</p><p>It is currently unclear whether the game will still be in Early Access when it launches via Steam. </p><p>“Bringing <em>33 Immortals</em> to Steam is an important milestone for us,” said creative director Stephan Logier in a press release. “The game has grown a lot through our first five updates, and we’re excited to keep building it with even more players joining the rebellion.”</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Thunder Lotus Games:</p><blockquote><p>First released into Early Access in March on <a title="Companies > Epic Games [355 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/epic-games">Epic Games</a> Store and Xbox, the game has steadily evolved alongside its community, surpassing one million players since launch. The Steam release will deliver the most up-to-date version of 33 Immortals and mark the next step in the game’s ongoing journey following multiple content updates and improvements since launch.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Since its Early Access debut, <em>33 Immortals</em> has continued to expand and improve through five major updates. These updates introduced new content and refinement across the experience, including additional gameplay features and quality-of-life improvements, all of which will be included in the Steam version.</p></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Steam Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="33 Immortals - Steam Trailer (ESRB)" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Xj2GcJV35Co?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/01/33-immortals-coming-to-steam-this-summer]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Climber Is An Incredibly Beautiful, Devastating Manga About Hubris]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/the-climber-shin-ichi-sakamoto-seinen-sports-manga-climbing/</link>
            <guid>1411300</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
      <p>The first time I encountered the word “egoist” was while watching the shonen sports anime <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Blue_Lock?ref=aftermath.site"><em><u>Blue Lock</u></em></a>. By all accounts, it was a solid first foray into how an (ego) death game-lite soccer tournament comprised of nothing but strikers would have hotheads butting heads. However, everything <em>Blue Lock</em> had to offer me might as well have been baby food by the time I finished the underappreciated seinen gem <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Climber_(manga)?ref=aftermath.site"><em><u>The Climber</u></em></a>—a brutal, transcendent tale about when grit and enlightenment arrive a hair too late to save men already ruined by their own compulsions.&nbsp;</p><p>Rather than being a glorified glossary of the sport like its breezier contemporaries, <em>The Climber</em>, written by novelist Jirō Nitta and adapted into a manga by <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shin-ichi_Sakamoto?ref=aftermath.site"><u>Shin-ichi Sakamoto</u></a>, is essentially about a group of climbers and the folly and pyrrhic victories of their impulses—namely, those of protagonist Mori Buntarō. When we first meet Mori, who’s loosely based on the <a href="https://onehundredmountains.blogspot.com/2010/10/life-and-death-on-matterhorn-of-japan.html?ref=aftermath.site"><u>real-life legend Katō Buntarō</u></a>, he’s an edgy transfer student already halfway checked out of humanity. After a run-in with a classmate who impressively scaled the school roof just to poke fun at Mori for being an antisocial prick, Mori repeats the climb, to the horror of everyone at the school, without a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Belaying?ref=aftermath.site"><u>belaying rope</u></a>. The instant he pulls off a ballsy double dyno jump to the school roof, Mori’s life shifts into a new paradigm as he chases an insatiable high for climbing, a sport the manga frames as his supposed salvation.</p><figure><figcaption><p><span>(Viz Media)</span></p></figcaption></figure><p>At the onset, Mori’s got everything your typical shonen protagonist would have: a built-in rival in his former bully turned climbing senpai, a mentor in his homeroom teacher and climbing coach, and a cute girl cheering him on from the sidelines. All signs point toward a clean, redemptive path to being a normal guy. But climbing doesn’t save him; it drags him deeper into himself. Mori doesn’t want to tether himself to a partner—he wants to be a solo climber, and if he could help it, he wants to be a solo climber without the lifeline of a belay rope. What follows are chapters, cleverly stylized as “climbs,” that amplify everything fundamentally broken in Mori long before they ever offer a way out—which he frequently refuses—as the manga tracks his psychological descent with grisly patience, from dropping out of high school to the isolating, obsessive adulthood that cements his effigy as the “immortal climber.”</p><p>Part of what makes <em>The Climber</em> so arresting is its insistence that the logic of “the ground” does not apply to the logic of the mountain. Down here, cutting a belay rope is unthinkable. Up there, if it comes down to severing that line or dying alongside your partner, you cut the rope. The manga never sensationalizes this binary choice of extremes; it simply presents the reader with the reality of a world where survival demands choices that would make no sense to anyone not already resigned to the possibility of dying for having made the climb in the first place.</p><figure><figcaption><p><span>(Images: Viz Manga)</span></p></figcaption></figure><p>To keep readers grounded without slowing the pace, each volume includes a glossary of climbing terms—clean, unobtrusive, and genuinely helpful—as well as interviews with real climbers explaining why they do what they do. But as the series reminds you, just because you can cut your ear off doesn’t make you Vincent Van Gogh. <em>The Climber</em> interrogates the “Why do you X?” refrain that runs through other art/athletics‑driven stories like <a href="https://aftermath.site/look-back-gkids-tatsuki-fujimoto/"><em><u>Look Back</u></em></a> or <a href="https://aftermath.site/100-meters-gkids-anime-movie-review/"><em><u>100 Meters</u></em></a>, only here the characters are often too far gone for a redemption that isn’t self‑destructive. Real egoists, the manga argues, are R.U.N.s: revolting, ugly, nauseating, and shameless—and <em>The Climber</em> is packed with them.&nbsp;</p><p>No arc better epitomizes the ambitions and the hubris of an egoist than <em>The Climber</em> putting its characters through the wringer in their attempt to conquer <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/K2?ref=aftermath.site"><u>K2</u></a>, one of the five tallest mountains on Earth, and also the deadliest. Given the mountain has killed one person for every four who reached the summit since the year 2021, totalling to around 96 deaths for every <a href="https://www.climbing.com/places/k2-worlds-second-highest-mountain/?ref=aftermath.site"><u>estimated 800 climbers who summited by the year 2023</u></a>, the odds of <em>The Climber</em>’s egoists being successful are dog water considering its climbing team would climb the bodies of their partners if it meant being the first to conquer its eastern face.&nbsp;</p><figure><div></div><figcaption><p><span>(Images: Viz Media)</span></p></figcaption></figure><p><em>The Climber</em> is also one of those manga where the artistry illustrates its point far more effectively than dialogue ever could. For 170 chapters, <em>The Climber</em>’s pages capture the true devastation of an avalanche, not as the usual cloud of powder sliding politely down a mountain, but as a catastrophic force of nature rendered through panels of skyscrapers and semi‑trucks plummeting downhill at blistering, irrational speeds. It’s a visual language designed to make you feel, in your bones, how dangerous climbing really is. And Sakamoto’s artistry drives that point home, shifting effortlessly between the magical realism of trippy, ethereal, dreamlike climbing sequences and the raw, uninhibited anguish his characters endure as they bivouac on the mountain and as they curl up in a husk below it, should they be fortunate enough to descend a climb by their own power without their frozen carcasses being helicoptered from a rocky metaphor for their own hubris.</p><figure><figcaption><span>(Image: Viz Media)</span></figcaption></figure><p><em>The Climber</em>’s answer to “Why do you X?” is a deceptively simple one. Mori doesn’t climb because he loves it, nor does he do it to be the best. He does it because it’s natural to go where you feel compelled to go. And, as in life, the path that demands the most courage is, more often than not, the one you’re supposed to take. Whether that place is the zenith of a man‑killing mountain, or its nadir, where the people who love you white-knuckle it out through deafeningly silent weeks for your safe return. Along his trek, Mori metamorphosizes from an irredeemable little shit into someone worth rooting for one brutal climb at a time.&nbsp;</p><p>By the time I tore through <em>The Climber</em>, taking many a “woosa” break, I felt I’d read a masterpiece on par with <a href="https://gizmodo.com/vinland-saga-creator-makoto-yukimura-looks-back-on-writing-his-pacifist-viking-epic-2000664303?ref=aftermath.site"><em><u>Vinland Saga</u></em></a>. It gave me a new appreciation for climbing—and scared me straight out of ever wanting to solo climb a mountain, much less face life’s less voluntary obstacles alone.</p>
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://aftermath.site/the-climber-shin-ichi-sakamoto-seinen-sports-manga-climbing/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Wccftech Awards ’25 – Best Games of 2025 and Most Anticipated of 2026 from Staff and Community]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/wccftech-awards-25-winners-clair-obscur-gta-6/</link>
            <guid>1411279</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>Following the conclusion of the staff and community polls, it is time to declare the winners of the <strong>Wccftech Awards '25</strong>, which include the <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-best-games-of-2025-year-of-the-indie-ish/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">best games of 2025</a></strong> and <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-most-anticipated-games-of-2026-the-return-of-aaa/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">most anticipated titles of 2026</a></strong>, based on the nominees from our genre lists.</p>



<p>Let's begin with the results of our best games of 2025 polls. When it comes to last year's releases, the Wccftech staff and our community <strong>agreed on practically every winner except for a single category</strong>, Strategy and Simulation, with our staff giving the award to <strong>Square Enix's Final Fantasy Tactics - Ivalice Chronicles, </strong>while our community preferred <strong>Slipgate's Tempest Rising</strong>.</p>



<p>The clear winner is, to the surprise of absolutely nobody at this point, <strong>Sandfall's Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</strong>, which walks away with <strong>four prizes</strong>: best indie game and <strong>Game of the Year</strong> from both staff and community.</p>



<p>The universally acclaimed game did, however, lose to <strong>Warhorse's Kingdom Come: Deliverance II</strong> in the best RPG category. Other multi-winners in the Wccftech Awards '25 include <strong>Sucker Punch's Ghost of Yotei</strong> in the action category, <strong>Team Cherry's Hollow Knight: Silksong</strong> in the platform category, <strong>Nintendo's Mario Kart World</strong> in the sports/racing category, <strong>AdHoc Studio's Dispatch</strong> in the adventure category, <strong>EA's Battlefield 6</strong> in the shooter category, <strong>KONAMI's Silent Hill f</strong> in the horror category, <strong>KOF Studio's Fatal Fury: City of Wolves</strong> in the fighting category, <strong>Embark's ARC Raiders</strong> in the multiplayer category, and <strong>NEOWIZ's Lies of P: Overture</strong> in the DLC/expansion category. </p>



<p>Without further ado, scroll for the full breakdown of the votes and rankings.</p>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Wccftech-Awards-25_16-HD.jpeg"></a></figure>



<ol>
<li><strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/review/ghost-of-yotei-exploring-the-price-of-vengeance-in-17th-century-ezo/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ghost of Yotei - WINNER (28,95% votes)</a></strong></li>



<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/review/ninja-gaiden-4-bathed-in-blood/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ninja Gaiden 4 - RUNNER UP (26,32% votes)</a></li>



<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/review/the-first-berserker-khazan-review-stranger-of-pell-los/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The First Berserker: Khazan (23,68% votes)</a></li>



<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/review/metroid-prime-4-beyond-scanning-wider-horizons/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Metroid Prime 4: Beyond (13,16% votes )</a></li>



<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/review/metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater-ps5-review-based-on-a-hideo-kojima-game/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater (7,89% votes)</a></li>
</ol>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Wccftech-Awards-HD-scaled.jpeg"></a></figure>



<ol>
<li><strong>Ghost of Yotei - WINNER (57,14% votes)</strong></li>



<li>Ninja Gaiden 4 - RUNNER UP (42,86% votes)</li>



<li>The First Berserker: Khazan (0% votes)</li>



<li>Metroid Prime 4: Beyond (0% votes) </li>



<li>Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater (0% votes</li>
</ol>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Wccftech-Awards-25_43-HD-scaled.jpeg"></a></figure>



<ol>
<li><strong>Dispatch - WINNER (71,43% votes)</strong></li>



<li>Blue Prince - RUNNER UP (28,57%)</li>



<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/review/keeper-review-shine-a-light/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Keeper (0% votes)</a></li>



<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/review/lost-records-bloom-rage-part-1-and-action/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Lost Records: Bloom &amp; Rage (0% votes)</a></li>



<li>Midnight Walk (0% votes)</li>
</ol>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Wccftech-Awards-25_55-HD-scaled.jpeg"></a></figure>



<ol>
<li><strong>Dispatch - WINNER (50,96% votes)</strong></li>



<li>Blue Prince - RUNNER UP (16,56% votes)</li>



<li>Keeper (12,74% votes)</li>



<li>Lost Records: Bloom &amp; Rage (11,46% votes)</li>



<li>The Midnight Walk (8,28% votes)</li>
</ol>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Wccftech-Awards-25_25-HD.jpeg"></a></figure>



<ol>
<li><strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/review/kingdom-come-deliverance-ii/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Kingdom Come: Deliverance II - WINNER (42,86% votes)</a></strong></li>



<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/review/clair-obscur-expedition-33-dont-fear-the-paintress/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 - RUNNER UP (28,57% votes)</a></li>



<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/review/avowed-surprisingly-meaty-unsurprisingly-deep/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Avowed (14,29%)</a></li>



<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/review/elden-ring-nightreign-conquering-the-night/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Elden Ring Nightreign (14,29% votes)</a></li>



<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/review/monster-hunter-wilds-peak-hunting/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Monster Hunter Wilds (0% votes)</a></li>
</ol>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Wccftech-Awards-25_29-HD.jpeg"></a></figure>



<ol>
<li><strong>Kingdom Come: Deliverance II - WINNER (44,29% votes)</strong></li>



<li>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 - RUNNER UP (43,84% votes)</li>



<li>Avowed (6,85% votes)</li>



<li>Monster Hunter Wilds (3,20% votes)</li>



<li>Elden Ring Nightreign (1,83% votes)</li>
</ol>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Wccftech-Awards-25_50-HD.jpeg"></a></figure>



<ol>
<li><strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/review/battlefield-6-battlefield-is-mostly-back/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Battlefield 6 - WINNER (42,86% votes)</a></strong></li>



<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/review/arc-raiders-review-speak-softly-and-carry-a-wolfpack/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">ARC Raiders - RUNNER UP (28,57% votes)</a></li>



<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/review/doom-the-dark-ages-review/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">DOOM: The Dark Ages - RUNNER UP (28,57% votes)</a></li>



<li>Metal Eden (0% votes)</li>



<li>Borderlands 4 (0% votes)</li>
</ol>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Wccftech-Awards-25_31-HD.jpeg"></a></figure>



<ol>
<li><strong>Battlefield 6 - WINNER (34,66% votes)</strong></li>



<li>ARC Raiders - RUNNER UP (28,29% votes)</li>



<li>DOOM: The Dark Ages (23,90% votes)</li>



<li>Metal Eden (9,16% votes)</li>



<li>Borderlands 4 (3,98% votes)</li>
</ol>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Wccftech-Awards-25_23-HD-scaled.jpeg"></a></figure>



<ol>
<li><strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/review/silent-hill-downpour-wet-creepy-night-town/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Silent Hill f - WINNER (71,43% votes)</a></strong></li>



<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/review/cronos-the-new-dawn-such-is-our-calling/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Cronos: The New Dawn - RUNNER UP (14,29% votes)</a></li>



<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/review/routine-review-lunar-software-raw-fury/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">ROUTINE - RUNNER UP (14,29% votes)</a></li>



<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/review/dying-light-the-beast/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Dying Light: The Beast (0% votes)</a></li>



<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/review/routine-review-lunar-software-raw-fury/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Hell is Us (0% votes)</a></li>
</ol>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Wccftech-Awards-25_12-HD-scaled.jpeg"></a></figure>



<ol>
<li><strong>Silent Hill f - WINNER (41,25% votes)</strong></li>



<li>Cronos: The New Dawn - RUNNER UP (30,00% votes)</li>



<li>Dying Light: The Beast (12,50% votes)</li>



<li>ROUTINE (10,00% votes)</li>



<li>Hell is Us (6,25% votes)</li>
</ol>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Wccftech-Awards-25_36-HD.jpeg"></a></figure>



<ol>
<li><strong>Fatal Fury: City of Wolves - WINNER (42,86% votes)</strong></li>



<li>2XKO - RUNNER UP (28,57% votes)</li>



<li>Absolum - RUNNER UP (28,57% votes)</li>



<li>CAPCOM Fighting Collection 2 (0% votes)</li>



<li>Virtua Fighter 5 R.E.V.O. World Stage (0% votes)</li>
</ol>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Wccftech-Awards-25_11-HD.jpeg"></a></figure>



<ol>
<li><strong>Fatal Fury: City of Wolves - WINNER (34,21% votes)</strong></li>



<li>CAPCOM Fighting Collection 2 - RUNNER UP (23,68% votes)</li>



<li>Virtua Fighter 5 R.E.V.O. World Stage (21,05% votes)</li>



<li>Absolum (13,16% votes)</li>



<li>2XKO (7,89% votes)</li>
</ol>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Wccftech-Awards-25_4-HD-scaled.jpeg"></a></figure>



<ol>
<li><strong>Hollow Knight: Silksong - WINNER (42,86% votes)</strong></li>



<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/review/donkey-kong-bananza/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Donkey Kong Bananza - RUNNER UP (28,57% votes)</a></li>



<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/review/revenge-of-the-savage-planet-review-funny-beautiful-and-tedious/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Revenge of the Savage Planet (14,29% votes)</a></li>



<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/review/split-fiction/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Split Fiction (14,29% votes)</a></li>



<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/review/donkey-kong-country-returns-hd/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Donkey Kong Country Returns HD (0% votes)</a></li>
</ol>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Wccftech-Awards-25_41-HD.jpeg"></a></figure>



<ol>
<li><strong>Hollow Knight: Silksong - WINNER (46,03% votes)</strong></li>



<li>Split Fiction - RUNNER UP (26,98% votes)</li>



<li>Donkey Kong Bananza (23,81% votes)</li>



<li>Revenge of the Savage Planet (1,59% votes)</li>



<li>Donkey Kong Country Returns HD (1,59% votes)</li>
</ol>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Wccftech-Awards-25_37-HD.jpeg"></a></figure>



<ol>
<li><strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/review/mario-kart-world/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Mario Kart World - WINNER (85,71% votes)</a></strong></li>



<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/review/rematch-review-an-excellent-football-game-thats-been-tackled-at-the-knees/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Rematch - RUNNER UP (14,29% votes)</a></li>



<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/review/sonic-racing-crossworlds/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Sonic Racing: Crossworlds (0% votes)</a></li>



<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/review/tony-hawks-pro-skater-3-4-review/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Tony Hawk's Pro Skater 3+4 (0% votes)</a></li>



<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/review/f1-25-review/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">F1 25 (0% votes)</a></li>
</ol>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Wccftech-Awards-25_49-HD.jpeg"></a></figure>



<ol>
<li><strong>Mario Kart World - WINNER (33,93% votes)</strong></li>



<li>Sonic Racing: Crossworlds - RUNNER UP (26,79% votes)</li>



<li>Tony Hawk's Pro Skater 3+4 (16,07% votes)</li>



<li>F1 25 (16,07% votes)</li>



<li>Rematch (7,14% votes)</li>
</ol>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Wccftech-Awards-25_18-HD.jpeg"></a></figure>



<ol>
<li><strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/review/final-fantasy-tactics-the-ivalice-chronicles-classic-strategy-modern-upgrades/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Final Fantasy Tactics - The Ivalice Chronicles - WINNER (42,86% votes) </a></strong></li>



<li>Tempest Rising - RUNNER UP (14,29% votes)</li>



<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/review/two-point-museum-two-point-at-its-best/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Two Point Museum - RUNNER UP (14,29% votes)</a></li>



<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/review/civilization-vii-one-more-turn/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Civilization VII - RUNNER UP (14,29% votes)</a></li>



<li>Mount &amp; Blade II - Bannerlord: War Sails - RUNNER UP (14,29% votes)</li>
</ol>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Wccftech-Awards-25_28-HD.jpeg"></a></figure>



<ol>
<li><strong>Tempest Rising - WINNER (40,00% votes)</strong></li>



<li>Two Point Museum - RUNNER UP (18,89% votes)</li>



<li>Final Fantasy Tactics - The Ivalice Chronicles (16,67% votes)</li>



<li>Civilization VII (13,33% votes)</li>



<li>Mount &amp; Blade II - Bannerlord: War Sails (11,11% votes)</li>
</ol>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Wccftech-Awards-Best-Indie-2025-HD-scaled.jpeg"></a></figure>



<ol>
<li><strong>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 - WINNER (50,00% votes)</strong></li>



<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/review/hades-2-supergiant-guide-us/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Hades II - RUNNER UP (33,33% votes)</a></li>



<li>Hollow Knight: Silksong (16,67% votes)</li>



<li>Routine (0% votes)</li>



<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/review/eternal-strands-the-world-is-your-playground/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Eternal Strands (0% votes)</a></li>
</ol>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Wccftech-Awards-25_52-HD.jpeg"></a></figure>



<ol>
<li><strong>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 - WINNER (50,00% votes)</strong></li>



<li>Hollow Knight: Silksong - RUNNER UP (20,63% votes)</li>



<li>Hades II (19,84% votes)</li>



<li>Routine (5,56% votes)</li>



<li>Eternal Strands (3,97% votes)</li>
</ol>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Wccftech-Awards-25_6-HD-scaled.jpeg"></a></figure>



<ul>
<li><strong>ARC Raiders - WINNER (42,86% votes)</strong></li>



<li>Battlefield 6 - RUNNER UP (28,57% votes)</li>



<li>Elden Ring Nightreign (14,29% votes)</li>



<li>Peak (14,29% votes)</li>



<li>Split Fiction (0% votes)</li>
</ul>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Wccftech-Awards-25_56-HD-scaled.jpeg"></a></figure>



<ol>
<li><strong>ARC Raiders - WINNER (32,33% votes)</strong></li>



<li>Battlefield 6 - RUNNER UP (29,32% votes)</li>



<li>Split Fiction (21,80% votes)</li>



<li>Elden Ring Nightreign (13,53% votes)</li>



<li>Peak (3,01% votes)</li>
</ol>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Wccftech-Awards-25_5-HD-scaled.jpeg"></a></figure>



<ol>
<li><strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/review/lies-of-p-overture-one-more-lie/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Lies of P: Overture - WINNER (42,86% votes)</a></strong></li>



<li>Kingdom Come: Deliverance II - Mysteria Ecclesiae - RUNNER UP (28,57% votes)</li>



<li>Sea of Stars: Throes of the Watchmaker (14,29%)</li>



<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/kirby-and-the-forgotten-land-nintendo-switch-2-edition-star-crossed-world-hands-on/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Kirby and the Forgotten Land + Star-Crossed World (14,29% votes)</a></li>



<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/super-mario-party-jamboree-nintendo-switch-2-edition-jamboree-tv-hands-on/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Super Mario Party Jamboree + Jamboree TV (0% votes)</a></li>
</ol>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Wccftech-Awards-25_19-HD.jpeg"></a></figure>



<ol>
<li><strong>Lies of P: Overture - WINNER (41,67% votes)</strong></li>



<li>Kingdom Come: Deliverance II - Mysteria Ecclesiae - RUNNER UP (29,17% votes)</li>



<li>Sea of Stars: Throes of the Watchmaker (12,50% votes)</li>



<li>Kirby and the Forgotten Land + Star-Crossed World (10,42% votes)</li>



<li>Super Mario Party Jamboree + Jamboree TV (6,25% votes)</li>
</ol>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Wccftech-Awards-25_20-HD-scaled.jpeg"></a></figure>



<ol>
<li><strong>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 - WINNER (42,86% votes)</strong></li>



<li>Kingdom Come: Deliverance II - RUNNER UP (28,57% votes)</li>



<li>Hollow Knight: Silksong (14,29% votes)</li>



<li>Death Stranding 2: On the Beach (14,29% votes)</li>



<li>Hades II (0% votes)</li>



<li>Battlefield 6 (0% votes)</li>



<li>Dispatch (0% votes)</li>



<li>ARC Raiders (0% votes)</li>



<li>Ghost of Yotei (0% votes)</li>



<li>Split Fiction (0% votes)</li>
</ol>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Wccftech-Awards-25_45-HD-scaled.jpeg"></a></figure>



<ol>
<li><strong>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 - WINNER (65,52% votes)</strong></li>



<li>Kingdom Come: Deliverance II - RUNNER UP (12,93% votes)</li>



<li>Hollow Knight: Silksong (6,03% votes)</li>



<li>Death Stranding 2: On the Beach (4,31% votes)</li>



<li>Hades II (3,45% votes)</li>



<li>Battlefield 6 (2,59% votes)</li>



<li>Dispatch (1,72% votes)</li>



<li>ARC Raiders (1,72% votes)</li>



<li>Split Fiction (0,86% votes)</li>



<li>Ghost of Yotei (0,86% votes)</li>
</ol>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Wccftechs-Most-Anticipated-Games-of-2026-scaled.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>These five are definitely among the most anticipated games of 2026.</em></figcaption></figure>



<p>While 2025 was essentially the year of the indie-ish, 2026 <strong>looks a lot more centered around triple-A releases</strong>, featuring heavyweight returns from triple-A developers, franchises, or both.</p>



<p>When it comes to the Wccftech staff and community 2026 polls, they were a fair bit more discordant than the 2025 polls, but that is to be expected given that we're talking about unreleased games. Our own staff also voted differently in a few categories, resulting in a few ties at the top.</p>



<p>Even so, one game emerged above all the others. Yes, it's obviously <strong>Rockstar's Grand Theft Auto 6</strong>, which received <strong>four prizes</strong>: most anticipated action game from the community, most anticipated multiplayer from the community, and most anticipated overall from both staff (tied) and community. The runner-up for most anticipated prizes is <strong>CAPCOM's Resident Evil Requiem</strong>, which got <strong>three</strong>: most anticipated horror game from both staff and community, and most anticipated overall from the staff (tied).</p>



<p>The other multi-winners were <strong>Playground's Fable</strong> (in the RPG category) and <strong>Forza Horizon 6</strong> (in sports/racing), <strong>The Coalition's Gears of War: E-Day</strong> (in shooter), <strong>ARC System Works' MARVEL Tōkon: Fighting Souls</strong> (in fighting), <strong>Crystal Dynamics/Flying Wild Hog's Tomb Raider: Legacy of Atlantis</strong> (in platform), the <strong>untitled STALKER 2 DLC</strong> (in expansion), <strong>Creative Assembly's Total War: Warhammer 40,000</strong> (in strategy/simulation), and <strong>Big Bad Wolf's Cthulhu: The Cosmic Abyss</strong> (in adventure). </p>



<p>Keep scrolling for the full breakdown per genre.</p>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Wccftech-Awards-25_46-HD.jpeg"></a></figure>



<ol>
<li><strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/marvels-wolverine-new-trailer-provides-first-look-at-gameplay-confirms-fall-2026-release-window/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Marvel's Wolverine - WINNER (42,86% votes)</a></strong></li>



<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/gta-6-could-evolve-into-an-mmorpg-as-many-of-its-planned-features-belong-to-the-genre-developer-has-heard/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">GTA VI - RUNNER UP (28,57% votes)</a></li>



<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/007-first-light-unveils-partnership-with-nvidia-official-pc-system-requirements/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">007 First Light (14,29% votes)</a></li>



<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/phantom-blade-zero-gamescom-hands-on-preview-setting-up-for-greatness/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Phantom Blade Zero (14,29% votes)</a></li>



<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/crimson-desert-has-release-date-recommended-requirements-reduced/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Crimson Desert (0% votes)</a></li>
</ol>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Wccftech-Awards-25_34-HD.jpeg"></a></figure>



<ol>
<li><strong>GTA VI - WINNER (46,84% votes)</strong></li>



<li>007 First Light - RUNNER UP (17,09% votes)</li>



<li>Crimson Desert (13,92% votes)</li>



<li>Phantom Blade Zero (12,66% votes)</li>



<li>Marvel's Wolverine (9,49% votes)</li>
</ol>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Wccftech-Awards-25_7-HD.jpeg"></a></figure>



<ol>
<li><strong>Cthulhu: The Cosmic Abyss - WINNER (42,86% votes)</strong></li>



<li>Cairn - RUNNER UP (14,29% votes)</li>



<li>Order of the Sinking Star - RUNNER UP (14,29% votes)</li>



<li>Into the Fire - RUNNER UP (14,29% votes)</li>



<li>Tides of Tomorrow - RUNNER UP (14,29% votes)</li>
</ol>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Wccftech-Awards-25_8-HD-scaled.jpeg"></a></figure>



<ol>
<li><strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/robocop-styx-and-cthulhu-announcements-headline-nacon-connect/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Cthulhu: The Cosmic Abyss - WINNER (27,78% votes)</a></strong></li>



<li>Tides of Tomorrow - RUNNER UP (22,22% votes)</li>



<li>Cairn (18,52% votes)</li>



<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/braid-the-witness-developer-thekla-announce-order-of-the-sinking-star-the-game-awards-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Order of the Sinking Star (18,52% votes)</a></li>



<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/dantes-ring-is-a-so-called-anti-combat-action-rpg-from-the-makers-of-the-invincible/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Into the Fire (12,96% votes)</a></li>
</ol>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Wccftech-Awards-25_47-HD-scaled.jpeg"></a></figure>



<ol>
<li><strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/fable-leak-shows-off-concept-art-confirms-location/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Fable - WINNER (28,6% votes)</a></strong></li>



<li><strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/roundup/nioh-3-everything-we-know-about-team-ninjas-supernatural-action-rpg/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Nioh 3 - WINNER (28,6% votes)</a></strong></li>



<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/the-blood-of-dawnwalker-devs-confirm-2026-launch-tease-several-announcements-to-come/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The Blood of Dawnwalker - RUNNER UP (14,3% votes)</a></li>



<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/dragon-quest-vii-reimagined-demo-launches-tomorrow-save-will-carry-to-full-game/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Dragon Quest VII Reimagined - RUNNER UP (14,3% votes)</a></li>



<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/control-resonant-switches-protagonist-brings-the-action-in-open-ended-manhattan-in-2026/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">CONTROL Resonant - RUNNER UP (14,3% votes)</a></li>
</ol>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Wccftech-Awards-25_35-HD-scaled.jpeg"></a></figure>



<ol>
<li><strong>Fable - WINNER (32,57% votes)</strong></li>



<li>The Blood of Dawnwalker - RUNNER UP (31,19% votes)</li>



<li>CONTROL Resonant (16,97% votes)</li>



<li>Dragon Quest VII Reimagined (12,84% votes)</li>



<li>Nioh 3 (6,42% votes)</li>
</ol>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Wccftech-Awards-25_1-HD-scaled.jpeg"></a></figure>



<ol>
<li><strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/gears-of-war-e-day-is-our-most-ambitious-game-yet-says-the-coalition/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Gears of War: E-Day - WINNER (71,4% votes)</a></strong></li>



<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/highguard-the-game-awards-announced-titanfall-apex-legends/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Highguard - RUNNER UP (28,6% votes)</a></li>



<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/witchfire-surpasses-500k-units-sold-gets-reckoning-update/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Witchfire (0% votes)</a></li>



<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/halo-remake-halo-campaign-evolved-coming-to-pc-xbox-ps5-2026/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Halo: Campaign Evolved (0% votes)</a></li>



<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/bungie-reveals-mild-marathon-pc-system-requirements/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Marathon (0% votes)</a></li>
</ol>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Wccftech-Awards-25_15-HD-scaled.jpeg"></a></figure>



<ol>
<li><strong>Gears of War: E-Day - WINNER (46,97% votes)</strong></li>



<li>Witchfire - RUNNER UP (21,21% votes)</li>



<li>Halo: Campaign Evolved (18,94% votes)</li>



<li>Marathon (9,85% votes)</li>



<li>Highguard (3,03% votes)</li>
</ol>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Wccftech-Awards-25_33-HD-scaled.jpeg"></a></figure>



<ol>
<li><strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/roundup/resident-evil-requiem-everything-we-know-about-the-new-game-in-capcoms-beloved-horror-franchise/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Resident Evil Requiem - WINNER (71,4% votes)</a></strong></li>



<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/clive-barkers-hellraiser-revival-gamescom-hands-on-preview-pleasure-and-pain/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Clive Barker's Hellraiser: Revival (14,3% votes)</a></li>



<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/fatal-frame-2-crimson-butterfly-remake-release-date-march-2026-ps5/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Fatal Frame II: Crimson Butterfly Remake (14,3% votes)</a></li>



<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/reanimal-gamescom-preview-a-nightmare-of-a-different-kind/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Reanimal (0% votes)</a></li>



<li>Halloween: The Game (0% votes)</li>
</ol>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Wccftech-Awards-25_42-HD-scaled.jpeg"></a></figure>



<ol>
<li><strong>Resident Evil Requiem - WINNER (69,70% votes)</strong></li>



<li>Clive Barker's Hellraiser: Revival - RUNNER UP (15,15% votes)</li>



<li>Reanimal (9,09% votes)</li>



<li>Fatal Frame II: Crimson Butterfly Remake (4,55% votes)</li>



<li>Halloween: The Game (1,52% votes)</li>
</ol>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Wccftech-Awards-25_22-HD-scaled.jpeg"></a></figure>



<ol>
<li><strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/marvel-tokon-fighting-soul-is-a-new-4-vs-4-fighting-game-by-arc-system-works-launches-in-2026-on-playstation-5-and-pc/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">MARVEL Tōkon: Fighting Souls - WINNER (71,4% votes)</a></strong></li>



<li>Invincible VS - RUNNER UP (14,3% votes)</li>



<li>Guilty Gear -Strive- Version 2.0 (14,3% votes)</li>



<li>Avatar Legends: The Fighting Game (0% votes)</li>



<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/riot-fighting-game-2xko-full-launch-pc-consoles-january-20-2026/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">2XKO (0% votes)</a></li>
</ol>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Wccftech-Awards-25_57-HD-scaled.jpeg"></a></figure>



<ol>
<li><strong>MARVEL Tōkon: Fighting Souls - WINNER (38,89% votes)</strong></li>



<li>Invincible VS - RUNNER UP (22,22% votes)</li>



<li>Guilty Gear -Strive- Version 2.0 (16,67% votes)</li>



<li>Avatar Legends: The Fighting Game (11,11% votes)</li>



<li>2XKO (11,11% votes)</li>
</ol>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Wccftech-Awards-25_26-HD-scaled.jpeg"></a></figure>



<ol>
<li><strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/tomb-raider-legacy-of-atlantis-features-completely-rebuilt-combat-exploration/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Tomb Raider: Legacy of Atlantis - WINNER (57,1% votes)</a></strong></li>



<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/lego-batman-legacy-of-the-dark-knight-release-date-the-game-awards-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">LEGO Batman: Legacy of the Dark Knight - RUNNER UP (28.6% votes)</a></li>



<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/yoshi-and-the-mysterious-book-nintendo-switch-2-spring-2026/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Yoshi and the Mysterious Book (14.3% votes)</a></li>



<li>Bloodstained: The Scarlet Engagement (0% votes)</li>



<li>Darwin's Paradox (0% votes)</li>
</ol>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Wccftech-Awards-25_9-HD-scaled.jpeg"></a></figure>



<ol>
<li><strong>Tomb Raider: Legacy of Atlantis - WINNER (36,59% votes)</strong></li>



<li>Bloodstained: The Scarlet Engagement - RUNNER UP (23,17% votes)</li>



<li>LEGO Batman: Legacy of the Dark Knight (18,29% votes)</li>



<li>Yoshi and the Mysterious Book (12,20% votes)</li>



<li>Darwin's Paradox (9,76% votes)</li>
</ol>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Wccftech-Awards-25_44-HD-scaled.jpeg"></a></figure>



<ol>
<li><strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/forza-horizon-6-leak-reveals-may-19-launch-date/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Forza Horizon 6 - WINNER (71,4% votes)</a></strong></li>



<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/star-wars-galactic-racer-the-game-awards-2025-fuse-games/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Star Wars Galactic Racer - RUNNER UP (14,3% votes)</a></li>



<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/mario-tennis-fever-launch-february-2026-nintendo-switch-2/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Mario Tennis Fever - RUNNER UP (14,3% votes)</a></li>



<li>Golf With Your Friends 2 (0% votes)</li>



<li>Exo Rally Championship (0% votes)</li>
</ol>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Wccftech-Awards-25_32-HD-scaled.jpeg"></a></figure>



<ol>
<li><strong>Forza Horizon 6 - WINNER (58,62% votes)</strong></li>



<li>Star Wars Galactic Racer - RUNNER UP (22,41% votes)</li>



<li>Mario Tennis Fever (8,62% votes)</li>



<li>Golf With Your Friends 2 (6,90% votes)</li>



<li>Exo Rally Championship (3,45% votes)</li>
</ol>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Wccftech-Awards-25_39-HD-scaled.jpeg"></a></figure>



<ol>
<li><strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/star-wars-zero-company-is-a-turn-based-tactics-game-set-in-the-clone-wars-and-due-next-year/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Star Wars Zero Company - WINNER (28,4% votes)</a></strong></li>



<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/ace-combat-8-wings-of-theve-announced-2026-launch-multiplayer-modes/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ace Combat 8: Wings of Theve - WINNER (28,4% votes)</a></li>



<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/total-war-warhammer-40000-announced-the-game-awards/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Total War: Warhammer 40,000 - WINNER (28,4% votes)</a></li>



<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/warhammer-40000-dawn-of-war-iv-shown-in-new-story-trailer/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Warhammer 40,000: Dawn of War IV - RUNNER UP (14,3% votes)</a></li>



<li>Nova Roma (0% votes)</li>
</ol>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Wccftech-Awards-25_24-HD-scaled.jpeg"></a></figure>



<ol>
<li><strong>Total War: Warhammer 40,000 - WINNER (26,00% votes)</strong></li>



<li>Warhammer 40,000: Dawn of War IV - RUNNER UP (22,00% votes)</li>



<li>Star Wars Zero Company (19,33% votes)</li>



<li>Ace Combat 8: Wings of Theve (18,00% votes)</li>



<li>Nova Roma (14,67% votes)</li>
</ol>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Wccftech-Awards-25_27-HD-scaled.jpeg"></a></figure>



<ol>
<li><strong>Slay the Spire II - WINNER (71,4% votes)</strong></li>



<li>Mina the Hollower - RUNNER UP (28,6% votes)</li>



<li>The Eternal Life of Goldman (0% votes)</li>



<li>MOUSE: P.I. For Hire (0% votes)</li>



<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/replaced-release-date-xbox-pc-march-2026/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Replaced (0% votes)</a></li>
</ol>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Wccftech-Awards-25_3-HD-scaled.jpeg"></a></figure>



<ol>
<li><strong>Replaced - WINNER (38,30% votes)</strong></li>



<li>MOUSE: P.I. For Hire - RUNNER UP (24,47% votes)</li>



<li>Slay the Spire II (19,15% votes)</li>



<li>The Eternal Life of Goldman (10,64% votes)</li>



<li>Mina the Hollower (7,45%) </li>
</ol>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Wccftech-Awards-25_30-HD-scaled.jpeg"></a></figure>



<ol>
<li><strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/the-duskbloods-will-feature-over-12-playable-characters-fromsoftware-isnt-abandoning-single-player/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The Duskbloods - WINNER (57,1% votes)</a></strong></li>



<li>GTA VI - RUNNER UP (28,6% votes)</li>



<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/enshrouded-wake-of-the-water-update-out-now-pc/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Enshrouded (14,3% votes)</a></li>



<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/cinder-city-preview-qa-open-world-shooter-mmo-like/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Cinder City (0% votes)</a></li>



<li>Marathon (0% votes)</li>
</ol>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Wccftech-Awards-25_2-HD-scaled.jpeg"></a></figure>



<ol>
<li><strong>GTA VI - WINNER (54,30% votes)</strong></li>



<li>Cinder City - RUNNER UP (15,89% votes)</li>



<li>Enshrouded (13,91% votes)</li>



<li>The Duskbloods (9,27% votes)</li>



<li>Marathon (6,62% votes)</li>
</ol>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Wccftech-Awards-25_14-HD-scaled.jpeg"></a></figure>



<ol>
<li><strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/stalker-2-first-dlc-in-2026-no-news-multiplayer-cross-platform-mods/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">STALKER 2 Heart of Chornobyl DLC - WINNER (28,6% votes)</a></strong></li>



<li><strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/team-cherry-hollow-knight-silksong-dlc-sea-of-sorrow-release-date/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Hollow Knight Silksong: Sea of Sorrow - WINNER (28,6% votes)</a></strong></li>



<li><strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/world-of-warcraft-midnight-officially-launching-march-2-2026/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">World of Warcraft: Midnight - WINNER (28,6% votes)</a></strong></li>



<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/ninja-gaiden-4-get-two-masters-dlc-early-2026/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ninja Gaiden 4: The Two Masters (14.3% votes)</a></li>



<li>Super Mario Bros. Wonder + Meetup in Bellabel Park (0% votes)</li>
</ol>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Wccftech-Awards-25_53-HD-scaled.jpeg"></a></figure>



<ol>
<li><strong>STALKER 2 Heart of Chornobyl DLC - WINNER (40,82% votes)</strong></li>



<li>Hollow Knight Silksong: Sea of Sorrow - RUNNER UP (30,61% votes)</li>



<li>Ninja Gaiden 4: The Two Masters (14,29% votes)</li>



<li>World of Warcraft: Midnight (9,18% votes)</li>



<li>Super Mario Bros. Wonder + Meetup in Bellabel Park (5,10% votes)</li>
</ol>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Wccftech-Awards-25_51-HD-scaled.jpeg"></a></figure>



<ol>
<li><strong>GTA VI - WINNER (28,6% votes)</strong></li>



<li><strong>Resident Evil Requiem - WINNER (28,6% votes)</strong></li>



<li><strong>Marvel's Wolverine - WINNER (28,6% votes)</strong></li>



<li>Phantom Blade Zero - RUNNER UP (14,3% votes)</li>



<li>The Blood of Dawnwalker (0% votes)</li>



<li>Crimson Desert (0% votes)</li>



<li>Control Resonant (0% votes)</li>



<li>007 First Light (0% votes)</li>



<li>The Duskbloods (0% votes)</li>



<li>Nioh 3 (0% votes)</li>
</ol>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Wccftech-Awards-25_10-HD-scaled.jpeg"></a></figure>



<ol>
<li><strong>GTA VI - WINNER (30,05% votes)</strong></li>



<li>Resident Evil Requiem - RUNNER UP (12,74% votes)</li>



<li>The Blood of Dawnwalker (12,02% votes)</li>



<li>Crimson Desert (11,78% votes)</li>



<li>Marvel's Wolverine (10,82% votes)</li>



<li>CONTROL Resonant (9,62% votes)</li>



<li>007 First Light (6,97% votes)</li>



<li>Phantom Blade Zero (3,37% votes)</li>



<li>The Duskbloods (1,92% votes)</li>



<li>Nioh 3 (0,72% votes)</li>
</ol>



<p>Congratulations to all the winners of the Wccftech Awards '25, and see you all next year!</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/wccftech-awards-25-winners-clair-obscur-gta-6/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Life is Strange will bring the Max and Chloe story to an end in new game]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/games/864438/life-is-strange-reunion-release-date-max-chloe</link>
            <guid>1411273</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span id="follow-author-standard_article_details-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTk3"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span></span><span>Andrew Webster</span></span></span></p> <p><span>is an entertainment editor covering streaming, virtual worlds, and every single Pokémon video game. Andrew joined The Verge in 2012, writing over 4,000 stories.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>A little over a decade ago, <em><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2015/10/28/9627302/life-is-strange-season-wrap-up">Life is Strange</a></em> burst onto the scene with a unique blend of teen drama and interactive storytelling. That first game told the story of Max Caulfield, who had the supernatural ability to reverse time, and her best friend Chloe Price. Now developer Deck Nine Games is finally bringing their story to an end with a new game called <em>Reunion</em>.</p><p>The latest entry in the series follows <a href="https://www.theverge.com/24289524/life-is-strange-double-exposure-review-pc-ps5-xbox">2024’s <em>Double Exposure</em></a>, which similarly continued Max’s story from the original game. The developer describes <em>Reunion</em> as the “emotional conclusion of the Max and Chloe saga.” Players will have three days to attempt to avoid a fire at their old college, where Max is now a teacher. Here’s the basic set-up:</p><div><blockquote><p>Returning from a weekend away, Max finds her beloved Caledon ablaze, as a raging inferno destroys the hallowed grounds and ends the lives of Max’s friends, students, and faculty alike. Max only escapes the devastation due to her Rewind power — returning from the original <em>Life is Strange </em>— a supernatural ability that lets her reverse time. Jumping back in time through a selfie, Max now has just three days to work out how the fire began. Can she make the most of her second chance to prevent this fiery disaster?</p></blockquote></div><p>The twist is that both characters will be playable for the first time. While Max retains her time travel power, Chloe’s skill is her back talk and attitude, which can apparently do a hella good job of dealing with suspects.</p><p>Of course, while <em>Reunion</em> marks the end of this particular storyline, that doesn’t necessarily mean <em>Life is Strange</em> won’t continue. The series has adopted something of an anthology format, with several games — <em><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/12/10/21003367/life-is-strange-2-season-review-xbox-ps4-pc-dontnod">Life is Strange 2</a></em> and <em><a href="https://www.theverge.com/22661479/life-is-strange-true-colors-review-xbox-ps5-switch">Life is Strange: True Colors</a></em> — telling all new stories within the same themes and gameplay structure.</p><p>It appears that <em>Life is Strange: Reunion</em> won’t be an episodic release — publisher Square Enix describes it as “a full-length adventure” — and it’s launching on March 26th on the PS5, Xbox, and PC.</p><div><p><span><strong>Follow topics and authors</strong> from this story to see more like this in your personalized homepage feed and to receive email updates.</span></p><ul><li id="follow-author-article_footer-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTk3"><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span><span>Andrew Webster</span></span></span></li><li></li><li></li><li></li></ul></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/games/864438/life-is-strange-reunion-release-date-max-chloe]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Witcher 3 Online Mod Lets You Hang Together With Friends]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/new-witcher-3-online-mod-lets-you-hang-together-with-friends-2000661320</link>
            <guid>1411264</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><em>The Witcher 3: Wild Hunt</em> is a fantastic single-player open-world RPG. One of the best ever made. And yet the incredibly detailed and lively world of the game would make for the perfect place to hang out with some friends. And thanks to a new mod, that dream can now be made real on PC.</p> <p><a href="https://www.polygon.com/witcher-3-online-multiplayer-mod/">As spotted by <em>Polygon</em></a>, <em>Witcher Online</em> is a new free mod for the PC version of <em>The Witcher 3</em> that adds online multiplayer for up to five players. <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/witcher3/mods/11590">The mod launched earlier this month and is available now on <em>Nexus Mods</em></a> and was created by user Rejuvenate. Here’s a trailer for the mod, which shows off what’s possible when five Geralts are hanging out together:</p>

  <p>To play <em>Witcher Online</em>, you’ll need to download and install the mod and own a “non-pirated”&nbsp;PC copy of the latest version of <em>The Witcher 3</em> from either Steam or GOG.</p> <p>The mod lets players customize their Geralt or use custom player characters while hanging out online. Folks can also relax and chill in the game’s various taverns using a separate <em>Witcher 3</em> mod, Chill Out, which is fully supported by <em>Witcher Online</em>. You and a few friends can play through all of <em>The Witcher 3: Wild Hunt</em> using this mod. However, <a href="https://rejuvenate.gitbook.io/witcheronline/general-information/playguide#:~:text=Other%20players%20cannot%20help%20you%20fight%20monsters%2C%20solve%20puzzles%2C%20or%20complete%20objectives.%20Because%20of%20this%2C%20you%20each%20must%20try%20to%20complete%20objectives%20at%20the%20same%20time%20as%20each%20other%20throughout%20the%20storyline.">there are a few caveats.</a> While the mod does sync all character animations, equipment, and combat across multiple players, you won’t be able to help other players fight monsters or complete quests, so the mod creator recommends you quest together and all “try to complete objectives at the same time as each other throughout the storyline.”</p>

 <p>But really, while you can go out and complete quests, <em>Witcher Online</em> seems more like a mod designed to let friends hang out in <em>The</em> <em>Witcher 3</em>‘s fantasy world and just enjoy the vibes while causing some random chaos or mayhem. And because this mod is free to access, I don’t think developers CDPR are going to go after it like the company <a href="https://kotaku.com/cyberpunk-2077-vr-mod-baldurs-gate-3-takedown-2000660987">recently did with a<em> Cyberpunk 2077</em> VR mod</a>.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/new-witcher-3-online-mod-lets-you-hang-together-with-friends-2000661320]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>