<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 20:36:03 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EA Cuts Around 300 Roles, Including Roughly 100 at Respawn]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/ea-cuts-around-300-roles-including-roughly-100-at-respawn</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ea-cuts-around-300-roles-including-roughly-100-at-respawn.1176858/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/ea-cuts-around-300-roles-including-roughly-100-at-respawn<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Wider EA cuts largely impacted the Experiences team.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">In addition to the roughly 100 job cuts IGN reported earlier today at Respawn Entertainment, EA has made wider cuts across its organization today, impacting around 300 individuals total including those <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/apex-legends-and-star-wars-jedi-dev-respawn-cancels-another-incubation-project-around-100-employees-impacted">already reported at Respawn</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">IGN understands that these wider cuts largely impacted EA's Experiences team, which includes groups such as EA's Fan Care team and various others working on customer support and marketing, though other EA departments saw reductions as well. As with other cuts at EA, those impacted will be given the opportunity to apply for other roles internally prior to being let go.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"As part of our continued focus on our long-term strategic priorities, we’ve made select changes within our organization that more effectively aligns teams and allocates resources in service of driving future growth," an EA spokesperson said in an official statement.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"We are treating our people with care and respect throughout this process, working to minimize impacts by helping affected employees explore new opportunities within the company when possible and providing support during the transition."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The roughly 100 jobs impacted at Respawn included individuals in development, publishing, and QA workers on Apex Legends, as well as smaller groups of individuals working on the Jedi team and two canceled incubation projects, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/respawn-has-quietly-canceled-a-multiplayer-fps-incubation-project">one of which we reported on back in March,</a> and the other of which was, <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-04-29/electronic-arts-lays-off-hundreds-cancels-titanfall-game?accessToken=eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiIsInR5cCI6IkpXVCJ9.eyJzb3VyY2UiOiJTdWJzY3JpYmVyR2lmdGVkQXJ0aWNsZSIsImlhdCI6MTc0NTk1MzQ2OCwiZXhwIjoxNzQ2NTU4MjY4LCJhcnRpY2xlSWQiOiJTVkhVQjFUMEcxS1cwMCIsImJjb25uZWN0SWQiOiJCMUVBQkI5NjQ2QUM0REZFQTJBRkI4MjI1MzgyQTJFQSJ9.Ok9U1G-8KnrQWSRme5JF1VqfCPIxgENs3iq9d32PeRc" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">per Bloomberg's reporting</a>, a new Titanfall game.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">These cuts follow a number of other layoffs over the last few years at EA, including the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/bioware-eliminates-50-jobs-to-match-studios-changing-needs">elimination of 50 jobs at BioWare</a> in 2023 and an <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/f1-developer-codemasters-suffers-round-of-layoffs">unknown number more at Codemasters</a>, and in 2024 a larger restructuring that resulted in <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ea-to-lay-off-around-670-to-advance-the-way-we-work">670 workers</a> laid off company-wide, including <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/apex-legends-hit-by-layoffs-amid-eas-ongoing-reductions">around two dozen workers at Respawn.</a>. And earlier this year, EA restructured BioWare, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/mass-effect-5-bioware-doesnt-require-support-from-the-full-studio-ea-moves-some-staff-to-other-teams">moving developers to other projects</a> and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/dragon-age-developers-reveal-theyve-been-laid-off-after-bioware-puts-full-focus-on-mass-effect">laying off others</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Rebekah Valentine is a senior reporter for IGN. You can find her posting on BlueSky @duckvalentine.bsky.social. Got a story tip? Send it to rvalentine@ign.com.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Electronic Arts lays off hundreds of staff, cancels early-stage Titanfall universe extraction shooter]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/electronic-arts-lays-off-hundreds-of-staff-cancels-early-stage-titanfall-universe-extraction-shooter</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/electronic-arts-lays-off-hundreds-of-staff-cancels-early-stage-titanfall-universe-extraction-shooter.1176852/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/electronic-arts-lays-off-hundreds-of-staff-cancels-early-stage-titanfall-universe-extraction-shooter<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
        </ul>

    
    <p><span>Approximately 100 staff from Respawn Entertainment.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Electronic Arts [1,769 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/electronic-arts">Electronic Arts</a> has laid off between 300 and 400 employees across the company, including approximately 100 staff at <em>Apex Legends</em> and <em>Star Wars Jedi</em> series developer <a title="Companies > Respawn Entertainment [108 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/electronic-arts/respawn-entertainment">Respawn Entertainment</a>, according to <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-04-29/electronic-arts-lays-off-hundreds-cancels-titanfall-game?accessToken=eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiIsInR5cCI6IkpXVCJ9.eyJzb3VyY2UiOiJTdWJzY3JpYmVyR2lmdGVkQXJ0aWNsZSIsImlhdCI6MTc0NTk1MzQ2OCwiZXhwIjoxNzQ2NTU4MjY4LCJhcnRpY2xlSWQiOiJTVkhVQjFUMEcxS1cwMCIsImJjb25uZWN0SWQiOiJCMUVBQkI5NjQ2QUM0REZFQTJBRkI4MjI1MzgyQTJFQSJ9.Ok9U1G-8KnrQWSRme5JF1VqfCPIxgENs3iq9d32PeRc&amp;leadSource=uverify%20wall" target="_blank">Bloomberg’s Jason Schreier</a>. <span id="more-962052"></span></p><p>“As part of our continued focus on our long-term strategic priorities, we’ve made select changes within our organization that more effectively aligns teams and allocates resources in service of driving future growth,” said Electronic Arts spokesman Justin Higgs in a statement.</p><p>In a message on <a href="https://twitter.com/Respawn/status/1917267367144423543" target="_blank">Twitter</a>, Respawn Entertainment independently confirmed the layoffs, as well as the cancelation of two early-stage incubation projects.</p><p>“As we sharpen our focus for the future, we’ve made the decision to step away from two early-stage incubation projects and make some targeted team adjustments across <em>Apex Legends</em> and <em>Star Wars Jedi</em>,” reads the statement. “These decisions aren’t easy, and we are deeply grateful to every teammate affected—their creativity and contributions have helped build Respawn into what it is today. We’re offering meaningful support to those impacted, including exploring new opportunities within [Electronic Arts].”</p><p>According to Bloomberg, one of those early-stage incubation projects was an unannounced <em>Titanfall</em> universe extraction <a title="Genres > Shooter [4,088 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/shooter">shooter</a> code-named “R7.” The second project was reportedly canceled earlier this year.</p><p>Respawn will continue development on the <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2024/09/star-wars-jedi-final-chapter-in-development-at-respawn-entertainment">next installment</a> in the <em>Star Wars Jedi</em> series—which is “aiming to raise the bar again for storytelling and gameplay”—as well as upcoming <em>Apex Legends</em> seasons and and an overhaul.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Almost Three Years After Neutrality Agreement, Negotiations Between Microsoft And Unionized Workers Aren’t Going Well]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/microsoft-zenimax-cwa-union-contract-negotiations-strike</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/almost-three-years-after-neutrality-agreement-negotiations-between-microsoft-and-unionized-workers-aren%E2%80%99t-going-well.1176843/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://aftermath.site/microsoft-zenimax-cwa-union-contract-negotiations-strike<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>All the way back in 2022, Microsoft made waves in the video game industry by striking a legally binding agreement with Communications Workers of America (CWA), the union that now represents thousands of workers within the company. “Microsoft will remain neutral when Activision Blizzard employees express interest in joining a union, providing a clear path to collective bargaining for almost 10,000 workers,” read <a href="https://news.microsoft.com/2022/06/13/cwa-microsoft-announce-labor-neutrality-agreement/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a joint release</a> from CWA and Microsoft during a time when the latter was facing regulatory scrutiny over its then-proposed purchase of Activision Blizzard. At the time, it seemed like a match made in heaven, but two years later, workers find themselves stuck in bargaining hell.&nbsp;</p><p>Today, approaching the third anniversary of the neutrality agreement and the second anniversary of QA workers at Zenimax – the first video game studio union at Microsoft – beginning the process of bargaining for a contract, CWA says proceedings have stalled. It chalks this up to Microsoft’s failure to address concerns about remote work, an issue that has led to <a href="https://aftermath.site/activision-workers-speak-out-against-return-to-office-mandate-that-they-see-as-soft-layoffs" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">outcry from workers at other Microsoft-owned companies like Activision</a>, as well as Microsoft’s “unilateral decision to replace in-house quality assurance work with outsourced labor without notifying the union.”</p><p>Aftermath reached out to Microsoft for more details, but the company did not reply as of this publishing.</p><p>While early returns, like <a href="https://aftermath.site/as-video-game-industry-goes-all-in-on-ai-workers-race-to-secure-their-rights" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">an agreement to curb destructive uses of AI</a>, seemed promising, <a href="https://aftermath.site/microsoft-activision-blizzard-layoffs-survival-report" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">multiple</a> <a href="https://aftermath.site/microsoft-lays-off-another-650-people" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">rounds</a> of mass layoffs soon followed in 2023 and 2024. The relationship between Microsoft and the nascent Zenimax QA union has since devolved.</p><p>“It’s become increasingly clear that although Microsoft tries to position itself as a good-faith employer, there’s another story being told behind the scenes at the bargaining table,” Zenimax Workers United member and senior QA tester Autumn Mitchell said in a statement received by Aftermath. “We are frustrated. Our union will continue fighting until we secure a first contract, and we’re prepared to do whatever it takes – even if that means withholding our labor.”&nbsp;</p><p>This follows demonstrations outside of Zenimax offices in Texas and Maryland last week, as well as <a href="https://cwa-union.org/news/releases/video-game-workers-vote-authorize-strike-microsoft" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a strike authorization</a> from the hundreds-strong Zenimax bargaining unit earlier this month, which 94 percent of members voted in favor of. At the time, workers spoke out against return-to-office policies and what they viewed as penny pinching from their corporate overlords.</p><p>“Underpayment and costly RTO initiatives have caused many of us to put our lives on pause because our income does not match even the rising cost of living in the cities where ZeniMax insists we live and work to maintain employment,” said Zenimax senior QA Tester Zachary Armstrong in <a href="https://cwa-union.org/news/releases/video-game-workers-vote-authorize-strike-microsoft" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a release</a> issued by CWA.</p><p>“Our in-house contractors have been working on minimal wages with no benefits, including no paid sick time,” associate QA Tester Aubrey Litchfield added. “Workers are choosing not to start families because of the uncertainty of finances. We’ve released multiple titles while working fully remote. When will enough be enough?”</p></div><div><h2>Stay in touch</h2><p>Sign up for our free newsletter</p></div><div><h2><span>More from Aftermath</span></h2><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/flcl-reanimated"><h3>I’m Obsessed With FLCL Reanimated</h3></a><p>300+ artists got together to swing the bat and give FLCL the tribute it deserves
</p></div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/all">See all posts<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="#000" stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round"><path d="M5 12h13m-6-7 7 7-7 7"></path></svg></a></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Game of Thrones: Kingsroad Full Launch Scheduled for May 21; Devs Want to Bring the ‘Entirety of Westeros’ to Life]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/game-of-thrones-kingsroad-full-launch-scheduled-for-may-21-devs-want-to-bring-the-entirety-of-westeros-to-life/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/game-of-thrones-kingsroad-full-launch-scheduled-for-may-21-devs-want-to-bring-the-%E2%80%98entirety-of-westeros%E2%80%99-to-life.1176828/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/game-of-thrones-kingsroad-full-launch-scheduled-for-may-21-devs-want-to-bring-the-entirety-of-westeros-to-life/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Today, Netmarble announced that Game of Thrones: Kingsroad will have its full launch as a free-to-play title on May 21, when the game will be available on PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3183280/Game_of_Thrones_Kingsroad/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a>, Epic Games Store, and Windows Launcher, and on mobile devices via Android or iOS across the world with the exception of Asia, which will have to wait until later this year. The online action/adventure/RPG <a href="https://wccftech.com/game-of-thrones-kingsroad-enters-early-access-on-march-26/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">launched on Steam Early Access on March 26</a>; the developers have introduced several fixes and improvements based on community feedback over the past few weeks.</p>
<p>Recently, Game Director Hyunil Jang outlined the game's roadmap with the following letter to the community:</p>
<p><em>First, let's talk about field boss matchmaking. Field bosses are multiplayer content that allows up to 12 players to participate together. During the early access period, we had them spawn frequently so that many players could take part. However, we noticed that because they appeared so often, players were more spread out and it actually made it harder for groups to come together and enjoy the content fully. To improve this, we're planning to reduce the number of times Drogon appears each day. We understand this will lower the number of attempts players can make, but we believe it's more important to create an environment where people can enjoy the content together. That said, if this change doesn't have the positive impact we're hoping for, we'll absolutely listen to your feedback and make adjustments again. </em></p>
<p><em>Among the feedback to the early access version of the game and the closed beta we had earlier, there were a lot of requests about additional language support. We're happy to let you know that we plan to support Portuguese and Turkish at launch.</em></p>
<p><em>[...] Next, I want to talk about the Founder's Pack and the availability of optional purchasable items within the game. For those who joined early access through the Founder's Packs, these were designed to include a sample of the various purchasable items that will be available at launch. To thank our Founder's Packs players for helping us fine-tune Game of Thrones: Kingsroad, additional costumes that can be used by all classes were sent to all players who purchased the Founder's </em><em>Packs. We're also preparing additional rewards for early access players before the official launch. Game of Thrones: Kingsroad is designed with player control in mind, ensuring a rich and rewarding experience regardless of optional purchasable items, as they are not essential to fully enjoy all aspects of the game.</em></p>
<p><em>Next, I'd like to talk about the RP system. We closely reviewed player feedback and gameplay patterns from early access and we identified several areas for improvement which we're currently working on. One of the biggest points was a shortage of RP. The original intent of the RP system was to help manage fatigue and ensure players could still earn meaningful rewards even with limited play time. However, many of you shared that the current RP supply felt too low, which made the overall experience less satisfying. We completely understand this concern, and the team is actively discussing balance adjustments to increase the daily amount of RP provided.</em></p>
<p><em>Another point we heard was that there isn't too much to do once RP runs out. Right now, players can still take part in content like field bosses or explore Westeros after using up their RP, but we </em><em>agree there's room to offer more. We're working on adding new types of content, including exploration challenges and co-op content, to keep things engaging even beyond RP. </em></p>
<p><em>If you've played our early access build, you'll have already explored the snowy regions of the North, the stained opulence of the Red Keep, and the lush green meadows of the Reach. Ultimately, our goal is to bring the entirety of Westeros to life with that same level of detail and authenticity. The next region we'll be visiting is one that hasn't received a lot of love in either the books or the show: the Stormlands, ruled by Stannis Baratheon. Our level and background teams work very hard to give each region its own distinct vibe, and the Stormlands live up to their name with a dark and oppressive feel and atmosphere matching the region's tone.</em></p>
<p><em>The narrative for this next chapter will be slightly darker as well. We'll dive a little more into the aspects of religion and what it would mean to a medieval society like that of Westeros to have</em><br>
<em>their king suddenly declare that all the people under his rule are now obliged to change their faith to that of a god whose name they can't even pronounce. </em></p>
<p><em>Our aim has always been to deliver a more polished and complete experience, but we recognized that there were areas like bugs and overall stability where we still have work to do. There may still be moments ahead where things don't meet expectations, but when that happens, we're committed to responding quickly, addressing issues and keeping communication open. As we work to improve, we'll continue working to make Game of Thrones: Kingsroad even better. Moving forward, our goal is to keep listening closely to your feedback and provide gaming service in a way that reflects our voices.</em></p>
<p><iframe title="[Game of Thrones: Kingsroad] Launch Date Announcement" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fpdoaR8N_a4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I Didn’t Think It Was Possible, But They’re Making Duolingo Worse]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/duolingo-ai</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/i-didn%E2%80%99t-think-it-was-possible-but-they%E2%80%99re-making-duolingo-worse.1176801/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://aftermath.site/duolingo-ai<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>You’ll remember my <a href="https://aftermath.site/duolingo-gamification" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">rant against Duolingo</a>, which has now turned one of Aftermath’s Discord channels into a regular vent session as we share the language learning app’s latest follies. (My recent complaint: I pop in to do one lesson and it keeps foisting XP boosts on me, a naked attempt to keep me on the app that absolutely works, because I am a rube.) Well, I’m back with a new complaint, which is the harder pivot to AI Duolingo CEO Luis von Ahn <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/657594/duolingo-ai-first-replace-contract-workers?utm_content=buffer2a099&amp;utm_medium=socialpost&amp;utm_source=twitter&amp;utm_campaign=buffer" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">announced yesterday</a>. </p><p>In a message to staff also posted to the company’s <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:7322560534824865792/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">LinkedIn</a>, von Ahn writes that “Duolingo will remain a company that cares deeply about its employees,” then says that the company will be replacing <a href="https://finance.yahoo.com/news/duolingo-cuts-10-contractors-uses-173030211.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">more</a> contractors with AI, writing, "We’ll gradually stop using contractors to do work that AI can handle." This is part of the company’s decision to become “AI-first,” a nonsense buzzword that even von Ahn can’t pitch without admitting it sucks, writing (emphasis mine) “Being AI-first means we will need to rethink much of how we work… [W]e can’t wait until the technology is 100% perfect. We’d rather <strong>move with urgency and take occasional small hits on quality</strong> than move slowly and miss the moment.”</p><p>This strategy will also involve considering AI in hiring and performance reviews, whatever that means, and that “headcount will only be given if a team cannot automate more of their work.” While von Ahn writes that "This isn’t about replacing Duos with AI" (contractors are indeed not staff) he does write that "It’s about removing bottlenecks so we can do more with the outstanding Duos we already have," which reads to me like a way of fancying up the "do more with less" afflicting countless industries these days.</p><p>In his note, von Ahn seems to claim that these decisions are in service of Duolingo’s mission: </p><blockquote><p>To teach well, we need to create a massive amount of content, and doing that manually doesn’t scale. One of the best decisions we made recently was replacing a slow, manual content creation process with one powered by AI.&nbsp;Without AI, it would take us decades to scale our content to more learners. We owe it to our learners to get them this content ASAP.</p><span><blockquote></blockquote></span></blockquote><p>Rather than use the revenue from Duolingo’s <a href="https://investors.duolingo.com/static-files/99006c40-d8cf-41ca-b5b1-c5cb1fa5ba88" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">nearly 10 million paid subscribers</a> to hire more experts to create–I cannot stress this enough–<em>learning content that requires subject matter expertise</em>, von Ahn seems to believe that quantity is the top goal, and that its users <em>deserve </em>a flood of what even he admits could be shit. This certainly squares with my own experience of Duolingo, which employs every cheap gamification trick in the book to simply keep me in the app and push me to pay.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><p>On <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:7322657005800759297/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">LinkedIn</a>, Duolingo’s chief engineering officer Natalie Glance shared a Slack message she wrote to the engineering team explaining how AI will fit into their work. This message features new directives such as “AI will be everywhere in our product” and “productivity expectations will rise.” Here’s my personal favorite: </p><blockquote><p>Start with AI for every task. No matter how small, try using an AI tool first. It won’t always be faster or better at first–but that’s how you build skill. Don’t give up if the first result is wrong.</p><span><blockquote></blockquote></span></blockquote><p>Again, these people are <em>literally admitting</em> AI won’t work, but are still asking engineers now laboring under heightened productivity expectations to spend their even-more-precious time managing this sub-par tech. "That's how you build skill" puts the AI tools' failing back on the user, the "<a href="https://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=Have%20Fun%20Staying%20Poor" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">have fun staying poor</a>" of the AI world, and asks engineers to troubleshoot AI when they could instead be using their <em>real live human skill to do the jobs they were hired for</em>.</p><p>That Duolingo execs can write all this and still insist the company prioritizes humans, whether that’s workers or users, is a staggering level of AI brainrot. None of this helps people. Workers, if they still have jobs, will be asked to pivot to clumsy tools. Users will be fed content Duolingo itself admits could have mistakes; in the language I’m learning, Irish, this is <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/dean-tane.bsky.social/post/3lnwt46sgps2u" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">already</a> a problem, with the computerized voices mangling the pronunciation to such an extent that I live in dread of the app giving me listening exercises because I often have no clue what it’s attempting to say. All of this means what AI always means: creating more–God help me–<em>content</em> with less people, assuming workers and users are so stupid that we’ll lap up whatever shit is shoved in our faces or crammed into our workflows because the people at the top can’t imagine we’re not as enthralled with the latest fad as they are.&nbsp;</p><p>I’m new enough to Duolingo that giving up my streak or uninstalling the app isn’t a big ask, though I’ll also admit that I’m loathe to give up on all the new vocabulary it’s teaching me. Luckily, I have options: my public library gives me free access to <a href="https://mangolanguages.com/libraries/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Mango Languages</a>, and I know other libraries have Rosetta Stone or other programs. I’ve recently been experimenting with user-made <a href="https://ankiweb.net/shared/decks" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Anki decks</a>; the program is much clunkier than Duolingo, but way more customizable and robust. For those of you learning less obscure languages than Irish, I’m sure there’s an even greater wealth of resources out there. </p></div><div><h2>Stay in touch</h2><p>Sign up for our free newsletter</p></div><div><h2><span>More from Aftermath</span></h2><div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/microsoft-zenimax-cwa-union-contract-negotiations-strike"><h3>Almost Three Years After Neutrality Agreement, Negotiations Between Microsoft And Unionized Workers Aren’t Going Well</h3></a><p>"Although Microsoft tries to position itself as a good-faith employer, there’s another story being told behind the scenes at the bargaining table"</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/flcl-reanimated"><h3>I’m Obsessed With FLCL Reanimated</h3></a><p>300+ artists got together to swing the bat and give FLCL the tribute it deserves
</p></div></div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/all">See all posts<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="#000" stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round"><path d="M5 12h13m-6-7 7 7-7 7"></path></svg></a></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Respawn reportedly lay off staff across Apex Legends and Star Wars Jedi teams, cancel two incubation projects]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/respawn-reportedly-lay-off-staff-across-apex-legends-and-star-wars-jedi-teams-cancel-two-incubation-projects</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/respawn-reportedly-lay-off-staff-across-apex-legends-and-star-wars-jedi-teams-cancel-two-incubation-projects.1176792/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/respawn-reportedly-lay-off-staff-across-apex-legends-and-star-wars-jedi-teams-cancel-two-incubation-projects<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="main-content" data-component="article-header">
  

        <p>Would be nice if they could just be honest for once</p>

    </div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p><em><strong>Update</strong>: Bloomberg's Jason Schreier has <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-04-29/electronic-arts-lays-off-hundreds-cancels-titanfall-game?accessToken=eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiIsInR5cCI6IkpXVCJ9.eyJzb3VyY2UiOiJTdWJzY3JpYmVyR2lmdGVkQXJ0aWNsZSIsImlhdCI6MTc0NTk1MzQ2OCwiZXhwIjoxNzQ2NTU4MjY4LCJhcnRpY2xlSWQiOiJTVkhVQjFUMEcxS1cwMCIsImJjb25uZWN0SWQiOiJCMUVBQkI5NjQ2QUM0REZFQTJBRkI4MjI1MzgyQTJFQSJ9.Ok9U1G-8KnrQWSRme5JF1VqfCPIxgENs3iq9d32PeRc&amp;leadSource=uverify%20wall">since reported</a> that between 300 and 400 positions have been "eliminated" across EA, including around 100 at EA. One of the cancelled incubation projects was also apparently an extraction shooter set in the <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/titanfall">Titanfall</a> universe.</em></p>
<p>
Apex Legends developer <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/companies/respawn-entertainment">Respawn Entertainment</a> have announced that two of its incubation projects have been cancelled, leading to what it calls a number of "target team adjustments across <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/apex-legends">Apex Legends</a> and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/star-wars-jedi-survivor">Star Wars Jedi</a>." You may notice that this language is particularly obtuse, in that it doesn't refer to these adjustments as layoffs. However, according to a report from <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/apex-legends-and-star-wars-jedi-dev-respawn-cancels-another-incubation-project-around-100-employees-impacted">IGN</a>, layoffs have occurred, though just how many is currently unknown.
</p>
<!--more-->
<p>
IGN says that it believes around 100 individuals are affected by the decision, which includes developers, publishing, and QA workers across the aforementioned Apex Legends, Star Wars Jedi, and incubation projects. It's worth noting that one of these projects was actually <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/respawn-has-quietly-canceled-a-multiplayer-fps-incubation-project">reportedly cancelled in March</a>, and IGN understands that "some, though not all, of the developers from the incubation project reported on in March have already been moved to work on Iron Man at EA Motive, Battlefield, and other projects."
</p> <div>

<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>
<a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/companies/electronic-arts">EA</a> also reportedly didn't comment on how many have been impacted, but did say that they are offering those affected 30 days to find another role within the company. They're also apparently trying to help find roles for as many people as they can internally.
</p>
<p>
The report also says that Respawn SVP of operations Daniel Suarez is now taking over the role of general manager at the studio, reporting directly to Vince Zampella. Alongside being founder of the studio, Zampella was previously general manager, while also serving as the head of the Battlefield series. Zampella is continuing as group GM and EVP for both Battlefield and Respawn.
</p>
<p>
It's probably also worth noting that Jeff Grubb, known for his insider information (he recently accurately reported on the Oblivion remaster dropping last week), has apparently been told that there are <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/grubb.wtf/post/3lnxurth7xs2y">wider layoffs taking place at EA</a>. Grubb says he doesn't know an exact number, but it's apparently similar in size to the <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/grubb.wtf/post/3lnxurth7xs2y">layoffs that took place last year</a>, which saw around 670 employees affected at the time.
</p>
<p>
Honestly, the whole announcement from Respawn is predictably tone deaf. It claims that Apex Legends will be "exploring bold experiences that push the boundaries of competitive play", while ignoring the fact that cutting a team to such a degree whilst it's in the midst of making "Apex 2.0" won't help them meet those margins the game is currently failing to achieve. Fingers crossed that everyone affected is able to land on their feet.

</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marvel Fighting Game With Over 300 Characters Finally Coming To Steam]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/marvel-contest-of-champions-pc-steam-300-characters-1851778350</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/marvel-fighting-game-with-over-300-characters-finally-coming-to-steam.1176789/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/marvel-contest-of-champions-pc-steam-300-characters-1851778350<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="b27c3fe7753d5f74b24e8ea972b79efa" data-recommend-id="image://b27c3fe7753d5f74b24e8ea972b79efa" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Kablam / Marvel</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="b27c3fe7753d5f74b24e8ea972b79efa" data-recommend-id="image://b27c3fe7753d5f74b24e8ea972b79efa" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/adding-squirrel-girl-to-marvel-s-contest-of-champions-d-1840929776?_gl=1*eqwr5g*_ga*MTc0MjY2NTg1OS4xNzQwMzc1OTc4*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTc0NTk0OTAxMy41Mi4xLjE3NDU5NDk5NzYuNDkuMC4w&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/adding-squirrel-girl-to-marvel-s-contest-of-champions-d-1840929776?_gl=1*eqwr5g*_ga*MTc0MjY2NTg1OS4xNzQwMzc1OTc4*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTc0NTk0OTAxMy41Mi4xLjE3NDU5NDk5NzYuNDkuMC4w"><em>Marvel Contest of Champions</em></a></span>, a long-running fighting game from mobile developer Kablam, is getting an official PC port and Steam release in the near future. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="195922" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Is Alan Wake Worth Playing Before Its Sequel? | Total Recall" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="390" data-playlist="195922,196345,195928" data-current="195922"><div><p>Is Alan Wake Worth Playing Before Its Sequel? | Total Recall</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195922/195922_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195922/195922_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195922/195922_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195922/195922_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21438.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>One of the most successful and popular Marvel video games is one that you might not have heard of: <em>Marvel Contest of Champions</em>. This mobile free-to-play fighting game has been around since 2014, and after a decade of updates it has a massive roster that <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://marvel-contestofchampions.fandom.com/wiki/List_of_Champions&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://marvel-contestofchampions.fandom.com/wiki/List_of_Champions" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">includes 300+ Marvel heroes and villains</a></span> including characters like Wolverine, Storm, Spider-Man, Captain America, Dazzler, Silver Surfer and so many more. And now this comic book fighter is hopping to a new platform.</p><p>On April 29, after plenty of rumors and fan speculation, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://youtu.be/eGDSf2PHJ40&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://youtu.be/eGDSf2PHJ40" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Kablam announced that <em>Marvel Contest of Champions</em> was officially coming to Steam</a></span>. This new PC port of the fighting game will feature improved HD visuals running at 60FPS as well as an “overhauled UI.” The PC port also supports both keyboard and controllers with fully remappable controls.</p><p>The devs say <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://store.steampowered.com/app/3127280/Marvel_Contest_of_Champions/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3127280/Marvel_Contest_of_Champions/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Contest of Champions</em> on PC</a></span> will receive monthly updates and events just like the mobile version, which makes sense as both versions support crossplay and cross-progression. So you should be able to kick some butt on your bus ride home and then get a few more fights in on your PC without missing a beat. </p><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://playcontestofchampions.com/pc-pre-reg/?utm_source=pr&amp;utm_medium=pr-na&amp;utm_campaign=pc-prereg&amp;utm_content=pc-pre-reg-announce-release&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://playcontestofchampions.com/pc-pre-reg/?utm_source=pr&amp;utm_medium=pr-na&amp;utm_campaign=pc-prereg&amp;utm_content=pc-pre-reg-announce-release" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Kablam is letting players pre-register</a></span> now ahead of the game’s release on PC. Doing so via the official website will unlock new gear and items when <em>Contest of Champion</em>s launches on PC. The company has yet to provide a specific date for when that will happen, but it sounds like fans won’t have to wait long to start punching Spider-Man, Mr. Fantastic, the Hulk and other heroes on Steam. </p><p> .<br></p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apex Legends and Star Wars: Jedi Dev Respawn Cancels Another Incubation Project, Around 100 Employees Impacted]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/apex-legends-and-star-wars-jedi-dev-respawn-cancels-another-incubation-project-around-100-employees-impacted</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/apex-legends-and-star-wars-jedi-dev-respawn-cancels-another-incubation-project-around-100-employees-impacted.1176780/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/apex-legends-and-star-wars-jedi-dev-respawn-cancels-another-incubation-project-around-100-employees-impacted<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">EA has canceled another incubation project at Respawn Entertainment today, and simultaneously laid off a number of individuals across its incubation, Apex Legends, and Star Wars: Jedi teams, IGN has learned.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In a post today from the studio, Respawn announced is has "made the decision to step away from two early-stage incubation projects and make some targeted team adjustments across Apex Legends and Star Wars Jedi." One of these canceled incubation projects is the same one <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/respawn-has-quietly-canceled-a-multiplayer-fps-incubation-project">already reported on back in March</a>. The other, <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-04-29/electronic-arts-lays-off-hundreds-cancels-titanfall-game" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Bloomberg reports</a>, was an extraction shooter set in the Titanfall universe, code-named R7.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"These decisions aren’t easy, and we are deeply grateful to every teammate affected — their creativity and contributions have helped build Respawn into what it is today," the post continued. "We’re offering meaningful support to those impacted, including exploring new opportunities within EA."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">IGN understands that roughly 100 individuals are affected by the changes, including a mix of developers, publishing, and QA workers on Apex Legends, as well as smaller groups of individuals on the Jedi team and on the incubation projects. IGN also understands that at least some, though not all, of the developers from the incubation project reported on in March have already been moved to work on Iron Man at EA Motive, Battlefield, and other projects. When asked, EA declined to comment on the exact number of individuals impacted, saying it is offering impacted individuals 30 days to find a new opportunity inside the organization and is endeavoring to find roles for as many individuals as it can internally.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Internally at Respawn, work will continue on Apex Legends as well as the game's next iteration, the next entry in the Star Wars: Jedi franchise, and support on the upcoming Bit Reactor Star Wars game, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/star-wars-zero-company-officially-revealed-with-2026-release-window">Star Wars: Zero Company</a>. EA declined to say whether or not any other incubation projects are currently in the works.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In addition to these changes, Respawn SVP of operations Daniel Suarez is being elevated to general manager of Respawn, and will report directly to Vince Zampella. Previously, Zampella served as GM of Respawn, the studio he founded, in addition to his role as head of the Battlefield franchise. Zampella will continue as group GM and EVP overseeing both Battlefield and Respawn.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Notably, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/apex-legends-isnt-doing-the-business-for-ea-so-its-making-apex-legends-20-to-come-out-after-battlefield">just last February</a>, EA told investors that Apex Legends was "not headed in the direction that we have wanted" and hadn't been for some time. CEO Andrew Wilson said that Respawn is currently working on a major update, dubbed "Apex 2.0".</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Our expectation is that Apex will also be one of those franchises and that sometime on a longer-term time horizon, there will be an even bigger, more meaningful update to that broader game experience, an Apex 2.0, if you will. This will not be the final incarnation of Apex," Wilson said.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">These changes continue a trend at EA of canceled projects, layoffs, and restructuring that's been going on for several years now. It began in 2023 with the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/bioware-eliminates-50-jobs-to-match-studios-changing-needs">elimination of 50 jobs at BioWare</a> and an <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/f1-developer-codemasters-suffers-round-of-layoffs">unknown number more at Codemasters</a>, and continued when EA <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ea-to-lay-off-around-670-to-advance-the-way-we-work">laid off 670 workers</a> company-wide, including <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/apex-legends-hit-by-layoffs-amid-eas-ongoing-reductions">around two dozen workers at Respawn,</a> and canceled several projects. More recently, EA restructured BioWare, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/mass-effect-5-bioware-doesnt-require-support-from-the-full-studio-ea-moves-some-staff-to-other-teams">moving developers to other projects</a> and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/dragon-age-developers-reveal-theyve-been-laid-off-after-bioware-puts-full-focus-on-mass-effect">laying off others</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Rebekah Valentine is a senior reporter for IGN. You can find her posting on BlueSky @duckvalentine.bsky.social. Got a story tip? Send it to rvalentine@ign.com.</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>A previous version of this article erroneously stated that around 100 people are employed at Respawn. This has been amended above and in the headline. The piece has also been updated to add more detail about ongoing projects at Respawn and developer re-allocation.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine 2 Patch 8 Detailed, Horde Mode Mechanics and Map Revealed]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/warhammer-40000-space-marine-2-patch-8-detailed-horde-mode-mechanics-and-map-revealed</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/warhammer-40-000-space-marine-2-patch-8-detailed-horde-mode-mechanics-and-map-revealed.1176774/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/warhammer-40000-space-marine-2-patch-8-detailed-horde-mode-mechanics-and-map-revealed<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Suffer not the xeno to live.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/warhammer-40000-space-marine-ii">Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine 2</a> is set for Patch 8 and with it the hotly anticipated Horde Mode, which fans hope will breathe new life into the third-person action game.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In <a href="https://community.focus-entmt.com/focus-entertainment/space-marine-2/blogs/197-april-community-update" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">a post on publisher Focus Entertainment’s website</a>, developer Saber Interactive revealed how the Horde mode will work. It’s for up to three players (you can play solo with two bots, like in the PvE Operations mode), and, as you’d expect, you fight increasingly difficult waves of Tyranids and Chaos. Your class and weapon levels are based on your PvE levels.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Difficulty will increase for each wave defeated, so you’ll have to prepare yourself accordingly to vaporize as many waves as you can,” Focus and Saber said.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The companies also offered a first look, below, at the Horde mode map, which takes place in Kadaku. Kadaku is the Imperial Jungle World Space Marine 2 players will already be familiar with. The Horde Mode release date is yet to be announced, but it sounds like it’s not too far off.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/04/29/sm2-1745946503242.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">That's a big gun on Kadaku. Image credit: focus Entertainment.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">As for what else Patch 8 will bring, Focus and Saber players can expect more free and premium DLC, including a Blood Angels cosmetic pack, a White Scars Champion Pack, and a rebalancing of the Absolute difficulty.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Fans had indicated that they wanted Absolute difficulty to be even tougher in order to differentiate it more from Lethal difficulty, and it sounds like that’s on the cards.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Last month, we did a community poll on Focus Together to collect your feedback and see what you were interested to see on the Absolute difficulty to differentiate it more from Lethal,” Focus and Saber said. “You will see the changes we made as part of the 8.0 update. Expect an even tougher challenge!”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Expect a lot more from Patch 8, the companies said. PTS players will be able to test Patch 8 before it's released.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Focus and Saber had previously confirmed that <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/warhammer-40000-space-marine-2-dev-moves-to-set-the-record-straight-insists-its-not-abandoning-the-game-following-space-marine-3-announcement"><u>Space Marine 2 </u><u><em>is </em></u><u>getting a new class</u></a>, but there’s no mention of it in the Patch 8 post. Most assume it will be the Apothecary, as close to a medic class as Space Marines have. But there is hope that it could be the Librarian, which would mean super cool warp-powered space magic. Also confirmed coming are new PvE operations and melee weapons.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">There’s a lot happening in the world of Space Marine 2, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/warhammer-40000-space-marine-3-announced-development-officially-begins-at-saber-interactive"><u>despite the surprise announcement that development of Space Marine 3 development had begun</u></a>. Space Marine 2’s year one roadmap remains in place.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Score 60% Off a Sam's Club Membership Today Only, and Secure Sold Out Pokémon TCG Sets at a Discount]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/score-60-off-a-sams-club-membership-today-only-and-secure-sold-out-pokemon-tcg-sets-at-a-discount</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/score-60-off-a-sams-club-membership-today-only-and-secure-sold-out-pok%C3%A9mon-tcg-sets-at-a-discount.1176771/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/score-60-off-a-sams-club-membership-today-only-and-secure-sold-out-pokemon-tcg-sets-at-a-discount<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Extra $5 off for today only.</h2></p><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">I want to call this a good day for anyone who likes saving money without working too hard. Sam's Club memberships are <a href="https://zdcs.link/QpXOVw?object_uuid=851fc1cd-08ba-4a3f-8d31-cf016fd7cf0b&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">60% off today through Groupon</a>, which is about the easiest win you are going to find if you like cheap bulk snacks, discounted tech, and occasional panic buys of kayaks you will never use.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Even better, a membership right now gets you access to <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-surging-sparks-booster-bundle-shining-fates-amazon-restock-latest">Pokémon TCG deals</a> that have been selling out fast, including the Charizard ex Super-Premium Collection at a price you can explain to your wallet.</p><p id="sams-club-membership-1-year"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Sam's Club Membership (1 Year)">Sam's Club Membership (1 Year)</h2></p><div catalogid="69f51126-8354-46ab-b22b-cabdf67d8cf0" id="219758"><div id="219758" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Sam's Club Membership (1 Year)</h3></p><div data-cy="solo-product-description"><p>Extra $5 off for today only</p></div></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Sam's Club memberships are rarely this cheap without some kind of catch, but today you can pick up a one-year "Club" membership for $20 after an extra $5 discount, or upgrade to "Plus" for $60 if you want perks like free shipping. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">I think the Club tier is the real steal here, especially if you just want access to the savings without needing someone to upsell you into a tire rotation package. With more than 25,000 people already jumping on it, I would not sit on this too long.</p></div><p id="charizard-ex-super-premium"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Charizard Ex Super-Premium">Pokémon TCG Charizard Ex Super-Premium Collection</h2></p><div catalogid="69f51126-8354-46ab-b22b-cabdf67d8cf0" id="219757"><div id="219757" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Pokemon TCG Charizard Ex Super-Premium Collection</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">If you have been trying to land the Charizard ex Super-Premium Collection without paying scalper prices, this is probably your moment. Sam's Club has it for $49.94, and in my opinion, that is about as good as it gets without waiting for some mythical clearance event. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">You are getting ten booster packs, three promo cards, a Charizard figure, and a code card for <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-game-sale-switch-2-woot">Pokémon</a> TCG Live. You will need a membership to grab it, but compared to what this set has been going for elsewhere, that feels like a small trade-off.</p></div><p id="single-pokmon-card-deals"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Single Pokémon Card Deals">Single Pokémon Cards Are Crashing</h2></p><p data-cy="paragraph">In my opinion, this is a strong two-for-one situation. You save on the membership, you get early access to deals that are usually wiped out by the time they hit the regular shelves, and if you have been thinking about jumping back into <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-deals-for-april-29-2025">Pokémon TCG </a>without paying eBay prices, this is probably one of the better windows you will see.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Christian Wait is a contributing freelancer for IGN covering everything collectable and deals. Christian has over 7 years of experience in the Gaming and Tech industry with bylines at Mashable and Pocket-Tactics. Christian also makes hand-painted collectibles for Saber Miniatures. Christian is also the author of "Pokemon Ultimate Unofficial Gaming Guide by GamesWarrior".  Find Christian on X @ChrisReggieWait.</em></p></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Apr 29, 2025 4:26 pm</p></div></div><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apex Legends Studio Cancels Two "Incubation" Projects, Lays Off Staff Amid Big EA Shakeup]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/apex-legends-studio-cancels-two-incubation-projects-lays-off-staff-amid-big-ea-shakeup/1100-6531200/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/apex-legends-studio-cancels-two-incubation-projects-lays-off-staff-amid-big-ea-shakeup.1176747/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/apex-legends-studio-cancels-two-incubation-projects-lays-off-staff-amid-big-ea-shakeup/1100-6531200/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6531200">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>In the latest blow to the video game labor community, Electronic Arts has confirmed layoffs at Apex Legends developer Respawn and the cancellation of two "incubation" projects at the studio. About 100 people at Respawn have been affected by the changes, a report said.</p><p>A report from <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-04-29/electronic-arts-lays-off-hundreds-cancels-titanfall-game?accessToken=eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiIsInR5cCI6IkpXVCJ9.eyJzb3VyY2UiOiJTdWJzY3JpYmVyR2lmdGVkQXJ0aWNsZSIsImlhdCI6MTc0NTk1MzQ2OCwiZXhwIjoxNzQ2NTU4MjY4LCJhcnRpY2xlSWQiOiJTVkhVQjFUMEcxS1cwMCIsImJjb25uZWN0SWQiOiJCMUVBQkI5NjQ2QUM0REZFQTJBRkI4MjI1MzgyQTJFQSJ9.Ok9U1G-8KnrQWSRme5JF1VqfCPIxgENs3iq9d32PeRc" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Bloomberg</a> said a Titanfall extraction shooter, which was said to be in early development, was one of the canceled incubation projects. The game was codenamed R7, the report said, adding that it was not close to being ready for release.</p><p>More widely, EA is making cuts that affect many people, <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/grubb.wtf/post/3lnxurth7xs2y" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">reporter Jeff Grubb of GameSpot sister site Giant Bomb said</a>. Bloomberg said between 300 and 400 people in total are losing their jobs at EA, including the 100 at Respawn. EA Sports FC and Apex Legends underperformed, leading to this latest wave of cuts at EA, GameSpot understands. Dragon Age: The Veilguard might not have <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/after-dragon-age-the-veilguard-comes-up-short-bioware-undergoes-changes/1100-6529105/">performed up to EA's sales expectations</a>, but we understand its performance is not related to the cuts across EA generally.</p><p>As for the non-Respawn layoffs, <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ea-cuts-around-300-roles-including-roughly-100-at-respawn" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">IGN</a> reported that EA's "Experiences" team was affected, along with customer support and marketing roles. Affected staffers were reportedly given a chance to apply for other internal roles prior to parting ways entirely.</p><p>"As part of our continued focus on our long-term strategic priorities, we've made select changes within our organization that more effectively aligns teams and allocates resources in service of driving future growth," a spokesperson for EA told Bloomberg.</p><p>A <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/dont-believe-those-titanfall-3-rumors-youve-heard/1100-6530730/" data-ref-id="1100-6530730">skunkworks project from Titanfall veteran Steve Fukuda</a> is not going ahead within Respawn, Grubb added, and "there is no Titanfall 3." That shouldn't come as a surprise, though, as Titanfall 3 was never a sure thing. It appears this could have been the Titanfall extraction game, but it's not clear.</p><div data-embed-type="tweet" data-src="https://x.com/JeffGrubb/status/1917273189001974166" data-has-image="false"><blockquote data-conversation="none" data-mce-disable-toolbar="true"><p dir="ltr">That Steve Fukuda project is in the bin. Laying off a ton of people. There is no Titanfall 3 -- as this should make clear. <br>I don't think people realize just how much EA Football Club and Apex Legends missed last year. Dragon Age isn't even a factor compared to those two. <a href="https://t.co/lqDw5nCK97" rel="nofollow ">https://t.co/lqDw5nCK97</a></p>  — Grubb (@JeffGrubb) <a href="https://twitter.com/JeffGrubb/status/1917273189001974166?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 29, 2025</a></blockquote>              </div><p>A <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/apex-legends-and-star-wars-jedi-dev-respawn-cancels-another-incubation-project-lays-off-unknown-number-of-individuals-again" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">memo first seen by IGN</a> states that EA made the decision to "step away from two early-stage incubation projects" at Respawn, along with making "targeted team adjustments" across Apex Legends and Star Wars Jedi. In addition to the rumored Titanfall extraction shooter, the other canceled incubation project at Respawn was reportedly a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/apex-legends-and-titanfall-studio-appears-to-cancel-unannounced-fps/1100-6529955/" data-ref-id="1100-6529955">multiplayer FPS that we first heard about earlier this year.</a></p><p>Respawn itself confirmed the changes in a memo posted online. In the statement, Respawn said it is a studio that embraces "bold ideas" and "creative risks," but they don't always pan out.</p><p>"Our commitment to player-first experiences remains unchanged," Respawn said.</p><p>EA said it is offering "meaningful support" to affected staffers.</p><p>People affected by the layoffs at Respawn include staffers working in publishing, QA, and members of the Star Wars Jedi and incubation teams, IGN reported.</p><p>Respawn will continue to develop more content for Apex Legends and build the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/respawn-to-develop-final-game-in-star-wars-jedi-trilogy-says-ea/1100-6526559/" data-ref-id="1100-6526559">next Star Wars: Jedi game</a>, but EA declined to confirm if any incubation projects are currently in the works.</p><p>For a long time already, EA management had signaled problems for Apex Legends. CEO Andrew Wilson said the game was <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ea-teases-a-bigger-newer-apex-legends-2-0/1100-6529289/" data-ref-id="1100-6529289">"not headed in the direction that we have wanted."</a> The executive also has talked about plans for something called <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ea-teases-a-bigger-newer-apex-legends-2-0/1100-6529289/" data-ref-id="1100-6529289">"Apex 2.0."</a></p><p>Respawn said it wants to expand "what Apex can be," with developers continue to refine gameplay and "bring new ideas to upcoming seasons." Respawn added that it wants to "push the boundaries of competitive play while staying true to the spirit of competition, creativity, and integrity that our community expects."</p><p>As for the Star Wars: Jedi team, Respawn said the next entry in the series aims to "raise the bar again for storytelling and gameplay."</p><p>In February 2024, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ea-laying-off-around-670-people-sunsetting-unspecified-games/1100-6521460/" data-ref-id="1100-6521460">EA laid off around 670 people</a>, which was about 5% of its global workforce. The new round of cuts across EA are said to be "similar" to that round of layoffs in 2024, Grubb said, though the exact number is unclear. EA is making these reported changes just ahead of its next investor briefing on May 6.</p><p>The new changes at Respawn come at a time of uncertainty in general in the economic market for most companies due in part to Trump's scattered tariff policies and other factors. Leading global bank JP Morgan says <a href="https://www.jpmorgan.com/insights/global-research/economy/recession-probability" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">the risk of a global recession stands at around 60%.</a></p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Sims 4's latest DLC brings kitchen clutter, workshop tinkering, and fashion for the elderly]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/the-sims-4s-latest-dlc-brings-kitchen-clutter-workshop-tinkering-and-fashion-for-the-elderly</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-sims-4s-latest-dlc-brings-kitchen-clutter-workshop-tinkering-and-fashion-for-the-elderly.1176744/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/the-sims-4s-latest-dlc-brings-kitchen-clutter-workshop-tinkering-and-fashion-for-the-elderly<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>Arriving later this week.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>EA</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
<a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/the-sims-4">The Sims 4</a> is about to get a little messier - and marginally more fashionable for those in a certain generational bracket - as it prepares to launch a fresh wave of newly announced Kit DLC.
</p>
<p>
These new small-scale DLC packs begin with The Sims 4's Kitchen Clutter Kit, which does exactly what it sounds like, providing various bits of decor players can use to give their cooking spaces a more lived-in feel. You've got fridges adorned with magnets, open cereal boxes, kitchen timers, recipe tablet, and "much more" - useful for when you're looking to create a living space with more personality than a showhome.
</p>
<p>
There's more mess to be found in The Sims 4's Restoration Workshop Kit, which looks to provide fixtures and furnishings players can use to build a well-utilised workshop. "With [this kit], Sims can take well-loved, broken-down appliances, including reviving a microwave, coffee maker, refrigerator and stove with the Handiness Skill," EA explains. "Restore the appliance to its former glory, and make it fully functional again."
</p>
<figure>

<figcaption>The Sims 4's Kitchen Clutter Kit. | <span>Image credit: <cite>EA</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>
Rounding out The Sims 4's latest batch of DLC drops is the Golden Years Kit, featuring fashionable looks and accessories Elder Sims can use to "express their individuality". EA is a bit vague on the details for this one, but expect the likes of toupees, gardening gloves, and glasses with straps - meaning Elder Sims with a penchant for partying won't lose them mid-swing.
</p>
<figure>

<figcaption>The Sims 4's Restoration Workshop Kit. | <span>Image credit: <cite>EA</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>
The Sims 4's Restoration Workshop Kit, Kitchen Clutter Kit, and Golden Years Kit all arrive this Thursday, 1st May. They'll likely cost £4.99 apiece, and will be available on all platforms - which is to say PlayStation 5, PlayStation 4, Xbox One, Xbox Series X/S, and PC.
</p>
<p>Elsewhere in the world of The Sims, footage from EA's new The Sims "game concept" - which may or may not be the much-discussed Project Rene - <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/six-minutes-of-eas-new-the-sims-game-concept-leak-online">recently surfaced online</a>, and fans eager for a proper Sims 4 sequel weren't exactly thrilled to see what looked like a naff mobile game.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EA Has Canceled Another Incubation Project At Respawn, Layoffs Reportedly Hit The Apex Legends, Star Wars Jedi And Incubation Teams]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/ea-has-canceled-another-incubation-project-at-respawn-layoffs-reportedly-hit-the-apex-legends-star-wars-jedi-and-incubation-teams/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ea-has-canceled-another-incubation-project-at-respawn-layoffs-reportedly-hit-the-apex-legends-star-wars-jedi-and-incubation-teams.1176732/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/ea-has-canceled-another-incubation-project-at-respawn-layoffs-reportedly-hit-the-apex-legends-star-wars-jedi-and-incubation-teams/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p><strong>Update 29/02/2025:&nbsp;</strong>A report from <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-04-29/electronic-arts-lays-off-hundreds-cancels-titanfall-game?accessToken=eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiIsInR5cCI6IkpXVCJ9.eyJzb3VyY2UiOiJTdWJzY3JpYmVyR2lmdGVkQXJ0aWNsZSIsImlhdCI6MTc0NTk1MzQ2OCwiZXhwIjoxNzQ2NTU4MjY4LCJhcnRpY2xlSWQiOiJTVkhVQjFUMEcxS1cwMCIsImJjb25uZWN0SWQiOiJCMUVBQkI5NjQ2QUM0REZFQTJBRkI4MjI1MzgyQTJFQSJ9.Ok9U1G-8KnrQWSRme5JF1VqfCPIxgENs3iq9d32PeRc">Bloomberg</a> clarifies that somewhere between 300-400 developers have been laid off at EA, with approximately 100 of those cuts coming from Respawn.</p>
<p>According to Bloomberg, the incubation project EA canceled was under the codename R7, and was an extraction shooter set within the world of Titanfall.</p>
<p>In a statement on the cuts, EA spokesperson Justin Higgs said, "<em>As part of our continued focus for our long-term strategic priorities, we've made select changes within our organization that more effectively aligns teams and allocates resources in service of driving future growth.</em>"</p>
<p><strong>Original Story:</strong></p>
<p>EA has canceled yet another project that was in an early incubation stage at Respawn, one month after it canceled a<a href="https://wccftech.com/respawn-cancels-another-unannounced-multiplayer-fps/"> multiplayer project at the same stage</a>, and according to a report from<a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/apex-legends-and-star-wars-jedi-dev-respawn-cancels-another-incubation-project-lays-off-unknown-number-of-individuals-again"> IGN</a>, EA will also be laying off an unknown number of employees at Respawn across the Apex Legends, Star Wars Jedi, and incubation teams.</p>
<p>In a statement published to <a href="https://x.com/Respawn/status/1917267367144423543">X</a>, Respawn announces that it has "<em>made the decision to step away from two early-stage incubation projects</em>," which refers to the project canceled last month, and another cancellation we're hearing about today for the first time. Respawn continues to add that there will be layoffs across the Apex Legends and Star Wars teams, though it doesn't mention the cuts to the incubation team, which come from IGN's sources.</p>
<p>It's unclear how many people have been cut from Respawn, though the cuts are reportedly being made across departments and aren't focused on one part of the studio.</p>
<p>"<em>As we sharpen our focus for the future, we've made the decision to step away from two early-stage incubation projects and make some targeted team adjustments across Apex Legends and Star Wars Jedi. These decisions aren't easy, and we are deeply grateful to every teammate affected - their creativity and contributions have helped build Respawn into what it is today. We're offering meaningful support to those impacts, including exploring new opportunities within EA,</em>" the studio's statement reads.</p>
<p>The statement also addressed what these cuts mean for Apex Legends and Star Wars Jedi, saying of the former that&nbsp;"<em>while the team will continue to refine gameplay and bring new ideas to upcoming seasons, we're also investing in what's next for the franchise - exploring bold experiences that push the boundaries of competitive play while staying true to the spirit of competition</em>."</p>
<p>Regarding the latter, Respawn simply added, "<em>We're excited to keep building new stories</em>—<em>with the next chapter of the Star Wars Jedi series aiming to raise the bar again for storytelling and gameplay</em>."</p>
<p>The booming success of Apex Legends and the Star Wars Jedi series in 2019 has, in many ways, made Respawn the crown jewel studio for EA's <a href="https://wccftech.com/ea-split-up/">entertainment side</a> of the business. But it's worth asking how long it could keep that status if EA consistently shuts down the new ideas the developers at Respawn come up with.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Respawn Hit by Further Layoffs as Two Unannounced Projects Canceled]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/respawn-layoffs-project-cancellations</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/respawn-hit-by-further-layoffs-as-two-unannounced-projects-canceled.1176729/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/respawn-layoffs-project-cancellations<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Star Wars Jedi&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>Titanfall&nbsp;</em>studio Respawn Entertainment has been hit by further layoffs, and the studio has also opted to cancel two of its "early-stage incubation projects".</p>

<p>Per a <a href="https://x.com/Respawn/status/1917267367144423543" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">post</a> on X, Respawn announces its decisions to "step away" from the aforementioned projects and to "make some targeted team adjustments" to teams working on&nbsp;<em>Star Wars Jedi&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>Apex Legends</em>. The projects in question aren't named, though.</p>

<p>The studio says it's "offering meaningful support to those impacted, including exploring new opportunities within EA", and that the decisions to cancel the projects and lay off the staff members in question "[weren't] easy".</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/apex-legends-respawn-layoffs.jpg?itok=gt0PpKXs 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/apex-legends-respawn-layoffs.jpg?itok=efjA4CKk 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Staff members working on&nbsp;<em>Apex Legends&nbsp;</em>and the&nbsp;<em>Star Wars Jedi&nbsp;</em>series have been laid off.</figcaption></figure><p>Respawn doesn't say which staff departments have been particularly affected by these layoffs, but it does say that the "next chapter" of the&nbsp;<em>Star Wars Jedi&nbsp;</em>series will "raise the bar again for storytelling and gameplay", so that's not one of the canceled projects.</p>

<p>The <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/star-wars-zero-company-respawn-bit-reactor" rel="nofollow">recently-revealed&nbsp;<em>Star Wars Zero Company</em></a>, a turn-based tactics game set in the dying days of the Clone Wars, also won't be affected; it's not an early-stage incubation project, after all, but one that's been fully unveiled.</p>

<p>Rumors are swirling that&nbsp;a third&nbsp;<em>Titanfall&nbsp;</em>game is in development, but those rumors are fairly insubstantial at the moment, so it's impossible to say whether that was one of the games Respawn decided to can.</p>

<p>We do, however, know that this isn't the first time in the last year or so that Respawn has been hit by layoffs. In March last year, it was revealed that <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/electronic-arts-to-lay-off-5-of-its-workforce-amid-refocus-on-owned-ip-and-sports-games" rel="nofollow">EA would lay off 5% of its workforce</a>, and that a&nbsp;<em>Star Wars&nbsp;</em>FPS in development at Respawn would be canceled, with <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/apex-legends-developer-respawn-hit-by-layoffs-among-cuts-at-electronic-arts" rel="nofollow">layoffs also hitting the studio</a>.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/star-wars-jedi-respawn-entertainment.jpg?itok=naJdoil_ 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/star-wars-jedi-respawn-entertainment.jpg?itok=meMkijgG 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>The next&nbsp;<em>Star Wars Jedi&nbsp;</em>game is still very much in development.</figcaption></figure><p>The latest layoffs at Respawn come as part of a wave that's still sweeping the industry, with studios like <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/bioware-layoffs-veilguard-failure" rel="nofollow">BioWare</a>, <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/rumbleverse-and-killer-instct-studio-iron-galaxy-suffers-layoffs" rel="nofollow">Iron Galaxy</a>, and even <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/microsoft-layoffs-january-2025" rel="nofollow">Microsoft</a> letting staff go in recent months.</p>

<p>We'll have to wait and see how these layoffs and project cancellations affect Respawn. Stay tuned for more on this as soon as we get it.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Star Wars: Jedi Studio Doesn't Mention Layoffs In Announcement About Laying Developers Off]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/respawn-layoffs-star-wars-jedi-apex-legends-titanfall-1851778330</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/star-wars-jedi-studio-doesnt-mention-layoffs-in-announcement-about-laying-developers-off.1176726/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/respawn-layoffs-star-wars-jedi-apex-legends-titanfall-1851778330<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Between <em>Apex Legends</em>, the <em>Star Wars: Jedi</em> series, and other projects, Respawn Entertainment has a lot on its plate, so it’s a little shocking to hear that EA is laying off even more members of the studio this year. The cuts come amid hundreds of new layoffs at the publisher which reportedly canceled a <em>Titanfall</em> extraction shooter that was very early in development. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196653" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="The Week In Games: A Star Wars Classic Returns &amp; More New Releases" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="105" data-playlist="196653,195840,196049" data-current="196653"><div><p>The Week In Games: A Star Wars Classic Returns &amp; More New Releases</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196653/196653_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196653/196653_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196653/196653_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196653/196653_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/22209.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>Respawn announced on Tuesday that it had recently stepped away from two unannounced incubation projects. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/Respawn/status/1917267367144423543&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/Respawn/status/1917267367144423543" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The statement mentioned</a></span> “difficult changes,” “targeted team adjustments,” and providing “meaningful support to those impacted,” but didn’t explicitly say there were layoffs or how many were affected. “Wait idk what this means,” one person responded on X. </p><p>To know what was actually going on, you’d have had to read <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.ign.com/articles/apex-legends-and-star-wars-jedi-dev-respawn-cancels-another-incubation-project-lays-off-unknown-number-of-individuals-again&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/apex-legends-and-star-wars-jedi-dev-respawn-cancels-another-incubation-project-lays-off-unknown-number-of-individuals-again" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">a new report by <em>IGN</em></a></span> that was posted at the exact same moment. The fresh layoffs, which reportedly <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.ign.com/articles/respawn-has-quietly-canceled-a-multiplayer-fps-incubation-project&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/respawn-has-quietly-canceled-a-multiplayer-fps-incubation-project" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">follow on the back of an earlier round in March</a></span>, included “a mix of developers, publishing, and QA workers on <em>Apex Legends</em>, as well as smaller groups of individuals on the <em>Jedi</em> team and on the incubation projects.” <em>IGN</em> reported here that up to 100 Respawn employees could be fired as part of today’s changes. </p><p>At least one of the cancelled incubation projects <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://insider-gaming.com/respawn-has-canceled-its-unannounced-fps-multiplayer-game/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://insider-gaming.com/respawn-has-canceled-its-unannounced-fps-multiplayer-game/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">was reportedly</a></span> a multiplayer first-person shooter, though little is known beyond that. Rumors of a new <em>Titanfall</em> game spring eternal, but had been circulating with greater intensity than usual lately as <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/titanfall/comments/1jva3cd/recent_titanfall_3_leaks_are_fake_according_to/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/titanfall/comments/1jva3cd/recent_titanfall_3_leaks_are_fake_according_to/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">dueling leakers</a></span> argued over whether any <em>Titanfall</em>-related projects remained active within Respawn and how close to seeing the light of day they were. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/JeffGrubb/status/1917273189001974166&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/JeffGrubb/status/1917273189001974166" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Giant Bomb</em>’s Jeff Grubb says</a></span> a new project from <em>Titanfall 2</em> game director Steve Fukuda was one of the things cancelled. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-04-29/electronic-arts-lays-off-hundreds-cancels-titanfall-game?accessToken=eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiIsInR5cCI6IkpXVCJ9.eyJzb3VyY2UiOiJTdWJzY3JpYmVyR2lmdGVkQXJ0aWNsZSIsImlhdCI6MTc0NTk1MzQ2OCwiZXhwIjoxNzQ2NTU4MjY4LCJhcnRpY2xlSWQiOiJTVkhVQjFUMEcxS1cwMCIsImJjb25uZWN0SWQiOiJCMUVBQkI5NjQ2QUM0REZFQTJBRkI4MjI1MzgyQTJFQSJ9.Ok9U1G-8KnrQWSRme5JF1VqfCPIxgENs3iq9d32PeRc&amp;sref=P6Q0mxvj&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-04-29/electronic-arts-lays-off-hundreds-cancels-titanfall-game?accessToken=eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiIsInR5cCI6IkpXVCJ9.eyJzb3VyY2UiOiJTdWJzY3JpYmVyR2lmdGVkQXJ0aWNsZSIsImlhdCI6MTc0NTk1MzQ2OCwiZXhwIjoxNzQ2NTU4MjY4LCJhcnRpY2xlSWQiOiJTVkhVQjFUMEcxS1cwMCIsImJjb25uZWN0SWQiOiJCMUVBQkI5NjQ2QUM0REZFQTJBRkI4MjI1MzgyQTJFQSJ9.Ok9U1G-8KnrQWSRme5JF1VqfCPIxgENs3iq9d32PeRc&amp;sref=P6Q0mxvj" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">According to<em> Bloomberg</em></a></span>, the project in question was codenamed R7 and was an extraction shooter set in the <em>Titanfall</em> universe that was “not close to being released.” </p><p>The Respawn cuts were just one part of a total 300-400 layoffs across EA this week. “As part of our continued focus on our long-term strategic priorities, we’ve made select changes within our organization that more effectively aligns teams and allocates resources in service of driving future growth,” EA spokesman Justin Higgs told <em>Bloomberg</em>.</p><p>EA CEO Andrew Wilson recently promised shareholders that<em> Apex Legends,</em> following a year of player burnout and downward trends, would get something of a “2.0" update in the future, suggesting a significant evolution of the battle royale is still in the pipeline. Respawn is also busy with the next <em>Star Wars: Jedi</em> game and is helping Bit Reactor with its recently revealed <em>XCOM</em>-style <em>Star Wars </em>game  called <em>Zero Company</em>. <em>IGN</em> reports that some developers previously at the studio were also moved to help EA Motive with its <em>Iron Man</em> game. </p><p>Respawn seems like the last place a publisher that prints money through <em>FIFA</em> and <em>Madden</em> loot boxes would look to cut, but the latest restructuring at Respawn comes after EA reported poorer-than-expected financial results last quarter due in part to <em>Dragon Age: The Veilguard</em> failing to meet the company’s sales expectations. The publisher thus also recently scaled back BioWare, which is now solely focused <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/mass-effect-5-bioware-dragon-age-veilguard-dlc-layoffs-1851750767&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/mass-effect-5-bioware-dragon-age-veilguard-dlc-layoffs-1851750767">on the next <em>Mass Effect</em></a></span>.</p><p><strong><em>Updated 4/29/2025 3:27 p.m. ET:</em></strong><em> Added new reporting from </em>Bloomberg<em>.</em> </p><p>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Evil Dead: The Game Has Been Mysteriously Delisted From Several Storefronts]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/evil-dead-the-game-has-been-mysteriously-delisted-from-several-storefronts/1100-6531206/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/evil-dead-the-game-has-been-mysteriously-delisted-from-several-storefronts.1176717/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/evil-dead-the-game-has-been-mysteriously-delisted-from-several-storefronts/1100-6531206/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6531206">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Regular support for <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/evil-dead-the-game-canceled-for-switch-no-future-content-planned-for-all-platforms/1100-6517845/">Evil Dead: The Video Game ended in late 2023</a>, and at the time, developer Saber Interactive pledged to keep the game servers online for the foreseeable future and address any major issues if they appeared. Curiously, it looks like the game has been delisted on several platforms, as fans noticed its removal from two storefronts.</p><p><a href="https://old.reddit.com/r/EvilDeadTheGame/comments/1ka4d44/update_evil_dead_the_games_epic_games_store/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Spotted by the ThePatMan117 on reddit</a>, Evil Dead: The Video Game is no longer listed for sale through The Epic Games Store or the PlayStation Store. At the time of writing, it can still be purchased through Steam or the Xbox Store, and developer Saber Interactive has yet to provide an update on the state of the game's future.</p><div tabindex="0" data-id="1501278900" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6461252,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Evil%20Dead%3A%20The%20Game%20%7C%20Game%20of%20the%20Year%20Edition%20Launch%20Trailer&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:97,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:false,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/evil-dead-the-game-game-of-the-year-edition-launch-trailer\/2300-6461252\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6461252\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6461252\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6461252\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6461252&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6461252,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6531206&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;evil-dead-the-game&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;3d,action,adventure,survival&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;playstation-5,playstation-4,xbox-series-x,pc,xbox-one,nintendo-switch&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;saber-interactive,h2-interactive-co-ltd,nighthawk-interactive&quot;,&quot;franchise&quot;:&quot;evil-dead&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;franchiseRoot&quot;:&quot;evil-dead&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6461252},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6461252\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;Publisher Asset&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4130157-33.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/q0GeMz81.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1682516820,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="q0GeMz81" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle" data-embed-type="video" data-ref-id="2300-6461252" data-src="/videos/evil-dead-the-game-game-of-the-year-edition-launch-trailer/2300-6461252/" data-width="854" data-height="480" data-video-start="0"><div><p>Evil Dead: The Game | Game of the Year Edition Launch Trailer</p><div><p>         Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?       </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!       </p></div></div><p>       Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.     </p><p>       This video has an invalid file format.     </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div><p>One of several asymmetrical multiplayer games based on an iconic horror film franchise--like Killer Clowns from Outer Space and The Texas Chain Saw Massacre to name just a few--Evil Dead: The Game was first revealed at the 2020 Game Awards. After being delayed beyond its initial planned launch date of 2021, the game arrived in 2022 for PC, PS4, PS5, Xbox One, and Xbox Series X|S, and it scooped up generally favorable reviews. Post-launch support for the game included <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/videos/evil-dead-the-game-splatter-royale-update-launch-trailer/2300-6460548/">Splatter Royale</a> and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/evil-dead-the-game-adds-army-of-darkness-update-update-with-new-map-exploration-mode-and-more/1100-6505459/">Army of Darkness</a> updates, and on console, a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/videos/evil-dead-the-game-game-of-the-year-edition-launch-trailer/2300-6461252/">Game of the Year Edition</a> was released</p><p>"Evil Dead: The Game is faithful, but sometimes to a fault. If there were more game modes or even more varied objectives in its one attractive game mode, it would feel more like a game for horror fans to play for a long time, maybe even moving competitors like Dead By Daylight or Hunt Showdown off their vaunted pedestals," Mark Delaney wrote In GameSpot's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/evil-dead-the-game-review-somewhat-groovy/1900-6417881/">Evil Dead: The Game review</a>.</p><p>Like the monsters constantly tormenting Evil Dead protagonist Ash Campbell, the IP regularly shows up in new forms. One of the more recent examples is <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/retrorealms-review-a-new-horror-multiverse-is-born/1900-6418302/">RetroRealms by developer WayForward</a>, as this gaming hub allowed players to grab Campbell's boomstick and take on the Deadites in a 2D platformer inspired by 16-bit classics.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                        
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/108490194306897153177?rel=author">Darryn Bonthuys</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[You Can Get A Free First Order Stormtrooper Skin In Fortnite]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/you-can-get-a-free-first-order-stormtrooper-skin-in-fortnite/1100-6531207/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/you-can-get-a-free-first-order-stormtrooper-skin-in-fortnite.1176714/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/you-can-get-a-free-first-order-stormtrooper-skin-in-fortnite/1100-6531207/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6531207">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/fortnite/" data-ref-id="5000-125765">Fortnite</a> is gearing up for the new <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fortnite-chapter-6-season-3-start-date-star-wars-battle-pass-and-everything-else-to-know/1100-6530938/" data-ref-id="1100-6530938">Star Wars: Galactic Battle season</a> on May 2, and now Epic Games and Disney are offering players a free First Order Stormtrooper skin ahead of the big crossover. There's also a Star Wars Watch Party happening and a free Asajj Ventress loading screen you can earn.</p><p dir="ltr">From now until August 31, you can unlock the First Order Stormtrooper outfit in Fortnite by connecting your Epic and MyDisney accounts. You don't even need to have Disney+ subscription. This is for the MyDisney account, which is free to sign up for.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394540/4484786-fortnite-first-order-stormtrooper-outfit-1920x1080-5f5992a58a9b.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4484786" data-ratio="0.56234567901235" data-width="1620" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394540/4484786-fortnite-first-order-stormtrooper-outfit-1920x1080-5f5992a58a9b.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4484786"></a><figcaption>Fortnite's First Order Stormtrooper skin</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394540/4484786-fortnite-first-order-stormtrooper-outfit-1920x1080-5f5992a58a9b.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">To link your account follow the steps below:</p><ul><li dir="ltr">Sign into your Epic account</li><li dir="ltr">On <a href="https://www.epicgames.com/account/connections">the Epic Games account page</a>, go to the Apps and Accounts section</li><li dir="ltr">Click "Connect" on the MyDisney Account option. You'll be directed to the MyDisney website to continue the process.</li></ul><p dir="ltr">After account linking, your First Order Stormtrooper will be waiting for you in your locker on Fortnite. This is a pretty sweet Star Wars skin that doesn't cost you a single V-Buck.</p><p dir="ltr">Fortnite is also hosting a <a href="https://www.fortnite.com/news/get-a-new-stormtrooper-in-fortnite-and-watch-two-episodes-of-star-wars-tales-of-the-underworld" rel="nofollow ">Star Wars Watch Party island</a> on May 2, starting at 7 AM PT / 10 AM ET to showcase the first two episodes of the new Star Wars: Tales of the Underworld animated series ahead of the big debut on Disney+.</p><p dir="ltr">You can find the Star Wars Watch Party island in the row of experiences you see after logging into Fortnite, or you can also use the magnifying glass in the top-left of the screen to search the island using the code 2124-6713-8076. Once on the island, you simply take a seat and enjoy the show. After watching both episodes, you'll get the Asajj Ventress loading screen in Fortnite within 72 hours. Epic says the island will be live until May 11.</p><p dir="ltr">Epic has shared an image of some of the skins coming to the battle pass for Galactic Battle, but the full details haven't been revealed yet. Here is <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fortnite-chapter-6-season-3-start-date-star-wars-battle-pass-and-everything-else-to-know/1100-6530938/">everything rumored and announced for Fortnite's Star Wars: Galactic Battle season</a>, including new POIs and gameplay changes.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>