<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 07:26:29 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[One of the Best Zombie Games in Years Is Finally Going on PlayStation Plus]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/best-zombie-games-years-playstation-plus/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/one-of-the-best-zombie-games-in-years-is-finally-going-on-playstation-plus.1005750/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/best-zombie-games-years-playstation-plus/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Hours ago, we reported on <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/playstation-plus-game-catalog-getting-14-new-games-in-october/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the full suite of games</a> making their way to PlayStation Plus in October. There are 14 fantastic titles headed to the service, but one game stands out above the rest.</p>



<p>In April 2023, Dambuster Studios finally released Dead Island 2 after more than a decade of troubled development. It had become one of the most highly anticipated open-world zombie survival games ever made, and when it hit the market, it didn’t disappoint.</p>



<p>In October, you’ll be able to get it for free on PlayStation 4 and PlayStation 5.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-kept-you-waiting">Kept You Waiting</h2>



<p>It has been a year and a half since Dead Island 2 hit the market, and in that time, Dambuster Studios has pumped plenty of content into the game, including two major expansions.</p>



<p>This stellar open-world zombie slasher ticked over seven million players in May 2024, and in just a few days, another monumental content drop will hit the platform. On October 22, players will get <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dead-island-2-horde-mode-new-game/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the ‘Neighbourhood Watch’ update</a>, which includes a horde mode and new game plus. </p>



<p>This patch will be free to take advantage of, and it lands at the perfect time for the game to be added to PlayStation Plus.</p>



<p>Before the game launched in April 2023, I was able to get exclusive access to the title and piece together my earliest impressions. From the moment I played the preview product, I was smitten with Dead Island 2. It’s a hilarious, gory romp that takes players through an immersive story that unfolds across a range of small sandbox environments.</p>



<p>It features returning characters from the series, a range of incredible weapons, and the freedom to become the kind of player you want to be.</p>



<p>Will you be downloading Dead Island 2 when it arrives on PS Plus this month? Let us know on the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/turkey-and-russia-ban-discord/">Turkey and Russia have banned Discord</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Turkey and Russia Have Blocked Discord, Leaving Gamers to Seek an Alternative]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/turkey-and-russia-ban-discord/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/turkey-and-russia-have-blocked-discord-leaving-gamers-to-seek-an-alternative.1005747/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/turkey-and-russia-ban-discord/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Turkey and Russia have moved to block access to Discord, the popular instant messaging platform used by millions of gamers worldwide. The platform reported it was launching an investigation into the outages in these regions, which suggests that the company wasn’t involved in the shutdown.</p>



<p>Turkey at least has explained why it has blocked Discord, but the reason is damning.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-severe-allegations">Severe Allegations</h2>



<p>Turkey has moved to block Discord, citing that the platform accommodates ‘crimes of child sexual abuse and obscenity’. This was a term thrown out against Discord in an Ankara court by Justice Minister Yilmaz Tunc, per <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/turkey-blocks-instant-messaging-platform-discord-2024-10-09/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">a report from Reuters</a>.</p>



<p>It was further referenced that Discord’s privacy policies make it almost impossible for security operatives to examine the content being shared on the platform.</p>



<blockquote>
<p>Security personnel cannot go through the content. We can only intervene when users complain to us about content shared there. Since Discord refuses to share its own information, including IP addresses and content, with our security units, we were forced to block access.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Russia recently banned Discord across the country because of the platform reportedly ‘violating Russian law’. It was stressed <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/russia-blocks-instant-messaging-platform-discord-tass-reports-2024-10-08/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">in a recent communication</a> that Russian regulators had reached out to Discord to delete a string of ‘illegal items’ but the platform failed to comply, forcing Russian governing bodies to block access to the application.</p>



<p>For years, certain countries have toyed with Discord access, and some maintain a restricted service that might block various aspects of the application, such as VOIP functionality. In the past, countries such as the United Arab Emirates and Egypt have blocked voice communications, but a blanket ban on Discord rarely takes place.</p>



<p>Discord’s representatives have advised that an investigation is underway, but it’s unclear how long the service will be offline in these countries.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/bungie-being-sued-for-copyright-infringement/">Bungie is being sued for copyright infringement</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Metal Bringer demo for PC now available]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/10/metal-bringer-demo-for-pc-now-available</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/metal-bringer-demo-for-pc-now-available.1005714/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/10/metal-bringer-demo-for-pc-now-available<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Featuring "Newbie" and "Extreme" modes.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > PLAYISM [274 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/playism">PLAYISM</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Alphawing [7 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/alphawing">Alphawing</a> have released a demo for <a title="Genres > Roguelite [196 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/roguelite">roguelite</a> <a title="Genres > Action [2,232 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action game</a> <em><a title="Games > Metal Bringer [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/metal-bringer">Metal Bringer</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > PC [21,428 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2334180/Metal_Bringer_Demo/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a>, the companies announced. The demo features “Newbie” and “Extreme” modes, and save data cannot be carried over to the full game. <span id="more-920489"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the demo, via PLAYISM:</p><blockquote><p><strong>■ About the Demo</strong></p><p>The <em>Metal Bringer</em> demo has been well received by visitors who tried it out at PAX West 2024 and Tokyo Game Show 2024, and now it’s finally come to Steam! The demo has two exclusive modes—“Newbie,” where you can play the beginning of the story, and “Extreme,” where you can try out a battle from midway through the game!</p><p>Both modes combined will let you experience the main game systems of Metal Bringer to give you a taste of the full game, so please check it out!</p><p><strong>Newbie</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Power up and customize your Labor with apps as you learn the basic game mechanics and play through the beginning of the story. Your Labor will start out weak, but keep growing stronger to defeat a boss within the time limit!</p><p><strong>Extreme</strong></p><p>Use Labor and Arms that have already been strengthened to a certain extent to take on mid-game battles. Choose whatever kind of Labor, weapon, and Arms you like to overpower the boss!</p><p>Extreme mode can be unlocked by defeating the boss in Newbie mode or by playing for a certain amount of time.</p><p>(Note: Demo save data cannot be carried over to the full game.)</p></blockquote><p><em>Metal Bringer</em> is due out for PlayStation 5 and PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2334170/Metal_Bringer/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> this winter.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dragon Quest III HD-2D Remake details monster arena tournaments, rescuing monsters, and more locations]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/10/dragon-quest-iii-hd-2d-remake-details-monster-arena-tournaments-rescuing-monsters-and-more-locations</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dragon-quest-iii-hd-2d-remake-details-monster-arena-tournaments-rescuing-monsters-and-more-locations.1005708/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/10/dragon-quest-iii-hd-2d-remake-details-monster-arena-tournaments-rescuing-monsters-and-more-locations<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>Get the details below.</p><div><p><strong>■ New Monster Arena Tournaments (Exclusive to this Remake)</strong></p><p>It’s time to talk about the brand-new monster arena tournaments that are exclusive to this remake. There are several monster arenas scattered across the world and each is home to its own ranked tournaments. The key to emerging victorious in these is to assemble your toughest team of up to three rescued monsters. What’s more, rescuing more than one of the same species of monster will make that type of creature even mightier. Do whatever you can to gather a group of strong critters that will lead you to victory and, most importantly, plenty of prizes!</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/Dragon-Quest-III-HD-2D-Remake_2024_10-09-24_001.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/Dragon-Quest-III-HD-2D-Remake_2024_10-09-24_002.jpg"></a></figure><!-- AD: content -->
        <figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/Dragon-Quest-III-HD-2D-Remake_2024_10-09-24_003.jpg"></a></figure><p><strong>1. Keep an eye out for mighty monsters on your travels!</strong></p><p>If you find your team too weak to conquer any given tournament, resume your <a title="Genres > Adventure [1,808 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a>. There’s every chance you’ll happen upon a monster that’s stronger than any you’ve rescued so far.</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/Dragon-Quest-III-HD-2D-Remake_2024_10-09-24_004.jpg"></a></figure><p><strong>2. Make a team that can survive multiple battles in a row!</strong></p><p>Each tournament is comprised of a series of three to four bouts and your team cannot heal between matches. Be sure to include at least one monster on your team that can recover HP during battles.</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/Dragon-Quest-III-HD-2D-Remake_2024_10-09-24_005.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/Dragon-Quest-III-HD-2D-Remake_2024_10-09-24_006.jpg"></a></figure><p><strong>3. Change your tactics if a match isn’t going your way!</strong></p><p>You can set how your monsters behave by selecting “Tactics” in the battle menu. Tactical tinkering can be the key to coming out on top!</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/Dragon-Quest-III-HD-2D-Remake_2024_10-09-24_007.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/Dragon-Quest-III-HD-2D-Remake_2024_10-09-24_008.jpg"></a></figure><p><strong>Get Multiple Monsters of the Same Species to Make Them Mightier</strong></p><p>Rescuing more than one of the same species of monster will benefit your critters. For starters, the first monster you rescued from that species will level up! That monster’s species strength will also increase. Not only does this boost your monsters’ attributes, it can also allow them to learn new spells and abilities, making it easier to triumph in tournaments.</p><p><em>—The first monster rescued in this species group gets a nice boost to their stats!</em></p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/Dragon-Quest-III-HD-2D-Remake_2024_10-09-24_009.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/Dragon-Quest-III-HD-2D-Remake_2024_10-09-24_010.jpg"></a></figure><p><em>—The more stars, the higher their species strength. You can also check what spells and abilities monsters know.</em></p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/Dragon-Quest-III-HD-2D-Remake_2024_10-09-24_011.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/Dragon-Quest-III-HD-2D-Remake_2024_10-09-24_012.jpg"></a></figure><p><strong>■ Rescuing Monsters</strong></p><p>Keep your eyes peeled for any friendly monsters in need of a helping hand while out and about. Every monster is different and you’ll need to use some special tricks to rescue some of them. <a title="Genres > Party [77 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/party">Party</a> members with the new monster wrangler vocation know a thing or two about these creatures and will come in handy when rescuing them.</p><p><em>—Interact with any friendly monsters you spot in towns, dungeons, and secret spots. You might be able to rescue to them.</em></p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/Dragon-Quest-III-HD-2D-Remake_2024_10-09-24_013.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/Dragon-Quest-III-HD-2D-Remake_2024_10-09-24_014.jpg"></a></figure><p><em>—Some critters will flee when exposed to certain sounds, smells, or people. In these cases, try using an ability that lets you approach quietly, or an item that can turn you invisible, or mask your scent.</em></p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/Dragon-Quest-III-HD-2D-Remake_2024_10-09-24_015.jpg"></a></figure><p><em>—Once you’ve rescued enough monsters, Monty the Monster Monitor will reward you!</em></p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/Dragon-Quest-III-HD-2D-Remake_2024_10-09-24_016.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/Dragon-Quest-III-HD-2D-Remake_2024_10-09-24_017.jpg"></a></figure><p><strong>Monster Wranglers to the Rescue!</strong></p><p>Having a monster wrangler in your party will stop friendly monsters from fleeing when you approach. They also possess the Animal Instinct ability which allows them to sense how many cordial critters are nearby. Monster wranglers also learn more abilities in line with the number of monsters you’ve saved.</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/Dragon-Quest-III-HD-2D-Remake_2024_10-09-24_020.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/Dragon-Quest-III-HD-2D-Remake_2024_10-09-24_021.jpg"></a></figure><p><em>—Monster wranglers will learn Monster Pile-On once you rescue enough friendly creatures. Save even more monsters to make it deal more damage!</em></p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/Dragon-Quest-III-HD-2D-Remake_2024_10-09-24_022.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/Dragon-Quest-III-HD-2D-Remake_2024_10-09-24_023.jpg"></a></figure><p><strong>■ More Areas Remade in HD-2D</strong></p><p><em>Dragon Quest III HD-2D Remake</em> is home to all sorts of civilizations and cultures. We’re going to touch on two of them here!</p><p><strong>Romaria</strong></p><p>A nation home to a magnificent castle, stunning statues, and a town square centered around a fountain. Its king is rumored to be quite the character and seems to have strong ties with Aliahan. Those after some fun should head into the bowels of the castle town to Romaria’s monster arena.</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/Dragon-Quest-III-HD-2D-Remake_2024_10-09-24_024.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/Dragon-Quest-III-HD-2D-Remake_2024_10-09-24_025.jpg"></a></figure><p><em>—Visiting the monster arena is a beloved Romarian pastime; guests from far afield are more than welcome to join in too!</em></p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/Dragon-Quest-III-HD-2D-Remake_2024_10-09-24_026.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/Dragon-Quest-III-HD-2D-Remake_2024_10-09-24_027.jpg"></a></figure><p><strong>Mur</strong></p><p>A rural village that’s no stranger to snow. Don’t be surprised if you spot an icicle or two hanging from most of the roofs. Mur’s inhabitants are a lively bunch, and it boasts its own market and wharf.</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/Dragon-Quest-III-HD-2D-Remake_2024_10-09-24_028.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/Dragon-Quest-III-HD-2D-Remake_2024_10-09-24_029.jpg"></a></figure><p><em>—Far off the beaten path, Mur rarely has the chance to welcome visitors.</em></p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/Dragon-Quest-III-HD-2D-Remake_2024_10-09-24_030.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/Dragon-Quest-III-HD-2D-Remake_2024_10-09-24_031.jpg"></a></figure></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sports Gamers Deserve Better]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/ea-fc-madden-nba-2k-recycled-dogshit</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sports-gamers-deserve-better.1005678/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://aftermath.site/ea-fc-madden-nba-2k-recycled-dogshit<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>I found myself playing a ton of sports games last month--it's the time of year most of them come out--and it has absolutely done me in.</p><p>I played some <em>Madden 25</em>, <em>NBA 2K25</em>, <em>EA Sports FC 25</em> and <em>eFootball</em>. All of these have things in common, shared horrors that overlap, season passes and packets of cards and menu screens that implore you to spend real money on both, like some venn diagram for the damned. But the predatory economics of these games are well-known, and quite frankly, I'm tired of talking about them.</p><p>What really struck me this year, playing through all four games together and so close to each other, is that I have fond memories of all four. <em>Madden 2002</em>, for example, was <em>incredible</em>, and gave me one of the most profound sports game experiences I have ever had, when I created myself as a QB in career mode, dropped back in the pocket for my first pass and heard the commentator actually say "Plunkett". I knew logically that he was just pulling the name from the disc because Jim Plunkett was included in the game as a classic QB, but still. In the early 2000s this felt like <em>witchcraft</em>, and was a big reason I spent hundreds of hours playing the game.</p><p>The <em>NBA 2K </em>series definitely hit a peak in the late 2010s. Not only did it play like a truly modern basketball game, it had genuine singleplayer aspirations, including a lavish (if also regularly embarrassing) storyline,<a href="https://aftermath.site/aston-villa-fifa-pes-pro-evo-efootball-avfc-ecl-champions-league" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> which as a guy who predominantly played offline</a> was really appreciated. <em>FIFA</em> and <em>PES</em> (as <em>eFootball</em> was previously known), meanwhile, have been with me for decades. <em>PES </em>was THE game for anyone into football in the 2000s, and <em>FIFA</em> had it bookended in the 90s and 2010s with its commitment to accessibility, flash and bombast.</p><p>In 2024, those memories of old games aren't as distant as I would have hoped.</p><div><figure><p><iframe title="FIFA 18 (PC) - Gameplay" width="710" height="399" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ygkU4TW5e_E?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><figcaption>Take a look at FIFA 18 here, first released in 2017....</figcaption></figure></div><p>Not much has changed across all four games, despite all the years gone by. All four games were stale. Like I was playing something that looked new on the surface, but which was based on a set of underlying systems and <em>feel </em>that are years, and in some cases <em>decades </em>old. Sure, the intervening years have added flashier crowd visuals and better TV-like presentation, extra frames of animation and some bouncier collisions, but <em>Madden's </em>on-field experience--the weight of the game, the way runners bounce off blockers, the interactions between a receiver, a defensive back and a flying ball--aren't that different from 2002.</p><p>It's the same with <em>NBA 2K25</em>. The publisher can claim a "next-gen" version has been available for a few years now, but while I appreciate that some rough edges have been sanded off and the lighting looks lovely, my 2024 hoops experience is alarmingly similar to my 2014 experience. <em>EA Sports FC 25's</em> big-shouldered player models, slippery movement and sluggish ball physics can be traced back to the 2010s. <em>eFootball</em>, on life support since Konami practically gave up competing with EA a few years back, plays like I'm opening a time capsule buried in 2018.</p><div><figure><p><iframe title="EA FC 25 | 4K Max Graphics | RTX 4090" width="710" height="399" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/XyZGOouLxAs?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><figcaption>Now look at EA Sports FC 25, released in 2024. It's nicer, sure, but is it <em>seven years</em> nicer?</figcaption></figure></div><p>For the longest time "gamers" who didn't play (or didn't understand the appeal of) sports games have mocked the genre, saying "you're just paying for the same game with new rosters". And for the longest time, that simply wasn't true! If you played <em>FIFA 98</em>, <em>FIFA 2004</em> then <em>FIFA 2009</em> you would have been playing three vastly different games. The jump between <em>Madden 96</em> and <em>Madden 03</em> was immense. As consoles leapt from the 32 to 64-bit era and beyond, every few years and every new generation would bring what at the time felt like a revolutionary new way to play your favourite sports games.</p><p>Now, though,<a href="https://aftermath.site/ps5-pro-price" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> we live in the age of diminishing returns</a>, and advances have slowed to a crawl, to the point where players can see and feel similarities in games that aren't just years apart, but decades. Part of this is down to the increasing costs and complexity of development, sure, but things are not helped by exclusivity deals robbing most of these games of their primary competition. I's no coincidence that <em>FIFA </em>and <em>Madden </em>had to be at their best when <em>PES</em> and <em>NFL 2K </em>were nipping at their heels, competition that has been all but removed thanks to EA signing deals with bodies like the NFL and Premier League.</p><p>The state of things is such that I find myself, once a victim of those "it's the same game every year!" taunts, now in the weird position where I'm still getting people saying that to me while I'm also joining in. I look at all four of the games I've just played and sigh heavily, not just at their dated gameplay but the way each of them is now increasingly overrun with casino-like microtransactions.</p><p>It's all such a huge bummer. These are some of the richest games in the world, released by some of the biggest publishers, with more resources than most other studios could even dream of. There's surely the talent and the horsepower to make something truly modern, a reimagining of what it means to play a sports video game on a contemporary console or PC. Yet, in a microcosm of tech's wider malaise, all EA and 2K seem to be interested in is releasing the same thing every year and just loading it up with more and more bullshit.&nbsp;</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Dual Screen Asus Zenbook Is On Sale For Amazon's Big Deal Days Event]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-dual-screen-asus-zenbook-is-on-sale-for-amazons-big-deal-days-event/1100-6527072/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-dual-screen-asus-zenbook-is-on-sale-for-amazons-big-deal-days-event.1005657/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-dual-screen-asus-zenbook-is-on-sale-for-amazons-big-deal-days-event/1100-6527072/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-main">

      
                    
  
              <header id="masthead"><nav></nav></header>      
                            <div id="site-wrapper" role="main">
          <div id="default-content">
        
          <p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p>
  
    <article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6527072">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">We're in the final hours of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/amazon-prime-day-deals/">Amazon's Prime Big Deal Days 2024 sale</a>, but there are still some amazing deals to grab before it's over. For anyone looking for a new work laptop <em>or </em>a new tablet, the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/ASUS-Zenbook-Certified-Graphics-UX8406MA-DS76T/dp/B0CRD1QRF4?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">dual-screen 14-inch Asus Zenbook</a> is available at a 20% discount, dropping the price to $1,202 (normally $1,500).</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1701/17013431/4382244-asusdualscreenhero.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4382244" data-ratio="0.552" data-width="1000" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1701/17013431/4382244-asusdualscreenhero.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4382244"></a><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1701/17013431/4382244-asusdualscreenhero.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">This particular configuration run Windows 11 and is loaded with an Intel Core Ultra 7-155H 4.8GHz CPU with integrated Intel Arc graphics, 16GB RAM, and a 1TB SSD. Its two 14-inch OLED touchscreens feature 1080p resolution and 60Hz refresh rate. The hybrid laptop includes an integrated kickstand, detachable keyboard, and ASUS Pen 2.0.</p><hr><p dir="ltr">If you're looking for something more conventional, we have a few suggestions for other ASUS laptops on sale during Amazon's Big Deal Days event.</p><p dir="ltr">For a gaming-focused option, check out this <a href="https://www.amazon.com/ASUS-ROG-Strix-Gaming-Laptop/dp/B0CRDCXRK2?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">ASUS ROG Strix G16 laptop</a> with RTX 4060 GPU, Intel Core i7-13650HX, 16Gb RAM, and 1TB SSD. It has a 16-inch 1080p screen with super-high 165Hz refresh rate and G-Sync support fo smooth visual performance. The laptop normally costs $1,400, but is currently $1,100 during Amazon's sale.</p><p dir="ltr">Need something more affordable for work or school? Check out the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/ASUS-Convertible-Touchscreen-Transparent-CX1400FKA-AS88F/dp/B0CRD2YLLC?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">14-inch Asus Chromebook Flip</a> that's on sale for $270 (down from $330). It features a 1080p touchscreen, Intel Celeron N6000 4-Core CPU, 8GB RAM, and 128GB flash storage.</p><p dir="ltr">That's just a few of the ASUS laptop and PC deals available at Amazon today. Check the links below for even more deals, but grab them fast--Amazon Prime Big Deal Days ends at 11:59 PM on October 10.</p><h2 dir="ltr">Amazon Prime Big Deal Days Asus Discounts</h2><p dir="ltr"><strong>Laptops and pre-built desktops</strong></p><ul><li dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/ASUS-ROG-Strix-Gaming-Laptop/dp/B0CRDCXRK2?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Asus ROG Strix 16-inch G16 (2024) Gaming Laptop - 165Hz Display, GeForce RTX 4060, Intel Core i7-13650HX, 16GB RAM, 1TB SSD</a> -- $1,100 (<del>$1,400</del>)</li><li dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CRDB8G1G?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">AsusTUF Gaming A15 (2024) Gaming Laptop - 144Hz Display, GeForce RTX 3050, AMD Ryzen 5 7535HS CPU, 8GB RAM, 512GB SSD</a> -- $780</li><li dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CRLF5CL5?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Asus ROG G16CH (2024) Gaming Desktop - Intel Core i7-14700F, GeForce RTX 4060Ti Dual, 32GB RAM, 1TB SSD</a> -- $1,200 (<del>$1,500</del>)</li><li dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/ASUS-Zenbook-Certified-Graphics-UX8406MA-DS76T/dp/B0CRD1QRF4?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Asus 14-inch Zenbook Duo Laptop - Intel Core Ultra 7 CPU, Intel Arc Graphics, 16GB RAM, 1TB SSD</a> -- $1,202 (<del>$1,500</del>)</li><li dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/ASUS-Convertible-Touchscreen-Transparent-CX1400FKA-AS88F/dp/B0CRD2YLLC?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Asus 14-inch Chromebook Flip CX1 Convertible Laptop</a> -- $270 (<del>$330</del>)</li></ul><p dir="ltr"><strong>Displays</strong></p><ul><li dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/ASUS-VG34VQL1B-DisplayPort-Adjustable-DisplayHDR/dp/B08LCMYT54?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Asus TUF 34-Inch Curved Gaming Monitor</a> -- $270 (<del>$370</del>)</li><li dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/ASUS-ZenScreen-MB16AC-Portable-Monitor/dp/B071S84ZW7?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Asus ZenScreen 15.6-inch 1080P Portable USB Monitor</a> -- $110</li></ul><p dir="ltr"><strong>Accerssories</strong></p><ul><li dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/ASUS-ROG-connectivity-remappable-Sensitivity/dp/B0CJN1LXT8?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Asus ROG Raikiri Pro Controller </a>-- $105 (<del>$150</del>)</li><li dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/ASUS-ROG-Headphones-Low-Latency-Cancelation/dp/B0BRSCKG2D?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Asus ROG Cetra True Wireless Gaming Headphones</a> -- $65 (<del>$100</del>)</li><li dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/ASUS-GT6-Tri-Band-Triple-Level-Acceleration/dp/B0BQ41N3XP?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Asus ROG Rapture GT6 AX10000 Tri-Band WiFi 6 Gaming Mesh System (2-pack)</a> -- $380 (<del>$480</del>)</li></ul><div data-embed-type="pinbox" data-ref-id="4304">  <ul>                              <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-hobbit-tolkien-illustrated-edition-is-free-at-amazon-when-you-buy-lotr-and-silmarillion/1100-6527038/">The Hobbit Tolkien Illustrated Edition Is Free At Amazon When You Buy LOTR And Silmarillion</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/get-3-months-of-xbox-game-pass-ultimate-for-50-off-today-only-october-9/1100-6526404/">Get 3 Months Of Xbox Game Pass Ultimate For 50% Off Today Only (October 9)</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/these-amd-and-intel-cpus-are-super-cheap-for-prime-big-deal-days/1100-6527035/">These AMD And Intel CPUs Are Super Cheap For Prime Big Deal Days</a></li>                          <li>         <span>+ Show More More Gaming, Tech, and Entertainment Deals &amp; Preorders Links (3)</span>       </li>          <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/popular-mini-pcs-are-on-sale-for-prime-big-deal-days/1100-6527039/">Popular Mini PCs Are On Sale For Prime Big Deal Days</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/star-trek-complete-original-series-steelbook-blu-ray-is-just-39-in-prime-big-deal-days-special/1100-6527029/">Star Trek: Complete Original Series Steelbook Blu-Ray Is Just $39 In Prime Big Deal Days Special</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ted-lasso-blu-ray-box-set-gets-significant-price-cut-for-prime-big-deal-days/1100-6523264/">Ted Lasso Blu-Ray Box Set Gets Significant Price Cut For Prime Big Deal Days</a></li>   </ul> </div>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/104300651635509044736?rel=author">Brendan Hesse</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article>

    
  

</div>
                      <meta itemprop="seamless-content-list-items" data-list-items="[{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6527039&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/popular-mini-pcs-are-on-sale-for-prime-big-deal-days\/1100-6527039\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526902&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/civilization-7-pc-specs-have-been-revealed\/1100-6526902\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526930&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/marvels-spider-man-2-on-sale-for-big-discount-for-prime-big-deal-days\/1100-6526930\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526927&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/amazon-prime-big-deal-days-buy-two-get-one-free-blu-ray-box-sets\/1100-6526927\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6527060&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/bluey-books-games-and-more-on-sale-for-prime-big-deal-days\/1100-6527060\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526917&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/ps5-console-exclusive-game-deals-amazon-prime-big-deal-days\/1100-6526917\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526922&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/the-complete-calvin-and-hobbes-is-on-sale-for-best-price-in-years-for-prime-big-deal-days\/1100-6526922\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526941&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/batman-blu-rays-and-graphic-novels-are-on-sale-and-b2g1-free-for-amazon-big-deal-days\/1100-6526941\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6527005&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/sandisk-1-5tb-microsd-gets-massive-discount-for-prime-big-deal-days\/1100-6527005\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6524903&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/backbone-one-iphone-and-android-controllers-discounted-for-big-deal-days\/1100-6524903\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526957&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/attack-on-titan-manga-and-anime-get-steep-discounts-for-amazon-prime-big-deal-days\/1100-6526957\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6527009&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/get-the-iconic-1989-batwing-in-lego-form-for-26-on-amazon-big-deal-days\/1100-6527009\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526952&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/lego-ideas-typewriter-gets-extremely-rare-discount-for-prime-big-deal-days\/1100-6526952\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6523456&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/get-castlevania-seasons-1-2-for-only-12-for-amazon-prime-big-deal-days\/1100-6523456\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6523811&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/gamecube-controller-enthusiasts-will-love-this-prime-big-deal-days-nintendo-switch-deal\/1100-6523811\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6524931&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/get-the-dark-knight-trilogy-on-4k-blu-ray-for-cheap-during-prime-big-deal-days\/1100-6524931\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526950&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/arcade1up-pac-man-galaga-countercade-up-for-preorder-alongside-big-deal-days-offers\/1100-6526950\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526964&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/the-90s-called-and-these-tamagotchi-deals-answered-for-prime-big-deal-days\/1100-6526964\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6527035&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/these-amd-and-intel-cpus-are-super-cheap-for-prime-big-deal-days\/1100-6527035\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6527037&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/get-this-like-new-playstation-portal-for-141-during-prime-big-deal-days\/1100-6527037\/&quot;}]">
            </div>
              
    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo playtesting mystery new Switch Online feature this month with up to 10K people]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-playtesting-mystery-new-switch-online-feature-this-month-with-up-to-10k-people</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-playtesting-mystery-new-switch-online-feature-this-month-with-up-to-10k-people.1005654/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-playtesting-mystery-new-switch-online-feature-this-month-with-up-to-10k-people<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>



            <p>
In a moment of enigmatic revery, Nintendo has announced it'll be playtesting a mysterious new Switch Online feature later this month, and it's inviting up to 10,000 people to get involved.
</p>
<p>
Nintendo, never one to prioritise form over function, is calling this newly announced venture the Nintendo Switch Online: Playtest Program, and the only clue it's currently willing to share is that it's explicitly "related to a new feature for the Nintendo Switch Online service."
</p>
<p>
To that end, participants must have an active Nintendo Switch Online + Expansion Pack membership, and the playtest will require them to download "exclusive software" to their Switch console in order to take part.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Eurogamer Newscast: When it costs £700, who exactly is the PS5 Pro for?" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Qb7vhF2ELZg?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Eurogamer Newscast: When it costs £700, who exactly is the PS5 Pro for?</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Qb7vhF2ELZg?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/Qb7vhF2ELZg?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Newscast: When it costs £700, who exactly is the PS5 Pro for?<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Qb7vhF2ELZg" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
To get in involved, participants must be at least 18 years of age and have a Nintendo Account registered in either Japan, the USA, the United Kingdom, France, Germany, Italy, or Spain. Sign-ups are due to open via <a href="https://playtest-p.nintendo.com/en-us">Nintendo's application form</a> on 10th October at 6pm PDT and will close on 15th October. The playtest itself runs from 23rd October to 5th November.
</p><p>
So what could it be? Something related to that <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-just-unveiled-an-alarm-clock-that-plays-mario-coin-noises-when-you-roll-over">clock thing</a>? The long overdue relaunch of Miiverse? An update that magically transforms your console into <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-switch-2-everything-we-know">Switch 2</a>? Pre-emptive legal action for whatever Nintendo fancies going after this week? Answers on a postcard below.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Best Buy Has the PS5 Game Deals Amazon Is Missing, and They'll Be Gone Tomorrow]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/best-buy-ps5-games-on-sale-october-prime-day-2024</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/best-buy-has-the-ps5-game-deals-amazon-is-missing-and-theyll-be-gone-tomorrow.1005639/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/best-buy-ps5-games-on-sale-october-prime-day-2024<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Final Fantasy VII Rebirth, Spider-Man 2, and more on sale.</h2></div><div><section><p>Alongside <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/amazon-prime-day-deals-october-2024">Prime Big Deal Days</a>, other retailers, like Best Buy, are offering <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-amazon-prime-day-alternative-sales-october-2024">competing discounts and sales</a>. Today only, you can save on select PlayStation 5 video games at Best Buy, with some of the biggest games of the past few years available at a discount. </p><p>This includes major 2024 titles like Final Fantasy VII Rebirth and even major PlayStation Studios games like Marvel's Spider-Man 2 and <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/god-of-war-ragnarok-review">God of War Ragnarok</a>. Since this sale is not exclusive to <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/how-much-does-amazon-prime-cost">paid members like Prime Day</a>, you do not need to be a My Best Buy member to score these deals. If you're looking for other Best Buy gaming deals, be sure to check out the <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-buy-prime-day-counter-sale-xbox-series-x-deal">discounted Xbox Series X</a>.</p><h2>Popular PlayStation 5 Games Are on Sale at Best Buy</h2><p>We've collected the best video game deals at Best Buy today above, which includes mostly first-party PlayStation Studios titles and a few third-party games. With these discounts, you can opt to either ship the item to your house or pick it up in store. It's likely that these discounts will end as the Best Buy sale wraps up tonight, so make sure to pick up these games before midnight. You can also check out our larger list of the <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-prime-day-ps5-deals-october-2024">best PlayStation deals</a> happening for October Prime Day.</p><h2>Should You Buy Now or Wait for Black Friday?</h2><p>While these are solid deals, we do recommend that you wait for Black Friday for better prices if you can. Generally, Black Friday and Cyber Monday offer much better deals for video games than Prime Day, so you can expect to see the best discounts for the year there. Titles like <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/final-fantasy-7-rebirth-review">Final Fantasy VII Rebirth</a> just recently hit $49.99, but we do expect to see games like <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/marvels-spider-man-2-review">Spider-Man 2</a> and God of War Ragnarok potentially hit all-time lows during Black Friday.</p><p>Additionally, dozens of more games will be available on sale during the event, so you can purchase items in bulk. These Best Buy deals are solid discounts and well worth the price, but keep in mind that prices will likely drop come November if you can wait. Black Friday is still the <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-time-to-buy-video-games">best time to buy video games</a>.<br>
</p></section><div><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Oct 9, 2024 11:14 pm</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Our Favorite Nintendo Switch Battery Case Is at Its Lowest Price for October Prime Day]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-switch-battery-case-deals-amazon-prime-day-2024</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/our-favorite-nintendo-switch-battery-case-is-at-its-lowest-price-for-october-prime-day.1005636/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-switch-battery-case-deals-amazon-prime-day-2024<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">The perfect Switch accessory.</h2></div><div><section><p>The <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2017/03/08/nintendo-switch-review">Nintendo Switch</a> is perfect if you're traveling on the go, as you can play games outside of your home with no issues. However, if you are out in public or in a remote location, you likely do not have access to power, and you can quickly run out of battery when playing games in handheld mode. While the Nintendo Switch has a limited battery capacity, you can extend this with a battery case. This is where the Newdery External Battery Station comes in. </p><p>For a limited time during <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/amazon-prime-day-deals-october-2024">Prime Big Deal Days</a>, you can save 20% off the Newdery External Battery Station. This deal is exclusive to Prime members, but you can sign up for a <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/how-much-does-amazon-prime-cost">free trial</a> if you do not currently have an <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/how-much-does-amazon-prime-cost">Amazon Prime membership</a>. This deal is set to end at midnight tonight as the sale comes to an end.</p><h2>The Newdery External Battery Station Is On Sale for Prime Day</h2><div catalogid="cb2b8bd1-c80a-4e97-bb54-01114005a15f" id="208816"><div id="208816" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p><h3>NEWDERRY External Battery Station for Nintendo Switch</h3></p></div><p>The Newdery External Battery Station is currently IGN's pick for the overall <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-nintendo-switch-battery-case">best battery case for Nintendo Switch</a>. This case provides a 10,000mAh battery in addition to the Switch's built-in battery, allowing for up to eight hours of additional playtime in handheld mode. This extra battery can make a huge difference, as you can play some games for up to 14 hours. </p><p>Beyond battery life, the Newdery External Battery Station is comfortable to hold. The grip behind the Joy-Con is extended, allowing all players to be comfortable during long play sessions. While some might find the Nintendo Switch uncomfortable, the Newdery External Battery Station alleviates that.</p><p>Additionally, the case features a built-in kickstand, which reveals a compartment to store extra game cartridges on the go. If you're someone who buys most of your games physically, this can allow you to bring up to three physical titles with you on the go without the need for a storage case. This is a great alternative to purchasing a <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-portable-charger">power bank</a> <em>and</em> a <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-nintendo-switch-case">Switch carrying case</a>.</p><h2>Is this Case Worth Buying at This Price?</h2><p>Overall, we absolutely recommend picking up the Newdery External Battery Station while it is 20% off. This is the <a href="https://camelcamelcamel.com/product/B07T7111QW" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">lowest we've ever seen</a> the accessory on Amazon, and we do not expect to see any further discounts for <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/black-friday-2024">Black Friday</a> or Cyber Monday. While both <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/prime-day-vs-black-friday-deals">Prime Day and Black Friday offer similar sales</a>, the October Prime Day often serves as a tease of Black Friday's offerings. You should plan to see a similar 20% discount during the major sales event next month.</p><h3>More Nintendo Switch Deals Today</h3></div></section><div><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Oct 9, 2024 10:01 pm</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Launching Mysterious Switch Online Test Soon, Here's How To Sign Up]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-launching-mysterious-switch-online-test-soon-heres-how-to-sign-up/1100-6527070/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-launching-mysterious-switch-online-test-soon-heres-how-to-sign-up.1005633/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-launching-mysterious-switch-online-test-soon-heres-how-to-sign-up/1100-6527070/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-main">

      
                    
  
              <header id="masthead"><nav></nav></header>      
                            <div id="site-wrapper" role="main">
          <div id="default-content">
        
          <p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p>
  
    <article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6527070">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Nintendo has announced that it will be performing a Nintendo Switch Online playtest for a new feature coming to the service. Sign-ups to participate in the test will begin on October 10 and run until October 15.</p><p>The playtest period will last between October 23 and November 5 and those who have an active Nintendo Switch Online + Expansion Pack membership are eligible to sign up. Applicants must also be at least 18 years of age, and have their Nintendo accounts registered in Japan, United States, United Kingdom, France, Germany, Italy, or Spain.</p><p>To sign up, those who are interested need to apply using the "<a href="https://playtest-p.nintendo.com/en-us" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">To Application Page</a>" link on the playtest page. Those from Japan will be chosen through a raffle if there are too many applicants from that region, and the ones outside of Japan will be chosen on a first-come-first-serve basis. Nintendo said that the playtest is expected to accept as many as 10,000 participants.</p><p>It's currently unknown what kind of new feature Nintendo is testing out here. Fans have begun <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/nintendo/comments/1g03fr3/nintendo_announces_nintendo_switch_online/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">speculating</a> possibilities, such as online battling and trading for older Pokemon games, early access, and an achievement system.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/115776530127739146123?rel=author">George Yang</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article>

    
  

</div>
                      <meta itemprop="seamless-content-list-items" data-list-items="[{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526887&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/new-paddington-in-peru-trailer-sends-a-little-bear-on-a-big-adventure\/1100-6526887\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526896&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/black-ops-6-will-be-available-to-stream-day-one-heres-where-and-how-much-it-costs\/1100-6526896\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526874&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/silent-hill-2-remake-bug-room-door-code-in-toluca-prison\/1100-6526874\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526907&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/space-marine-2-dev-says-game-can-succeed-without-selling-absurd-number-of-units\/1100-6526907\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526904&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/11-years-later-gta-online-adds-a-fan-requested-location-for-new-zombie-mode\/1100-6526904\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526905&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/diablo-4-is-first-microsoft-game-to-have-ps5-pro-enhancement-confirmed\/1100-6526905\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526902&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/civilization-7-pc-specs-have-been-revealed\/1100-6526902\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526908&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/get-a-disney-lorcana-booster-box-for-80-today-only\/1100-6526908\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526913&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/joker-folie-a-deux-4k-steelbook-edition-is-cheaper-than-other-recent-releases\/1100-6526913\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526910&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/joker-folie-a-deuxs-shocking-ending-explained\/1100-6526910\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526912&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/the-last-of-us-on-ps5-pro-looks-even-more-impressive-in-action\/1100-6526912\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526903&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/sony-inzone-m9-deal-get-a-gaming-monitor-that-matches-your-ps5-before-its-gone-for-good\/1100-6526903\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526916&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/a-horror-game-showcase-is-coming-this-month-with-dozens-of-spooky-trailers\/1100-6526916\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526915&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/dragon-age-the-veilguard-has-gone-gold\/1100-6526915\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526911&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/nintendo-museum-puts-limits-on-gift-store-merch-to-discourage-scalpers\/1100-6526911\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526906&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/metal-gears-david-hayter-seemingly-teasing-new-performance-as-snake\/1100-6526906\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526893&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/new-sims-4-life-death-expansion-lets-you-reap-souls-plan-funerals-and-unmask-the-grim-reaper\/1100-6526893\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526899&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/how-long-is-starfield-shattered-space-full-quest-list\/1100-6526899\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526897&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/get-saw-for-free-right-now-with-game-pass-ultimate\/1100-6526897\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526898&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/disney-removes-four-indiana-jones-movies-leaving-just-one-left\/1100-6526898\/&quot;}]">
            </div>
              
    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Everywhere You Can Preorder The PS5 Slim Anniversary Edition Starting October 10]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/everywhere-you-can-preorder-the-ps5-slim-anniversary-edition-starting-october-10/1100-6527071/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/everywhere-you-can-preorder-the-ps5-slim-anniversary-edition-starting-october-10.1005618/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/everywhere-you-can-preorder-the-ps5-slim-anniversary-edition-starting-october-10/1100-6527071/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-main">

      
                    
  
              <header id="masthead"><nav></nav></header>      
                            <div id="site-wrapper" role="main">
          <div id="default-content">
        
          <p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p>
  
    <article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6527071">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">The upcoming PS5 Slim Digital is getting an awesome-looking Anniversary Edition that features PS1-inspired faceplates and DualSense controller. The $500 console will launch on November 21, but <strong>preorders go live at online retailers starting October 10 at 7 AM PT / 10 AM ET</strong>. We expect the PS5 Slim Digital Anniversary Edition to sell out fast online, so be sure to bookmark the links below so you can be ready to grab the console once preorders are live.</p><div title="6527071 - PS5 Slim anniversary edition preorders" data-embed-type="buylink" data-ref-id="2731" data-template="4" data-size="buylink__listicle" data-title="6527071 - PS5 Slim anniversary edition preorders" data-collection="">             <h2>                    <a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1804712/565706/9383?veh=aff&amp;sourceid=imp_000011112222333344&amp;u=https://www.walmart.com/ip/seort/12283761453&amp;subId1=subid_value" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/goto.walmart.com\/c\/1804712\/565706\/9383?veh=aff&amp;sourceid=imp_000011112222333344&amp;u=https:\/\/www.walmart.com\/ip\/seort\/12283761453&amp;subId1=subid_value&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1804712/565706/9383?veh=aff&amp;sourceid=imp_000011112222333344&amp;u=https://www.walmart.com/ip/seort/12283761453&amp;subId1=subid_value">PS5 Slim Digital Anniversary Edition</a>       </h2>                                   <h3>                      <a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1804712/565706/9383?veh=aff&amp;sourceid=imp_000011112222333344&amp;u=https://www.walmart.com/ip/seort/12283761453&amp;subId1=subid_value" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/goto.walmart.com\/c\/1804712\/565706\/9383?veh=aff&amp;sourceid=imp_000011112222333344&amp;u=https:\/\/www.walmart.com\/ip\/seort\/12283761453&amp;subId1=subid_value&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://goto.walmart.com/c/1804712/565706/9383?veh=aff&amp;sourceid=imp_000011112222333344&amp;u=https://www.walmart.com/ip/seort/12283761453&amp;subId1=subid_value">$500</a>         </h3>                                                                                                                      <p>The PS5 Slim Digital Anniversary Edition will be available to preorder at <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fgoto.walmart.com%2Fc%2F1804712%2F565706%2F9383%3Fveh%3Daff%26sourceid%3Dimp_000011112222333344%26u%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2Fseort%2F12283761453%26subId1%3Dsubid_value&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Feverywhere-you-can-preorder-the-ps5-slim-anniversary-edition-starting-october-10%2F1100-6527071%2F%3Fftag%3DCAD-01-10abi2f&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Walmart</a>, <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fshop-links.co%2F1855979596402021566%3Fu1%3Dsubid_value&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Feverywhere-you-can-preorder-the-ps5-slim-anniversary-edition-starting-october-10%2F1100-6527071%2F%3Fftag%3DCAD-01-10abi2f&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Best Buy</a>, and Target. Note that Walmart preorders are exclusive to paid <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fgoto.walmart.com%2Fc%2F1804712%2F565706%2F9383%3Fveh%3Daff%26sourceid%3Dimp_000011112222333344%26u%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fplus%26subId1%3Dsubid_value&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Feverywhere-you-can-preorder-the-ps5-slim-anniversary-edition-starting-october-10%2F1100-6527071%2F%3Fftag%3DCAD-01-10abi2f&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Walmart+ members</a> ($13/month or $98/year). While that may be an extra hurdle to jump through for Walmart shoppers, the upshot is you hopefully won't have to contend with as many people--nor as many bots and scalpers--trying to order the console at the same time. Online preorders at Best Buy and Target are open to all customers.</p>                      </div><p dir="ltr">The PS5 Slim Digital Anniversary Edition costs $100 more than the baseline PS5 Slim Digital, and is identical to it in terms of hardware and features, but comes with exclusive faceplates and a DualSense controller with gray color schemes inspired by the original PlayStation console. Like the regular PS5 Slim Digital, the Anniversary Edition does not include a disc drive, so it can only play digitally-downloaded PS5 games out of the box. You can purchase the optional <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fgoto.walmart.com%2Fc%2F1804712%2F565706%2F9383%3Fveh%3Daff%26sourceid%3Dimp_000011112222333344%26u%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FPlayStation-5-Disc-Drive-For-PS5-Digital-Slim-Console%2F5113175921%26subId1%3Dsubid_value&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Feverywhere-you-can-preorder-the-ps5-slim-anniversary-edition-starting-october-10%2F1100-6527071%2F%3Fftag%3DCAD-01-10abi2f&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">PS5 Disc Drive accessory</a> if you want to play physical games on the system, and it comes with an extra PS1-themed faceplate that will fit around the drive once attached. The PS5 disc drive normally costs $80--however, due to the upcoming PS5 Slim Digital Anniversary Collection and disc-drive-less PS5 Pro, the PS5 Disc Drive is hard to come by right now. That said, it's worth checking out the links below to see if it's in stock.</p><hr><p dir="ltr">PS5 Pro and PS5 Chroma preorders</p><p dir="ltr">As mentioned above, the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DGY63Z2H?tag=gamespot-preorders-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">PS5 Pro</a> is also launching in a few weeks on November 7. Early preorders have been <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ps5-pro-hasnt-sold-out-right-away-like-some-expected/1100-6526790/" data-ref-id="1100-6526790">available exclusively through the PlayStation Store</a>, but go live at major retailers starting October 10. Check our <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ps5-pro-preorder-guide-price-release-date-amazon-best-buy-walmart/1100-6526406/" data-ref-id="1100-6526406">PS5 Pro preorder guide</a> for everywhere you can order the new, more powerful version of Sony's latest console.</p><hr><p dir="ltr">Alongside the new PS5 consoles, Sony is also launching a new Chroma line of console faceplates and DualSense controllers featuring unique iridescent color schemes.</p><hr><div data-embed-type="pinbox" data-ref-id="4304">  <ul>                              <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-hobbit-tolkien-illustrated-edition-is-free-at-amazon-when-you-buy-lotr-and-silmarillion/1100-6527038/">The Hobbit Tolkien Illustrated Edition Is Free At Amazon When You Buy LOTR And Silmarillion</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/get-3-months-of-xbox-game-pass-ultimate-for-50-off-today-only-october-9/1100-6526404/">Get 3 Months Of Xbox Game Pass Ultimate For 50% Off Today Only (October 9)</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/these-amd-and-intel-cpus-are-super-cheap-for-prime-big-deal-days/1100-6527035/">These AMD And Intel CPUs Are Super Cheap For Prime Big Deal Days</a></li>                          <li>         <span>+ Show More More Gaming, Tech, and Entertainment Deals &amp; Preorders Links (3)</span>       </li>          <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/popular-mini-pcs-are-on-sale-for-prime-big-deal-days/1100-6527039/">Popular Mini PCs Are On Sale For Prime Big Deal Days</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/star-trek-complete-original-series-steelbook-blu-ray-is-just-39-in-prime-big-deal-days-special/1100-6527029/">Star Trek: Complete Original Series Steelbook Blu-Ray Is Just $39 In Prime Big Deal Days Special</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ted-lasso-blu-ray-box-set-gets-significant-price-cut-for-prime-big-deal-days/1100-6523264/">Ted Lasso Blu-Ray Box Set Gets Significant Price Cut For Prime Big Deal Days</a></li>   </ul> </div>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/104300651635509044736?rel=author">Brendan Hesse</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article>

    
  

</div>
                      <meta itemprop="seamless-content-list-items" data-list-items="[{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526989&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/arthur-fleck-was-never-the-real-joker-director-todd-phillips-confirms\/1100-6526989\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526991&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/switch-firmware-update-out-now-described-by-expert-as-major\/1100-6526991\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6523811&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/gamecube-controller-enthusiasts-will-love-this-prime-big-deal-days-nintendo-switch-deal\/1100-6523811\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525641&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/final-fantasy-pixel-remaster-anniversary-collection-now-available-for-switch-and-playstation\/1100-6525641\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526927&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/amazon-prime-big-deal-days-buy-two-get-one-free-blu-ray-box-sets\/1100-6526927\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6527005&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/sandisk-1-5tb-microsd-gets-massive-discount-for-prime-big-deal-days\/1100-6527005\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526985&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/james-bond-blu-ray-collection-with-collectible-aston-martin-is-50-off\/1100-6526985\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6527024&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/8bitdo-retro-keyboard-with-arcade-stick-drops-to-lowest-price-ever-for-big-deal-days\/1100-6527024\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6517586&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/star-trek-54-disc-picard-legacy-collection-is-100-off-for-prime-big-deal-days\/1100-6517586\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6527038&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/the-hobbit-tolkien-illustrated-edition-is-free-at-amazon-when-you-buy-lotr-and-silmarillion\/1100-6527038\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6518504&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/2024-upcoming-games-release-schedule\/1100-6518504\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6523188&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/legos-new-imperial-star-destroyer-is-already-30-off-for-prime-big-deal-days\/1100-6523188\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6527039&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/popular-mini-pcs-are-on-sale-for-prime-big-deal-days\/1100-6527039\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526969&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/check-out-these-big-magic-the-gathering-booster-box-discounts-at-amazon\/1100-6526969\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6527018&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/demons-souls-is-more-than-dark-souls-weird-brother\/1100-6527018\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526944&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/magic-the-gathering-lord-of-the-rings-booster-boxes-get-rare-discounts\/1100-6526944\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526972&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/indiana-jones-4k-box-set-is-over-50-off-for-prime-big-deal-days\/1100-6526972\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526981&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/amazon-exclusive-dragon-ball-z-complete-blu-ray-box-set-is-over-30-off\/1100-6526981\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526952&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/lego-ideas-typewriter-gets-extremely-rare-discount-for-prime-big-deal-days\/1100-6526952\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6527054&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/the-popular-8bitdo-ultimate-and-8bitdo-pro-2-controllers-get-nice-discount-for-prime-big-deal-days\/1100-6527054\/&quot;}]">
            </div>
              
    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Valorant Spotlight Series EMEA 2024 Schedule and Format]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/valorant-spotlight-series-emea-2024-schedule-and-format/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/valorant-spotlight-series-emea-2024-schedule-and-format.1005603/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/valorant-spotlight-series-emea-2024-schedule-and-format/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Interested in the Valorant Spotlight Series EMEA 2024 event? This VCT offseason tournament series will give fans the Valorant action they have been craving, with some of the best competitors facing each other in an offline event. Here is the official schedule and format.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-what-is-the-valorant-spotlight-series-emea-2024-tournament">What is the Valorant Spotlight Series EMEA 2024 Tournament?</h2>



<p>This offline Valorant tournament features mix-gender competition, including VCT, Game Changers and VCL players. All teams are required to have at least two Game Changers players.</p>



<figure></figure>







<p>The series is considered a B-Tier tournament, with 14 different teams competing. The event features a decently large prize pool, with the actual prize spread remaining to be announced.</p>



<h4 id="h-tournament-prize-pool">Tournament Prize Pool:</h4>



<ul>
<li>$32,926</li>
</ul>



<p>With some of the best players in the game competing against each other, the tournament will feature a standard format.</p>



<hr>



<h3 id="h-tournament-format">Tournament Format</h3>



<p>The Valorant Spotlight Series EMEA 2024 tournament is a double-elimination bracket with an Upper Bracket and a Lower Bracket.</p>



<figure></figure>







<p>All teams competing were invited. Here is a list of every team players can expect to see participate in the tournament series:</p>



<ul>
<li>BBL Queens</li>



<li>G2 Esports</li>



<li>GIANTX</li>



<li>Karmine Corp</li>



<li>KOI</li>



<li>ALTERNATE aTTaX</li>



<li>FOKUS</li>



<li>Gamax Esports</li>



<li>NASR Esports</li>



<li>NOVO Esports</li>



<li>SK Gaming</li>



<li>Twisted Minds</li>



<li>Valiant</li>



<li>Zerance</li>
</ul>



<p>The event will be held on Europe servers with all competitors hailing from this region of the world. </p>







<hr>



<h3 id="h-tournament-schedule">Tournament Schedule</h3>



<p>The Valorant Spotlight Series EMEA 2024 tournament is set to begin on October 10 and end on October 14, 2024. The event will be viewable on the official <a href="https://www.twitch.tv/valorant_emea">Valorant EMEA Twitch</a>.</p>



<p>Be sure to tune in to on October 10 to get a piece of the action. Who do you think will win the Valorant Spotlight Series?</p>



<p>Stay tuned to Insider Gaming for more <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/category/esports/">esports news</a> and make sure to sign up for our <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/">forum</a> for additional gaming news and more.</p>



<hr>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo is taking applications to join a mysterious Switch Online playtest]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/9/24266478/nintendo-switch-online-invite-application-beta-playtest</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-is-taking-applications-to-join-a-mysterious-switch-online-playtest.1005591/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/9/24266478/nintendo-switch-online-invite-application-beta-playtest<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><article id="content"><div><div><h2>Nintendo is taking applications to join a mysterious Switch Online playtest</h2><p><span><span> / </span><h2>As many as 10,000 participants will be allowed to try something new for Switch Online — recruitment opens Thursday morning.</h2></span></p></div><div><p><span>By</span> <span><span></span> <span><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/jay-peters">Jay Peters</a></span><span>, <span>a news editor who writes about technology, video games, and virtual worlds. He’s submitted several accepted emoji proposals to the Unicode Consortium.</span></span></span></p><p><time datetime="2024-10-09T22:16:42.652Z"> <!-- -->Oct 9, 2024, 10:16 PM UTC</time></p><div><h2>Share this story</h2></div></div></div><div><div><p>Nintendo is inviting people to apply to play test a new feature for Nintendo Switch Online — though the company isn’t specifying what the feature is. </p><p>Considering that this company j<a href="https://www.theverge.com/24266272/nintendo-alarmo-sound-clock-hands-on">ust launched a gesture-controlled alarm clock</a>, this could mean just about anything up to and including a preview of features for the much-anticipated <a href="https://www.theverge.com/24051677/nintendo-switch-2-pro-rumors-news">Switch 2</a>. Guesses from <em>Verge </em>staffers ran the gamut of bringing GameCube games to Switch Online to a preview for a Wii mini retro console or perhaps another <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/9/29/16383958/star-fox-2-snes-classic-nintendo-review">long-lost <em>Star Fox </em>game</a>. Feel free to leave your best guesses in the comments.</p><p>Applications will be open from Thursday, October 10th, at 11AM ET to Tuesday, October 15th, at 10:59AM ET. You can apply by clicking the “To Application Page” link <a href="https://playtest-p.nintendo.com/en-us">on this page</a>. People from outside of Japan will be chosen “on a first-come-first-serve basis,” Nintendo says, while participants from Japan will be chosen by a raffle “if there are many Japanese applicants.”</p><p>Users can apply if they meet the <a href="https://x.com/NintendoAmerica/status/1844135979369791600">following criteria</a> as of Wednesday, October 9th, at 6PM ET, which was the exact same time this playtest <a href="https://x.com/NintendoAmerica/status/1844135977327145001">was announced</a>:</p><div><blockquote><p>Have a Nintendo Account</p><p>Be an active Nintendo Switch Online + Expansion Pack member</p><p>Be at least 18 years old</p><p>Be registered in any of the following countries: Japan, US, UK, France, Germany, Italy, Spain</p></blockquote></div><p>Nintendo says the playtest is “expected to accept as many as 10,000 participants.” The company says it will close applications early if “the number of accepted participants has reached its limit.” You’ll have to download “exclusive software” to your Switch to participate in the test.</p><p>The playtest will run from October 23rd at 9PM ET to November 5th at 7:59PM ET.</p></div><div><p>Most Popular</p><p>Most Popular</p><ol><li><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/9/24265781/tesla-robotaxi-elon-musk-claims-safety-driverless-level-5"><h2>The bill finally comes due for Elon Musk</h2></a><hr></li><li><a href="https://www.theverge.com/24265288/satellite-messages-iphone-pixel-how-to-send"><h2>How to send messages via satellite on your iPhone or Pixel</h2></a><hr></li><li><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/9/24266419/internet-archive-ddos-attack-pop-up-message"><h2>The Internet Archive is under attack, with a breach revealing info for 31 million accounts</h2></a><hr></li><li><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/9/24265984/nintendo-alarmo-alarm-clock-date-price"><h2>Nintendo is making an alarm clock so you can wake up to Zelda and Super Mario sounds</h2></a><hr></li><li><a href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/24262468/amazon-prime-day-best-deals-sales-tech-gadgets-october-2024"><h2>The best deals from Amazon’s October Prime Day sale</h2></a><hr></li></ol></div></div></article></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No, You Shouldn’t Livestream Hurricane Milton For Clout]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/adin-ross-75k-hurricane-milton-tiktok-streamers-tampa-1851669306</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/no-you-shouldn%E2%80%99t-livestream-hurricane-milton-for-clout.1005588/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/adin-ross-75k-hurricane-milton-tiktok-streamers-tampa-1851669306<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/hurricane-milton-storm-surge-simulation-unnreal-florida-1851668336?_gl=1*1xiy9vg*_ga*MjAxMTA0MDE1Ny4xNzI1Njc1NzAy*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTcyODUwNzQwNi43NC4xLjE3Mjg1MTA1MzAuNTcuMC4w&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/hurricane-milton-storm-surge-simulation-unnreal-florida-1851668336?_gl=1*1xiy9vg*_ga*MjAxMTA0MDE1Ny4xNzI1Njc1NzAy*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTcyODUwNzQwNi43NC4xLjE3Mjg1MTA1MzAuNTcuMC4w">Hurricane Milton</a></span>, one of the biggest storms in recorded history, is set to make landfall in Florida on October 9. It will likely cause tens of billions of dollars of damage and could kill or injure many people who are unable to evacuate Tampa Bay and the surrounding region in time.<br></p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="197284" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Iconic Director And Proud Nerd Kevin Smith On Sneaking Into Movies, Mallrats, And More" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="643" data-playlist="197284,197260,197209" data-current="197284"><div><p>Iconic Director And Proud Nerd Kevin Smith On Sneaking Into Movies, Mallrats, And More</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197284/197284_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197284/197284_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197284/197284_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197284/197284_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/22826.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>And yet, some influencers, TikTok content creators, and streamers are claiming that they will stick around and livestream through the historic storm. It’s a horrible idea and  yet another example of how some creators are willing to do anything just to get more views, clicks, and subscribers. </p><p>On Tuesday, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/conormurray/2024/10/09/some-influencers-arent-leaving-florida-despite-hurricane-milton-sparking-online-criticism/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/conormurray/2024/10/09/some-influencers-arent-leaving-florida-despite-hurricane-milton-sparking-online-criticism/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Forbes </em>reported</a></span> on numerous influencers who suggested in videos posted online that they would be sticking around even as Hurricane Milton makes its way closer and closer to Florida. </p><p>Influencer and writer  Caroline Calloway posted on Twitter that even though her house is located in the evacuation zone and is on the beach, she won’t be leaving. Instead, she tweeted about how she’s not leaving and included an ad for her upcoming advice book. “I have champagne and four generations of Floridians in my veins. It’ll be fine,” <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/carolinecaloway/status/1844029274304758109&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/carolinecaloway/status/1844029274304758109" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">tweeted Calloway</a></span>. </p><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.tiktok.com/@kricketfelt&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.tiktok.com/@kricketfelt" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Another TikTok creator, kricketfelt</a></span>, has been posting videos about how her home is made out of concrete and she and her husband are going to stay and not evacuate. She’s continued to upload videos, making light of the situation, as the storm gets closer. </p><p>Meanwhile, a clip of controversial Kick Streamer Adin Ross supposedly offering people $30,000 to stick around and livestream through the hurricane <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.tiktok.com/@thestreamingplug/video/7423293968361819435&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.tiktok.com/@thestreamingplug/video/7423293968361819435" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">went viral after being shared on Twitter and TikTok</a></span>. However, during the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://kick.com/adinross/videos/44f70e5c-1021-46d8-bd85-50f1dc27963b&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kick.com/adinross/videos/44f70e5c-1021-46d8-bd85-50f1dc27963b" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">full seven-hour livestream</a></span>, it’s clear Ross isn’t offering this money to anyone and in fact, was just joking around with a friend. During that same stream, he also told viewers to evacuate Tampa Bay and suggested the hurricane was being used to <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.tiktok.com/@abdenrose/video/7423283240120700190&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.tiktok.com/@abdenrose/video/7423283240120700190" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">“distract”</a></span> people from the upcoming election. So a mixed bag.</p><p><em>Kotaku </em>has reached out to Adin Ross for comment about his stream and statements. </p><p>Even though the offer wasn’t real, that didn’t stop some streamers from claiming that they were streaming live from Florida in the path of the hurricane. One Kick streamer, MikeSmallsJr, claimed to be streaming from Florida with nothing but an air mattress and some snacks. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://kick.com/mikesmallsjr/videos/e537a9a5-9df8-45ed-84bc-067651a8a049&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kick.com/mikesmallsjr/videos/e537a9a5-9df8-45ed-84bc-067651a8a049" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">During one moment of his stream</a></span>, he admitted that Ross’ offer wasn’t real and was taken out of context, but suggested the streamer still should pay him something for what he was doing. </p><p>“At the end of the day, I was the first Kick streamer to do this shit during Hurricane Helene. I’m out here busting my ass to entertain the people,” said MikeSmallsJr. Later he reportedly heard he wasn’t getting anything and wasn’t happy.&nbsp;</p><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://kick.com/jamesworley&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kick.com/jamesworley" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Another streamer, JamesWorley</a></span>, claimed to be streaming during the storm and, when asked what he would do when or if he lost cell service, said: “I guess the stream will end.” A few moments later, his stream cut off. It returned a minute later. </p><p><em>Kotaku</em> wasn’t able to verify their locations, but some did at least seem to be in Florida and were streaming during large amounts of rain. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.cnn.com/weather/live-news/hurricane-milton-florida-10-09-24#cm22c79jm00053b6rp12zapy0&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.cnn.com/weather/live-news/hurricane-milton-florida-10-09-24#cm22c79jm00053b6rp12zapy0" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The storm isn’t set to make landfall until 8 p.m. EST</a></span>, though thunderstorms and tornadoes are already covering much of the Sunshine State.</p><p>The reality is that even though Adin Ross didn’t actually offer large sums of money to encourage people to stream through the storm, the comments sadly might have inspired some people to stick around even as a deadly, incredibly powerful hurricane is about to hit where they live. </p><p>For some content creators, a massive hurricane is just an opportunity to risk their lives, troll their viewers, or create “edgy” content while possibly earning more views and subscribers. All of this in an effort to conquer the algorithm and rise above the thousands and thousands of other creators out there, all trying to desperately make money on social media and streaming platforms that, more and more, feel like  sinking ships and not the future of entertainment. </p><p> .<br></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Genshin Impact Update 5.1 Lacks English Voice-Over as Video Game Voice Acting Strike Continues]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/genshin-impact-update-english-voice-over-voice-acting-strike</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/genshin-impact-update-5-1-lacks-english-voice-over-as-video-game-voice-acting-strike-continues.1005585/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/genshin-impact-update-english-voice-over-voice-acting-strike<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>Genshin Impact's version 5.1 update lacks English voice acting in some areas due to "recording arrangements," developer HoYoverse has said.</p><p>Though the patch notes detailing the missing content don't give a more explicit reason, the lack of English voice over is like due to the ongoing American Federation of Television and Radio Artists (SAG-AFTRA) <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/what-the-sag-aftra-video-game-actors-strike-means-for-gamers">video game voice actor strike</a>.</p><p>"Due to recording arrangements, some content in version 5.1 does not have English voice overs," HoYoverse said. "We sincerely apologize for the inconvenience caused."</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>The strike began on July 26, 2024 with aims to improve the working conditions of voice actors and highlight their concerns regarding AI. It sings a similar tune to <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-hollywood-actors-strike-ends-today-as-sag-aftra-reaches-tentative-deal-with-studios">the actor and writer strikes of 2023 which essentially brought Hollywood to a standstill</a>, and the impact on video games is seemingly now being seen too.</p><p>Myriad voice actors have commented on the threat of AI, including Metal Gear Solid and Mass Effect actress Jennifer Hale. "The truth is, AI is just a tool like a hammer," she said. "If I take my hammer, I could build you a house. I can also take that same hammer and I can smash your skin and destroy who you are.”</p><p><a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/metal-gear-solid-voice-actress-jennifer-hale-says-she-was-paid-1200-for-naomi-hunter-role">Hale revealed in October 2023 she was paid just $1,200 for her role as Naomi Hunter</a> in the original Metal Gear Solid, a game which eventually grossed $176 million for publisher Konami (<a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/metal-gear-solid-master-collection-includes-original-metal-gear-1-and-2-alongside-solid-trilogy">and is still making the company money through myriad re-releases</a>).</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3>Video Game Voice Actors' Thoughts on AI</h3></div></output><p><a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-witcher-voice-actor-doug-cockle-calls-ai-inevitable-but-dangerous">The Witcher 3: Wild Hunt lead Doug Cockle similarly expressed caution and frustration</a> at the growing presence of AI within the video game industry, calling it "inevitable" but "dangerous."</p><p>Cissy Jones, a voice actor known for her roles in Disney's Owl House, Destiny 2: The Witch Queen, Shin Megami Tensei 5, and more, has <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/meet-the-company-fighting-to-make-ai-ethical-for-voice-actors">started a company called Morpheme.ai to let voice actors embrace AI and gain control of their own voices going forward</a>.</p><p><em>Ryan Dinsdale is an IGN freelance reporter. He'll talk about The Witcher all day.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch Online new feature closed playtest announced]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/10/nintendo-switch-online-new-feature-closed-playtest-announced</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-switch-online-new-feature-closed-playtest-announced.1005582/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/10/nintendo-switch-online-new-feature-closed-playtest-announced<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Applications open on October 10.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Platforms > Nintendo [20,968 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo">Nintendo</a> will host a playtest for a new feature coming to the <a title="Platforms > Switch [16,153 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Nintendo Switch</a> Online service for Switch, the company <a href="https://twittercom/NintendoAmerica/status/1844135977327145001" rel="noopener" target="_blank">announced</a>. <span id="more-920426"></span></p><p>Users can apply via <a href="https://playtest-p.nintendo.com/ja-jp" rel="noopener" target="_blank">the application website</a> from <a href="https://www.timeanddate.com/worldclock/fixedtime.html?iso=20241011T0300" rel="noopener" target="_blank">October 10 at 8:00 p.m. PT / 11:00 p.m. ET</a> until <a href="https://www.timeanddate.com/worldclock/fixedtime.html?iso=20241016T0259" rel="noopener" target="_blank">October 15 at 7:59 p.m. PT / 10:59 p.m. ET</a>. Applicants must have an active Nintendo Switch Online + Expansion Pack Membership, be at least 18 years of age, and be located in either the United States, United Kingdom, France, Italy, Germany, Spain, or Japan. Participants from outside Japan will be chosen on a first-come-first-serve basis, while participants from Japan will be chosen via raffle if the number of applicants exceeds a fixed amount.</p><p>The actual playtest will run from <a href="https://www.timeanddate.com/worldclock/fixedtime.html?iso=20241024T0100" rel="noopener" target="_blank">October 23 at 6:00 p.m. PT / 9:00 p.m. ET</a> until <a href="https://www.timeanddate.com/worldclock/fixedtime.html?iso=20241106T0059" rel="noopener" target="_blank">November 5 to 4:59 p.m. PT / 7:59 p.m. ET</a>. Users will need to download exclusive software to their Switch in order to participate.</p><p>Nintendo did not share any additional information about the new feature.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dragon Age: The Veilguard won't have an arachnophobia mode because it doesn't have a single spider]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/dragon-age-the-veilguard-wont-have-an-arachnophobia-mode-because-it-doesnt-have-a-single-spider</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dragon-age-the-veilguard-wont-have-an-arachnophobia-mode-because-it-doesnt-have-a-single-spider.1005576/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/dragon-age-the-veilguard-wont-have-an-arachnophobia-mode-because-it-doesnt-have-a-single-spider<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/dragon_age_veilguard_rookrogue.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>EA / BioWare</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
Dragon Age, a series not exactly known for being shy when it comes to chucking in a spider or two, is taking a novel approach to the increasingly common practice of implementing an arachnophobia mode for its upcoming fourth instalment: it's getting rid of all its spiders.
</p>
<p>
That's according to BioWare community manager blackhairvioleteyes (thanks <a href="https://www.thegamer.com/dragon-age-the-veilguard-no-spiders-arachnophobic/">TheGamer</a>), who shared the news on the Dragon Age subreddit after fans began <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/dragonage/comments/1fz1yyu/comment/lqz1wbr/">querying the lack of an arachnophobia mode</a> following Dragon Age: The Veilguard's <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/dragon-age-the-veilguard-has-five-difficulty-settings-and-a-further-option-to-customise-it-all">accessibility features reveal</a> earlier this week. "No mention of arachnophobia filter," noted redditor ZZssk, to which BioWare's blackhairvioleteyes replied, "No arachnophobia mode because there's no spiders!"
</p>
<p>
The immediate reaction to the news was mixed, albeit good-naturedly. Flyingfalcon01 was, for instance, overjoyed, writing, "Oh thank goodness!! My arachnophobic heart is pleased!", while others lamented the fact this almost certainly means the terrifying <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/dragonage/comments/1doi01b/im_looking_forward_to_seeing_what_these/">spiders-with-human-hands</a> seen in BioWare's early work-in-progress renders got the chop.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Dragon Age: The Veilguard - 7 Details You Need to Know" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/pEbfOR5trH4?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Dragon Age: The Veilguard - 7 Details You Need to Know</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/pEbfOR5trH4?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/pEbfOR5trH4?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Dragon Age: The Veilguard - seven things you need to know.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pEbfOR5trH4" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
Dragon Age isn't the first game to take an unusual approach to the arachnophobia problem, of course. Developer Coffee Stain opted to <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/finally-a-video-game-with-an-arachnophobia-mode">replace spiders with adorable pictures of cats</a> in its automation sim Satisfactory, while Obsidian's Grounded - a game positively bursting with the things - let players dial the spider details all the way back to 'innocuous circle'. Then there was last year's Lethal Company, which imaginatively <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/lethal-company-is-taking-a-novel-approach-with-its-new-arachnophobia-mode">replaced all its spiders with the word "spider"</a>, scuttling around the place. Dragon Age: The Veilguard is, however, probably the first game to take the scorched earth approach to solving the arachnid problem (unlike, say, <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-tips-and-tricks">Shadow of the Erdtree</a>, which <a href="https://eldenring.wiki.fextralife.com/Spider+Scorpion">stuck a scorpion on a spider</a> and made everything a million times worse).
</p><p>
So arachnophobes rest easy; you'll be able to adventure in spider-free bliss when Dragon Age: The Veilguard launches for Xbox Series X/S, PlayStation 5, and PC release on 31st October. And even better news: BioWare's series revival is <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/whisper-it-but-dragon-age-the-veilguard-has-me-thinking-the-unthinkable-it-looks-like-bioware-is-back">looking pretty good</a>.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Go Around the Bend Again With New Game Plus in Silent Hill 2]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/new-game-plus-in-silent-hill-2/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/go-around-the-bend-again-with-new-game-plus-in-silent-hill-2.1005540/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/new-game-plus-in-silent-hill-2/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>If you’re brave enough to delve into the unknown and venture through Silent Hill 2 Remake’s terrifying streets once, you can do it a second time in New Game Plus. It’s not enough to uncover some of the story and its secrets. It would help if you uncovered all of them, and it’s easier to do on a second playthrough. Here’s how the New Game Plus mechanic works!</p>



<h2 id="h-how-to-unlock-new-game-plus-in-silent-hill-2-remake">How to Unlock New Game Plus in Silent Hill 2 Remake</h2>



<p>To unlock the New Game Plus mode, you must first finish Silent Hill 2 Remake in its entirety once. It does not matter which ending you unlock or what difficulty setting you play on; so long as you beat the game all the way through the first time, the mechanic opens up for a second playthrough.</p>



<p>Once you finish the credits, navigate to the main menu. Upon selecting New Game, you can start either a standard playthrough or the newly unlocked New Game Plus.</p>



<p>Afterward, be careful which save file you load. Your New Game Plus file will be marked as such, while the regular playthrough will not have any such description by the file name.</p>







<h2 id="h-what-s-different-in-silent-hill-2-s-new-game-plus-mode">What’s Different in Silent Hill 2’s New Game Plus Mode?</h2>



<p>In most video games, New Game Plus enhances the player’s character, making them more potent than ever by retaining skills and weapons or unlocking unlimited ammunition. However, that’s not the case in Silent Hill 2. Instead, New Game Plus unlocks additional filters, items, and a couple of unique endings that are only available in this mode.</p>



<p>You’ll receive a total of 10 filters, eight endings, and a single new weapon. The Chainsaw is overpowered and fun to use, but it’s somewhat game-breaking. </p>



<p>Unfortunately, nothing whatsoever transfers over, so don’t expect to keep your current weapons and ammunition. You’ll start fresh!</p>



<p>Is New Game Plus worthwhile in Silent Hill 2? Let us know in the comments below, or start a discussion on the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forums</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>Did you hear <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/silent-hill-2-remake-is-exclusive-to-ps5-for-a-year/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Silent Hill 2 Remake is exclusive to PlayStation 5</a> for the next year? That’s a long time for Xbox Series X|S fans to wait!</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon Slashes up to 37% Off Logitech's Most Affordable Racing Wheels for Prime Day]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/logitech-racing-wheel-for-ps5-xbox-prime-day-deal-2024</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/amazon-slashes-up-to-37-off-logitechs-most-affordable-racing-wheels-for-prime-day.1005537/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/logitech-racing-wheel-for-ps5-xbox-prime-day-deal-2024<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Immersive racing from your PS5, Xbox, or PC without ever leaving the house.</h2></div><div><section><p>For October Prime Day, Amazon has dropped the prices on all three of its mainstream Logitech racing wheels: the <a href="https://zdcs.link/92bepM?object_uuid=5a094290-9a3d-4de0-a666-e824dffd9e28&amp;t=article" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Logitech G29</a> for PlayStation 5 and PC and the <a href="https://zdcs.link/9wGe0y?object_uuid=5a094290-9a3d-4de0-a666-e824dffd9e28&amp;t=article" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Logitech 920</a> for Xbox Series X and PC includes the racing wheel and pedals. The newer <a href="https://zdcs.link/QVD7P3?object_uuid=5a094290-9a3d-4de0-a666-e824dffd9e28&amp;t=article" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Logitech G923</a>, which is compatible with both Xbox and PS5, also includes a shifter.</p><h2>37% Off Logitech G29 and G920 Driving Force Racing Wheels</h2><div id="165363" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger" catalogid="6cb98a80-665b-49b5-95ee-db8f1bb621e3"><p><h3>Logitech G29 Driving Force Racing Wheel for PS5</h3></p></div><div catalogid="6cb98a80-665b-49b5-95ee-db8f1bb621e3" id="208785"><div id="208785" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p><h3>Logitech G920 Driving Force Racing Wheel</h3></p></div><p>The Logitech G29 and Logitech G920 were already some of the <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-best-racing-wheels">best racing wheels</a> under $300. If you're a big fan of racing games like <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/franchise/gran-turismo">Gran Turismo 7</a> or <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/forza-horizon-5">Forza Horizon 5</a> and you've been using your standard PS5 or Xbox controller this entire time, then this sale might be the excuse you experience greater immersion in racing games for the first time.</p><p> Standout features include a gorgeous hand-stitched leather racing wheel with 900 degrees of rotation, sturdy metal base, durable steel ball bearings in the shaft, gear-driven dual-force motor feedback, stainless shifter and pressure sensitive pedals. The force feedback does an excellent job of simulating providing force and resistance and certain adds to the immersion; if you want something better than this, you'd have to shell out a lot more money for a direct-drive or belt-driven wheel, like Logitech's own <a href="https://zdcs.link/9wGVbD?object_uuid=5a094290-9a3d-4de0-a666-e824dffd9e28&amp;t=article" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">$1,000 G Pro</a> direct-drive <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/logitech-g-pro-racing-wheel-review">racing wheel we reviewed</a>.</p><p>The G29 is a bit nicer than the Xbox's G920 variant. The G29 has LED shift lights located on the top of the wheel's spokes. These LEDs light up progressively as the car's RPMs rise in-game. The G29 also has a rotary knob on the wheel that can be customized to different functions, like traction control, brake bias, or split differential.</p><h2>20% Off Logitech G923 TRUEFORCE Racing Wheel</h2></div><div id="208786" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger" catalogid="2c6b7e67-5eaa-4e3d-8abc-05a8d4e1810e"><p><h3>Logitech G923 TRUEFORCE Racing Wheel, Pedals, and G Driving Force Shifter</h3></p></div><div catalogid="2c6b7e67-5eaa-4e3d-8abc-05a8d4e1810e" id="208787"><div id="208787" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p><h3>Logitech G923 TRUEFORCE Racing Wheel, Pedals, and G Driving Force Shifter</h3></p></div><p>The Logitech G923 (one of the best accessible racing wheels for both the <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-racing-wheels-for-xbox-series-xs">Xbox</a> and <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-racing-wheels-for-ps5">PS5</a>) is a newer model released in 2020 that is based off the G29 wheel. The biggest upgrade of the G923 over its predecessors is its TRUEFORCE technology. New vibrational motors built into the wheel adds haptic feedback on top of the DRIVING FORCE force feedback. Since immersion is the name of the game (and a big reason why many higher-end wheels cost hundreds more), this is a more significant change than it sounds on paper. In his <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/logitech-g923-review">Logitech G923 review</a>, Luke Reilly writes "The Logitech G923 is a great option for new racing game players who want a wheel that's a step up over the budget option... For a budget-friendly price, this wheel with a full metal pedal set lets you feel the intricacies of the road thanks to geared force feedback and Trueforce technology." </p><p>If you're looking for deals on other PS5 accessories, check out the <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-prime-day-ps5-deals-october-2024">best Prime Day PS5 deals</a> going on right now (we update it often). If you don't yet own a PS5 console, you're in luck. The <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ps5-slim-october-prime-day-2024">PS5 Slim</a> is currently on sale for Prime Day, and Sony recently announced a more powerful <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/where-to-buy-ps5-pro">PS5 Pro</a> that is currently up for preorder and ships out next month. </p><p>For Xbox accessories, check out the <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-xbox-deals-october-prime-day-2024">best Prime Day Xbox deals</a>. There aren't any great Xbox console deals going on right now, however there is a pretty amazing deal on <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-xbox-game-pass-ultimate-deal-for-prime-day">Xbox Game Pass Ultimate</a>, which itself is a great value since you won't have to pay for every new release game in order to enjoy them on launch day. For all other deals, head over to our <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/amazon-october-prime-day-2024">Prime Day megapost</a> to see our cherry-picked list of the best deals we've found.</p><h2>More Prime Day Deals on Gaming Hardware</h2><h2>More Prime Day Deals on Video Games</h2><p><em>Eric Song is the IGN commerce manager in charge of finding the best gaming and tech deals every day. When Eric isn't hunting for deals for other people at work, he's hunting for deals for himself during his free time.</em></p></div></section><div><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Oct 9, 2024 7:50 pm</p></div></div><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Destiny 2 Discord Quest Gets You A Free Shader]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/new-destiny-2-discord-quest-gets-you-a-free-shader/1100-6527069/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-destiny-2-discord-quest-gets-you-a-free-shader.1005531/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/new-destiny-2-discord-quest-gets-you-a-free-shader/1100-6527069/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6527069">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/destiny-2/" data-ref-id="5000-463450">Destiny 2</a> developer Bungie has teamed with Discord for one of the chat app's video game "quest" advertisements, offering players a free shader if they log in to its newly released content season, Revenant.</p><p>The blue-ish shader is called Celestial Ties, released during the Season of the Lost in 2022, and earning it is pretty easy if you're a Discord user, requiring you only to play Destiny 2 for a total of 15 minutes. Once that's done, you can redeem the quest in Discord for a redemption code to use on Bungie's website to receive the shader. It's altogether pretty easy--I completed the quest and got my shader before I was finished writing this article.</p><p>Here's what Celestial Ties looks like applied in action.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1581/15811374/4382164-20241009133907_1.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4382164" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1581/15811374/4382164-20241009133907_1.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4382164"></a><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1581/15811374/4382164-20241009133907_1.jpg"></figure><p>Discord recently began offering "quests" to users as a new approach to advertising on the app, which, if you're somehow not familiar, offers voice and text chat functions and is often used as an alternative to in-game chat features. Quests encourage you to play a specific game while logged into the Discord app. The rewards quests offer vary, but several have previously provided users with icons or graphics to add to their Discord user avatars. The Destiny 2 quest is the first I've seen to offer an in-game item.</p><p>The quest works on PC, Xbox One, Xbox Series X|S, PlayStation 4, and PS5, and is available to complete until October 22. Once the actual quest is done, you have until December 31 to redeem your shader.</p><p>Though it's easy to complete, you first have to find it on Discord to start it, which can be tough if you don't know where to look for it. Quests are kept in Discord's "Discover" tab, located under a little compass-like icon at the bottom of your list of servers and contacts on the left side of the app. Inside, you can find the quest for Revenant, but you have to click "accept" to activate it and set whether you'll play on PC or console.</p><p>Once that's done, your only requirement is to play Destiny 2 for 15 minutes with Discord running simultaneously. You'll receive a prompt on Discord to redeem the quest when it's done, which provides a code you can take to the Bungie redemption website, bungie.net/redeem. You need to link your Bungie and Discord accounts, though, and to log in on the Bungie website.</p><p>Inside Destiny 2, you can grab the shader from Special Deliveries kiosk in the Tower, located between Banshee and Cryptarch Rahool.</p><p>Revenant brings a lot of new content to Destiny 2, so check out our guide on what's new in the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/destiny-2-onslaught-salvation-guide-potions-banes-and-new-defenses/2900-5849/" data-ref-id="2900-5849">Onslaught: Salvation activity</a> and the rest of our Destiny 2 coverage.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ubisoft's NLF Game Remixes Fantasy Football, And You Can Sign Up For The Closed Beta]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ubisofts-nlf-game-remixes-fantasy-football-and-you-can-sign-up-for-the-closed-beta/1100-6527068/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ubisofts-nlf-game-remixes-fantasy-football-and-you-can-sign-up-for-the-closed-beta.1005528/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ubisofts-nlf-game-remixes-fantasy-football-and-you-can-sign-up-for-the-closed-beta/1100-6527068/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6527068">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>The closed beta for NFL Primetime Fantasy is out now on Android devices. Ubisoft's take on fantasy football was announced back in August, introduced as a free-to-play game for both Android and iOS where you create a roster of players using collectible cards and compete with others online. While the NFL is already on Week 6 of the season, the beta should provide a glance at what to expect once the game releases later this year.</p><p>After pre-registering on <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.ubisoft.nfl.primetime.fantasysports.football.live" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Google Play</a>, you'll have to wait and see if you're selected for the beta. If so, you'll receive an invite notification to download the game from the Android store. The same can be done on the <a href="https://register.ubisoft.com/primetime-fantasy?_gl=1*1l1s88u*_gcl_au*MTk5MTUzNDY2MC4xNzI4NTAwNjE4*_ga*MTA2NDgxNzAyOS4xNzI4NTAwNjE5*_ga_C4N5020N2R*MTcyODUwMDYxOC4xLjEuMTcyODUwMTczNC42MC4wLjA." data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">App Store</a>, but there's currently no closed beta for Apple devices. Pre-registering also guarantees an early access bundle at launch for both platforms, which will include x100 Adrenaline to enable modifiers during live games, as well as one Classic+ card pack with a Dynasty premium card guaranteed in it.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9ItgPAy0q_I" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/9ItgPAy0q_I" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>As for what to expect in terms of gameplay, collectible cards have individual stat boosters that can be leveled up. You can then register lineups for multiple games in a weekend or just hop in alongside a specific team on Sundays. As expected, there are leaderboards to compete with others online and, well, microtransactions, although it's early to say how much you'll be able to ignore them.</p><p>If you want to scratch the NFL itch further, in GameSpot's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/madden-nfl-25-review-gridiron-grates/1900-6418271/" data-ref-id="1900-6418271">Madden NFL 25 review</a>, Mark Delaney scored it a 6/10, highlighting the on-field gameplay, collision variety, and Team Builder mode. "I've played over 30 hours of Madden 25 so far, and I will play hundreds more before next August, at which point I will get the newest Madden and undoubtedly do it all over again," Delaney wrote. "In the end, maybe that's the real Madden Curse."</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/115652868521335484896?rel=author">Diego Nicolás Argüello</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Here’s Your Much-Needed Look at the Red Dead Redemption System Requirements]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/red-dead-redemption-system-requirements/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/here%E2%80%99s-your-much-needed-look-at-the-red-dead-redemption-system-requirements.1005510/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/red-dead-redemption-system-requirements/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Can you believe the original Red Dead Redemption launched on PlayStation 3 and Xbox 360 in May 2010? That’s such a long time ago, an entire lifetime for some players, and now we’re about to get the title on PC after more than a decade. To ensure you’re ready, here’s a look at the Red Dead Redemption system requirements!</p>



<h2 id="h-red-dead-redemption-minimum-and-recommended-system-requirements">Red Dead Redemption Minimum and Recommended System Requirements</h2>



<p>As a more than decade-old game, you wouldn’t expect something like Red Dead Redemption to tax your system. Well, it doesn’t. The open-world game’s system requirements prove relatively approachable, for the most part, with most systems able to easily handle even the recommended requirements.</p>



<h3 id="h-minimum-system-requirements">Minimum System Requirements:</h3>



<ul>
<li><strong>OS</strong>: Windows 10 64-Bit</li>



<li><strong>Processor</strong>: Intel® Core™ i5-4670 / AMD FX-9590</li>



<li><strong>Memory</strong>: 8 GB RAM</li>



<li><strong>Graphics</strong>: NVIDIA GeForce GTX 960 / AMD Radeon R7 360</li>



<li><strong>DirectX</strong>: Version 12</li>



<li><strong>Storage</strong>: 12 GB Available Space (SSD Recommended)</li>



<li><strong>Sound Card</strong>: Direct X Compatible</li>
</ul>



<h2 id="h-recommended-system-requirements">Recommended System Requirements:</h2>



<ul>
<li><strong>OS</strong>: Windows 10 64-Bit</li>



<li><strong>Processor</strong>: Intel® Core™ i5-8500 / AMD Ryzen 5 3500X</li>



<li><strong>Memory</strong>: 8 GB RAM</li>



<li><strong>Graphics</strong>: NVIDIA GTX 2070 / AMD RX 5700 XT</li>



<li><strong>DirectX</strong>: Version 12</li>



<li><strong>Storage</strong>: 12 GB Available Space (SSD Recommended)</li>



<li><strong>Sound Card</strong>: Direct X Compatible</li>
</ul>







<h2 id="h-when-can-you-play-red-dead-redemption-on-pc">When Can You Play Red Dead Redemption on PC?</h2>



<p>After countless years of eagerly awaiting the PC release of Red Dead Redemption, Rockstar Games decided to give us all a present before the holidays. You can play the open-world Wild West adventure on October 29.</p>



<p>When the game launches, it does so with numerous PC-specific features, including 4k resolution, ultrawide and super ultrawide support, HDR10 support, full mouse and keyboard controls, DLSS and FSR, adjustable draw distances, shadow quality settings, and more.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Red Dead Redemption and Undead Nightmare Coming to PC October 29" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/mnvc6uC6xZE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>Oh, and it does include Undead Nightmare!</p>



<p>Will you pick up a copy of Red Dead Redemption day one on PC? Let us know in the comments below, or join the discussion in our <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">official community forums</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>If you’re a fan of Rockstar Games, you might like to hear about how the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/grand-theft-auto-6-song-band/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">studio reportedly offered $7500 to use a band song</a> in Grand Theft Auto 6 with exclusive rights.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Save Big On The Razer Edge Gaming Tablet And Other Accessories At Amazon]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/save-big-on-the-razer-edge-gaming-tablet-and-other-accessories-at-amazon/1100-6526929/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/save-big-on-the-razer-edge-gaming-tablet-and-other-accessories-at-amazon.1005507/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/save-big-on-the-razer-edge-gaming-tablet-and-other-accessories-at-amazon/1100-6526929/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6526929">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">A bunch of Razer products are getting <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/amazon-prime-day-deals/">Prime Day Deal Days</a> discounts at Amazon. You'll find price cuts to some of Razer's best gaming headsets, gaming mice, controllers, mobile gaming gear, and more. Most of these discounts are only sticking around until October 9, so be sure to grab any that you're interested in before they run out.</p><p dir="ltr">One deal worth highlighting is the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CKM287V2?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Razer Edge WiFi gaming tablet</a>, which is down to $317. The Android-based handheld gaming device is akin to a Nintendo Switch or Steam Deck in form factor and is capable of playing Android-compatible games or streaming GamePass or remote play titles over wifi. It also features a 6.8-inch 1080p AMOLED screen with 144Hz refresh rate. The gaming tablet normally costs $400, but this discount saves you $83.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1701/17013431/4379511-razeredge.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4379511" data-ratio="0.552" data-width="1000" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1701/17013431/4379511-razeredge.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4379511"></a><figcaption>Razer Edge Wifi </figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1701/17013431/4379511-razeredge.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">If you want a cheaper alternative, you can transform your existing Android phone or iPhone into a gaming handheld using the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CCWN3Q1G?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Razer Kishi V2 Pro controller</a>, which is down to $90 (was $100). The standard Kishi V2 is even cheaper, at just $<a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0B16PJ31L?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">60 for the iPhone model</a> or <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0B16NGTCT?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">$57 for Android</a>. Those who want a standard controller to use on Xbox consoles, PC, or mobile can also grab the white <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B09JJ4592H?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Wolverine V2 Chroma</a> for just $56 (was $150). And while it's more expensive, the wireless Wolverine V2 Pro for PS5/PC is down to $200 (was $250). PC players can also pick up the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Razer-DeathAdder-Wireless-Gaming-Mouse/dp/B0B6Y52YXB?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">DeathAdder 3 Pro wireless gaming mouse</a> for just $120 (was $150).</p><p dir="ltr">You can also snag a bunch of gaming Razer headsets like the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CXGTGPZQ?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Blackshark V2 X</a>, but those who want something sleeker should check out the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0C3G2PMC8?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Hammerhead Pro true wireless gaming earbuds</a>, which are on sale for $160 (was $200). A few streaming accessories are also getting limited-time price cuts, including the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B09GJXKYR4?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Razer Seiren V2 mic</a>, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B09NF3RPYY?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Razer Key Light</a>, and <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0B5FV1BY6?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Razer Stream Controller</a>.</p><p dir="ltr">There are many more <a href="https://www.amazon.com/stores/page/03508F9D-3610-49AC-9E57-C476A4E7B219?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Razer discounts available at Amazon</a>, and we've rounded some of the best in the list below. For even more savings, be sure to check <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/amazon-prime-day-deals/">GameSpot's Prime Big Deal Days coverage</a> for all the best deals on electronics, video games, anime, and more that are still available through October 9.</p><h2 dir="ltr">Razer Prime Big Deal Days Discounts</h2><p dir="ltr"><strong>Gaming mice</strong></p><ul><li dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Razer-DeathAdder-Wireless-Gaming-Mouse/dp/B0B6Y52YXB?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Razer DeathAdder V3 Pro Wireless</a> -- $120 (<del>$150</del>)</li><li dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Razer-Acari-Ultra-Low-Friction-Gaming/dp/B08D1RM9DD?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Acari Ultra-low Friction Mouse Pad</a> -- $48 (<del>$60</del>)</li></ul><p dir="ltr"><strong>Headsets &amp; earbuds</strong></p><ul><li dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Razer-BlackShark-Gaming-Headset-Detachable/dp/B086PKMZ1Q?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Blackshark V2</a> -- $65 (<del>$100</del>)</li><li dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Razer-BlackShark-HyperSpeed-Wireless-Headset/dp/B0CF3LHQSM?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Blackshark V2 Hyperspeed</a> -- $100 (<del>$130</del>)</li><li dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CXGTGPZQ?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Blackshark V2 X</a> -- $38 (<del>$50</del>)</li><li dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Wireless-Gaming-Headset-Haptics-playstation-5/dp/B09KML1RVR?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Kaira Pro Wireless (PlayStation)</a> -- $75 (<del>$200</del>)</li><li dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Razer-Kaira-Wireless-Gaming-Headset-Xbox/dp/B08LRV49W8?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Kaira Pro Wireless (Xbox)</a> -- $75 (<del>$150</del>)</li><li dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0BFG2N19C?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Kaira X</a> -- $34 (<del>$6</del>0)</li><li dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Razer-Kraken-Wired-Gaming-Headset-PC/dp/B0D54V8N2K?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Kraken V3 X</a> -- $69 ($100)</li><li dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Razer-Kraken-Kitty-Wireless-Headset/dp/B0CCWDJ6GF?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Kraken Kitty Wireless</a> -- $70 (<del>$100</del>)</li><li dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0C3G2PMC8?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Hammerhead Pro wireless earbuds</a> -- $160 (<del>$200</del>)</li></ul><p dir="ltr"><strong>Controllers</strong></p><ul><li dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Wolverine-Wireless-Gaming-Controller-PlayStation-Console/dp/B0BWSLLWF2?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Wolverine V2 Pro Wireless</a> -- $200 (<del>$250</del>)</li><li dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B09JJ4592H?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Wolverine V2 Chroma</a> (white) -- $56 (<del>$150</del>)</li><li dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B09CKFSRK7?tag=gamespot-primeday-20&amp;tag=gamespot-buybutton-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Wolverine V2 Chroma</a> (black) -- $136 (<del>$150</del>)</li><li dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08LRTTGM6?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Wolverine V2 wired</a> -- $59 (<del>$63</del>)</li><li dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Razer-Universal-Charging-Wireless-Controller/dp/B0BP9DBWRP?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Razer Wireless Xbox Controller 6 Quick Charging Stand</a> -- $115 with coupon code (<del>$200</del>)</li><li dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B09KYGQFHV?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">PS5 Controller Quick Charging Stand</a> -- $19 (<del>$40</del>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B09DHPM1YC?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Xbox Controller Quick Charging Stand</a> -- $20 (<del>$40</del>)</li></ul><p dir="ltr"><strong>Mobile gaming</strong></p><ul><li dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CKM287V2?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Razer Edge WiFi gaming tablet</a> -- $317 (<del>$400</del>)</li><li dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CCWN3Q1G?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Razer Kishi V2 Pro smartphone controller (Android)</a> -- $90 (<del>$100</del>)</li><li dir="ltr">Razer Kishi V2 smartphone controller  <ul><li dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0B16NGTCT?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Android</a> -- $57 (<del>$100</del>)</li><li dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0B16PJ31L?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">iPhone (Black)</a> -- $60 (<del>$100</del>)</li></ul></li></ul><p dir="ltr"><strong>Accessories</strong></p><ul><li dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B09GJXKYR4?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Razer Seiren V2 Mic</a> -- $48 (<del>$100</del>)</li><li dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B09NF3RPYY?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Razer Key Light Chroma</a> -- $275 <del>($300</del>)</li><li dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0B5FV1BY6?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Razer Stream Controller</a> -- $143 (<del>$270</del>)</li><li dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Razer-Vinyl-Console-Skin-PlayStation-Application/dp/B0C95LHT86?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">PS5 Vinyl Console Skin</a> -- $17 (<del>$40</del>)</li></ul><hr><div data-embed-type="pinbox" data-ref-id="4304">  <ul>                              <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-hobbit-tolkien-illustrated-edition-is-free-at-amazon-when-you-buy-lotr-and-silmarillion/1100-6527038/">The Hobbit Tolkien Illustrated Edition Is Free At Amazon When You Buy LOTR And Silmarillion</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/get-3-months-of-xbox-game-pass-ultimate-for-50-off-today-only-october-9/1100-6526404/">Get 3 Months Of Xbox Game Pass Ultimate For 50% Off Today Only (October 9)</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/these-amd-and-intel-cpus-are-super-cheap-for-prime-big-deal-days/1100-6527035/">These AMD And Intel CPUs Are Super Cheap For Prime Big Deal Days</a></li>                          <li>         <span>+ Show More More Gaming, Tech, and Entertainment Deals &amp; Preorders Links (3)</span>       </li>          <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/popular-mini-pcs-are-on-sale-for-prime-big-deal-days/1100-6527039/">Popular Mini PCs Are On Sale For Prime Big Deal Days</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/star-trek-complete-original-series-steelbook-blu-ray-is-just-39-in-prime-big-deal-days-special/1100-6527029/">Star Trek: Complete Original Series Steelbook Blu-Ray Is Just $39 In Prime Big Deal Days Special</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ted-lasso-blu-ray-box-set-gets-significant-price-cut-for-prime-big-deal-days/1100-6523264/">Ted Lasso Blu-Ray Box Set Gets Significant Price Cut For Prime Big Deal Days</a></li>   </ul> </div>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/104300651635509044736?rel=author">Brendan Hesse</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dungeons & Dragons Comes to Universal Fan Fest]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/dungeons-dragons-comes-to-universal-fan-fest</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dungeons-dragons-comes-to-universal-fan-fest.1005498/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/dungeons-dragons-comes-to-universal-fan-fest<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><a href="https://techraptor.net/games/dungeons-dragons" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><em>Dungeons &amp; Dragons</em></a> is coming to Universal Studios Hollywood. Wizards of the Coast's iconic fantasy TTRPG will be a part of the park's newest event. The aptly titled Universal Fan Fest will bring several beloved nerd properties to life in a new after-hours event.</p>
<h2>The <em>Dungeons &amp; Dragons</em> Universal Fan Fest Announcement</h2>
<p>According to its <a href="https://www.universalstudioshollywood.com/web/en/us/things-to-do/events-and-seasonal-activities/fan-fest-nights">official event page</a>, the Universal Fan Fest will celebrate several beloved sci-fi, fantasy, and anime properties through immersive live experiences, themed-food, and exclusive merchandise.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/dungeons-dragons-xanathar-artwork.jpg?itok=wSh068P- 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/dungeons-dragons-xanathar-artwork.jpg?itok=IJ7YIw9B 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>In the case of the <em>Dungeons &amp; Dragons</em> Universal Fan Fest event, it will bring attendees into the world of Faerun. They will help the Harpers save the city of Waterdeep from the machinations of the mercenary leader, Xanathar.</p>
<p>But the Forgotten Realms won't be the only experience at the event. Attendees can also embark on <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/star-trek-panic-review-she-cannae-take-anymore" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><em>Star Trek's</em></a> iconic Enterprise-D bridge, join Luffy's crew for a <em>One Piece</em> pirate adventure, and witness an epic sorcery battle from the world of <em>Jujutsu Kaisen</em>.</p>
<p>The Universal Fan Fest is by the same creators as Halloween Horror Nights. This is another after-hours Universal Studios Hollywood event dedicated to Haunted House attractions based on horror properties like <em>Ghostbusters</em>, <a href="https://blog.discoveruniversal.com/events/everything-you-need-to-know-about-the-strangerthings-4-house-at-halloween-horror-nights-2023-hhn/"><em>Stranger Things</em></a>, and <a href="https://halloweenhorrornights.fandom.com/wiki/Welcome_to_Silent_Hill_(Orlando)"><em>Silent Hill</em></a>.</p>
<p>Further details are scarce on <em>Dungeons &amp; Dragons</em> Universal Fan Fest. According to an official <a href="https://x.com/UniStudios/status/1844061649327526162">social media post</a> on X (formerly Twitter), the event will be live between April 25 and May 18 2025. There is currently no information on ticket prices or pre-order details.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/dungeons-dragons-young-minds-inspired-kit-image.jpg?itok=hCv-JNKL 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/dungeons-dragons-young-minds-inspired-kit-image.jpg?itok=qfJi4KPx 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><h2>Dungeons &amp; Dragons Young Minds Inspired Classroom Kit</h2>
<p>On the more academic side, Wizards of the Coast <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/wizards-of-coast-announces-dd-adopt-classroom-partnership" rel="noopener" target="_blank">has continued</a> to leverage the creative application of <em>Dungeons &amp; Dragons</em> in a classrom context.</p>
<p>The studio has recently partnered with the group Young Minds Inspired to create <a href="https://ymiclassroom.com/lesson-plans/places/"><em>Dungeons &amp; Dragons: Places, Cities, and Worlds</em></a>. It's a set of resources designed for students grades 3-5 and 6-8.</p>
<p>The goal of the kit is to get students to explore the role of settings in storytelling through the collaborative power of TTRPGs. It is designed to encourage creative thinking and narrative writing skills.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Ever since he was small, Tyler Chancey has had a deep, abiding love for video games and a tendency to think and overanalyze everything he enjoyed. This… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/tyler-chancey">More about Tyler</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Monsters In New Quiet Place Horror Game Can Hear You Scream In Real Life]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/quiet-place-new-game-long-road-mic-hear-you-scream-ps5-1851669208</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/monsters-in-new-quiet-place-horror-game-can-hear-you-scream-in-real-life.1005495/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/quiet-place-new-game-long-road-mic-hear-you-scream-ps5-1851669208<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/games/a-quiet-place-the-road-ahead&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/games/a-quiet-place-the-road-ahead"><em>A Quiet Place: The Road Ahead</em></a></span><em>, </em>an upcoming horror game from Saber and Stormind Games, includes a neat and creepy feature. If you have a microphone activated, the monsters in the game can hear you cough and scream in real life just like in the movies. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="193897" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="10 Creatures We Wanna Ride In Star Wars Jedi: Survivor" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="418" data-playlist="193897,194012,193132" data-current="193897"><div><p>10 Creatures We Wanna Ride In Star Wars Jedi: Survivor</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/193897/193897_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/193897/193897_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/193897/193897_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/193897/193897_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/19360.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>The <em>Quiet Place </em>film franchise started in 2018 with <em>A Quiet Place,</em> a horror film about humans trying to survive after  alien monsters invade Earth. The creatures are incredibly fast and deadly, but can’t see or smell and rely exclusively on sound to hunt their prey, so survivors have to remain quiet or they’ll get killed by the aliens. And in the upcoming video game based on the movies, you the player will have to be quiet, too. Or else the digital monsters will hear you and attack.</p><p><strong>Pre-order <em>A Quiet Place: The Road Ahead</em>:</strong> <span><a data-ga="[]" href="https://www.amazon.com/Quiet-Place-Road-Ahead-Xbox-X/dp/B0DBWJQ1QV/ref=asc_df_B0DBWQQP5Q/?asc_campaign=kinjakotakulink-20&amp;asc_refurl=https://kotaku.com/quiet-place-new-game-long-road-mic-hear-you-scream-ps5-1851669208&amp;asc_source=&amp;tag=kinjakotakulink-20" target="_blank" rel="sponsored noopener noreferrer nofollow noskim" data-vtas-click="self:InlineUrl:inline-url-postbody" data-amazonasin="B0DBWJQ1QV" data-amazontag="kinjakotakulink-20">Amazon</a></span> | <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://howl.me/cngwpqYZbNl&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://howl.me/cngwpqYZbNl" target="_blank" rel="sponsored noopener noreferrer nofollow noskim" data-vtas-click="self:InlineUrl:inline-url-postbody">Best Buy</a></span></p><p>On October 9, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://youtu.be/5eCKy9TfsFM&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://youtu.be/5eCKy9TfsFM" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Saber Interactive released a new traile</a></span>r for <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/quiet-place-game-road-ahead-release-date-trailer-ps5-1851614631&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/quiet-place-game-road-ahead-release-date-trailer-ps5-1851614631"><em>A Quiet Place: The Road Ahead</em></a></span><em> </em>and revealed an optional feature in the game: “Microphone Noise Detection.” </p><p>Here’s how the publisher explained the feature via a press release. </p><blockquote data-type="BlockQuote"><p> By activating your microphone, this optional feature lets the game’s deadly creatures detect every sound you make in real life, bringing the horror right into your room. Get a glimpse of what it’s like when any noise can betray you with the game’s new “Survive in Silence” live-action trailer! </p></blockquote><p>So yeah, if you are playing the game with this feature turned on and your phone rings or you sneeze that might be enough noise to get the attention of a nasty alien monster, likely leading to your in-game character’s death. </p><p>I love when games use microphones like this and it feels like a perfect fit for this franchise. Past examples I can think of include<em> Splinter Cell: Chaos Theory</em>—which forced co-op players to whisper in-game to avoid enemies hearing them—and <em>Manhunt</em>—which let you use the mic to distract deadly guards. <em>Alien Isolation</em> also included a mic detection feature, too. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/alien-isolation-2-sequel-confirmed-announced-sega-ca-1851666754&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/alien-isolation-2-sequel-confirmed-announced-sega-ca-1851666754">Hopefully, it’s also in the just-announced sequel</a></span>. </p><p>I’m all for these weird features as they add a whole new layer to the gameplay. But I’m also happy most of them, like in the <em>Quiet Place</em> game, are optional. Otherwise, I’d be killed a lot because of my cat coming in and meowing for attention. </p><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://howl.me/cngwpqYZbNl&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://howl.me/cngwpqYZbNl" target="_blank" rel="sponsored noopener noreferrer nofollow noskim" data-vtas-click="self:InlineUrl:inline-url-postbody"><em>A Quiet Place: The Road Ahead</em></a></span> launches October 17 on Xbox Series X/S, PS5, and PC. </p><p> .<br></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Get A Highly Rated Steam Deck Docking Station For Only $24]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/get-a-highly-rated-steam-deck-docking-station-for-only-24/1100-6527067/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/get-a-highly-rated-steam-deck-docking-station-for-only-24.1005492/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/get-a-highly-rated-steam-deck-docking-station-for-only-24/1100-6527067/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6527067">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">One of the best-rated third-party Steam Deck docking stations, the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/JSAUX-Compatible-Ethernet-Charging-Deck-HB0602/dp/B0B28PCDM2?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">JSAUX Docking Station</a>, is getting a big discount at Amazon. You can pick up the accessory for just $24 (was $40), but the deal only lasts until midnight tonight when <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/amazon-prime-day-deals/">Amazon's Prime Big Deal Days</a> event ends.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1701/17013431/4382118-steamdeckdockhero.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4382118" data-ratio="0.552" data-width="1000" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1701/17013431/4382118-steamdeckdockhero.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4382118"></a><figcaption>JSAUX Docking Station</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1701/17013431/4382118-steamdeckdockhero.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">JSAUX's Docking Station features all the expected I/O ports you'd want from a Steam Deck dock, including HDMI, USB-C, Ethernet, and two USB-A 2.0 slots. The dock also has an additional USB-C cable that plugs into the Steam Deck. The HDMI port supports up to 4K 60fps video output. There's also a rubberized cradle for placing your Steam Deck.</p><p dir="ltr">Compared to Valve's official Steam Deck dock, JSAUX's is not only more affordable, but it's also compatible with a wider range of devices PC gaming handhelds like the ROG Ally, MSI Claw, and Lenovo Legion Go, as well as Android smartphones and tablets.</p><p dir="ltr">JSAUX also offers <a href="https://www.amazon.com/JSAUX-Compatible-Ethernet-Ports-HB0604-Included/dp/B0BNTQWKN6?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">an upgraded model that includes an M.2 SSD slot</a> for expanded storage while your Steam Deck (or other device) is plugged into the dock. This is a great upgrade for those who often use their Steam Deck while docked, and you can get it for just $72 (was 90). However, you'll need to supply your own M.2 SSD. Luckily, several models are also on sale at Amazon, including <a href="https://www.amazon.com/WD_BLACK-SN770-Internal-Gaming-Solid/dp/B09QV692XY?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">this 1TB model from WD_Black</a> that you can grab for $61 (was $110).</p><p dir="ltr">Amazon's Big Deal Days sale is a great time to pick up other Steam Deck accessories like grips, cases, portable batteries, and more. Check the list below for a round-up of our favorite Steam Deck accessory deals.</p><h2 dir="ltr">Amazon Big Deal Days - Best Steam Deck Accessory Deals</h2><ul><li dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/JSAUX-Compatible-Ethernet-Charging-Deck-HB0602/dp/B0B28PCDM2?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">JSAUX Docking Station</a> -- $24 (<del>$40</del>)</li><li dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/JSAUX-Compatible-Ethernet-Ports-HB0604-Included/dp/B0BNTQWKN6?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">JSAUX M.2 Docking Station</a> -- $72 (<del>$90</del>)</li><li dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/WD_BLACK-SN770-Internal-Gaming-Solid/dp/B09QV692XY?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">WD_BLACK 1TB SN770 NVMe Internal Gaming SSD</a> -- $61 (<del>$110</del>)</li><li dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/SanDisk-1-5TB-microSDXC-Memory-Adapter/dp/B0CJMRW771?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">SanDisk 1.5TB Ultra microSD card</a> -- $90 (<del>$150</del>)</li><li dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/SanDisk-Extreme-microSDXC-Memory-Adapter/dp/B09X7MPX8L?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">SanDisk 1TB Extreme microSD card</a> -- $79 (<del>$93</del>)</li><li dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Antank-Magnetic-Compatible-16000mAh-Detechable/dp/B0BNQFMQP5?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Antank Magnetic Steam Deck Power Bank - 20000mAh 45W, Fast Charging 3.0</a> -- $40 (<del>$60</del>)</li><li dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/JSAUX-PC0104-Detachable-Accessories-Protective/dp/B0BRXHK2QL?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">JSAUX Steam Deck Comfort Grip Modcase</a> -- $24 (<del>$30</del>)</li><li dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Syntech-Protective-Compatible-Accessories-Alignment-Gray/dp/B0BQBTBBQP?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Steam Deck Rubberized Grip Case</a> -- $19 (<del>$25</del>)</li><li dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/JSAUX-Protector-Hardness-Resistant-Tempered/dp/B0B55ZD4HL?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">JSAUX Steam Deck Screen Protector - 2-Pack</a> -- $8 (<del>$10</del>)</li><li dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Carrying-Accessories-Protective-Lightweight-nintendo-wii/dp/B09ZYFV1GD?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Tomtoc Steam Deck Shoulder Bag Travel Case</a> -- $40 (<del>$50</del>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0D6V6YFQL?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Syntech Steam Deck Sling Bag Carrying Case</a> -- $28 (<del>$35</del>)</li></ul><hr><div data-embed-type="pinbox" data-ref-id="4304">  <ul>                              <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-hobbit-tolkien-illustrated-edition-is-free-at-amazon-when-you-buy-lotr-and-silmarillion/1100-6527038/">The Hobbit Tolkien Illustrated Edition Is Free At Amazon When You Buy LOTR And Silmarillion</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/get-3-months-of-xbox-game-pass-ultimate-for-50-off-today-only-october-9/1100-6526404/">Get 3 Months Of Xbox Game Pass Ultimate For 50% Off Today Only (October 9)</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/these-amd-and-intel-cpus-are-super-cheap-for-prime-big-deal-days/1100-6527035/">These AMD And Intel CPUs Are Super Cheap For Prime Big Deal Days</a></li>                          <li>         <span>+ Show More More Gaming, Tech, and Entertainment Deals &amp; Preorders Links (3)</span>       </li>          <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/popular-mini-pcs-are-on-sale-for-prime-big-deal-days/1100-6527039/">Popular Mini PCs Are On Sale For Prime Big Deal Days</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/star-trek-complete-original-series-steelbook-blu-ray-is-just-39-in-prime-big-deal-days-special/1100-6527029/">Star Trek: Complete Original Series Steelbook Blu-Ray Is Just $39 In Prime Big Deal Days Special</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ted-lasso-blu-ray-box-set-gets-significant-price-cut-for-prime-big-deal-days/1100-6523264/">Ted Lasso Blu-Ray Box Set Gets Significant Price Cut For Prime Big Deal Days</a></li>   </ul> </div>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/104300651635509044736?rel=author">Brendan Hesse</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bolt Action 3rd Edition Review - Snapping Into Action]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/bolt-action-3rd-edition-review-snapping-into-action</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/bolt-action-3rd-edition-review-snapping-into-action.1005483/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/bolt-action-3rd-edition-review-snapping-into-action<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>In the world of historical miniature wargaming, there are few conflicts that quite capture the imagination of gamers quite like World War II - and for those gamers, one of the most popular games on the market is <i>Bolt Action</i>. Warlord Games just released a new edition of the game, and they sent me a copy to review. Could this be a good entry point into historical wargaming? Read my <i>Bolt Action</i> 3rd Edition Review to find out!</p>

<p>First developed by Alessio Cavatore and Rick Priestley in 2012, <i>Bolt Action</i> is a 28mm miniature wargame taking place across the span of WWII. And while Warlord Games creates many different models for a wide array of armies, the game itself is technically manufacturer agnostic. As long as your miniatures are 28mm scale and set on round 25mm bases, there’s nothing saying you can’t use them.</p>
<p>In the game, players will collect, build, and paint armies from this era, clashing against one another on the tabletop. And while this review is also covering the rules in general, we’re mainly taking a look at <a href="https://us.warlordgames.com/products/bolt-action-battle-of-the-bulge-starter-set-with-hardback-rulebook">the new <i>Battle of the Bulge Starter Set</i></a><i>.</i></p>
<h2><b>What’s Included in the <i>Bolt Action Battle of the Bulge</i> 3rd Edition Starter Set?</b></h2>
<p>Included in the <i>Bolt Action</i> <i>Battle of the Bulge</i> 3rd Edition Starter<i> </i>Set are the Bolt Action A5 rulebook (this is the entire rulebook, condensed into a smaller sized softcover book), a starter scenario and assembly booklet, Bolt Action dice, and six-sided dice.</p>
<p>On the miniatures front, we get 24 hard plastic US Winter Army infantry models (on 4 sprees), 18 hard plastic German Winter Fallschirmjäger paratrooper models (on 3 sprues), 1 hard plastic M8 Greyhound armored car (can also make an M20 scout car) with a transfer sheet, 1 hard plastic Ruined Farmhouse terrain piece, plenty of pin markers, and templates for heavy explosive attacks.</p>
<p>For an extra $50 USD, you can upgrade the bundle to also include a hardcover version of the rulebook. And while I don’t know if I would have upgraded had they not sent me the hardcover, I’m glad to have it - as the text is much bigger and makes leafing through to run down a rule all the easier.</p>
<h2><b>How Do You Play <em>Bolt Action</em> 3rd Edition?</b></h2>
<p>In my opinion, the core of what sets <i>Bolt Action </i>apart and makes it special is the way the game handles activating units. For each of your units on the board, you’ll add a special six-sided die to a bag. Your opponent will do the same with their own (differently colored) dice. Then, someone will reach into the bag and remove one die - whoever’s color is pulled is first to activate a unit. Once that unit has activated, you repeat the process, pulling another die from the bag.</p>
<p>You get to choose which of your units you activate, and you get to choose how you activate them (more on that in a moment), but the thrill of not knowing when you’re going to get to activate adds some really nice tension to the game. This does a really nice job of breaking up the “I Go, You Go” nature of so many miniature wargames.</p>
<h2><b>Attacking in <em>Bolt Action</em> 3rd Edition</b></h2>
<p>When activating units, you’ll fire upon your enemies with various weapons, all of which have different ranges, amounts of dice they roll, armor penetration values (for larger weapons), and more.&nbsp;</p>
<p>To simplify things a bit, you’ll essentially be doing the following: rolling a collection of d6’s to see if you hit your target, then your opponent can potentially react by hitting the deck (and losing their action), and then you’ll roll for damage, and they’ll roll for cover saves! Each model has 1 health, so one point of damage takes them out. Remove enough units in one go, and you might just scare your enemy off the board if they fail a morale test.</p>
<h2><b>Activating With <em>Bolt Action</em> Dice</b></h2>
<p>The <i>Bolt Action</i> dice - those same custom dice you’ll pull from the dice bag to see who activates first - also tell you the six different actions you can assign to your units. Let’s break it down one by one, because it very cleanly lays out how to play the game!</p>
<ul><li><b>Fire </b>- Unit fires their weapons at full effect</li>
<li><b>Advance </b>- Unit moves their Advance speed (6” for infantry) and then fires<b> </b>(with a -1 penalty to non-Assault weapons)</li>
<li><b>Run - </b>Unit moves at twice their Advance speed</li>
<li><b>Ambush - </b>Unit holds their action and waits to attack</li>
<li><b>Rally - </b>Unit removes all pin markers (pin markers make it harder to shoot <i>and</i> harder to take any action at all)</li>
<li><b>Down - </b>Unit gains either 5+ cover save or (if already in cover) a +2 to their cover save rolls. Also, if they stay Down for two turns, remove all pin markers.</li>
</ul><h2><b>Units Included In the <i>Bolt Action Battle of the Bulge</i> 3rd Edition Starter Set</b></h2>
<p>Now I want to briefly chat about the units included in the <i>Bolt Action Battle of the Bulge</i> starter set. For the American forces, it instructs you to build one NCO unit of three (with quick-bursting SMGs), one 11-man unit, and a 10-man unit. You’ll also build the M8 Greyhound armored truck.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Of all of the army construction I did with this box, this was the only aspect that gave me trouble. Maybe it’s a skill issue, (though god knows I’ve put together my fair share of confounding Sylvaneth Treelord Ancients) but I seriously struggled to follow along, and ended up with (gasp!) extra parts left by the wayside.</p>
<p>For the German combatants, you’ll build one 3-man NCO team, and then three 5-man Veteran units (Veteran units are harder to hit, and have higher morale). Two of those three units also include a one-shot anti-vehicle weapon, giving them a shot against that Greyhound.</p>
<p>All in all, both sides of the field feel very well-balanced, especially when weapon upgrades are factored in. And the starter scenarios in the assembly booklet help ease you into the game (before, tantalizingly, presenting a final scenario where you need units not included in the starter set).</p>
<h2><b><i>Bolt Action </i>3rd Edition Review - Final Thoughts</b></h2>
<p>Though I didn’t have any experience playing any historical wargaming prior to this, I’ve had my eye on <i>Bolt Action</i> for a long time. For years, words like “accessible” and “fast-paced” have been thrown around when people talk about this game, setting it apart from the (perhaps incorrect) preconception of historical wargames as being a bit stuck in the mud.</p>
<p>When the opportunity to check out <i>Bolt Action </i>3rd Edition came around, I jumped at the opportunity. And what I found in this box is a game that is absolutely engrossing, with an approachable ruleset that doesn’t skimp at all on depth and detail. The rulebook is full of gorgeously painted dioramas and battle scenes, and there’s so much to dig into once you begin building beyond what’s included in the core box.</p>
<p>If I had any critiques of the Starter Set box as a whole, it would be the lack of diversity among models included. While I understand that keeping the models included in the box limited to infantry and one vehicle lessens the amount of rules needed to jump into the game, it would have been nice to see something like a mortar team.&nbsp;</p>
<p>That being said, because you’re starting with mostly infantry, playing the game was fun and, yes, fast-paced. The action economy in this game is second-to-none, and rolling a clutch of dice as your soldiers unleash punishing rifle fire is extremely satisfying, every time.</p>
<p>But more important than all of that is that fact that <i>Bolt Action</i> 3rd Edition completely ignited my imagination, and made me want to go out and learn everything I could about these specific WWII battles, and immerse myself in more of the in-depth, tactical history of the war.</p>
<p>That’s the true power of a historical wargame. Sure, <i>Warhammer Age of Sigmar</i> can inspire you to read fantasy literature. And <i>Marvel: Crisis Protocol</i> can inspire you to check out back-issues of your favorite super-heroes. But with a game like <i>Bolt Action</i>, I find myself looking for books to read and movies to watch about The Battle of the Bulge. It’s an experience that can be, for the right gamer, as enriching as it is entertaining - and when that happens, it’s truly something special.</p>
<hr><p><em>The copy of&nbsp;</em>Bolt Action 3rd Edition Battle of the Bulge Starter Set&nbsp;<em>used in the creation of this review was provided by Warlord Games. All photos courtesy the author.</em></p>
</div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Giaco Furino joined the TechRaptor team as a Staff Writer in 2019 after searching for a dedicated place to write and talk about Tabletop Games. In 2020, he… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/giaco-furino">More about Giaco</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[All the buzz about Nintendo’s Alarmo clock]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/9/24266353/nintendo-alarmo-sound-clock</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/all-the-buzz-about-nintendo%E2%80%99s-alarmo-clock.1005480/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/9/24266353/nintendo-alarmo-sound-clock<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div role="region" aria-labelledby="stream-lede"><p>It seems like Nintendo just revealed its mysterious device that recently crossed the <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/9/23/24251736/nintendo-mmwave-device-24ghz-fcc-filing">Federal Communications Commission (FCC)</a> — and it’s not <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/5/7/24150891/nintendo-switch-2-console-announcement-earnings-q4-2024">the Switch 2</a>. On Wednesday, Nintendo announced, of all things, the “Alarmo” alarm clock. But in classic Nintendo fashion, the clock has some playful tricks.</p><p>The clock responds to your movements, which you can use to snooze your alarm with motion. Its faces feature Nintendo characters from franchises like <em>Super Mario</em> and <em>Zelda</em>, and you can set the alarm to wake you up with music from those franchises. The Alarmo can also track how much you move in your sleep.</p><p>The Alarmo — officially, the “Nintendo Sound Clock: Alarmo” — is available to purchase in “early access” for Nintendo Switch Online subscribers and at the Nintendo NY store. We’ve actually already picked one up, and we’ve published some <a href="https://www.theverge.com/24266272/nintendo-alarmo-sound-clock-hands-on">initial impressions and a bunch of photos</a>.</p><p>Here’s all of our coverage of Nintendo’s Alarmo clock.</p></div><div><h2>Highlights</h2></div><section id="updates-section"><ul><li role="article" id="stream-entry-58ab3efd-c89e-4abc-aebb-aa2006b27348"><span><svg width="9" height="14" viewBox="0 0 9 14" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"><title>Pin</title><path fill-rule="evenodd" clip-rule="evenodd" d="M2.29145 0.51845L7.17163 0.475916C7.24785 0.475123 7.31068 0.536866 7.31136 0.613206L7.32587 2.27502C7.32667 2.35136 7.26493 2.4142 7.18865 2.41467L6.71631 2.41893L6.73549 4.6093C7.91274 5.27884 8.71197 6.53941 8.72468 7.99076C8.72511 8.02456 8.7249 8.05811 8.72425 8.09173C8.72224 8.21576 8.73196 8.20511 8.60916 8.20618L5.50884 8.23328L4.84626 13.5557L4.09124 8.24574L0.986492 8.273C0.862549 8.27396 0.877529 8.27839 0.873323 8.15352C0.872351 8.12245 0.87163 8.09099 0.871287 8.05941C0.858454 6.60819 1.63527 5.33346 2.8005 4.64357L2.78119 2.45333L2.30866 2.45752C2.23257 2.45819 2.16973 2.39644 2.16893 2.32023L2.15411 0.658225C2.15362 0.581946 2.21536 0.519115 2.29145 0.51845Z" fill="#5200FF"></path></svg>PINNED</span><div><h2><a href="https://www.theverge.com/24266272/nintendo-alarmo-sound-clock-hands-on">A closer look at Nintendo’s adorable Alarmo clock</a></h2><p>Look, I’m a sucker for instant gratification. It’s often one of my favorite things about living in New York City. This morning, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/9/24265984/nintendo-alarmo-alarm-clock-date-price">Nintendo announced its $99 Alarmo clock</a>, and when the company’s store in Rockefeller Center opened a couple hours later, I walked in and picked one up. Did I feel a little iffy about paying $108.91 after tax for a plastic alarm clock? You bet. But fortunately, in my field, this counts as a work expense. (Technically, this product is called Nintendo Sound Clock: Alarmo — but no one is ever going to refer to it that way. It’s Alarmo.)</p><p><em>The Verge</em>’s senior entertainment editor Andrew Webster will have a full review of Alarmo coming up, but I wanted to check it out for myself. Mostly, I was curious about the audio quality. If the speaker in this relatively tiny clock sounds tinny or shrill, that would ruin the whole concept for me.</p><p><span><a href="https://www.theverge.com/24266272/nintendo-alarmo-sound-clock-hands-on">Read Article &gt;</a></span></p></div></li><li role="article" id="stream-entry-2bbb28fa-96a7-4ac0-b64e-ca97a63a59f5"></li><li role="article" id="stream-entry-aa59004d-083d-4ad8-b1d3-a3f5b44cae10"><div><h2><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/9/24266135/nintendo-original-alarm-clock-alarmo-prototypes">Nintendo’s original alarm clock prototypes were a lot less playful</a></h2><p>Nintendo just announced <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/9/24265984/nintendo-alarmo-alarm-clock-date-price">its new Alarmo clock</a> with a motion sensor, and even though we’re still soaking in the $100 device, the company also shared a look at some interesting early prototypes that reveal how the project changed during its development.</p><p>While the Alarmo is round and an eye-catching red, one “early” prototype Nintendo showed in an “Ask the Developer” interview had a more boxy shape and came in gray. This prototype did have an interesting feature in its dot matrix LED display (similar to the <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/7/24/24205675/amazon-discontinue-echo-dot-with-clock">now-discontinued Echo Dot with Clock</a>), but Nintendo ultimately went in a different direction because “we felt that this display system wouldn’t be able to communicate the instructions sufficiently,” says Nintendo’s Yosuke Tamori, who oversaw the development of the Alarmo. “It was especially difficult to explain the product’s new features, such as the motion sensor,” he says.</p><p><span><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/9/24266135/nintendo-original-alarm-clock-alarmo-prototypes">Read Article &gt;</a></span></p></div></li><li role="article" id="stream-entry-5955c8c3-5e1f-4d38-929b-9e22f3b87d2e"></li><li role="article" id="stream-entry-df5a3dbc-ec5d-4169-adc8-3d1f8503992e"><div><h2><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/9/23/24251736/nintendo-mmwave-device-24ghz-fcc-filing">What’s this new mystery Nintendo device?</a></h2><p>Nintendo has submitted a <a href="https://apps.fcc.gov/oetcf/eas/reports/ViewExhibitReport.cfm?mode=Exhibits&amp;RequestTimeout=500&amp;calledFromFrame=Y&amp;application_id=m9V0HXBXo8nolsDsEYU3Nw%3D%3D&amp;fcc_id=BKECLO001">mysterious new wireless device</a> to the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) this weekend, and it isn’t the Switch 2 console we’re expecting to be revealed before next April. The CLO-001 model number doesn’t reveal what it <em>actually</em> is, but it appears to be an entirely new product line given the “001” codes used on devices like the original Switch (HAC-001) and DS (NTR-001) consoles.</p><p>It’s tagged only as a “wireless device,” not a “wireless game console” or any kind of controller like a Joy-Con. A basic diagram within the documents shows an outline of where the FCC label will be “displayed in a depression area on the bottom” of something with a squarish footprint and rounded-off corners. </p><p><span><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/9/23/24251736/nintendo-mmwave-device-24ghz-fcc-filing">Read Article &gt;</a></span></p></div></li></ul></section></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Green Lantern HBO Show Makes Rebel Ridge Star Its John Stewart]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/green-lantern-hbo-rebel-ridge-john-stewart-aaron-pierre-1851669212</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/green-lantern-hbo-show-makes-rebel-ridge-star-its-john-stewart.1005474/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/green-lantern-hbo-rebel-ridge-john-stewart-aaron-pierre-1851669212<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="2b9da35996e512bfca4b28768b2d158c" data-recommend-id="image://2b9da35996e512bfca4b28768b2d158c" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="John Stewart from the cartoon appears alongside Aaron Pierre. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="John Stewart from the cartoon appears alongside Aaron Pierre. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Warner Bros. / Neftlix / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="2b9da35996e512bfca4b28768b2d158c" data-recommend-id="image://2b9da35996e512bfca4b28768b2d158c" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="John Stewart from the cartoon appears alongside Aaron Pierre. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>HBO’s <em>Green Lantern</em> show has cast its John Stewart. Aaron Pierre, the retired Marine seeking justice in Netflix’s<em> Rebel Ridge</em>, will star in <em>Lanterns</em> alongside <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/hbo-green-lantern-hal-jordan-kyle-chandler-coach-1851655222&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/hbo-green-lantern-hal-jordan-kyle-chandler-coach-1851655222"><em>Friday Night Lights</em> coach  Kyle Chandler</a></span> as the comic book detective show begins to take shape. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="193818" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="The Last of Us’s Lamar Johnson On Learning Sign Language For The Show" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="258" data-playlist="193818,197284,197260" data-current="193818"><div><p>The Last of Us’s Lamar Johnson On Learning Sign Language For The Show</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/193818/193818_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/193818/193818_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/193818/193818_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/193818/193818_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/19270.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p> DC Studios head James Gunn confirmed the news on social media today, and according to <em>The Hollywood Reporter</em>, the final choice came down to Pierre and Stephan James, who previously starred in <em>The Piano Lesson</em> and <em>Race</em>. “Welcome to DC, Aaron Pierre,” Gunn <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/JamesGunn/status/1844057078882763222?t=Bck5kEqc45t3NbB9waOTlA&amp;s=19&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/JamesGunn/status/1844057078882763222?t=Bck5kEqc45t3NbB9waOTlA&amp;s=19" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">wrote</a></span>. “After a long and grueling series of auditions I am absolutely sure we’ve found an incredible John Stewart.”</p><p><em>Lanterns</em> is reported to by a gritty murder mystery in the vein of HBO’s hit anthology series <em>True Detective</em>. The initial premise at least appears to revolve around Chandler as an older, grumpier Hal Jordan training up Pierre’s Stewart as his replacement Green Lantern while the two try to unravel the conspiracy behind a grizzly murder. </p><p>A Green Lantern show might have previously seemed like an awkward fit for TV, especially coming off of DC’s incredibly spotty record on the big screen. But <em>The Penguin</em> has somehow managed to take Colin Farrell’s riff on the Gotham supervillain and turn it into a compelling show about warring crime bosses and underworld politics.</p><p>Pierre also seems like a great fit <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.vulture.com/article/review-rebel-ridge-an-instant-slow-burn-action-classic.html&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.vulture.com/article/review-rebel-ridge-an-instant-slow-burn-action-classic.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">coming off of <em>Rebel Ridge</em></a></span>, a revenge flick about corrupt cops in Louisiana that started streaming on Netflix last month and which co-stars Don Johnson of <em>Miami Vice</em> and more recently, HBO’s previous DC adaptation, <em>Watchmen</em>. It’s a great movie with strong performances in which Pierre still manages to stand out as a rising action star. He also plays Mufasa in the upcoming <em>Lion King</em> prequel. </p><p><em>Lanterns </em>still doesn’t have a release date but it’s expected to hopefully begin filming as early as next year. </p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>