<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 14:56:52 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Here's How To Watch Tomorrow's 24-Minute Pokémon Presents, And DJ Pikachu Beforehand]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/pokemon-presents-legend-z-a-youtube-dj-pikachu-1851786626</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/heres-how-to-watch-tomorrows-24-minute-pok%C3%A9mon-presents-and-dj-pikachu-beforehand.1248752/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>It feels like such a long time since we had any big <em>Pokémon </em>news. Back in February <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/pokemon-legends-z-a-trailer-switch-mega-evolution-1851766684&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-legends-z-a-trailer-switch-mega-evolution-1851766684">we had our last chunk of information about this year’s Switch game, <em>Pokémon Legends: Z-A</em></a></span>, but since then all has been tremendously quiet. Could tomorrow’s extra-long <em>Pokémon </em>Presents be about to give us something new to chew on?</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196165" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="What’s Coming Out Beyond Pokémon: The Indigo Disk | The Week In Games" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="95" data-playlist="196165,195519,195905" data-current="196165"><div><p>What’s Coming Out Beyond Pokémon: The Indigo Disk | The Week In Games</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196165/196165_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196165/196165_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196165/196165_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196165/196165_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21711.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>Starting at 9 a.m. EDT on Tuesday, July 22, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/pokemon-presents-july-legends-z-a-scarlet-violet-1851782666?_gl=1*ub8a79*_ga*NjgyMDU5NjUzLjE3NTAwODIwMTA.*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*czE3NTMxMDI2MzMkbzU5JGcxJHQxNzUzMTA0OTk5JGo1MyRsMCRoMA..&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-presents-july-legends-z-a-scarlet-violet-1851782666?_gl=1*ub8a79*_ga*NjgyMDU5NjUzLjE3NTAwODIwMTA.*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*czE3NTMxMDI2MzMkbzU5JGcxJHQxNzUzMTA0OTk5JGo1MyRsMCRoMA..">we were actually informed of this <em>Pokémon </em>Presents</a></span> all the way back in May—rather strange, as these pre-recorded streams are usually announced just a few days ahead. But instead of a build-up to some big reveal, there’s been silence since. Now, the Spearow-eyed Joe Merrick of <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://serebii.net/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://serebii.net/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Serebii</em></a></span> has <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://bsky.app/profile/joemerrick.bsky.social/post/3lufiuhjqq22w&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://bsky.app/profile/joemerrick.bsky.social/post/3lufiuhjqq22w" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">spotted</a></span> that due to a slip-up by the official Korean Pokémon YouTube channel, we know that this edition will be a lengthy 24 minutes.</p><p>But 24 minutes of what? A big part of why things feel so quiet right now is that, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/pokemon-z-a-scarlet-violent-sword-shield-switch-2-1851766786&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-z-a-scarlet-violent-sword-shield-switch-2-1851766786">at any point over the last fifteen years</a></span>, this would be the point in the three-yearly cycle where we’d be inundated with reveals of an all-new generation of pocket monsters, building up to the fall release of the big, new, mainline <em>Pokémon </em>game. Except, for reasons never announced, that’s not happened—we’re experiencing our first four-year gap in the franchise in ages. (God, I <em>hope</em> it’s just four years.) And while <em>Z-A</em> is looking intriguing, and we’ll definitely get a good look at it again tomorrow, one thing it isn’t going to do is add any new Pokémon to the roster.</p><p>So could this Presents be hiding some sort of tease for Gen X? I wish I could believe that, but I have my doubts. If there is going to be a new mainline game next year, all of history suggests it won’t be until around October, and starting reveals over a year early seems unlikely. Still, it’d be good!</p><p>What’s more likely is we’ll get updates for the array of <em>Pokémon</em> games already out there, including <em>Unite</em>, <em>TCG Pocket</em>, <em>Sleep</em> and the rest, as well as reveals for perhaps a couple of new mobile apps and games, and maybe a new multiplayer game. Oh, and something about <em>Horizons</em> season 2, perhaps. Perhaps more on the new season of the wonderful stop-motion <em>Concierge.</em>&nbsp;</p><p>The stream will start tomorrow, July 22, at 9 a.m. EDT, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.youtube.com/pokemon&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.youtube.com/pokemon" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">via the official YouTube channel</a></span>. And intriguingly, if you tune into the Japanese channel an hour earlier, there’s apparently going to be an hour of DJ Pikachu Live? I have no idea. But it could well be promoting a surprise reveal of a DJ-based game in the main event.</p><p>.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/pokemon-presents-legend-z-a-youtube-dj-pikachu-1851786626]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[CoD: Black Ops 7 Continues Franchise's Obsession With Weed]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cod-black-ops-7-continues-franchises-obsession-with-weed/1100-6533294/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cod-black-ops-7-continues-franchises-obsession-with-weed.1248748/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6533294">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-2025-everything-we-know-about-rumored-black-ops-2-sequel/1100-6529073/" data-ref-id="1100-6529073">Call of Duty: Black Ops 7</a>'s ESRB description has been posted, and included in the ratings description is confirmation that the new game will carry forward the franchise's appreciation for marijuana.</p><p>The <a href="https://www.esrb.org/ratings/40736/call-of-dutyr-black-ops-7/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">ESRB description</a> says some weapons in the game feature "marijuana/joints/paraphernalia" and that operators can be seen "inhaling through bongs as part of execution sequences." These are likely references to cosmetics, as Call of Duty's online multiplayer is known for its raft of weed-themed DLC. It remains to be seen, however, if Black Ops 6's in-game purchases and operator bundles--<a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/youll-never-guess-who-the-next-cod-operator-might-be/1100-6531191/" data-ref-id="1100-6531191">like the pot-themed Seth Rogen pack</a>--will carry forward to Black Ops 7 when it releases later this year.</p><p>The Call of Duty series has embraced marijuana for years, with all manner of weed-themed DLC. The legendary stoners <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/new-call-of-duty-dlc-is-all-about-weed-turns-enemies-into-joints/1100-6522734/" data-ref-id="1100-6522734">Cheech and Chong came to Modern Warfare 3</a>, while that game had a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-4-20-event-brings-cheech-and-chong-a-stoned-sloth-and-weed-themed-bundles/1100-6522208/" data-ref-id="1100-6522208">pot-smoking sloth bundle</a>, too. Black Ops 6, meanwhile, added a special <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cods-iconic-nuketown-map-gets-a-4-20-makeover-soon-in-black-ops-6/1100-6530460/" data-ref-id="1100-6530460">4/20-themed Nuketown map called Blazetown.</a></p><p>Beyond the weed stuff, the ESRB description for Black Ops 7 confirms an M rating for the game for its "blood and gore, intense violence, strong language, suggestive themes, and use of drugs." The description also states that the campaign story will involve players trying to "prevent a tech titan from gaining power."</p><p>"Battles are realistic and frenetic, highlighted by gunfire, cries of pain, and blood-splatter effects. Some levels allow players to engage in execution moves/sequences (e.g., repeatedly stabbing a foe in the chest, throat, torso). Some weapons cause characters to explode into bloody chunks of flesh," the description says.</p><p>Black Ops 7 is developed by Treyarch and Raven Software, the two main co-developers of 2024's Black Ops 6. This is the first time Activision is releasing new Black Ops games in consecutive years. The <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-reveal-set-for-gamescom-in-august/1100-6533147/" data-ref-id="1100-6533147">global reveal for Black Ops 7 will take place at Gamescom in August</a>, and this <a href="https://x.com/TheGhostOfHope/status/1945137697418359215" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">could be followed by the Call of Duty Next event in September.</a></p><p>As for the competitor Battlefield series, it's been reported that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/heres-when-battlefield-6-could-be-revealed-and-its-soon/1100-6533290/" data-ref-id="1100-6533290">EA and DICE will reveal Battlefield 6 on July 31.</a></p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cod-black-ops-7-continues-franchises-obsession-with-weed/1100-6533294/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Atari 50 Is Getting Yet Another DLC Pack, This Time Focused On Namco Titles]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/07/atari-50-is-getting-yet-another-dlc-pack-this-time-focused-on-namco-titles</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/atari-50-is-getting-yet-another-dlc-pack-this-time-focused-on-namco-titles.1248736/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>The Pac is Back</p>
</section></header><section>

<p><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/atari_50_the_anniversary_celebration">Atari 50: The Anniversary Celebration</a> is getting another DLC expansion in the form of '<strong>The Namco Legendary Pack DLC</strong>'.</p>
<p>No release date has been set at the time of writing, but the new DLC will contain an additional timeline looking at Namco's history with Atari, along with multiple playable versions of <strong>Atari PAC-MAN</strong>, <strong>GALAGA</strong>, <strong>GALAXIAN</strong>, <strong>DIG DUG</strong>, and <strong>XEVIOUS</strong>.</p>
<p>You can expect a whole load of new photos, archival material, videos, and interviews, with the trailer highlighting more footage from the interview between Atari's co-founder Nolan Bushnell and current CEO Wade Rosen.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>- 3 Atari PAC-MAN games: PAC-MAN 2600, 5200, and Atari 8-bit. This marks the first ever re-release of these games for consoles.</p>
<p>- Interactive timeline exploring the history of Namco titles on Atari consoles featuring video interviews with developers, archival materials and documents, photos from the era, and more.</p>
<p>- The U.S. arcade versions of DIG DUG and XEVIOUS, developed by Namco in Japan and originally released by Atari, re-released in this form for the first time ever.</p>
<p>- Home console versions of GALAGA, XEVIOUS, GALAXIAN, and DIG DUG.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>That's not all, though. For the Atari enthusiasts out there, the company has also announced an <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TP3JZ1RMdEA">Atari 2600+ Pac-Man Edition</a>, featuring a custom design based on the Pac-Man IP with a bonus double-feature game including the brand-new Pac-Man 7800 and the original Pac-Man 2600.</p>
<p>The cartridge will also be made available separately, or via a new '<a href="https://atari.com/products/high-score-collection-7800">High-Score Collection set</a>', which includes all aforementioned games for either the Atari 2600+ or Atari 7800+ (or, indeed, the original 7800).</p>
<p>Atari 50 has already been expanded with two additional DLC packs; one looking at 'The Wider World of Atari', and the other looking at 'The First Console War'.</p>
<figure><a title="Atari 2600+ Pac-Man Edition" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/0221ca5bbfcc4/atari-2600plus-pac-man-edition.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Atari</em></figcaption></figure>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-articles:168283,172612,174244 @ 1753109131 -->
<p><em>Will you be checking out the new Atari 50 DLC on Switch? Let us know your thoughts with a comment.</em></p></section></article><div><p>Nintendo Life’s resident horror fanatic, when he’s not knee-deep in Resident Evil and Silent Hill lore, Ollie likes to dive into a good horror book while nursing a lovely cup of tea. He also enjoys long walks and listens to everything from TOOL to Chuck Berry.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Olliemar28"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/ollie-nl.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Olliemar28');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/07/atari-50-is-getting-yet-another-dlc-pack-this-time-focused-on-namco-titles]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dying Light: The Beast Final Hands-On (PC) Preview]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/dying-light-the-beast-final-hands-on-pc-preview/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dying-light-the-beast-final-hands-on-pc-preview.1248734/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>As part of a world tour leading up to the launch of their latest entry in the zombie survival/parkour action series, Techland recently invited Wccftech and a small number of other content creators and journalists out to California to go hands-on with the opening hours of Dying Light: The Beast.</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>While our earlier preview was focused on the protagonist Kyle Crane coming to terms with his newfound Beast powers, this session was more intimate, instead centered around the opening hours of the adventure in Castor Peaks (minus the introductory moments where Kyle breaks free from his decade-long captivity). You could consider these where Kyle Crane slowly gets his groove back, returning to the freerunning zombie slayer he once was.</p>



<p>Castor Peaks represents a much needed change in scenery from the concrete jungles of prior Dying Light games. While there are still scattered settlements with tightly clustered buildings to parkour across, much of the landscape is filled with nature and untouched areas free from human influence. Given Castor Peaks’ status as a nature conservation, this fits the setting and builds out the world into more of a playground where Kyle Crane can let his inner beast truly run wild.&nbsp;</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>Given that Dying Light: The Beast carries off a decade from the original Dying Light, there has clearly been the passage of time where the protagonist wasn’t working on his wallclimbing or hammer throwing. In proper open-world gameplay fashion, this leads the player into a series of tutorial segments meant to both onboard the player and return Kyle Crane back to fighting condition. This means the usual gamut of learning how to wield a melee weapon as well as where and how to climb around the environment. White paint splashed across ledges and open windows serve as pathways for the player to traverse and thankfully they blend well enough into the backdrop of Castor Peaks that one might not even notice they’re present unless actively looking for them.</p>



<p>Dying Light: The Beast’s parkour system still takes some getting used to the intricate jankiness to truly appreciate. While it’s true that Kyle Crane can climb up and mantle over just about anything with a flat surface, some of the more puzzling sections can be an exercise in patience. Rather than moving and clamboring at the speed I’d want to move, sometimes I found myself needing to stop and look over at the ledge I wanted to mantle over to and wait for Kyle to stretch his arm out and indicate that he was locked onto the ledge and by jumping, he would automatically reach for it. There were a number of high stakes moments where the sense of urgency was pulled back by needing to wait for the precision to climb above. Given that Dying Light: The Beast is still an RPG at its core with a robust skill tree, I anticipate seeing some new abilities pop up that will mitigate my concerns with the traversal.</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>At the same time, combat is the other key pillar to what makes the Dying Light series. Played out entirely in first-person (minus the third-person cutscenes and menus), players will experience the visceral combat through the eyes of Kyle Crane. Whether wielding a one- or two-handed weapon or firearm, zombies are constantly on the move for the protagonist’s flesh and won’t stop until their head is knocked clean off. Dying Light: The Beast features an overhauled dismemberment system and there is a gratuitous amount of gore as Kyle swings away with any implement he can get his hands on. And yes, once again, weapon durability is a constant stuggle to maintain but now that Kyle Crane has been around an apocalypse or two before, he’s skilled enough to repair his weapons on the go with a fair bit of scrap metal and other materials he’s scavenged up. No more having to trade out broken pipes every 90 seconds just because you tried to take on an entire zombie horde instead of taking the high road to run away.</p>


<figure>
<div>

<figure>
<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>
</figure>
<div>
			    		
			    		
				    	<p><span>2 of 9</span>
			    	</p></div>
</div>
</figure>



<p>As this session of Dying Light: The Beast was focused on the early hours of Kyle Crane’s revenge story, many of the more interesting upgrades and Beast powers were locked away for players to rediscover. One thing’s for certain though: years of captivity have turned Kyle Crane into a raging beast.</p>



<p>Dying Light: The Beast will launch on August 22nd, 2025 for PlayStation 5, Xbox Series S|X and PC for $59.99/$69.99 or as a free standalone DLC for those who purchased the Ultimate Edition of Dying Light 2.</p>



<p><em>[Editor’s Note: Travel and accommodations were provided by Techland to attend their preview event in Los Angeles, CA.]</em></p>





			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/dying-light-the-beast-final-hands-on-pc-preview/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dying Light: The Beast Preview - The Return Of Crane]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/features/dying-light-beast-preview-return-of-crane</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dying-light-the-beast-preview-the-return-of-crane.1248732/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>The <a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="224ada69-abcb-4bde-8ebc-1cd2a0b91343" href="https://techraptor.net/games/dying-light-2-stay-human" rel="nofollow"><em>Dying Light</em></a> series has always held a special place in the zombie genre. After all, it was one of the first, if not the first, to implement parkour and make it a vital part of surviving. Thankfully, <em>Dying Light: The Beast</em> follows the same formula that fans have come to expect while building upon the game's overall story. Ahead of the game's launch, Tech Raptor was recently invited to a hands-on preview event where we got to play a little over four hours of the upcoming game.</p>

<p>Interestingly, <em>Dying Light: The Beast</em> breaks the trend of playing as a new character. Instead, players are once again in the boots of Kyle Crane, the protagonist of the first <a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="ca6b8cd3-8473-4246-ba44-281fcce108ac" href="https://techraptor.net/games/dying-light-bad-blood" rel="nofollow"><em>Dying Light</em></a>. But things are a bit different this time around. Due to a series of experiments on him, Crane now has superhuman-like abilities called Beast Mode that allow him to murder anything around him easily. The only way to activate it was by building a bar that would only fill when you attacked someone. If timed right, Beast Mode can help out in the heat of battle.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/dying-light_-the-beast-screenshot-10.jpg?itok=bNFrlgkd 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/dying-light_-the-beast-screenshot-10.jpg?itok=dXWvRq8O 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>This takes Beast Mode to a whole new meaning.</figcaption></figure><p>My demo opened up with Crane running through the woods into a mansion. I noticed early on that The Beast does a great job of blending Urban environments with Nature. There'll be a lot of times where you'll find yourself running through the woods and have nothing to climb onto or jump on. This was a new direction to take the series because, in previous titles, you always had some kind of roof or ledge from which you could jump when needed.</p>

<p>At first, this may not sound like a good idea on paper, but it adds an extra layer of fear in the game. Because in many ways, you're now exposed, and it requires you to think quickly, if not, you run the risk of getting swarmed by a horde of zombies. To combat this, Techland introduced 4x4 trucks that you can drive in certain map regions. Admittedly, though I found myself avoiding cars because of how unreliable they can be, because of how it can get stuck in ditches or in a street filled with abandoned cars, running around proved to be the better method nine times out of ten.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/dying-light_-the-beast-screenshot-12-1.jpg?itok=8Quo17_K 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/dying-light_-the-beast-screenshot-12-1.jpg?itok=Kwz4tieN 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Nothing like the great outdoors... and zombies.</figcaption></figure><p>Once I entered the mansion and fought through a small group of zombies, I was immediately ambushed by a larger-than-life zombie called Chimera. These are essentially lab-created super zombies that are in Beast Mode 24/7.</p>

<p>Throughout my demo, I fought a small handful of Chimera, and each had its own unique fight. Despite that, they all shared a few common traits. Like Souls-like games, each boss has a second phase, and once you get to it, their moveset would drastically change, and throughout the fight, they would eventually call for backup, and you'd be forced to fight regular zombies while dealing with trying not to get killed by the boss.</p>

<p>As fun and engaging as these fights were, they all handicapped themselves because of how beefy the bosses were. A lot of the time, it felt as if my hits weren't doing too much damage, and this caused nearly all of the fights to drag on longer than I would have liked.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/dying-light_-the-beast-screenshot-20.jpg?itok=WkYkA_tT 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/dying-light_-the-beast-screenshot-20.jpg?itok=U5poB19t 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>These zombies are about to catch these hands.</figcaption></figure><p>Another thing worth pointing out is some of the tropes implemented in <em>Dying Light: The Beast</em>. As I progressed through the story, I was eventually greeted by a woman who betrayed the game's main antagonist. The issue that stood out to me was that it followed an old 2000s trope of having an attractive blonde woman help this dark and broody man through the powers of science, because she couldn't defend or accomplish what she wanted to do herself. It felt odd then and odd now to see such dated clichés being played out again in 2025. But that's where a lot of my complaints begin and end.</p>

<p>Although many of the story beats I got were extremely limited to the small section I was playing, it offered an interesting twist. In short, Crane is looking to get revenge on the man who experimented on him, and to do this, he has to gain the trust of local survivors to ensure he'll have enough manpower to do so. But that wasn't the part that stood out to me. The Beast makes it clear that the big bad of this game is, by all accounts, a monster and someone who lost their humanity in hopes of gaining power. But to take him down, Crane has to become a monster himself, literally.</p>

<p>This is done by mixing his DNA with the dead Chimeras you kill along the way. This proposed a unique question: "How much of yourself can you sell, before you lose your humanity?" Obviously, this question wasn't answered in the few hours I played, but it left me wondering how the bigger picture would unfold.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/dying-light_-the-beast-screenshot-16.jpg?itok=8TFALs55 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/dying-light_-the-beast-screenshot-16.jpg?itok=gDJI6oDO 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Am I a man... Or am I a monster?</figcaption></figure><p>One thing that caught me off guard was the improved combat system. Sure, shooting a bow and gun feels good, but at its core, <em>Dying Light</em> has always been a guerrilla survival game in the sense that just about anything can be a melee weapon. In <em>Dying Light: The Beast</em>, swinging a weapon around feels a lot more authentic. Seeing the difference in animations between lighting one-handed blades and two-handed hammers was something I appreciated, even more so when I found myself in tight environments, because this forced my character to use these in unique ways that still felt realistic.</p>

<p>In keeping things realistic, The Beast didn't shy away from the gore this time. As I was hacking and slashing through zombies, I immediately saw the effects my weapons were having. For example, every time I would hit a zombie in the face, I would see their flesh and skull open more and more with each hit. Or if I went for a gut attack, their intestines would come flying out.</p>

<p>The nice cherry on top of this was how precise arm attacks would be. I found myself testing how accurate it was. If I used a blade and swung at the hand only, the hand would fall off, but if I hit the elbow, then the bottom half of the arm would fall off. This nice attention to detail helps sell how grim and dark the world of <em>Dying Light</em> is.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/dying-light_-the-beast-screenshot-08.jpg?itok=T6lGITMx 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/dying-light_-the-beast-screenshot-08.jpg?itok=jEQU-Zia 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Hack and slash.</figcaption></figure><p>Of course, some of <em>Dying Light's</em> core parts are the parkour and Day and Night systems. I'm happy to report that both are as fun and engaging as ever. Like the other Dyling Light games, the world still feels like a massive sandbox. This makes running from rooftop to rooftop even more fun because the game encourages you to run around and find hidden paths that make getting around much easier.</p>

<p>When night hits, the rules of the game are flipped once again. Although it's still possible to be aggressive and hunt down zombies, it's not the best idea. This is mainly because this is one of the only times Volatiles come out, and fighting them is never an easy task. But what's interesting is if you happen to get spotted by one, it'll create a unique sequence that lets you know how many Volatiles are actively trying to kill you. If you have a Volatile chasing you, more will appear, and the hunt for you will be even more challenging to survive.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/dying-light_-the-beast-screenshot-17.jpg?itok=vx4QnnF2 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/dying-light_-the-beast-screenshot-17.jpg?itok=EzVAh6ey 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Can you survivethe night?</figcaption></figure><p>Overall, my time with <em>Dying Light: The Beast</em> was fun. If you've played any of the games, you can pick up a controller and understand it almost instantly. Although it feels similar to the first two <em>Dying Light</em> games, it captures the charm of what makes them so enjoyable while improving many core features that help take the game in a new direction. <em>Dying Light: The Beast</em> will be released on August 22 and will be playable on PC, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series X|S.</p>


</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Luis Gutierrez is a journalist who's worked with various outlets, including IGN, GameSpot, Kotaku, and many more. He has a degree in journalism and loves… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/luis-gutierrez">More about Luis</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/features/dying-light-beast-preview-return-of-crane]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Chinese Room Splits from Sumo Group in Management Buyout]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/the-chinese-room-management-buyout</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-chinese-room-splits-from-sumo-group-in-management-buyout.1248730/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Vampire: The Masquerade - Bloodlines 2&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>Still Wakes the Deep&nbsp;</em>developer The Chinese Room has announced that it's splitting from parent company Sumo Group, following layoffs at the latter earlier this year.</p>

<p>As spotted by <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/still-wakes-the-deep-studio-the-chinese-room-announces-management-buyout-gaining-independence-from-sumo-digital" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">IGN</a>, the British studio's management has bought the studio in order to make it independent. Prior to the buyout, The Chinese Room's future had been uncertain; in February, Sumo Group said it would <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/sumo-group-layoffs-refocus" rel="nofollow">focus more on "development services for partners"</a> rather than original work, although the aforementioned&nbsp;<em>Bloodlines 2&nbsp;</em>would come under that heading.</p>

<p>The Chinese Room says that its sale to a third party was looking "increasingly likely" before the buyout, and that becoming independent will not only allow it to "work on new, original intellectual property", but also to "partner with other studios on other projects when they fit in with [the studio's] vision".</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/vampire-the-masquerade-bloodlines-2-the-chinese-room.jpg?itok=4nvtcGzZ 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/vampire-the-masquerade-bloodlines-2-the-chinese-room.jpg?itok=19BVgUmW 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>The Chinese Room is working on&nbsp;<em>Vampire: The Masquerade - Bloodlines 2</em>.</figcaption></figure><p>According to IGN's report, The Chinese Room is now working on two brand new IPs, but before those see the light of day, the studio will be releasing the long-awaited&nbsp;<em>Vampire: The Masquerade - Bloodlines 2&nbsp;</em>later this year.</p>

<p>Back in March, the game was <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/vampire-masquerade-bloodlines-2-delayed-october-2025" rel="nofollow">once again delayed</a>, this time to October. It's been <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/vampire-masquerade-bloodlines-2-delayed-yet-again" rel="nofollow">delayed</a> a number of times <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/vampire-masquerade-bloodlines-2-delayed-indefinitely" rel="nofollow">before</a>, but given that The Chinese Room was only announced as the game's developer <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/vampire-masquerade-bloodlines-2-is-back-developed-by-chinese-room" rel="nofollow">back in September 2023</a>, it's entirely possible a lot of the earlier work on the game was thrown out when that development change happened.</p>

<p>In the interim, however, The Chinese Room hasn't been resting on its laurels. Earlier this year, the studio released a paid DLC pack for its narrative horror game&nbsp;<em>Still Wakes the Deep</em>, which was <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/chinese-room-still-wakes-the-deep-release-date" rel="nofollow">released in June last year</a>.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/the-chinese-room-management-buyout-still-wakes-the-deep.jpg?itok=1tWQJUJK 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/the-chinese-room-management-buyout-still-wakes-the-deep.jpg?itok=gSs8yZqV 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Still Wakes the Deep&nbsp;</em>got itself a DLC pack earlier this year.</figcaption></figure><p>We'll have to wait and see what The Chinese Room will do now that it's independent from Sumo Group, but for now, the buyout doesn't seem to have changed the studio's plans for the immediate future. Stay tuned for more.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/the-chinese-room-management-buyout]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How 28 Days Later, Stranger Things, and Pac Man influenced Dying Light: The Beast]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/interviews/how-28-days-later-stranger-things-and-pac-man-influenced-dying-light-beast</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/how-28-days-later-stranger-things-and-pac-man-influenced-dying-light-the-beast.1248728/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Ahead of <em>Dying Light: The Beast</em>, TechRaptor was invited to a hands-on preview where we played the game for a handful of hours. On top of hacking and slashing the army of the dead, we also got to sit down and chat with Tymon Smektala, the franchise director for the <em><a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="224ada69-abcb-4bde-8ebc-1cd2a0b91343" href="https://techraptor.net/games/dying-light-2-stay-human" rel="nofollow">Dying Light</a></em> series, about where the team draws inspiration from and where the series can go from here.</p>

<p>One of the most significant changes about <em>The Beast</em> in comparison to previous games is that a large portion of the game takes place in the woods, where there are few to no areas for players to use parkour to help them get out of a tricky situation. Smektala explains that they wanted to try this out and see if they could take the series to a new location and still feel authentic.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/bober-the-beaver-screenshot-4.jpg?itok=cDiOMGjk 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/bober-the-beaver-screenshot-4.jpg?itok=h6cdHukz 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Go and touch some grass.</figcaption></figure><p>"We wanted to see if we could have a <em>Dying Light</em> game where we could [occasionally] take away parkour. What we discovered is that it works very well for us because, in a way, parkour is a survival mechanic. You can use it to get away quickly. [Taking away parkour] even adds to the survival aspect because suddenly you feel more exposed and fragile against threats. It adds a lot of tension," Smektala said.</p>

<p>Many survival-horror games involve players running for their lives, but the latest installment of <em>Dying Light</em> introduces a new mechanic called "Beast Mode." In short, this makes you an unstoppable force of nature that can kill just about everything in your path. Smektala told TechRaptor that this was implemented so they could give players a fighting chance when they find themselves overwhelmed by zombies. The idea of having this second wind stemmed from an unlikely game… <em><a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="bcdf3e0e-b246-4766-a64d-4a145078a64f" href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/shadow-labyrinth-preview-pax-east-2025" rel="nofollow">Pac-Man</a></em>.</p>

<p>"It's kind of the same setup. You feel very fragile because when the ghosts are chasing you, all they need to do is touch you, and you'll die. But when you grab the power pellet, that's when you turn the tables. [Beast Mode] is the same mechanic, and in <em>Pac-Man</em>, the uncertainty of not knowing if you'd reach the power pellet adds to the excitement like in <em>Dying Light: The Beast</em>," Smektala said.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/dying-light_-the-beast-screenshot-10_0.jpg?itok=u7FiIdsl 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/dying-light_-the-beast-screenshot-10_0.jpg?itok=JYbWRXAz 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Time to eat some Power Pellets.</figcaption></figure><p>As mentioned in our recent preview, a prominent theme of <em>The Beast</em> is the main character literally becoming a beast to stop someone who's metaphorically a beast. This idea largely stemmed from a Korean film called <em>Old Boy</em>.</p>

<p>The film explores similar themes and shares similar story beats of a person being captured for years, and once they escape, they set out to kill everyone who has wronged them. But <em>Old Boy</em> wasn't the only piece of media that helped inspire <em>Dying Light: The Beast</em>. Smektala went on to cite shows such as <em>Twin Peaks</em> and <em><a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="e5de03d1-d8cd-419d-8918-561c018bd3c0" href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/interview/liches-vecna-and-stranger-things-our-time-with-chris-perkins" rel="nofollow">Stranger Things</a> </em>as also playing a huge role in setting the narrative location for the upcoming game.</p>

<p>"Both take place in those little towns, where they are [cut off from] the outside world, and the outside world doesn't matter," he said. "It all happens within this town, and a lot of very weird and strange things transpire."</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/dying-light_-the-beast-screenshot-14.jpg?itok=wB3qR7F1 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/dying-light_-the-beast-screenshot-14.jpg?itok=V-NPwWbJ 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Parkour!</figcaption></figure><p>Zombie fans may quickly notice how much the game draws inspiration from the <em>28 </em>movie trilogy. This can be seen in the music, scenery, and chases players encounter. When asked if the team used the movie series as a point of reference, Smektala said that Techland views <em>Dying Light</em> as "[one of the] top games in the zombie genre." But the <em>28 </em>series has been a big inspiration for Techland, and he discussed how both series have gone down similar paths.</p>

<p>"All of those movies try to do something different. If you compare <em>28 Days Later </em>and <em>28 Weeks Later</em>, they are completely different movies. Again, <em>28 Years Later</em> is very different when compared to the first two," Smektala said. "What happens in those movies is very similar to what we are doing with <em>Dying Light</em>. <em>28 Days Later</em> was a very intimate movie with mostly one character in a very empty space, where he was feeling weak against zombies. This was a similar feeling to the early hours of <em>Dying Light 1</em>.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/dying-light_-the-beast-screenshot-05.jpg?itok=C5rC4OyL 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/dying-light_-the-beast-screenshot-05.jpg?itok=TrwvJAuc 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Fight the dead, fear the living.</figcaption></figure><p>"When you look at <em>28 Weeks Later</em>, it's much more focused on action. With people in big action sequences, people shooting guns, and a lot more blockbuster moments. This is the same with <em><a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="224ada69-abcb-4bde-8ebc-1cd2a0b91343" href="https://techraptor.net/games/dying-light-2-stay-human" rel="nofollow">Dying Light 2 Stay Human</a></em>. This was our action game; it was focused on big moments. Now, <em>28 Years Later</em>, is a different story that is similar to <em>The Beast</em>, because it's very experimental in a way. A lot of weird things are happening in <em>28 Years Later</em>, as in <em>The Beast</em>."</p>

<p>Speaking of a lot of weird things happening, <em>Dying Light: The Beast</em> introduces a new zombie variant called Chimeras. Smektala said that introducing a new zombie variant can always be difficult because they don't want to lean too far out of the world of realism. So the Chimeras came from the idea of "something that could have happened if you applied proper science to it." That's where a lot of the visual inspiration came into play.</p>

<p>"When it comes to the design of the Chimeras, two main sources of inspiration are anatomy books. The second one is an anime series called <em><a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="fa17d54b-1887-4176-82c7-9f626553cc5f" href="https://techraptor.net/games/attack-on-titan-2" rel="nofollow">Attack on Titan</a></em>, which has those types of monsters that are skinless with all of their bodies exposed. That informed the visual designs for the Chimera," he said.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/dying-light_-the-beast-screenshot-20_0.jpg?itok=v88fsavZ 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/dying-light_-the-beast-screenshot-20_0.jpg?itok=_rNtwCqj 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Chimera or Titan?</figcaption></figure><p>One final piece of information that long-time franchise fans may be excited to hear is that <em>The Beast</em> is supposed to set the canon for the franchise going forward, and it takes place after the first two installments. This is notable because every <em>Dying Light</em> game has multiple endings, and it's left up to the player to decide what ending they want. But according to Smektala, <em>The Beast</em> will have one ending because the team wanted "to set the canon for the universe."</p>

<p>Smektala even teased that The Beast's ending will "answer several questions from both the first and second game." <em>Dying Light: The Beast</em> will release on August 22 and will be playable on PC, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series X|S.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Luis Gutierrez is a journalist who's worked with various outlets, including IGN, GameSpot, Kotaku, and many more. He has a degree in journalism and loves… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/luis-gutierrez">More about Luis</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/interviews/how-28-days-later-stranger-things-and-pac-man-influenced-dying-light-beast]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[5 Things We Just Learned About The Future Of Warframe]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/warframe-soulsframe-switch-2-tau-trailer-tennocon-2025-1851786622</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/5-things-we-just-learned-about-the-future-of-warframe.1248722/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Now in it’s 12th year, the free-t0-play loot shooter <em>Warframe</em> is still going strong and the future looks bright coming off a whirlwind series of announcements and teases from TennoCon 2025. The multi-day event included details on new story expansions, new frames, and access to an alpha build for Digital Extremes’ fantasy spin-off, <em>Soulframe</em>. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="197565" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Nintendo Switch 2 Could Launch With Almost No Reviews" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="122" data-playlist="197565,197567,196181" data-current="197565"><div><p>Nintendo Switch 2 Could Launch With Almost No Reviews</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197565/197565_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197565/197565_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197565/197565_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/23089.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>There was also an update on <em>Warframe</em> for mobile, which is getting a <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.warframe.com/android&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.warframe.com/android" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">closed beta this fall</a></span>, and of course every new <em>Warframe</em> expansion gets a new kick-ass song, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yPKo04oNQ9k&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yPKo04oNQ9k" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">this year’s included</a></span>. Here are the five biggest takeaways from the annual fan extravaganza. </p><h2 id="h418558"><a id=""></a>Unannounced fall 2025 update will finally explain <em>Warframe</em>’s convoluted mod process to new players</h2><figure id="" data-id="3c4a6e9f04dc9b517f81e72144eddf53" data-recommend-id="image://3c4a6e9f04dc9b517f81e72144eddf53" data-format="png" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Warframes appear in art for the fall season. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Warframes appear in art for the fall season. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Digital Extremes</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="3c4a6e9f04dc9b517f81e72144eddf53" data-recommend-id="image://3c4a6e9f04dc9b517f81e72144eddf53" data-format="png" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Warframes appear in art for the fall season. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p><em>Warframe</em>, like <em>Destiny</em>, is practically ancient by modern live-service gaming standards now, and it has acquired a number of systems that have become second nature to ongoing players but inscrutable to newcomers. One of those is the mod system, which features a lot of customization and crafting. </p><p>While Digital Extremes hasn’t dished on what its big fall update will include (more info is coming in a devstream on September 25), we do know it will have a new quest called Teacher that will onboard players to the game’s most important buildcrafting tool. Hopefully it’s a good onramp for everyone still looking for one. </p><h2 id="h418559"><a id=""></a>The next story chapter is called<em> The Old Peace</em></h2><p><em>Warframe</em>’s next expansion drops near the end of 2025 and will take players into the past to witness the game’s “most tectonic historical event,” known as “The Old War.” It’ll feature a visual overhaul to player controlled Tenno Operators and WWI-inspired trench warfare. </p><p>It’ll include a playable Excalibur Prime for one of the quests, Caliban Prime, new Sentient allies and enemies, the devil-inspired Warframe Uriel, and two new Protoframes. Most importantly, it’ll set the stage for something the game has never done before.</p><h2 id="h418560"><a id=""></a>2026 will takes players to the distant Tau star system</h2><p>Following the events of <em>The Old Peace</em>, players will, for the first time in Warframe’s history, be taken to the new Tau star system. It was a target for colonization within the game’s fiction long ago, with self-replicating terraforming machines called Sentients tasked with preparing Tau for inhabitation. What will await players there next year is anybody’s guess. </p><h2 id="h418561"><a id=""></a><em>Soulframe</em> is still years away but fans went hands-on with an early test build called <em>Preludes</em></h2><p>In addition to continuing <em>Warframe</em>’s legacy, Digital Extremes has also been busy with the fantasy-based spin-off <em>Soulframe</em>. An extended demo during TennoCon 2025 showed character customization and a player tracking a monster through the woods, using a combination of melee weapons, archer, and spells to survive various woodland threats. While fans were able to try out the pre-alpha <em>Preludes</em> build over the weekend, a lasting free demo sounds a bit farther away. </p><p>Will the game be ready before the end of 2025? That’s sounding less and less likely.  “It’s an aspirational goal,” community manager Sarah Asselin told fans during a Q&amp;A <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.eurogamer.net/soulframe-alpha-prelude-access-2025-delay-2026&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/soulframe-alpha-prelude-access-2025-delay-2026" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">over the weekend</a></span>. “We’re looking at where we’re at by the end of the year, but we want to feel confident that we’ve built<em> Soulframe</em> out to the point where it feels good to do so, for the players and the developers.” </p><h2 id="h418562"><a id=""></a><em>Warframe</em>’s devs would love to make a Switch 2 version but still haven’t received a dev kit from Nintendo</h2><figure id="" data-id="eaf5981b80d6f1aaf29bba3e598ac81e" data-recommend-id="image://eaf5981b80d6f1aaf29bba3e598ac81e" data-format="png" data-width="1186" data-height="669" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Warframe characters appear on a Switch 2. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Warframe characters appear on a Switch 2. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Nintendo / Digital Extremes / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="eaf5981b80d6f1aaf29bba3e598ac81e" data-recommend-id="image://eaf5981b80d6f1aaf29bba3e598ac81e" data-format="png" data-width="1186" data-height="669" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Warframe characters appear on a Switch 2. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p><em>Fortnite</em>,<em> No Man’s Sky</em>, and other Switch 1 ports have started receiving upgrades for Switch 2. Will <em>Warframe</em>, which could certainly benefit from better performance on Nintendo’s handheld hybrid device, be getting a similar treatment? Not until Nintendo gives Digital Extremes a Switch 2 dev kit, apparently. Like lots of other big third-party developers, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/NintendoSwitch2/comments/1kbl11o/official_source_nintendo_switch_2_dev_kits_are/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/NintendoSwitch2/comments/1kbl11o/official_source_nintendo_switch_2_dev_kits_are/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">it’s still waiting for the hardware</a></span>. </p><p> “Our tech team is so excited to take advantage of the high-speed cores and the other really cool features of it,” CEO Steve Sinclair said <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.ign.com/articles/tennocon-2025-everything-revealed&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/tennocon-2025-everything-revealed" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">during a Q&amp;A</a></span>. “There’s just such a backlog for dev kits. So, yeah, if you know anyone…just one, that’s all it would take. I know our programmers are just, like, ‘Oh, I can’t wait.’ We definitely have plans. When we get a dev kit, we will be doing a custom build for <em>Warframe</em>. Absolutely.” </p><p>We’ll see what ends up coming out first: <em>Warframe</em>’s Switch 2 upgrade or <em>Soulframe</em>. </p><p>.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/warframe-soulsframe-switch-2-tau-trailer-tennocon-2025-1851786622]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[There Are Plans For Switch 2 Edition Of Warframe, But One Big Issue Is Holding It Up]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/there-are-plans-for-switch-2-edition-of-warframe-but-one-big-issue-is-holding-it-up/1100-6533295/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/there-are-plans-for-switch-2-edition-of-warframe-but-one-big-issue-is-holding-it-up.1248716/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6533295">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">Warframe developer Digital Extremes "is so excited" to build a Switch 2 version of the free-to-play game, but that's impossible without dev kits. So far, the studio hasn't received any, noting a "backlog" for the devices.</p><p dir="ltr">Speaking to <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/warframe-studio-would-love-to-do-a-proper-switch-2-version-but-its-still-waiting-on-a-dev-kit-so-if-you-know-anyone" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Eurogamer</a>, Digital Extremes CEO Steve Sinclair talked about the team's desire to create a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/every-game-getting-switch-2-edition-enhanced-versions/2900-6398/#1">Switch 2 edition</a> of Warframe. "Our tech team is so excited to take advantage of the [Switch 2's] high-speed cores and the other really cool features of it, [but] there's just such a backlog for dev kits," Sinclair said.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="321667567" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6466121,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Nintendo%20Switch%202%20Console%20Review&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:904,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/nintendo-switch-2-console-review\/2300-6466121\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466121\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466121\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466121\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6466121&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6466121,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6533295&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;warframe&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;3d,action,shooter,third-person&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;pc,playstation-4,xbox-one,nintendo-switch,playstation-5,xbox-series-x,ios-iphoneipad,nintendo-switch-2&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;digital-extremes&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6466121},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6466121\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;GameSpot&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1565\/15650751\/4513820-site.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/htxhuu6a.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1749856800,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="htxhuu6a" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> Nintendo Switch 2 Console Review</p>
      </div>
<p dir="ltr">Sinclair added that "we definitely have plans" for Warframe on Switch 2, and it'll be a custom build of the online action-RPG. The game is playable on <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/is-the-nintendo-switch-2-backwards-compatible/1100-6527615/">Nintendo's new hybrid console thanks to backward compatibility</a>. While it originally launched in 2013, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/warframe-out-now-on-nintendo-switch-an-impressive-/1100-6463299/">Warframe came to Switch</a> in late 2018.</p><p dir="ltr">This follows a report from last week stating that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/lack-of-switch-2-dev-kits-could-explain-limited-third-party-game-announcements-report/1100-6533186/">the lack of Switch 2 dev kits is limiting third-party game announcements</a> for the system. Supposedly even bigger companies like Capcom and Sega are still waiting for more access to the devices, too.</p><p dir="ltr">Even after a decade, Warframe is still one of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/best-free-games/2900-5406/">the 25 best free games to play</a>. Additionally, it was <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/top-10-gaming-franchises-of-2024-according-to-fandom/2900-6075/#1">one of the top 10 gaming franchises last year</a>, according to GameSpot parent company Fandom. Digital Extremes is also working on <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/soulframes-incredible-world-is-built-in-part-from-scottish-slang-and-ancient-bear-mythology/1100-6533287/">Soulframe, a free-to-play, open-world multiplayer RPG</a> with a fantasy setting.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/there-are-plans-for-switch-2-edition-of-warframe-but-one-big-issue-is-holding-it-up/1100-6533295/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[From Banjo to a Star Wars Death Star, fans are having a lot of fun with Donkey Kong Bananza's artist mode]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/from-banjo-to-a-star-wars-death-star-fans-are-having-a-lot-of-fun-with-donkey-kong-bananzas-artist-mode</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/from-banjo-to-a-star-wars-death-star-fans-are-having-a-lot-of-fun-with-donkey-kong-bananzas-artist-mode.1248714/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Nintendo/CucumberExisting729/@AS_12239/Eurogamer</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/donkey-kong-bananza">Donkey Kong Bananza</a> released last week, and has <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/donkey-kong-bananza-climbs-to-top-of-uk-physical-sales-charts-but-still-sells-less-than-half-of-mario-odyssey">proven a popular addition to the Switch 2's library</a>.</p>
<p>But, while the base game itself has been met with plenty of praise, its inclusion of an artist mode has also tickled many peoples' fancy. This mode is somewhat reminiscent of the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/super-mario-64">Super Mario 64</a>'s interactive menu, and lets players sculpt their own creations out of rock by using the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/digitalfoundry-2025-nintendo-switch-2-the-digital-foundry-hardware-review">Switch 2</a>'s mouse controls.</p>
<p>Creations so far have included fellow famous Nintendo faces such as Luigi, as well as carved works showing Banjo of Banjo-Kazooie fame, and even a <a href="https://x.com/michaeljhaley/status/1947011457373335896">Star Wars Death Star</a>. Others have taken things even further, and a little darker, and sculpted DK's crucifixion. </p>

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Donkey Kong Bananza Tips EVERY Player Needs To Know" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8RQbNsuMFz0?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Donkey Kong Bananza Tips EVERY Player Needs To Know</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8RQbNsuMFz0?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/8RQbNsuMFz0?autoplay=1" title="Donkey Kong Bananza Tips EVERY Player Needs To Know">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Donkey Kong Bananza Tips EVERY Player Needs To Know. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8RQbNsuMFz0" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>


<p>Below are some of the best Donkey Kong Bananza creations that we have seen so far. I can confidently say that, despite already sinking hours into Bananza, I am nowhere close to being able to recreate characters with as much skill.</p>
<blockquote data-embed-height="566"><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/donkeykong/comments/1m2rcoq/spent_2_hours_in_dk_artist_mode_on_this_and_it/">spent 2 hours in DK artist mode on this, and it was 100% worth it for this alone</a><br> by<a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/OpraZebb/">u/OpraZebb</a> in<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/donkeykong/">donkeykong</a></blockquote><p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span></p><blockquote data-embed-height="546"><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/donkeykong/comments/1m5h82d/a_lot_of_my_dk_artist_creations/">A lot of my DK artist creations</a><br> by<a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/CucumberExisting729/">u/CucumberExisting729</a> in<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/donkeykong/">donkeykong</a></blockquote><p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span></p><blockquote data-embed-height="546"><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/donkeykong/comments/1m30dhx/did_second_best_nintendo_guy_here/">Did second best nintendo guy here</a><br> by<a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/Chrononaut_X/">u/Chrononaut_X</a> in<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/donkeykong/">donkeykong</a></blockquote><p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span></p><blockquote data-embed-height="546"><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/donkeykong/comments/1m4mitt/i_made_king_boo_in_dk_artist/">I made king boo in dk artist!</a><br> by<a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/CucumberExisting729/">u/CucumberExisting729</a> in<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/donkeykong/">donkeykong</a></blockquote><p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span></p><blockquote data-embed-height="739"><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/donkeykong/comments/1m2q6ll/doh/">D'oh</a><br> by<a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/Quinnafred24/">u/Quinnafred24</a> in<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/donkeykong/">donkeykong</a></blockquote><p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span></p><blockquote data-embed-height="739"><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Metroid/comments/1m2mp6e/samus_sculpture_i_made_in_dk_bananza/">Samus Sculpture I made in DK Bananza!</a><br> by<a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/Familiar-Clothes8116/">u/Familiar-Clothes8116</a> in<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Metroid/">Metroid</a></blockquote><p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span></p><blockquote data-embed-height="546"><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/donkeykong/comments/1m3awp4/i_made_leo_luster_in_dk_artist/">I Made Leo Luster in DK Artist</a><br> by<a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/More_Yellow_3701/">u/More_Yellow_3701</a> in<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/donkeykong/">donkeykong</a></blockquote><p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span></p><blockquote data-embed-height="739"><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/donkeykong/comments/1m1sw8e/the_crucifixion_of_kong/">The Crucifixion of Kong</a><br> by<a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/Mannihorst/">u/Mannihorst</a> in<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/donkeykong/">donkeykong</a></blockquote><p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span></p><div>

<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
 <div>

<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
 <div>

<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<blockquote data-bluesky-cid="bafyreia547c5fzapk47pyevgiuqlauyx6eew3onrmzpgyfsk7jry4ufdqy" data-bluesky-embed-color-mode="system" data-bluesky-uri="at://did:plc:ljlojgkp2z4t2i5hlcgeypqg/app.bsky.feed.post/3lu75l2xfv22h">— KingK (<a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:ljlojgkp2z4t2i5hlcgeypqg?ref_src=embed">@kingklonoa.bsky.social</a>) <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:ljlojgkp2z4t2i5hlcgeypqg/post/3lu75l2xfv22h?ref_src=embed">July 18, 2025 at 1:05 AM</a></blockquote><p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span></p><p>"A brilliant core mechanic and clever design twists make Bananza a delightfully sticky 3D platform adventure topped off with a sweet central character relationship," our Alex wrote <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/donkey-kong-bananza-review">Eurogamer's Donkey Kong Bananza review</a>, awarding Nintendo's newest Switch 2 release four stars.</p>
<p>If you have started playing Donkey Kong Bananza, but need a little steer in the right direction, our Guides team has you covered. Here is <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/best-skills-donkey-kong-bananza">a guide on the best skills in Donkey Kong Bananza to get you started</a>.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/from-banjo-to-a-star-wars-death-star-fans-are-having-a-lot-of-fun-with-donkey-kong-bananzas-artist-mode]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ready or Not Soars Past 1 Million Copies Sold On Console In Four Days, Brings Total Sales Past 10 Million]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/ready-or-not-past-1-million-copies-sold-consoles-10-million-total-copies-sold/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ready-or-not-soars-past-1-million-copies-sold-on-console-in-four-days-brings-total-sales-past-10-million.1248712/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>VOID Interactive's Ready or Not has surpassed 1 million copies sold on consoles, just four days after its console launch, which brings the game's total sales past 10 million, after it hit <a href="https://wccftech.com/ready-or-not-surpasses-9-million-copies-sold-ahead-of-its-console-launch-this-summer/">9 million copies sold on PC earlier this year</a>.</p>



<p>"<em>When we launched Ready or Not on PC, it took about 36 days to reach 1 million units sold. On console, it took about 3.6 days. I’m incredibly proud of the team and what we’ve accomplished together. It’s a huge moment — and one we don’t take for granted,</em>" said developer and publisher VOID Interactive's chief executive officer, Julio Rodriguez, in a press release. "<em>Game reviews are holding strong as we head into our first weekend, and the team is already hard at work ironing out issues and continuously improving the experience. To our players, partners, and everyone who believed in the project — thank you.</em>"</p>



<figure><figcaption>Ready or Not passes 1 million copies sold on consoles. Image credit: VOID Interactive</figcaption></figure>



<p>VOID Interactive's chief operating officer and creative director, Stirling Rank, added, "<em>The response from console players has completely blown us away. Going from the days of excitement from our Early Access trailer blowing up on PC to seeing the community grow globally so much across platforms &nbsp;is humbling, but &nbsp;testament to the incredible dedication of the entire VOID Interactive team to make this vision a reality for Ready or Not.</em>"</p>



<p>While the console launch has quickly been the next chapter of success in Ready or Not's story, it's also been another chapter marked with controversy. The console release came with an <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1144200/view/526472884483263337?l=english">update and changes</a> that some players considered to be censorship, with certain aspects of gore, nudity, and violence changed in both the console and PC versions of the game. VOID Interactive maintains that the changes were "<em>to support stability and align with policies enforced by global platforms and age rating bodies."</em></p>



<p>VOID Interactive has always emphasized that Ready or Not is a "<em>hyper-realistic tactical FPS,"</em> and the changes ranging from victims in one level being nude, to now being partially clothed, to a child no longer appearing as having been dismembered post-mortem seem to clash with what players believed the original vision of the game to be. </p>



<p>While players on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1144200/Ready_or_Not/#app_reviews_hash">Steam have taken to review-bombing</a> the game to show their displeasure, it's clear that this uproar hasn't had an overtly negative impact on sales. If you're also dissatisfied with the changes, a player released a mod that reverts the changes to how the game was pre-console launch just <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ready-or-not-modder-retcons-censorship-changes-within-an-hour-of-new-patch-going-live">20 minutes after the update went live</a>.</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/ready-or-not-past-1-million-copies-sold-consoles-10-million-total-copies-sold/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sony’s 30th Anniversary DualSense Controller is back in stock online at 10AM ET]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/tech/710545/playstation-30th-anniversary-dualsense-controller-restock</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sony%E2%80%99s-30th-anniversary-dualsense-controller-is-back-in-stock-online-at-10am-et.1248710/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="__next"><p><a href="#content"><span>Skip to main content</span></a></p><nav aria-label="Sticky Nav"></nav><div><main id="content"><article><div><div><div><p><span><ul><li><a href="https://www.theverge.com/tech">Tech</a><span> /</span></li><li><a href="https://www.theverge.com/games">Gaming</a><span> /</span></li><li><a href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals">Deals</a></li></ul></span></p></div><div><p>PlayStation Plus subscribers can order today, and preorders for everyone else start on July 23 at 10AM ET.</p></div></div><div><p>PlayStation Plus subscribers can order today, and preorders for everyone else start on July 23 at 10AM ET.</p><div><p><span><time datetime="2025-07-21T12:38:45+00:00">Jul 21, 2025, 12:38 PM UTC</time></span></p></div></div></div><div><div><div><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/brandt-ranj">Brandt Ranj</a> <span><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/brandt-ranj">Brandt Ranj</a> is a commerce reporter for <em>The Verge </em>writing about the best deals and gadgets. He previously wrote for <em>Business Insider, Rolling Stone, </em><em>Futurism, </em>and <em>Popular Science.</em></span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Sony will have a “limited restock” of its 30th Anniversary DualSense Wireless Controller on the <a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=1025X1701640&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fdirect.playstation.com%2Fen-us%2Fbuy-accessories%2Fdualsense-wireless-controller-30th-anniversary-limited-edition" rel="sponsored">PlayStation Direct storefront</a>. The $79.99 gamepad is available for preorder starting July 21st at 10AM ET for PlayStation Plus subscribers and on July 23rd at 10AM ET for everyone else. It will begin shipping on September 9th. If you want to order today, a <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-us/ps-plus/#subscriptions">PlayStation Plus Essential subscription</a> costs $9.99 per month or $79.99 per year.</p><div data-product-filter=""><p><span>$<!-- -->80</span></p><div><p>The 30th Anniversary DualSense Wireless Controller is a fully-functional gamepad with the same colors as the original PlayStation console released in December of 1994.</p></div></div><p>The limited-edition PlayStation 5 controller was released last year to commemorate the launch of the original PlayStation in December of 1994. Its outer shell and buttons feature the same color scheme as Sony’s original console and peripherals, and the “PS” button matches the multicolor logo Sony used at that time. However, it’s a fully functional DualSense Controller, with the same features as a <a rel="sponsored" href="https://www.amazon.com/PlayStation-DualSense%C2%AE-Wireless-Controller-Midnight-5/dp/B0CQKKHT5J?tag=theverge02-20">non-limited edition</a> <a rel="sponsored" href="https://www.amazon.com/PlayStation-DualSense%C2%AE-Wireless-Controller-Midnight-5/dp/B0CQKKHT5J?tag=theverge02-20">gamepad</a>. In addition to the DualSense, the UK and Canadian PlayStation stores are also restocking the 30th Anniversary PlayStation Portal and PS5 Digital Bundle, which were part of <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/9/20/24249600/ps5-pro-30th-anniversary-photos">last year’s campaign</a>.</p><div><form><div><h2>Verge Deals</h2><p><span>Sign up for Verge Deals to get deals on products we’ve tested sent to your inbox weekly.</span></p></div></form></div></div></div><div><form><div><h2>Verge Deals</h2><p><span>Sign up for Verge Deals to get deals on products we’ve tested sent to your inbox weekly.</span></p></div></form></div></div></article></main></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/tech/710545/playstation-30th-anniversary-dualsense-controller-restock]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ready Or Not Console Release Tops 1m Sales Despite 'Censorship' Controversy]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/ready-or-not-console-release-tops-1m-sales-despite-censorship-controversy</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ready-or-not-console-release-tops-1m-sales-despite-censorship-controversy.1248706/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">"It took about 36 days to reach 1 million units sold on PC. On console, it took about 3.6 days."</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/ready-or-not"><u>Ready or Not</u></a>'s console port finally released last week, and it's already surpassed one million sales. Combined with sales of its early access PC version, which released in December 2023, the game has now topped 10 million units sold.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"When we launched Ready or Not on PC, it took about 36 days to reach 1 million units sold," said VOID CEO, Julio Rodriguez. "On console, it took about 3.6 days. I’m incredibly proud of the team and what we’ve accomplished together. It’s a huge moment — and one we don’t take for granted." </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Rodriguez then went on to thank Ready or Not's players and "everyone who believed in the project."  </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ready-or-not-developer-void-interactive-proceeds-with-controversial-censor-changes-to-satisfy-console-makers-despite-fan-blacklash-heres-the-full-patch-notes"><u>Last week</u></a>, July 15, VOID Interactive proceeded with changes introduced to controversial shooter Ready or Not despite widespread condemnation from fans who <a href="https://steamcommunity.com/id/NoRandomAddsPlsThx/recommended/1144200/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>claimed</u></a> the developer was "censoring" the game's gore and violence by "appeasing console market regulators." </p><p data-cy="paragraph">VOID said it had to <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ready-or-not-review-bombed-on-steam-as-pc-players-claim-shooter-was-censored-to-satisfy-console-makers"><u>adjust levels of gore, nudity, violence, and the "mistreatment of children" ahead of console release</u></a>, and rather than "maintaining multiple versions with different assets and mechanics" that would "increase the likelihood of bugs," some aspects of the PC version would also have to be revised. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">At the time, VOID insisted the changes were "small enough that most people here wouldn't notice if we didn't say anything," but it "wanted to be transparent" with its players. Players disagreed, and the news caused Ready or Not's Steam user review rating to <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ready-or-not-dev-releases-before-and-after-screenshots-as-it-battles-against-censorship-backlash-and-steam-review-bomb-campaign"><u>plummet to "mostly negative" for recent reviews</u></a>. Up until the controversy, it had accured a "Mostly Positive" rating. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Within 20 minutes of implementing unpopular changes to Ready or Not, however, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ready-or-not-modder-retcons-censorship-changes-within-an-hour-of-new-patch-going-live"><u>a mod was available to reverse the changes</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Vikki Blake is a reporter for IGN, as well as a critic, columnist, and consultant with 15+ years experience working with some of the world's biggest gaming sites and publications. She's also a Guardian, Spartan, Silent Hillian, Legend, and perpetually High Chaos. Find her at </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vixx.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>BlueSky</em></a><em>.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/ready-or-not-console-release-tops-1m-sales-despite-censorship-controversy]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Deals for Today: Pokémon TCG Black Bolt ETB In Stock For Less and Switch 2 In Stock]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/deals-for-today-july-21</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/deals-for-today-pok%C3%A9mon-tcg-black-bolt-etb-in-stock-for-less-and-switch-2-in-stock.1248704/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Amazon has quietly become one of the best places to pick up Pokémon TCG products this week, with a surprise restock that brings several popular Elite Trainer Boxes closer to MSRP than we’ve seen in months. The best deal right now is the <a href="https://zdcs.link/Q47ZEd?object_uuid=fb8ac615-6810-468a-b321-87fc97ead2a8&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Black Bolt Elite Trainer Box at just $78.75</a>. Throw in the <a href="https://zdcs.link/aMJ0V1?object_uuid=fb8ac615-6810-468a-b321-87fc97ead2a8&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Paradox Rift ETB for under $78</a> and a handful of affordable premium collections like <a href="https://zdcs.link/985dBv?object_uuid=fb8ac615-6810-468a-b321-87fc97ead2a8&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Cynthia’s Garchomp ex</a> and <a href="https://zdcs.link/QbbE1J?object_uuid=fb8ac615-6810-468a-b321-87fc97ead2a8&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Charizard ex</a>.</p><p id="featured-in-this-article"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Featured in this article">TL;DR: Deals For Today</h2></p><p data-cy="paragraph">Beyond cards, today’s best deals span everything from <a href="https://zdcs.link/zJg4Vl?object_uuid=fb8ac615-6810-468a-b321-87fc97ead2a8&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Apple AirPods Pro 2 at a rare $169</a>, to the surprisingly powerful <a href="https://zdcs.link/z7ODbP?object_uuid=fb8ac615-6810-468a-b321-87fc97ead2a8&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">KRK Kreate Studio Monitors</a> that deliver clean, rich sound that certainly outperform the usual "gaming gear" and "cinema quality" markup. Plus, <a href="https://zdcs.link/aAgjbq?object_uuid=fb8ac615-6810-468a-b321-87fc97ead2a8&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Zelda fans can scoop up hardcover best-selling books</a> for less, and if you're still hunting for a <a href="https://zdcs.link/985dbR?object_uuid=fb8ac615-6810-468a-b321-87fc97ead2a8&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Nintendo Switch 2</a>, <a href="https://zdcs.link/9YWgd2?object_uuid=fb8ac615-6810-468a-b321-87fc97ead2a8&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Amazon’s invite system</a> is your best shot right now. Prepping for travel? this <a href="https://zdcs.link/QL8An0?object_uuid=fb8ac615-6810-468a-b321-87fc97ead2a8&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">$19 INIU power bank</a> should have you covered for a top up too.</p><p id="black-bolt-elite-trainer-box"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Black Bolt Elite Trainer Box">Black Bolt Elite Trainer Box</h2></p><div catalogid="04ac607f-8252-4021-86e9-9a8593559093" id="225517"><div id="225517" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Black Bolt Elite Trainer Box</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Amazon selling anything for near MSRP Pokémon TCG related is a miracle in itself, but this Black Bolt ETB is available right now for just under $79.<a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokmon-tcg-black-bolt-and-white-flare-preview-why-this-dual-expansion-is-epic"> I loved opening Black Bolt and White Flare</a>, and it's certainly one of the best Scarlet and Violet sets to collect Illustration Rares from. This is a good deal in the current climate, snap this up.</p></div><p id="featured-in-this-article"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Featured in this article">Pokémon TCG Stock Update</h2></p><p data-cy="paragraph">Amazon is finally killing it for Pokémon TCG elite trainer box stock and pricing, and some are the closest to MSRP the big box retailer has been for weeks. Not only is the Black Bolt ETB vastly undercutting the secondary market, Paradox Rift ETB is even cheaper (And an overlooked set in my opinion, stock up now). </p><p data-cy="paragraph">There's other great deals on ex boxes too, which are also near MSRP and around the same or just under listings on TCG Player. The sealed market is becoming more competitive, so it's more important than ever to give eBay a quick check before hitting buy.</p><p id="featured-in-this-article"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Featured in this article">Nintendo Switch 2 Stock Updates</h2></p><div><div id="225528" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Nintendo Switch 2 + Mario Kart World Bundle</h3></p></div><div id="225529" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Nintendo Switch 2</h3></p></div></div><p data-cy="paragraph">As predicted, Nintendo Switch 2's launch window is seeing stock shortages. If you didn't preorder at launch, you've probably been waiting for stock drops since launch. Amazon currently has it's invitation system in place for both the standard console SKU and the Mario Kart world bundle, so it's always worth getting on the waiting list whilst you wait. If successful, your purchase link will be live for 72 hours.</p><p id="2-x-nintendo-eshop-50-gift-card"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="2 x Nintendo eShop $50 Gift Card">2 x Nintendo eShop $50 Gift Card</h2></p><div catalogid="04ac607f-8252-4021-86e9-9a8593559093" id="225542"><p data-cy="paragraph">Why pay $100 when you could pay $88? Redemmable on US Nintendo eShop accounts, this cheeky little bargain will save $12 off $100 worth of eShop games, including Nintendo Switch 2 games.</p></div><p id="featured-in-this-article"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Featured in this article">The Legend of Zelda Hardcover Book Sale</h2></p><p data-cy="paragraph">Nearly every The Legend of Zelda hardcover book you need for your collection is available in this sale with some cracking discounts. It includes my favorite one,  Hyrule Historia, that fills in more than a few gaps in the LoZ lore, although the timeline has already been slightly retconned. It also includes full and expanded official guides for <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/the-legend-of-zelda-breath-of-the-wild">Breath of the Wild</a> and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-legend-of-zelda-tears-of-the-kingdom-review">Tears of the Kingdom</a>.</p><p id="featured-in-this-article"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Featured in this article">KRK Kreate Powered Studio Monitors</h2></p><p data-cy="paragraph">I can personally guarantee a set of powered studio monitors will sound better than almost any sound system with or without a subwoofer. The new line of KRK Kreate studio monitors aren't just for recording music (Although they'd do an amazing job), they're a versatile sound option for content creation, editing, gaming, watching TV and movies and more. Buyers can even teather to them via Bluetooth for no fuss connections.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">I've been using the 8-inch speaker models for a couple of weeks now, and they destory my soundbar and subwoofer combo that cost's nearly double the price of these. There's precision adjustments knobs on the back, which I keep mostly in neutral with volume up by half for a crisp flat sound with the right amount of bass. Although that can be cranked up when needed. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Personally I use an audio splitter so my Krate 8s can handle my Nano QuadCortex guitar amp moddler, my TV audio and gaming PC audio for the best experience. For me, going from a 3-inch to 8-inch speaker option is night and day. The clarity difference and range is top-tier, not to mention the jack, XLR and aux outputs available on each monitor that fits in perfectly in everyone's setup. You're getting top-of-the-range brand quality without the "gaming" brand tax, it's a win-win.</p><p id="apple-airpods-pro-2"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Apple AirPods Pro 2">Apple AirPods Pro 2</h2></p><div catalogid="04ac607f-8252-4021-86e9-9a8593559093" id="225530"><div id="225530" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Apple AirPods Pro 2</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">AirPods Pro 2 are one of those earbuds I keep noticing for their mix of sound quality and thoughtful features. At $199, they offer a strong balance of value and performance. The active noise cancellation blocks out a lot of background noise while adaptive audio automatically adjusts based on your surroundings. You get four sizes of silicone tips for a customizable fit, and once those are set they stay comfortable even through longer listening sessions. The personalized spatial audio and hearing aid features add extra depth, giving them more flexibility than just a standard pair of wireless earbuds.</p></div><p id="iniu-portable-charger-10000mah-45w"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="INIU Portable Charger 10000mAh 45W">INIU Portable Charger 10000mAh 45W</h2></p><div catalogid="04ac607f-8252-4021-86e9-9a8593559093" id="225531"><div id="225531" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>INIU Portable Charger 10000mAh 45W</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">This is ideal for carrying around when you've forgot to stick your phone on charge overnight, 45W is more than enough power to charge anything whilst using it, from phones to Nintendo Switch 2. So who can argue for $12?</p></div><p id="donkey-kong-bananza"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Donkey Kong Bananza">Donkey Kong Bananza</h2></p><div catalogid="04ac607f-8252-4021-86e9-9a8593559093" id="225532"><div id="225532" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Donkey Kong Bananza</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">If you own a Switch 2 and not Donkey Kong Bananza, there's something a-miss. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/donkey-kong-bananza">We've given it a rare 10/10,</a> and is officially Nintendo's latest handheld's first killer app and system seller. It's from the same team behind <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/super-mario-odyssey">Super Mario Odyssey</a> and takes full advantage of the power packed into Nintendo Switch 2. Just get it, play it, then thank me later.</p></div></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/deals-for-today-july-21]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This Stunning Mod Brings Fallout's Necropolis to Doom: 'Never Seen a Fan Project Get So Close to the OG Vibe']]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/this-stunning-mod-brings-fallouts-necropolis-to-doom-never-seen-a-fan-project-get-so-close-to-the-og-vibe</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/this-stunning-mod-brings-fallouts-necropolis-to-doom-never-seen-a-fan-project-get-so-close-to-the-og-vibe.1248702/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">"This looks frickin' legit."</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Someone has recreated a whole new Fallout map in the GZDoom Engine. </p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6e8WrmOibpM" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>In a stunning and surprisingly cinematic teaser</u></a>, modder Alexander "Red888guns" Berezin has been hard at work recreating Fallout's city of Necropolis from the original Fallout game. As <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/fallout/a-jaw-dropping-mod-to-remake-part-of-fallout-1-in-doom-has-resurfaced-after-3-years-of-silence/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>PC Gamer</u></a> points out, the Fallout: Bakersfield project was initially unveiled back in <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FMjJM9HAqqk" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>2022</u></a>, but we've heard very little since, leading some to speculate that the project may have been abandoned. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Now, however, we know Berezin is still working on recreating the Necropolis sequence, complete with the obligatory boss fight with Harry in the watershed. To be honest, it's kind of wild that this entire world has been recreated by just two people — Berezin and what's presumed to be a family member, Denis Berezin. </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">"Never seen a fan project get so close to the OG vibe," said one commenter on the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6e8WrmOibpM" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">YouTube page</a>. Another agreed, writing: "Duuuuuuude whaaaat this looked cool at first, but the gameplay got me so hyped. This looks frickin' legit. This has more Fallout vibes than the last few actual games."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Given the quality of the teaser, you'd be forgiven for thinking the mod's release is imminent, but an infographic at the end of the teaser suggests development is only about 60% done. Berezin posits that he's about 30% of the way through creating the creatures, 50% done with making the weapons and UI, and completed 80% of walls, tiles, and scenery. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The mod's release date is simply listed as: ??.??.202?... which takes us right up until December 31, 2029, unfortunately.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/tv/fallout-the-series"><u>Fallout Season 1</u></a> hit Prime Video in April 2024 and was an instant breakout hit. While the show’s popularity sparked a flood of new players across all Fallout games, Bethesda — and by extension parent company Microsoft — failed to make the most of it with, for example, the release of a new Fallout game. For Fallout Season 2, it's off to New Vegas, the setting of Obsidian's much-loved <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/fallout-new-vegas"><u>Fallout: New Vegas</u></a>, and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/with-fallout-season-2-waiting-in-the-wings-fallout-76-creative-director-says-bethesda-has-plans-for-tie-ins-with-the-amazon-show"><u>it sounds like tie-in content is indeed planned</u></a> for <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/fallout-76"><u>Fallout 76</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Of course, a brand-new Fallout game is also coming down the pipe, with Howard confirming <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/fallout-5"><u>Fallout 5</u></a> is in the long-term plan, potentially after <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/the-elder-scrolls-vi"><u>The Elder Scrolls 6</u></a> comes out. </p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Vikki Blake is a reporter for IGN, as well as a critic, columnist, and consultant with 15+ years experience working with some of the world's biggest gaming sites and publications. She's also a Guardian, Spartan, Silent Hillian, Legend, and perpetually High Chaos. Find her at </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vixx.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>BlueSky</em></a><em>.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/this-stunning-mod-brings-fallouts-necropolis-to-doom-never-seen-a-fan-project-get-so-close-to-the-og-vibe]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The 10 Best Donkey Kong Games]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/the-10-best-donkey-kong-games</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-10-best-donkey-kong-games.1248700/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Despite being Nintendo’s original mascot and being one of legendary game designer Shigeru Miyamoto’s most iconic character creations, Donkey Kong has had a bit of a weird history of getting his own video games compared to that mustachioed plumber he’s frequently feuding with. Sometimes he’s the hero. Sometimes he’s the villain. Sometimes he’s a bongo drummer. But with Donkey Kong Bananza out now - DK’s first new starring role in over a decade and first new 3D platformer in over 25 years - it’s time to ride a rickety minecart down memory lane and look back at the big ape’s greatest games. Here are the ten best Donkey Kong games of all time.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">10. Donkey Kong Country 3: Dixie Kong’s Double Trouble</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/07/21/dkc-3-1753093410807.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">While Dixie Kong’s Double Trouble (an admittedly strange name for the third game in a series) isn’t exactly a game where you play as Donkey Kong himself, it does continue to build on the momentum based platforming gameplay that kicked off with the first Donkey Kong Country. Double Trouble tags in Dixie Kong and her cousin Kiddy Kong for another adventure, bringing more collectible coins, rideable animal sidekicks, and incredibly catchy background songs along with them. New abilities like Dixie’s ponytail hover (which feels similar to Tails’ foxtail helicopter hover seen in the Sonic games) add some interesting new mechanics to the mix, and while Double Trouble doesn’t quite reach the heights of its predecessors, it’s still an excellent and occasionally tough as nails adventure on its own and one of the best looking games on the Super Nintendo. </p><h2 data-cy="title2">9. Donkey Kong 64</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/07/21/dk64-1753093280987.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Donkey Kong’s first (and until recently, only) foray into joystick-controlled platforming wasn’t quite as strong as when Super Mario and The Legend of Zelda’s Link made the jump from 2D games on the Super Nintendo to 3D games on the N64, but hey, those were the early days of 3D gaming and there were bound to be some growing pains. Donkey Kong 64 is often derided for its over abundance of often tedious collectibles but when levels open up and progression requirements get out of your way, it’s an absolute blast to explore.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">DK 64’s main hook is allowing players to control an entire family of Kongs for the first time instead of splitting them off into duos like the Donkey Kong Country series was known for. There are a ton of levels to hop around in, secret areas to unlock, and seemingly endless things to collect, plus a bonus multiplayer mode where Kongs run around shooting each other with guns, which may seem strange until you remember Donkey Kong 64 was made by Rare, the same company known for reinventing console multiplayer shooters two years earlier with their hit game GoldenEye 007. However, ask any kid who grew up playing Donkey Kong 64 and they’ll tell you their two fondest memories have nothing to do with the gameplay itself. First, the bright banana yellow cartridge the game was released on, and second and most importantly, the DK Rap theme song, possibly the catchiest title screen music in the history of video games. </p><h2 data-cy="title2">8. Donkey Kong Jungle Beat</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/07/21/dk-jb-1753093543875.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">During the GameCube era Nintendo experimented with a bunch of offbeat peripherals, but one of the strangest (and most adorable) were the DK Bongos, a large plastic pair of drums shaped like wooden barrels. The DK Bongos were most famously used for a series of rhythm games known as Donkey Konga, inviting players to smack the bongos in time with the beat to various songs. But the real star of the bongo supported GameCube game library was Donkey Kong Jungle Beat, a side scrolling platforming game that used bongo inputs to control Donkey Kong across a wide variety of stages. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">By smacking the bongos individually or together, Donkey Kong can move around, interact with objects, and beat the bananas out of a ton of different enemies and bosses. And while Jungle Beat is a bit on the short side, players were encouraged to replay it to beat their high scores over and over again. Jungle Beat eventually made its way to the Nintendo Wii and Wii U with updated Wiimote motion controls so here’s hoping it gets ported to the Nintendo Switch 2 so more players can finally experience this often forgotten modern classic.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">7. Donkey Kong</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/07/21/dk-arcade-1753093638939.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">The first Donkey Kong game is still one of the greatest arcade games ever made, even decades later. At the time of its release in 1981, Nintendo was struggling to connect with arcade audiences and fast tracked a new game from then unknown game developer Shigeru Miyamoto. The result was the Kong Kong inspired Donkey Kong game, a unique arcade experience that showcased multiple levels, challenging platforming gameplay, and a little guy named Jumpman, now known around the world as Super Mario. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Donkey Kong was not only a massive hit for Nintendo, it also inspired two increasingly stranger arcade sequels, Donkey Kong Jr and Donkey Kong 3. It also served as the basis for the hit film King of Kong which documents the real life feud between two Donkey Kong high score world champions. For being a 40+ year old arcade game, the first Donkey Kong game ever made still holds up well today and brought the world Mario, Donkey Kong, and Pauline. Hey, wouldn’t it be cool if they let some Mario developers make a game with Donkey Kong and Pauline! Well, more on that in a bit.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">6. Donkey Kong Country</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/07/21/dkc-1753093816318.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s hard to express just how revolutionary Donkey Kong Country was when it first came to the Super Nintendo in 1994. For starters, DKC was a total reinvention of Donkey Kong, his world, and his enemies. It gave us Diddy Kong, Donkey’s acrobatic sidekick who went on to appear in tons more games, including a few of his own. It featured groundbreaking pre-rendered graphics based on scans of 3D assets and an amazing soundtrack to boot. It gave us the Kremlings and King R. Rool and a bunch of other huge bosses. And it gave us Cranky Kong, Funky Kong, and Candy Kong. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Donkey Kong Country was a massive success, spawning several sequels as well as Game Boy and Game Boy Advance ports and remakes. It’s absolutely packed with diverse environments, tricky platforming, animal sidekicks, and collectibles and the minecart levels are still tense and challenging to this day. At the time it was incredibly rare (pun intended) for Nintendo to outsource one of their most important characters to a UK-based studio instead of just making a game in house but the result was a redefining of Donkey Kong that still impacts how he’s seen today.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">5. Donkey Kong Country 2: Diddy’s Kong Quest</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/07/21/dkc2-1753093922620.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">What do you do with Donkey Kong after the groundbreaking Donkey Kong Country? Well, you lock him in a cage so he can be rescued by Diddy Kong and Dixie Kong, obviously. Coming out just one year after the original, Donkey Kong Country 2: Diddy’s Kong Quest improved on nearly everything from the first game and cemented itself as the best game in the original trilogy. The levels are tougher and more clever, the graphics are better, the soundtrack is somehow even catchier, and the two playable characters are a ton of fun to control. There are dozens and dozens of secrets and collectibles to unearth across its eight vast worlds and 52 levels and finding them allows players to ultimately display a “102%” next to their save file.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">4. Donkey Kong Country Returns</h2><a href="https://assets2.ignimgs.com/2010/10/14/donkey-kong-country-returns-20101014073207929-3333506.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">After Microsoft bought Donkey Kong Country creators Rare, the Donkey Kong games series was in a bit of a strange place. But 16 years to the day since the original Donkey Kong Country was released, Donkey Kong Country... well, returned again with Donkey Kong Country Returns for the Nintendo Wii, this time being developed by Metroid Prime creator Retro Studios. Returns was less of a total overhaul for the series and more of a return to form but it still managed to bring along a ton of new features and some seriously brilliant level design.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Returns featured a totally new and distinct art direction for the series which also allowed the characters and world to be much more expressive and fun. Equally inventive were the stages and locales which were teeming with life and personality and more importantly, challenging and rewarding platforming, chaotic autoscrolling levels, and more. Donkey Kong Country Returns sold over 6.5 million copies on the Nintendo Wii and has been ported to every Nintendo handheld and console since. It’s a master class in how to bring a once dormant series back, a thing that Donkey Kong seems to have a habit of doing.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">3. Donkey Kong ‘94</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/07/21/dkc-94-1753094034300.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Similar to the original arcade game, you don’t actually play as Donkey Kong in the Game Boy’s incredible Donkey Kong ‘94 even though his name is in the title. But that’s not the only thing those games share in common. Like his first game, Donkey Kong has once again captured Pauline, leaving Mario to jump and hammer his way to her rescue. But after a clever revisit of the Donkey Kong arcade four levels, Donkey Kong ‘94 opens up ninety seven more stages full of platform puzzle challenges. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Outside of how much fun Mario is to control, one of the best parts of Donkey Kong ‘94 is how expressive and charismatic Donkey Kong is here. He’s big and hulking and tough but also funny and goofy and seeing so much personality shine through the tiny and blurry original Game Boy screen was revelatory. The game saw a ton of spiritual successors in the Mario vs Donkey Kong series and spinoffs, although none were ever quite as good as Donkey Kong ‘94. Here’s hoping it gets a remake someday, but for now it’s totally accessible through the Nintendo Switch Online Game Boy app and it absolutely still feels great to play.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">2. Donkey Kong Country: Tropical Freeze</h2><a href="https://assets2.ignimgs.com/2013/06/11/wiiudkcountryscrn04e3jpg-30b8fb.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Like Diddy’s Kong Quest, Tropical Freeze once again took all of the solid foundation laid down in the game before it and built an even bigger and better sequel, making it the best 2D Donkey Kong game ever made. Donkey Kong’s once peaceful world has been taken over by snow themed bad guys, and as the title suggests, that means a beautiful mix of palm trees and ice everywhere, leading to some truly genius (and very tough) platforming sequences.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">But if you find things a bit too tough, just try out Funky Mode, an optional difficulty decrease that allows players to play as everyone’s favorite monkey that owns an airport. Speaking of which, Tropical Freeze features more playable Kongs than any Donkey Kong game before it including Donkey, Diddy, Dixie, and at long last, Cranky Kong who just couldn’t stay retired. Tropical Freeze is the culmination of all of the best things from the best Donkey Kong Country games mixed up in one perfect frozen cocktail. Once Retro gets Metroid Prime 4 in the rear view it would be amazing to see them return to this series one more time. But luckily for us, there’s another Donkey Kong game to hold us over.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">1. Donkey Kong Bananza</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/04/03/dkpreview-1743659889915.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">As it turns out, the latest Donkey Kong game is his greatest. Developed by the team behind the incredible Super Mario Odyssey, Donkey Kong Bananza gives DK a whole new bag of toys to play with and a whole new world to destroy. De-emphasizing the tight platforming that the Country series was known for, Bananza opts instead to celebrate Donkey Kong’s brute force and heavy fists, allowing him to punch holes in the earth in search of collectibles, rip out huge rocks to ride around and throw, and so much more. It also reunites him with Pauline, this time as friends and collaborators.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Bananza is also Donkey Kong’s biggest game yet. It’s absolutely packed with secret areas, unlockable costumes, and optional challenge rooms and it can easily take players dozens of hours to find it all. It’s a loving celebration of this iconic and legendary Nintendo character, hopefully paving the way for more Donkey Kong games like it for years to come. For a character that has been reinvented a ton of times since 1981, it’s amazing to see Donkey Kong return for his first 3D game since 1999 and to do so with a game that feels both totally fresh and quintessentially Nintendo.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">And there you have it, the ten best Donkey Kong games of all time. Did any of the games on this list kongfuse you? Were there any other DK games we should have kongsidered? Well, go bananas and let me know in the kongments below. </p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/the-10-best-donkey-kong-games]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[These Classic Atari Games Are Now Playable In Cars]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/these-classic-atari-games-are-now-playable-in-cars/1100-6533293/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/these-classic-atari-games-are-now-playable-in-cars.1248698/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6533293">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Decades ago, Atari games were some of the first titles to leap from arcades to home consoles. Now, a small selection of Atari's re-imagined classics are heading to AirConsole, an entertainment and gaming platform designed exclusively for cars.</p><p>AirConsole and Atari <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/airconsole-brings-legendary-atari-arcade-games-to-cars-302507956.html" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">have announced</a> that Asteroids Recharged and Breakout Charged are now playable for the in-vehicle entertainment system that is currently available in supported Volkswagen models. To play the games, drivers need an active VW Connect Plus contract and an internet connection on a smartphone. However, the games will only work if the car is parked. Once players scan the accompanying QR codes, their phones become the controllers for the AirConsole titles.</p><p>"The AirConsole team has a phenomenal track record of optimizing the in-car controls and producing amazing playing experiences in vehicles," said Atari vice president of games Ethan Stearns in a statement. "We are excited for Volkswagen drivers and their passengers to discover these modern versions of our classic titles."</p><p>Atari will eventually add Missile Command: Recharged to its AirConsole lineup, but no other specific titles were mentioned by name. AirConsole is also working with carmakers Audi and BMW, but the Atari games are currently only available through Volkswagen cars.</p><p>Earlier this year, Atari announced <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/atari-and-polybius-creator-are-reimagining-the-rare-arcade-game-i-robot/1100-6529425/" data-ref-id="1100-6529425">a new version of the 1984 arcade game I, Robot</a>, and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/atari-revisits-an-arcade-classic-with-breakout-beyond/1100-6529212/" data-ref-id="1100-6529212">Breakout Beyond</a>, an updated title that was originally intended to be released on Intellivision's Amico, a console that has yet to launch.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/these-classic-atari-games-are-now-playable-in-cars/1100-6533293/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ubisoft CEO Blames Star Wars Outlaws Failure on the IP, Says No Game Can Be Supported Forever]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/ubisoft-ceo-blames-star-wars-outlaws-failure-on-the-ip-says-no-game-can-be-supported-forever/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ubisoft-ceo-blames-star-wars-outlaws-failure-on-the-ip-says-no-game-can-be-supported-forever.1248690/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Ubisoft CEO Yves Guillemot answered several questions during the company's General Meeting 2025 held earlier this month (a recording is available <a href="https://edge.media-server.com/mmc/p/zzxygofu/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">here</a>, though you'll have to register first to access it).</p>



<p>The executive addressed hot topics related to Ubisoft, such as the commercial failure of Star Wars Outlaws, which he blamed largely on the IP's current woes:</p>



<p><em>For Star Wars Outlaws, we didn't reach our sales targets. The game suffered from a number of items. First, it suffered from the fact that it was released at a time when the brand - the brand that it belonged to - was in 'choppy waters'. And the game had a few items that still needed to be polished, and they were polished and debugged in the early weeks after release, but it did affect sales volumes. We did heavily improve the game after those early weeks, and when it will be released on upcoming consoles such as the Nintendo Switch 2, it will have a new version of the game.  </em></p>



<p>Guillemot refers to the fact that some Star Wars products that were released immediately before Star Wars Outlaws did not perform well. Chiefly, he might be referring to The Acolyte, which aired between June and July 2024 and was already canceled in August due to low viewership.</p>



<p>It's hard to imagine The Acolyte having such a big impact on Star Wars Outlaws sales, though. After all, other live action TV series like The Mandalorian, Andor, and Ahsoka had much better reception among fans. Much more accurate is the other half of Guillemot's statement, where the Ubisoft CEO admits that the game launched with several problems that were only ironed out over the course of the following months. Perhaps the game, in its current, improved state, will find a new audience on the Nintendo Switch 2, where it is scheduled to launch on September 4.</p>



<p>In the General Meeting 2025, the Ubisoft CEO also commented on the <a href="https://wccftech.com/publishers-argue-stop-killing-games-proposals-would-make-online-games-prohibitively-expensive/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Stop Killing Games initiative</a>:</p>



<p><em>Regarding the petition, we operate in a market and whenever we release a game, we provide a lot of support for that game. We also provide a lot of services to make sure that the game is accessible and remains playable 24/7. So, we provide information regarding the game and how long the game can be played. Players and buyers are forewarned that the game may be discontinued. </em></p>



<p><em>[...] This kind of issue is not specific to Ubisoft. All video game publishers are faced with that issue. You provide a service, but nothing is written in stone and at some point, the service may be discontinued. Nothing is eternal. We are doing our best to make sure that things go well for all players, because obviously, support for old games cannot last forever. But that's an issue that we're working on, and it's something that the industry at large is working on to minimize impact on players. But clearly, it's something that you need to factor in. The lifespan of a piece of software, whenever there is a service component, eventually the services may be discontinued because the software may become obsolete over time. </em></p>



<p>What do you think about the comments made by the Ubisoft CEO? Let us know in the comments below.</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/ubisoft-ceo-blames-star-wars-outlaws-failure-on-the-ip-says-no-game-can-be-supported-forever/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battlefield 6 Open Beta is Scheduled to Go Live in Early August; Expected to Have Improvements Over Latest Battlefield Labs Build – Rumor]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/battlefield-6-open-beta-august/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/battlefield-6-open-beta-is-scheduled-to-go-live-in-early-august-expected-to-have-improvements-over-latest-battlefield-labs-build-%E2%80%93-rumor.1248688/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The Battlefield 6 open beta may go live in around two weeks, judging from some recent discoveries shared online today.</p>



<p>As reported on the Battlefield series subreddit, members of the 1BF Telegram group discovered via the API of EA's backend services that the publication of the Battlefield 6 open beta build spotted earlier this month is scheduled for August 4. The open beta itself may not become available on the same day, but the fact that it is being published suggests that it should go live not too long after its publication. In addition, it has been discovered that this open beta build is five numbers ahead of the latest Battlefield Labs beta, meaning that it should sport plenty of improvements and possibly some new features not found in the latest testing build. The launch of the open beta will likely be preceded by the announcement of the game's release date and opening of pre-orders, as, according to another redditor, an <em>"early open beta access"</em> line has been discovered in the API, continuing the trend of pre-orders granting early access to beta tests.</p>



<p>The Battlefield 6 open beta becoming available in early August also falls in line with rumors of EA hosting a three-day event later this month for media and creators. The event is said to also feature a <a href="https://wccftech.com/battlefield-6-rumored-unveil-3-day-event/">live reveal</a> in the vein of the Battlefield 1 reveal, which also included live gameplay besides the official announcement. As such, it looks like it won't take long to finally see more of the next entry in the long-running series and how it will attempt to achieve its ambitious target of <a href="https://wccftech.com/battlefield-6-targeting-100-million-players/">100 million players.</a></p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/battlefield-6-open-beta-august/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Call Of Duty's Next Operator Knows What You Did Last Summer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-next-operator-knows-what-you-did-last-summer/1100-6533292/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/call-of-dutys-next-operator-knows-what-you-did-last-summer.1248686/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6533292">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/call-of-duty-black-ops-6/" data-ref-id="5000-630093">Call of Duty: Black Ops 6</a> has a great hook for its next Operator, as the murderous Fisherman from I Know What You Did Last Summer is slashing their way into the game. Dressed to kill, this Operator is being released to promote the new entry in the horror film franchise. "Last summer, they know what you did. This summer, the Fisherman's in your lobby," the message reads for the brief teaser trailer.</p><p>While it doesn't have a number attached to it, I Know What You Did Last Summer is the fourth film in the slasher series, and it's a direct sequel to 1998's I Still Know What You Did Last Summer. Set 27 years after the Tower Bay murders, the movie features a new hook-wielding killer on the loose targeting a group of friends, one year after they covered up a car crash in which they may have killed someone. The movie premiered on July 18 to mixed reviews, and so far, it has scared up a worldwide box office gross of $24.6 million.</p><p>A release date for Fisherman--who bears a striking resemblance to the <a href="https://youtu.be/vgIY_U6Npxg" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Hash-Slinging Slasher</a> from SpongeBob SquarePants--has not been announced, but they are expected to debut in Season Five of Call of Duty: Black Ops 6. This new reveal follows hot on the heels of several surprising crossovers in the game, as <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-dutys-american-dad-collab-is-real-shop-bundles-coming-soon/1100-6533245/" data-ref-id="1100-6533245">American Dad</a>, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-dutys-beavis-and-butt-head-trailer-is-a-sight-to-behold/1100-6532887/" data-ref-id="1100-6532887">Beavis &amp; Butt-Head</a>, and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/see-ballerinas-killer-abilities-in-call-of-dutys-new-john-wick-crossover-out-today/1100-6531996/" data-ref-id="1100-6531996">Eve Macarro from the John Wick spin-off Ballerina</a> have all been added in recent weeks.</p><p>In other Call of Duty news, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-is-now-asking-players-to-verify-their-age/1100-6533243/" data-ref-id="1100-6533243">a new age-verification measure is being added</a>, and Treyarch's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cod-black-ops-7-announced-marks-first-back-to-back-black-ops-release-eve/1100-6532238/" data-ref-id="1100-6532238">Call of Duty: Black Ops 7</a> was recently announced with a slick trailer.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-next-operator-knows-what-you-did-last-summer/1100-6533292/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Here's When Battlefield 6 Could Be Revealed, And It's Soon]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/heres-when-battlefield-6-could-be-revealed-and-its-soon/1100-6533290/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/heres-when-battlefield-6-could-be-revealed-and-its-soon.1248684/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6533290">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/battlefield-6-release-date-trailer-news/1100-6526583/" data-ref-id="1100-6526583">Battlefield 6</a>, or whatever the game may be called, will be announced on July 31, according to a new report. <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-reveal-event/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Insider Gaming</a> reported that EA and DICE plan to reveal the game on that day as part of an event likened to COD Next, which is Activision's annual announcement event for the Call of Duty series.</p><p>The report added that EA and DICE are inviting people to a behind-closed-doors event to play the new Battlefield game beginning July 29, with the event culminating in the global reveal on July 31. People can expect to see gameplay footage and hear directly from developers, the report said.</p><p>Insider Gaming also reported that some influencers are being sent care packages pointing to an upcoming announcement. The post referenced above has since been deleted, but Insider-Gaming said it's legitimate.</p><p>Officially speaking, EA has said it will officially announce the new Battlefield game sometime this summer. Fans theorized it might happen in June alongside the industry's other major gaming events, and when that didn't happen, an <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/battlefield-6-reveal-still-happening-this-summer-ea-assures/1100-6532481/" data-ref-id="1100-6532481">EA boss assured fans a reveal was still coming sometime later.</a></p><p>GameSpot has contacted EA in an attempt to get more details on the reveal plans for the next Battlefield.</p><p>EA is currently allowing some people to play Battlefield 6 through a limited closed alpha test. An <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/battlefield-6-open-beta-revealed-in-datamining-leak-but-nothing-is-confirmed-yet/1100-6533138/" data-ref-id="1100-6533138">open beta for the game</a> may be in the works and could be announced during the reported July 31 event, but nothing is confirmed at this stage.</p><p>EA has confirmed that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/battlefield-6-will-be-fully-revealed-this-summer-launching-by-march-2026/1100-6531349/" data-ref-id="1100-6531349">Battlefield 6 will be released by the end of March 2026</a>. With <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/grand-theft-auto-6-everything-we-know/1100-6503729/" data-ref-id="1100-6503729">GTA 6</a> now delayed to May 2026, many are theorizing that EA will release the game this year instead of next.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/heres-when-battlefield-6-could-be-revealed-and-its-soon/1100-6533290/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PlayStation 5 Pro Will Run Pure Pool Pro At Native 8K Resolution, 60 FPS]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/playstation-5-pro-native-8k-60-fps-pure-pool-pro/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/playstation-5-pro-will-run-pure-pool-pro-at-native-8k-resolution-60-fps.1248680/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Another game is soon joining the small lineup of PlayStation 5 Pro targeting native 8K resolution and 60 frames per second gameplay.</p>



<p>Pure Pool Pro, sequel to 2014's Pure Pool by Ripstone Games revealed today with a new trailer, will reportedly run at native 8K resolution and 60 frames per second on Sony's mid-generation refresh system, and at native 4K resolution and 120 frames per second on the base model. In a statement sent to <a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/news/2025/07/ps5-pro-pockets-a-native-8k-60fps-game">Push Square</a>, Ripstone Games' George Holland provided some additional information on the matter, saying that the nature of the pool being fixed around the table, their relatively lightweight proprietary engine and their initial pre-alpha testing before any optimization led the team to believe that 8K@60 FPS on the PlayStation 5 Pro is achievable.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Pure Pool Pro - Gameplay Reveal Trailer | New 8K Native Cue Sports Sim - Coming 2025" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6aXyjAT5pvs?start=1&amp;feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>As mentioned above, Pure Pool Pro will be joining a small lineup of games targeting 8K resolution on the system. Among them are <a href="https://wccftech.com/playstation-5-pro-gran-turismo-7-pssr-8k/">Gran Turismo 7</a> and <a href="https://wccftech.com/playstation-5-pro-impressive-8k-resolution-no-mans-sky/">No Man's Sky</a>, but neither of them can run at native 8K resolution on the system, instead taking advantage of the PlayStation Spectral Super Resolution upscaler to reconstruct a lower resolution, usually in the ballpark of 4K resolution, to 8K. Considering how 8K displays aren't widespread, not too many players are able to enjoy these few PlayStation 5 Pro games at 8K resolution, but having more options is never a bad thing.</p>



<p>Besides allowing developers to implement 8K modes in their games, the PlayStation 5 Pro has a lot to offer over the base model, as its higher specs than the base model can offer the same image quality seen in Quality display modes at 60 frames per second. You can learn more about the system by checking out Kai's <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/playstation-5-pro-hardware-the-next-gen-graphics-upgrade/">review.</a></p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/playstation-5-pro-native-8k-60-fps-pure-pool-pro/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shadow Labyrinth Review]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/07/21/shadow-labyrinth-review/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/shadow-labyrinth-review.1248670/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
			
			<p>When a developer chooses to take a long-running franchise and change its gameplay formula, it is a high-risk, high-reward situation. Taking Pac-Man and deciding to create a Metroidvania using the character is the risk Bandai Namco has taken to celebrate 45 years of the icon. Has that high risk come to fruition in Shadow Labyrinth? The answer is no.</p>
<p><iframe title="Shadow Labyrinth - Launch Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/j_KKX42-m5U?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Shadow Labyrinth starts off with a huge opening action scene with a galactic war taking place, and ships being ripped apart. The outcome of this leaves Puck (So named because Pac-Man’s original name was Puck-Man), trapped on the planet of its enemy. To complete its mission, Puck summons your character Swordsman No.8 to assist in fighting the enemies and navigating this world to complete its objective. It is a pretty interesting premise, casting Pac-Man as a kind of military intelligence and it provides a good reason to fight enemies, and introduce characters from other Bandai Namco series to develop a shared universe.</p>


<p>As Swordsman No.8 you have, as expected, a sword to fight enemies by putting together combos and abilities. You also have access to a mech known as GAIA who can be summoned for brief spells to clear enemies or deal damage to bosses when you get into a tight spot. Things start off well enough as you get used to the combat, and when you are used to the way to fight you are left waiting to gain new perks and abilities. The progression system is nearly unforgivably slow, with Shadow Labyrinth holding back any interesting new abilities for hours between them.</p>


<p>This means combat become stale fast. You do have the option to level up your sword and ESP bar to make them stronger/last longer, and it helps to make progress through the world. However, using the same attack over and over without having to really change things up is boring. As you venture through the different areas you do come across various enemy types but, aside from a select few and the bosses, you quickly realise these new enemies are reskins of enemies from the first area down to movement and attacks. Not only does combat become stale, so do the enemies.</p>
<p>As a Metroidvania, Shadow Labyrinth needs to have a map worth exploring and the platforming to make that enjoyable. &nbsp;The layout of the map in Shadow Labyrinth is odd, with paths that lead to huge, empty areas in which there is nothing, and looping paths that don’t add anything to the experience. The opening areas look decent but eventually each area kind of blends together, with uninspired artistic design for the backgrounds.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the platforming is fine when you are No.8 but there are moments where you are going along the rails as Puck. You can choose to move manually or let Puck ride the rails autonomously, and you can attack with a spinning blade attack which helps clear enemies out of the way, but the jumping when on the rails leaves a lot to be desired, proving to be unnecessarily fiddly, often not panning out how you wanted it to. That’s okay in areas where you have time, but there are sections which are timed including the Maze stages, which are more like classic Pac-Man with lots of twists put in. They require absolute precision to complete and a couple of mistakes can lead to running out of time or lives.</p>
<p>You will make mistakes which will lead to No 8 dying, and when this happens you have the option to start from a save point or checkpoint. Save points can be considered checkpoints, but the reverse is not true. When you are at a save point you can spend oras to upgrade No.8’s skills and equip different perks, provided you have bought some from a shop, travel to different save points, and refill your health. Checkpoints are limited and will refill your health to what you had when you activated, but you can only transport to other save points, not checkpoints, and that’s it.</p>

<p>These checkpoints don’t let you upgrade equipment. It is such an annoying system especially since save points and checkpoints are so frugally placed around that if you die you could be sent back pretty far from where you fell. When you progress through levels you will eventually open up shortcuts to reduce the travel time, but even so the sparse save points and checkpoints feed into feeling like progress is slow.</p>
<p>The story of Shadow Labyrinth is not that interesting even with Bandai Namco using other properties to expand it, and make this a cross universe plot. Puck is not a likeable character, coming across as cold and calculating. No.8 is a silent character so you are looking to the side characters to provide some personality to the game, which they do, but you see them so rarely that they don’t have much chance to shine.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/07/21/shadow-labyrinth-review/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Poll: What Review Score Would You Give Donkey Kong Bananza?]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/features/poll-what-review-score-would-you-give-donkey-kong-bananza</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/poll-what-review-score-would-you-give-donkey-kong-bananza.1248668/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Return of the Kong</p>
</section></header><section>

<p>Last week Donkey Kong returned to the world of 3D platforming over 25 years since his last fully-3D outing in <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/n64/donkey_kong_64">DK64</a> - and what a return it was!</p>
<p><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/donkey-kong-bananza">Donkey Kong Bananza</a> scored an 'Excellent' 9/10 in <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/nintendo-switch-2/donkey-kong-bananza">Jim's review</a>, and most of Team NL has spent this weekend having a smashing time catching up with DK, Diddy, Dixie, and (Void) co. in what Jimbo described as "an almighty re-introduction to the world of 3D platforming for DK, and arguably the Switch 2's first absolute must-play."</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:184766 @ 1753108265 -->
<p>At the time of writing, the game is enjoying "Universal Acclaim" with a <a href="https://www.metacritic.com/game/donkey-kong-bananza/">Metascore of 90</a>, but now everyone has had their chance to go bananas with it, we're wondering if you concur. How would you rate DKB?</p>
<p>While many of you might have blasted through the entire game over the weekend, if you're anything like us your minecart will have gotten derailed by the countless distractions and doohickeys away from the critical path. If you haven't finished the game, no sweat - voting in the poll below doesn't mean your score has to stay the same.</p>
<p>Yes, you can come back at any time to either change your score or add one when you've settled on a rating from 1-10. If you've already rated the game in our database, thank you kindly - your score already counts! If not, feel free to drop your mark below and let's find out how Bananza measures up to <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/guides/best-donkey-kong-games-of-all-time">DK's big bunch of other games</a>.</p>


<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:185275,185249,185197 @ 1753106512 --></section></article><div><p>Gavin first wrote for Nintendo Life in 2018 before joining the site full-time the following year, rising through the ranks to become Editor. He can currently be found squashed beneath a Switch backlog the size of Normandy.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/dartmonkey"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('dartmonkey');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/features/poll-what-review-score-would-you-give-donkey-kong-bananza]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A Nintendo Switch 2 Fire Emblem Game May Be In Development – Rumor]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/ninetndo-switch-2-fire-emblem-development/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/a-nintendo-switch-2-fire-emblem-game-may-be-in-development-%E2%80%93-rumor.1248666/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>A new entry in the Fire Emblem series may be in the works for Nintendo Switch 2, judging from a recent online discovery.</p>



<p>As spotted by&nbsp;<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gAPgmb2p7L8">Doctre81</a>, a veteran Japanese 3D character modeler who has worked with Square Enix, SEGA, and Cygames, among other publishers, revealed on LinkedIn that they have worked from January 2025 until April 2025 on the "sequel of Nintendo's SRPG (tactical role-playing game) on Switch 2". While the 3D character modeler hasn't mentioned the name of the game, or the series it belongs to, there's a very good chance this sequel is a new entry in the Fire Emblem series, as the other notable tactical role-playing series by the Japanese company, Advance Wars, hasn't seen a new entry in a very long time, and it may not be as popular nowadays as to warrant a sequel, considering how Advance Wars 1+2: Re‑Boot Camp did not set the sales charts on fire. The fact that the 3D character modeler only worked for a few months in the game may also suggest this isn't a new entry in the series, but possibly a Nintendo Switch 2 upgrade for one of the Fire Emblem games released on the original Switch.</p>



<figure><figcaption>Is this sequel a new Fire Emblem game for Nintendo Switch 2?</figcaption></figure>



<p>It has been some time since we saw a new entry in the Fire Emblem series, so a new game launching on Nintendo Switch 2 would make many fans quite happy, especially those who didn't exactly like the latest entry in the franchise, Fire Emblem Engage. The game launched in 2023 features very solid gameplay, bringing back some classic mechanics, but its mixed bag of character designs, disappointing storyline, and trite social elements left something to be desired. You can learn more about the game by checking out Nathan's <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/fire-emblem-engage/">review.</a></p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/ninetndo-switch-2-fire-emblem-development/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This week in PC games: Wuchang, Killing Floor 3, open world spirit biking and some eerie glyph puzzles]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/this-week-in-pc-games-wuchang-killing-floor-3-open-world-spirit-biking-and-some-eerie-glyph-puzzles</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/this-week-in-pc-games-wuchang-killing-floor-3-open-world-spirit-biking-and-some-eerie-glyph-puzzles.1248664/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>What we're feeding the Maw</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Rock Paper Shotgun / 505 Games</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Sometimes our patron news deity the Maw opens beneath my feet like a toothy sinkhole, and sometimes it leaps up and slobbers all over my face like an exhilarated labradoodle after a weekend at the kennels.</p>
<p>Down boy! Down, you ridiculous creature! Stop putting your tentacles in my ear. Who wanna biscuit? Do you wanna biscuit? Well, you can't have a biscuit - the only things I have to offer are new PC games. Here's what's coming down the chute this week.</p><!--more-->
<h2>Monday 21st July</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/the-king-is-watching">The King Is Watching</a>, but perhaps his gaze will be lured away by <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3214400/Rainbow_Cloud_A_GAY_RPG/">Rainbow Cloud: A Gay RPG</a>, which demo players have described as a "homoerotic Castlevania".</li>
<li>It's never too early in the week to play a horror game. <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1729740/Luto/">Luto</a> is about the dread of going outside, while <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3076240/True_Nightmare__Roadside_Safe/">True Nightmare: Roadside Cafe</a> is part of a growing category of chillers featuring lonely service jobs.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Tuesday 22nd July</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3504780/Wildgate/">Wildgate</a> is the latest "Sea Of Thieves in space". Based on the trailer, I rate it six warps out of Picard.</li>
<li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1332180/CIPHER_ZERO/">Cipher Zero</a> has you solving glyph puzzles that appear to correspond to evolving pixel landscapes and a mood of mounting historical cataclysm. Slight Gorogoa vibes.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/hell-clock">Hell Clock</a> is a dark fantasy action roguelite inspired by the "War of Canudos" in 19th century Brazil. </li>
</ul>
<h2>Wednesday 23rd July</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/ghost-bike">Wheel World</a> - the latest from Nidhogg devs Messhof - is an open world biking sim about saving spirits and crafting the slickest bloody Penny Farthing known to science. </li>
</ul>
<h2>Thursday 24th July</h2>
<ul>
<li>It's time to bosh some peacocking bosses in <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/wuchang-fallen-feathers">Wuchang: Fallen Feathers</a> (pictured in header) and kill exactly three floors in <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/killing-floor-3">Killing Floor 3</a>. </li>
<li>Today's Bemused Chin-Stroking Award goes to <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2454960/The_Great_Villainess_Strategy_of_Lily/">The Great Villainess: Strategy of Lily</a>, which is a strategy RPG in which you fly around in an airship-sized Twitch feed you can use to distract enemy generals into submission.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Friday 25th July</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2752180/No_Sleep_For_Kaname_Date__From_AI_THE_SOMNIUM_FILES/">No Sleep For Kaname Date</a> is the latest bizarro detective RPG from AI: The Somnium Files creators Spike Chunsoft.</li>
<li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3570070/Paddle_Paddle_Paddle/">Paddle Paddle Paddle</a> is here to kill off any friendships left standing by <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/chained-together">Chained Together</a>.</li>
</ul><p>


I can't remember what the rest of the RPS editorial team are up to this week because I spent the whole morning meeting dying for the loo. I believe there are reviews, guides, news and features in the works. My plans include some tentative follow-up necromancy. How about you?

        </p></div>

        </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/this-week-in-pc-games-wuchang-killing-floor-3-open-world-spirit-biking-and-some-eerie-glyph-puzzles]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ubisoft CEO Blames Outlaws' Struggles On 'Choppy' Star Wars Universe]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/star-wars-outlaws-ubisoft-ceo-shareholders-choppy-1851786615</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ubisoft-ceo-blames-outlaws-struggles-on-choppy-star-wars-universe.1248662/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Ubisoft CEO Yves Guillemot has made some comments on the sales issues of <em>Star Wars Outlaws. </em>The big boss claims that <em>Outlaws</em>’ middling performance last year was, in large part, because the whole <em>Star Wars</em> franchise was in “choppy waters.”</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196842" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Star Wars Outlaws Lost Me With Its Story Trailer" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="138" data-playlist="196842,196406,196566" data-current="196842"><div><p>Star Wars Outlaws Lost Me With Its Story Trailer</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196842/196842_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196842/196842_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196842/196842_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196842/196842_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/22392.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>Guillemot was at <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://edge.media-server.com/mmc/p/zzxygofu/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://edge.media-server.com/mmc/p/zzxygofu/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">a recent shareholders Q&amp;A</a></span>, addressing complaints that last August’s open-world action-adventure didn’t hit the exceedingly high sales milestones that had been hoped for. The game—in which you play as space criminal Kay Vess, rushing around the galaxy committing acts of malfeasance—had “softer than expected” sales on release, which caused a huge drop in Ubisoft’s share value to the lowest it had been in ten years.</p><p>The causes of this were, of course, multi-factorial. The enormous game was buggy, had crappy stealth and lackluster space-based sections, and these significant shortfalls immediately hurt word-of-mouth. It also released into the worst of <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/avowed-microsoft-obsidian-anti-woke-dei-twitter-1851714901&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/avowed-microsoft-obsidian-anti-woke-dei-twitter-1851714901">2024's tiresome campaigning by the wannabe-Nazis of the alt-right</a></span>, with the game committing the twin crimes of featuring a central character who was both a woman <em>and</em> a person of color. Also, people were noticeably getting tired of Ubisoft’s repetitive formula across all its games, and <em>Outlaws</em> took the brunt of this. It was a whole bunch of stuff, but the game’s own failings were a significant part of it. What no one at all was saying was, “It’s because <em>Book of Boba Fett</em> wasn’t that great of a show.”</p><p>During the shareholder meeting, someone in the audience stood up to ask an interminable barrage of questions, during which he asked of <em>Outlaws</em>, “What have you learned from the failure in terms of sales? Have you learned anything in terms of pricing, in terms of marketing?”</p><p> Guillemot replied, “We didn’t reach our sales targets. The game suffered from a number of items.” The first of these he listed was that “the brand that it belonged to was in a bit of choppy waters,” stopping before explaining exactly what he meant by that. He then added that “the game still had a few items that needed to be polished,” rapidly adding that they received polish in the early weeks of release, but saying that it “did affect sales volumes.” Guillemot then described the upcoming Switch 2 port as “a new version of the game.”</p><p>His underplaying of the bugginess of the game, dropped in as an afterthought after attempting to throw the entirety of <em>Star Wars</em> under the bus, is just odd! Was this an attempt to lump the game in with Disney+ TV series <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/star-wars-the-acolyte-canceled-season-2-1851627217&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/star-wars-the-acolyte-canceled-season-2-1851627217"><em>The Acolyte</em></a></span>, which was also the target of a hate campaign from the organized bigots? While the movies had gone quiet since 2021, the TV series were otherwise flying high, with <em>Obi-Wan Kenobi</em>, <em>Ahsoka</em>, and of course the beloved <em>Andor</em> proving critical successes. And if the entire franchise is to blame, then why didn’t this affect EA’s 2023 title <em>Star Wars Jedi: Survivor</em>? EA CEO Andrew Wilson described that game’s sales as “strongly” beating expectations, saying that EA was “overjoyed” with its performance. </p><p>Anyway, shareholders and stock values are the antithesis of creative pursuits, and <em>Outlaws</em> was a fine game released into a broken industry where only astonishing success is acceptable.</p><p>.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/star-wars-outlaws-ubisoft-ceo-shareholders-choppy-1851786615]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>