<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 19:55:57 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Is The 2005 Fantastic Four Movie As Bad As You Remember? Pretty Much]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/fantastic-four-first-steps-2005-movie-mcu-chris-evans-1851757273</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/is-the-2005-fantastic-four-movie-as-bad-as-you-remember-pretty-much.1102395/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/fantastic-four-first-steps-2005-movie-mcu-chris-evans-1851757273<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>We’re coming up on the 20th anniversary of 20th Century Fox’s first attempt at bringing the Fantastic Four to the big screen, and it’s probably been just as long since I watched the 2005 movie in full. Unlike <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/x-men-movies-best-worst-ranked-deadpool-logan-wolverine-1851595435&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/x-men-movies-best-worst-ranked-deadpool-logan-wolverine-1851595435">the <em>X-Men</em></a></span>, the First Family didn’t take off at all in the mid-2000s as the focus of a lucrative film franchise. While the movie got a sequel two years later, Fox axed plans for a full trilogy and we didn’t see Mr. Fantastic, Invisible Woman, Human Torch or The Thing back in theaters until the much-maligned 2015 reboot. With the characters now in the hands of Disney, and MCU entry <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/fantastic-four-first-steps-galactus-thing-trailer-mcu-1851755094&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/fantastic-four-first-steps-galactus-thing-trailer-mcu-1851755094"><em>Fantastic Four: First Steps</em></a></span><em> </em>just a few months out, I wondered if the original 2005 film was as bad as it’s remembered, so I pulled it up on Disney+ and gave it an earnest shot.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196406" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Why This Under-the-Radar AAA Title Is More Than Just A Far Cry Clone" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="102" data-playlist="196406,197298,197284" data-current="196406"><div><p>Why This Under-the-Radar AAA Title Is More Than Just A Far Cry Clone</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196406/196406_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196406/196406_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196406/196406_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196406/196406_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21954.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>Sadly, yeah, it’s pretty bad. The <em>Fantastic Four </em>movie is weighed down by too many of the worst aspects of its mid-2000s era, and I’m not just talking about very ropey CGI. There’s cheesy butt rock that follows the chaotic playboy Johnny Storm in nearly every scene he gets by himself, half the scenes are bogged down by a stilted Disney Channel awkwardness that never quite reaches endearing camp, and there’s even a blatant, intrusive ad for the original Xbox featured prominently onscreen at one point. But even with these aspects put aside, the movie fails to scratch the surface of why the Fantastic Four have been mainstays in Marvel’s catalog.</p><p>Sure, it hits the two major bullet points: The quartet goes up into space and is exposed to a cosmic cloud that alters their DNA and gives them superpowers, and a person going by the name Victor Von Doom is the baddy. The problem is that <em>Fantastic Four </em>portrays the fiery familial passion of the group with the intensity of lightly flavored mineral water. Ioan Gruffudd and Jessica Alba’s Mr. Fantastic and Invisible Woman are devoid of any romantic magnetism, but I’m supposed to believe they have a storied, angsty past as they argue about Reed’s meticulous nature in a flat monotone. Julian McMahon’s Doom is supposed to complete a love triangle, but everyone in this group talks to each other as if they just met at a bar, aren’t interested in each other, and are trying to politely let each other down. Making matters worse, Doom is such a non-presence in the film that when he starts to do villain-y things, it feels like someone speaking up at a party after sitting in the corner alone for an hour. I don’t believe he loves Sue (or even thinks he does) when he proposes to her. I barely believe that he’s human, even before he gets hit with cosmic rays and turns into a deteriorating metallic villain. Doom as a bastard billionaire instead of a mystical tyrant probably focus-tested better 20 years ago, but it’s another example of the movie robbing the <em>Fantastic Four </em>of any vibrancy.</p><p>The saving graces of the cast are Chris Evans as the Human Torch and Michael Chiklis as the Thing. Though I’m not thrilled with the throat-destroyingly gravelly voice Chiklis puts on, there are affecting moments when he struggles with his new golem-like appearance, trying to find people who will accept him now rather than cower in fear. Evans is the standout, however, and it’s not surprising that he would be the one to stay in the superhero business after these movies. He lucked out, being the only character who’s happy with this superpowered turn of events, but he’s also the only actor who seems excited to be there.</p><h2 id="h3454"><a id=""></a><strong>Fantastic Four’s biggest problem is that it’s boring</strong></h2><p>While many are wont to claim the Marvel Cinematic Universe is the harbinger of the end of cinema, at least many of its movies aren’t a complete slog. <em>Fantastic Four</em>, on the other hand,<em> </em>carries itself with a dreary level of self-seriousness. It’s a superpowered soap opera that lacks the charisma or chemistry that makes you care about the drama. The stoicism of this film is so suffocating that even Evans’ joy is smothered.</p><p>That’s <em>Fantastic Four</em>’s biggest problem: not the weird deviations from the source material, but just how boring it all is. Emotionally, visually, and cinematically, everything about the film is flat. I’m surprised that its memetic notoriety for being bad has persisted this long because it’s not even bad in any way that’s interesting; it’s simply forgettable. For a group of heroes known as a family above all else, it’s jarring how much this version of the Fantastic Four feels like coworkers acting out a corporate-mandated skit. It’s giving when your corpo boss says “We’re a family” and throws a pizza party.</p><p>It’s encouraging that <em>First Steps </em>seems to have learned some lessons from Fox’s failures, with the group’s proper MCU debut leaning into a distinct retro-future aesthetic that distinguishes it from the rest of the franchise. Hopefully it feels like the proper adaptation the First Family deserves when it premieres on July 25.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Watch Homelander Audition To Be James Bond As Fans Joke: 'Breast Milk, Squeezed Not Pumped']]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/henry-cavill-james-bond-homelander-audition-youtube-1851757227</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/watch-homelander-audition-to-be-james-bond-as-fans-joke-breast-milk-squeezed-not-pumped.1102392/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/henry-cavill-james-bond-homelander-audition-youtube-1851757227<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>In hindsight it feels like Daniel Craig was born to play James Bond, but picking who to play the world’s most iconic spy is is big decision with lots of risks. Many other actors tried out for the role in 2006's <em>Casino Royale </em>and their screen tests were recently uploaded to a small YouTube account for the whole world to gawk at. It’s a fascinating inside look at what might have been, and at just how awkward tryouts can be. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="197298" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Live Forever in the Universe of 'New World: Aeternum'" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="108" data-playlist="197298,197284,197260" data-current="197298"><div><p>Live Forever in the Universe of 'New World: Aeternum'</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"></video></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>Antony Starr, who currently plays the sociopathic Nazi superhero Homelander on <em>The Boys</em>, was one of those candidates tapped to do a screen test for the role of MI6's 007. In it, he recites a scene from the <em>GoldenEye </em>screenplay in which <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Oz8TYyn-k40&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Oz8TYyn-k40" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Bond is at a Blackjack table flirting with femme fatale assassin Xenia Onatopp</a></span>. Except instead of being in a fancy hotel, he’s acting from a bed in a random hotel room. </p><p>Starr punctuates a lot of the tit-for-tat dialogue with raised eyebrows and cocking his head to the side. There’s a ton of lip-smacking at the start of every line. It’s not great! But it’s one of the better “what if” <em>Bond</em> screen tests the mysterious Ron South YouTube account has uploaded so far:</p><p>Starr had appeared a bunch in the New Zealand show <em>Mercy Peak</em> at the time but was still basically unknown until he broke out years later with the crime drama <em>Banshee</em>. He’s of course best known now for his unhinged role in <em>The Boys</em>, spawning numerous notorious GIFs and memes in the process. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.gamesradar.com/entertainment/james-bond-movies/homelander-actor-antony-starrs-james-bond-screen-test-for-casino-royale-has-been-leaked-online-and-the-boys-fans-are-all-making-the-same-joke/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.gamesradar.com/entertainment/james-bond-movies/homelander-actor-antony-starrs-james-bond-screen-test-for-casino-royale-has-been-leaked-online-and-the-boys-fans-are-all-making-the-same-joke/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">So as <em>Gamesradar</em> notes</a></span>, existing fans have had a field day going back and imaging his James Bond performance through the lens of Homelander. “Breast milk, squeezed not pumped,” joked one user <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/JamesBond/comments/1iionw2/anthony_starr_james_bond_screen_tests_2005/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/JamesBond/comments/1iionw2/anthony_starr_james_bond_screen_tests_2005/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">on Reddit</a></span>. “Lander, Homelander,” wrote another (<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7vs8tZwRGOs&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7vs8tZwRGOs" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">if you’re not familiar with <em>The Boys </em>then, uh, how do I explain...</a></span>)</p><p>But screen tests are all relative. Moviemakers are looking for something they can work with, cultivate, and shape into what might be best in the final movie once everything is rehearsed, shot, edited, and brought to life with music, sets, costumes, and props. As twitchy and off as Starr’s test looks, Henry Cavill’s was arguably even rougher. </p><p>From the long black hair and facial stubble to the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://boymeetsworld.fandom.com/wiki/Jonathan_Turner&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://boymeetsworld.fandom.com/wiki/Jonathan_Turner" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Jonathan Turner biker jacket</a></span>, it’s all very not Bond. And then Cavill opens his mouth, almost speaking through gritted teeth, appearing almost ponderous at times. It reads like a young boy trying on daddy’s clothes in the mirror. Maybe a good place to explore for a Bond origin movie, but clearly not what the studio was looking for with <em>Casino Royale</em> (Cavill’s full-blown himbo hunk debut didn’t come until 2011's <em>Immortals</em>). </p><p>Of course, the movie’s producers maintain they always wanted Daniel Craig from the start. You can watch his much more polished screen test and see that they maybe had a point, and Starr, Cavill, and others may have just been backups in case the brooding <em>Layer Cake </em>star never said yes. Sean Connery apparently didn’t make a great first impression either when he was scouted for the role all those years ago. Bond author Ian Flemming <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.thegentlemansjournal.com/article/true-story-how-sean-connery-became-james-bond-007/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.thegentlemansjournal.com/article/true-story-how-sean-connery-became-james-bond-007/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">reportedly hated him for the part</a></span>. It wasn’t until he walked out of the 1962 premiere of <em>Dr. No </em>that he became a believer. </p><p>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mythwrecked: Ambrosia Island coming to PS5, PS4 in 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/02/mythwrecked-ambrosia-island-coming-to-ps5-ps4-in-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mythwrecked-ambrosia-island-coming-to-ps5-ps4-in-2025.1102383/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/02/mythwrecked-ambrosia-island-coming-to-ps5-ps4-in-2025<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Currently available for Xbox Series, Xbox One, Switch, and PC.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Whitethorn Games [33 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/whitethorn-games">Whitethorn Games</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Polygon Treehouse [7 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/polygon-treehouse">Polygon Treehouse</a> will release exploration friendship <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,028 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure game</a> <em><a title="Games > Mythwrecked: Ambrosia Island [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/mythwrecked-ambrosia-island">Mythwrecked: Ambrosia Island</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,790 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a> and <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,670 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a> in 2025, the companies announced. <span id="more-942431"></span></p><p><em>Mythwrecked: Ambrosia Island</em> first launched for Xbox Series, Xbox One, Switch, and PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2000210/Mythwrecked_Ambrosia_Island/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-us/games/store/mythwrecked-ambrosia-island/9nc4x3lp87tn" target="_blank">Microsoft Store</a> on December 5, 2024.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Whitethorn Games:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>In <em>Mythwrecked: Ambrosia Island</em>, players take on the role of backpacker Alex, who has found herself stranded on the mysterious shores of Ambrosia Island. As she begins to explore her surroundings, she discovers that she is not alone—the island is populated by the gods of Greek myth and legend! However, something is amiss—the gods are unable to remember who they are. In order to find her way home, she must befriend the inhabitants and help them to restore their memories.</p><p>Explore the dynamic island in this non-linear adventure inspired by elements of the Ace Attorney franchise and <a title="Games > A Short Hike [4 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/a-short-hike">A Short Hike</a>. Unravel the story of the island and build friendships with the gods through a unique relationship mechanic. The closer you become, the more they are willing to help Alex with their godly powers. Solve the mystery of Ambrosia Island, save the gods, and help Alex find a way back home!</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Gods <a title="Games > Among Us [8 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/among-us">Among Us</a></strong> – Many Gods call Ambrosia Island home, from Ares to Athena, Hermes to Hades. Tracking them all down is made easier with the Ambrosidex, though some may be harder to meet than others.</li><li><strong><a title="Companies > Treasure [14 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/treasure">Treasure</a> in the Sandbox</strong> – Use the radar signal on the Ambrosidex to hunt for lost godly treasures hidden all over the island! Return them to their rightful owners to help rekindle their memories and learn more about the island’s fate.</li><li><strong>Conversational Wizard</strong> – Explore the island, examine new objects and locations, and talk to others to unlock new conversation topics. Maybe some Gods know something that will help Alex on her adventure, but some sensitive topics may be off-limits until you have earned their friendship.</li><li><strong>Even Gods Need a Friend</strong> – <a title="Companies > Experience [210 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/experience">Experience</a> a non-linear, emotional story about the importance of friendship, family, and community.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span><a title="Platforms > PlayStation [46,883 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation">PlayStation</a> Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Mythwrecked: Ambrosia Island - PlayStation Announce Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/SuOIP4cLrLY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Slime Heroes coming to PS5, PS4 in 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/02/slime-heroes-coming-to-ps5-ps4-in-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/slime-heroes-coming-to-ps5-ps4-in-2025.1102377/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/02/slime-heroes-coming-to-ps5-ps4-in-2025<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Xbox Series, Xbox One, Switch, and PC versions launch February 13.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Whitethorn Games [33 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/whitethorn-games">Whitethorn Games</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Pancake Games [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/pancake-games">Pancake Games</a> will release 3D <a title="Genres > Action [2,468 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a> <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,028 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure game</a> <em><a title="Games > Slime Heroes [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/slime-heroes">Slime Heroes</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,790 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a> and <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,670 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a> in 2025, the companies announced. <span id="more-942430"></span></p><p><em>Slime Heroes</em> will launch first for Xbox Series, Xbox One, Switch, and PC via <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-us/games/store/slime-heroes/9nbr0qg1c3fq" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-us/games/store/slime-heroes/9nbr0qg1c3fq" target="_blank">Microsoft Store</a> on February 13.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Whitethorn Games:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>In <em>Slime Heroes</em>, journey through a whimsical world entrusted to an unlikely hero, a slime, tasked to save it from a mysterious corruption. Explore the expansive 3D world—alone or with a friend—and encounter ferocious enemies, challenging but approachable puzzles, and uncover forgotten treasures. Gain magical gems throughout the world and dynamically combine them to create unique and powerful magical skills that can take down even the most corrupt minions and bosses. Discover a touching story of overcoming expectations, friendship, and forgiveness as you progress because even slimes can be heroes!</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <ul><li><strong>Gain Abilities and Change Them Up On the Fly</strong> – Collect and consume an arsenal of gems obtained from defeating enemies, and dynamically combine skills to craft unique attacks that suit your playstyle at any time.</li><li><strong>Play Alone or With a Friend</strong> – Venture off solo or jump into a friend’s game at any time for a fun couch and online <a title="Genres > Co-Op [230 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer/co-op">cooperative</a> adventure. With a shared loot system, you’ll both be able to create complimentary abilities to take on the fiercest corrupted enemies.</li><li><strong>Travel Across an Expansive World</strong> – Explore six distinct regions in a vibrant, vast open world and meet the gods that rule over each region. Discover secret passageways, hidden areas and unique puzzle dungeons each with their own challenges to overcome.</li><li><strong>Make Your Slime Your Own</strong> – Give your slime some personality as you customize their face and colors to your liking. Find hats throughout the map that not only give your slime that little extra pizazz but also provide helpful stat buffs, keeping you fashionable and ready for battle.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span><a title="Platforms > PlayStation [46,883 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation">PlayStation</a> Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Slime Heroes - PlayStation Announce Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/pbmn_oLG7uU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dungeons of Hinterberg coming to PS5, PS4 on March 13]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/02/dungeons-of-hinterberg-coming-to-ps5-ps4-on-march-13</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dungeons-of-hinterberg-coming-to-ps5-ps4-on-march-13.1102374/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/02/dungeons-of-hinterberg-coming-to-ps5-ps4-on-march-13<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Currently available for Xbox Series, Xbox One, and PC.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Curve Games [55 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/curve-games">Curve Games</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Microbird [5 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/microbird">Microbird</a> will release single-player <a title="Genres > Action RPG [1,489 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg/action-rpg">action RPG</a> and social <a title="Genres > Simulation [643 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/simulation">simulation game</a> hybrid <em><a title="Games > Dungeons of Hinterberg [5 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/dungeons-of-hinterberg">Dungeons of Hinterberg</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,790 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a> and <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,670 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a> on March 13, the companies <a href="https://twitter.com/MicrobirdGames/status/1887517123456430204" target="_blank">announced</a>. Wishlisting is available now via <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/concept/10007196" target="_blank">PlayStation Store</a>. <span id="more-942461"></span></p><p><em>Dungeons of Hinterberg</em> first launched for Xbox Series and PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1983260/Dungeons_of_Hinterberg/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a>, <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/p/dungeons-of-hinterberg-854b1e" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Epic Games Store</a>, and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-us/games/store/dungeons-of-hinterberg/9pgx472j0rjp" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Microsoft Store</a> on July 18, 2024, followed by Xbox One on December 4, 2024.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Curve Games:</p><blockquote><p>Welcome to Hinterberg, a new tourist hotspot in the idyllic Austrian Alps! As Luisa, your escape from the treadmill of corporate life quickly unravels when the mysterious local dungeons stir back into life once more. Will you restore peace to this once-serene alpine paradise, or be sent straight back to your humdrum life back home?</p><p>Every inch of Hinterberg has been crafted with a captivating art style you’ll want to savor. Whether you’re snowboarding down a glacier, climbing mountains, or taking in the lakeside scenery, there’s so much available to explore.</p><p>Hinterberg’s dungeons are packed full of playful puzzles designed to surprise and challenge you. Get your thinking cap on and use every spell at your disposal to tackle each dungeon’s unique puzzling twist. Monsters lurk around every corner in Hinterberg, and your sword and magic skills are essential for keeping them at bay. Harness the wind, conjure a hoverboard out of thin air, or freeze your enemies in a jelly block.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Explore the world or conquer dungeons by day, then spend your evenings forging friendships with the locals and other adventurers in town. Some will help you get stronger, while others are here strictly for the excitement and the selfies. Stop by Olivia’s Store in town and browse through a collection of stylish outfits! Once you’re decked out in your finest, simply fire up Photo Mode where you can apply filters, poses and overlays to capture a lasting memory of your very own Luisa.</p></blockquote></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The First Twitch Stream From The International Space Station Is Happening On February 12]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-first-twitch-stream-from-the-international-space-station-is-happening-on-february-12/1100-6529302/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-first-twitch-stream-from-the-international-space-station-is-happening-on-february-12.1102371/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-first-twitch-stream-from-the-international-space-station-is-happening-on-february-12/1100-6529302/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529302">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">NASA will be hosting its first-ever Twitch stream from the International Space Station (ISS) next week. The National Aeronautics and Space Administration made the announcement via its official X (formerly Twitter) account, and shared some details on what viewers can expect from the stream.</p><p dir="ltr">"This Twitch event from space is the first of many," said Brittany Brown, who directs NASA's Office of Communications Digital and Technology Division. "We spoke with digital creators at TwitchCon about their desire for streams designed with their communities in mind, and we listened. In addition to our spacewalks, launches, and landings, we’ll host more Twitch-exclusive streams like this one. Twitch is one of the many digital platforms we use to reach new audiences and get them excited about all things space."</p><p>The stream itself will take place on the ISS--roughly 250 miles above Earth's surface--and will feature appearances from NASA astronauts Don Pettit (who is currently aboard the ISS) and Matt Dominick (who recently returned to Earth after participating in NASA's Crew-8 mission). The spacefaring duo will discuss topics like daily life aboard the ISS and the microgravity experiments currently being performed on board, while also highlighting "ways for Twitch users to engage with NASA, including citizen science projects and science, technology, engineering, and math programs designed to inspire the Artemis Generation."</p><p dir="ltr">The Artemis Generation refers to the astronauts who will explore Earth's moon as a part of NASA's Artemis Program.</p><p dir="ltr">"We will collaborate with commercial and international partners and establish the first long-term presence on the Moon," the <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/artemis/" rel="nofollow ">official Artemis Program website</a> reads. "NASA will land the first woman, first person of color, and first international partner astronaut on the Moon using innovative technologies to explore more of the lunar surface than ever before."</p><p dir="ltr">This isn't the first time NASA has conducted a Twitch livestream, nor is it the first time the agency has broadcast a livestream from the ISS. But according to the <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/news-release/nasa-goes-live-first-twitch-stream-from-space-station/" rel="nofollow ">official NASA website</a>, "This conversation will be the first NASA event [livestreamed] from the International Space Station developed specifically for the agency’s Twitch platform."</p><p>The stream will take place on <a href="https://www.twitch.tv/nasa">NASA's Twitch channel</a> on Wednesday, February 12 at 8:45 AM PT / 11:45 AM ET.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[World of Warcraft finally tackles the housing crisis]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/games/607646/world-of-warcraft-player-housing-details</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/world-of-warcraft-finally-tackles-the-housing-crisis.1102341/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/games/607646/world-of-warcraft-player-housing-details<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>After 20 years, <em>World of Warcraft</em> is finally adding player housing. During its <a href="https://www.youtube.com/live/0rEfOTxr59o?si=pyWkjBlqsZZ0IuAa"><em>Warcraft</em> 30th Anniversary Direct</a> last year, Blizzard delighted players with the surprise announcement that the feature — a long-time staple in other MMOs — was on the way. Now the studio has revealed a bit more information <a href="https://worldofwarcraft.blizzard.com/en-us/news/24176592">with a new blog</a> explaining how it’s all supposed to work.</p><p>In the past, <em>WoW</em> has obliquely flirted with the concept of player housing with the garrison feature from the <a href="https://www.polygon.com/2014/11/26/7297125/world-of-warcraft-warlords-draenor-review-pc-mac-mmo"><em>Warlords of Draenor</em></a> expansion in 2014. Players had their own home base or “garrisons” that they could customize from a pool of buildings, but they couldn’t invite others in to see them or have any say over decor. Player housing, on the other hand, is meant to give players greater control over everything.</p><p>According to Blizzard there are three principles driving the development of player housing in Azeroth: self-expression, sociability, and longevity. The team wants players to be able easily customize their houses and socialize with their friends and guildmates within a feature that’s meant to last for expansions to come.</p><p>Initially, Blizzard plans on implementing only two housing areas, one for each faction. These houses will be arranged into neighborhoods that are either public with everyone free to come and go as they please, or private neighborhoods established and maintained by friend groups or guilds. Decor for these homes will be obtained either by questing or purchasing and are meant to reflect all the different aesthetics of the game’s numerous races, cultures, and locations that make up <em>WoW</em>’s ever expanding world. </p><p>Interestingly,<em> WoW</em> has also said it wants to make player housing available for everyone which included a very pointed shot across the bow at one of <em>WoW</em>’s biggest competitors —<em> Final Fantasy XIV</em> — which has had player housing for several years. As a player of the “critically acclaimed MMORPG,” I can tell you the requirements for obtaining housing (and <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/buying-a-house-in-final-fantasy-14-left-me-a-broken-woman/">the hoops you have to go through to actually get and keep one</a>) <a href="https://www.polygon.com/24115574/how-to-get-a-house-apartment-lottery-wards-plots">are so onerous</a> that it’s never been worth pursuing. It’s good that Blizzard is differentiating its housing initiative from others by making it clear what players can expect in that regard.</p><p>“If you want a house, you can have a house,” Blizzard’s post read. “No exorbitant requirements or high purchase costs, no lotteries, and no onerous upkeep (and if your subscription lapses, don’t worry, your house doesn’t get repossessed!).” </p><p>Blizzard hasn’t given a timeline on when housing will be implemented. The company released its latest expansion <em>War Within</em>, last year as the first part of its <a href="https://www.theverge.com/games/2023/11/3/23945426/blizzard-announces-the-next-three-wow-expansions">three-expansion long continuous story</a> dubbed “The Worldsoul Saga.” Housing could come as soon as a <em>War Within</em> patch or when the next expansion, <em>Midnight</em>, releases likely sometime in 2026.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indiana Jones and the Great Circle Is Proof 'You Don't Need AI to Steal My Soul,' Harrison Ford Says]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-is-proof-you-dont-need-ai-to-steal-my-soul-harrison-ford-says</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-is-proof-you-dont-need-ai-to-steal-my-soul-harrison-ford-says.1102335/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-is-proof-you-dont-need-ai-to-steal-my-soul-harrison-ford-says<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Indiana Jones actor Harrison Ford has said Troy Baker playing the beloved character in video game Indiana Jones and the Great Circle is proof "you don't need artificial intelligence to steal my soul."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Ford discussed alleviating control of Indy with <a href="https://www.wsj.com/style/harrison-ford-shrinking-1923-captain-america-7b1f9b3f" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Wall Street Journal Magazine</a>, saying he was very happy with the performance of The Last of Us actor Baker.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"You don’t need artificial intelligence to steal my soul," Ford said. "You can already do it for nickels and dimes with good ideas and talent. He did a brilliant job, and it didn’t take AI to do it."</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/indiana-jones-devs-interview-machine-games-lucasfilm-games">The Great Circle arrived in December as an "authentic"</a> but maybe not canonical entry in the long running series, which received its first new film in a long time in 2023 with Indiana Jones and the Dial of Destiny.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/indiana-jones-and-the-dial-of-destiny-review">This wasn't well received at all</a>, however, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-review">while the game was</a>, so the creatives behind the franchise might be inclined to go in this new direction instead of having Ford put the hat back on.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The legendary actor of Star Wars, Indiana Jones, and soon Marvel fame is one of many creatives to criticize the use of AI in films and other forms of media, with the likes of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/tim-burton-slams-ai-generated-artwork">Tim Burton calling AI generated art "very disturbing"</a> and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nicolas-cage-calls-ai-performances-a-dead-end-as-robots-cannot-reflect-the-human-condition">Nicolas Cage calling it a "dead end."</a></p><p data-cy="paragraph">Several voice actors have rallied against it too, including <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/gta-5-actor-ned-luke-calls-out-bullst-ai-chatbot-that-uses-his-voice">Grand Theft Auto 5's Ned Luke</a> who called out a chatbot which used his voice. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-witcher-voice-actor-doug-cockle-calls-ai-inevitable-but-dangerous">The Witcher voice actor Doug Cockle also told IGN that AI was "inevitable" but "dangerous"</a>, sharing in Luke's assessment that chatbots and similar uses are "effectively robbing [voice actors] of income."</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Ryan Dinsdale is an IGN freelance reporter. He'll talk about The Witcher all day.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Paradox Interactive to acquire Haemimont Games]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/02/paradox-interactive-to-acquire-haemimont-games</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/paradox-interactive-to-acquire-haemimont-games.1102332/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/02/paradox-interactive-to-acquire-haemimont-games<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
        </ul>

    
    <p><span>Acquisition expected to close within a few days.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Paradox Interactive [103 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/paradox-interactive">Paradox Interactive</a> has signed an agreement to acquire all shares in <em><a title="Games > Jagged Alliance 3 [6 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/jagged-alliance-3">Jagged Alliance 3</a></em> developer <a title="Companies > Haemimont Games [11 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/haemimont-games">Haemimont Games</a>, the companies <a href="https://www.paradoxinteractive.com/media/press-releases/press-release/paradox-interactive-acquires-haemimont-games" target="_blank">announced</a>. The acquisition, the purchasing price of which was not disclosed, is expected to close within a few days. <span id="more-942636"></span></p><p>Following the acquisition, the current leadership and development team of Haemimont Games will remain active with the studio, and the studio’s ongoing projects will remain in development.</p><p>“We are very happy to welcome Haemimont Games to Paradox!” said Paradox Interactive CE Fredrik Wester in a press release. “They bring a tight-knit team with long experience in developing <a title="Genres > Management [27 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/management">management games</a> with many well received projects in their portfolio. Moreover, they have a strong creative streak, technology developed for their niche, a new [intellectual property] in development and a strong culture that fits Paradox’s way of working. We have strong faith in their team and leadership, and our main focus now is to ensure that they can continue to create great games under new ownership.”</p><p>Haemimont Games founder Gabriel Dobrev aded, “We’re delighted to become a part of the Paradox family! The cultural fit between our companies is remarkable, and we already feel at home. This partnership empowers us to push the boundaries of our games, delivering deeper and more intense experiences to our players. It also opens new horizons for our team, technology, and creative processes, which we’re eager to explore. Expect amazing new games from us!”</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Baldur's Gate 3 Patch 8 Update Hammers Out Some Of The Bugs]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/baldurs-gate-3-patch-8-update-hammers-out-some-of-the-bugs/1100-6529301/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/baldurs-gate-3-patch-8-update-hammers-out-some-of-the-bugs.1102329/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/baldurs-gate-3-patch-8-update-hammers-out-some-of-the-bugs/1100-6529301/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-main">

      
                    
  
              <header id="masthead"><nav></nav></header>      
                            <div id="site-wrapper" role="main">
          <div id="default-content">
        
          <p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p>
  
    <article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529301">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/baldurs-gate-3-review-let-freedom-reign/1900-6418131/" data-ref-id="1900-6418131">Baldur's Gate 3</a> may be a work of art, but <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/baldurs-gate-3-patch-8-introduces-cross-play-photo-mode-and-more/1100-6528863/" data-ref-id="1100-6528863">Patch 8</a> remains a work in progress. A select group of players were invited to take part in Larian Studios' stress test for Patch 8, which is still ongoing. However, Larian has already put together an update that addresses some of the bugs that have been uncovered in Patch 8.</p><p>As laid out in <a href="https://baldursgate3.game/news/stress-test-update-1_135" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">a new post by Larian Studios</a>, there don't appear to be any game-breaking bugs in Patch 8. But there are issues that have come up in several areas, including the newly added Photo Mode. Now, creatures will supposedly obey the "look at the camera" command, and dragonborn won't lose their tails in the pictures. </p><p>Cross-play is another big addition of Patch 8, which is meant to connect players from consoles and PCs. This update only has a small number of fixes, but Larian notes that "we are still investigating instances of cross-play not working as intended." Other changes are meant to smooth out unintended effects, including an "issue causing the Flaming Fist armor to clip and generally freak out a bit."</p><p>Patch 8 Update 1 is expected to go live later today, but only for Baldur's Gate 3 players who were invited to take part in the stress test. Everyone else will get the complete Patch 8 after it receives refinement from Larian. After Larian wraps up its work on Patch 8, the studio will turn its full attention to its next project, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/baldurs-gate-3-dev-now-giving-full-attention-to-next-game-codenamed-excalibur/1100-6528758/" data-ref-id="1100-6528758">codenamed Excalibur</a>. Baldur's Gate 3 is almost certainly going to get a sequel, which <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/hasbro-hopes-next-baldurs-gate-game-is-here-before-2050/1100-6522712/" data-ref-id="1100-6522712">will be developed by another studio</a>.</p><p>You can find the Patch 8 Update 1 notes below.</p><h3>Gameplay</h3><ul><li>Fixed containers inside inventories not scattering their contents when they get destroyed, which could potentially lead to key quest items getting lost for good.</li><li>Fixed a bug causing Oath of the Crown paladins to lose spell slots instead of gaining them when levelling up.</li><li>Fixed an issue where picking up items from the ground in multiplayer could then block movement via the controller stick.</li><li>Fixed the Wild Shape: Panther's Prowl action and Prowling condition not working correctly.</li><li>Fixed a bug where items getting added to the inventory would lose their conditions. This could cause, for example, the Elemental Cleaver buff to disappear when the imbued weapon is thrown.</li><li>Shadow Blade will now retain the behavior of being locked to the caster when upcast.</li></ul><h3>Photo Mode</h3><ul><li>Added an in-game pop-up for Photo Mode that triggers at the beach at the start of the game and can be found in the Journal.</li><li>Updated Photo Mode's screenshot function on Steam Deck so that it uses Steam's proprietary screenshot function, so you can access your photos more readily from the Steam Screenshots page.</li><li>Prevented characters from being able to pop into private cutscenes while activating Photo Mode when playing in multiplayer.</li><li>Hid the 'Toggle Photo Preview' legend while taking screenshots via Steam's screenshot function.</li><li>Fixed Photo Mode making the screen go blurry when opened on split screen.</li><li>Added camera shutter SFX when taking a photo in Photo Mode.</li><li>Fixed the Attacking and Jumping poses for wolves.</li><li>Fixed a cross appearing in the middle of the screen when the Vignette is at its thickest setting.</li><li>Fixed some creatures not listening when you select the 'Look At Camera' option.</li><li>Fixed the game sometimes freezing when switching quickly between tabs in Photo Mode.</li><li>Improved the Depth of Field sliders so the strength and distance scale in proportion to the slider itself.</li><li>Fixed an issue causing dragonborn tails to appear detached from the body.</li><li>The Grasping Vine's poses now work correctly.</li></ul><h3>Cross-Play</h3><ul><li>Fixed an issue that could get the client stuck in a loading screen if the client unfriends the host and then clicks 'Join Party' after re-adding the host.</li><li>Fixed some of the PS5 splashscreens not showing up when they should.</li><li>Fixed a crash at the start of combat.</li></ul><h3>Subclasses</h3><ul><li>The Booming Blade tooltip now updates its values when upcast.</li><li>Fixed an inaccurate bonus value in the Rakish Audacity tooltip.</li><li>Updated Toll the Dead and Bursting Sinew to work with Potent Cantrip and deal half damage on saves.</li><li>Fixed Pact of the Blade's Extra Attack being added to Deepened Pact even if you didn't choose Pact of the Blade.</li></ul><h3>Art</h3><ul><li>Fixed an issue causing the Flaming Fist armor to clip and generally freak out a bit.</li></ul><h3>UI</h3><ul><li>Fixed a bug with Gale's donation UI preventing you from feeding him magical items.</li><li>All of the Hexblade's class actions and subclass features are now shown correctly in Character Creation.</li><li>Fixed button or keyboard shortcut inputs in the UI sometimes not working.</li><li>Fixed some Reaction tooltips like Divine Allegiance not showing some values correctly in the description.</li><li>Fixed a bug causing the UI to lock up when rapidly switching between keyboard and mouse input and controller input.</li><li>Fixed a bug where opening the Main Menu on controller wouldn't automatically select the 'Resume' option at the top of the menu.</li><li>Fixed the condition icons on the party line getting duplicated when transitioning between acts during cross-play.</li><li>Fixed some settings that were missing their wrap-around navigation functionality on controller, preventing you from looping from the last option back to the first option with the same button input.</li><li>Fixed a bug where you'd have to deselect your current passive when respeccing a character before selecting a new one. Now, you can just click the new one.</li><li>Fixed a bug that caused the toggleable Illithid Powers to disappear from the Character Sheet and be uninteractable in the Illithid Powers UI.</li><li>Fixed player avatars not showing up in the multiplayer/cross-play lobby.</li></ul><h3>Scripting</h3><ul><li>With 12 new subclasses arriving in Patch 8, we’ve rechecked some achievements, including ensuring the armed version of Stunning Strike no longer counts as an unarmed attack for the Fists of Fury achievement, and its unarmed variant now does.</li><li>Monks' Unarmed Strike bonus action now also correctly counts toward the Action Surge achievement.</li></ul><h3>Crashes</h3><ul><li>Fixed a crash when trying to start a game from a lobby multiple times.</li><li>Fixed several crashes and freezes related to the UI.</li><li>Fixed a crash on Vulkan when taking a photo in Photo Mode.</li></ul>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article>

    
  

</div>
                      <meta itemprop="seamless-content-list-items" data-list-items="[{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6521083&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/get-all-15-seasons-of-supernatural-for-over-50-off-at-amazon\/1100-6521083\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526471&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/2025-upcoming-games-release-schedule\/1100-6526471\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529091&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/playstation-plus-essential-free-games-for-february-2025\/1100-6529091\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529190&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/how-to-play-the-new-battlefield-early-sign-up-for-a-chance-to-get-into-test-program\/1100-6529190\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529257&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/game-pass-members-can-upgrade-to-avoweds-90-premium-edition-for-a-fraction-of-the-price\/1100-6529257\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529202&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/the-last-of-us-season-2-will-introduce-a-character-who-was-only-mentioned-in-the-games\/1100-6529202\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529255&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/these-analysts-expect-the-switch-2-will-launch-for-400\/1100-6529255\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529223&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/the-batman-beyond-complete-series-blu-ray-is-cheap-right-now\/1100-6529223\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529210&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/how-long-is-civilization-7-turns-to-win-and-playthrough-estimates\/1100-6529210\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529270&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/25-years-into-the-sims-ea-is-still-making-the-same-mistakes\/1100-6529270\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529226&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/helldivers-2-players-can-now-dig-their-way-out-of-trouble-with-a-shovel\/1100-6529226\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529204&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/treyarch-co-founder-pleads-guilty-to-crashing-drone-into-firefighting-plane\/1100-6529204\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529242&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/destiny-2-episode-heresy-best-builds-for-hunter-warlock-and-titan\/1100-6529242\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529240&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/the-united-kingdom-wont-change-its-laws-to-address-games-going-offline\/1100-6529240\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529246&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/live-action-legend-of-zelda-fan-film-gets-shut-down-by-nintendo\/1100-6529246\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529236&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/the-last-of-us-season-2-timeline-wont-be-same-as-the-game\/1100-6529236\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529183&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-guides-hub\/1100-6529183\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6507171&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/disney-dreamlight-valley-recipes-list\/1100-6507171\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529268&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/rooster-teeth-is-back-from-the-dead-with-one-of-its-original-founders-in-charge\/1100-6529268\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529195&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/triguns-new-deluxe-edition-manga-is-50-off-at-amazon\/1100-6529195\/&quot;}]">
            </div>
              
    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon Prime Members Get These Free Games In February]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/amazon-prime-members-get-these-free-games-in-february/1100-6529144/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/amazon-prime-members-get-these-free-games-in-february.1102323/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/amazon-prime-members-get-these-free-games-in-february/1100-6529144/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529144">

            
            
    


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Amazon has revealed the free PC games coming to Prime Gaming in February, and the lineup includes games like Wolfenstein: Youngblood, BioShock Infinite Complete Edition, Deus Ex: Human Revolution Director's Cut, and many more.</p><p>The first set of freebies is available now, including BioShock Infinite Complete Edition, Surf World Series, AK-xolotl: Together, Sands of Auro, and The Talos Principle. More games will be added in batches debuting on February 13, February 20, and then concluding for the month on February 27.</p><p>As a reminder, all of the free games that you claim through Prime Gaming are yours to keep forever, even if your subscription expires. If you aren't a member, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/prime/pipeline/signup?tag=gamespot-promos-20&amp;tag=gamespot-buybutton-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">you can sign up for Amazon Prime</a> for as little as one month to take advantage of the subscription and the freebies offered through it.</p><h2>Prime Gaming free games for February 2025</h2><h3><strong>Available now</strong></h3><ul><li>BioShock Infinite Complete Edition</li><li>Surf World Weries</li><li>AK-xolotl: Together</li><li>Sands of Aura</li><li>The Talos Principle: Gold Edition</li></ul><h3>February 13</h3><ul><li>Stunt Kite Party</li><li>The Smurfs 2 - The Prisoner of the Green Stone</li><li>Hardspace: Shipbreaker</li><li>Lysfanga: The Time Swift Warrior</li><li>Dark Sky</li></ul><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4439936-free.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4439936" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4439936-free.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4439936"></a><figcaption>Free is a nice price.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4439936-free.jpg"></figure><h3>February 20</h3><ul><li>Wolfenstein: Youngblood</li><li>El Hijo - A Wild West Tale</li><li>Colt Canyon</li><li>Republic of Jungle</li><li>Royal Romances: Cursed Hearts Collector's Edition</li></ul><h3>February 27</h3><ul><li>Night Reverie</li><li>Sine Mora EX</li><li>Redemption Reapoers</li><li>Yes, Your Grace</li></ul><p>Prime subscribers will also be able to the following games in February via the Prime Gaming Luna channel:</p><ul><li>Fallout 3: Game of the Year Edition</li><li>Fallout New Vegas: Ultimate Edition</li><li>Fortnite</li><li>Lego Fortnite</li><li>Rocket Racing</li><li>Fortnite Festival</li><li>Trackmania</li></ul>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          

                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Report: Hi-Rez Studios laid off dozens of developers from Smite team]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/hi-rez-studios-cut-dozens-of-staff-from-smite-team</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/report-hi-rez-studios-laid-off-dozens-of-developers-from-smite-team.1102317/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/hi-rez-studios-cut-dozens-of-staff-from-smite-team<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="captioned-content" data-testid="featured-image"><p><span>Image via Hi-Rez Studios.</span></p></div><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Smite </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/hi-rez-studios-pulling-the-plug-on-divine-knockout-and-realm-royale-reforge">Realm Royale</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"><span> </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">developer Hi-Rez Studios seems to have conducted layoffs this week. Nearly 30 employees (at time of writing) revealed they were impacted on social media, and their posts have been compiled into a single </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Smite/comments/1ij5sjy/hirez_layoffs_megathread/">Reddit</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> megathread.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">A reason for the layoffs has currently not been disclosed. According to </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:7293312305092599809/">Gaming World's Jake Lucky</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, these cuts are "massive" and seem to primarily impact the </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Smite </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">team, which is developing the sequel </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Smite 2</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Hi-Rez previously laid off workers </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/hi-rez-studios-lays-off-staff-to-ensure-smite-2-s-long-term-success">October 2024</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, targeting the cosmetic and system features teams across its various subsidiaries. This new round looks to be more widespread: producers, designers, programmers, and esports commentators are among those affected.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">With last year's cuts, CEO Stewart Chisam explained the studio eliminated staff to ensure </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Smite 2's </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">long-term success. Chisam's X account has been deleted since then, and at time of writing, a statement on today's layoffs has not been published to LinkedIn or other channels.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">This makes Hi-Rez the latest developer to cut staff this week, preceded by </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/report-probablymonsters-conducting-more-layoffs-after-pledging-to-build-stable-home-for-developers-">ProbablyMonsters</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/iron-galaxy-lays-off-66-developers-in-last-resort-lifesaving-effort">Iron Galaxy</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/31st-union-head-michael-condrey-reportedly-fired-after-project-ethos-reveal">31st Union</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer has reached out to Hi-Rez for comment, and will update when a response is given.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Contributing Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">A Kansas City, MO native, Justin Carter has written for numerous sites including IGN, Polygon, and SyFy Wire. In addition to Game Developer, his writing can be found at io9 over on Gizmodo. Don't ask him about how much gum he's had, because the answer will be more than he's willing to admit.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vowels Are Back As ESA Announces New Conference]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/esa-iicon-e3</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/vowels-are-back-as-esa-announces-new-conference.1102299/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://aftermath.site/esa-iicon-e3<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>From the minds that brought you the alliterative Electronic Entertainment Expo (E3), the ESA today announced the Interactive Innovation Conference, which they are calling "iicon" and not I2, and which is set to take place in Las Vegas in 2026.</p><p>According to the ESA’s <a href="https://www.theesa.com/entertainment-software-association-unveils-iicon-game-changing-thought-leader-summit-to-harness-the-power-of-interactive-entertainment-and-shape-the-future-of-business-and-culture/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">press release</a>, iicon will be “a first-of-its-kind event designed to connect visionaries, thought leaders and innovators from across industries to harness the power of interactive entertainment.” Who are those visionaries? Participants confirmed so far include EA, Epic, Microsoft, Sony, Take-Two, Ubisoft, Square Enix, and Nintendo, among others. What are the industries these visionaries hail from across? Video games.&nbsp;</p><p>You might now be asking yourself what about this is, as the ESA states, first-of-its-kind, and not just a more embarrassingly-named E3. It looks like the “invitation-only” conference aims to focus on where video games connect to other fields, with the event’s <a href="https://www.iicon.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">website</a> saying that “iicon promises to bring together a broad spectrum of sectors that converge with interactive entertainment, including film, television, and music, as well as sports, healthcare, education, finance, and more.” The site promises that “attendees will gain exclusive access to visionary keynotes, engaging discussions and workshops, and elite networking opportunities,” which would suggest more of a DICE or GDC-style event than E3’s presentations and show floor.&nbsp;</p><p>The press release quotes several game industry execs sweatily insisting that video games are interesting to fields outside of video games. “The games industry is constantly evolving, and the intersection with other disciplines is more pronounced than ever before,” says <a href="https://aftermath.site/amazon-lays-off-180-employees-in-its-games-division" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Amazon Games</a> VP Christoph Hartmann. <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/gaming-industry/ubisoft-closes-another-studio-announces-layoffs-at-3-more-as-part-of-ongoing-efforts-to-prioritize-projects-and-reduce-costs/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ubisoft</a>’s Laurent Detoc says that “video games push the boundaries of technology and creativity, extending far beyond entertainment.” With companies like <a href="https://aftermath.site/wb-earnings-zaslav" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Warner Bros.</a> and <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-us/editorial/playstation-goes-to-the-movies/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Sony</a> desperately trying to turn their games into everything that isn’t games in order to make lines across the world go up, it feels like iicon is an attempt to pivot away from E3’s gamer reputation, with the iicon site encouraging potential attendees to go “beyond entertainment” and “align your brand with a rapidly growing industry… being used to drive positive growth in the areas that matter most.”&nbsp;</p><p>E3, which began in 1995, was <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/entertainment/video-games/2023/12/12/e3-permanently-canceled/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">officially cancelled</a> in 2023, after several years of decline and the impact of covid on the games industry and live events. <a href="https://aftermath.site/tag/geoff-keighley" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Geoff Keighley</a> has done his best to give E3 a run for its money and fill the space left by its absence, with the leg up of “Keigh-3” being a much more fun name than “iicon.”&nbsp;</p></div><div><h2>Stay in touch</h2><p>Sign up for our free newsletter</p></div><div><h2><span>More from Aftermath</span></h2><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/all">See all posts<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="#000" stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round"><path d="M5 12h13m-6-7 7 7-7 7"></path></svg></a></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Where is Cache in Counter-Strike 2? (Answered)]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/where-is-cache-in-counter-strike-2-answered/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/where-is-cache-in-counter-strike-2-answered.1102278/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/where-is-cache-in-counter-strike-2-answered/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>The fluctuating map pool of Counter-Strike keeps the iconic first-person shooter from getting stagnant, but CS2 players have not gotten to (officially) experience Cache yet. In fact, Cache has not been in <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/cs2-adds-train-to-map-pool/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the “active duty map pool”</a> for years, and the last time it was played at a Major was before the COVID-19 pandemic.</p>



<p>So where is Cache?</p>



<p><em>Before you jump below, consider&nbsp;<a href="https://trk.clash.gg/click?o=2&amp;a=47&amp;c=11&amp;sub_id1=Best4" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">trying your luck on Clash.gg</a>&nbsp;– you could turn your unwanted skins into something much more valuable (18+ only)</em></p>



<h2 id="h-why-is-cache-not-in-counter-strike-2">Why Is Cache Not in Counter-Strike 2?</h2>



<p>Cache is not in CS2 yet because the the original map creator, Shawn “FMPONE” Snelling, is still remaking it. According to the creator’s Discord, a portion of the map areas are complete, but this update was last made in July 2024. The areas that are supposedly complete are the A site, A Main, A Long, B Halls, B Checkers, B Site, Garage, Middle, and the T Spawn. This leaves areas like CT Spawn, A Truck, Highway, Z, Heaven, and Tree as potentially still being worked on.</p>



<p>FMPONE is one of the three original creators of Cache for CS:GO, along with Sal “Volcano” Garozzo and Lenz “penE” Monath. While the other two have gone on to other projects, FMPONE has created other maps such as Santorini and Thera. However, those maps never reached the active duty map pool, and fans continued to clamor for a remade Cache.</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>Back in late 2023, after CS2 was originally announced, FMPONE <a href="https://x.com/FMPONE/status/1645147213205520385" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">did confirm</a> that he would remake Cache. However, he opted to focus on creating his new maps first. Still, throughout 2024, FMPONE released a series of images teasing the return of Cache and showing progress on the remake. Every update that’s been posted has been met with a wave of excitement from long-time players who are eagerly awaiting the debut of a new look Cache.</p>



<h2 id="h-when-is-cache-coming-to-cs2">When is Cache Coming to CS2?</h2>



<p>The last public update fans saw of Cache though came back in October, with a collection of screenshots showing T spawn, the CT truck angle of A site, and other areas. Prior to this update, fans were treated to new screenshots every month. But as of February 2025, it’s been more than three months since the last Cache update. Is FMPONE focused on other things at this time? Or is the radio silence building to a soon-to-be-revealed surprise launch?</p>



<p>Do you want to see Cache officially return to CS2? Let us know in the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<p><em>If you want to unlock free daily cases and rewards in CS2,&nbsp;<a href="https://trk.clash.gg/click?o=2&amp;a=47&amp;c=11&amp;sub_id1=Best4" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">check out Clash.gg</a>&nbsp;(18+ only)</em></p>



<hr>



<p>Stay tuned to Insider Gaming for the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/category/esports/">latest esports news</a>. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bandai Namco has quietly laid off over 100 employees since spring 2024]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/bandai-namco-has-quietly-laid-off-over-100-employees-since-spring-2024</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/bandai-namco-has-quietly-laid-off-over-100-employees-since-spring-2024.1102275/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/bandai-namco-has-quietly-laid-off-over-100-employees-since-spring-2024<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">It appears the number of Bandai Namco staff has quietly shunk for nearly a full year.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Per </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://automaton-media.com/en/news/bandai-namco-studios-staff-silently-reduced-by-over-100-people-japan-pension-service-database-shows/">Automaton</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, the online database for </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www2.nenkin.go.jp/do/search_section">Japan's Pension Service</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> (JPS) includes the number of insured employees at a company. Bandai Namco's </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.bandainamcostudios.com/en/company/overview">website</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> shows 1,294 employees as of April 1, 2024; the JPS page shows 1,177 employees, meaning 117 people have left between then and now.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">In October 2024, Bloomberg reported the Japanese developer was "</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/report-bandai-namco-is-cutting-its-workforce-and-cancelling-several-titles">pressuring</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">" up to 200 Tokyo-based employees (of a then-overall 1,300 worker headcount) to resign. Alleged actions involved putting team members in rooms with nothing to do, and it was claimed at the time that nearly 100 employees had already left voluntarily.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Why the effort? Last year, Bandai Namco faced a huge loss with its action-MMO, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/production/bandai-namco-online-torches-blue-protocol-and-terminates-publishing-deal-with-amazon-games">Blue Protocol</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. The game was only playable in Japan and was set to be published by Amazon Games in the west, but the developer terminated the deal and killed the game in January 2025.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The internal team that makes </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/bandai-namco-online-faces-insolvency-post-blue-protocol-launch">online games</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> like </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Blue Protocol</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, and which had already shut down </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/bandai-namco-s-i-gundam-evolution-i-to-shut-down-in-november">Gundam Evolution</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"><span> </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">a year after that game's launch, was </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/bandai-namco-dissolving-online-studio-after-blue-protocol-s-collapse">dissolved</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> at the end of 2024.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">More recently, the Bandai Namco subsidiary Reflector Entertainment laid off staff in </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/report-reflector-entertainment-cuts-jobs-after-launching-debut-title-unknown-9">November 2024</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/reflector-confirms-more-layoffs-after-unknown-9-falls-short-of-expectations">January 2025</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. The cuts came after the commercial underperformance of its debut title, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Unknown 9. </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">Plans to expand the game into a transmedia venture have been scrapped, and the studio is now working on a project based on a pre-existing Bandai Namco IP.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Despite these reductions, the developer has recently revealed </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-sales-punch-up-to-5-million-copies">Dragon Ball: Sparking Zero!</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"><span> </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">sold 5 million copies. Its recent </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.bandainamco.co.jp/files/ir/financialstatements/pdf/20250205_en_Presentation.pdf">third quarter earnings</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> for the 2024-2025 fiscal year also noted "favorable results" for </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Elden Ring </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">due to DLC and repeat sales.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer has reached out to Bandai Namco for comment, and will update when a response is given.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Contributing Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">A Kansas City, MO native, Justin Carter has written for numerous sites including IGN, Polygon, and SyFy Wire. In addition to Game Developer, his writing can be found at io9 over on Gizmodo. Don't ask him about how much gum he's had, because the answer will be more than he's willing to admit.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Blind Squirrel Games acquires Colombia-based Distributed Development]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/blind-squirrel-games-acquires-colombia-based-distributed-development</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/blind-squirrel-games-acquires-colombia-based-distributed-development.1102272/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/blind-squirrel-games-acquires-colombia-based-distributed-development<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="captioned-content" data-testid="featured-image"><p><span>Image via Blind Squirrel Games.</span></p></div><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Developer Blind Squirrel Games has expanded into Colombia by purchasing the service-based Distributed Development for an undisclosed amount.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The new offshoot, rebranded to </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://blindsquirrelentertainment.com/news/Colombian-Studio-Acquired-by-BSG">Blind Squirrel Colombia</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, will initially focus on co-developing games for its parent company. Eric Herrera will continue to lead as its studio director, and the team is expected to expand "significantly" to 25-30 employees by the end of 2025.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">In the announcement, Herrera noted his team previously worked with Blind Squirrel on projects such as </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Age of Darkness: Final Stand's </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">multiplayer. To him, those team-ups "made clear that formally joining forces would be mutually beneficial. Beyond our studio initiatives, we also look forward to also playing a central role in nurturing and growing talent in the region."</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Distributed Development's proprietary AI tool a big factor">Distributed Development's proprietary AI tool a big factor</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Before the acquisition, Distributed Development worked with clients such as Microsoft on deep software development. Blind Squirrel hopes to use the Manizales, Colombia-based studio's proprietary AI tool made for Unreal Engine, which it hopes will "improve project efficiency and streamline development, and help the company deliver high-quality game experiences while optimizing resources."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Along with Colombia, Blind Squirrel has teams in California, Texas, and New Zealand. The new get is part of "[our] strategy to continue scaling development efforts and tapping into new talent pools globally," said Blind Squirrel.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Mainly known for co-developing </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>State of Decay 3 </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Warframe Mobile, </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">Blind Squirrel is developing its own original games again. </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Cosmorons, </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">an arcade shooter slated to release later in 2025, is its first non-support project since 2021's Early Access launch for </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Drifters Loot the Galaxy.</span></span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Contributing Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">A Kansas City, MO native, Justin Carter has written for numerous sites including IGN, Polygon, and SyFy Wire. In addition to Game Developer, his writing can be found at io9 over on Gizmodo. Don't ask him about how much gum he's had, because the answer will be more than he's willing to admit.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Sims 4's next expansion lets you run a pet cafe, laundrette, or tattoo parlour - depending what other DLC you own]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/the-sims-4s-next-expansion-lets-you-run-your-own-pet-cafe-laundrette-or-tattoo-parlour</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-sims-4s-next-expansion-lets-you-run-a-pet-cafe-laundrette-or-tattoo-parlour-depending-what-other-dlc-you-own.1102269/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/the-sims-4s-next-expansion-lets-you-run-your-own-pet-cafe-laundrette-or-tattoo-parlour<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div>
        

        <p>And it's launching in March.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/sims-4-business-hobbies-exp.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Eurogamer/EA</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Entrepreneurially minded <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/the-sims-4">The Sims 4</a> players are about to get a whole new set of options, courtesy of the new Businesses &amp; Hobbies expansion - which'll enable the likes of player-run pet cafes and tattoo parlours when it launches on 6th March - depending what other DLC you own.
</p>
<p>
The Sims 4's Businesses &amp; Hobbies Expansion Pack - the 18th major expansion since its release back in 2014 - is, as its name suggests, focused on two key areas. Starting with hobbies, there's talk of Hobby Meet-ups, where Sims can socialise with like-minded individuals, learn to master their chosen craft from mentors during Classes and Lecturers, and perhaps even become mentors themselves if they become sufficiently skilled.
</p>
<p>
Business seems to be where the bulk of the new expansion's focus lies, however, with players able to establish a small business to bring in the Simoleons. It's possible to create a dedicated space on a residential lot to sell your wares to passing customers, or you can build on the new Small Business Venture Lot instead. There's also a new Ticket Kiosk, providing a way to charge customers either one time or by the hour, and players have the choice between hiring staff or running their fledgling enterprise as a family unit.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="The Sims™ 4 Businesses &amp; Hobbies Expansion Pack | Official Reveal Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/LtroCEUo_e4?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>The Sims™ 4 Businesses &amp; Hobbies Expansion Pack | Official Reveal Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/LtroCEUo_e4?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/LtroCEUo_e4?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>The Sims 4 - Businesses &amp; Hobbies Expansion Pack trailer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LtroCEUo_e4" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
As a business grow, Sims earn Business Perks - unlocking new interactions and effects - and there's a Business Renown system enabling players to either run things by the book or to indulge in their unscrupulous side. However, EA notes that becoming a Dreamer or Schemer can impact Sims' lives outside of work.
</p>
<p>
And as for the type of small business players can run, that'll depend on the Sims 4 expansions and game packs they own. With just Businesses &amp; Hobbies installed, players can build business around either the new tattoo skill (which introduces a Tattoo Paint Mode to create custom designs using a growing collection of stamps and stencils) or the new pottery skill. The latter adds a pottery wheel and kiln for Sims to utilise, with players able to make either decorative or functional pieces, and glaze them for the finishing touch.
</p>
<p>
However, if the idea of running a tattoo parlour or pottery shop doesn't appeal, Cats and Dogs expansion owners can open pet cafes, while the Get Together expansion unlocks the ability to run dance clubs and game arcades. City Living unlocks karaoke bars, Get Famous unlocks acting classes, Laundry Day makes it possible to run a laundrette, and Bowling Night is for those that want to open their own bowling alley. And finally, Spa Day is the game pack you'll need if you want to wring your customers dry in the name of relaxation.
</p>
<p>
The Sims 4's Businesses &amp; Hobbies Expansion Pack - which also includes a new world in the form of Nordhaven - launches for all platforms on 6th March. Anyone that picks it up before 18th April gets the Practice Makes Perfect Priscilla Statue, Sweetest Treat Display Case, and Beautiful Flaws Lamp, as <a href="https://www.ea.com/games/the-sims/the-sims-4/news/businesses-and-hobbies-expansion-pack">detailed in EA's announcement</a>.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Former Bioware & EA Devs Reveal New ARPG, Cloudheim]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/former-bioware-ea-devs-reveal-new-arpg-cloudheim/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/former-bioware-ea-devs-reveal-new-arpg-cloudheim.1102260/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/former-bioware-ea-devs-reveal-new-arpg-cloudheim/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Cloudheim is a brand-new multiplayer action RPG from the independent studio Noodle Cat Games. This game comes from a studio comprised of veteran developers from Epic Games, <a href="https://wccftech.com/ea-lays-off-5-of-its-employees-cancels-star-wars-respawn-fps-and-seeks-to-move-away-from-licensed-ips/">EA</a>, Codemasters, Disney, and <a href="https://wccftech.com/dragon-age-the-veilguard-director-leaving/">Bioware</a>. To celebrate the reveal of Cloudheim, the developers have released a gameplay trailer that you can see down below.</p>
<p><iframe title="Cloudheim - Announce Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/bHnpo84ybmM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>This debut title will be set to launch in Q3 2025 for PC, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series X|S. You'll be in for a fun and chaotic time, as there is physics-based combat, as well as plenty of exploration, looting, and base creation in a Norse-inspired world.</p>
<p>"Cloudheim blends the exceptional talent of a veteran team with an experimental, iterative development process informed by science and modern psychology. Every member of the team has a meaningful creative impact, allowing us to push exceptional gameplay quality for our team size, budget, and development time. I'm proud of what we've built, and how the team has proven this process is ultimately better for the ones who matter most - our players," said David Hunt, CEO and Founder of Noodle Cat games.</p>
<p>Cloudheim is set to stand out from the crowd, with a ton of chaos to unleash on the world, as it's a fully breakable world where players can chain together their abilities with other teammates to defeat enemies. Whether this means pulling down pillars to crush enemies, lassoing enemies into tornadoes, or shooting monsters out of cannons, there's plenty of chaos to be had around every corner.</p>
<p>You are given the option to play solo, or you can join forces with up to three of your friends in online co-op, where you will share every weapon and ability unlocked and can work together to explore, uncover secrets, and discover new playable characters as a team.</p>
<p>"Our core gameplay began with a simple question - what if we take the juggling from fighting games and make it the combat foundation in a co-op action RPG?" said David Hunt. "Mix in a hauntingly beautiful world, a chaotic symphony of physics combos, and base customization - that's Cloudheim."</p>
<p>While you will be defeating monstrous foes and goblins, there will also be opportunities to team up with creatures such as a Swordcupine, Blins, and a Gnasher to help you through tough conquests when you need them.</p>
<p>As stated above, this title is set to release later this year. If you want to be kept up to date on this title, the Cloudheim <a href="https://cloudheimgame.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">website</a> will provide all the info you could need on this upcoming ARPG.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Chernobylite 2: Exclusion Zone to Launch on Steam Early Access on March 6]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/chernobylite-2-exclusion-zone-to-launch-on-steam-early-access-on-march-6/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/chernobylite-2-exclusion-zone-to-launch-on-steam-early-access-on-march-6.1102257/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/chernobylite-2-exclusion-zone-to-launch-on-steam-early-access-on-march-6/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Today, Polish developer The Farm 51 announced the early access release date of their upcoming title, <a href="https://wccftech.com/chernobylite-2-exclusion-zone-open-world-sequel-announced-for-2025-pc-requirements-already-available/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Chernobylite 2: Exclusion Zone</a>. The game, which is currently <a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/thefarm51/chernobylite-2-exclusion-zone-an-open-world-sci-fi-rpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener">on Kickstarter to gather funds</a>, will be available on Steam starting on March 6. They also shared a CGI story trailer where we can first glimpse the game's narrative.</p>
<p>Cole Grey, a former military and security guard, lives in a reality where the economy and industry are entirely based on a substance called Chernobylite. With its help, humans have made a real leap forward in civilization. However, the construction of this utopia has been paid for by massive unemployment, pushing people like Cole to the margins of society.</p>
<p>Faced with severe financial problems, he joins the mysterious 'Planewalker' initiative to provide for his family. It soon becomes apparent that there is a shortage of Chernobylite in Cole's universe, and the solution is the morally questionable initiative, which involves traveling to parallel worlds in search of the mineral and obtaining it by any means necessary.</p>
<p>The Planewalker service also requires genetic modifications. Cole must, therefore, physically absorb the essence of the Chernobylite and lose part of his humanity to enhance his physical and intellectual abilities. Seeing no other option for himself, he agrees to the bloody and dangerous service, which results in him being trapped in the most sinister place in the world: the Chornobyl Exclusion Zone. There, he meets a Black Stalker, the Zone's dark leader and silent ruler. Cole's ultimate goal is, of course, to escape the sinister Exclusion Zone and return home.</p>
<p><iframe title="Chernobylite 2: Exclusion Zone Early Access Announcement CGI Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/lEoeb1g88e0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>The Kickstarter campaign for Chernobylite 2: Exclusion Zone is going well so far. With a week left, the game has already surpassed the minimum funding goal while unlocking a few stretch goals, such as the optional first-person combat mode, the return of all guns from the first Chernobylite, weapon customizations, and new locations for both solo play and cooperative missions, one of the sequel's new features. The next stretch goals would unlock a customizable interface for both first-person and third-person views, and a customizable dialogue camera.</p>
<p>The system requirements are also available on the Steam page, so we've embedded them below for those interested. For more info on the game, you can read our <a href="https://wccftech.com/chernobylite-2-qa-20-times-bigger-world-2-3x-longer-playtime/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Gamescom 2024 interview with the developers</a>.</p>
<div><p><strong>Minimum:</strong></p><ul>
<li>
<ul>
<li><strong>OS:</strong>&nbsp;64-bit Windows 10 / 11</li>
<li><strong>Processor:</strong>&nbsp;Intel Core i7-7700K / AMD Ryzen 5 1600X</li>
<li><strong>Memory:</strong>&nbsp;16 GB RAM</li>
<li><strong>Graphics:</strong>&nbsp;Intel Arc A580 / GeForce GTX 1060 6 GB / Radeon RX 580</li>
<li><strong>DirectX:</strong>&nbsp;Version 12</li>
<li><strong>Storage:</strong>&nbsp;150 GB available space</li>
<li><strong>Additional Notes:</strong>&nbsp;Graphics Preset: LOW / Resolution: 1080p / Expected FPS: 30</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
<div><p><strong>Recommended:</strong></p><ul>
<li>
<ul>
<li><strong>OS:</strong>&nbsp;64-bit Windows 10 / 11</li>
<li><strong>Processor:</strong>&nbsp;Intel Core i5-12600K / AMD Ryzen 5 5600</li>
<li><strong>Memory:</strong>&nbsp;16 GB RAM</li>
<li><strong>Graphics:</strong>&nbsp;Intel Arc A770 / GeForce RTX 3060 8 GB / Radeon RX 6700 XT</li>
<li><strong>DirectX:</strong>&nbsp;Version 12</li>
<li><strong>Storage:</strong>&nbsp;150 GB available space</li>
<li><strong>Additional Notes:</strong>&nbsp;Graphics Preset: HIGH / Resolution: 1080p / Expected FPS: 45</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</div>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2's Most Popular Mods All Make The Game Easier, Less Annoying]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-kc2-rpg-mods-easy-hard-pc-1851757081</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/kingdom-come-deliverance-2s-most-popular-mods-all-make-the-game-easier-less-annoying.1102251/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-kc2-rpg-mods-easy-hard-pc-1851757081<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="e892ed94c034b780d9e5ef3e5c8fd93f" data-recommend-id="image://e892ed94c034b780d9e5ef3e5c8fd93f" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Deep Silver / Warhorse Studios</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="e892ed94c034b780d9e5ef3e5c8fd93f" data-recommend-id="image://e892ed94c034b780d9e5ef3e5c8fd93f" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/games/kingdom-come-deliverance-ii&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/games/kingdom-come-deliverance-ii"><em>Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2</em></a></span><em> </em>has only been out for 48 hours and yet it already has a ton of mods available to download and install. The most popular of the lot are all about making the famously grounded and hard RPG easier and less annoying. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196742" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="What Is Dragonsplague? Dragon’s Dogma 2’s Devastating Contagion Explained" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="254" data-playlist="196742,195150,196773" data-current="196742"><div><p>What Is Dragonsplague? Dragon’s Dogma 2’s Devastating Contagion Explained</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196742/196742_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196742/196742_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196742/196742_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196742/196742_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/22297.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>Like the its 2018 predecessor, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-reviews-how-long-witcher-1851754074&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-reviews-how-long-witcher-1851754074"><em>Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2</em></a></span> is a big, sprawling, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-preview-medieval-rpg-1851626849&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-preview-medieval-rpg-1851626849">“authentically medieval”</a></span> open-world RPG that tries to be very immersive and realistic. For example, if you want to save your game in <em>Deliverance 2</em>, you have to either find a bed and sleep in it or brew a special potion that lets you save anywhere. Another example is that you get dirty as you explore and fight, and people react to that, which can cause problems if you’re covered in mud and stink. And while the studio behind the RPG deliberately designed the game to have all this friction and realism, many fans on PC have quickly responded: No, thanks! </p><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.pcgamer.com/games/rpg/that-was-fast-a-modder-already-added-an-unlimited-save-game-feature-to-kingdom-come-deliverance-2/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/rpg/that-was-fast-a-modder-already-added-an-unlimited-save-game-feature-to-kingdom-come-deliverance-2/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">As spotted by <em>PC Gamer</em></a></span>, over on <em>Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2</em>'s <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.nexusmods.com/kingdomcomedeliverance2/mods&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.nexusmods.com/kingdomcomedeliverance2/mods" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Nexus Mods page</a></span>, you can see that two of the most popular mods—with over 50,000 downloads combined—<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.nexusmods.com/kingdomcomedeliverance2/mods/14&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.nexusmods.com/kingdomcomedeliverance2/mods/14" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">simply let you save wherever you want</a></span>, no potion or bed needed. </p><p>Another popular mod with nearly 12,000 installs makes your character <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.nexusmods.com/kingdomcomedeliverance2/mods/59&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.nexusmods.com/kingdomcomedeliverance2/mods/59" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">stay cleaner for longer</a></span>. Yet another lets you carry more stuff. Other popular mods include the ability to skip animations, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.nexusmods.com/kingdomcomedeliverance2/mods/60&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.nexusmods.com/kingdomcomedeliverance2/mods/60" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">make potions last longer</a></span>, and <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.nexusmods.com/kingdomcomedeliverance2/mods/35&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.nexusmods.com/kingdomcomedeliverance2/mods/35" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">gain more XP</a></span>. </p><p>So it seems that while a lot of players, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/KingdomComeRPG/status/1887155053821149227&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/KingdomComeRPG/status/1887155053821149227" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">over a million already</a></span>, love the realism and hard gameplay of<em> Deliverance 2</em>, there are plenty who just want a less “realistic” medieval RPG. That’s the beauty of playing games on a computer; you can always download or make a mod to change how something works. </p><p><em>Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2 </em>is out now on Xbox, PlayStation, and PC. </p><p> .<br></p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Original Halo Trilogy Soundtrack Is Getting A Gorgeous Vinyl Box Set In April]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/original-halo-trilogy-soundtrack-is-getting-a-gorgeous-vinyl-box-set-in-april/1100-6529287/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/original-halo-trilogy-soundtrack-is-getting-a-gorgeous-vinyl-box-set-in-april.1102248/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/original-halo-trilogy-soundtrack-is-getting-a-gorgeous-vinyl-box-set-in-april/1100-6529287/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-main">

      
                    
  
              <header id="masthead"><nav></nav></header>      
                            <div id="site-wrapper" role="main">
          <div id="default-content">
        
          <p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p>
  
    <article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529287">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>The Halo series has some of the most iconic and beloved original soundtracks in gaming history, so it's fitting that the franchise is getting such an elaborate vinyl box set. Fans can <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DMPKSPLJ?tag=gamespot-preorders-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">preorder the Halo Original Trilogy Soundtrack Box Set</a> for $200 (was $211) at Amazon ahead of its April 11 release. The box set includes the soundtracks for the first three Halo games across eight discs. If you are partial to one of these soundtracks, you can preorder each one individually instead. Soundtracks for Halo: Combat Evolved, Halo 2, and Halo 3 also release on April 11.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DMPKSPLJ?tag=gamespot-preorders-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Halo Original Trilogy Original Soundtrack Box Set</a> -- $200 (<del>$211</del>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Halo-Combat-Evolved-Original-Soundtrack/dp/B0DMPKFLJX?tag=gamespot-preorders-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Halo: Combat Evolved Original Soundtrack</a> -- $48 (<del>$51</del>) </li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Original-Soundtrack-Salvatori-Michael-ODonnell/dp/B0DMPKTYY2?tag=gamespot-preorders-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Halo 2 Original Soundtrack</a> -- $72</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Halo-Original-Soundtrack-Martin-ODonnell/dp/B0DMPK6NQL?tag=gamespot-preorders-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Halo 3 Original Soundtrack</a> -- $72 </li></ul><div title="6529287 - Halo Original Trilogy Vinyl Soundtrack" data-embed-type="buylink" data-ref-id="3144" data-template="4" data-size="buylink__listicle" data-title="6529287 - Halo Original Trilogy Vinyl Soundtrack" data-collection="">             <h2>                    <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DMPKSPLJ?tag=gamespot-preorders-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/dp\/B0DMPKSPLJ?tag=gamespot-preorders-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DMPKSPLJ?tag=gamespot-preorders-20">Halo Original Trilogy Vinyl Soundtrack Box Set</a>       </h2>                                   <h3>                      <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DMPKSPLJ?tag=gamespot-preorders-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/dp\/B0DMPKSPLJ?tag=gamespot-preorders-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DMPKSPLJ?tag=gamespot-preorders-20">$200 (was $211) | Releases April 11</a>         </h3>                                                                                                                      <div><p>Each piece of music has been specially remastered for this collection, and in total, there are 83 tracks here from composers Martin O'Donnell and Michael Salvatori. Everything from "Brothers in Arms" to "Finish the Fight" is included. The presentation also looks great, as each disc comes in its own sleeve featuring the game's logo. The sleeves are stored in jackets with full illustrations of Master Chief. Everything is stored inside minimalistic box, but many fans will probably want to display the jacket cover art.</p><p>If you were to buy each soundtrack individually instead, you'd spend $192 at the moment.</p></div>                      </div><h2>Do you need a record player?</h2><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/scale_super/1601/16018044/4439814-lp-1.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4439814" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/scale_super/1601/16018044/4439814-lp-1.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4439814"></a><figcaption>Udreams vinyl record player</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/scale_super/1601/16018044/4439814-lp-1.jpg"></figure><p>If you don't own a record player and don't feel like rummaging through your grandparents' attic for one, the good news is that there are plenty of budget-friendly, modernized record players with vintage designs. Audio quality naturally differs from product to product, but one of the most popular budget models on Amazon is <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Turntable-Belt-Driven-Phonograph-Entertainment-Decoration/dp/B081DSDPMW?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">this $50 record player by Udreamer</a>. Amazon <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/prime/pipeline/signup?tag=gamespot-promos-20&amp;tag=gamespot-buybutton-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Prime members</a> can save 20% right now, dropping the price to only $40. This turntable has two built-in stereo speakers and three speeds. You can also listen to music from your smartphone and other devices via Bluetooth.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/scale_super/1601/16018044/4439815-lp-2.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4439815" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/scale_super/1601/16018044/4439815-lp-2.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4439815"></a><figcaption>Victrola Nostalgic vinyl record player</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/scale_super/1601/16018044/4439815-lp-2.jpg"></figure><p>For something a bit more robust, there's the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Victrola-Nostalgic-Bluetooth-Turntable-Entertainment/dp/B00NQL8Z16?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Victrola Nostalgic</a>. This one also has a vintage-inspired design and built-in stereo speakers, but you're also getting a cassette player, AM/FM radio, CD player, and Bluetooth for music streaming. Normally $160, you can pick this up for $100 through Amazon as part of a time-limited deal.</p><div data-embed-type="pinbox" data-ref-id="4304">  <ul>                              <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/save-on-sid-meiers-civilization-7-preorders-for-pc-mac-early-access-starts-february-6/1100-6525971/">Save On Sid Meier's Civilization 7 Preorders For PC &amp; Mac - Early Access Starts February 6</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/apple-airpods-4-discounted-to-only-100-at-amazon/1100-6526375/">Apple AirPods 4 Discounted To Only $100 At Amazon</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fortnite-festival-riffmaster-guitar-controller-gets-biggest-discount-yet/1100-6528970/">Fortnite Festival Riffmaster Guitar Controller Gets Biggest Discount Yet</a></li>                          <li>         <span>+ Show More More Gaming, Tech, and Entertainment Deals &amp; Preorders Links (5)</span>       </li>          <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/monster-hunter-wilds-preorders-where-to-get-steelbook-edition-and-best-deals/1100-6526687/">Monster Hunter Wilds Preorders - Where To Get Steelbook Edition And Best Deals</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/geforce-rtx-50-series-gpus-launched-today-but-its-not-easy-to-grab-one/1100-6528684/">GeForce RTX 50-Series GPUs Launched Today, But It's Not Easy To Grab One</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/alienware-rtx-50-series-gaming-pcs-are-up-for-preorder-for-a-small-fortune/1100-6529159/">Alienware RTX 50-Series Gaming PCs Are Up For Preorder For A Small Fortune</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/assassins-creed-shadows-preorder-guide-collectors-edition-release-date-bonuses/1100-6523479/">Assassin's Creed Shadows Preorders Include Post-Launch Story Expansion</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/these-discounted-and-new-lego-sets-would-be-perfect-for-valentines-day/2900-6180/">These Discounted And New Lego Sets Would Be Perfect for Valentine's Day</a></li>   </ul> </div>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                        
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/108490194306897153177?rel=author">Darryn Bonthuys</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article>

    
  

</div>
                      <meta itemprop="seamless-content-list-items" data-list-items="[{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529207&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/halo-infinite-doesnt-have-a-fuel-rod-cannon-but-will-have-a-rocket-that-fires-fuel-rods\/1100-6529207\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6473057&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/best-vr-headset\/1100-6473057\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6527183&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/terrifier-3s-very-strange-collectors-box-set-is-available-now-at-amazon\/1100-6527183\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529164&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/popular-call-of-duty-warzone-guns-are-getting-changes-next-week\/1100-6529164\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529140&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/the-sims-1-and-2-are-now-available-on-pc-every-expansion-included\/1100-6529140\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529165&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/clair-obscur-expedition-33-joins-the-list-of-gestating-live-action-movie-adaptations\/1100-6529165\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529170&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/amazon-exclusive-pokemon-tcg-poke-ball-tin-bundles-get-first-discounts\/1100-6529170\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529168&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/marvels-spider-man-2-is-apparently-off-to-rough-start-on-pc\/1100-6529168\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529167&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/classic-cartoon-style-shooter-mouse-p-i-for-hire-wont-have-microtransactions\/1100-6529167\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529169&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/multiversus-shuts-down-in-may-but-can-still-be-played-offline-if-you-update-in-time\/1100-6529169\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529166&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/elden-ring-nightreign-network-test-codes-are-being-scalped-on-ebay\/1100-6529166\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526687&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/monster-hunter-wilds-preorders-where-to-get-steelbook-edition-and-best-deals\/1100-6526687\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529177&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/killing-floor-3-has-three-editions-physical-preorders-available-now\/1100-6529177\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529162&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/diablo-4-season-7-bug-is-letting-players-deal-near-infinite-damage-but-nobody-knows-exactly-why\/1100-6529162\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529182&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/destiny-2-heresy-will-be-missing-some-voice-content-because-of-the-ongoing-actors-strike\/1100-6529182\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6528998&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/civilization-7-how-merchants-and-trade-routes-work\/1100-6528998\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529056&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/civilization-7-how-to-upgrade-towns-into-cities\/1100-6529056\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529057&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/civilization-7-how-to-sail-the-open-ocean\/1100-6529057\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529085&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/civilization-7-how-to-become-a-suzerain-and-what-it-does\/1100-6529085\/&quot;}]">
            </div>
              
    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>