<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 19:06:06 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Baldur’s Gate 3 to Get Cross-Play, 12 New Subclasses, and Photo Mode Next Year]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/baldurs-gate-3-to-get-cross-play-12-new-subclasses-and-photo-mode-next-year/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/baldur%E2%80%99s-gate-3-to-get-cross-play-12-new-subclasses-and-photo-mode-next-year.1046853/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/baldurs-gate-3-to-get-cross-play-12-new-subclasses-and-photo-mode-next-year/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Larian Studios might be <a href="https://wccftech.com/baldurs-gate-3-no-sequel-dlc-larian-dropping-dungeons-and-dragons/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">done</a> with Baldur's Gate 4 or with any potential Baldur's Gate 3 DLCs, but it is not done at all with the base game. After <a href="https://wccftech.com/baldurs-gate-3-patch-7-out-now-on-pc-adds-mod-tools-manager-evil-endings-and-more/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Update 7</a>, which added mod tools and a mod manager as well as evil endings and much more, the team is already <a href="https://x.com/baldursgate3/status/1861823843041481138" target="_blank" rel="noopener">back with a new community update</a> that outlines what's coming to Baldur's Gate 3 next year. As it turns out, it's a lot. The game will be updated to include cross-play multiplayer between all platforms, and Larian is also adding twelve new subclasses and the long-requested Photo Mode. To access the cross-play functionality, you must register for a Larian account, as shown in the screenshot below.</p>

<figure></figure>

<p>From a gameplay standpoint, the twelve new subclasses are by far the more interesting addition. There will be one for each class, as outlined below by the developer.</p>
<p><strong><em>Bard - College of Glamour</em></strong></p>
<p><em>As a College of Glamour Bard, you’ll have the power to heal friends and command enemies in equal measure. Cast Mantle of Inspiration to bestow your allies with 5 temporary hit points. And should an enemy attack while it is cast, they’ll find themselves Charmed. Play your hand correctly and you’ll be able to use this to your advantage with Mantle of Majesty. Target Charmed enemies and you can command them to flee, move closer, freeze, drop to the ground, or drop their weapon.</em></p>

<figure></figure>

<p><strong><em>Barbarian - Path of Giants</em></strong></p>
<p><em>Opt for the Path of Giants, and your newfound giant strength will make it easier for you to yeet friend and foe alike. Forget chugging potions to pump those muscles, these Barbarians benefit from the Giant’s Rage passive that grants both strength and size - allowing you to deal additional damage with Throw attacks. Pockets weighing you down? Not for you and your increased carry capacity!</em></p>
<p><strong><em>Cleric - Death Domain</em></strong></p>
<p><em>As a cleric of death in Baldur's Gate 3, you’ll find a few dark new tricks up your sleeves - from spells that specialize in necrotic damage to three new necromancy cantrips. This includes Toll The Dead, a cantrip that causes 1~8 damage when your cleric rings the bell of impending doom - a number that scales if your target has already been damaged. We’ve also added the homebrewed ability to explode nearby corpses, damaging enemies.</em></p>

<figure></figure>

<p><strong><em>Druid - Circle of Stars</em></strong></p>
<p><em>These Druids look to the stars for answers, taking on one of three Starry Forms for their power - the constellations of the Archer, Chalice, and Dragon. Each one favours a different play style and strategy - the Archer dealing radiant damage with astral arrows, the life-giving Chalice restoring hitpoints to you and others nearby, and the wise Dragon, allowing you to deal damage with an added bonus to constitution rolls. The Starry Forms offer not just a celestial aesthetic but practical, powerful options to enhance your role as a healer, fighter, or strategist.</em></p>

<figure></figure>

<p><strong><em>Paladin - Oath of the Crown</em></strong></p>
<p><em>You’ve been sworn to uphold the principles of law. Stay true to your oath and you'll be rewarded with the power to aid your allies and disrupt your foes. Guide your companions in Baldur's Gate 3 battles with Righteous Clarity, taunt enemies with strategic interrupts, and keep your party standing strong with Divine Allegiance, absorbing their damage while restoring their health.</em></p>
<p><strong><em>Fighter - Arcane Archer</em></strong></p>
<p><em>Mastering the dual arts of magic and marksmanship, the Arcane Archer subclass offers unique skills on top of new shooting animations. Banish foes to the Feywild, removing them from the battlefield for a turn, or unleash Psychic damage that forces enemies to make a Wisdom saving throw or be blinded until the start of their next turn.</em></p>

<figure></figure>

<p><strong><em>Monk - Drunken Master</em></strong></p>
<p><em>Putting the brew in homebrew, as the Drunken Master, you have the ability to consume alcohol straight from your inventory, as well as drink from bottles you see around the Sword Coast, in order to recover Ki. By sharing the bottle with your enemies using Intoxicating Strike, you’ll generate a buff towards your Armour Class and your Chance to hit Drunk targets. Drunk enemies are also susceptible to the Drunken Masters' other abilities, like Sobering Realisation - which sobers up drunk targets, dealing physical and Psychic damage.</em></p>
<p><strong><em>Ranger - Swarmkeeper</em></strong></p>
<p><em>The Swarmkeeper subclass provides Baldur's Gate 3 Rangers with three kinds of deadly swarms to assist them in combat. The Cloud of Jellyfish deals extra lightning damage - potentially shocking your enemy. The Flurry of Moths deals Psychic damage, giving you the potential to Blind your enemy. The Legion of Bees deals piercing damage and forces the enemy to make a strength-saving throw or be knocked back 15ft. Each swarm also has the ability to provide you with teleportation capabilities.</em></p>

<figure></figure>

<p><strong><em>Rogue - Swashbuckler</em></strong></p>
<p><em>This Rogue subclass introduces a range of new actions fit for the piratical life. Play dirty by tossing sand at enemies to Blind them. Flick your weapon at a target to Disarm them. Or use your new Fancy Footwork passive while meleeing your enemy to ensure they can’t make opportunity attacks against you for the rest of your turn.</em></p>
<p><strong><em>Sorcerer - Shadow Magic</em></strong></p>
<p><em>As a Shadow Magic Sorcerer, you deal in a form of magic that makes you deadliest in darkness. This subclass gives its sorcerer Superior Darkvision, as well as the ability to Shadow Walk between places of dim light or darkness. It also lets you call forth the perfectly homebrewed Hound of Ill Omen to harass your foes, and use Strength of the Grave to prevent you from being downed - ideal for those attempting Honour Mode runs.</em></p>

<figure></figure>

<p><strong><em>Warlock - Hexblade</em></strong></p>
<p><em>Hexblade Warlocks in Baldur's Gate 3 make a pact with an entity from the Shadowfell that manifests in the form of magical weapons. Curse your enemies and force their souls to do your bidding. Slay any enemy that isn’t generally an element of nature, construct, giant blob, or already dead, and you’ll be able to raise their spirit from their corpse for ten turns. This new summon can deal necrotic damage and will rip away a chunk of your enemy’s soul to provide your Hexblade Warlock with healing.</em></p>
<p><strong><em>Wizard - Bladesinging</em></strong></p>
<p><em>The Bladesinging subclass merges swordplay with wizardry. Expect new spellcasting animations when casting spells with your weapon, a new Bladesong ability to grant you supernatural speed, agility, and focus, plus gives you a bonus to any Constitution saving throw you make.</em></p>

<figure></figure>

<p>Perhaps it is not so surprising that Larian continues to improve Baldur's Gate 3. After all, the game was <a href="https://wccftech.com/baldurs-gate-3-saw-more-players-this-year-than-its-release-in-2023/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">played</a> more in 2024 than in 2023. Still, this is likely to be one of the very last significant updates. Fans of the series will then have to wait and see which<a href="https://wccftech.com/baldurs-gate-franchise-to-continue-as-wizards-of-the-coast-talks-to-many-partners/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> new partner Wizards of the Coast will pick to continue the franchise</a> after this smash-hit success.</p>

				

			
	<div>
		<h2>Products mentioned in this post</h2>
		
		<!--<p class="story-notice text-center">The links above are affiliate links. As an Amazon Associate, Wccftech.com may earn from qualifying purchases.</p>-->
	</div>

			
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Frostpunk 2 post-launch roadmap announced]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/11/frostpunk-2-post-launch-roadmap-announced</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/frostpunk-2-post-launch-roadmap-announced.1046847/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/11/frostpunk-2-post-launch-roadmap-announced<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>The journey into the frostland deepens.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > 11 bit studios [51 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/11-bit-studios">11 bit studios</a> has announced the post-launch roadmap for <em><a title="Games > Frostpunk 2 [7 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/frostpunk-2">Frostpunk 2</a></em> following its release for <a title="Platforms > PC [21,794 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1601580/Frostpunk_2/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a>, <a href="https://www.epicgames.com/store/p/frostpunk-2" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Epic Games Store</a>, and <a href="https://www.gog.com/game/frostpunk_2" target="_blank" rel="noopener">GOG</a> on September 20. <span id="more-930044"></span></p><p>Get the details below.</p><blockquote><p>The <em>Frostpunk 2</em> team at 11 bit studios is immensely grateful for the invaluable feedback provided by players since the game’s launch in September. Your suggestions, ideas, and bug reports have played a pivotal role in shaping our journey thus far and continue to guide our plans for what lies ahead.</p><p>As highlighted in the roadmap, the frostland expedition is far from over, with a wealth of updates and content planned for 2025. Here’s a glimpse at some key milestones:</p><ul><li><strong><a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,426 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a> and <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [6,399 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a> Launch</strong> – A highly anticipated event, bringing New London to console players worldwide. We can’t wait to expand the city’s reach to new platforms.</li><li><strong>Downloadable Content</strong> – While the specifics remain shrouded in secrecy, each upcoming downloadable content—currently operating under codenames—will introduce entirely new dimensions to the unforgiving world of <em>Frostpunk 2</em>.</li><li><strong>Free Major Content Updates</strong> – In addition to the downloadable content, we are committed to delivering significant free updates inspired by player feedback. These updates will enhance and evolve your experience in meaningful ways.</li></ul><p>Beyond these major milestones, the development team will continue to roll out hotfixes and general improvements to ensure the game remains stable and polished.</p></blockquote><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Alongside the console versions’ launch in 2025, <em>Frostpunk 2</em> will also be made available via Game Pass.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sony's PlayStation retrospective digs into the console's 30-year hardware history]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/playstation-sony-30-year-retrospective</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sonys-playstation-retrospective-digs-into-the-consoles-30-year-hardware-history.1046844/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/playstation-sony-30-year-retrospective<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Sony has released a </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.playstation.com/en-gb/playstation-history/1994-ps-one/">retrospective</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> for its PlayStation consoles ahead of the original PlayStation's 30th Japanese anniversary on December 3.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">In it, the console maker looks back on the history and significant milestones of major PlayStation hardware. For example, the now </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.playstation.com/en-gb/playstation-history/2000-ps2-psp/">20-year-old PlayStation 2</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> has sold over 160 million units—corroborating what PlayStation boss </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/playstation-2-s-console-sales-reportedly-top-160m-units">Jim Ryan</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> first stated back in April. It continues to be one of the highest-selling consoles ever.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Along with the sales, Sony recognized the PS2 for taking "giant steps forward in home console gaming," and touted then-revolutionary features such as online play, "hugely attractive" DVD playback, and backwards compatibility with PlayStation 1 titles. Praise was also given for first-party titles like Team ICO's </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Ico</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Shadow of the Colossus, </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">plus franchises like Sly Cooper and God of War that have since expanded to other PlayStation systems.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Sony goes on to note the PlayStation 4 sold 117 million units sold in its lifetime, while the original PlayStation and PlayStation 3 respectively sold 102 million and 87 million units. Hard numbers weren't given for the PlayStation 5, the PlayStation Vita, or either of the PlayStation VR headsets, but Sony's latest </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.sony.com/en/SonyInfo/IR/library/presen/er/pdf/24q2_supplement.pdf">fiscal report</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> reveals the PS5 has sold over 65.5 million lifetime units.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="PlayStation 5 is still riding global waves">PlayStation 5 is still riding global waves</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The PS5's writeup acknowledged the console was PlayStation's biggest global launch (and equally big for game consoles overall), despite releasing in "challenging global conditions." It came out in 2020 during the early days of the COVID pandemic, and its supply was impacted by a </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/toshiba-warns-semiconductor-shortage-will-continue-to-affect-console-makers">component shortage</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. During that time, Sony increased the console's price in </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/sony-announces-playstation-5-price-increase-in-select-markets-">several territories,</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> including </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/sony-is-raising-the-price-of-playstation-5-hardware-in-japan">Japan</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/game-platforms/report-sony-is-tackling-ps5-shortage-with-more-ps4s">made more PS4s</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> to make up for the new system's shortage.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">As of last year, those supply issues have been </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/game-platforms/sony-assures-its-playstation-5-supply-issues-are-over">rectified</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, and Sony has since released </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/sony-unveils-slim-playstation-5-with-detachable-disc-drive">Slim</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/the-playstation-5-pro-has-finally-been-unveiled">Pro</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> versions of the PlayStation 5, plus the </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/sony-s-playstation-portal-handheld-will-release-later-this-year">PlayStation Portal</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> cloud streaming device. Earlier this week, reports claimed the company is developing a </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/console/report-sony-is-developing-a-dedicated-playstation-handheld">new portable console</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> that can play PlayStation 5 games, making it the first dedicated PlayStation handheld since the PlayStation Vita.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">You can see the full timeline of PlayStation history </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.playstation.com/en-gb/playstation-history/1994-ps-one/">here</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Contributing Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">A Kansas City, MO native, Justin Carter has written for numerous sites including IGN, Polygon, and SyFy Wire. In addition to Game Developer, his writing can be found at io9 over on Gizmodo. Don't ask him about how much gum he's had, because the answer will be more than he's willing to admit.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Everything Coming In Baldur’s Gate 3’s Eighth Big Patch]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/baldurs-gate-3-patch-8-cross-play-photo-mode-date-1851709476</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/everything-coming-in-baldur%E2%80%99s-gate-3%E2%80%99s-eighth-big-patch.1046820/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/baldurs-gate-3-patch-8-cross-play-photo-mode-date-1851709476<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/baldurs-gate-3-bg3-review-dungeons-dragons-rpg-larian-1850726491&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/baldurs-gate-3-bg3-review-dungeons-dragons-rpg-larian-1850726491"><em>Baldur’s Gate 3</em></a></span><em> </em>is <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/baldurs-gate-3-anniversary-larian-studios-dlc-patch-1851612285&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/baldurs-gate-3-anniversary-larian-studios-dlc-patch-1851612285">over a year old now</a></span>, and developer Larian Studios is still bringing a bevy of new features to the RPG in its upcoming eighth patch. Some of these features were announced a while ago but are finally making their way to the game with this update which, it seems, is currently a few months out. Larian is looking to do some stress testing on Patch 8 for all platforms in January, so it sounds like the update will roll out to everyone later next year. Larian has outlined most of the new features coming to <em>Baldur’s Gate 3 </em>in a <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1086940/view/4461474037375172735'&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1086940/view/4461474037375172735'" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">lengthy Steam post</a></span>, so let’s unpack what’s coming.<br></p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="194214" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Elden Ring's Top Five Spells, According To FromSoftWare's Stats" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="315" data-playlist="194214,197298,197284" data-current="194214"><div><p>Elden Ring's Top Five Spells, According To FromSoftWare's Stats</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/194214/194214_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/194214/194214_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/194214/194214_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/194214/194214_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/19689.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>The biggest new feature is crossplay functionality, which the game has desperately needed as its audience is split across PC, Mac, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series X/S. It doesn’t sound like there will be any limitations once the feature goes live, and you’ll be able to make cross-platform co-op lobbies no matter where you’re playing <em>Baldur’s Gate 3</em>.</p><p>Alongside crossplay, the other big feature coming in Patch 8 is photo mode. If you’re anything like me, someone who takes well over 1500 screenshots every time he plays a video game, this is probably music to your ears. Thankfully, it looks like Larian is putting together a really robust photo mode for <em>Baldur’s Gate 3</em>, including the typical camera, lens, and frame options, as well as more thorough options like the ability to pose your characters to create a dramatic or funny scene.</p><p>For the gameplay mechanic sickos, Larian is also introducing a major overhaul to subclasses, which will introduce a new subclass for each base class in the game. For a breakdown of each, check out Larian’s full rundown below:</p><h2 id="h30197"><a id=""></a><strong>Bard - College of Glamour</strong></h2><p>As a College of Glamour Bard, you’ll find you have the power to heal friends and command enemies in equal measure. Cast <strong>Mantle of Inspiration </strong>to bestow your allies with 5 temporary hit points. And should an enemy attack while it is cast, they’ll find themselves <strong>Charmed</strong>. Play your hand correctly and you’ll be able to use this to your advantage with <strong>Mantle of Majesty</strong>. Target Charmed enemies and you can command them to flee, move closer, freeze, drop to the ground, or drop their weapon.</p><h2 id="h30198"><a id=""></a><strong>Barbarian - Path of Giants</strong></h2><p>Opt for the Path of Giants, and your newfound giant strength will make it easier for you to yeet friend and foe alike. Forget chugging potions to pump those muscles, these Barbarians benefit from the <strong>Giant’s Rage </strong>passive that grants both strength and size - allowing you to deal additional damage with Throw attacks. Pockets weighing you down? Not for you and your increased carry capacity!</p><h2 id="h30199"><a id=""></a><strong>Cleric - Death Domain</strong></h2><p>As a cleric of death, you’ll find a few dark new tricks up your sleeves - from spells that specialise in necrotic damage to three new necromancy cantrips. This includes <strong>Toll The Dead</strong>, a cantrip that causes 1~8 damage when your cleric rings the bell of impending doom - a number that scales if your target has already been damaged. We’ve also added the homebrewed ability to explode nearby corpses, damaging enemies.</p><h2 id="h30200"><a id=""></a><strong>Druid - Circle of Stars</strong></h2><p>These Druids look to the stars for answers, accessing powers beyond those offered through the classic wildshapes. Taking on one of three <strong>Starry Forms </strong>for their power - the constellations of the Archer, Chalice, and Dragon. Each one favours a different play style and strategy - the Archer dealing radiant damage with astral arrows, the life-giving Chalice restoring hitpoints to you and others nearby, and the wise Dragon, allowing you to deal damage with an added bonus to constitution rolls. The Starry Forms offer not just a celestial aesthetic, but practical, powerful options to enhance your role as a healer, fighter, or strategist.</p><h2 id="h30201"><a id=""></a><strong>Paladin - Oath of the Crown</strong></h2><p>You’ve been sworn to uphold the principles of law. Stay true to your oath and you’ll be rewarded with the power to aid your allies and disrupt your foes. Guide your companions in battle with <strong>Righteous Clarity</strong>, taunt enemies with strategic interrupts, and keep your party standing strong with <strong>Divine Allegiance</strong>, absorbing their damage while restoring their health.</p><h2 id="h30202"><a id=""></a><strong>Fighter - Arcane Archer</strong></h2><p>Mastering the dual arts of magic and marksmanship, the Arcane Archer subclass offers unique skills on top of new shooting animations. Banish foes to the Feywild, removing them from the battlefield for a turn, or unleash Psychic damage that forces enemies to make a Wisdom saving throw or be blinded until the start of their next turn.</p><h2 id="h30203"><a id=""></a><strong>Monk - Drunken Master</strong></h2><p>Putting the brew in homebrew, as the Drunken Master, you have the ability to consume alcohol straight from your inventory, as well as drink from bottles you see around the Sword Coast, in order to recover Ki. By sharing the bottle with your enemies using <strong>Intoxicating Strike</strong>, you’ll generate a buff towards your Armour Class and your Chance to hit Drunk targets. Drunk enemies are also susceptible to the Drunken Masters’ other abilities, like <strong>Sobering Realisation</strong>- which sobers up drunk targets, dealing physical and Psychic damage.</p><h2 id="h30204"><a id=""></a><strong>Ranger - Swarmkeeper</strong></h2><p>The Swarmkeeper subclass provides Rangers with three kinds of deadly swarms to assist them in combat. The <strong>Cloud of Jellyfish </strong>deals extra lightning damage - potentially shocking your enemy. <strong>The Flurry of Moths </strong>deals Psychic damage, giving you the potential to Blind your enemy. The <strong>Legion of Bees </strong>deals piercing damage and forces the enemy to make a strength-saving throw or be knocked back 15ft. Each swarm also has the ability to provide you with teleportation capabilities!</p><h2 id="h30205"><a id=""></a><strong>Rogue - Swashbuckler</strong></h2><p>This Rogue subclass introduces a range of new actions fit for the piratical life. Play dirty by tossing sand at enemies to <strong>Blind </strong>them. Flick your weapon at a target to <strong>Disarm </strong>them. Or use your new <strong>Fancy Footwork </strong>passive while meleeing your enemy to ensure they can’t make opportunity attacks against you for the rest of your turn.</p><h2 id="h30206"><a id=""></a><strong>Sorcerer - Shadow Magic</strong></h2><p>As a Shadow Magic Sorcerer, you deal in a form of magic that makes you deadliest in darkness. This subclass gives its sorcerer <strong>Superior Darkvision</strong>, as well as the ability to <strong>Shadow Walk </strong>between places of dim light or darkness. It also lets you call forth the perfectly homebrewed <strong>Hound of Ill Omen </strong>to harass your foes, and use <strong>Strength of the Grave </strong>to prevent you from being downed - ideal for those attempting Honour Mode runs.</p><h2 id="h30207"><a id=""></a><strong>Warlock - Hexblade</strong></h2><p>Hexblade Warlocks make a pact with an entity from the Shadowfell that manifests in the form of magical weapons. Curse your enemies and force their souls to do your bidding. Slay any enemy that isn’t generally an element of nature, construct, giant blob, or already dead, and you’ll be able to raise their spirit from their corpse for ten turns. This new summon can deal necrotic damage and will rip away a chunk of your enemy’s soul to provide your Hexblade Warlock with healing.<br></p><h2 id="h30208"><a id=""></a><strong>Wizard - Bladesinging</strong></h2><p>The Bladesinging subclass merges swordplay with wizardry. Expect new spellcasting animations when casting spells with your weapon, a new Bladesong ability to grant you supernatural speed, agility, and focus, plus gives you a bonus to any Constitution saving throw you make.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Everything New in Baldur’s Gate 3 Patch 8]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/everything-new-in-baldurs-gate-3-update-30/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/everything-new-in-baldur%E2%80%99s-gate-3-patch-8.1046817/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/everything-new-in-baldurs-gate-3-update-30/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>It wasn’t long ago that Baldur’s Gate 3 took the gaming world by storm, thrusting the CRPG genre into the mainstream. Since then, developer Larian has introduced countless content updates, expanding the already massive RPG tenfold. But it’s not done yet. Following <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/top-10-baldurs-gate-3-mods-on-mods-io/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">mod support</a>, which they revealed is doing exceptionally well, with over 70 million downloads total, the studio unveiled Baldur’s Gate Patch 8. It’s coming in 2025 and includes photo mode, cross-play support, and 12 additional subclasses!</p>



<h2 id="h-everything-coming-to-baldur-s-gate-3-in-patch-8">Everything Coming to Baldur’s Gate 3 in Patch 8</h2>



<p>Patch 8 promises to be a massive experience for anyone still enjoying Baldur’s Gate 3 or planning on returning in the new year. According to the <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1086940/view/4461474037375172735" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">blog post</a>, we can expect cross-play support, photo mode, new subclasses, bug fixes, and quality-of-life improvements galore. For now, let’s focus on the prominent new features, such as:</p>



<h3 id="h-cross-play-support">Cross-Play Support</h3>



<p>Full cross-play support is coming to Baldur’s Gate 3, allowing anyone to play between PC, PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X|S, and yes, even Mac. This support features cross-platform progression, allowing you to progress through your campaign no matter where you play.</p>



<p>Furthermore, the game’s multiplayer lobbies will allow you to invite players from any system through the Larian Network!</p>



<h3 id="h-photo-mode">Photo Mode</h3>



<p>As someone who adores taking screenshots in-game, I love it when a studio includes photo mode. Previously, snapping a screenshot in Baldur’s Gate 3 felt like a chore, as you must contend with the menu and panned-out camera, but that’s about to change in Patch 8 with a full-fledged photo mode. It features:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Camera Settings</strong></li>



<li><strong>Lens Settings</strong></li>



<li><strong>Scene Settings</strong></li>



<li><strong>Post Processing Effects</strong></li>



<li><strong>Frames</strong></li>



<li><strong>Stickers</strong></li>
</ul>







<h3 id="h-12-new-subclasses">12 New Subclasses</h3>



<ul>
<li><strong>Bard </strong>– College of Glamour</li>



<li><strong>Barbarian </strong>– Path of Giants</li>



<li><strong>Cleric </strong>– Death Domain</li>



<li><strong>Druid </strong>– Circle of Stars</li>



<li><strong>Paladin </strong>– Oath of the Crown</li>



<li><strong>Fighter </strong>– Arcane Archer</li>



<li><strong>Monk </strong>– Drunken Master</li>



<li><strong>Ranger </strong>– Swarmkeeper</li>



<li><strong>Rogue </strong>– Swashbuckler</li>



<li><strong>Sorcerer </strong>– Shadow Magic</li>



<li><strong>Warlock </strong>– Hexblade</li>



<li><strong>Wizard </strong>– Bladesinging</li>
</ul>



<p>Before Patch 8 is available to everyone in 2025, the studio will undergo extensive stress testing to ensure it’s ready for the community. </p>



<p>Are you still playing Baldur’s Gate 3? Tell us about your latest campaign over at the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming community forums</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>According to a Larian executive, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ubisoft-management-to-blame-for-prince-of-persia-the-lost-crown-sales-issues-baldurs-gate-3-exec-says/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ubisoft management is to blame for Prince of Persia: The Lost Crown’s poor sales</a> following launch!</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk Says He’s Going to Launch an AI Game Studio to “Make Games Great Again”]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/elon-must-ai-game-studio/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/elon-musk-says-he%E2%80%99s-going-to-launch-an-ai-game-studio-to-%E2%80%9Cmake-games-great-again%E2%80%9D.1046811/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/elon-must-ai-game-studio/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Elon Musk has said on X (formerly Twitter) that he’s going to launch an AI game studio to “make games great again.”</p>



<p>In the <a href="https://x.com/elonmusk/status/1861801046949191686" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">tweet</a>, Musk says that there are “too many game studios that are owned by massive corporations” and that xAI will soon have its own game studio.</p>



<p>What such a game studio will look like is unclear, but in recent years, game studios have increasingly relied on AI to cut spiraling costs and help with creative ideas. One such project to leverage AI is <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ubisoft-alterra-animal-crossing-inspired-game/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ubisoft’s new ‘Alterra’ project</a>, which heavily used AI during the creative and ideation process to create its characters named ‘Matterlings’. </p>



<p>Earlier this month, it was <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/elon-musk-top-20-diablo-4-player/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">revealed that he was somehow a top 20 Diablo 4 player</a> despite him running companies including Tesla, SpaceX, X, and more. The billionaire also dabbled in streaming, too, with his <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/elon-musk-stream-success/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">first stream on X pulling 1.3 million watchers</a>. To put that into perspective, xQc has a recorded peak of 312,158, DrDisrespect reached heights of 363,980, and Ninja hit 616,693, to name a few big streamers.</p>



<p>It remains to be seen whether Musk is serious about an AI game studio, but knowing him, he probably is.</p>



<p>What do you think of Elon Musk’s claims? Do you think we need an AI game studio? Join the discussion below, or in the official&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/threads/1269/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming Tech, check out our&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gray Zone Warfare: Night Ops Launch Trailer is a Mini Action Movie and I Love It]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/gray-zone-warfare-night-ops-launch-trailer/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gray-zone-warfare-night-ops-launch-trailer-is-a-mini-action-movie-and-i-love-it.1046808/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/gray-zone-warfare-night-ops-launch-trailer/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Gray Zone Warfare’s Night Ops update goes live today, and it’s the biggest overhaul the game has seen since being released in April 2024. This sizeable – and free – update introduces a day-night cycle, but it also brings in some new weapons, tweaks to the game’s AI, many quality-of-life improvements, and some all-new mechanics.</p>



<p>It’s a sizeable update that I was fortunate to preview in August at Gamescom and in the last few days using a private server provided to me by MADFINGER.</p>



<p>Night Ops is finally here, and it will change how you experience Gray Zone Warfare.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-when-darkness-falls">When Darkness Falls</h2>



<p>The launch trailer for Night Ops is nothing short of a mini-action movie, and the cinematic quality of it represents something I’d watch as a feature film. It’s one of the best productions the team has put together since the game was released in April.</p>







<figure><p>
<iframe title="Gray Zone Warfare: Night Ops Launch Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/vHd8fSP-gik?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>







<p>In the short showcase, we get a peek at Night Ops in all its dark and gloomy glory. The day-night shift will bring about a paradigm shift, with players venturing out into the darkness of Lamang to take on all comers and tackle new quests that can <strong>only </strong>be completed at night.</p>



<p>With night mode comes a range of attachments and items to combat the darkness, and from what I’ve seen, MADFINGER has worked tirelessly to make night vision aids as realistic as humanly possible. Exploring a dark jungle with nothing but a torch and a rifle feels intense, and slapping on a set of NVGs makes you feel as though you’ve entered a new world.</p>



<p>Gray Zone Warfare still isn’t perfect, though. I had a few frame rate drops and some audio bugs when I was playing, but I <strong>was </strong>using a pre-release version of the Night Ops build, so I can chalk my performance issues up to that — hopefully. Otherwise, I had a blast diving back into Gray Zone Warfare to experience the Night Ops update, and I’m sure you will too.</p>



<p>Did you ever get Gray Zone Warfare? Let us know on the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/kai-cenat-twitch-sub-record-hanging/">Kai Cenat ‘hung someone’ on stream</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dark Sector Is Free on Steam For the Next 72 Hours in Celebration of Warframe: 1999]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/dark-sector-is-free-on-steam-for-the-next-72-hours-in-celebration-of-warframe-1999</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dark-sector-is-free-on-steam-for-the-next-72-hours-in-celebration-of-warframe-1999.1046805/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/dark-sector-is-free-on-steam-for-the-next-72-hours-in-celebration-of-warframe-1999<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">The 2008 third-person shooter is free for a short time.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">IGN can exclusively reveal that Dark Sector, the 2008 third-person shooter from Warframe developer Digital Extremes, is now free on Steam for the next 72 hours in celebration of the upcoming free Warframe: 1999 expansion that is set to be released in December 2024.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Aside from a small number of regions like Japan, Australia, New Zealand, and South Africa, Steam users can head over to <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/29900/Dark_Sector/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Dark Sector's Steam page</a> and download the game right now and skip its current $9.99 price tag.</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/11/27/dark-sector-1732726784575.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">For those unfamiliar, Dark Sector places you in the shoes of Hayden Tenno, a covert operative who must invade the fictional Eastern European city of Lasria that hides a very dangerous Cold War secret. During his mission, he gets infected with a Technocyte Virus that turns him into a killing machine with powers and a deadly glaive that he must use to save everything.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In our <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2008/03/25/dark-sector-review-2">Dark Sector review,</a> we said, "Dark Sector's fun. Hearing guards scream for help just before they take a glaive to the face, marching around in this Metal Gear-looking Jackal tank while rocketing bad guys into the air and wielding a pimped-out shotgun make the experience something any action fan can get behind. However, when the really similar levels and waves of opponents get too repetitive towards the end of the game, Dark Sector's weak storyline might not be enough to carry the more fickle fan to the finish line. It's fun, but it's not perfect."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As for how Dark Sector is connected to Warframe: 1999, the expansion will take players to the year before Y2K and a retro European-style city of Höllvania to become Arthur Nightingale. This is obviously a far cry from the space setting Warframe fans are used to, but it should be an exciting one.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Speaking to <a href="https://www.vg247.com/warframe-1999-new-zone-unlikely-inspiration-dark-sector" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">VG247,</a> creative director Rebecca Ford shared that Dark Sector was definitely an inspiration for this expansion and the team looked to the game for its tone and a city that felt European. </p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Have a tip for us? Want to discuss a possible story? Please send an email to </em><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/"><em>newstips@ign.com</em></a><em>.</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Adam Bankhurst is a writer for IGN. You can follow him on X/Twitter </em><a href="https://twitter.com/AdamBankhurst" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>@AdamBankhurst</em></a><em> and on </em><a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@adambankhurst" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>TikTok.</em></a></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tower Defense Simulator Codes (November 2024)]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/tower-defense-simulator-codes</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/tower-defense-simulator-codes-november-2024.1046802/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/tower-defense-simulator-codes<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Looking for Tower Defense Simulator codes to earn additional Gems, Crates, Coins, and more? This article has you covered. Here you can find a list of all the currently active Tower Defense Simulator codes that will give you a variety of rewards when redeemed.</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/11/25/tower-defense-simulator-2-1732558671229.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>Active Tower Defense Simulator Codes (November 2024) </strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Here are the currently active Tower Defense Simulator codes for November 2024 and the rewards you'll get for redeeming them:</p><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>TDS5YEARS!:</strong> 1 Party Crate</li></ul><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>All Expired Tower Defense Simulator Codes</strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">The following Tower Defense Simulator codes can no longer be redeemed as of November 2024:</p><ul data-cy="list"><li>IMCONSUMING</li><li>MERRYXMAS2023</li><li>QNJOU11</li><li>HAPPYHALLOWEEN</li><li>NAMETAGSRCOOL</li></ul><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>How to Redeem Tower Defense Simulator Codes</strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">To redeem active Tower Defense Simulator codes, follow these steps:</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/11/25/tower-defense-simulator-1-1732558671228.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><ol data-cy="list"><li>Launch <strong>Tower Defense Simulator</strong> on Roblox</li><li>Look for the <strong>blue bird icon</strong> on the left of the screen</li><li>Click on Codes and <strong>paste the code</strong> into the bar </li><li>Press enter and enjoy your rewards!</li></ol><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>Why Isn't My Tower Defense Simulator Code Working? </strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">When a code for Tower Defense Simulator isn't working, it's usually for one of two reasons. Either the code has expired, or it's been mistyped. To avoid any misspelled codes, we'd recommend copying them directly from this article. We test each one to make sure it works before adding it to this article, so when you paste them into the bar, if they've not expired, they'll work. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">If you paste in a code that has a mistake in it or is expired, you'll receive a notification that the "Code is invalid or entered correctly." You'll be reminded to double check that you haven't accidentally included additional spaces when copying the code. </p><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>How to Get More Tower Defense Simulator Codes </strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">We'll keep this article updated daily, adding new Tower Defense Simulator Codes as they're released. You can also find codes by joining the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/tds" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Tower Defense Simulator Discord</a>. </p><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>What is Tower Defense Simulator in Roblox?</strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">In Tower Defense Simulator, you work solo or with others to stop waves of enemies from attacking. You'll fend off zombies while building the ultimate defense. As tougher enemies and larger waves of zombies swarm your base, you'll need to upgrade your army of recruits and unlock new and powerful towers. </p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Lauren Harper is a freelance writer and editor who has covered news, reviews, and features for over a decade in various industries. She has contributed to guides at IGN for games including Elden Ring, The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom, Starfield, Pikmin 4, and more. With an MA in Victorian Gothic History and Culture, she loves anything that falls under that category. She's also a huge fan of point-and-click adventures, horror games and films. You can talk to her about your favourites over at </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/prettyheartache.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>@prettyheartache.bsky.social</em></a><em>.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Attack on Titan Revolution Codes (November 2024)]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/attack-on-titan-revolution-codes</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/attack-on-titan-revolution-codes-november-2024.1046796/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/attack-on-titan-revolution-codes<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Redeem these Attack on Titan Revolution codes for extra Spins, Luck Potions, and more.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Whether you're looking for extra Spins, potions, or Crates, these Attack on Titan Revolution codes will have you covered. Here you can find a list of all the currently active and working AoT Revolution codes in Roblox to give you a little helping hand on tackling those Titans. </p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/11/25/aot-revolution-codes-1-1732546853388.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>Active Attack on Titan Revolution Codes (November 2024) </strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">As of November 2024, newly released AoT Revolution codes are only active for one week, so check back regularly to avoid missing out. Here are all the currently active Attack on Titan Revolution codes in November 2024, and the rewards you'll get for redeeming them:</p><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>ENDERSPINS:</strong> 150 Spins</li><li><strong>COLESPINS:</strong> 150 Spins</li><li><strong>UPDATE2HALLOWEEN:</strong> 600 Halloween tokens</li><li><strong>UPDATE2FATE:</strong> 4 crates</li><li><strong>UPDATE2DEMON:</strong> 4 crates</li><li><strong>UPDATE2SPINS:</strong> 350 spins</li></ul><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>All Expired Attack on Titan Revolution Codes</strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">The following codes can no longer be redeemed as of November 2024:</p><ul data-cy="list"><li>CODESEXPIREAFTER1WEEK</li><li>UPDATE2PATCH</li><li>LIKES350K</li><li>ARMOREDTITANSOON</li><li>SOSORRY4DELAY</li><li>WELOVEBRASIL</li><li>ROBLOXFIX</li><li>LIKES325K</li><li>DEVCODE3</li><li>MYBAD</li><li>UPDATESOON2</li><li>SORRY4DELAY3</li><li>LIKES300K</li><li>RANDOMCODE1</li><li>RANDOMCODE2</li></ul><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>How to Redeem Attack on Titan Revolution Codes</strong></h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/11/25/aot-revolution-codes-1732538502008.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><ol data-cy="list"><li>Reach<strong> Level 15</strong> in Attack on Titan Revolution</li><li>Launch <strong>AoT Revolution</strong> </li><li>Find <strong>Codes</strong> on the <strong>Main Menu</strong> as you load up the experience</li><li>Click on Codes and the box will appear on the bottom right corner</li><li>Paste in your code and press enter to get your goods</li></ol><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>Why Isn't My Attack on Titan Revolution Code Working? </strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">If you find your AoT Revolution code isn't working, it could be for a few reasons. Firstly, you'll need to <strong>be Level 15+ before codes will work</strong>, so spend some time leveling up before attempting to use them.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">If you're Level 15+ and your code isn't working, it's either because there's a typo in the code or it's expired. If a code has run out, it will say "Expired" when you press enter. If there's a typo, or the code is very old, it will say "Invalid." If you don't meet the level requirement to use the code, it will say "Error." </p><p data-cy="paragraph">To avoid typos, we'd recommend copying the code directly from this article. Then, paste it into the Codes bar on the Main Menu of the AoT Revolution screen. Just be sure to check that there's no extra space at the beginning or the end of the code.  </p><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>How to Get More Attack on Titan Revolution Codes </strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">We update this article daily with any new Attack on Titan Revolution codes. But if you want to get AOTR codes the moment they drop, it's best to follow the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/aotrevolution" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">AoT Revolution Discord</a>. Codes are posted in the #Announcements channel.</p><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>What is Attack on Titan Revolution in Roblox? </strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Attack on Titan Revolution is a Roblox experience inspired by the AoT Japanese manga. In an attempt to save humanity and lead the revolution against giant creatures, you'll be tasked with slaying the Titans and reclaiming freedom. Customize your fighting style with Gear, Upgrades, Perks, and more, to take on tougher challenges as you level up. </p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Lauren Harper is a freelance writer and editor who has covered news, reviews, and features for over a decade in various industries. She has contributed to guides at IGN for games including Elden Ring, The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom, Starfield, Pikmin 4, and more. With an MA in Victorian Gothic History and Culture, she loves anything that falls under that category. She's also a huge fan of point-and-click adventures, horror games and films. You can talk to her about your favourites over at </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/prettyheartache.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>@prettyheartache.bsky.social</em></a><em>.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Anime Reborn Codes (November 2024)]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/anime-reborn-codes</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/anime-reborn-codes-november-2024.1046790/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/anime-reborn-codes<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Looking for the newest Anime Reborn codes? You're in the right place! Here you'll find a list of all the active Anime Reborn codes, which you can redeem for Rerolls, Keys, Potions, and more. </p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/11/25/anime-reborn-codes-1-1732565968323.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>Active Anime Reborn Codes (November 2024) </strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Below, you'll find all the currently active Anime Reborn codes in November 2024:</p><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Iboughtbundles!!</strong> - 50,000 Red Tickets (This will only work if you have previously purchased ticket bundles before restarts)</li><li><strong>1MMembers:</strong> 10,000 Red Tickets, 15 Trait Rerolls, 10 Potential Keys, 10 Frost Keys</li><li><strong>Freetickets:</strong> 5,000 Red Tickets</li><li><strong>20Mvisits</strong> - 1000 Gems, 5 Trait Crysals, 3 Potential Keys, 3 Frost Keys and 1 Basic Luck Potion</li><li><strong>UpdateSoon!:</strong> 1000 Gems, 10 Rerolls, 5 Frost Keys</li><li><strong>20Mvisits:</strong> 1,000 Gems, 5 rerolls, 3 potential keys, 3 frost keys, Basic luck potion</li><li><strong>XMEGACODE:</strong> 2,000 Gems, 15 Rerolls, 10 Frost Keys, 10 Potential Keys,<strong> </strong>Legends Potion</li><li><strong>SubtoZillas:</strong> 250 Gems, 1 Reroll</li><li><strong>SubtoRlxsage: </strong>250 Gems, 1 Trait Crystal</li><li><strong>MozKing: </strong>250 Gems, 1 Trait Crystal</li></ul><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>All Expired Anime Reborn Codes</strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">The following codes can no longer be redeemed as of November 2024:</p><ul data-cy="list"><li>sorry4shutdown</li></ul><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>How to Redeem Anime Reborn Codes</strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">To redeem Anime Reborn Codes, you'll need to locate the Codes chest in-game. You can do this by following these steps:</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/11/25/anime-reborn-codes-2-1732565968324.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><ol data-cy="list"><li>Launch <strong>Anime Reborn</strong> on Roblox</li><li>From the spawn point, go forward and to the right, past the shop</li><li>You'll find <strong>Luffy sitting on a blue chest</strong>, which says <strong>Redeem Codes!</strong> above it</li><li><strong>Press E</strong> to interact with the chest when you walk up to it</li><li>Then enter the codes, and press Redeem</li></ol><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>Why Isn't My Anime Reborn Code Working? </strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Whenever a code isn't working in Anime Reborn, the code has likely either expired or has been mistyped. If a code is entered incorrectly, then you'll see a "Code Invalid" message pop up. Codes are often case-sensitive, so to avoid mistakes, we'd recommend copying the code directly from this article. Then paste it into the codes bar in Anime Reborn, but be sure to check and see if there are any extra spaces before or after the code. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">In some cases, you'll need to be a certain level before you can redeem a code. In this case, you'll see a message that tells you the level you need to be before the code works. </p><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>How to Get More Anime Reborn Codes </strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">We'll keep this article updated daily and add any Anime Reborn codes as they're announced, so you can check back here. If you want to stay on top of code drops, you can also join the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/animereborn" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Anime Reborn Discord </a>channel. You'll also see the owners of Anime Reborn,  @<a href="https://x.com/RealMozKIng" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">RealMozKIng</a>, @<a href="https://x.com/rlxsage" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">RlxSage</a>, and @<a href="https://x.com/RealZillas" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">RealZillas</a>, regularly posting codes on their X accounts.</p><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>What is Anime Reborn in Roblox?</strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Anime Reborn is a strategic Tower Defense game in Roblox where you'll need to defeat waves of enemies to protect your base. The big difference with this experience is the units that you'll purchase and equip are legendary heroes from across various anime. Each one has their own abilities, and you'll upgrade and evolve them to improve their attacks. </p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Lauren Harper is a freelance writer and editor who has covered news, reviews, and features for over a decade in various industries. She has contributed to guides at IGN for games including Elden Ring, The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom, Starfield, Pikmin 4, and more. With an MA in Victorian Gothic History and Culture, she loves anything that falls under that category. She's also a huge fan of point-and-click adventures, horror games and films. You can talk to her about your favourites over at </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/prettyheartache.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>@prettyheartache.bsky.social</em></a><em>.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pet Simulator 99! Codes (November 2024)]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/pet-simulator-99-codes</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pet-simulator-99-codes-november-2024.1046787/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/pet-simulator-99-codes<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Keep up to date with any Pet Simulator 99! codes as they appear. </h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">If you're looking for Pet Simulator 99! codes, you're in the right place. Unfortunately, for now, there are no codes available. However, as soon as they drop, we'll have a list here of any and all active codes. </p><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>Active Pet Simulator 99! Codes (November 2024)</strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">There are currently <strong>no known active Pet Simulator 99! codes</strong>. </p><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>All Expired Pet Simulator 99! Codes</strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">There are <strong>no expired Pet Simulator 99! codes.</strong></p><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>How to Redeem Pet Simulator 99! Codes</strong></h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/11/26/pet-sim-codes-1732639441867.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/11/26/pet-simulator-redeem-codes-1732637435439.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">There are <strong>only merch codes available</strong> for Pet Simulator 99! currently. It's also worth nothing you can only redeem codes when using a desktop. If you do have a merch code, follow these steps to redeem it:</p><ol data-cy="list"><li>Click on the<strong> red basket icon</strong> on the left side of the screen to open the shop. </li><li>Scroll down to the bottom of this menu to find the <strong>Redeem Codes </strong>option.</li><li>Click the <strong>Redeem! button</strong> then enter the code </li><li>Press redeem again and receive your reward</li></ol><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>Why Isn't My Pet Simulator 99! Code Working?</strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">If your code isn't working, it'll most likely be because the code has expired or it's been mistyped. Whenever you can, be sure to copy codes directly and paste them into the redemption bar to avoid any mistakes. If you type a code incorrectly, you'll see a message that tells you to double check the code and try similar looking numbers and letters if it's still not working; for example an 0 instead of an O. </p><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>How to Get More Pet Simulator 99! Codes</strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">When Pet Simulator 99! codes are released, we'll add them to this article. To stay up to date with any news on codes, you can also join the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/biggames" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">BIG Games Discord channel</a>. </p><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>What is Pet Simulator 99! in Roblox?</strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">In Pet Simulator 99!, you'll work to build an army of pets that will help you earn more so you can progress. You'll start by equipping a few pets to aid you in breaking coins and earning diamonds, to unlock more eggs.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As you hatch more of them, you'll discover different types of eggs from monkeys to corgis, and axolotls. You'll be able to unlock additional areas that bring new items, obstacle courses that offer special rewards, and upgrade your character to give them perks, all with the help of your pets.  </p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Lauren Harper is a freelance writer and editor who has covered news, reviews, and features for over a decade in various industries. She has contributed to guides at IGN for games including Elden Ring, The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom, Starfield, Pikmin 4, and more. With an MA in Victorian Gothic History and Culture, she loves anything that falls under that category. She's also a huge fan of point-and-click adventures, horror games and films. You can talk to her about your favourites over at </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/prettyheartache.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>@prettyheartache.bsky.social</em></a><em>.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PLS DONATE Codes (November 2024)]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/pls-donate-codes</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pls-donate-codes-november-2024.1046784/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/pls-donate-codes<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Looking to unlock booths or earn some additional Giftbux? These PLS DONATE codes have you covered. Here you'll find a list of all codes for PLS DONATE that are currently active. </p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/11/25/pls-donate-codes-2-1732563760955.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>Active PLS DONATE Codes (November 2024) </strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Below are all the currently active PLS Donate codes in November 2024: </p><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>hazem:</strong> 50 Giftbux</li><li><strong>Eagle_15</strong>: 15 Giftbux</li><li><strong>plsdonate2:</strong> 20 Giftbux</li><li><strong>lazarbeam:</strong> Lazerbeam Booth</li><li><strong>pixel:</strong> PixelPlayground Booth</li><li><strong>quataun</strong>: 50 Giftbux</li></ul><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>All Expired PLS DONATE Codes</strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">The following codes can no longer be redeemed as of November 2024:</p><ul data-cy="list"><li>pd2024</li><li>glass</li><li>valentine2024</li></ul><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>How to Redeem PLS DONATE Codes</strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Redeeming codes in PLS DONATE is simple, all you need to do is follow these steps:</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/11/25/pls-donate-codes-1732563573317.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><ol data-cy="list"><li>Launch <strong>PLS Donate</strong> on Roblox</li><li>Look to the <strong>left of the screen </strong>to find a <strong>yellow ticket icon</strong></li><li>Click on this icon to open up the Codes box</li><li>Paste the code in and click <strong>Redeem</strong></li></ol><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>Why Isn't My PLS DONATE Code Working? </strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">There are two main causes behind a PLS Donate code not working and that's the code being expired, or incorrectly typed in. If a code can no longer be redeemed, you'll see "Code Expired." If you misspell a code, you'll just see a spinning circle. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">To avoid losing out on any of the rewards above, be sure to copy the code directly from this article. We check each code before we add it, so you'll always know they're working. Just check to make sure there isn't an extra space before or after the word when you're copying it over.</p><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>How to Get More PLS DONATE Codes </strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">We'll update this article daily and add any new PLS DONATE codes we find. But if you want to stay up to date with any codes announcements, you can join <a href="https://discord.com/invite/NrvuaMSz6E" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Hazem's Server on Discord</a>.</p><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>What is PLS DONATE in Roblox?</strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">In PLS Donate, players can ask for or donate Robux in exchange for game passes and marketplace items. Each player can create their own stand, and customize it with a message so others know what they're raising Robux for. </p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Lauren Harper is a freelance writer and editor who has covered news, reviews, and features for over a decade in various industries. She has contributed to guides at IGN for games including Elden Ring, The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom, Starfield, Pikmin 4, and more. With an MA in Victorian Gothic History and Culture, she loves anything that falls under that category. She's also a huge fan of point-and-click adventures, horror games and films. You can talk to her about your favourites over at </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/prettyheartache.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>@prettyheartache.bsky.social</em></a><em>.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Baldur’s Gate III ‘Patch 8’ launches in 2025, adds cross-play, photo mode, and 12 new subclasses]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/11/baldurs-gate-iii-patch-8-launches-in-2025-adds-cross-play-photo-mode-and-12-new-subclasses</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/baldur%E2%80%99s-gate-iii-%E2%80%98patch-8%E2%80%99-launches-in-2025-adds-cross-play-photo-mode-and-12-new-subclasses.1046778/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/11/baldurs-gate-iii-patch-8-launches-in-2025-adds-cross-play-photo-mode-and-12-new-subclasses<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p><a title="Companies > Larian Studios [40 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/larian-studios">Larian Studios</a> will release <em><a title="Games > Baldur's Gate III [25 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/baldurs-gate-iii">Baldur’s Gate III</a></em>‘s “Path 8” in 2025, which adds cross-play, a  photo mode, and 12 new subclasses to the game, the developer <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1086940/view/4461474037375172735" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced</a>. A stress test for the patch will be held in early January. <span id="more-930137"></span></p><p>Get the details below.</p><div><p><strong>■ Cross-Play</strong></p><p>Whether you’re joining <a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,426 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a> players from your <a title="Platforms > PC [21,794 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a>, or jumping into a game with Mac users from your <a title="Platforms > Xbox [25,124 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox">Xbox</a>, <em>Baldur’s Gate III</em> <a title="Genres > Multiplayer [415 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer">multiplayer</a> will soon feature full cross-platform progression, including cross-play—just as the gaming gods intended.</p><p>Once the update is live you’ll be able to invite your friends to join your cross-play lobby directly, regardless of platform and find available multiplayer lobbies with friends on other systems using the Larian Network.</p><p><strong>■ Subclasses</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Patch 8 will introduce a new way to play your favorite class, adding one new subclass for each of the existing Bard, Barbarian, Cleric, Druid, Paladin, Fighter, Monk, Ranger, Rogue, Sorcerer, Warlock and Wizard classes in the game.</p><p>Expect new abilities, animations, video effects, summons and cantrips, and unique voiced dialogue lines for the Oathbreaker Knight with written reactivity for Oathbreakers, along with a touch of homebrewing on certain <a title="Genres > Action [2,330 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a>s to enhance your <a title="Genres > RPG [16,823 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg">role-playing</a> experience.</p><ul><li><strong>Bard: College of Glamour</strong> – As a College of Glamour Bard, you’ll find you have the power to heal friends and command enemies in equal measure. Cast Mantle of Inspiration to bestow your allies with 5 temporary hit points. And should an enemy attack while it is cast, they’ll find themselves Charmed. Play your hand correctly and you’ll be able to use this to your advantage with Mantle of Majesty. Target Charmed enemies and you can command them to flee, move closer, freeze, drop to the ground, or drop their weapon.</li><li><strong>Barbarian: Path of Giants</strong> –&nbsp;Opt for the Path of Giants, and your newfound giant strength will make it easier for you to yeet friend and foe alike. Forget chugging potions to pump those muscles, these Barbarians benefit from the Giant’s Rage passive that grants both strength and size – allowing you to deal additional damage with Throw attacks. Pockets weighing you down? Not for you and your increased carry capacity!</li><li><strong>Cleric: Death Domain</strong> – As a cleric of death, you’ll find a few dark new tricks up your sleeves—from spells that specialize in necrotic damage to three new necromancy cantrips. This includes Toll The Dead, a cantrip that causes 1 to 8 damage when your cleric rings the bell of impending doom—a number that scales if your target has already been damaged. We’ve also added the homebrewed ability to explode nearby corpses, damaging enemies.</li><li><strong>Druid: Circle of Stars</strong> – These Druids look to the stars for answers, accessing powers beyond those offered through the classic wildshapes. Taking on one of three Starry Forms for their power—the constellations of the Archer, Chalice, and Dragon. Each one favors a different play style and strategy—the Archer dealing radiant damage with astral arrows, the life-giving Chalice restoring hitpoints to you and others nearby, and the wise Dragon, allowing you to deal damage with an added bonus to constitution rolls. The Starry Forms offer not just a celestial aesthetic, but practical, powerful options to enhance your role as a healer, fighter, or strategist.</li><li><strong>Paladin: Oath of the Crown</strong> – You’ve been sworn to uphold the principles of law. Stay true to your oath and you’ll be rewarded with the power to aid your allies and disrupt your foes. Guide your companions in battle with Righteous Clarity, taunt enemies with strategic interrupts, and keep your party standing strong with Divine Allegiance, absorbing their damage while restoring their health.</li><li><strong>Fighter: Arcane Archer</strong> – <a title="Companies > Mas" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/mas">Mas</a>tering the dual arts of magic and marksmanship, the Arcane Archer subclass offers unique skills on top of new shooting animations. Banish foes to the Feywild, removing them from the battlefield for a turn, or unleash Psychic damage that forces enemies to make a Wisdom saving throw or be blinded until the start of their next turn.</li><li><strong>Monk: Drunken Master</strong> – Putting the brew in homebrew, as the Drunken Master, you have the ability to consume alcohol straight from your inventory, as well as drink from bottles you see around the Sword Coast, in order to recover Ki. By sharing the bottle with your enemies using Intoxicating Strike, you’ll generate a buff towards your Armor Class and your Chance to hit Drunk targets. Drunk enemies are also susceptible to the Drunken Masters’ other abilities, like Sobering Realisation—which sobers up drunk targets, dealing physical and Psychic damage.</li><li><strong>Ranger: Swarmkeeper</strong> – The Swarmkeeper subclass provides Rangers with three kinds of deadly swarms to assist them in combat. The Cloud of Jellyfish deals extra lightning damage—potentially shocking your enemy. The Flurry of Moths deals Psychic damage, giving you the potential to Blind your enemy. The Legion of Bees deals piercing damage and forces the enemy to make a strength-saving throw or be knocked back 15 feet. Each swarm also has the ability to provide you with teleportation capabilities!</li><li><strong>Rogue: Swashbuckler</strong> – This Rogue subclass introduces a range of new actions fit for the piratical life. Play dirty by tossing sand at enemies to Blind them. Flick your weapon at a target to Disarm them. Or use your new Fancy Footwork passive while meleeing your enemy to ensure they can’t make opportunity attacks against you for the rest of your turn.</li><li><strong>Sorcerer: Shadow Magic</strong> – As a Shadow Magic Sorcerer, you deal in a form of magic that makes you deadliest in darkness. This subclass gives its sorcerer Superior Darkvision, as well as the ability to Shadow Walk between places of dim light or darkness. It also lets you call forth the perfectly homebrewed Hound of Ill Omen to harass your foes, and use Strength of the Grave to prevent you from being downed—ideal for those attempting Honor Mode runs.</li><li><strong>Warlock: Hexblade</strong> – Hexblade Warlocks make a pact with an entity from the Shadowfell that manifests in the form of magical weapons. Curse your enemies and force their souls to do your bidding. Slay any enemy that isn’t generally an element of nature, construct, giant blob, or already dead, and you’ll be able to raise their spirit from their corpse for ten turns. This new summon can deal necrotic damage and will rip away a chunk of your enemy’s soul to provide your Hexblade Warlock with healing.</li><li><strong>Wizard: Bladesinging</strong> – The Bladesinging subclass merges swordplay with wizardry. Expect new spellcasting animations when casting spells with your weapon, a new Bladesong ability to grant you supernatural speed, agility, and focus, plus gives you a bonus to any Constitution saving throw you make.</li></ul><p><strong>■ Photo Mode</strong></p><p>Finally, you can stop using pictures of fish you’ve caught on your dating profile and start snapping photos with your Hound of Ill Omen. Photo Mode is coming to <em>Baldur’s Gate III</em> in Patch 8!</p><p><em>Baldur’s Gate III</em>‘s Photo Mode is a little like a photo booth that lets you set up pretty much any shot you’d like. This new feature introduces a whole slew of options to let you customize and edit your in-game photography, with various levels of freedom depending on whether you’re using it while adventuring, or during combat, dialogue, and cinematic scenes.</p><p><strong>Camera Settings</strong></p><p>Toggleable from the HUD, located near the minimap, or by using the hotkey binding (F9 on PC, and by pressing both analog sticks at the same time on console), you’ll get to choose which character you want to take centre stage, determine their best side, and adjust the camera position to suit.</p><p>As long as they’re in your party while you’re adventuring, you’ll be able to line up your scene perfectly—including summons and those in a Wild Shape! For all budding virtual photographers, you can also turn on the camera reticle and composition grid to make sure you’re lining up the perfect shot.</p><p><strong>Lens Settings</strong></p><p>Determined the angle and sorted the positioning? You’ll be able to jump over to the Lens Settings where you can play around with the Field of View, Exposure, Depth of Field, and Focus.</p><p><strong>Scene Settings</strong></p><p>NPC ruining your shot? Toggle off either Playing, <a title="Genres > Party [79 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/party">Party</a>, NPC, or Enemy characters.</p><p>Now you’re ready for your close-up! Or, if you’re feeling creative, set the scene for a full-on Faerûn musical—choose a set facial expression, plus a range of over 40 static and animated poses, each with multiple variations to help give you the perfect layout.</p><p>Internal playtesting for Patch 8 is already well underway, and we wanted to highlight just a couple of the great shots our playtesters have been grabbing using photo mode, and how they’ve chosen to edit them!</p><p><strong>Post Processing Effects</strong></p><p>While you won’t be able to adjust your party or play around with lens and camera settings during cinematic scenes and dialogues, you’ll be able to color-grade your shot and experiment with contrast, saturation, highlights, brightness and vignette.</p><p><strong>Frames</strong></p><p>Add flair to your scene with a range of different frames and letterboxing to nail those cinematic shots.</p><p><strong>Stickers</strong></p><p>Choose from over 300 stickers and add up to 30 to your scene, including emojis, icons, blood splatters, textures, objects and items, and of course, cat ears.</p><p>In your hands soon, you’ll be able to take role-play to the next level with unique combinations of poses, stickers, and frames. We can’t wait to see what absolute nightmare fuel you come up with.</p></div><p><em>Baldur’s Gate III</em> is available now for PlayStation 5, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [6,399 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, and PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1086940/Baldurs_Gate_3/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> and <a href="https://www.gog.com/en/game/baldurs_gate_iii" target="_blank" rel="noopener">GOG</a>.</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Devolver Delayed Awards 2024 Recognizes Three Games Being Delayed To 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/devolver-delayed-awards-2024-recognizes-three-games-being-delayed-to-2025/1100-6528093/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/devolver-delayed-awards-2024-recognizes-three-games-being-delayed-to-2025.1046775/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/devolver-delayed-awards-2024-recognizes-three-games-being-delayed-to-2025/1100-6528093/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6528093">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">As the game industry prepares for Geoff Keighley's annual smorgasbord of news from The Game Awards, Devolver Digital has decided it's not going to wait until next month. Today, the publisher released Devolver Delayed 2024, a tongue-in-cheek awards show recognizing three games that have been pushed to 2025: Baby Steps, Stick It To The Stickman, and Skate Story.</p><p dir="ltr">Each game's delay was announced as a specific "award" given to the game against other fictional nominees. Specifically, the awards were named as follows:</p><ul><li dir="ltr"><strong>Best Inadvertent Tripping Simulator</strong> - Baby Steps</li><li dir="ltr"><strong>Best Late Stage Capitalism Roguelite</strong> - Stick It To The Stickman</li><li dir="ltr"><strong>Best Glass Demon In A Leading Role</strong> - Skate Story</li></ul><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/3/37852/4406334-baby-steps.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4406334" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/3/37852/4406334-baby-steps.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4406334"></a><figcaption>Baby Steps, winner of Best Inadvertent Tripping Simulator</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/3/37852/4406334-baby-steps.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">The "awards ceremony" then proceeded to a fourth award, <strong>Best Color Version Of A Monochromatic Classic</strong>. The winner was the previously unknown Volvy's Adventure DX, with a brief gameplay teaser showing an 8-bit side-scrolling platformer starring Devolver's rat-like mascot.</p><p dir="ltr">The presentation never actually confirms the game's existence, and Inscryption creator Daniel Mullins specifically says he "doesn't even think it's a real game" when he appears to receive the award for some unexplained reason, so whether or not Volvy's Adventure DX actually exists remains to be seen.</p><p dir="ltr">All three of the confirmed games in the presentation--Baby Steps, Stick It To The Stickman, and Skate Story--will now be launching in 2025 after being previously announced for a 2024 release window. Baby Steps was first unveiled at the Devolver Digital Showcase in June 2023, while both Skate Story and Stick It To The Stickman debuted the previous year.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/115235460361630065469?rel=author">Jason Fanelli</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Get The PS5 Game Returnal For A Great Price Right Now For Black Friday]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/get-the-ps5-game-returnal-for-a-great-price-right-now-for-black-friday/1100-6528106/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/get-the-ps5-game-returnal-for-a-great-price-right-now-for-black-friday.1046772/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/get-the-ps5-game-returnal-for-a-great-price-right-now-for-black-friday/1100-6528106/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="default-content">
        
          <p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p>
  
    <article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6528106">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/black-friday/">Black Friday</a> rolls on with more and more deals, and one of the offers available now is a pretty great discount on the third-person shooter Returnal from developer Housemarque and Sony.</p><p>Amazon and Best Buy are currently selling the PlayStation 5 game for only $30, which is a nice discount off its usual $70 price point. Prime members can get fast and free shipping.</p><p>Returnal originally launched in April 2021 for PS5, scoring <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/returnal-review-pc-update-live-die-repeat/1900-6417669/" data-ref-id="1900-6417669">generally great reviews across the board.</a> Here at GameSpot, we praised the game of elements from shooters, roguelikes, action games, and horror to combine for a "mysterious, moody masterpiece," <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/returnal-review-pc-update-live-die-repeat/1900-6417669/" data-ref-id="1900-6417669">as our reviewer said.</a></p><p>After launch, Housemarque released an <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/returnal-ascension-update-is-out-now-adds-co-op-and-more/1100-6501770/" data-ref-id="1100-6501770">Ascension update that added online co-op</a>, allowing up to two people to play through the campaign together.</p><p>Following the launch of Returnal, Housemarque was acquired by Sony. The Finnish studio is now <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/returnal-developer-housemarque-reveals-its-working-on-a-new-ip/1100-6501204/" data-ref-id="1100-6501204">making a new IP that will presumably be exclusive to PlayStation.</a></p><p>Black Friday is in full swing, and there are numerous other deals on PlayStation games available now. Titles like <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Astro-Bot-PS5-PlayStation-5/dp/B0D5SM3K4Q?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Astro Bot</a>, <a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/god-of-war-ragnarok-standard-edition-playstation-5/6523243.p?skuId=6523243&amp;nrtv_cid=6os529kmx5cro&amp;irclickid=UURSqsWrOxyKWT0XXXUZQWNzUkCQdMyFRSo60M0&amp;irgwc=1&amp;ref=198&amp;loc=Howl%20Technologies%2C%20Inc.&amp;acampID=0&amp;mpid=376373&amp;affgroup=%22Content%22" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">God of War Ragnarok</a>, and <a href="https://howl.link/nprb6mym35y40?article_name=Gamespot&amp;article_url=https://www.gamespot.com/17322751867394?u1=subid_value" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Helldivers 2</a> are all on sale, as are a <a href="https://www.amazon.com/PlayStation%C2%AE5-console-slim-SPORTS-College-Football/dp/B0D9JLP9N8?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">variety of PlayStation 5 hardware bundles.</a></p><p><strong>Best PlayStation Deals</strong></p><ul><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Astro-Bot-PS5-PlayStation-5/dp/B0D5SM3K4Q?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20" rel="nofollow ">Astro Bot</a> -- $50 (<del>$60</del>)</li><li><a href="https://howl.link/zj4ws3n38gf1g?article_name=Gamespot&amp;article_url=https://www.gamespot.com/1732403022804?u1=subid_value" rel="nofollow ">Days Gone</a> -- $20 (<del>$40</del>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08FC5TTBF?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20" rel="nofollow ">Demon's Souls</a> -- $30 (<del>$70</del>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CGXZQ4CD?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20" rel="nofollow ">Final Fantasy 7 Rebirth (Exclusive Amazon Edition)</a> -- $40 (<del>$70</del>)</li><li><a href="https://howl.link/n5wbexvtz1ltl?article_name=Gamespot&amp;article_url=https://www.gamespot.com/17324029494702?u1=subid_value" rel="nofollow ">Death Stranding Director's Cut</a> -- $20 (<del>$50</del>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CGXZQ4CD?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20" rel="nofollow ">Final Fantasy 7 Rebirth (Exclusive Amazon Edition)</a> -- $40 (<del>$70</del>)</li><li><a href="https://howl.link/e64spmv177l3e?article_name=Gamespot&amp;article_url=https://www.gamespot.com/17322749518382?u1=subid_value" rel="nofollow ">God of War: Ragnarok (PS4)</a> -- $20 (<del>$60</del>)</li><li><a href="https://howl.link/e64spmv177l3e?article_name=Gamespot&amp;article_url=https://www.gamespot.com/17322749518382?u1=subid_value" rel="nofollow ">God of War: Ragnarok (PS5)</a> -- $30 (<del>$70</del>)</li><li><a href="https://howl.link/jv2xz17rgr5hu?article_name=Gamespot&amp;article_url=https://www.gamespot.com/17327242304167?u1=subid_value" rel="nofollow ">Gran Turismo 7 (PS4)</a> -- $20 (<del>$60</del>)</li><li><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fgoto.walmart.com%2Fc%2F1804712%2F565706%2F9383%3Fveh%3Daff%26sourceid%3Dimp_000011112222333344%26u%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FGran-Turismo-7-PlayStation-5%2F443954076%3FclassType%3DVARIANT%26athbdg%3DL1200%26from%3D%2Fsearch%26subId1%3Dsubid_value&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fget-the-ps5-game-returnal-for-a-great-price-right-now-for-black-friday%2F1100-6528106%2F&amp;event_type=click" rel="nofollow ">Gran Turismo 7 (PS5)</a> -- $30 (<del>$70</del>)</li><li><a href="https://howl.link/nprb6mym35y40?article_name=Gamespot&amp;article_url=https://www.gamespot.com/17322751867394?u1=subid_value" rel="nofollow ">Helldivers 2</a> -- $30 (<del>$40</del>)</li><li><a href="https://howl.link/pdlz4ucl74s62?article_name=Gamespot&amp;article_url=https://www.gamespot.com/17322752225582?u1=subid_value" rel="nofollow ">Horizon Forbidden West Complete Edition</a> -- $40 (<del>$60</del>)</li><li><a href="https://howl.link/w6t5hkwsbavwe?article_name=Gamespot&amp;article_url=https://www.gamespot.com/17322752925656?u1=subid_value" rel="nofollow ">Marvel's Spider-Man: Miles Morales</a> -- $20 (<del>$50</del>)</li><li><a href="https://howl.link/zksce24mfl59s?article_name=Gamespot&amp;article_url=https://www.gamespot.com/1732275262119?u1=subid_value" rel="nofollow ">Marvel's Spider-Man: Miles Morales Ultimate Edition</a> -- $40 (<del>$70</del>)</li><li><a href="https://howl.link/s6gr50llrjvay?article_name=Gamespot&amp;article_url=https://www.gamespot.com/17322753314645?u1=subid_value" rel="nofollow ">Marvel's Spider-Man 2: Standard Edition</a> -- $40 (<del>$70</del>)</li><li><a href="https://howl.link/r3xz6uaq1c8qe?article_name=Gamespot&amp;article_url=https://www.gamespot.com/17322754355803?u1=subid_value" rel="nofollow ">Ratchet &amp; Clank: Rift Apart</a> -- $30 (<del>$70</del>)</li><li><a href="https://howl.link/dscmlnyxoc0cf?article_name=Gamespot&amp;article_url=https://www.gamespot.com/17322754571828?u1=subid_value" rel="nofollow ">Returnal</a> -- $30 (<del>$70</del>)</li><li><a href="https://howl.link/mfcexzughujpc?article_name=Gamespot&amp;article_url=https://www.gamespot.com/17322750143548?u1=subid_value" rel="nofollow ">Rise of the Ronin</a> -- $40 (<del>$70</del>)</li><li><a href="https://howl.link/9tcy8p26e98kp?article_name=Gamespot&amp;article_url=https://www.gamespot.com/17322749294671?u1=subid_value" rel="nofollow ">Stellar Blade</a> -- $50 (<del>$70</del>)</li><li><a href="https://howl.link/hjtgv10z93ke4?article_name=Gamespot&amp;article_url=https://www.gamespot.com/17322443950035?u1=subid_value" rel="nofollow ">The Last of Us Part 1</a> -- $30 (<del>$70</del>)</li><li><a href="https://howl.link/mph3vc1g3yucc?article_name=Gamespot&amp;article_url=https://www.gamespot.com/17322749899611?u1=subid_value" rel="nofollow ">The Last of Us Part 2 Remastered</a> -- $40 (<del>$50</del>)</li><li><a href="https://howl.link/odvrhrvlownkg?article_name=Gamespot&amp;article_url=https://www.gamespot.com/17322755198005?u1=subid_value" rel="nofollow ">Uncharted: Legacy of Thieves Collection</a> -- $20 (<del>$50</del>)</li></ul><p><strong>PS5 Console &amp; Accessory Deals</strong></p><ul><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CJSY6961?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20" rel="nofollow ">DualSense Controller</a> -- $55-$60 (<del>$75-$80</del>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0C1Q9X8VH?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20" rel="nofollow ">PSVR 2 Horizon Call of the Mountain Bundle</a> -- $349 (<del>$600</del>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/PULSE-Explore-Wireless-Earbuds-PlayStation-5/dp/B0CMDFSB89?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20" rel="nofollow ">Pulse Explore Wireless Earbuds</a> -- $170 (<del>$200</del>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/PlayStation-Pulse-Elite-Wireless-Headset-5/dp/B0CMDH9M5W?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20" rel="nofollow ">Pulse Elite Wireless Headset</a> -- $129 (<del>$150</del>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/PS5-Console-Fortnite-Cobalt-PlayStation-5/dp/B0DJHF6Q9Z?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20" rel="nofollow ">PS5 Slim Fortnite Cobalt Star Bundle</a> -- $425 (<del>$500</del>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/PlayStation%C2%AE5-console-slim-SPORTS-College-Football/dp/B0D9JLP9N8?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20" rel="nofollow ">PS5 Slim College Football 25 Bundle</a> -- $454</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Playstation-PS5-Console-Fortnite-Digital-5/dp/B0DJHG2VVS?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20" rel="nofollow ">PS5 Slim Digital Fortnite Cobalt Star Bundle</a> -- $375 (<del>$450</del>)</li><li><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fgoto.walmart.com%2Fc%2F1804712%2F565706%2F9383%3Fveh%3Daff%26sourceid%3Dimp_000011112222333344%26u%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FPlayStation-5-Digital-Slim-Console%2F9602603812%26subId1%3Dsubid_value&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fget-the-ps5-game-returnal-for-a-great-price-right-now-for-black-friday%2F1100-6528106%2F&amp;event_type=click" rel="nofollow ">PS5 Slim Digital NBA 2K25 Bundle</a> -- $374 (<del>$500</del>)</li><li><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fgoto.walmart.com%2Fc%2F1804712%2F565706%2F9383%3Fveh%3Daff%26sourceid%3Dimp_000011112222333344%26u%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2F5350977288%26subId1%3Dsubid_value&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fget-the-ps5-game-returnal-for-a-great-price-right-now-for-black-friday%2F1100-6528106%2F&amp;event_type=click" rel="nofollow ">PS5 Slim with Extra DualSense Controller</a> -- $475</li></ul>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article>

    
  

</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[For Love of God, Make Your Own Website]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/website-musk-twitter-facebook-internet</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/for-love-of-god-make-your-own-website.1046760/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://aftermath.site/website-musk-twitter-facebook-internet<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Browsing the internet used to be a hobby of mine. Ever since my dad got us a modem when I was around ten, I spent hours at a time just looking at different websites. The internet felt like a limitless expanse of free expression. Now, despite how many more people use the internet, I usually end up at the same three or four websites, and I end up a lot more bored.</p><p>Part of the appeal of the internet when I was young was making your own website. I taught myself HTML as a tween to facilitate that desire (I made a website about Sailor Saturn from <em>Sailor Moon.</em>). Free web hosting on sites like Angelfire or Geocities was abundant, and you could waste an entire day just looking at the dumb things people put online. Just take a look at the <a href="https://geocities.restorativland.org/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Geocities Gallery</a>—people made websites about their favorite animals, their life experiences, or celebrities they loved, and I devoured all of these things with equal enthusiasm. This website is <a href="https://geocities.restorativland.org/Hollywood/Lot/1214/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">just a list of links that a guy named Dave likes</a>! This person from Texas <a href="https://geocities.restorativland.org/Hollywood/Lot/1348/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">wanted to mail people giallo movies on VHS</a>! This is <a href="https://geocities.restorativland.org/Paris/Metro/2406/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">literally just pictures of North Vietnam</a>, taken by a person from South Vietnam who now lives in America!</p><p>If you could figure out how to host your own website, you’d have even more freedom over the design and the content. Other than LiveJournal, this was my first introduction to the power of fandom. <a href="http://ohtori.nu/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ohtori.nu</a> was a website maintained by diehard <em>Utena</em> fans and included scanned animation cells, critical analysis and their own translation of scripts. The fact that the site is still up and still hosting mostly the same material is a testament to the small group of people who made and maintained it.</p><p>Social media erased the need to build a website to express yourself online. Sure, early social media like MySpace allowed for you to radically change the look and feel of your page—adding music and changing the background—but ultimately, it was still a MySpace page, with a comment wall and your top eight friends. On top of that, MySpace had total ownership of that page, meaning when the site was bought and sold, individual users had no say in the changes. By 2019, you couldn’t even look at your old MySpace accounts anymore <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2019/mar/18/myspace-loses-all-content-uploaded-before-2016" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">because they lost all the data</a> from prior to 2016.</p><figure><blockquote><p>Though we all moved to these platforms for their convenience, over time they became less convenient.</p></blockquote></figure><p>This only accelerated as we moved to new social media, like Facebook, which was determined to keep all important contact information within the app. Instead of a local business making a website on Geocities, they would make themselves a Facebook page—or now, an Instagram account—because all their customers likely had Facebook accounts already.&nbsp;</p><p>Though we all moved to these platforms for their convenience, over time they became less convenient. I don’t remember exactly when or why I stopped looking at Facebook, just that now <a href="https://aftermath.site/facebook-ai-tiny-house" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">it’s overrun with AI slop</a> and has <a href="https://aftermath.site/facebook-marketplace-is-not-fun-to-use" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">become barely usable</a>. Twitter is experiencing the same “enshittification” process as we speak: After the election, <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/tech/tech-news/x-sees-largest-user-exodus-musk-takeover-rcna179793" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">users left the Elon Musk-owned platform in droves</a>, unwilling to centralize the way they talk to people online around this one website. Not that it matters much—Musk and Facebook’s Mark Zuckerberg have already made billions of dollars off of convincing everyone to invest their time into these websites, and if they had their way, you would spend even more time there, earning them even more money.</p><p>Unfortunately, this is what all of the internet is right now: social media, owned by large corporations that make changes to them to limit or suppress your speech, in order to make themselves more attractive to advertisers or just pursue their owners’ ends. Even the best Twitter alternatives, like Bluesky, aren’t immune to any of this—the more you centralize onto one single website, the more power that website has over you and what you post there. More than just moving to another website, we need <em>more websites.</em></p><p>I didn’t realize how important that was until I started my own website, and I didn’t even learn it from helping to run the damn thing. When I meet people at events, they tell me that they’ve set Aftermath as their homepage. People tell me they love interacting with other people in the comments. They tell me it’s one on a small list of websites, not social media, that they check in on every day. People, it seems, actually like going to a website, and they like that we made one.</p><figure><blockquote><p>We were already long overdue for a return to websites we control, rather than feeds manipulated by tech oligarchs</p></blockquote></figure><p>I cannot remember the last time I actually went to a website and browsed, took my time discovering the way a person expressed themselves through code. Does anyone else remember the website <a href="https://superbad.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Superbad</a>, a little personal project that took you through bizarre web design experiments? <a href="https://zombo.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Zombo com</a>? These websites are still around because they don’t depend on the benevolence of a billionaire for their existence.</p><p>“Building our own websites, making independent media, and striving for more democratic social networks—I think these are some of the small but crucial things we need to be doing to create alternatives to the monopolistic, billionaire-owned and increasingly authoritarian tech ecosystems currently dominating our lives,” Brian Merchant, author of <em>Blood in the Machine</em>, told me. “We still have to figure out how to triumph over extractive tech companies and curtail aggressively toxic social networks that encourage the spread of hateful messages, and to fund and elevate alternatives not in thrall to tech billionaires, but building working models is a necessary and urgent first step.”</p><p>It is clear that tech billionaires like Musk know that when they own the means of communication, they run the whole show. If you’ve made a home on Twitter, you’re basically <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/xtwitter-is-making-more-changes-to-the-block-button-making-posts-from-public-accounts-visible-to-everyone" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">completely vulnerable to Musk’s randomly changing whims</a>, and also his disgusting political beliefs. He campaigned with Trump and immediately congratulated him when he won the election. Also congratulating the President-elect were <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2024/11/06/trump-2024-election-win-tech-ceos-give-their-congratulations.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Zuckerberg and Amazon’s Jeff Bezos, two</a> tech oligarchs who also want us to use their proprietary apps and websites for everything in our lives.</p><p>“We were already long overdue for a return to websites we control, rather than feeds manipulated by tech oligarchs,” Molly White from Web3 Is Going Great! told me. “Now that they’ve made it clear how eager they are to help usher in authoritarianism, I think it will only become more painfully clear how important sovereign websites are to protecting information and free expression.”</p><p>To me, having my own website, even one I run as a business with my friends, gives me a degree of freedom over my own work that I’ve never had before. If you look at my work on Kotaku, there’s so many garbage ads on the screen you can barely see the words. Waypoint and Motherboard are both being run like a haunted ship, <a href="https://aftermath.site/vice-waypoint-site-news-reopen-open" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">pumping out junk so that Vice’s new owners can put ads on it</a>. I don’t have to worry about that anymore—I don’t have to worry about my work being taken down or modified or sold, or <a href="https://www.404media.co/someone-made-a-dataset-of-one-million-bluesky-posts-for-machine-learning-research/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">put in an AI training set against my will</a>. I have my own website, and it is mine, and I get to own it completely. I hope someday soon I can visit your website.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[December’s PS Plus Monthly Games feature It Takes Two & Temtem]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/11/27/decembers-ps-plus-monthly-games-feature-it-takes-two-temtem/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/december%E2%80%99s-ps-plus-monthly-games-feature-it-takes-two-temtem.1046751/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/11/27/decembers-ps-plus-monthly-games-feature-it-takes-two-temtem/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>The <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/ps-plus">PlayStation Plus</a> monthly games for December 2024 have been announced, and Sony’s getting right into the holiday spirit with one of the best local co-op games out there, some family friendly monster battling aaaaaaand…. Aliens.</p>
<h2>What are the PS Plus December 2024 games?</h2>
<p>The following three games will be available from the first Tuesday of the month, which will be 3rd December.</p>


<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2021/03/24/it-takes-two-review/"><strong>It Takes Two</strong></a> (PS5 | PS4)</li>
<li><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2023/06/19/aliens-dark-descent-review/"><strong>Aliens: Dark Descent</strong></a> (PS5 | PS4)</li>
<li><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/temtem"><strong>Temtem</strong></a> (PS5)</li>
</ul>

<p>If you haven’t already played <strong>It Takes Two</strong>, then I don’t know what is wrong with you – OK, so it can be difficult to get someone to sit down for co-op, and maybe 3D platformers ain’t your thing. Hazelight’s latest game is easily their greatest, though, with full couch co-op at the heart of the game (and an online counterpart that works really well), and a quirky story that sends its married protagonists on a wild and ever-changing adventure. It’s well worth playing, if you can, and chances are this is tying in with a new Hazelight game announcement very soon. Fares has a knack of popping up at The Game Awards…</p>


<p>For a complete change of pace we have <strong>Aliens: Dark Descent</strong>, a fraught real time tactical game set in the dark sci-fi universe. You have to command a small team of Colonial Marines on missions where the possibility of xenomorphs appearing to attack you is around every corner. In our review, Steve said “It absolutely nails the feel of the films and brings exactly the kind of tense and thrilling strategy combat you would want. The iconic motion tracker and creature design fit perfectly with the genre and there is even an interesting narrative that introduces some new perspectives to the series. While game over can come far too swiftly at times, there is always something to draw you back in.”</p>

<p>Rounding this month out is the PS5-only <strong>Temtem</strong>, a game that riffs off the monster collecting and battling of Pokémon with an online multiplayer twist. The game spent a good year or two in early access, building out from an initial island to a broader game. We played that initial launch, with Aran saying “So far Temtem has captured similar feelings to what I felt when playing Pokémon originally on the Game Boy, but with the MMO layer on top of that, TemTem has a chance to become many people’s obsession for years to come.”</p>
<p>So, what do you think of this month’s games?</p>
<h2>Can you still get the November 2024 PS Plus games?</h2>
<p>You can still grab November’s titles up until the new set of game’s arrives on 3rd December, so make sure to grab them while you can! They are:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2022/03/21/ghostwire-tokyo-review-ps5/"><strong>Ghostwire: Tokyo</strong></a> (PS5)</li>
<li><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2023/10/17/hot-wheels-unleashed-2-turbocharged-review/"><strong>Hot Wheels Unleashed 2 – Turbocharged</strong></a> (PS5|PS4)</li>
<li><strong>Death Note Killer Within</strong> (PS5|PS4)</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/11/05/novembers-ps-plus-monthly-games-include-deathwire-tokyo/">Head here for more details.</a></p>
<p><em>Source:&nbsp;<a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2024/10/30/playstation-plus-monthly-games-for-november-hot-wheels-unleashed-2-turbocharged-ghostwire-tokyo-death-note-killer-within/">PS Blog</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[In Dante's Ring, you are a firefighter wrestling with your inner demons while sledding down a volcano]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/in-dantes-ring-you-are-a-firefighter-wrestling-with-your-inner-demons-while-sledding-down-a-volcano</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/in-dantes-ring-you-are-a-firefighter-wrestling-with-your-inner-demons-while-sledding-down-a-volcano.1046748/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/in-dantes-ring-you-are-a-firefighter-wrestling-with-your-inner-demons-while-sledding-down-a-volcano<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
  

        <p>A "disaster combat" game from the creators of The Invincible</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/ss_8ec55b01941486305347a02f9ddf835daf088d5b.1920x1080.jpg?width=1200&amp;height=1200&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Starward Industries</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>I have one urgent request for Starward Industries, creators of the just-announced “anti-combat” survival RPG Dante’s Ring – don’t use the phrase “ring of fire” in your English marketing materials. I get that you’re going for a cocktail of Divina Commedia and FromSoftware associations, but you have to remember that this is the internet and we're all desperately crude. I can’t speak for people from other English-language countries, but when I hear somebody talking about their "ring of fire", I tend to assume they’ve been at the vindaloo.</p><!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Dante's Ring - Teaser Trailer (Golden Joystick Awards)" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/IogYUUlDkSI?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Dante's Ring - Teaser Trailer (Golden Joystick Awards)</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/IogYUUlDkSI?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/IogYUUlDkSI?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IogYUUlDkSI" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>There’s no time for such shenanigans in Dante’s Ring. It doesn’t look like it has a sense of humour at all, probably to its credit. According to <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2988030/Dantes_Ring/">the Steam page</a>, it’s “an action-adventure RPG with survival and arcade elements, and a disaster combat theme, where you confront the deadliest forces of nature — from raging fires and molten lava to powerful earthquakes.”</p>
<p>You play somebody exploring an extinct volcanic mountain range that isn’t quite as extinct as advertised. Rather than fighting any individual enemies, you must “strive to survive and save as many lives as possible while facing the force of nature, the aftermath of a natural disaster, deep-seated human beliefs, social conflicts, and your own inner demons”.</p><p>To do all this, you’ll scavenge for resources and make use of “retro” gadgets such as propellor-powered sleds and vulcanologist suits, together with more basic instruments such as fireaxes. “Will you fight a frenetic fire or flee from a pyroclastic flow?” the Steam page goes on. “Break the door to rescue someone or stop and give first aid?”</p>
<p>That covers the immediate “disaster combat” aspect, anyway. As regards the themes of belief and social conflict, there’s talk of “complex moral choices” and negotiating between “diverse” NPC factions. The game is hub-based, with the ability to choose a loadout before embarking on a mission. The world appears to evolve from mission to mission, “with outcomes that can influence the course of the story”.</p>
<p>The social/religious theming here sounds laboured, if I’m honest, but I like the idea of a game about making ends meet on the surface of an active volcano. I imagine they have a propagating fire system and fluid physics for the lava. Hopefully, they’ll give the likes of <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/far-cry-2">Far Cry 2</a> a run for their money. Hopefully, they'll also improve on their previous game <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-invincible-review">The Invincible</a>, which Julian Benson described as "an engaging sci-fi adventure that can leave you cold and confused the moment it stops holding your hand".</p>
<p>Dante’s Ring will launch into Steam early access next year. If you want something weird and fiery to play in the meantime, there's always <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/noita">Noita</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Two Of The Best PS2 Games Ever Are Coming To PS Plus Next Month]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/ps-plus-games-december-2024-classics-ps2-sly-cooper-jak-1851709425</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/two-of-the-best-ps2-games-ever-are-coming-to-ps-plus-next-month.1046739/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/ps-plus-games-december-2024-classics-ps2-sly-cooper-jak-1851709425<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Sony has announced more PlayStation 2 games are coming to PS Plus’ Classics Catalog next month, and the lineup includes two of the best platformers ever released on the console:<em>&nbsp;</em>2004's <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/games/sly-2-band-of-thieves&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/games/sly-2-band-of-thieves"><em>Sly 2: Band of Thieves</em></a></span><em> </em>and 2005's <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/games/sly-3-honor-among-thieves&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/games/sly-3-honor-among-thieves"><em>Sly 3: Honor Among Thieves</em></a></span><em>.</em> Oh, and of course, some other stuff will be arriving in December for all PS Plus subscribers, too. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196230" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="This Cool New Retro Console Is A Great Gift For Atari Fans" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="217" data-playlist="196230,195859,196470" data-current="196230"><div><p>This Cool New Retro Console Is A Great Gift For Atari Fans</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196230/196230_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196230/196230_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196230/196230_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196230/196230_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21779.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://blog.playstation.com/2024/11/27/playstation-plus-monthly-games-for-december-it-takes-two-aliens-dark-descent-temtem/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://blog.playstation.com/2024/11/27/playstation-plus-monthly-games-for-december-it-takes-two-aliens-dark-descent-temtem/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">On November 27, PlayStation revealed</a></span> some of the games that are going to be added to PS Plus in December. Keep in mind this isn’t the full list; that will be revealed later next month. </p><p>The big news is that, as part of the company’s continuing 30th anniversary celebration, Sony is adding even more PS2 games to its Classics Catalog in December. These older PS1, PS2, PS3, and PSP games are only available to PS Plus Premium subscribers. </p><p>And this time around, Sony is completing the OG <em>Sly Cooper</em> trilogy with the addition of <em>Sly 2</em> and <em>Sly 3,</em> the best games in the series. Back in May, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/playstation-2-classics-ps4-ps5-tomb-raider-star-wars-1851503467&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/playstation-2-classics-ps4-ps5-tomb-raider-star-wars-1851503467">Sony added the original <em>Sly Cooper</em></a></span>. Since then, I’ve wondered when or if these other two games would arrive. It’s nice to see some of the best platformers ever released on the PS2 finally playable on PS4 and PS5. It’s easier than ever to play through these colorful platformers about a thieving, talking raccoon stealing valuable items from criminals around the world while avoiding the police. </p><p>It’s a shame that these are just so-so emulated versions of the PS2 games and not the much better-looking and playing PS3 remasters, but <em>Sly Cooper</em> fans will take what they can get at this point. (Oh, and <em>Jak and Daxter</em> is being added too, which is nice.) </p><p>The last game that needs to be added is 2013's <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/lets-take-a-look-at-a-playstation-game-pitch-1847183157&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/lets-take-a-look-at-a-playstation-game-pitch-1847183157"><em>Sly Cooper: Thieves in Time</em></a></span><em>.</em> That would make the entire series playable on PS4 and PS5. Sadly, that game was released on PS3 and, as such, won’t be playable natively on either platform, so if it arrived at all, it would be as a streaming title. Still, like I said, <em>Sly </em>fans will take what they can get. </p><p>Meanwhile, starting December 3, <em>all</em> PlayStation Plus subscribers will be able to grab <em>It Takes Two</em>, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/temtem-pokemon-mmo-end-development-1851310155&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/temtem-pokemon-mmo-end-development-1851310155"><em>TemTem</em></a></span>, and <em>Aliens: Dark Descent </em>as part of the month’s free games.</p><p> <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/it-takes-two-creates-an-almost-perfect-union-of-story-a-1846576907&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/it-takes-two-creates-an-almost-perfect-union-of-story-a-1846576907">Co-op puzzler <em>It Takes Two</em></a></span> is a perfect game to grab during the holidays as you and a family member visiting for a few days can easily beat it in a weekend while gorging on leftovers and booze. Just make sure whoever you play with doesn’t mind some dark moments. </p><p> .<br></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Best Buy Black Friday Deals Are Popping Off]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/best-buy-black-friday-deals-are-popping-off/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/best-buy-black-friday-deals-are-popping-off.1046736/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/best-buy-black-friday-deals-are-popping-off/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>There’s nothing wrong with being excited about Thanksgiving. It’s a time to spend with friends and family, enjoy exceptional home-cooked meals, and skirt around the latest doom-and-gloom in the news. But for some, it’s just another day. The actual holiday is Black Friday, where you can score the year’s top electronics, video games, peripherals, and more at significantly reduced prices. Well, it’s upon us, so here are the Best Buy Black Friday deals popping off right now!</p>



<h2 id="h-best-buy-black-friday-deals-and-doorbusters-for-gamers">Best Buy Black Friday Deals and Doorbusters for Gamers</h2>



<p>Best Buy is known for more than its gaming peripherals, computer components, and video game selection. They have a broad array of electronics, like cordless vacuums and smartwatches, for the technologically-focused homeowner and busybody. But this is Insider Gaming; it’s right there in the name. We’re all about gaming, and we want to highlight the top Best Buy Black Friday deals for gaming:</p>



<h3 id="h-doorbusters"><strong>Doorbusters</strong></h3>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/lg-ultragear-45-oled-curved-wqhd-240hz-0-03ms-freesync-and-nvidia-g-sync-compatible-gaming-monitor-with-hdr400-black/6575395.p?skuId=6575395" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">LG UltraGear 45″ OLED Curved Gaming Monitor ($999.99)</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/hp-victus-15-6-full-hd-gaming-laptop-amd-ryzen-5-7535hs-8gb-ddr5-memory-amd-radeon-rx-6550m-512gb-ssd-mica-silver/6578933.p?skuId=6578933" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">HP Victus 15.6″ Full HD Gaming Laptop ($429.99)</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/asus-rog-ally-7-120hz-fhd-1080p-gaming-handheld-amd-ryzen-z1-extreme-processor-512gb-white/6542964.p?skuId=6542964" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">ASUS ROG Ally X 7″ Gaming Handheld ($499.99)</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/promo/college-football-25-and-madden-nfl-25-savings" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">College Football 25 ($29.99)</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/promo/college-football-25-and-madden-nfl-25-savings" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Madden NFL 25 ($29.99)</a></li>
</ul>







<h3 id="h-black-friday-deals-at-best-buy">Black Friday Deals at Best Buy</h3>



<p>Alongside the slew of Black Friday doorbusters available at Best Buy, most of which will only be available for a limited time, the electronics store is holding a massive sale on countless peripherals, accessories, and systems, ranging from the ASUS ROG Ally X to the PlayStation 5!</p>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/lg-65-class-ut70-series-led-4k-uhd-smart-webos-tv-2024/6593578.p?skuId=6593578" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">LG 65″ LED 4K UHD AI Smart TV ($379.99)</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/promo/save-on-select-playstation-5-consoles" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">PlayStation 5 Consoles (Save Up to $125)</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/sony-playstation-vr2-horizon-call-of-the-mountain-bundle-white/6542113.p?skuId=6542113" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">PlayStation VR Horizon Call of the Mountain Bundle ($349.99)</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/promo/save-on-select-nintendo-switch-games" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Nintendo Switch Video Games (Save Up to 50%)</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/promo/save-on-lenovo-legion-go-gaming-handheld" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Lenovo Legion Go (Save $200)</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/promo/save-on-select-astro-gaming-headsets" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Astro Gaming A50 Gen 4 Wireless Headset (Save $100)</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/razer-kraken-v3-pro-hypersense-wireless-gaming-headset-for-pc-black/6480356.p?skuId=6480356" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Razer Kraken V3 Pro HyperSense Wireless Headset ($99.99)</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/samsung-27-odyssey-fhd-ips-240hz-g-sync-gaming-monitor-black/6507926.p?skuId=6507926" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Samsung 27″ Odyssey FHD Gaming Monitor ($199.99)</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/promo/select-pc-gaming-savings" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">PC Gaming Essentials (Save Up to 50%)</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/promo/select-pc-gaming-accessories" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Gaming Accessories (Save Up to 50%)</a></li>
</ul>



<p>Let us know what you’re picking up this Black Friday in the comments below! Or, show us your haul over at the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forums</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>If you’re a PC gamer, you can score a ton of high-quality peripherals cheap with the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/redragon-black-friday-deals-gaming-mice-keyboards/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Redragon Black Friday deals</a> going on now!</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch Online Adds Three Genesis Games, Including Some Leaving Steam]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-switch-online-adds-three-genesis-games-including-some-leaving-steam/1100-6528102/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-switch-online-adds-three-genesis-games-including-some-leaving-steam.1046730/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-switch-online-adds-three-genesis-games-including-some-leaving-steam/1100-6528102/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6528102">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Not every title from the 16-bit era of consoles is readily available to legally play, but three more games from the Sega Genesis vault are heading to Nintendo Switch. ToeJam &amp; Earl in Panic on Funkotron, Vectorman, and Mercs will all be available starting today. Nintendo made the announcement on X and dropped a brief trailer for all three games.</p><div data-embed-type="tweet" data-src="https://twitter.com/NintendoAmerica/status/1861593424215838733" data-has-image="true"><blockquote data-conversation="none" data-mce-disable-toolbar="true"><div dir="ltr"><p>Three classic SEGA Genesis games have just been made available for <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/NintendoSwitchOnline?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#NintendoSwitchOnline</a> + Expansion Pack members!</p><p> ☑️ ToeJam &amp; Earl in Panic on Funkotron<br>☑️ Vectorman<br>☑️ WOLF OF THE BATTLEFIELD: MERCS<br>Original packaging shown. Contest has ended. <a href="https://t.co/83mMTzfl4m" rel="nofollow ">pic.twitter.com/83mMTzfl4m</a></p></div>  — Nintendo of America (@NintendoAmerica) <a href="https://twitter.com/NintendoAmerica/status/1861593424215838733?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 27, 2024</a></blockquote>              </div><p>ToeJam &amp; Earl in Panic on Funkotron is the first sequel in the franchise, and it debuted on Genesis in 1993. While the aliens known as ToeJam and Earl were stranded on Earth in the first game, Panic on Funkotron brings the duo back to their home planet where new problems await them. Several humans stowed away on their journey to Funkotron, and it's up to ToeJam and Earl to make things right in this side-scrolling platformer.</p><p>Vectorman was a state-of-the-art game by 1995 standards, and also Genesis' answer to Super Nintendo's Donkey Kong Country. Developer BlueSky Software successfully utilized pre-rendered 3D models that made this 2D action-platformer stand out from other Genesis titles. The initial story for the game is similar to Pixar's WALL-E, because the Earth has been abandoned by humans who left robots behind to clean up their mess. The story diverges when one of the robots becomes a nuclear-powered tyrant known as WarHead, leaving Vectorman as the only robot on Earth who isn't under his control.</p><p>Mercs--or Wolf of the Battlefield: Mercs--was an arcade title developed and released by Capcom before Sega brought it to the Genesis in 1990. Up to three players could assume control of the covert mercenaries in Wolf Force. Their mission was to infiltrate Zutula--a fictional African country--and rescue the former President from rebels who seized control of the land.</p><p>ToeJam &amp; Earl in Panic on Funkotron and Vectorman are among <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/sega-is-delisting-many-of-its-classic-games-in-december/1100-6527642/" data-ref-id="1100-6527642">the long list of games that Sega is delisting from Steam</a> in December. Meanwhile, Sega launched a new line of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/sega-launches-a-new-classics-merch-collection-at-amazon/1100-6527687/" data-ref-id="1100-6527687">Genesis game-themed merchandise</a> at Amazon. The company is also planning to reboot <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/sega-announces-new-jet-set-radio-crazy-taxi-and-more-long-awaited-sequels/1100-6519798/" data-ref-id="1100-6519798">five of its classic franchises</a>: Jet Set Radio, Shinobi, Golden Axe, Streets of Rage, and Crazy Taxi.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ratchet & Clank Rift Apart Is Only $30 Right Now On PS5 For Black Friday]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ratchet-clank-rift-apart-is-only-30-right-now-on-ps5-for-black-friday/1100-6528105/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ratchet-clank-rift-apart-is-only-30-right-now-on-ps5-for-black-friday.1046724/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ratchet-clank-rift-apart-is-only-30-right-now-on-ps5-for-black-friday/1100-6528105/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-main">

      
                    
  
              <header id="masthead"><nav></nav></header>      
                            <div id="site-wrapper" role="main">
          <div id="default-content">
        
          <p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p>
  
    <article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6528105">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>The <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/black-friday/">Black Friday</a> shopping season is here, and plenty of PlayStation games are on sale. If your'e looking for a copy of Ratchet &amp; Clank: Rift Apart, you're in luck, as Target and Best Buy have the game on PS5 for only $30 right now for the popular shopping season. It normally sells for $70.</p><p>Rift Apart was released in 2021 from developer Insomniac Games, and scored solid reviews across the board, including a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/ratchet-clank-rift-apart-review-a-riveting-adventure/1900-6417686/" data-ref-id="1900-6417686">9/10 from GameSpot.</a> We praised the game's gorgeous presentation and DualSense controller features, and also lauded the addition of the instantly lovable character, Rivet.</p><p>Developer Insomniac would go on to release Marvel's Spider-Man 2 in 2023 and is now working on Marve's Wolverine, which will be exclusive to PlayStation. The developer has not announced any new entries in the series, with Rift Apart being the most recent.</p><p>There are loads of other PlayStation games on sale this Black Friday, including <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Astro-Bot-PS5-PlayStation-5/dp/B0D5SM3K4Q?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Astro Bot</a>, <a href="https://howl.link/n5wbexvtz1ltl?article_name=Gamespot&amp;article_url=https://www.gamespot.com/17324029494702?u1=subid_value" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Death Stranding's Director's Cut</a>, and <a href="https://howl.link/9tcy8p26e98kp?article_name=Gamespot&amp;article_url=https://www.gamespot.com/17322749294671?u1=subid_value" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Stellar Blade</a>, among others. If you're in the market for a new PS5 console, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Playstation-PS5-Console-Fortnite-Digital-5/dp/B0DJHG2VVS?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">you can get the PS5 Slim Fortnite Cobalt bundle for under $400.</a></p><p>Keep checking back with GameSpot for more Black Friday deals in the days ahead.</p><p><strong>Deals On PS5 Exclusives</strong></p><ul><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Astro-Bot-PS5-PlayStation-5/dp/B0D5SM3K4Q?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20" rel="nofollow ">Astro Bot</a> -- $50 (<del>$60</del>)</li><li><a href="https://howl.link/zj4ws3n38gf1g?article_name=Gamespot&amp;article_url=https://www.gamespot.com/1732403022804?u1=subid_value" rel="nofollow ">Days Gone</a> -- $20 (<del>$40</del>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08FC5TTBF?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20" rel="nofollow ">Demon's Souls</a> -- $30 (<del>$70</del>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CGXZQ4CD?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20" rel="nofollow ">Final Fantasy 7 Rebirth (Exclusive Amazon Edition)</a> -- $40 (<del>$70</del>)</li><li><a href="https://howl.link/n5wbexvtz1ltl?article_name=Gamespot&amp;article_url=https://www.gamespot.com/17324029494702?u1=subid_value" rel="nofollow ">Death Stranding Director's Cut</a> -- $20 (<del>$50</del>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CGXZQ4CD?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20" rel="nofollow ">Final Fantasy 7 Rebirth (Exclusive Amazon Edition)</a> -- $40 (<del>$70</del>)</li><li><a href="https://howl.link/e64spmv177l3e?article_name=Gamespot&amp;article_url=https://www.gamespot.com/17322749518382?u1=subid_value" rel="nofollow ">God of War: Ragnarok (PS4)</a> -- $20 (<del>$60</del>)</li><li><a href="https://howl.link/e64spmv177l3e?article_name=Gamespot&amp;article_url=https://www.gamespot.com/17322749518382?u1=subid_value" rel="nofollow ">God of War: Ragnarok (PS5)</a> -- $30 (<del>$70</del>)</li><li><a href="https://howl.link/jv2xz17rgr5hu?article_name=Gamespot&amp;article_url=https://www.gamespot.com/17327242304167?u1=subid_value" rel="nofollow ">Gran Turismo 7 (PS4)</a> -- $20 (<del>$60</del>)</li><li><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fgoto.walmart.com%2Fc%2F1804712%2F565706%2F9383%3Fveh%3Daff%26sourceid%3Dimp_000011112222333344%26u%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FGran-Turismo-7-PlayStation-5%2F443954076%3FclassType%3DVARIANT%26athbdg%3DL1200%26from%3D%2Fsearch%26subId1%3Dsubid_value&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fratchet-clank-rift-apart-is-only-30-right-now-on-ps5-for-black-friday%2F1100-6528105%2F%3Fftag%3DCAD-01-10abi2f&amp;event_type=click" rel="nofollow ">Gran Turismo 7 (PS5)</a> -- $30 (<del>$70</del>)</li><li><a href="https://howl.link/nprb6mym35y40?article_name=Gamespot&amp;article_url=https://www.gamespot.com/17322751867394?u1=subid_value" rel="nofollow ">Helldivers 2</a> -- $30 (<del>$40</del>)</li><li><a href="https://howl.link/pdlz4ucl74s62?article_name=Gamespot&amp;article_url=https://www.gamespot.com/17322752225582?u1=subid_value" rel="nofollow ">Horizon Forbidden West Complete Edition</a> -- $40 (<del>$60</del>)</li><li><a href="https://howl.link/w6t5hkwsbavwe?article_name=Gamespot&amp;article_url=https://www.gamespot.com/17322752925656?u1=subid_value" rel="nofollow ">Marvel's Spider-Man: Miles Morales</a> -- $20 (<del>$50</del>)</li><li><a href="https://howl.link/zksce24mfl59s?article_name=Gamespot&amp;article_url=https://www.gamespot.com/1732275262119?u1=subid_value" rel="nofollow ">Marvel's Spider-Man: Miles Morales Ultimate Edition</a> -- $40 (<del>$70</del>)</li><li><a href="https://howl.link/s6gr50llrjvay?article_name=Gamespot&amp;article_url=https://www.gamespot.com/17322753314645?u1=subid_value" rel="nofollow ">Marvel's Spider-Man 2: Standard Edition</a> -- $40 (<del>$70</del>)</li><li><a href="https://howl.link/r3xz6uaq1c8qe?article_name=Gamespot&amp;article_url=https://www.gamespot.com/17322754355803?u1=subid_value" rel="nofollow ">Ratchet &amp; Clank: Rift Apart</a> -- $30 (<del>$70</del>)</li><li><a href="https://howl.link/dscmlnyxoc0cf?article_name=Gamespot&amp;article_url=https://www.gamespot.com/17322754571828?u1=subid_value" rel="nofollow ">Returnal</a> -- $30 (<del>$70</del>)</li><li><a href="https://howl.link/mfcexzughujpc?article_name=Gamespot&amp;article_url=https://www.gamespot.com/17322750143548?u1=subid_value" rel="nofollow ">Rise of the Ronin</a> -- $40 (<del>$70</del>)</li><li><a href="https://howl.link/9tcy8p26e98kp?article_name=Gamespot&amp;article_url=https://www.gamespot.com/17322749294671?u1=subid_value" rel="nofollow ">Stellar Blade</a> -- $50 (<del>$70</del>)</li><li><a href="https://howl.link/hjtgv10z93ke4?article_name=Gamespot&amp;article_url=https://www.gamespot.com/17322443950035?u1=subid_value" rel="nofollow ">The Last of Us Part 1</a> -- $30 (<del>$70</del>)</li><li><a href="https://howl.link/mph3vc1g3yucc?article_name=Gamespot&amp;article_url=https://www.gamespot.com/17322749899611?u1=subid_value" rel="nofollow ">The Last of Us Part 2 Remastered</a> -- $40 (<del>$50</del>)</li><li><a href="https://howl.link/odvrhrvlownkg?article_name=Gamespot&amp;article_url=https://www.gamespot.com/17322755198005?u1=subid_value" rel="nofollow ">Uncharted: Legacy of Thieves Collection</a> -- $20 (<del>$50</del>)</li></ul><p><strong>PS5 Console &amp; Accessory Deals </strong></p><ul><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CJSY6961?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20" rel="nofollow ">DualSense Controller</a> -- $55-$60 (<del>$75-$80</del>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0C1Q9X8VH?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20" rel="nofollow ">PSVR 2 Horizon Call of the Mountain Bundle</a> -- $349 (<del>$600</del>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/PULSE-Explore-Wireless-Earbuds-PlayStation-5/dp/B0CMDFSB89?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20" rel="nofollow ">Pulse Explore Wireless Earbuds</a> -- $170 (<del>$200</del>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/PlayStation-Pulse-Elite-Wireless-Headset-5/dp/B0CMDH9M5W?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20" rel="nofollow ">Pulse Elite Wireless Headset</a> -- $129 (<del>$150</del>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/PS5-Console-Fortnite-Cobalt-PlayStation-5/dp/B0DJHF6Q9Z?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20" rel="nofollow ">PS5 Slim Fortnite Cobalt Star Bundle</a> -- $425 (<del>$500</del>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/PlayStation%C2%AE5-console-slim-SPORTS-College-Football/dp/B0D9JLP9N8?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20" rel="nofollow ">PS5 Slim College Football 25 Bundle</a> -- $454</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Playstation-PS5-Console-Fortnite-Digital-5/dp/B0DJHG2VVS?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20" rel="nofollow ">PS5 Slim Digital Fortnite Cobalt Star Bundle</a> -- $375 (<del>$450</del>)</li><li><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fgoto.walmart.com%2Fc%2F1804712%2F565706%2F9383%3Fveh%3Daff%26sourceid%3Dimp_000011112222333344%26u%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FPlayStation-5-Digital-Slim-Console%2F9602603812%26subId1%3Dsubid_value&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fratchet-clank-rift-apart-is-only-30-right-now-on-ps5-for-black-friday%2F1100-6528105%2F%3Fftag%3DCAD-01-10abi2f&amp;event_type=click" rel="nofollow ">PS5 Slim Digital NBA 2K25 Bundle</a> -- $374 (<del>$500</del>)</li><li><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fgoto.walmart.com%2Fc%2F1804712%2F565706%2F9383%3Fveh%3Daff%26sourceid%3Dimp_000011112222333344%26u%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2F5350977288%26subId1%3Dsubid_value&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fratchet-clank-rift-apart-is-only-30-right-now-on-ps5-for-black-friday%2F1100-6528105%2F%3Fftag%3DCAD-01-10abi2f&amp;event_type=click" rel="nofollow ">PS5 Slim with Extra DualSense Controller</a> -- $475</li></ul>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article>

    
  

</div>
                      <meta itemprop="seamless-content-list-items" data-list-items="[{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6528097&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/gran-turismo-7-is-available-for-a-fantastic-price-right-now-during-black-friday\/1100-6528097\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6527965&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/ps5-exclusives-are-getting-big-black-friday-price-cuts\/1100-6527965\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6528106&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/get-the-ps5-game-returnal-for-a-great-price-right-now-for-black-friday\/1100-6528106\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6528100&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/horizon-forbidden-wests-complete-edition-is-on-sale-for-a-great-price-right-now\/1100-6528100\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6521900&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/the-best-batman-animated-series-is-only-30-on-blu-ray-in-amazons-black-friday-sale\/1100-6521900\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6527814&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/silent-hill-2-for-ps5-drops-to-30-in-walmarts-black-friday-sale\/1100-6527814\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6527896&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/pikmin-1-2-collection-for-nintendo-switch-is-only-30-at-amazon-for-black-friday\/1100-6527896\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6528062&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/get-yoshis-crafted-world-for-a-good-price-right-now-during-black-friday\/1100-6528062\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6527939&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/save-30-on-alan-wake-2-deluxe-edition-with-this-black-friday-discount\/1100-6527939\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6527963&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/astro-bot-gets-first-discount-for-black-friday\/1100-6527963\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6527988&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/official-ps5-console-covers-are-discounted-for-black-friday\/1100-6527988\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6527812&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/pick-up-the-last-of-us-saga-on-ps5-with-these-black-friday-deals\/1100-6527812\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6527850&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/nintendo-switch-pro-controller-is-only-50-for-black-friday-lowest-price-ever\/1100-6527850\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6528005&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/lego-mclaren-racing-2-pack-is-only-52-at-amazon-for-black-friday\/1100-6528005\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6527935&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/dualsense-ps5-controllers-get-first-major-discounts-of-2024-for-black-friday\/1100-6527935\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6528017&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/this-official-zelda-themed-wireless-controller-is-only-25-at-amazon-for-black-friday\/1100-6528017\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6527712&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/black-friday-ps5-deals-consoles-games-controllers\/1100-6527712\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526930&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/marvels-spider-man-2-for-ps5-gets-biggest-discount-ever-for-black-friday\/1100-6526930\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6528013&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/these-impressive-poke-ball-replicas-are-on-sale-for-black-friday\/1100-6528013\/&quot;}]">
            </div>
              
    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Leaked image suggests Valve's rumoured new Steam Controller taking design cues from Steam Deck]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/leaked-image-suggests-valves-rumoured-new-steam-controller-taking-design-cues-from-steam-deck</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/leaked-image-suggests-valves-rumoured-new-steam-controller-taking-design-cues-from-steam-deck.1046721/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/leaked-image-suggests-valves-rumoured-new-steam-controller-taking-design-cues-from-steam-deck<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>Two sticks! Twin track pads! More!</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/ss_c22b43258190b8e43a7ed776f830367f0fccacfa.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Valve</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
Following last week's report Valve is working on a new iteration of its brilliant (if divisive) Steam Controller, a fresh leak has offered what might well be a first look at its refreshed design - and it's probably not a complete surprise to see it taking plenty of cues from Steam Deck.
</p>
<p>
Valve's original Steam Controller was <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/steam-controller-revealed">initially unveiled in 2013</a>, accompanying chatter of third-party Steam machines. But while the latter initiative eventually floundered, the controller lived on, eventually releasing in November 2015. Sadly, it was <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/valve-calls-time-on-its-divisive-steam-controller">time to say farewell</a> just four years later, amid a patent infringement lawsuit relating to its paddle-like rear buttons.
</p>
<p>
Valve <a href="https://www.polygon.com/2021/2/3/22264213/valve-steam-controller-lawsuit-scuf-4-million">initially lost that case</a> and was ordered to pay $4m USD in damages, but it successfully appealed the verdict in August 2021, paving the way for a Steam Controller 2. All of which brings us to last week, when knowledgeable Valve source Brad Lynch claimed that not only was a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/valve-reportedly-reviving-its-divisive-steam-controller-trackpads-now-different-sizes-and-shapes">new Steam Controller in the works</a>, it was "being tooled for a mass production... right now".
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Hands on with the Steam controller" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/i-3Qwffu-NQ?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Hands on with the Steam controller</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/i-3Qwffu-NQ?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/i-3Qwffu-NQ?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>A Steam Controller hands-on from back in the day!<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=i-3Qwffu-NQ" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
Lynch also reported the new device's "biggest change will be the shape/size of the trackpads", with Valve edging toward a more traditional "gamepad-y form". And, again thanks to Lynch, we've now got a much better idea of what the new Steam Controller might look like, thanks to a <a href="https://x.com/SadlyItsBradley/status/1861543924470251771">low-quality image</a> squirrelled in Valve's SteamVR drivers.
</p><div>

<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>
And it seems Valve is taking many of its design cues from Steam Deck this time around - which seems entirely appropriate given how much the handheld PC owes to the original Steam Controller. Assuming the newly discovered render is accurate, Valve's second iteration could, like the Steam Deck, feature a more traditional twin analog stick set-up alongside twin track pads, all packed into what appears to be a much more ergonomic design.
</p>
<p>
The original Steam Controller's single analog stick set-up wasn't universally loved, but it's been a staple of my couch/PC set-up ever since launch thanks to those track pads. This newly uncovered design, then, is definitely encouraging, promising the best of both worlds.
</p>
<p>
Officially, of course, Valve's Steam Controller 2 remains nothing more than a rumour at present, but an exciting one nonetheless (although I'll readily admit I probably love the original controller more than most). And it's not the only new hardware rumoured to be in the works at Valve: the company is also said to be working on a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZOEgUmkhzOU">new standalone hybrid VR headset known as "Deckard"</a>, which'll apparently feature new wand-like controllers, codenamed Roy.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>