<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 13:54:14 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Respawn Cancels Another Unannounced Multiplayer FPS]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/respawn-cancels-another-unannounced-multiplayer-fps/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/respawn-cancels-another-unannounced-multiplayer-fps.1128000/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/respawn-cancels-another-unannounced-multiplayer-fps/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>It appears that Respawn Entertainment has quietly canceled another game project. The news was shared via LinkedIn by former Executive Assistant and Production Coordinator&nbsp;Emilee Evans, who wrote (as <a href="https://thegamepost.com/titanfall-developer-respawn-canceled-fps-game/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">spotted</a> by The Game Post):</p>
<p><em>The unannounced incubation project I was a part of for the past year was canceled this week, so I am joining the group of extremely talented and kind people in the games industry searching for a new role.</em></p>
<p>Evans did not specify what kind of project it was, but the studio had been <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/jobs/view/game-design-director-incubation-team-at-respawn-entertainment-3789765830/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">hiring</a> people with 'significant professional experience designing Multiplayer FPS experiences' for the Incubation Team, hinting that it would have been a multiplayer first-person shooter game. That's certainly not surprising, considering that the studio built its fortune on that kind of game with Titanfall and later Apex Legends.</p>
<p>We'll probably never know for sure if it was another attempt to make a new Titanfall, though Jeff Grubb <a href="https://wccftech.com/titanfall-game-reportedly-in-development-at-respawn-though-it-wont-be-a-sequel/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">said</a> last year that the studio was indeed developing another game in the franchise. This would be the second time (that we know of) a new franchise installment gets canceled, following the <a href="https://wccftech.com/titanfall-legends-single-player-gamer-canceled-ea/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">closure of the Titanfall Legends single player project</a> in early 2023.</p>
<p>About a year later, Respawn Entertainment's parent company, Electronic Arts, <a href="https://wccftech.com/ea-lays-off-5-of-its-employees-cancels-star-wars-respawn-fps-and-seeks-to-move-away-from-licensed-ips/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">canceled</a> another game in development at the studio, a multiplayer first-person shooter set in the world of Star Wars. Back then, EA CEO Andrew Wilson highlighted the need to move away from licensed IPs due to the licensing costs. That excuse is certainly not applicable to new Titanfall games, though.</p>
<p>Right now, the Los Angeles based studio is certainly <a href="https://wccftech.com/star-wars-jedi-series-to-get-final-chapter-of-the-trilogy/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">working</a> on the third and final entry in the Star Wars Jedi franchise. They should also still be publishing an upcoming XCOM-like Star Wars tactics strategy game with Bit Reactor. In June 2024, the developers <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/strategy/bitreactor-has-a-star-wars-tactical-strategy-game-in-the-works-15-xcom-veterans-on-its-team-and-an-ambitious-vision-for-the-future-of-the-genre/?utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=twitter.com&amp;utm_campaign=socialflow" target="_blank" rel="noopener">talked to PC Gamer</a> about the partnership:</p>
<p><em>Respawn really treats us like an internal team. They've been really good to us. They encourage collaboration and communication between teams. And so they've been just flat out the best experience I've ever had in publishing. They trust us to make the kind of game we know how to make.</em></p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch Online Gets Two More Game Boy Classics]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/nintendo-switch-online-picross-donkey-kong</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-switch-online-gets-two-more-game-boy-classics.1127997/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/nintendo-switch-online-picross-donkey-kong<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Nintendo has added two more Game Boy classics to the Nintendo Switch Online library, and if you're a fan of classic puzzlers or old-school retro delights, then these games are very much for you.</p>

<p>As with all of the <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/nintendo-switch-online-donkey-kong-land" rel="nofollow">other</a> Game Boy <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/nintendo-switch-online-game-boy-launch" rel="nofollow">games</a> available on the Switch Online <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/nintendo-switch-online-zelda-july" rel="nofollow">service</a> (although not Game Boy Advance games, importantly), these two new games can be enjoyed if you've got a basic Switch Online membership. You won't need the Expansion Pack addon to play them.</p>

<p>First to be added today is&nbsp;<em>Donkey Kong</em>, also known as&nbsp;<em>Donkey Kong '94&nbsp;</em>after the year in which it was released. It's essentially an adaptation of the original&nbsp;<em>Donkey Kong</em>, albeit with many, many more levels and some additional gameplay quirks to contend with.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/nintendo-switch-online-game-boy-march-2025-donkey-kong.jpg?itok=z4_NZHzQ 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/nintendo-switch-online-game-boy-march-2025-donkey-kong.jpg?itok=vwgm3CTD 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Donkey Kong '94&nbsp;</em>is one of two games being added to Nintendo Switch Online today.</figcaption></figure><p>The game blends gameplay elements from several different Nintendo titles; it's got the item pickup mechanic from&nbsp;<em>Super Mario Bros. 2&nbsp;</em>(that's the weird one, not&nbsp;<em>Lost Levels</em>), as well as the rope-climbing from&nbsp;<em>Donkey Kong Jr.&nbsp;</em>and, of course, the basic structure of the original&nbsp;<em>Donkey Kong</em>.</p>

<p>Your second Game Boy offering in today's haul is&nbsp;<em>Mario's Picross</em>. If you're familiar with nonogram-style puzzles, then this one probably doesn't need much introduction.</p>

<p>If you're not, though, nonograms are essentially puzzles where you must systematically eliminate squares on a grid in order to uncover a picture. You'll need to observe the numbers along the sides of the grid carefully to determine which squares need to be filled in and which should be left alone.</p>

<p>As you might expect,&nbsp;<em>Mario's Picross&nbsp;</em>has plenty of&nbsp;<em>Mario</em>-themed images for you to uncover, so if you're looking for a fun way to while away an hour or two, you could do a lot worse.</p>




<p>Both&nbsp;<em>Donkey Kong '94&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>Mario's Picross&nbsp;</em>are available to play right now on Nintendo Switch Online. You can sign up for a membership via your Switch console's eShop if you're not already subscribed.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Who is Danny Dyer and Why is Rockstar Posting About His Latest Movie?]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/who-is-danny-dyer-and-why-is-rockstar-posting-about-his-latest-movie</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/who-is-danny-dyer-and-why-is-rockstar-posting-about-his-latest-movie.1127994/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/who-is-danny-dyer-and-why-is-rockstar-posting-about-his-latest-movie<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">GTA: Vice City’s Kent Paul is back… well, the actor behind him. </h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">If you follow Rockstar Games on X (the Everything App formerly known as Twitter), then you may have been surprised, confused, or a combination of the two when you saw the GTA studio posting about the film Marching Powder and its star, Danny Dyer. </p><blockquote data-theme="light">— Rockstar Games (@RockstarGames) <a href="https://twitter.com/RockstarGames/status/1897764284651762165?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">March 6, 2025</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">Why on earth would Rockstar be posting about a small British film to its audience of 21 million followers? And who is this Danny Dyer guy? Don’t worry, we’re here to explain. </p><h2 data-cy="title2">Who is Danny Dyer?</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Danial John Dyer, better known as Danny Dyer, is an actor from East London. And if you live in the UK, he needs no introduction. As Rockstar’s post states, he’s an “absolute legend”. If you don’t speak British slang, then please refer to the <a href="https://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=legend" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Urban Dictionary’s definition of the term</a> to better understand Dyer’s reputation:</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>“A person who embodies the pinnacle of all the important social aspects. Any person who is funny, reckless, original and sensitive in the right measures is likely to be nominated a legend by his associates. A person to whose persona you aspire.”</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph">Dyer has been acting since 1993 and has built up a reputation for playing rough-and-ready working class characters. That’s in part due to his public persona; he’s considered somewhat outspoken on societal and government issues, and is known for his “tough uncle” approach to life. For example, in 2010 when offering advice to readers of Zoo magazine, Dyer told a man attempting to recover from a recent break-up that he should go “on a rampage [drinking session] with the boys."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Dyer is also beloved for his many wild social media posts, such as this gem: </p><blockquote data-media-max-width="560" data-theme="light"><p data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr">Roll on bonfire night..........it's gonna get strapped to a great big massive fuck off Rocket so it can join the other Furbys in the sky...</p>— Danny Dyer (@MrDDyer) <a href="https://twitter.com/MrDDyer/status/378183407521759232?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">September 12, 2013</a></blockquote> <h2 data-cy="title2">How is Danny Dyer Connected to Rockstar?</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">If you’ve no idea who Danny Dyer is, but are a big fan of the Grand Theft Auto games, then you’ve almost certainly heard his voice. Dyer plays Kent Paul in GTA: Vice City, the manager of Scottish rock band, Love Fist. He reprised the role for GTA: San Andreas, in which Kent represented a new band, the Gurning Chimps, and later produced for rapper Madd Dogg. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Dyer has a more important connection to Rockstar, though, and it comes from an unusual place. In 2004, Dyer starred in The Football Factory, a British film directed by Nick Love and produced by… Rockstar Games. Yes, once upon a time Rockstar helped create a feature film. </p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/03/07/the-football-factory-1741347914065.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Danny Dyer (right, wearing the tan jacket) starred in The Football Factory, which was produced by Rockstar Games. | Image credit: Vertigo Films</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Marching Powder, a new film releasing in the UK and Ireland this week, reunites Danny Dyer with Nick Love. The project, while not a sequel to The Football Factory, pulls on many of the same ideas, including football hooliganism (see: violence among fans), heavy drinking and drug use, and a uniquely British gritty sense of humour. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Despite the post on X, Rockstar has nothing to do with Marching Powder. It seems the studio is simply championing the film because of its prior connection to Dyer and Love and their work on The Football Factory. </p><h2 data-cy="title2">Is Vice City's Kent Paul Returning for GTA 6?</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Short answer: we’ve no idea. And this social media post certainly has nothing to do with GTA 6. But hey, we might as well theorise anyway. Could Kent Paul show up in Grand Theft Auto 6?</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s important to remember that GTA is split up into two very different eras: the 3D era (games released on the PS2 and PSP) and the HD era (GTA 4 onwards). Both are considered their own universes – storylines from one do not continue into the other. That’s why GTA 5’s Los Santos looks entirely different to San Andreas’ equivalent city, and why there’s no direct mention of characters from the PS2-era games in GTA 4 and 5.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/03/07/kent-paul-gta-vc-1741348272844.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Tommy Vercetti tackles Kent Paul in Grand Theft Auto: Vice City | Image credit: Rockstar Games</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">That’s not to say there’s no overlap, though. CJ’s home cul-de-sac, Grove Street, appears in GTA 5, and many of the gangs that first featured in the 3D universe are present in the HD universe, including the Ballas. Lazlo, the infamous ponytailed scumbag, has also been in a number of GTA games spanning the two eras. And here’s the kicker: Kent Paul has his name on the Vinewood Walk of Fame.  </p><p data-cy="paragraph">So is there a chance that Kent Paul could return for GTA 6? It’s certainly possible. But a post on X about Marching Powder certainly doesn’t bring us any closer to confirmation. </p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Matt Purslow is IGN's Senior Features Editor. </em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Destiny 2 Guardian Games 2025 Adds New Boss Rush Mode, Rushdown]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/destiny-2-guardian-games-2025-adds-new-boss-rush-mode-rushdown/1100-6529969/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/destiny-2-guardian-games-2025-adds-new-boss-rush-mode-rushdown.1127991/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/destiny-2-guardian-games-2025-adds-new-boss-rush-mode-rushdown/1100-6529969/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529969">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Since 2020, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/destiny-2-review/1900-6416758/" data-ref-id="1900-6416758">Destiny 2</a> has pit the three Guardian classes against each other in the Guardian Games to determine whether the Titans, the Warlocks, or the Hunters will reign supreme for a year. On March 11, the 2025 Guardian Games will begin with a few changes. Guardian Games Nightfalls and Focused Activities have been dropped from this year's event. In their place is a new boss rush mode called Rushdown, which looks like it will test even the most seasoned Destiny 2 players.</p><p>Bungie has shared <a href="https://www.bungie.net/7/en/News/Article/twid_03_06_2025" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the details for this year's Guardian Games</a>, including the way that Rushdown will work. Rushdown will assemble bosses from the campaigns, the seasonal story missions, and the exotic missions in battles that will get exponentially more difficult for players. Each run through Rushdown will feature five boss encounters, all of which must be completed before time expires. Time gets added to the clock with each boss that goes down, and teams that finish more quickly have a better chance of earning higher quality rewards.</p><p>Rushdown includes warm-up, standard, and expert modes, but only the last two will include combatants with modifiers while also letting players receive revive tokens. However, players will get a higher score if they use fewer revive tokens. All three modes will be open for standard matchmaking, class-based matchmaking, and private fireteam matches. Players will be judged by how many bosses they defeated and by their overall score.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1837/18375603/4455148-destiny2guardiangamestraceriffle.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4455148" data-ratio="0.56230769230769" data-width="1300" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1837/18375603/4455148-destiny2guardiangamestraceriffle.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4455148"></a><figcaption>The new Arc Trace riffle from this year's Guardian Games.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1837/18375603/4455148-destiny2guardiangamestraceriffle.jpg"></figure><p>It just wouldn't be a Guardian Games without a new weapon. This year's addition to the armory is called Keraunios. It's a powerful new Arc Trace rifle that features jolting impact, recycled energy, and rolling storm. Last year's addition, the Allstar Vector Skimmer, will be available again during this year's Guardian Games. Players will receive a temporary version of the weapon for the duration of the event. But if players want to permanently add it to their collection, they will need to complete a drop-in quest. </p><p>Players who finish three encounters in any of the Rushdown modes will be guaranteed to receive a Guardians Games weapon during that run. The five scoring thresholds are bronze, silver, gold, platinum, and diamond. Naturally, players who reach the higher tiers in standard or expert will get better rewards. And players who achieve high scores in expert mode will also get the chance to pick up fully Masterworked Guardian Games weapons.</p><p>In order for players to help their preferred faction to win the overall Guardian Games, they have to team up with members of the same class and fight in PvP and other activities to earn medallions. Once the medallions are in hand, players need to bring them to the podium to count them among the total points for their class. There will be winning classes on every day of the event, but only one faction will be named the victor when the Guardian Games close after three weeks of competition. </p><p>Outside of this event, Bungie recently announced <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/new-destiny-2-pvp-mode-heavy-metal-lets-you-finally-pilot-a-brig/1100-6529865/" data-ref-id="1100-6529865">a brand-new, limited-time PvP mode</a> called Heavy Metal that will arrive during Heresy Act 3. This will finally give players their chance to pilot a Brig. There's also <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/destiny-2s-new-rite-of-the-nine-event-is-for-dungeon-newcomers-and-veterans-alike/1100-6529863/" data-ref-id="1100-6529863">a Rite of the Nine event</a> that's geared for both Destiny 2 veterans and newcomers.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GTA 6 developer Rockstar shares new trailer… for Danny Dyer-fronted film]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/gta-6-developer-rockstar-shares-new-trailer-for-danny-dyer-fronted-film</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gta-6-developer-rockstar-shares-new-trailer%E2%80%A6-for-danny-dyer-fronted-film.1127988/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/gta-6-developer-rockstar-shares-new-trailer-for-danny-dyer-fronted-film<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Screenshot-from-Marching-Powder-showing-actor-Danny-Dyer-with-no-shirt-on-against-a-backdrop-covered-in-hearts.-An-image-of-GTA6-leads-Jason-and-Lucia-is-overlayed-on-top.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Rockstar/True Brit Entertainment/Eurogamer</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>While we are all here frothing at the mouth in anticipation for more Grand Theft Auto 6 news, developer Rockstar is casually sharing a trailer for a Danny Dyer-fronted film instead.</p>
<p>The film in question is Marching Powder, which has been <a href="https://uk.movies.yahoo.com/movies/danny-dyer-marching-powder-film-interview-stephanie-leonidas-162145794.html">described as a "Bridget Jones with the C-word"</a>. In Marching Powder, Dyer stars as Jack, an ageing, drug-taking football hooligan.</p>
<p>"From our friends Nick Love and Danny Dyer, the absolute legends behind The Football Factory..." Rockstar wrote on social media, with an accompanying trailer. "[Marching Powder] - a proper naughty comedy out tomorrow in the UK and Ireland." The studio then shared a link for tickets.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="9 Exciting 2025 Open-World Games We Can't Wait to Play" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/UtaSpf-70nc?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>9 Exciting 2025 Open-World Games We Can't Wait to Play</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/UtaSpf-70nc?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/UtaSpf-70nc?autoplay=1" title="9 Exciting 2025 Open-World Games We Can't Wait to Play">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>9 Exciting 2025 Open-World Games We Can't Wait to Play. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UtaSpf-70nc" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>Now, in fairness to Rockstar, this isn't a totally random trailer for the company to share.  <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/companies/rockstar-games">Rockstar Games</a> actually produced sports drama film The Football Factory, which was released in 2004, so the team does have a connection to Nick Love and Danny Dyer's films.</p>
<p>But, even so, this post has caught the attention of Rockstar's gaming community, who are crying out for another GTA 6 trailer, not a footy film trailer.</p>
<p>"Okay. Y'all are definitely trolling now," reads one reply. "Doing anything except giving us content for the biggest game of all time," another adds. One social media user quipped that Rockstar had "dropped the wrong trailer" with its latest post.</p>
<p>GTA 6 is set to release this autumn - a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/gta-6-still-coming-this-autumn-confirms-take-two-despite-ongoing-delay-rumours">window publisher Take-Two Interactive remains confident of</a>. </p>
<p>
But, even though in the grand scheme of things we should be getting our hands on the next Grand Theft Auto game relatively soon, we still haven't actually seen or heard that much about it. In fact, we've only had one trailer, which was released over a year ago. Surely the developer is going to tell us something more soon... right?</p> <div>

<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>Well while we wait to find out, here's <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/gta-6-everything-we-know-so-far-9357">everything we know about GTA 6 so far</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Balatro developer stopped playing other roguelikes to try and "reinvent the wheel" with hit poker game]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/balatro-developer-stopped-playing-other-roguelikes-to-try-and-reinvent-the-wheel-with-hit-poker-game</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/balatro-developer-stopped-playing-other-roguelikes-to-try-and-reinvent-the-wheel-with-hit-poker-game.1127985/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/balatro-developer-stopped-playing-other-roguelikes-to-try-and-reinvent-the-wheel-with-hit-poker-game<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>"I didn't want to borrow tried-and-true designs."</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Untitled-1_hq5o1ws.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>LocalThunk</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
The creator of Balatro has revealed fresh details on the hit indie card game's development, including the fact he gave up playing other roguelikes for more than two years to avoid subconsciously borrowing ideas.
</p>
<p>
LocalThunk, the Canadian IT-worker-turned-indie-game-maestro, published a <a href="https://localthunk.com/blog/balatro-timeline-3aarh">lengthy timeline of Balatro's development</a> today on his blog. It features insights into his design decisions while working on the project, and notes about his own personal life and health over the course of the last three years.
</p>
<p>
In December 2021, after beginning work on a Balatro prototype, LocalThunk said he made "a very conscious effort not to play any more roguelike games starting now". 
</p>
<figure>
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<figcaption>Does anyone really want long games anymore?<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=D9-4YFvps5k" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>
"I want to be crystal clear here and say that this was not because I thought it would result in [Balatro being] a better game, this was because making games is my hobby, releasing them and making money from them is not, so naively exploring roguelike design (and especially deckbuilder design, since I had never played one before) was part of the fun for me," LocalThunk continued. 
</p>
<p>
"I wanted to make mistakes, I wanted to reinvent the wheel, I didn't want to borrow tried-and-true designs from existing games. That likely would have resulted in a more tight game but it would have defeated the purpose of what I love about making games."
</p>
<p>
It was a pledge he seemingly kept until May 2023, when LocalThunk writes:
</p>
<p>
"I downloaded <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/slay-the-spire">Slay the Spire</a> and played it for the first time. Holy shit. Now that is a game.
</p>
<p>
"I did this because I was having some troubles in my controller implementation and I wanted to see how they handled controller inputs for a card game but I ended up getting sucked in. Thank goodness I avoided playing it until now because I surely would have just copied their incredible design (intentionally or subconsciously)."
</p>
<p>
The full development timeline is lengthy but well worth a read for anyone who's played Balatro and is interested at what point various features made it into the game (which for a long time was alternatively named Joker Poker).
</p>
<p>
Balatro's fundamental Chip X Mult scoring system was part of the game since its earliest days - back when it was called Big Cheat - in 2021. However, it wasn't until late 2023 that the decision to include as many as 150 Jokers in the game was finalised. 
</p>
<p>
It was also during late 2023 that LocalThunk reports on difficulties with his health, due to the increasing attention that Balatro was getting and the long hours spent working on its development. 
</p>
<p>
Balatro began life as a game project LocalThunk hoped to share with friends, or potentially launch on Steam just to have something he could show to a future employer. As of January 2025, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/balatro-passes-5m-copies-sold-as-developer-implores-fans-to-play-more-indie-games">the game has now sold 5m copies</a>.
</p>
<p>
"It's the game that's been on everyone's lips (and brain, and console, and phone and practically every device going) since it took the world by storm back in February," our Katharine wrote, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-50-best-games-of-2024-ranked">praising Balatro as one of Eurogamer's best games of 2024</a>. "Balatro has been a force of nature this year."

</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Left 4 Dead 2 RTX Remix Mod Obliterates Performance On an RTX 5080 at 4K Resolution, Proving Hardware Is Not Yet Ready For Path Tracing]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/left-4-dead-2-path-tracing-rtx-5080-obliterates-performance/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/left-4-dead-2-rtx-remix-mod-obliterates-performance-on-an-rtx-5080-at-4k-resolution-proving-hardware-is-not-yet-ready-for-path-tracing.1127970/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/left-4-dead-2-path-tracing-rtx-5080-obliterates-performance/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Path tracing looks stunning in video games, both old and new, but the hardware definitely still isn't quite there yet to offer decent performance on anything that isn't top-end, as highlighted in a new showcase of a recently released Left 4 Dead 2 RTX Remix mod.</p>
<p>The mod, which can be downloaded&nbsp;<a href="https://github.com/xoxor4d/l4d2-rtx" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here</a>, is a compatibility mod that makes the classic game by Valve compatible with RTX Remix and, as such, lacks some advanced features. Even with some issues, however, path tracing undoubtedly breathes new life into the game's visuals in some scenarios but does so at a very heavy cost, as highlighted in the new showcase shared on YouTube by <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@MxBenchmarkPC" target="_blank" rel="noopener">MxBenchmarkPC</a>. At 4K resolution, very high settings, the game goes from running at around 500 FPS to running at unsteady 60 FPS with the RTX Remix mod and NVIDIA DLSS 4 at the Performance preset, a huge hit in performance that highlights how even one of the most powerful GPUs on the market isn't ready to handle path tracing at 4K resolution. Even at 1440p resolution, the RTX 5080 doesn't run the game as well as one might expect with the path tracing mod, requiring Frame Generation to hit an average of 90 FPS with NVIDIA DLSS Quality.</p>
<p><iframe title="Left 4 Dead 2 Path Tracing with RTX Remix On vs Off - Graphics/Performance Comparison | RTX 5080" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/DHKBqCJW9Jk?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Looking at how the Left 4 Dead 2 RTX Remix path tracing mod challenges even an RTX 5080 GPU, it looks like Frame Generation will continue to be a necessity to reach acceptable levels of performance in games that support the technology. Multi Frame Generation, which is currently available on RTX 5000 series cards only, makes it possible to enjoy games with path tracing at high resolution and framerates, as seen in <a href="https://wccftech.com/cyberpunk-2077-rtx-5080-path-tracing-120-fps/">Cyberpunk 2077</a>.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[RoboCop: Rogue City - Unfinished Business Announced for Summer]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/robocop-rogue-city-unfinished-business-announced</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/robocop-rogue-city-unfinished-business-announced-for-summer.1127967/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/robocop-rogue-city-unfinished-business-announced<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Nacon has announced&nbsp;<em>RoboCop: Rogue City - Unfinished Business</em>, a "standalone adventure" intended to serve as a followup (but not necessarily a full-blown sequel) to 2023's&nbsp;<em>RoboCop: Rogue City</em>.</p>

<p>Announced during yesterday's Nacon Connect showcase, <i>Unfinished Business&nbsp;</i>will once again put you in the (presumably extremely heavy) shoes of RoboCop as he prepares to take down a "group of highly trained mercenaries" in the massive housing complex known as OmniTower.</p>

<p>Essentially,&nbsp;<em>Unfinished Business&nbsp;</em>sounds rather like&nbsp;<em>RoboCop: Rogue City&nbsp;</em>meets&nbsp;<em>The Raid&nbsp;</em>or&nbsp;<em>Die Hard</em>&nbsp;(or, indeed, 2012's&nbsp;<em>Dredd</em>). Nacon is promising new enemy types, deadly traps, and elite troops to take down.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/robocop-rogue-city-unfinished-business-summer-electrocution.jpg?itok=AbXZdMtw 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/robocop-rogue-city-unfinished-business-summer-electrocution.jpg?itok=RKcev0ri 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>RoboCop: Rogue City - Unfinished Business&nbsp;</em>is a "standalone adventure" coming this summer.</figcaption></figure><p>As before, you'll have access to RoboCop's full arsenal, including the brand new Cryo Cannon, which sounds like a pretty good way to make a persuasive argument for criminals to comply.</p>

<p>What's more, you'll also get the chance to play as Alex Murphy, RoboCop's pre-transformation alter ego, and "discover a different side" of the iconic hero.</p>

<p><em>RoboCop: Rogue City - Unfinished Business&nbsp;</em>launches on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3527760/RoboCop_Rogue_City__Unfinished_Business/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC</a>, <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/concept/10014077" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PlayStation 5</a>, and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/robocop-rogue-city-unfinished-business/9NNNFB5F54C9" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Xbox Series X|S</a> in summer.&nbsp;You can check out the announcement trailer for the game<em>&nbsp;</em>right here.</p>




<h2>What else was revealed during Nacon Connect 2025?</h2>

<p>Plenty of other Nacon games were revealed during the publisher's Connect showcase yesterday.</p>

<p>As well as <i>Unfinished Business</i>, Nacon also revealed a new game in the stealthy&nbsp;<em>Styx&nbsp;</em>series.&nbsp;<em>Styx: Blades of&nbsp;</em><em>Greed&nbsp;</em>is described as a "blend of stealth, action, and strategy", and it's coming to PC and current-gen machines in fall.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/styx-blades-of-greed-nacon-connect-2025.jpg?itok=eEvtb0ue 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/styx-blades-of-greed-nacon-connect-2025.jpg?itok=LBe1IBCP 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Styx: Blades of Greed&nbsp;</em>is a new stealth game in the&nbsp;<em>Styx&nbsp;</em>series, and it's coming in fall.</figcaption></figure><p><em>The Council&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em><a href="https://techraptor.net/games/vampire-the-masquerade-swansong" rel="nofollow">Vampire: The Masquerade - Swansong</a>&nbsp;</em>developer Big Bad Wolf also revealed&nbsp;<em>Cthulhu: The Cosmic Abyss</em>, an investigative horror game along the lines of its previous work. That's set for next year on PC and current-gen consoles.</p>

<p>That's not the only eldritch horror game revealed during the show, either.&nbsp;<em>Zeno Clash&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>Clash: Artifacts of Chaos&nbsp;</em>developer ACE Team revealed&nbsp;<em>The Mound: Omen of Cthulhu</em>, a first-person co-op horror game loosely based on Lovecraft's novel of the same name. That one's coming next year.</p>

<p>If you'd like to catch up with the full Nacon Connect 2025 showcase, then you can do so below.</p>



</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Complete WWE 2K25 Trophy List—All Achievements And Trophies]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/complete-wwe-2k25-trophy-list-all-achievements-and-trophies/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/complete-wwe-2k25-trophy-list%E2%80%94all-achievements-and-trophies.1127961/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/complete-wwe-2k25-trophy-list-all-achievements-and-trophies/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>WWE 2K25 is loading up its hands to deliver its most devastating blow yet. 2K’s wrestling franchise mirrors the real-life WWE and continues to go from strength to strength. If you’re entering the ring this year, you should peek at the WWE 2K25 Trophy List.</p>



<p>Hard-hitting heavyweights, Wonder Woman-like female wrestlers, and godlike veterans make up the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/all-wwe-2k25-ratings-roster-confirmed-so-far-every-superstar-legend-dlc-characters/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">WWE 2K25 roster</a>. It’s more stacked than a Wrestlemania card, and has a ton of <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/complete-wwe-2k25-dlc-roadmap-season-pass/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">post-launch DLC</a> on the way. This year’s WWE game features intergender matches, women bleeding, glass, and more.</p>



<p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/wwe-2k25-release-date-platforms-editions-and-price/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">WWE 2K25</a> has attitude, and a banging Trophy and Achievement list.</p>



<h2 id="h-how-to-get-every-wwe-2k25-achievement-amp-trophy">How to Get Every WWE 2K25 Achievement &amp; Trophy</h2>



<figure><figcaption>The Hall of Famer looks as great as ever. Credit to 2K</figcaption></figure>



<p>There are a lot of Trophies in Achievements in the <a href="https://wwe.2k.com/2k25/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">WWE 2K25</a> list. Its names are terrific and you can tell a lot of thought went into them. You’ll have to cover every square-inch of WWE 2K25 if you hope to complete the collection. WWE 2K25 is a tough cookie, but nothing we can’t devour.</p>



<p>Here’s the complete list of trophy names and how to unlock each one.</p>



<div>
<div>
<figure><table><thead><tr><th data-align="center">Trophy &amp; Achievement Name</th><th data-align="center">Description</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td data-align="center">All Trophies Earned</td><td data-align="center">Earn all trophies.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Day 1 Ish</td><td data-align="center">Complete One Objective in Showcase.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Mic’ Up</td><td data-align="center">Complete a Self-Promo rivalry action (Universe Classic or Superstar Mode).</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Enough Talk</td><td data-align="center">Start an immediate match or a brawl from a Call-Out or Prom-Interrupt rivalry action (Universe Classic or Superstar Mode).</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Open Season</td><td data-align="center">Complete an Issue Open Challenge or Accept Open Challenge rivalry action promo (Universe Classic or Superstar Mode).</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Wrestling Royalty</td><td data-align="center">Crown a new King and Queen of the Ring (Universe Classic or Superstar Mode).</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Biggest Nights of the Year</td><td data-align="center">Complete both nights of WrestleMania (Universe Classic or Superstar Mode).</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Going Solo</td><td data-align="center">Defeat Roman Reigns in a Bloodline Rules match without summoning any allies on Legend difficulty (Play Mode vs AI)</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Underground Reign</td><td data-align="center">Rack up 25 consecutive wins via KO or submission in an Underground match on Legend difficulty (Play Mode vs AI)</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Back By Popular Demand</td><td data-align="center">Complete a chain wrestling sequence, win or lose, on any difficulty (Play Mode vs AI)</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<figure><table><tbody><tr><td data-align="center">This Is New</td><td data-align="center">Perform a successful dive attack off the barricade (any difficulty) (Play Mode vs AI)</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Miraculous Comeback</td><td data-align="center">Win a match via KO after mounting a comeback from a Critical KO situation on Legend difficulty (Play Mode vs AI)</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Impeccable Ring Awareness</td><td data-align="center">Win via pin or submission without having any rope breaks called against you on Legend difficulty (Play Mode vs AI).</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Recovery Deferred</td><td data-align="center">Win 25 matches on Legend difficulty without using Instant Recovery (Play Mode vs AI).</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Size Matters</td><td data-align="center">Using any Giant, win a 5-Entrant Turmoil Gauntlet on Legend difficulty without losing all Armor.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Mami’s Revenge</td><td data-align="center">As Rhea Ripley, defeat all Judgment Day Members via Pin or Submission on Legend (Play Mode vs AI).</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Let’s Run It Back</td><td data-align="center">Successfully run through a 20-Entrant Turmoil Gauntlet match on Legend difficulty (Play Mode vs AI).</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Faction Wars Champion</td><td data-align="center">Defeat 30 Faction Wars Bosses in MyFACTION.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Rise Through the Ranks</td><td data-align="center">Earn a Leaderboard Reward from a Ranked Play Season.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Loyalty Confirmed</td><td data-align="center">Earn a Loyalty Reward in MyFACTION.</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>
</div>



<figure><table><tbody><tr><td data-align="center">Taste of Victory</td><td data-align="center">Win a match in MyFACTION.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">A Promising Start</td><td data-align="center">Complete a Lifetime Challenge in MyFACTION.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Journey of a Lifetime</td><td data-align="center">Complete 15 Lifetime Challenges in MyFACTION.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Weekly Winner</td><td data-align="center">Complete a Weekly Tower in MyFACTION.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Daily Progress</td><td data-align="center">Complete a Daily Challenge in MyFACTION.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Start of the Journey</td><td data-align="center">Complete a Location World Tour in MyFACTION.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">United States Champion</td><td data-align="center">Complete all of the USA matches in World Tour in MyFACTION</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Champion For A Day</td><td data-align="center">Complete all 3 of a day’s Daily Challenges in MyFACTION.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Never Felt More A-LIVE</td><td data-align="center">Complete 10 LIVE Events in MyFACTION.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Beginner’s Luck</td><td data-align="center">Complete ALL Intro Challenges in MyFACTION.</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<figure><table><tbody><tr><td data-align="center">Host With The Most</td><td data-align="center">MyGM: Host and Complete a MyGM Online Wrestlemania show with 3 other human controlled brands.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Just a Scratch</td><td data-align="center">MyGM: Have 5 or more superstars get injured on your brand during a go home show.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Medical Bill</td><td data-align="center">MyGM: Collect $150k or more by releasing an injured Cash Suplex from your roster.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Use It Or Lose It</td><td data-align="center">MyGM: Have a balance of exactly $0 after booking your show.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Inevitable</td><td data-align="center">MyGM: Have an Immortal Kyle Slickman win a WrestleMania Main Event while on your roster.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Rando Rising</td><td data-align="center">Win A Match with a Randomized Custom Superstar.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">BANZAI!</td><td data-align="center">Crush Hulkamania at the 1993 King of the Ring with Yokozuna.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">I Did It For the People</td><td data-align="center">Stun “Stone Cold” at No Mercy 2000 with Rikishi.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">The N.T.C.</td><td data-align="center">Win The Bloodline WARGAMES with Team Solo Sikoa.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">The O.T.C.</td><td data-align="center">Win The Bloodline WARGAMES with Team Roman Reigns.</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<figure><table><tbody><tr><td data-align="center">Head of the Table</td><td data-align="center">Crowned Your Tribal Chief.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">The Draft and the Furious</td><td data-align="center">Drafted #1</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Then There Were Two</td><td data-align="center">Created a 2nd Character</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">United We Stand</td><td data-align="center">Win Unity Titles for the first time.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Bold Moves</td><td data-align="center">Played a Bold and Brash Personality Story</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Laughing Last</td><td data-align="center">Played a Comedic Personality Story</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">The Strategist</td><td data-align="center">Played a Scheming Personality Story</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Survivor Squad</td><td data-align="center">Recruited Two Allies</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Legends Assemble</td><td data-align="center">Chose “Legendary Help” branch in Reclaim ending</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Indie Infiltration</td><td data-align="center">Chose “Indie Assistance” branch in Reclaim ending</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<figure><table><tbody><tr><td data-align="center">Multiverse of MyPlayers</td><td data-align="center">Chose “Blasts from the Past” in Reclaim ending.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Forged in Battle</td><td data-align="center">Won NXT Championship – fought Trick Williams or IYO SKY</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Victory By Design</td><td data-align="center">Won NXT Championship – fought Ashante Adonis or Wendy Choo</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Righteous Victory</td><td data-align="center">Completed Story – Reclaim ending</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Mutiny Mastermind</td><td data-align="center">Mutiny Mastermind</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Encore Performance</td><td data-align="center">Completed the Story Again</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">We’ll Do It Live</td><td data-align="center">Played a Live Event Match in MyRise</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Live Event MVP</td><td data-align="center">Earned 50 Stars in Live Event Matches</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Live Event Legend</td><td data-align="center">Earned 100 Stars in Live Event Matches</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">GM Punk</td><td data-align="center">MyGM: Enter the Hall Of Fame in first place with CM Punk as your GM and Mutiny as your brand.</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<figure><table><tbody><tr><td data-align="center">The 1%</td><td data-align="center">MyGM: Win the main event of every PLE while playing as the Mutiny Brand.</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>
</div>



<h2 id="h-all-wwe-2k25-dlc-trophies-and-achievements">All WWE 2K25 DLC Trophies and Achievements</h2>



<p>The Island gives WWE 2K25 even more Trophies and Achievements to go for. You can check out the extras right here.</p>



<figure><table><thead><tr><th data-align="center">Trophy &amp; Achievement Name</th><th data-align="center">Description</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td data-align="center">In Your Image</td><td data-align="center">Complete the MySuperstar Builder (First Time)</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Let’s Go!</td><td data-align="center">Complete the Quest “Welcome to My Island”</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">The Road to Glory</td><td data-align="center">Complete A Hall of Fame Challenge</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Badges? We Need These Stinkin’ Badges!</td><td data-align="center">Unlock A Badge</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Terminally Online</td><td data-align="center">Complete A PvP Match</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<h2 id="h-how-many-trophies-amp-achievements-in-wwe-2k25">How Many Trophies &amp; Achievements in WWE 2K25?</h2>



<p><strong>WWE 2K25 has a Chris Jericho-sized list of 66 PlayStation 5 Trophies and 61 Xbox Achievements. But if you’re on PlayStation 4 and Xbox One, you only get 61 and 56 extra accomplishments respectively.</strong></p>



<p>This is because of The Island. A new game mode introduced in WWE 2K25—but it’s exclusive to PS5 and Xbox Series X. Meaning, if you’re on last-gen, not only do you miss out on The Island, you can’t get the five DLC trophies or achievements either.</p>



<hr>



<p>What do you think of the WWE 2K25 DLC list? Are you also impressed with the level of creativity on display? Is there a fun objective the developer has overlooked? Drop a comment and share your ideas.</p>



<p>If you’re keen to pick up WWE 2K25, or you’re contemplating it, you might wanna browse its <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/does-wwe-2k25-have-early-access/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Early Access</a> and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/is-wwe-2k25-coming-to-xbox-game-pass/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Xbox Game Pass</a> details.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The sequel to Robocop: Rogue City sounds more like Dredd]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-sequel-to-robocop-rogue-city-sounds-more-like-dredd</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-sequel-to-robocop-rogue-city-sounds-more-like-dredd.1127946/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-sequel-to-robocop-rogue-city-sounds-more-like-dredd<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article">
        <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/robocop-rogue-city-unfinished-business-1.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Nacon</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>RoboCop will be climbing an apartment tower full of slimebags in a standalone follow-up to his trudging but faithful 2023 shooter. <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/robocop-rogue-city-unfinished-business">Robocop: Rogue City - Unfinished Business</a> is so over-named it looks like DLC, but is actually an independent sequel from the same developers, and directly follows the events of the recent criminal justice 'em up. It'll see metal man Murphy going floor to floor as he and other Detroit city policefolk ascend a residential tower after "a group of highly trained mercenaries armed with cutting-edge weapons takes control of the building and turns it into their deadly fortress." Wait... doesn't this sound like another cyberpunk dystopia?</p>
<!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="RoboCop: Rogue City - Unfinished Business | Reveal Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/HZxqWFQI7GY?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>RoboCop: Rogue City - Unfinished Business | Reveal Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/HZxqWFQI7GY?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/HZxqWFQI7GY?autoplay=1" title="RoboCop: Rogue City - Unfinished Business | Reveal Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HZxqWFQI7GY" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>"Prepare to take on a new breed of enemies: OmniTower is packed with high-tech threats," says the game's blurb <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3527760/RoboCop_Rogue_City__Unfinished_Business/">on Steam</a>. "From flying drones to exploding bots and anti-personnel turrets, every floor is riddled with deadly traps, and heavily armed elite troops. Expect to face minigun-toting armoured squads, special forces equipped with jet packs or even katana-wielding foes who look more machine than man."</p>
<p>If you have seen 2012's <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=G-eI5oLlIeY">Dredd</a> starring Karl Urban, you may have raised an eyebrow (if you have seen <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=m6Q7KnXpNOg">The Raid</a>, you have raised both). Yes, this sounds like the same premise. But maybe that's no big deal. Developers Teyon seem to be doing their due diligence by adding all the requisite RoboCop-flavoured elements. You will play through FPS flashbacks with Murphy as a pre-cyberized meatcop, for example, and get some new abilities and weapons, such as a freezey cryo cannon and "devastating finishing moves" where you can slam crime-doer faces into nearby walls and vending machines.</p>
<p>The additional hands-on bone-crunching checks out. One of the more enjoyable parts of Robo's recent wreckabout was being able to lift any perp and yeet them ragdollifically across the city streets and prison corridors that you stomped through. Other than that I wasn't too fond of the shooter in my <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/robocop-rogue-city-review">RoboCop: Rogue City review</a> but I did acknowledge that it would likely be pleasing to long time fans of Paul Verhoeven's ultra-violent satire. </p>
<p>The sequel-follow-up-not-DLC-we-promise is due out sometime in "Q3 2025" which is business speak for "I dunno, autumn, I guess". </p></div>

        </article>

  
    </div><div data-component="article-footer">
    <div>
      <p><span><a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/authors/brendan-caldwell">Brendan Caldwell</a></span>: Brendan likes all types of games. To him there is wisdom in Crusader Kings 2, valour in Dark Souls, and tragicomedy in Nidhogg.
      </p>
    </div>




  



  <section>
    <p>In this article</p>

    

  </section>

  <section>
    <p>Related topics</p>

    
  </section>

  <div data-mode="signup" data-component="smart slot">
      <p>
        Rock Paper Shotgun is better when you sign in
      </p>

      <p>
        Sign in and join us on our journey to discover strange and compelling PC games.
      </p>

      
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Retro peripheral manufacturer Hyperkin sorry for "lack of transparency" and "failing to communicate" with customers]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/retro-peripheral-manufacturer-hyperkin-sorry-for-lack-of-transparency-and-failing-to-communicate-with-customers</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/retro-peripheral-manufacturer-hyperkin-sorry-for-lack-of-transparency-and-failing-to-communicate-with-customers.1127943/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/retro-peripheral-manufacturer-hyperkin-sorry-for-lack-of-transparency-and-failing-to-communicate-with-customers<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>"We don't want to fail you again."</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/hyperkin-guitar-ps3.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Hyperkin</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Retro peripheral manufacturer Hyperkin has apologised for a "lack of transparency" and "failing to communicate" with its customers.</p>
<p>The company has had a series of fumbles in recent years, with a tendency to announce new products too early. Last year it announced a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/theres-a-handheld-sega-mega-drive-device-in-the-works">handheld Mega Drive device</a> but has since gone quiet, while back in January it revealed <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/soon-you-will-be-able-to-play-your-xbox-with-a-ps5-style-controller">PS5-style controllers compatible with Xbox and PC</a> but without a release date.</p>
<p>Also in January, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/a-new-guitar-hero-controller-will-release-for-the-wii-this-year">Hyperkin revealed its new Hyper Strummer guitar controller</a> for the Wii, but customers accused the company of simply reusing unsold stock of its Wii guitars. The company refuted the accusations and is set to release an <a href="https://shop.hyperkinstore.com/products/hyper-jammer-wireless-guitar-for-pc-ps3-hyperkin?_pos=1&amp;_sid=00762d90e&amp;_ss=r">equivalent controller for PC and PS3</a>.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Newscast: Xbox currently has more first-party games coming to PlayStation 5 this year than Sony" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NXBJ-a0iUaw?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Newscast: Xbox currently has more first-party games coming to PlayStation 5 this year than Sony</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NXBJ-a0iUaw?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/NXBJ-a0iUaw?autoplay=1" title="Newscast: Xbox currently has more first-party games coming to PlayStation 5 this year than Sony">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Xbox currently has more first-party games coming to PlayStation 5 this year than Sony.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NXBJ-a0iUaw" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>Now the company has issued an apology in a bid to rebuild trust with its customers.</p>
<p>"The Hyperkin team has taken time to reflect on our values as a company," a statement on social media reads.</p>
<p>"We have overpromised and under-delivered. We failed to properly communicate and let down countless fans in the community with our lack of transparency."</p>
<p>It continued: "Our previously announced guitars are examples of us failing to communicate. There are no excuses and we take full responsibility for these mistakes. Trust is earned, not given, and we recognise that we have a lot of work to do to earn yours back with our modern guitar controller that is still being worked on."</p>
<p>Hyperkin promised to "break the habit", acknowledging its past administration was "eager to announce projects still early in development", which will no longer be the case with the new team the company is building.</p>
<div>

<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>

<p>As such it's focused on three areas: improved transparency in communication, "consistent connection" to keep customers informed, and "uncompromising quality" as it meets its goal to "deliver hardware that exceeds expectations".</p>
<p>"For every victory there will be an announcement," it concluded. "For every shortcoming there will be a statement. Thank you to our fans, supporters and multiple communities that have put up with our missteps. We don't want to fail you again."</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Monopoly movie banks Dungeons & Dragons film writers]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/monopoly-movie-banks-dungeons-dragons-film-writers</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/monopoly-movie-banks-dungeons-dragons-film-writers.1127940/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/monopoly-movie-banks-dungeons-dragons-film-writers<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/michelle-rodriguez-in-dungeons-and-dragons-honor-among-thieves-with-a-picture-of-the-Monopoly-man-giving-a-thumbs-up-overlayed-on-top.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Hasbro/Paramount/Eurogamer</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Lionsgate and Hasbro's upcoming Monopoly movie will be penned by the duo who bought us the criminally underrated Dungeons &amp; Dragons: Honor Among Thieves film.</p>
<p><a href="https://deadline.com/2025/03/monopoly-movie-lionsgate-luckychap-john-francis-daley-jonathan-goldstein-1236311872/">Deadline</a> reports John Francis Daley and Jonathan Goldstein have been brought onto the project, which is based on Hasbro's classic board game. The twosome's other writing credits include Spider-Man: Homecoming.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Lionsgate's Monopoly film will be <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/barbies-margot-robbie-to-produce-monopoly-movie-with-hasbro">produced by Margot Robbie's production company LuckyChap Entertainment</a></p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Newscast: Xbox currently has more first-party games coming to PlayStation 5 this year than Sony" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NXBJ-a0iUaw?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Newscast: Xbox currently has more first-party games coming to PlayStation 5 this year than Sony</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NXBJ-a0iUaw?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/NXBJ-a0iUaw?autoplay=1" title="Newscast: Xbox currently has more first-party games coming to PlayStation 5 this year than Sony">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Xbox currently has more first-party games coming to PlayStation 5 this year than Sony.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NXBJ-a0iUaw" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>"We knew LuckyChap would be a beacon for the best talent in town, and Lionsgate and Hasbro are thrilled that Goldstein and Daley have decided to join the fun," said Erin Westerman, co-president, Lionsgate Motion Picture Group.</p>
<p>"We've been longtime admirers of their work - telling bold, original, intelligent stories for all audiences. They are the perfect architects for this franchise."</p>
<p>In addition to adapting Monopoly for the big screen, last year it was announced that <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/barbies-margot-robbie-to-produce-the-sims-movie-adaptation">LuckyChap was working on a film adaptation of Maxis' life-simulation series The Sims</a> alongside EA.</p>
<p>For more on the board game itself, be sure to check out Christian Donlan's excellent feature: <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/inside-monopolys-secret-war-against-the-third-reich">Inside Monopoly's secret war against the Third Reich</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battlefield Releases Its First Community Update on Battlefield Labs Playtests]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-labs-first-playtest/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/battlefield-releases-its-first-community-update-on-battlefield-labs-playtests.1127925/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-labs-first-playtest/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Battlefield Labs will have its first-ever playtest for the next Battlefield game today and with it, the developers have released the first community update.</p>



<p>The update is intended to keep the entire community updated on Battlefield Labs – even those not in the playtest. For the first test, Battlefield Labs will be testing the games Gun and Movement. If you’re not in the test, players can still <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-sign-up-for-battlefield-labs/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up to Battlefield Labs</a>. </p>



<p><strong>The first Battlefield Labs test update reads:</strong></p>



<p>We’ve continually evolved our gunplay and movement mechanics throughout the Battlefield series. Now, within Battlefield Labs, we’re focused on refining the best elements from past titles, modernizing them, and validating if they feel fun and rewarding, and have the right balance between intuitive control and dynamic combat.</p>



<p>We’re designing the combat experience to ensure players of all skill levels can enjoy our gunplay and movement systems. Our goal is to offer gameplay that rewards skill with precise weapon feedback and movement options for veterans, while providing an intuitive experience for new players to learn and enjoy.</p>



<p>For gunplay we’re exploring designs centered on helping you learn and develop skills and muscle memory through action, as weapons naturally signal their recoil direction. This feedback loop allows you to understand and adjust your aim, making it easier to handle different weapons. This system not only adds variety but also enhances each weapon’s unique feel and play style.</p>



<p>Movement is also deeply integrated with gunplay, as your actions and targets are all part of the same cohesive combat experience. We aim to make movement both feel intuitive and rewarding to move within the world and during combat, but also when playing against someone using both the gunplay and movement systems to their maximum potential.</p>



<h2 id="h-what-s-new-and-improved-for-gunplay-and-movement">What’s new and improved for gunplay and movement?</h2>



<p>Initially we’ll test select but important areas that create the foundation required to create a fun and rewarding Battlefield combat experience. We’re making focused efforts to create consistent and optimized millisecond-to-millisecond soldier combat, and we’ll share some key examples of changes that will be available during our initial playsessions.</p>



<p>We’ve reduced the time it takes for bullets to appear on your screen from when you press fire. This change decreases input delay, makes shooting feel more responsive, and helps you better track and hit moving targets.</p>



<p>We’re optimizing for a 60Hz tick rate, ensuring the game server more frequently updates the positions and actions for all players. This results in responsive gameplay across all platforms and inputs. You’ll notice more precise shooting and movement, enhanced damage feedback, and more accurate representation of other players’ positions and combat outcomes.</p>



<p>We’ve adjusted the recoil system to make the different weapon types feel unique when firing them. Through enhancements to gunplay recoil, camera shakes, and firing settles, each shot’s recoil direction now matches its gameplay angle. The weapon visually stabilizes the more accurate your handling is, making you feel like you’re actually firing and controlling it.</p>



<p>To evolve the moment system we’ve revamped animations and reintroduced movement features such as crouch sprint, combat dive and landing roll, and added visual indicators to make it easier to understand when movements such as vaulting or leaning are possible.</p>



<h2 id="h-feedback-and-validation">Feedback and Validation</h2>



<p>At this stage content within Battlefield Labs is pre-alpha, and playsessions take place within a closed dev environment focused on testing small chunks of a larger array of features. Some gameplay features are placeholder, work-in-progress and with bugs and performance not being representative of the final experience. However, even during this early stage of development you’ll get a good sense of our new design approach.</p>



<p>During our first playsession our teams will be validating the systems and stability of Battlefield Labs such as server performance, while participants will be able to familiarise themselves with what’s next for Battlefield through testing the gunplay and movement experience, focused on:</p>



<ul>
<li>Feel of the different weapon archetypes</li>



<li>Improvements to aim and control</li>



<li>Weapon balance and fun factor</li>



<li>Look and feel of movement</li>



<li>Moving and interacting within the map</li>



<li>Combat pacing</li>
</ul>



<h2 id="h-stay-tuned">Stay Tuned</h2>



<p>Lastly, a reminder that while our playsession will be within a closed environment, and we can’t invite everyone to every session, we’ll make sure to keep you informed on ongoing Battlefield Labs playsessions and learnings through these regular Community Updates.</p>



<p>We’ll be back in the coming weeks to talk more about our learnings from our first playsessions, as well as another feature focused Community Update.</p>



<p>Have you already signed up to the Battlefield Labs playtests? Let us know on the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/">Insider Gaming forum</a>&nbsp;if you have any success.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read about the latest Xbox Insider update reportedly causing consoles to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-update-is-resetting-consoles-to-factory-default-settings/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">reset to their factory settings</a>. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[All Rare & Legendary Jokers in Balatro & What They do]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/all-rare-legendary-jokers-in-balatro-what-they-do/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/all-rare-legendary-jokers-in-balatro-what-they-do.1127922/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/all-rare-legendary-jokers-in-balatro-what-they-do/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Balatro’s assortment of Rare and Legendary Jokers should always be on your mind. While you can build toward most decks and strategies, there’s a good chance you need to pivot if one of these bad boys comes along. Let’s teach you about each one and how to unlock them.</p>



<p>Every game of Balatro is different—unless you use one of the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/best-balatro-seeds/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">best Balatro Seeds</a>. The final destination may be similar to runs you’ve had before, but the sheer depth of the game’s content means practically every run is new. There are thousands of possibilities, and one run could see you solely pursue <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-use-tarot-cards-in-balatro-all-tarot-cards-explained/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Tarot Cards</a>, or you may seek out Balatro’s Rare and Legendary Jokers.</p>



<p>If you’re new to Balatro—because of <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/is-balatro-coming-to-xbox-game-pass/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Xbox Game Pass</a> or something else—you might need a quick walkthrough of every Rare and Legendary Joker.</p>



<h2 id="h-all-rare-jokers-in-balatro-amp-what-they-do">All Rare Jokers in Balatro &amp; What They do</h2>



<figure><figcaption>You have much to learn and unlock. Image by Insider Gaming</figcaption></figure>



<p>There are 20 Rare Jokers in Balatro. Many are unlocked from the get-go, whereas others need to be unlocked through nefarious and devious means.</p>



<p>Here’s every <a href="https://www.playbalatro.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Balatro</a> Rare Joker, giving you a glimpse into powerful, game-changing Jokers.</p>



<figure><table><thead><tr><th data-align="center">Legendary Joker Name</th><th data-align="center">Description</th><th data-align="center">How to Unlock</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td data-align="center">DNA</td><td data-align="center">If&nbsp;first hand&nbsp;of round has only&nbsp;1&nbsp;card, add a permanent copy to deck and draw it to&nbsp;hand.</td><td data-align="center">Available from start.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Vagabond</td><td data-align="center">Create a&nbsp;Tarot&nbsp;card if hand is played with&nbsp;$4&nbsp;or less.</td><td data-align="center">Available from start.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Baron</td><td data-align="center">Each&nbsp;King&nbsp;held in hand gives&nbsp;X1.5&nbsp;Mult</td><td data-align="center">Available from start.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Obelisk</td><td data-align="center">This Joker gains&nbsp;X0.2&nbsp;Mult&nbsp;per&nbsp;consecutive&nbsp;hand played without playing your most played&nbsp;poker hand<br>(Currently&nbsp;X1&nbsp;Mult)</td><td data-align="center">Available from start.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Baseball Card</td><td data-align="center">Uncommon&nbsp;Jokers each give&nbsp;X1.5&nbsp;Mult</td><td data-align="center">Available from start.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Ancient Joker</td><td data-align="center">Each played card with&nbsp;[suit]&nbsp;gives&nbsp;X1.5&nbsp;Mult&nbsp;when scored,<br>suit changes at end of round.</td><td data-align="center">Available from start.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Campfire</td><td data-align="center">This Joker gains&nbsp;X0.25&nbsp;Mult&nbsp;for each card&nbsp;sold, resets when&nbsp;Boss Blind&nbsp;is defeated<br>(Currently&nbsp;X1&nbsp;Mult)</td><td data-align="center">Available from start.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Blueprint</td><td data-align="center">Copies ability of&nbsp;Joker&nbsp;to the right</td><td data-align="center">Win 1 run.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Wee Joker</td><td data-align="center">This Joker gains&nbsp;+8&nbsp;Chips&nbsp;when each played&nbsp;2&nbsp;is scored<br>(Currently&nbsp;+0&nbsp;&nbsp;Chips)</td><td data-align="center">Win a run in 18 or fewer rounds.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Hit The Road</td><td data-align="center">This Joker gains&nbsp;X0.5&nbsp;Mult&nbsp;for every&nbsp;Jack&nbsp;discarded this round<br>(Currently&nbsp;X1&nbsp;Mult)</td><td data-align="center">Discard&nbsp;5 Jacks&nbsp;at the same time.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">The Duo</td><td data-align="center">X2&nbsp;Mult&nbsp;if played hand contains a&nbsp;Pair</td><td data-align="center">Win a run without playing a&nbsp;Pair.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">The Trio</td><td data-align="center">X3&nbsp;Mult&nbsp;if played hand contains a&nbsp;Three of a Kind</td><td data-align="center">Win a run without playing a&nbsp;Three of a Kind.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">The Family</td><td data-align="center">X4&nbsp;Mult&nbsp;if played hand contains a&nbsp;Four of a Kind</td><td data-align="center">Win a run without playing a&nbsp;Four of a Kind.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">The Order</td><td data-align="center">X3&nbsp;Mult&nbsp;if played hand contains a&nbsp;Straight</td><td data-align="center">Win a run without playing a&nbsp;Straight.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">The Tribe</td><td data-align="center">X2&nbsp;Mult&nbsp;if played hand contains a&nbsp;Flush</td><td data-align="center">Win a run without playing a&nbsp;Flush.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Stuntman</td><td data-align="center">+250&nbsp;Chips,<br>-2&nbsp;hand size</td><td data-align="center">Earn at least 100 million (100,000,000) Chips in a single hand.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Invisible Joker</td><td data-align="center">After&nbsp;<strong>2</strong>&nbsp;rounds, sell this card to&nbsp;Duplicate&nbsp;a random Joker<br>(Currently&nbsp;0/2)<br>(Removes&nbsp;Negative&nbsp;from copy)</td><td data-align="center">Win a game while never having more than 4 jokers.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Brainstorm</td><td data-align="center">Copies the ability of leftmost&nbsp;Joker</td><td data-align="center">Discard a&nbsp;Royal Flush.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Driver’s License</td><td data-align="center">X3&nbsp;Mult&nbsp;if you have at least&nbsp;16&nbsp;Enhanced cards in your full deck<br>(Currently&nbsp;0)</td><td data-align="center">Enhance 16 cards in your deck.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Burnt Joker</td><td data-align="center">Upgrade the level of the first&nbsp;discarded&nbsp;poker hand each round.</td><td data-align="center">Sell 50 cards.</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<h2 id="h-all-legendary-jokers-in-balatro-amp-what-they-do">All Legendary Jokers in Balatro &amp; What They do</h2>



<p>It’s time for the cream of the crop. Balatro’s Legendary Jokers are the rarest and some of the most devastating. Getting a Soul Card is quite difficult and only happens every few hours of gameplay (unless you’re lucky), but you learn to savor a Legendary Joker if you get the chance to use one.</p>



<p>Take a look at the greatness each Legendary Joker holds.</p>



<figure><table><thead><tr><th data-align="center">Legendary Joker Name</th><th data-align="center">Description</th><th data-align="center">How to Unlock</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td data-align="center">Canio</td><td data-align="center">This Joker gains&nbsp;X1&nbsp;Mult&nbsp;when a&nbsp;face&nbsp;card is destroyed. (Currently&nbsp;X1&nbsp;Mult)</td><td data-align="center">Find this&nbsp;Joker&nbsp;from the&nbsp;Soul&nbsp;card.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Triboulet</td><td data-align="center">Played Kings and Queens each give&nbsp;X2&nbsp;Mult&nbsp;when scored.</td><td data-align="center">Find this&nbsp;Joker&nbsp;from the&nbsp;Soul&nbsp;card.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Yorick</td><td data-align="center">This Joker gains X1 mult every 23 [23] Cards discarded. (Currently X1 Mult)</td><td data-align="center">Find this&nbsp;Joker&nbsp;from the&nbsp;Soul&nbsp;card.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Chicot</td><td data-align="center">Disables effect of every&nbsp;Boss Blind</td><td data-align="center">Find this&nbsp;Joker&nbsp;from the&nbsp;Soul&nbsp;card.</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Perkeo</td><td data-align="center">Creates a&nbsp;Negative&nbsp;copy of&nbsp;1&nbsp;random&nbsp;consumable&nbsp;card in your possession at the end of the&nbsp;shop.</td><td data-align="center">Find this&nbsp;Joker&nbsp;from the&nbsp;Soul&nbsp;card.</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<hr>



<p>Have you got your eye on any Jokers in particular? If you’re a regular Balatro player, which of the Rare or Legendarys do you favor above others? Let us know.</p>



<p>For more Balatro guides, check out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/what-does-the-blank-voucher-do-in-balatro/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">what the Blank Voucher does</a>, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/what-does-1-ante-1-hand-each-round-mean-in-balatro-hieroglyph-voucher-explained/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">what -1 Ante -1 Hand means</a>, and the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/balatro-trophy-guide-all-achievements-trophies/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Balatro Trophy List</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jackbox Games coming to Smart TVs for free]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/jackbox-games-coming-to-smart-tvs-for-free</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/jackbox-games-coming-to-smart-tvs-for-free.1127919/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/jackbox-games-coming-to-smart-tvs-for-free<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>Will they survive the internet?</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/sc8l0b.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Jackbox Games</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>You'll soon be able to play a selection of Jackbox Games on your Smart TV for free.</p>
<p>The games will be streamed via the cloud, starting with a small collection of ad-supported games for free.</p>
<p>Then, down the line, the entire catalogue of games will be available for a subscription fee.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Play The Jackbox Naughty Pack this holiday season (Rated M for Mature)" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/iwXmwQSTI2A?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Play The Jackbox Naughty Pack this holiday season (Rated M for Mature)</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/iwXmwQSTI2A?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/iwXmwQSTI2A?autoplay=1" title="Play The Jackbox Naughty Pack this holiday season (Rated M for Mature)">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Play The Jackbox Naughty Pack this holiday season (Rated M for Mature)<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iwXmwQSTI2A" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>While there's no release date yet for the service, Jackbox Games is hoping to bring a beta version to "one or two smart TV platforms" in spring this year. More platforms and features will then follow.</p>
<p>"It has always been our goal to bring these games to as many people as possible and make them as easy to play as we can," reads a notice on the <a href="https://www.jackboxgames.com/blog/jackbox-coming-to-your-smart-tv-for-free">Jackbox website</a>. "That is why we are announcing a new Jackbox app that will allow you to play Jackbox Games on your smart TV and other platforms."</p>
<p>If you're yet to play them, Jackbox Games are a collection of party games available on Steam that players can join on their mobile device.</p>
<p>Games include the likes of joke writing game Quiplash, T-shirt design game Tee KO, and the meme creation game Survive The Internet, among many others. The robot rap battle game Mad Verse City is a personal favourite.</p>
<p>Last year <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/jackbox-finally-adding-megapicker-for-seamless-minigame-swapping-across-packs">Jackbox added a Megapicker</a> to combine all its various game packs into a single selection, making it easier to switch between games.</p>
<p>It also released a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/jackbox-wants-us-to-answer-questions-like-which-meat-most-wants-to-be-called-daddy-in-its-new-naughty-pack">Naughty Pack of more mature games</a>, though considering most players like to make the basic games rude, it's unclear how popular these have been.</p>
<p>It's unknown if these mature games will be included on TVs to awkwardly play with your family.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tony Hawk's Pro Skater 3+4 is switching up how THPS4 works]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/tony-hawks-pro-skater-34-is-switching-up-how-thps4-works</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/tony-hawks-pro-skater-3-4-is-switching-up-how-thps4-works.1127916/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/tony-hawks-pro-skater-34-is-switching-up-how-thps4-works<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>Kickturn up for the books.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Tony-Hawks-Pro-Skater-3-and-4-image-showing-three-female-skaters-performing-tricks_g72B5Dr.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Activision</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>There will be some changes to how things work in the remake of <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/tony-hawks-pro-skater-4">THPS4</a> when <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/tony-hawks-pro-skater-3-4">Tony Hawk's Pro Skater 3+4</a> releases this summer. As a reminder, the original release of <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/tony-hawks-pro-skater-3">Tony Hawk Pro Skater 3</a> included a two-minute time limit in which players could complete a level's challenges. This was removed for Pro Skater 4.</p>
<p>But, while in the OG Tony Hawk Pro Skater 4 players were able to skate around levels freely in Career mode and then talk to other characters around the stage to trigger challenges, on the remake's release this July, the game will instead follow a different structure.</p>
<p>Eurogamer can confirm the objectives for players to complete in Tony Hawk Pro Skater 3 + 4 will be based on a timer for both games. There will also be a Free Skate mode, which has no timer at all, as well as Speed Run and Single Session modes. The Free Skate mode in Tony Hawk Pro Skater 3 + 4 will not let players to complete challenges in the same way that they were able to in the original Pro Skater 4 Career mode.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Tony Hawk's Pro Skater 3 + 4 - Reveal Trailer | PS5 &amp; PS4 Games" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/57dD5_Gbjxw?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Tony Hawk's Pro Skater 3 + 4 - Reveal Trailer | PS5 &amp; PS4 Games</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/57dD5_Gbjxw?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/57dD5_Gbjxw?autoplay=1" title="Tony Hawk's Pro Skater 3 + 4 - Reveal Trailer | PS5 &amp; PS4 Games">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Tony Hawk's Pro Skater 3 + 4 reveal trailer. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=57dD5_Gbjxw" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>Earlier this week, and after <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/tony-hawks-pro-skater-announcement-teased-in-call-of-duty-black-ops-6s-latest-map">plenty of whispers and speculation</a>, Activision announced Tony Hawk's Pro Skater 3 and 4 were finally getting the remake treatment. Tony Hawk's Pro Skater 3 + 4 will be released across PlayStation 4, PS5, Xbox One, Xbox Series X/S, PC (via Steam, Battle.net and Microsoft Store), and Nintendo Switch on 11th July. It will also be coming to Game Pass Ultimate and Game Pass PC.</p>
<p>"Developed with attention to detail by Iron Galaxy Studios and in collaboration with Tony Hawk and Activision, Tony Hawk's Pro Skater 3 + 4 picks up seamlessly right where the critically acclaimed <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/tony-hawks-pro-skater-1-2">Tony Hawk's Pro Skater 1 and 2</a> game left off," the official blurb reads.</p>
<p>You can find more information on the upcoming remakes, as well as the various editions, in our <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/tony-hawks-pro-skater-3-4-official-announcement-reveals-deluxe-edition-with-doom-slayer">original Tony Hawk Pro Skater 3+4 announcement post here</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Capcom soon to fix Monster Hunter Wilds issue where its celebrated food scenes aren't showing]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/capcom-soon-to-fix-monster-hunter-wilds-issue-where-its-celebrated-food-scenes-arent-showing</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/capcom-soon-to-fix-monster-hunter-wilds-issue-where-its-celebrated-food-scenes-arent-showing.1127913/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/capcom-soon-to-fix-monster-hunter-wilds-issue-where-its-celebrated-food-scenes-arent-showing<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article">
        <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>You'll be grateful for the fix.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/83cf5d70-32af-4450-8dea-e6db54fc8c18.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Capcom / Eurogamer</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
    <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Capcom will soon release another update for <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/monster-hunter-wilds">Monster Hunter Wilds</a>, which will fix an issue where the game's celebrated food scenes are occasionally not being shown.</p>
<p>Version 1.000.05.00 will be released on 10th March, with Capcom noting any online sessions will be discontinued and the update will be required to continue playing online. Capcom has already released the <a href="https://www.monsterhunter.com/support/wilds/en/faq/detail/060">patch notes</a> detailing what will be included.</p>
<p>Top of the list of fixes is an issue where the "Meal Invitation event at Azuz and Sild does not occur on some occasions". These are the scenes where characters chomp on those <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/monster-hunter-wilds-delectable-cuisine-causes-cheese-naan-sales-to-surge">delectable-looking cheese naans that's caused a surge in sales in Japanese restaurants</a>.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Monster Hunter Wilds Tips: 28 Things You NEED To Know Before You Start" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/e6AJCE5gOCA?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Monster Hunter Wilds Tips: 28 Things You NEED To Know Before You Start</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/e6AJCE5gOCA?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/e6AJCE5gOCA?autoplay=1" title="Monster Hunter Wilds Tips: 28 Things You NEED To Know Before You Start">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Monster Hunter Wilds Tips: 28 Things You NEED To Know Before You Start<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=e6AJCE5gOCA" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>Other incoming fixes include an issue where when cutting off monster parts, they change into those of a different monster - particularly frustrating when you're grinding for specific materials.</p> <div>
<div data-domain="twitter.com"><blockquote><div dir="ltr" lang="en"><p>Heads up, hunters: Hotfix patch Ver.1.000.05.00 is planned to go live on all platforms on 10th March. </p><p>Planned fix details can he found here: <a href="https://t.co/FmMGsHWQpO">https://t.co/FmMGsHWQpO</a></p><p>Once the update is out, any online sessions will be discontinued and you will need to update to continue playing…</p></div>— Monster Hunter Status (@MHStatusUpdates) <a href="https://twitter.com/MHStatusUpdates/status/1897950391544791530?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">March 7, 2025</a></blockquote></div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>The full list of issues to be addressed in the next patch are as follows:</p>
<ul>
<li>The Meal Invitation event at Azuz and Sild does not occur on some occasions.</li>
<li>An issue occurring when using Equipment Loadout, causing decorations to be removed from equipment, Bowgun Customization being reverted back to default, and Kinsects reverting to the initial rarity.</li>
<li>When cutting off monster parts, the parts change into a monster part from a different monster.</li>
<li>Gravios does not gain resistance to flinches after breaking its parts.</li>
<li>An issue which may cause crashes or some monsters to act strangely under certain situations.</li>
<li>Some skills are unintentionally activated under certain conditions.</li>
<li>Some items/rewards can be obtained repeatedly under certain conditions.</li>
<li>When trying to catch a fish with a capture net, the fishes nearby do not swim away from the fishing spot.</li>
<li>Some environmental features such as floating rubbles can be activated multiple times.</li>
<li>An issue wherein Main Mission: Chapter 5-1 "Omens" cannot be progressed.</li>
<li>Palico's support move "Attract Vigorwasps" may cause the hunter to become unresponsive to some controls.</li>
<li>When scrolling through the quest list, only the first 20 quests are shown correctly.</li>
<li>An issue which may cause the game to forcefully shut down when starting a game with saved data that encountered a force quit.</li>
</ul>
<p>In the patch notes, Capcom reiterated some currently known issues, including a problem where a network error can occur after firing an SOS flare at the start of a quest that's yet to be fixed.</p>
<p>Another known issue means player Hunter Profiles cannot be edited on some occasions.</p>
<p>The <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/monster-hunter-wilds-patch-notes-warn-of-network-error-when-firing-sos-flares">previous patch was released earlier this week</a>.</p>
<p>Yesterday Japanese magazine Famitsu released sales figures for the past week, showing <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/monster-hunter-wilds-has-biggest-physical-launch-of-any-ps5-game-in-japan">Monster Hunter Wilds had the biggest physical launch ever for a PS5 game</a> in the country.</p></div>



        </article>

  
    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Forever Winter's water will no longer drain away while you're offline]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-forever-winters-water-will-no-longer-drain-away-while-youre-offline</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-forever-winters-water-will-no-longer-drain-away-while-youre-offline.1127901/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-forever-winters-water-will-no-longer-drain-away-while-youre-offline<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/the-forever-winter-water-update-3.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Fun Dog Studios</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Mechy and messy extraction shooter <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/the-forever-winter">The Forever Winter</a> sees a big update today that addresses the biggest player complaint the game had on launch - the precious water that drained away in real-time, even while you weren't playing the game. The patch to the early access shooter reworks water so it becomes a currency that you use to infiltrate the game's brutal maps at different entry points, instead of dripping away and threatening to leave you thirsty and destitute. And this isn't the only promising news - enemy spawning changes, reworked gunplay, and a new map also appear. </p>
<!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="The Forever Winter - March Update: “The Descent to Averno is Easy”" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/agY8OeKcur0?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>The Forever Winter - March Update: “The Descent to Averno is Easy”</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/agY8OeKcur0?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/agY8OeKcur0?autoplay=1" title="The Forever Winter - March Update: “The Descent to Averno is Easy”">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=agY8OeKcur0" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>If you missed the water fury the first time around, let me explain. The Forever Winter's brutal warzones would often hide barrels of water you could strap to your back. Escape the map and you would add these litres to a big water tank in your home base (a hub of bullet merchants where you stash all the good gear you've scavenged). But that water supply would slowly drain - the cost of keeping your hub running. If it hit zero, your hub would "die" and all your stashed goodies would vanish. This water supply would deplete even while offline, the idea being that this adds more stress to the process of surviving in an apocalyptic hellscape. </p>
<p>Now the game's creators are ditching that idea entirely. "Water is no longer a resource that drains [in] real-time," say developers Fun Dog Studios in the update's <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/2828860/view/496063443495814171">patch notes on Steam</a>. "It is now a currency that is used to access region entry points. Region entry points have specific water costs that are in an RNG range."</p>
<p>This basically means the game's maps now have a default entry point, and you'll need to use water as payment to enter the hellish battleyards from other starting points (you may also need to have a good reputation with certain factions for this). Water can now also be traded from player to player, and the frequency of scavengable water barrels appearing in maps has been rebalanced, say the devs. </p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/the-forever-winter-water-update-1.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Fun Dog Studios</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Unsurprisingly, many players disliked the original water premise. It became one of the biggest gripes in an early access launch marred by performance issues and unpredictable enemy behaviour. The developers promised changes, but didn't want to remove water as a stressy driving force completely. </p>
<p>One early patch saw <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-forever-winter-devs-answer-complaints-about-water-scarcity-by-adding-thieves-who-invade-your-hq-and-steal-your-water">thieves creep into your subterranean home to steal your last drops</a>. Defeating these scoundrels offered a last chance to save your stash from a water shortage. Later, the developers added a <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/2828860/view/547848028756640978">"thief-proof vault"</a> - a limited space for goodies that would never be lost, even in a critical water crisis. They also introduced water bots that would let players collect water automatically. (The meme-faced water thieves will still appear following this latest update, we're told. Although the consequences for not dealing with them won't be so high anymore.) </p>
<p>The water system, for all the ire it attracted, was the least significant of my complaints when I played The Forever Winter for <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-forever-winter-struggles-into-early-access-with-poor-performance-and-a-deadly-thirst-for-your-time">our early access review</a>. Enemy spawning was wacky, their combat behaviour was difficult to understand, levels were cluttered and visually noisy, bugs were commonplace, and even the simple act of picking up items from the ground was a chore. I loved the core idea (little scav caught in the middle of an eternal robo-war) and the art direction is precisely my weathered cloth bag. But it was hard to stomach the rough state of the launch.</p>
<p>This update addresses several of those problems too, though. Enemy spawning has been adjusted to "hopefully completely remove" the problem of "seeing enemies spawn right in front of you out of thin air" or "having enemies spawn right on top of you or out of view." Guns have seen a big rework, and a new map featuring a fiery stone staircase has been added. We're also told "rendering improvements have been made to increase FPS" and "enemy detection icons show up more reliably with the correct information", meaning that you should theoretically be able to understand when and where a foe spots you or a teammate.</p>
<p>This is all good news, and I want to return to the game to see if it plays a little smoother now. I'm in favour of the water rework too. I understand that game designers often aim to elicit strong emotions in players, and here Fun Dog's designers desired a feeling of unease and insecurity, all the better to fit their game's permawar theme. But I prefer when those feelings are confined to the time when I'm actually playing the game, rather than spreading like a nervous tendril into my real life. I imagine many others feel the same about "FOMO" designs like this. </p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Remember Starfield? Bethesda reassures fans it has "exciting things planned" for 2025, as wait continues for news on what's next]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/remember-starfield-bethesda-reassures-fans-it-has-exciting-things-planned-for-2025-as-wait-continues-for-news-on-whats-next</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/remember-starfield-bethesda-reassures-fans-it-has-exciting-things-planned-for-2025-as-wait-continues-for-news-on-whats-next.1127898/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/remember-starfield-bethesda-reassures-fans-it-has-exciting-things-planned-for-2025-as-wait-continues-for-news-on-whats-next<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>Nearing six months since Shattered Space.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/ION_Journey_Through_Space_16x9_Center.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Bethesda</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Bethesda has reassured <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/starfield-main-story-walkthrough-9352">Starfield</a> fans it is still "hard at work" on what's next for its ambitious sci-fi role-playing game, almost six months on from last September's Shattered Space expansion.
</p>
<p>
Starfield arrived in a blaze of marketing back in September 2023, though updates for the game have since slowed. Much of Bethesda's messaging of late on the game's social media channels has been focused on highlighting community-made content.
</p>
<p>
Now, there's a fresh update from Bethesda, acknowledging the wait for news. "We know you're eager for an update," <a href="https://x.com/StarfieldGame/status/1897709518013997493">Bethesda wrote</a>, replying to a fan who contacted the company saying it needed to start communicating what was happening with the game's next update or DLC.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="STARFIELD Stealth: How To Make It Actually *WORK* - STARFIELD XBOX SERIES X STEALTH GAMEPLAY TIPS" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/3HILurWvxiU?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>STARFIELD Stealth: How To Make It Actually *WORK* - STARFIELD XBOX SERIES X STEALTH GAMEPLAY TIPS</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/3HILurWvxiU?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/3HILurWvxiU?autoplay=1" title="STARFIELD Stealth: How To Make It Actually *WORK* - STARFIELD XBOX SERIES X STEALTH GAMEPLAY TIPS">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>How to be stealthy in Starfield.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3HILurWvxiU" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
"We truly appreciate your passion for Starfield," Bethesda continued. "The team has been hard at work, and while we're not ready to share specific details just yet, we have a lot of exciting things planned for the game this year that we can't wait to talk about when the time is right."
</p>
<p>
Responses from fans include excitement to see what's next, as well as messages speculating that Bethesda is busy working on the game's PlayStation 5 version before pushing forward with any other expansion.
</p>
<p>
"While Shattered Space is quite possibly one of Starfield's most enjoyable storylines to date, it once again struggles to offer any real consequences," our Katharine wrote of the game's first expansion, in <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/starfield-shattered-space-review">Eurogamer's Starfield: Shattered Space review</a>. "And its new setting feels woefully underutilised."
</p>
<p>
<a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/bethesdas-todd-howard-confirms-at-least-one-more-starfield-expansion-after-shattered-space">Bethesda's Todd Howard previously confirmed Starfield would receive at least one more Starfield expansion after Shattered Space</a> - though there's no word on when that will turn up.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Starfield Will Get Exciting Things Later This Year, Says Bethesda]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/starfield-will-get-exciting-things-later-this-year-says-bethesda/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/starfield-will-get-exciting-things-later-this-year-says-bethesda.1127877/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/starfield-will-get-exciting-things-later-this-year-says-bethesda/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>It's been a while since Bethesda Game Studios provided an updated roadmap of what's next for Starfield. Fans have been reaching out to the developer, and now the game's official X account has <a href="https://x.com/StarfieldGame/status/1897709518013997493" target="_blank" rel="noopener">teased</a> 'lots of exciting things' coming to the game later in 2025:</p>
<p><em>We know you're eager for an update, and we truly appreciate your passion for Starfield. The team has been hard at work, and while we're not ready to share specific details just yet, we have a lot of exciting things planned for the game this year that we can't wait to talk about when the time is right. We’re always listening and taking your feedback to heart. Thanks for being part of this journey with us.</em></p>
<p>2024 was filled with lots of updates, such as the one that added the much-requested Rev-8 land vehicle, not to mention the Shattered Space expansion. However, the premium DLC wasn't that well-received, getting just a six out of 10 in <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/starfield-shattered-space-may-the-great-serpent-save-us/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Wccftech's review</a> by Francesco De Meo:</p>
<p><em>The Starfield Shattered Space expansion leaves a lot to be desired. While it introduces a more focused and engaging story compared to the base game, the average map and quest design, along with the lack of new features, turn the adventure in Va'Ruun'kai into a bit of a slog rather quickly. Although the tighter focus is welcome, the Starfield experience as a whole needs something more substantial to reach its full potential.</em></p>
<p>It'll be interesting to see if the game gets another full-fledged expansion this year or just some free updates. Bethesda's Todd Howard did <a href="https://wccftech.com/starfield-crossed-14-million-players-will-get-annual-story-expansions-shattered-space-set-on-single-planet-is-far-harbor-sized/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">say</a> the team was gearing up to release annual story expansions, but plans might have changed, especially as the studio is very busy with The Elder Scrolls VI.</p>
<p>Still, there is that Starborn trademark that Bethesda&nbsp;<a href="https://wccftech.com/starborn-trademark-could-hint-at-starfields-next-expansion/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">registered</a> in the Summer of 2024; fans have been speculating it could be the title of the next Starfield expansion. We'll probably learn a lot more about the future of Starfield during June's Xbox Games Showcase. Keep in mind that one of those exciting things could very well be the long rumored PlayStation 5 release, which is <a href="https://wccftech.com/fable-starfield-playstation-5-nintendo-switch-2/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">said</a> to be close now.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Goblin stealth gaming returns in Styx: Blades Of Greed, out in 2025 - here's the first trailer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/goblin-stealth-gaming-returns-in-styx-blades-of-greed-out-in-2025-heres-the-first-trailer</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/goblin-stealth-gaming-returns-in-styx-blades-of-greed-out-in-2025-heres-the-first-trailer.1127874/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/goblin-stealth-gaming-returns-in-styx-blades-of-greed-out-in-2025-heres-the-first-trailer<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Cyanide and Nacon have announced <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/styx-blades-of-greed">Styx: Blades Of Greed</a>, the third in a trilogy of goblin <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-stealth-games">stealth</a> games known for puke-based mechanics and many a snarky note-to-self. I never completed the previous <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/styx-master-of-shadows">Styx: Master Of Shadows</a> or <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/styx-shards-of-darkness">Styx: Shards Of Darkness</a>, and if I'm honest, I fear Cyanide's impish infiltrator is doomed to forever butt his smirking, warty head against the 6/10 glass ceiling, with Thief's Garrett flashing V-signs on the other side.</p>
<p>Still, I have a certain respect for the series. There aren't many third-person sneakers like this any more, still fewer that have successfully gotten away with a protagonist who sounds like a chaddy Sam Fisher and looks like he should be cleaning toilets in Moria. So a quiet hip-hooray, then, for Blades Of Greed, which is out later in 2025. Here's a trailer.
</p><!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Styx: Blades of Greed - Official Cinematic Reveal Trailer | Nacon Connect 2025" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wxS7-6uT2Bo?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Styx: Blades of Greed - Official Cinematic Reveal Trailer | Nacon Connect 2025</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wxS7-6uT2Bo?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/wxS7-6uT2Bo?autoplay=1" title="Styx: Blades of Greed - Official Cinematic Reveal Trailer | Nacon Connect 2025">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wxS7-6uT2Bo" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>
What's the Green Plague up to in this one, then? The usual, from the looks of it: clambering up massive citadels, shivving or bamboozling their guards, cracking the bad kind of bad joke, making away with the treasure. You can still sick up a clone of yourself and turn invisible using Amber, but you also get powers derived from a new energy source, Quartz - these include mind control and time manipulation. 
</p>
<p>
The story is about stealing Quartz from the human Inquisition, and takes you via airship to three large environments - "The Wall, which marks the boundary of the human world; the lush orc village of Turquoise Dawn; and the Ruins of the elven capital, Akenash". New areas become available within those sandboxes via "Metroidvania-style" tool-gating. You'll also get to craft weapons and potions before undertaking each heist.
</p>
<p>
The setting has always been Styx's big draw for me. All that cobbled-together, piled-up masonry, buttressed by some respectable grimdark lore. I share Alec Meer's (RPS in peace) distaste for the character's internal monologue, however. "Clearly, a lot of money and skill has gone into making Shards Of Darkness, which only makes the fact that you have to battle past this woeful characterisation to get to the strong stealth meat below all the more tragic," he <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/styx-shards-of-darkness-review">wrote of the most recent Styx outing</a>.</p>
<p>Re-reading that review, I'm struck by the mention of rampant fourth-wall-breaking, which I don't remember being quite so abundant in Master Of Shadows. Hopefully they've eased off on it in Blades Of Greed. <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3290690/Styx_Blades_of_Greed/">Find out more on Steam</a>.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[50% of all Steam users in February were Chinese-speaking]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/50-of-all-steam-users-in-february-were-chinese-speaking</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/50-of-all-steam-users-in-february-were-chinese-speaking.1127862/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/50-of-all-steam-users-in-february-were-chinese-speaking<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/mecha-break-art.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Amazing Seasun Games</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Chinese-speaking users accounted for 50 percent of Steam's playerbase last month.</p>
<p>Valve has released its latest <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/hwsurvey/">Steam Hardware and Software Survey</a>, which revealed a 20.88 percent increase in Simplified Chinese-speaking users in February 2025, making up half of the entire userbase.</p>
<p>As <a href="https://automaton-media.com/en/news/steam-saw-chinese-users-spike-and-exceed-50-of-worldwide-playerbase-in-february-2025/">Automaton</a> noted, February usually brings an increase of Chinese users to Steam as it coincides with Chinese New Year holidays. However, this year's increase was significantly higher than usual - 2024 saw an equivalent increase of 7.26 percent.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Mecha BREAK - Global Storm Open Beta Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/0JritlNXW18?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Mecha BREAK - Global Storm Open Beta Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/0JritlNXW18?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/0JritlNXW18?autoplay=1" title="Mecha BREAK - Global Storm Open Beta Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Mecha BREAK - Global Storm Open Beta Trailer<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0JritlNXW18" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>English-speaking users are the next highest, accounting for an almost 24 percent proportion of the userbase. Similarly, the Christmas season usually results in a spike in proportion.</p>
<p>The success of Game Science's <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/black-myth-wukong">Black Myth: Wukong</a> is likely a contributing factor to this increase in Chinese users. While its player numbers have dwindled since launch, it remains a huge success story and has the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/black-myth-wukong-already-steams-most-played-single-player-game-of-all-time">second highest all-time concurrent player count on the platform</a>.</p>
<p>Another factor could be the demo for Mecha Break, a multiplayer mech shooter from Chinese developer Amazing Seasun Games that <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/sale/nextfestmostplayed_feb_2025">dominated Steam Next Fest</a> - it reached a <a href="https://x.com/MechaBREAK/status/1897105111476003317">peak player count of over 300,000</a>.</p>
<p>Other contributing factors could be the ongoing success of NetEase's Marvel Rivals that saw its new season launch in this period, as well as the release of <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/monster-hunter-wilds">Monster Hunter Wilds</a> at the very end of the month that saw <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/monster-hunter-wilds-propels-steam-to-highest-ever-player-count">Steam reach its highest ever concurrent player count</a>.</p>
<p>What's more, this upward trend in Chinese-speaking users is likely to continue. If Mecha Break's demo is anything to go by, its full release later this year will be huge.</p>
<p>Then there's the likes of the PlayStation-published Chinese action game <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/lost-soul-aside-launches-in-2025-nine-years-after-devil-may-cry-and-final-fantasy-15-inspired-action-games-reveal">Lost Soul Aside</a>, as well as another Chinese action game <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/heres-a-fresh-look-at-chinese-fantasy-soulslike-wuchang-fallen-feathers">Wuchang: Fallen Feathers</a> (not to be confused with Wukong), while the free-to-play <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/fragpunk-console-launch-delayed-as-neteases-shooter-hits-pc-this-week">FragPunk</a> follows Marvel Rivals as NetEase's next big shooter.</p>
<p>It's clear that Chinese studios are thriving, and that's resulting in a surge of Steam users in the country.</p>
<p>Yet political relations between China and the US are causing friction in the industry. NetEase laid off a number of Marvel Rivals developers from its US team despite the game's success. Reportedly, further downsizing is yet to come, though <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/marvel-rivals-surpasses-40m-players-as-netease-denies-abandoning-western-studios">NetEase has denied such allegations</a>.</p>
<p>At the start of the year, Chinese conglomerate <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/us-labels-tencent-as-a-chinese-military-company">Tencent was labelled a military company by the US</a> - the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/tencent-threatens-legal-proceedings-if-us-doesnt-overturn-decision-to-label-it-as-a-chinese-military-company">company threatened legal proceedings in response</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[First look at Disco Elysium "spiritual successor" Hopetown shows a painterly, gorgeous, and utterly unconvincing RPG]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/first-look-at-disco-elysium-spiritual-successor-hopetown-shows-a-painterly-gorgeous-and-utterly-unconvincing-rpg</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/first-look-at-disco-elysium-spiritual-successor-hopetown-shows-a-painterly-gorgeous-and-utterly-unconvincing-rpg.1127847/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/first-look-at-disco-elysium-spiritual-successor-hopetown-shows-a-painterly-gorgeous-and-utterly-unconvincing-rpg<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Longdue Games have shared the first gameplay image from <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/hopetown">Hopetown</a>, their <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-rpgs">RPG</a> "spiritual successor" to <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/disco-elysium">Disco Elysium</a>, coming soon to <a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/longduegames/hopetown/">Kickstarter</a>.</p>
<p>First namelessly <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/former-disco-elysium-devs-are-working-on-a-spiritual-successor-at-new-studio-longdue-though-robert-kurvitz-and-aleksander-rostov-arent-involved">teased last October</a> as part of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/sure-why-not-third-group-of-former-disco-elysium-devs-announce-revolutionary-new-rpg-studio">The Great Disco Thrupening</a>, then <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-psychogeography-est-of-disco-elysiums-spiritual-successors-is-a-gonzo-journalism-rpg-named-hopetown">revealed last month</a>, Hopetown was described as "merging the raw emotional depth and psychological intricacy of Disco Elysium with the philosophical richness and narrative complexity of <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/planescape-torment">Planescape: Torment</a>."</p>
<!--more-->
<p>At the time, I hoped this tone and tenor of trying too hard<em> </em>was just press release guff. No such luck, if the writing shown off below is any indication.</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Hopetown-gameplay-1.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Longdue</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>But let's first back up a moment, because it does <em>look</em> great. So great I'm having some difficulty believing this is what the game looks like, rather than just being concept art. It's stunning. The purple and yellow palette. The painterly style, soft but sharp with detail.</p>
<p>Then you start reading. "Let me introduce myself," says your character to a sweet old lady feeding pigeons. "I don't shit in my own drinking water - though I see that's not a deal-breaker".</p>
<p>In Disco Elysium, your character could find a leather jacket with "Fuck The World" written on the back. If you tried hard enough, you could even convince your partner Kim to wear a complimentary jacket that read "Pissf****t". Someone at Longdue evidently thought those jackets were a good baseline for character development.</p>
<p>Admittedly, I'm viewing this dialogue through eyes pre-exhausted by Longdue's description of your character as "a chaotic, self-destructive provocateur who sees humanity as inherently selfish and cruel" and "unapologetically cynical and dangerously unhinged". Disco Elysium was frequently self-satisfied, show-offish, and overly slick. But it wasn't ever, you know, <a href="https://youtu.be/rr56tvKSe28">Nathan Barley on the bus</a>.</p>
<p>The pigeon lady offers your character a loaf of bread. You've got three responses to that, one of which is categorised "Noblesse N'oblige". I like that name. The dialogue itself is "I'd rather lick the bin [knock the bread from her hands]" - a jejune and obliviously mean-spirited interpretation of why the chaotic cringe comedy options in Disco were so much fun.</p>
<p>Your "Gonzo" option is: "Yeah, feed the masses! So let it be done. EAT UP, SKY RATS! (Take the bread)". You ever see a sentence that reads like someone wrote the exclamation points first and worked backwards from there? The attempts at understated philosophy feel just as unconvincing: "They give the filth on the ground a fighting chance to touch the sky. That's admirable".</p>
<p>I don't expect or even especially want a carbon copy of Disco Elysium from Hopetown, but if you're going to piggyback off the imagination of people that<a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/disco-elysium-studio-bosses-humiliated-the-cancelled-expansions-lead-writer-for-speaking-to-journalists-claims-report"> have allegedly had their work stolen from them</a>, apparently justified by the sole contribution of a lone systems designer from an outsourced studio (who I'm sure is excellent at their job and likely had no say in the "spiritual successor" marketing angle), I think you should probably make a more convincing attempt to better understand the spirit you're succeeding.</p>
<p>Still, bloody gorgeous art. And, look, I'm obviously cherrypicking lines out of context from a single screenshot. I'd be very happy to be eat crow for doubting pigeons here. If not, there's always two <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/yet-another-studio-formed-of-disco-elysium-alumni-has-announced-a-cerebral-sci-fi-rpg-just-to-confuse-you">others</a> anyway.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch Online adds Mario, Donkey Kong classics]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-switch-online-adds-mario-donkey-kong-classics</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-switch-online-adds-mario-donkey-kong-classics.1127841/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-switch-online-adds-mario-donkey-kong-classics<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>Two more Game Boy titles land.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/(423)-Game-Boy-%E2%80%93-March-2025-%E2%80%93-Nintendo-Switch-Online-00-00-10-(1).png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Nintendo</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Nintendo has added two more Game Boy titles to its Switch Online subscription catalogue - and you can play them right now. 
</p>
<p>
1994 classic Donkey Kong is the star of the show here - the highly-regarded puzzle platformer that serves as a continuation of the classic DK arcade game, with elements of Donkey Kong Jr, and also the subsequent Mario vs Donkey Kong titles.
</p>
<p>
If you've never played it before, there's a fun surprise after the first four levels - which are the ones found in the original Donkey Kong arcade cabinet. It's safe to say the game is bigger than just those.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Game Boy – March 2025 – Nintendo Switch Online" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Nna-zWXRjcg?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Game Boy – March 2025 – Nintendo Switch Online</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Nna-zWXRjcg?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/Nna-zWXRjcg?autoplay=1" title="Game Boy – March 2025 – Nintendo Switch Online">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Nna-zWXRjcg" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>
Also available today is Mario's Picross - which is, as you'd expect, Picross puzzles to colour in based on Mario and Mushroom Kingdom designs. Originally released for Game Boy in 1995, this was one of the earliest Picross games, and the first to the west.
</p>
<p>
We're now just one month away from finding out more about <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/its-official-nintendo-switch-2-revealed-after-months-of-waiting">Nintendo Switch 2</a>, when Nintendo lifts the lid on its next console via a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-announces-timing-of-its-dedicated-switch-2-direct">special Nintendo Direct livestream on 2nd April</a>. If you're a Nintendo Switch Online subscriber, the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-confirms-backwards-compatibility-for-switch-2">Switch 2's backwards compatibility</a> suggests you'll be able to continue playing your classic games.
</p>
<p>
You can check out the full run down of everything available on Nintendo's subscription service via our <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/all-nintendo-switch-online-games-available-to-play-right-now">handy guide detailing all the Nintendo Switch Online games available to play</a> right now.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Sinking City 2 Shows Off Gameplay and Launches Kickstarter Campaign]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/the-sinking-city-2-shows-off-gameplay-and-launches-kickstarter-campaign/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-sinking-city-2-shows-off-gameplay-and-launches-kickstarter-campaign.1127835/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/the-sinking-city-2-shows-off-gameplay-and-launches-kickstarter-campaign/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>It's been exactly a year since Frogwares <a href="https://wccftech.com/the-sinking-city-2-goes-to-kickstarter-soon-as-frogwares-needs-a-safety-net-from-the-war/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">told</a> its fans that The Sinking City 2 would get a Kickstarter funding campaign. Back then, the Ukrainian studio aimed to launch it shortly, but clearly, there were some hiccups.</p>
<p>The campaign is finally <a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/frogwares/the-sinking-city-2?ref=discovery_category&amp;total_hits=21544&amp;category_id=35" target="_blank" rel="noopener">live</a>, though, and its minimum goal of €100K has already been nearly doubled as of this writing. So far, Frogwares has not shared any info on the stretch goals, but they're sure to come with 29 days left in the campaign.</p>
<p><iframe title="The Sinking City 2 - Developer Deep Dive" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/jN0mNkrXHJc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Wael Amr, CEO of Frogwares, said in a statement:</p>
<p><em>After 3 years of this horrid war hanging over our daily lives, we've learned to adapt, though it has never been easy. In 2023 when we released Sherlock Holmes The Awakened with the help of Kickstarter and our loving fans, we built ourselves a safety net that saved us more than once. From power outages and the need for team members to relocate on short notice, to having to pause development for days, this safety net was crucial. Given that The Sinking City 2 is a far more complex and demanding game, we’ve decided to take the same route as before.</em></p>
<p>Frogwares Publishing Director Sergiy Oganesyan also spoke about the previously <a href="https://wccftech.com/the-sinking-city-2-announcement-ue5-horror-frogwares-deliver-ukraine-war/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced</a> slight genre change, moving away from adventure to a full-fledged horror title:</p>
<p><em>When we announced The Sinking City 2 back in 2024, we stated this is going to be our chance to shift our studio into creating games that are more “horror first” focused and the results we’re all seeing internally are extremely promising. We’re not ditching our investigation roots entirely, but the chance to spread and challenge our norms has really helped the team grow. We’ve placed combat and exploration first while still keeping an air of investigation that adds depth but is entirely optional.</em></p>
<p><iframe title="The Sinking City 2 - Gameplay Reveal &amp; Kickstarter Now Live!" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/AtyEOb2IBZQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>The Sinking City 2 is being made with Unreal Engine 5 and will launch on PC (Steam, Epic Games Store, GOG), PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series S|X.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>