<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 15:07:58 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Game of the Year 2025 – Best Remake]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/12/15/game-of-the-year-2025-best-remake/</link>
            <guid>1383460</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>It seems just like yesterday we were handing out our Game of the Year 2024 awards, but time has passed and another year is close to wrapping up. Which means it is time for our Game of the Year 2025 Awards! We are starting this year’s awards with one that is the epitome of the saying “everything old is new again”, and that is the Best Remake Award! Which game has come back from years past to grab our attention again?</p>

<p>What could be a better winner than <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/10/29/dragon-quest-i-ii-hd-2d-remake-review/">Dragon Quest I &amp; II HD-2D Remake</a> for this award? This package takes us back to the very beginning of Dragon Quest, the origin point of a franchise that has enamoured millions of fans around the world, and done it in such style with the use of the HD-2D engine bringing new life to two classics.</p>


<p>It is not just the way Dragon Quest I &amp; II HD-2D Remake looks that make it our winner this year. Both games were essentially rebuilt and expanding, adding new stories, party members, changes to the battle system, as well as an orchestral soundtrack. Not only does this remake offer something new to newcomers, older fans of Dragon Quest get a new experience with the remake.</p>
<p>Dragon Quest I &amp; II HD-2D Remake is so good in fact that the only negative thing we could find when reviewing it was that progression could be vague. Other than that, the total package offered and the improvements has made Dragon Quest I &amp; II HD-2D Remake our Best Remake of 2025.</p>

<h4>Yooka-Replaylee – Runner Up</h4>
<p>Back in 2017, Yooka-Laylee promised to bring back the 3D collectathon platformer in the vein of Banjo-Kazooie. It succeeded, in some ways, but the original release didn’t quite live up to being a bird and bear’s spiritual successor. Instead of letting things lie, Playtonic Games decided to remake the game and re-release it as <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/10/24/yooka-replaylee-review-banjos-tribute-act-gets-their-encore/">Yooka-Replaylee</a>. What we got was an experience where the potential of the original release was finally realised with major gameplay improvements and more content.</p>
<p>Yooka-Replaylee is a remake that does what a good remake should, and that is vastly improve upon what came before. Quality of life changes has made Yooka and Laylee’s adventure much more friendly for players, which makes it appealing to young and old players alike.</p>
<h4>The Talos Principle Reawakened – Runner Up</h4>
<p>How do you improve upon one of the most critically acclaimed puzzle games of all time? Ten years ago <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/04/10/the-talos-principle-reawakened-review-more-in-heaven-and-earth-than-your-philosophy/">The Talos Principle</a> was released to huge acclaim, and this year Croteam re-released the game after upgrading it to Unreal Engine 5, and taking the opportunity to update other parts of the game as well. What we got is a game that retains all of the excellence the original had combining it with a fresh new look, the Road to Gehenna and the new chapter In the Beginning, which added a good few more hours’ worth of gameplay.</p>
<p>Perhaps the biggest addition to The Talos Principle Reawakened is the Puzzle Editor, allowing the community to create and share their own challenges with others. That alone makes this remake bigger than the original, as it provides fans with a possible endless supply of content. And providing ways to keep a much loved game active for the long term should be applauded.</p>
<p><strong>Honourable mentions (in alphabetical order)</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><span data-sheets-root="1">The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion Remastered</span></li>
<li><span data-sheets-root="1">Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater</span></li>
</ul>
<p><em>That’s all for today’s award. Come back for tomorrow’s Best Narrative award, and all the tall tales that video games can tell.</em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/12/15/game-of-the-year-2025-best-remake/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Not Everyone Is Excited That Leon Is Back In Resident Evil Requiem]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/resident-evil-requiem-leon-kennedy-grace-playable-split-2000653406</link>
            <guid>1383448</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><span>After weeks of rumors, speculation, and leaks, Capcom confirmed at last week’s Game Awards ceremony that </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/capcom-leon-kennedy-is-playable-in-resident-evil-requiem-re9-game-awards-2000652755"><span>Leon Kennedy is returning in </span><i><span>Resident Evil Requiem</span></i></a><span> as a playable character. The older version of the Raccoon City cop will co-lead the upcoming survival horror game alongside new hero Grace Ashcroft when it launches on February 27. For some, this reveal was a moment of celebration, as Leon is a fan-favorite character who hasn’t been playable in a mainline game since 2012’s </span><i><span>Resident Evil 6 </span></i><span>(though he’s playable in two of Capcom’s more recent remakes), but for others, the fact that Grace doesn’t have the spotlight to herself is a disappointment.</span></p> <p><span>Ever since </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/onimusha-way-sword-pragmata-resident-evil-9-preview-2000618849"><i><span>Requiem</span></i></a><span>’s surprise announcement at Summer Game Fest, the game</span> <span>has been marketed as Grace’s story, one that would </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/resident-evil-requiem-9-2-4-horror-scary-grace-2000630216"><span>lean into a more survival horror/puzzle-centric playstyle</span></a><span>. So imagine everyone’s surprise when Leon showed up with a small arsenal, his trademark cheesy one-liners, and much more action-focused gameplay. Capcom says that </span><i><span>Requiem</span></i><span> will be a </span><a href="https://www.famitsu.com/article/202512/60614"><span>roughly 50/50 split</span></a><span> between the two characters, which sounds like a good way to keep the game from getting stale, at least. But some feel that </span><i><span>Resident Evil </span></i><span>is leaning too heavily on its original cast of characters, and that the series</span> <span>could use some new blood.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <p><span>After two games starring the deliberately nondescript Ethan Winters, and most of the games before that passing the protagonist ball back and forth between Leon, Jill Valentine, and the Redfield siblings, fans were excited about Grace and </span><i><span>Resident Evil </span></i><span>putting the spotlight on a relative unknown. She has ties to previous games through her mother Alyssa Ashcroft, who appeared in the </span><i><span>Outbreak </span></i><span>games, but Grace is the first new </span><i><span>Resident Evil </span></i><span>hero in a hot minute. So some fans are a little disappointed that she’ll be sharing the spotlight with one of the series’ biggest names.</span></p>

 <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="und" dir="ltr">oh <a href="https://t.co/NxPWf4wABN">https://t.co/NxPWf4wABN</a> <a href="https://t.co/hg0daoQ3Ca">pic.twitter.com/hg0daoQ3Ca</a></p> <p>— ୨୧ (@redfieldcode) <a href="https://twitter.com/redfieldcode/status/1999926697878245588?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 13, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">me wanting the horror experience with a female protagonist and then suddenly i have to complete a section with bad driving and corny jokes <a href="https://t.co/BBZiiK79bK">https://t.co/BBZiiK79bK</a> <a href="https://t.co/RyfYksRb77">pic.twitter.com/RyfYksRb77</a></p> <p>— nunu (@ijbolyuri) <a href="https://twitter.com/ijbolyuri/status/2000151672509874496?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 14, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">This is supposed to be about Grace, now im seeing people bring up that Leon is there because he's ger father. Suddenly shes getting all the hate and we've not even played as her yet. This is ridiculous, Leon makes people blind and dumb to anything but him. <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/REBHFun?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#REBHFun</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/ResidentEvil?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#ResidentEvil</a> <a href="https://t.co/wdFrQQOyde">pic.twitter.com/wdFrQQOyde</a></p> <p>— Biohazard_RPD (@JillRpd) <a href="https://twitter.com/JillRpd/status/1998867143824478617?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 10, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <p><span>“Leon is gonna overshadow Grace, which sucks,” oliviaplays08 </span><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/residentevil/comments/1pkmg92/now_that_its_100_confirmed_how_do_you_honestly/"><span>wrote on Reddit</span></a><span>. “Grace is officially the protag, but Leon probably got far more attention from Capcom as the ‘fan favorite.’”</span></p>

 <p><span>“I like Leon, I just hope Grace isn’t another damsel for him to rescue and can stand on her own as a strong well written character,” Nikolai508 wrote in the same thread.</span></p> <p><span>Some fans speculate that Capcom anticipated some fans would start ignoring Grace once their favorite rookie cop, who has officially undergone </span><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/lgbt/comments/1ctqo8z/what_is_twink_death/"><span>twink death</span></a><span>, would be a co-protagonist, and that’s why they didn’t lead with him in the early trailers and marketing. Even now that the cat’s out of the bag, the company has been referring to the presence of the two characters as representing </span><a href="https://x.com/RE_Games/status/1999317087034950074?s=20"><span>“two generations”</span></a><span> of survival horror coming together. Perhaps </span><i><span>Requiem </span></i><span>will be a story of Leon “passing the torch” to a new hero, with future </span><i><span>Resident Evil </span></i><span>games focusing on new characters moving forward. If so, maybe Grace will take on a solo leading role in a hypothetical </span><i><span>Resident Evil 10</span></i><span>, or at least work alongside someone who hasn’t been in these games for 30 years. Hopefully, that means Leon gets a cushy retirement plan rather than meeting a grimmer outcome that might take him off the board for future games.</span></p> <p><span>While some folks are doubtful about the decision, others are just happy to see Leon back and for </span><i><span>Requiem </span></i><span>to seemingly be scratching the itch for both an action-oriented </span><i><span>Resident Evil </span></i><span>and a more tense, horror-driven one. I understand the initial disappointment some are feeling, but I’m open to </span><i><span>Requiem </span></i><span>being an origin story that allows </span><i><span>Resident Evil </span></i><span>to explore new characters without being burdened by the past. We’ll see how it all plays out on February 27.</span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/resident-evil-requiem-leon-kennedy-grace-playable-split-2000653406]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This Week’s Saturday Night Live Was Drowning In Grim AI Slop]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/snl-ai-slop-saturday-night-live-nbc-2000653399</link>
            <guid>1383445</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p id="featured-image">
                              <figure id="attachment_featured" aria-describedby="featured-caption">
                                                                          <figcaption id="featured-caption">
                    <span>An image from SNL, with an AI woman at a slot machine.</span> © NBC / Kotaku
                  </figcaption>
                </figure>
                                                      </p><div>
              
              <p>One of the huge joys of&nbsp;<em>Saturday Night Live</em> over the last 50 years has been the extraordinary level of craft that goes into every episode. The sketches might often suck, but the sets, costumes and make-up will be incredible, despite the long-experienced crew often having less than 24 hours notice of what needs to be prepared. It’s been a stunning achievement for five decades, which makes this week’s episode’s extensive use of AI slop an extraordinary letdown.</p> <p>From the opening moment of the Josh O’Connor-hosted episode, it looked like AI art was being used in place of the usually superb creations of the long-running show’s incredible prop and design team. A storybook with a poem loosely in the style of <em>The Night Before Christmas</em>, leading up to a cold-open with Trump giving interviews on Air Force One, was illustrated with artwork that looked incredibly likely to be AI-generated. While not egregiously bad, little details appear to give the game away, like the suddenly broken path in a picture of a snowy village:</p>

 <figure id="attachment_2000653400" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000653400"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000653400">© NBC / Kotaku</figcaption></figure> <p>And this girl’s frighteningly thin leg and then entirely missing second foot:</p> <figure id="attachment_2000653401" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000653401"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000653401">© NBC / Kotaku</figcaption></figure> <p>Plus it all just has that&nbsp;<em>look</em>, that sheen that rings hollow. As soon as it appeared on screen it looked off to me, and I remember thinking how disappointing it is to see a real artist denied the chance to draw something lovely for the show.</p>

 <p>Things became more egregious during Weekend Update, where the usually amusingly poor Photoshops and stock images that appear over Colin Jost and Michael Che’s shoulders were replaced with extremely suss slop. A gag about a horse on a plane received this image that—in fairness—looks like the usual amusingly slapdash Photoshopping, until you look a bit closer at details like the foreheads of the people in the rows behind. And then what might be an attempt to remove the horse’s genitals, but it’s damned weird.</p>

 <figure id="attachment_2000653402" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000653402"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000653402">© NBC / Kotaku</figcaption></figure> <p>More obvious was the image of a woman on O2 at a slot machine, seen at the top of this post. The hose doesn’t actually touch the O2 canister, the slot machine is weirdly shaped, and the lights and buttons are all irregular shapes.</p> <p>Alongside these, there was an almost certainly AI-generated image of a man taking off an Elsa costume, and the most horrifically poor rotating head of Kristi Noem in a joke based on&nbsp;<em>The Exorcist</em>. It all gave the usually fun segment of <em>SNL</em> a grim edge.</p>

 <figure id="attachment_2000653408" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000653408"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000653408">© NBC / Kotaku</figcaption></figure> <p>People on social media were quickly to call out the apparent AI, disappointed that a program known for its creativity would sink to smothering itself in AI slop. It presumably makes sense when a show is put together from start to finish in six days, with cold-opens and Weekend Update usually written in the final 24 hours before live broadcast, to try to find ways to speed up production, but cutting corners and replacing creative work with this kind of dross isn’t it.</p>

 <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">A lot of reasons why SNL using AI for stuff like this sucks, but my main gripe is just that it’s less funny! The intentionally kind of janky photoshops are part of the joke and beat the weird smooth AI aesthetic. <a href="https://t.co/ZBBoXQSgUS">pic.twitter.com/ZBBoXQSgUS</a></p> <p>— Josh Billinson (@jbillinson) <a href="https://twitter.com/jbillinson/status/2000212581206655450?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 14, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <p>It was more of a shame given that this was, overall, a decent episode of the hit-and-miss show. Lily Allen was a great musical guest, and appeared in a fun and silly sketch spoofing her own on-the-nose lyrics, Bowen Yang <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=l1sTpOSv8XU">reprised one of his creepiest characters</a>, and this sketch of the most sensitive bachelorette strippers was the funniest of the night:</p>

  <p>Plus Jane Wickline did another of her adorable Weekend Update songs, this time about the greatest threat to the survival of humanity:</p>  <p>Yeah, most of the show’s sketches are overlong duds, and sure,&nbsp;<em>you</em> stopped watching years ago, but&nbsp;<em>SNL</em> remains a crucial fixture in comedy, still creating viral sketches and beginning the careers of many of the best comedians. It also boasts one of the most talented behind-the-scenes crews in television, and to see their talents eschewed for AI slop is devastating. <em>SNL</em>, don’t do that; be better.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/snl-ai-slop-saturday-night-live-nbc-2000653399]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Resident Evil Requiem is ‘Almost Like Having Two Games’, Says Director]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/resident-evil-requiem-is-almost-like-having-two-games-says-director/</link>
            <guid>1383439</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Resident Evil Requiem director has arrived with new details about the upcoming title after their big reveal at The Game Awards 2025, stating it’s almost like playing two games. </p>



<p>Capcom has kept a lot of stuff under wraps since Resident Evil Requiem was revealed, with Leon Kennedy being playable as the biggest secret of them all. However, we had an idea from the leaks, but confirmation was required. Now that Leon has been officially <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/resident-evil-requiem-leon-kennedy-the-game-awards-trailer/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">confirmed</a>, the director has revealed how the gameplay of both characters contrasts. </p>







<h2 id="h-resident-evil-requiem-s-leon-and-grace-sections-are-almost-equally-split-but-heavily-differ-from-each-other">Resident Evil Requiem’s Leon and Grace Sections are ‘Almost Equally Split’, But Heavily Differ From Each Other</h2>



<p>During a new interview with <a href="https://automaton-media.com/en/interviews/resident-evil-requiems-dual-protagonist-system-will-be-like-repeatedly-jumping-into-a-cold-bath-after-a-hot-sauna-we-ask-the-devs-about-leons-role-and-re4-style/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Automaton</a>, Resident Evil Requiem director Akifumi Nakanishi&nbsp;spoke about Leon and Grace’s gameplay, along with other details. Nakanishi first revealed that “in terms of gameplay, Grace and Leon’s playable sections are almost equally split,” with the structure being similar to Revelations. The director added that Leon isn’t “well suited to horror”, hence his sections “focus on intense, adrenaline-pumping action”. Grace has the scarier sections, and the devs are “really emphasizing the difference in their experiences this time.”</p>



<p>Nakanishi explains that the two experiences are “almost like having two games with completely different types of tension mixed together.” Players would feel like “jumping into a cold bath after sitting in a hot sauna,” he said while laughing. The director also revealed that Leon’s chapters are where the players will feel safer and scared again when Grace comes back on. It is a “consciously designed horror structure,” he stated. </p>







<p>In other news, Resident Evil Code Veronica and Zero Remakes are <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/resident-evil-code-veronica-and-zero-remakes-scheduled-for-2027-2028-respectively-its-claimed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">reportedly scheduled for 2027 and 2028</a>, respectively. Additionally, Requiem might have <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/resident-evil-requiem-leak-reveal-new-playable-character/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">another playable character</a>. What are your thoughts on Resident Evil Requiem feeling like almost two different games? Leave your thoughts down in the comments, and join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/stellar-bladed-director-recognition-president/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Stellar Blade director receiving recognition from the South Korean president</a>.&nbsp;Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/resident-evil-requiem-is-almost-like-having-two-games-says-director/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Resident Evil Code Veronica and Zero Remakes Scheduled for 2027 & 2028 Respectively, It’s Claimed]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/resident-evil-code-veronica-and-zero-remakes-scheduled-for-2027-2028-respectively-its-claimed/</link>
            <guid>1383436</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Resident Evil insider has revealed details about the release windows for Code Veronica and Zero Remakes. </p>



<p>Based on insider information, it was already known that the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/resident-evil-code-veronica-and-zero-are-next-two-remakes-insider-claims/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">next remakes</a> in development for the Resident Evil franchise are allegedly Code Veronica and Zero. The insider had also revealed earlier that these games are scheduled for <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/next-resident-evil-remakes-are-releasing-in-2027-2028-its-claimed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">2027/2028</a>, but didn’t have exact details. Now, he is back with more. </p>







<h2 id="h-resident-evil-code-veronica-remake-will-reportedly-be-announced-next-year-and-release-in-2027">Resident Evil Code Veronica Remake Will Reportedly be Announced Next Year, And Release in 2027</h2>



<p>The new details about Resident Evil Code Veronica and Zero Remakes come from a prominent insider, Dusk Golem. Most recently, their highly anticipated leak about <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/resident-evil-requiem-leon-kennedy-the-game-awards-trailer/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Leon being playable</a> in Requiem was proven to be true through a new trailer at The Game Awards 2025. Now they are back with a new scoop, this time providing us with the announcement and release windows for the next remakes in the franchise. </p>



<p>According to Dusk Golem’s new post on <a href="https://x.com/aestheticgamer1/status/1999736688848113831" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">X</a> (formerly Twitter), they have heard that Code Veronica will be announced in 2026 and released in 2027. The Zero Remake is scheduled to release in 2028. Readers should take this information with a grain of salt, as there is no official announcement regarding these release windows, and they may change depending on how development progresses. </p>







<p>Back in October 2025, it was reportedly revealed that Resident Evil 0 Remake is in development under the nickname ‘<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/resident-evil-0-remake-report/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Chamber</a>‘ and won’t be released until 2028. Additionally, Resident Evil Requiem leak suggests there’s <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/resident-evil-requiem-leak-reveal-new-playable-character/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">another playable character</a>. Do you think Resident Evil Code Veronica and Zero remakes will be released in 2027 and 2028, respectively? Leave your thoughts down in the comments, and join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/stellar-bladed-director-recognition-president/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Stellar Blade director receiving recognition from the South Korean president</a>.&nbsp;Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/resident-evil-code-veronica-and-zero-remakes-scheduled-for-2027-2028-respectively-its-claimed/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Invincible VS Gets April Release Date Alongside 'Ella Mental' Character Reveal In Gameplay Trailer]]></title>
            <link>https://gameinformer.com/the-game-awards-2025/2025/12/15/invincible-vs-gets-april-release-date-alongside-ella-mental</link>
            <guid>1383433</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p><a href="https://gameinformer.com/product/invincible-vs">Invincible VS</a> is bringing Robert Kirkman's critically acclaimed superhero comic/animated series to the video game fighting space, and the latest trailer reveals that it launches on April 30 on PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X/S, and PC. That same trailer also reveals Ella Mental, an all-new original character who will be making her <em>Invincible</em> universe debut in Invincible VS when it launches next year.&nbsp;</p><p>The trailer, which debuted at <a href="https://gameinformer.com/the-game-awards-2025/2025/12/11/every-winner-at-the-game-awards-2025-the-complete-list">The Game Awards 2025</a>, highlights Ella Mental's abilities to command earth, wind, fire, and water after discovering an ancient family totem that grants her superpowers. She will be voiced by rapper Tierra Whack, too.&nbsp;</p><p><strong>Check out Ella Mental in the latest Invincible VS trailer below:&nbsp;</strong></p><p height="360" width="640" url="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rzPTZAj014U"><iframe width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rzPTZAj014U" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay" allowfullscreen="true">&nbsp;</iframe></p><p>"Created by <em>Invincible</em> co-creators Robert Kirkman and Cory Walker, Ella Mental's story begins as an heiress to her family's fortune," a press release reads. "Known for being studious and hardworking, she becomes her grandfather's favorite and gains access to his inheritance, where she discovers an ancient totem that grants her superpowers."&nbsp;</p><p>In the press release, Tierra Whack, Ella Mental's voice actor, says, "When I was reading the role for Ella Mental, it felt just like I was reading about myself; it felt divine. We're so alike. She's powerful, she's strong, and she knows what she wants. She's a trailblazer, and as an <em>Invincible</em> fan, I'm so excited to get to voice her."&nbsp;</p><p>Ella Mental is one of the 18 playable fighters available in Invincible VS when it launches in April. She joins the likes of Invincible himself, Mark Grayson, Thula, Bulletproof, Atom Eve, Rex Splode, Omni-Man, Battle Beast, Cecil Stedman, Robot, and Monster Girl.&nbsp;</p><p>While waiting for Invincible VS, read <a href="https://gameinformer.com/preview/2025/06/10/a-faithfully-bloody-adaptation"><em>Game Informer's </em>hands-on preview</a> of the game, and then <a href="https://gameinformer.com/preview/2025/10/09/cecil-joins-the-roster-new-story-details-and-an-original-character-arrives">check out this preview</a> for more details about Cecil.&nbsp;</p><hr><p><em>Are you checking out Invincible VS when it launches in April? Let us know in the comments below!</em></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://gameinformer.com/the-game-awards-2025/2025/12/15/invincible-vs-gets-april-release-date-alongside-ella-mental]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Here's where Tomb Raider: Catalyst sits on the series timeline]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/heres-where-tomb-raider-catalyst-sits-on-the-series-timeline</link>
            <guid>1383430</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>

  <figure>
      <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Lara-Croft-in-Tomb-Raider-Catalyst_jkGViUg.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Lara-Croft-in-Tomb-Raider-Catalyst_jkGViUg.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Lara-Croft-in-Tomb-Raider-Catalyst_jkGViUg.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Lara-Croft-in-Tomb-Raider-Catalyst_jkGViUg.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Lara-Croft-in-Tomb-Raider-Catalyst_jkGViUg.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Lara-Croft-in-Tomb-Raider-Catalyst_jkGViUg.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Lara-Croft-in-Tomb-Raider-Catalyst_jkGViUg.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Lara-Croft-in-Tomb-Raider-Catalyst_jkGViUg.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Lara-Croft-in-Tomb-Raider-Catalyst_jkGViUg.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Crystal Dynamics</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>The Tomb Raider: Catalyst team has confirmed where the upcoming game sits in the series timeline.</p>
<p>According to game director Will Kerslake, Catalyst - <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/next-tomb-raider-game-known-as-catalyst-finally-revealed-at-the-game-awards">which will see the globe trotting Lara Croft heading to Northern India</a> - takes place after <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/tomb-raider-underworld">Tomb Raider: Underworld</a>. That's the game where Lara pops along to Helheim whilst wielding Thor's hammer, Mjolnir.</p>
<!-- code from Primis - Eurogamer.net - eurogamer.net -->
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<!-- code from Primis -->
<p>"From a timeline perspective, Tomb Raider: Catalyst is set years after the events of Tomb Raider: Underworld," <a href="https://www.gamesradar.com/games/tomb-raider/tomb-raider-catalyst-picks-up-years-after-2008s-underworld-finally-continuing-lara-crofts-story-from-the-legend-trilogy-after-almost-two-decades/">Kerslake told GamesRadar+</a>. He added the more recently concluded Survivor reboot trilogy, which saw Lara taking on Trinity in the likes of Siberia and South America, will still serve as Lara's origin story.</p>
<p>"So we're seeing a more experienced Lara Croft," the Catalyst developer said, before adding you won't need to have played or hold a deep knowledge of the other <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/tomb-raider-games-order">Tomb Raider games</a> to be able to follow along.</p>
<p>"What's important to know is that this is a new chapter in Tomb Raider," he stated. "So whether you followed Lara from the start, or this is your first Tomb Raider game, Tomb Raider: Catalyst is designed to stand on its own as an adventure that can be enjoyed by everyone."</p>
<p>If you want a visual representation of how Catalyst and the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/fully-fledged-from-the-ground-up-tomb-raider-remake-announced">newly-announced Legacy of Atlantis remake</a> fit into the unified Tomb Raider timeline, you can check out the infographic by <a href="https://x.com/FeoUltima">@FeoUltima</a> below.</p>
<figure>
 


<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>@FeoUltima/X</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Tomb Raider: Legacy of Atlantis is due to release next year, while Tomb Raider: Catalyst will be arriving on PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X/S and Steam in 2027.  </p>
<p>Over the weekend, Lara Croft actress Camilla Luddington passed her bow and arrows over to Alix Wilton Regan, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/lara-croft-actress-camilla-luddington-bids-farewell-to-tomb-raider-as-alix-wilton-regan-teases-were-just-getting-started">sharing a farewell post to the character she had embodied for 10 years</a>. "The Survivor Trilogy was a decade of adventure I will never ever forget," Luddington wrote. "I could not be prouder of what we created."</p>

        </div>

  
      </article>



  



  

  <section>
    <span>Related topics</span>

    
  </section>
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/heres-where-tomb-raider-catalyst-sits-on-the-series-timeline]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Rise And Fall of Queer Cartoons]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/queer-cartoons-elon-musk-libsoftiktok-dogs-in-space-netflix/</link>
            <guid>1383424</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
      <p>A little while back, conservatives discovered the existence of cartoons, but only their existence. What they do not know, and perhaps can’t know, is that for a brief moment cartoons got really good, and really gay, and now they are dying.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><p>Now, I’ll be using the term ‘cartoons’ here, but when I do I’ll be referring to animated content released commercially for children and early teenagers in English-speaking countries. The term definitely excludes many things that are obviously cartoons: <em>The Simpsons</em>, <em>Neon Genesis Evangelion</em>, <em>Arcane,</em> <em>Scavengers Reign</em>, even <em>Bluey</em> since its core audience is too young. It’s cartoons as in ‘Saturday morning cartoon’: thirty minutes long if you count commercials, narrative-based, usually with other concerns like a toy line, with an audience who are older than toddlers but younger than teenagers.</p><p>On September 29th of 2025, the X account LibsofTikTok, run by former real estate agent Chaya Raichik, discovered the Netflix show <em>Dead End Paranormal Park</em>, which had been cancelled in 2023 after two seasons. In a short clip, the show’s lead character Barney talks about how working at a haunted amusement park allows him to be himself rather than just the one trans kid at his school. Having seen the show, Barney’s gender is mentioned at most a handful of times, the word ‘trans’ might only appear in the clip that Raichik excerpted.</p><p>A day later, Raichik posted a video sourced from Instagram in which a man with a British accent films his TV playing the Netflix show <em>Jurassic Park: Camp Cretaceous</em>, a teen-centric sidequel to the film Jurassic World in which a group of teenagers try to survive on Isla Nublar while Chris Pratt is riding motorcycles and the like. In the clip, the character Yasmina confesses that she’s fallen for the character Sammy—they are both female. The adult watching the cartoon whines ‘lord have mercy.’ The final season of this show aired in 2022.&nbsp;</p><p>Elon Musk encouraged his followers to ‘<a href="https://x.com/elonmusk/status/1973292474375479556?ref=aftermath.site"><u>Cancel Netflix for the health of your kids</u></a>’ shortly after Raichik shared the clips above. Culture war content isn’t exactly uncommon on Musk’s account, though it is often submerged by his genuinely side-splitting comedy and cutting-edge memes, but what are rare are references to children, childcare or fatherhood. Musk is the world’s foremost pronatalist: he believes that the world is dangerously underpopulated and that we should be ‘teach(ing) fear of childlessness’, and yet it doesn’t seem to interest him.&nbsp;</p><p>You already know <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2025/feb/25/elon-musk-pronatalism-mothers-social-media-parenting?ref=aftermath.site"><u>what he is doing personally to solve this problem</u></a>, but something he never does is talk about his own experiences as a father. As Joyce Carol Oates has pointed out, despite posting on average <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/EnoughMuskSpam/comments/1fjrunp/elon_musks_outofcontrol_tweeting_habits_i/?ref=aftermath.site"><u>68 times per day</u></a>, he never talks about anything remotely human: ‘pride in a friend’s or relative’s accomplishment; condolences for someone who has died; pleasure in sports; acclaim for a favorite team; references to history’. More important than any of that: somebody with an estimated fourteen children never talks about them. Obviously security and privacy concerns mean that he can’t share everything, but he never posts a picture one of his children drew or a celebration of good grades.&nbsp;</p><p>The fact that he was surprised by the content of years-old Netflix cartoons points to something else: he doesn’t have much interest in what his own children are interested in, and it appears that few conservatives do. In this case, it means that his calls to #cancelnetflix fail to take into account the sweeping changes that have changed the cartoon industry into something unrecognisable.</p><figure><figcaption><span>Dogs in Space/Netflix</span></figcaption></figure><p>You can separate kids cartoons into rough phases. The first was the Golden Age of Saturday Morning cartoons: <em>Transformers, G.I Joe, She-Ra </em>and<em> Thundercats</em>. These were almost always tied to a toy line—they were functionally commercials, with plots dictated largely by what stock needed to be moved in a given quarter. That didn’t stop them from being incredibly popular: although viewing figures are difficult to come by because of the nature of how they were syndicated, we can see their impact through toy sales: <a href="https://www.seibertron.com/transmissions/poor-sales-may-deal-toy-robots-fatal-blow/18246/?ref=aftermath.site"><u>Hasbro made $950 million from the Transformers franchise alone in the 1980s</u></a>.&nbsp;</p><p>The second stage I don’t want to call the Silver Age, because that implies a level of value that it didn’t have. Throughout the nineties and into the early 2000s cartoons tried, mostly unsuccessfully, to replicate the success of the eighties shows. Remember <em>Exo Force</em>, <em>Pirates of Dark Water, Biker Mice from Mars or SWAT Cats</em>? With this model exhausted, new creators who wanted to make cartoons first and move product second entered the scene thanks to newly established networks like Nickelodeon and Cartoon Network, producing cult hits like <em>Ren and Stimpy</em> and breakout successes like <em>Spongebob Squarepants</em>.&nbsp;</p><p><em>Avatar: The Last Airbender</em> was an anomaly during this time. Though it was Nickelodeon shows like <em>Rugrats</em> and <em>Fairly Odd Parents</em>, it was tonally different from almost everything else out there. You could even call it a continuation of the failed experiments of animation’s not-quite silver age: long-form stories with a large cast, a more adult approach to morality, complex worldbuilding, as well as a very clear attempt to bring anime sensibilities into western animation. It was successful, not only critically but with audiences: <a href="https://www.theanimationblog.com/avatar-the-last-airbender-ratings-hit-all-time-high/?ref=aftermath.site"><u>5.6 million people watched its finale</u></a>, it launched <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-egQ79OrYCs&amp;ref=aftermath.site"><u>one bad live action adaptation</u></a>, one <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ByAn8DF8Ykk&amp;ref=aftermath.site"><u>okay live action adaptation</u></a> and will soon become a trilogy when <a href="https://variety.com/2025/tv/news/avatar-last-airbender-seven-havens-animated-series-nickelodeon-1236313495/?ref=aftermath.site"><u>Avatar: Seven Havens</u></a> debuts. It helped that <em>Avatar’s</em> release in 2005 came at the high point of the Young Adult fiction wave, so it didn’t seem that kids who were, say, thirteen to sixteen, had to choose between genuine children’s content and adult shows. It blazed a trail that nobody would follow for a long time—for almost a decade it remained the only show that tried to hit that sweet spot of children’s animation that teenagers and even adults could enjoy.</p><blockquote>In a short time it became uncommon to have long-form narrative animation without at least one queer character.</blockquote><p>If Avatar showed that kid’s shows could be blockbusters then 2006’s <em>Adventure Time</em> showed that they could be arthouse. Pendleton Ward’s ten minute long trips were deeply idiosyncratic, down to the strange cadence of the dialogue and the leisurely unfolding of what turned out to be one of the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qYXo8HxJj3Q&amp;ref=aftermath.site"><u>most complex and unique fantasy stories of the 21st century</u></a>, one that is <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uSbyC1A9KHk&amp;ref=aftermath.site"><u>still going two decades later</u></a>. I can’t say that the show has directly influenced anything else -except for <a href="https://www.cbr.com/adventure-time-chainsaw-man-crossover-illustration/?ref=aftermath.site"><u>Chainsaw Man</u></a>- but it has instead functioned as a <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2018/09/02/arts/television/adventure-time-animators-reflect-on-its-legacy.html?ref=aftermath.site"><u>talent incubator for a new generation of animators</u></a> (storyboard artist <a href="https://www.papermag.com/rebecca-sugar-noelle-stevenson?ref=aftermath.site#rebelltitem47"><u>Rebecca Sugar created <em>Stephen Universe</em></u></a>, for example) and a general call to the industry to raise its game. Also, while it was not the first <em>ever</em> cartoon to feature a queer couple (as far as I can tell that was <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jziWWARbG30&amp;ref=aftermath.site"><u><em>Hey Arnold </em>&nbsp;in 1998</u></a>), the centuries-long on-again-off-again <em>thing</em> between Princess Bubblegum and Marceline was the first involving main characters and not presented as a Very Special Episode.</p><p>In 2012, the Disney Channel released Alex Hirsch’s <em>Gravity Falls</em>. It’s rare that a single show can cause a paradigm shift in the industry—usually they come about from market over-saturation of the creation of new networks. <em>Gravity Falls </em>was different: it looked like a kids cartoon, but, speaking as an adult, it’s genuinely smart and funny. Kids could watch it, but teenagers would <em>get</em> it and adults would appreciate it. It wasn’t purely a cult phenomenon: the series finale, ‘Weirdmageddon’, <a href="https://www.bubbleblabber.com/2016/02/ratings-are-in-22316-gravity-falls-finale-sets-record-for-disney-xd/?ref=aftermath.site"><u>Disney reported</u></a>, was ‘a dominant #1 in its time period across all cable TV among Total Viewers, Kids 6-11, Boys 6-11 and Boys 2-11 demographics’.&nbsp;</p><p>While this was happening, a parallel development in young adult fiction would have ramifications for the cartoon industry: <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/2024/apr/30/more-than-a-quarter-of-readers-of-ya-are-over-the-age-of-28-research-shows?ref=aftermath.site"><u>adults were starting to read books written for teenagers</u></a>, which meant that books were being written for adults who wanted to read books for teenagers. The fandom for these books skewed&nbsp; female and <a href="https://www.researchgate.net/publication/365675750_Queer_Literary_Ecologies_and_Young_Adult_Literature?ref=aftermath.site"><u>queer</u></a>, and the publishing industry responded by <a href="https://www.publishersweekly.com/pw/by-topic/childrens/childrens-industry-news/article/93417-who-is-ya-for.html?ref=aftermath.site"><u>buying up books that appealed to this audience</u></a>. That seems to have made solid business sense: Young Adult fiction is <a href="https://www.thebookseller.com/spotlight/2024-young-adult-fiction--booktok-boom-continues-to-sound-for-ya?ref=aftermath.site"><u>still on an upward trajectory</u></a>, even without blockbusters like the Harry Potter franchise, thanks in part to the cross-pollination between YA and Romantasy and its promotion through BookTok.</p><p><em>Gravity Falls </em>and <em>Avatar: The Last Airbender</em> didn’t have any overt queer representation (<a href="https://screenrant.com/gravity-falls-disney-lgbtq-representation-alex-hirsch/?ref=aftermath.site"><u>Disney cut it out</u></a> from the former and it was only present in the sequel to the latter), but their tone and style pointed the way for shows like Cartoon Network’s <em>Steven Universe </em>and Netflix’s <em>She-Ra and the Princesses of Power</em>, which caught on like wildfire in the larger ‘fandom’ community. Pretty soon most significant cartoons married the deep storytelling of <em>Gravity Falls</em> and <em>Avatar: the Last Airbender</em> with themes, such as queer representation, reflecting the adult-YA community: <em>The Owl House</em>, <em>Centaurworld, Dogs in Space, Star vs. the Forces of Evil, Voltron: Legendary Defender, My Little Pony: Friendship is Magic, Amphibia, The Dragon Prince</em>, <em>Battle Kitty</em>, <em>Kipo and the Age of Wonderbeasts, Hilda, </em>and the aforementioned <em>Dead End Paranormal Park </em>and <em>Jurassic World: Camp Cretaceous</em>. In a short time it became uncommon to have long-form narrative animation without at least one queer character. Sometimes the representation was subtle, as in <em>Hilda</em> where they were background characters. Several shows, like <em>She-Ra and the Princesses of Power </em>and <em>The Owl House</em> had queer <em>main</em> characters and their love stories were key plot points.&nbsp;</p><p>Jeremiah Cortez was showrunner on Netflix’s <em>Dogs in Space </em>during this period. He grew up loving animation, took every class he could take on it in college, and drew free-form stories about a Corgi named Garbage’s adventures in space while working at a factory job (he had no emotional connection to dogs and didn’t like sci-fi so it felt like something he could do for fun, with no emotional connection). His co-workers liked it, which led to him producing a rough short, and a chance meeting led to the opportunity to pitch Netflix.</p><figure><figcaption><span>Dogs in Space/Netflix</span></figcaption></figure><p>“So I went to Netflix,” he told me, “pitched in person, and then left, and I just thought, like, yeah, they're not interested. It was nice that I got to go to the Netflix building and see inside, but I just took it as a nice opportunity, a nice experience. And I left, went back to my job. And then, yeah, about two weeks later, they called me again and said, hey, we want to buy the show.”</p><p>There was a good vibe at Netflix at the time: “Netflix was a great studio to work with when I was there. When I got there, that was the dream studio I wanted to go with. They really believed in what they were selling—Netflix was the place where the shows that other networks wouldn’t get picked up got picked up. They were the place where all the overlooked ideas can come and be a show.”</p><p>The studio was perfectly willing to take a chance on a first-time showrunner, and were collaborators with him rather than the cliche of out-of-touch studio executives handing down notes. The only major change they pushed for was casting Haley-Joel Osmet as Captain Garbage—Jeremiah would have preferred somebody with an older-sounding voice like Will Forte. When Osmet auditioned he nailed it and Jeremiah remains extremely happy with the performance.</p><p><em>Cuphead </em>and <em>Centaurworld</em> were both being made in the same Burbank studio, and both shared <em>Dogs’</em> adults-can-enjoy-it-too vibe. As Jeremiah tells it, this came from Netflix’s genuine desire to make the best shows possible, but there’s business logic there: children are a very small and very fickle demographic, but bringing in what would be traditionally regarded as more adult elements opens animated shows up to a larger audience that includes adults. We still see this today: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Zlmswo0S0e0&amp;t=18s&amp;ref=aftermath.site"><em><u>Hazbin Hotel</u></em></a> and <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OlahNrlcgS4&amp;ref=aftermath.site"><em><u>Helluva Boss</u></em></a>, both by Vivienne ‘VivziePop’ Medrano are definitely for adults in terms of swearing and sex references, but have the vibe of children’s cartoons in a way that other adult cartoons like <em>Scavengers Reign</em> and <em>King of the Hill</em> don’t. They seem made for the generation that was just the right age when <em>Gravity Falls</em>, <em>Adventure Time</em> and <em>Avatar: The Last Airbender</em> were at their peak and are now in their twenties and thirties.</p><blockquote>These shows were being made during a major shift in the way that children consumed entertainment.</blockquote><p>The second this golden age of animation became unprofitable it stopped. You can practically pin a date down to the very week this happened: on November 15th of 2024, ten days after Donald Trump’s second election, <a href="https://www.polygon.com/news/479614/disney-reportedly-pulls-marvels-moon-girl-and-dinosaur-episode-over-trans-athlete-story/?ref=aftermath.site"><u>Disney removed an episode of <em>Moon Girl and Devil Dinosaur</em></u></a> that dealt with trans athletes. It wasn’t the first show that a network had censored —Cartoon Network <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=a5Mt7S7U2KA&amp;ref=aftermath.site"><u>even fired somebody over the ‘Bubbleine’ romance</u></a>—but this time felt different. Disney wasn’t just giving notes to writers to keep things PG, they were actively removing a show that dealt with a very specific topic that conservatives are particularly focused on. That felt like the permissive, progressive attitude that had defined the late 2010s to early 2020s was officially over.</p><p>At nearly exactly the same time, the entire age of peak animation collapsed. There were <a href="https://luminatedata.com/blog/whats-driving-the-animated-tv-series-falloff/?ref=aftermath.site"><u>86 new children’s animated series orders on streaming platforms in 2022 and 113 overall</u></a>. In 2025, that number dropped to 24 on streaming and 35 overall. The only major new animated show for middle-childhood and teen viewers that debuted on streaming platforms in 2025 was Netflix’s <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QqDDuVe9dw8&amp;ref=aftermath.site"><em><u>The Wolf King</u></em></a>. My own son was growing up when these shows were airing, so I watched them with him. They were all genuinely good. The second Golden Age of animation was brief, but intense—<em>Over the Garden Wall</em> is, in my estimation, a classic; <em>Dogs in Space</em> and <em>Centaurworld</em> needed much bigger audiences than they got.&nbsp;</p><p>And that was the problem. These shows were being made during a major shift in the way that children consumed entertainment. A good portion of these shows were produced by Netflix, and the world’s largest streaming media company is <a href="https://www.nplusonemag.com/issue-49/essays/casual-viewing/?ref=aftermath.site"><u>notoriously bad at promoting its content</u></a>. Why should it bother when, being a subscription service, it doesn’t need anyone to actually <em>watch</em> its shows, just keep up their monthly payments?</p><p>This goes double for children’s shows: it is very difficult to actually promote children’s content. In times past you could rely on children being around on Saturday mornings and after school, watching whatever was on. Saturday morning cartoons ended on October 4th of 2014, when the <a href="https://gizmodo.com/this-is-the-first-weekend-in-america-with-no-saturday-m-1642441646?ref=aftermath.site"><u>CW ended Vortexx</u></a>, which had been holding out long after other networks had cancelled their Saturday morning shows, due largely to FCC regulations that mandated three hours of education programming a day on broadcast TV. Later, when viewers had to actively seek out shows on Netflix, and later Disney+, these companies didn’t have a marketing strategy beyond giving them prime spots on their own platforms and uploading trailers to YouTube. There was no place where you could put an advertisement for a relatively high-budget show like <em>Kipo and the Age of Wonderbeasts</em> that would establish ‘this is important’.&nbsp;</p><figure><figcaption><span>Centaurworld/Netflix</span></figcaption></figure><p>Obviously, some children’s content does break through. <em>K-Pop Demon Hunters</em> is a phenomenon, but Netflix’s efforts had little to do with that—marketing analysts might say that it ‘<a href="https://www.contentgrip.com/kpop-demon-hunters-viral-strategy/?ref=aftermath.site"><u>activated fandoms at scale</u></a>’, but viral clips like <a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DLqV_-XyNTd/?utm_source=ig_embed"><u>Jay from ENHYPHEN dancing to ‘Soda Pop’</u></a> came <em>after</em> the film had become successful, not before. What really happened was that enthusiasm spread virally because the film was always going to ‘activate’ the kind of people who are going to spread things virally—K-pop stans, TikTokkers, cosplayers and so on. Importantly, that level of viral success just doesn’t seem to happen for serialised shows: Netflix’s <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EHYcymIQ7xo&amp;ref=aftermath.site"><em><u>Jentry Chau vs. The Underworld</u></em></a>, which also features K-pop and the hunting of demons, isn’t anywhere near as successful.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><p>Jeremiah explained that “We're still in this flux. In 2024 people would say: survive ‘til ‘25, when there's going to be all these new shows getting green lit, and everyone's going to be back. We’re already at the tail end of 2025 and it's stayed pretty flat. But Netflix has <em>K-Pop Demon Hunters</em>, and I think this will be the catalyst for a change.”</p><p>The difficulty of (reliably) marketing to young people today has meant that an entire section of the media has functionally disappeared in a very short time. Every one of the shows above is still on their respective streaming services (save for the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cooujuNHsBU&amp;ref=aftermath.site"><u>deeply queer</u></a> <em>Battle Kitty</em>, which was removed when Netflix stopped supporting interactive content), but <a href="https://luminatedata.com/blog/whats-driving-the-animated-tv-series-falloff/?ref=aftermath.site"><u>new shows simply aren’t being commissioned</u></a>. Of the shows mentioned above, only <em>Jentry Chau</em> has any possibility of getting another season as of time of writing.&nbsp;</p><p>The reasons are pretty obvious: <em>Roblox</em> is <a href="https://roblox.fandom.com/wiki/Number_of_users_joining_Roblox_each_year?ref=aftermath.site"><u>adding millions of players each year</u></a>, <em>Fortnite </em><a href="https://www.tekrevol.com/blogs/fortnite-revenue-usage-statistics/?ref=aftermath.site"><u>is a major force in popular culture</u></a> and the first generation of ‘iPad kids’ are entering their mid teens. <em>Demon Slayer: Kimetsu no Yaiba - The Movie: Mugen Train</em> became the highest grossing Japanese film of all time, with <a href="https://www.the-numbers.com/movie/Demon-Slayer-Kimetsu-no-Yaiba-The-Movie-Mugen-Train-(2020-Japan)?ref=aftermath.site#tab=summary"><u>$512.7 million in ticket sales on a budget of $15.7 million</u></a>&nbsp; while <em>Wish</em>, a film that Disney promoted as the celebration of a century of filmmaking, made <a href="https://www.the-numbers.com/movie/Wish-(2023)?ref=aftermath.site#tab=summary"><u>$237.9 million on an estimated $200 million budget</u></a>. Anime and manga are handily beating western cultural products among young people: when the French government <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/07/28/arts/france-culture-pass.html?ref=aftermath.site"><u>gave children €350 each to spend on culture</u></a> they didn’t spend it on Proust and Balzac, but manga, starting a ‘<a href="https://www.lefigaro.fr/medias/le-pass-culture-entraine-une-ruee-vers-les-mangas-20210610?ref=aftermath.site"><u>manga rush</u></a>’. The country’s most popular animated show is a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=K-KZwTAkijc&amp;ref=aftermath.site"><u>magical girl anime</u></a>. Netflix, Amazon Prime and Disney+ have little reason to chase an audience that shows little interest in western animation, so they have dramatically cut their output and bought up shows like <em>Demon Slayer</em> and <em>Jujutsu Kaizen</em> to fill the gaps (though a good portion of Netflix’s anime isn’t suitable for pre-teen kids). Within three years the entire format of long-form English-language children’s animation functionally disappeared.</p><blockquote>Now that animators can no longer rely on networks and streaming platforms for employment, many are turning to independent animation.</blockquote><p>Or evolved. If the second Golden Age is over on streaming platforms then it continues on YouTube. Prompted by the success of ViziePop’s shows, studios like Australia’s <a href="https://www.glitchprod.com/?ref=aftermath.site"><u>Glitch Productions</u></a> were born online and are continuing the style of peak children’s animation in shows like <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mImFz8mkaHo&amp;t=8s&amp;ref=aftermath.site"><em><u>Murder Drones</u></em></a>, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HwAPLk_sQ3w&amp;t=705s&amp;ref=aftermath.site"><em><u>The Amazing Digital Circus</u></em></a>, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IC8KsZniulw&amp;t=1113s&amp;ref=aftermath.site"><em><u>The Gaslight District</u></em></a><em> </em>and <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MCAdbUaMlAE&amp;ref=aftermath.site"><u><em>Knights of Guinevere</em> </u></a>(the latter two being more adult-orientated, but still fine for older kids if you don’t mind them hearing a couple of PG-13 swears). Success is no longer getting your show picked up by one of the major streaming platforms but building an entirely digital fanbase.</p><p><em>Knights of Guinevere</em> is significant because it is being helmed by Dana Terrence, the showrunner of Disney’s <em>The Owl House</em>, and is a very clear indictment of Disney. Terrace is an interesting figure here as the only creator who has worked across the old and new children’s media. Beginning her career as a storyboard artist on <em>Adventure Time</em>, she became a director on Disney’s <em>Ducktales</em> reboot, then got to helm her own self-created show, <em>The Owl House</em>. There was, it seems, a falling out between her and Disney, hence the move to Glitch.&nbsp;</p><p>She <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lm6tEcvVUy4&amp;ref=aftermath.site"><u>explains in an interview</u></a> that “I was pissed off one day and this became a cathartic release… I worked with big mainstream studios for about ten years and now I don’t and I’m enjoying myself quite a lot.” The experience of working with Disney left her quite willing to burn bridges: when the company started to use generative AI in their shows, she tweeted ‘<a href="https://x.com/DanaTerrace/status/1989147042904699271?ref=aftermath.site"><u>Unsubscribe from Disney+. Pirate Owl House. I don’t care. Fuck gen AI</u></a>.’&nbsp;</p><p>Collectively, these shows are chalking up hundreds of millions of views—<em>The Amazing Digital Circus</em>’s pilot has <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HwAPLk_sQ3w&amp;t=706s&amp;ref=aftermath.site"><u>398 million views</u></a> as of time of writing, and though some will be repeats (about eight are mine) that’s an incredible viewership for a show with zero marketing budget beyond the Glitch brand name. These shows are also interesting for their business model. YouTube alone wouldn’t fund the large, professional operation that is currently producing three high-quality shows, so they supplement their funds with merchandising.&nbsp;</p><p>Glitch Productions’s output and other web series like <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vffu6FG4YP4&amp;ref=aftermath.site"><em><u>Lackadaisy</u></em></a> are syntheses of the two golden ages of animation: relatively sophisticated Young-Adult orientated stories supported by business models heavily reliant on merchandising (though unlike eighties Saturday morning cartoons, the stories far and away come first). Despite their success, they are a niche within the larger online world and, although some are now available on streaming services, are hamstrung by releasing episodes every few months and the fickle nature of virality. Now that animators can no longer rely on networks and streaming platforms for employment, many are turning to independent animation, and unfortunately few are breaking a million views.</p><figure><figcaption><span>Centaurworld/Netflix</span></figcaption></figure><p><em>The Amazing Digital Circus</em> racks up hundreds of millions of views per episode, while <em>The Gaslight District</em>’s pilot has just broken twenty million views after six months. Non-Glitch indie animations exist, but none have broken through like <em>Digital Circus,</em> which has been snapped up by Netflix.) Independent animation can be successful on its own terms, but there are no points for indie cred in children’s animation, especially when you have something to say. This isn’t like the indie music boom of the 1980s, where the <em>This Band Could Be Your Life</em> generation were creating sounds that nobody could hear on commercial radio and MTV. Music would still exist if Steve Albini never sat behind a mixing deck–if these shows don’t fill the void left by major studios, then there will be no animated narrative fiction for children.</p><p>That matters. I can see what these shows meant for my son and how they benefited him. He is more emotionally intelligent than I was at his age and better able to understand complex narratives, and that isn’t just going to make him better at understanding fiction, but better at understanding people. Part of that is not having parents who were lead-poisoned in a decaying mining village then hammered into the rough shape of adults by the military like I did, but part of that is that he grew up watching stories about people with feelings instead of extended toy adverts. Kids younger than him are going to grow up watching other kids play videogames or whoever replaces Mr. Beast after his inevitable cancellation and/or arrest. That type of ‘content’ (because it is content, not art) is fine in moderation, but people need stories.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><p>More than that, while children’s cartoons can’t undo centuries of systemic racism and sexism, representation does still matter. Fiction is inherently destabilising because it cannot help but force viewers to see things outside of their perspective. If a creator feels that a character should be black or queer, or if an artist draws a character wearing a hijab because that’s where their inspiration takes them, then that’s what viewers get. Because long-form narratives can put in the work to develop diverse characters,viewers can learn the most important lesson that stories can teach us: we are somehow both radically similar to and radically different from each other. There needs to be more than one production company making these shows or a whole way to communicate to kids is going to disappear.</p><blockquote>It turned out that capitalism won the battle before reactionaries even knew that they were fighting.</blockquote><p>Which brings us back to LibsofTikTok. Because of the way that conservative parents relate, or rather don’t relate to their children they will have little interest in what they are consuming. The number of conservative families who will genuinely raise their children fully outside of the mainstream is going to be very small. Living a trad lifestyle takes money that only a tiny percentage of people will have. Most conservative households are going to parent for the most part like more liberal households, by doing the best they can with limited resources, and part of that is allowing kids to have time in front of a TV or iPad.</p><p>The difference will be emotional coldness, indifference to suffering and a greater incidence of abuse. Starting after <em>Brown vs. Board of Education</em>, the Christian far-right in particular has developed a parallel theory of child-rearing as disciplines like attachment theory and critical pedagogy made most childhoods kinder and freer (with support from shows like <em>Sesame Street </em>and <em>Mr. Rogers Neighborhood</em>). Talia Lavin’s book <a href="http://bookshop.org/p/books/wild-faith-how-the-christian-right-is-taking-over-america/?ref=aftermath.site"><em><u>Wild Faith</u></em></a><em> </em>details how this mirror-world came into being: home-schooling, religious schools and camps, and parenting manuals like James Dobson’s 1970 book <em>Dare to Discipline</em>. This instructed parents to ‘bring some pain to the child when it is necessary for his eventual good.’ One person who grew up in a conservative Christian household told Lavin that “almost every spanking I’ve ever received was a result of asking ‘why?’”. This is not a lesson that is compatible with the worldviews of the kind of people who want to make children happy by making fun shows for them. The long-term effects of this type of parenting <a href="https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC4760853/?ref=aftermath.site"><u>are very well documented</u></a>.</p><p>Not every conservative is Christian (Raichik is Jewish, Musk atheist), but every part of the authoritarian ecosystem puts their own spin on these ideas. For most it’s nothing as systematic as the dictates of a parenting manual—more likely its arbitrary punishment, inconsistent discipline and general disinterest in the emotional life of children. Plenty more are more like Finn from <em>Adventure Time</em>’s parents: kind of, sort of okay people, but so wrapped up in their own problems and so laden with their own baggage that they can’t really ‘parent’ as such. Nowhere in authoritarian (or simply shitty) parenting is there space to sit down with your kid and watch shows together.&nbsp;</p><p>We can see that in one of the largest and most successful authoritarian parents’ campaigns in recent years, <a href="https://www.brookings.edu/articles/moms-for-liberty-where-are-they-and-are-they-winning/?ref=aftermath.site"><u>Moms for Liberty</u></a>: their target was books. Only <a href="https://literacytrust.org.uk/research-services/research-reports/children-and-young-peoples-reading-in-2024/?ref=aftermath.site"><u>one in three children enjoys reading and one in five actually reads every day</u></a>, while they spend <a href="https://www.aacap.org/AACAP/Families_and_Youth/Facts_for_Families/FFF-Guide/Children-And-Watching-TV-054.aspx?ref=aftermath.site"><u>seven and a half hours each day in front of screens</u></a>. However, parents can pick up books, flick through them and see horrors like the <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2022/01/27/us/tennessee-school-board-removes-maus?ref=aftermath.site"><u>mouse penis in Maus</u></a>, while they have to actually sit down and concentrate to find out that the protagonist of <em>Dead End Paranormal Park</em> isn’t just trans, they’re trying to save demons from an angel. Their lack of concern for their children as human beings meant that they never noticed the second golden age of cartoons, which let dozens of shows grow and a generation of artisans hone their craft.</p><p>So it turned out that capitalism won the battle before reactionaries even knew that they were fighting. If they were more invested in the lives of their children <em>as children</em> then they would have seen that animation has so fundamentally changed in the past two years that there is no need to #cancelnetflix. Netflix cancelled itself, or its animation arm at least, and with it an entire medium for communicating with children, one that I believe they benefitted from. Perhaps in 2028 LibsofTikTok will notice that Zooble from <em>The Amazing Digital Circus</em> is an allegory for trans experience and get all worked up about that, but until then the rest of us, and our children, are going to have to live in a media environment that is increasingly less human.&nbsp;</p>
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://aftermath.site/queer-cartoons-elon-musk-libsoftiktok-dogs-in-space-netflix/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ASUS Goes on Clearance With Its ROG Strix G16 Gaming Laptop (RTX 5060, 32GB RAM, 1TB SSD) for the Holidays]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/asus-goes-on-clearance-with-its-rog-strix-g16-gaming-laptop-rtx-5060-32gb-ram-1tb-ssd-for-the-holidays-2000653340</link>
            <guid>1383412</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Gaming laptops, especially the muscular options from high-end brands, don’t come in cheap. Most models with solid graphics, a powerful processor, and massive memory sit well over $2,000, but that’s not the case today.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6391/">Right now, you can grab the 16-inch ASUS ROG Strix G16 gaming laptop at a 31% discount, which drops its price to $1,800.</a> It’s still a bit of an investment, but one that’s going to be worth it. Windows 11 Pro comes pre-installed, and you also get a pair of headphones with a gaming mouse for free with your purchase. Amazon is offering it as a limited-time deal, though. We recommend placing your orders sooner rather than later to avoid last-minute disappointments.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6391/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Incredible Graphics</h2>
<p>This powerhouse is equipped with the latest 16-core 14th Gen Intel Core i7-14650HX processor, featuring 30MB cache and 5.2GHz clock speed. It’s got enough muscle to tackle gaming, streaming, creative workloads, and even intense multitasking during your busy days. Backing the processor up is a NVIDIA GeForce RTX 5060 laptop GPU, with a max TGP of 115W. Features like DLSS 4 and ray tracing technology create a hyper-realistic visual experience, bringing all your favorite titles to life. You will be able to play both the classics and the latest releases in an immersive way like never before.</p>
<p>There’s a massive 32 GB of blazing-fast DDR5 5600MHz RAM that ensures quicker game access, faster loads, and smoother frame rates. It’s also great for work professionals looking to multitask their way through busy days, where they can juggle a whole bunch of tasks at the same time without slowing down. The spacious, expansive 1 TB PCIE 4.0 SSD storage takes the experience even further in two ways. First, it lets you house all your important titles and projects in a single place. Secondly, SSDs are much faster than traditional hard drives, and make for faster boot and transfer times. Even better, the PCIe Gen 5-ready SSD slots let you easily upgrade the space as your needs grow in the future.</p>



<p>As for the display, you’ll enjoy fighting the bad guys on a bright, vibrant 16-inch screen that offers an impressive 165Hz/3ms refresh rate. The 300 nits of brightness provide consistent visuals in all lighting conditions, while the exceptional color accuracy makes sure all the high and low lights stay exactly as intended by the creator. But despite all this incredible power, the laptop stays calm and cool as it works. Thanks to its ROG Intelligent Cooling tech. The tri-fan airflow, vapor chamber, and liquid metal come together to offer peak performance while maintaining temperatures on the inside.</p>
<p>Some other features that deserve a mention are Dolby Atmos audio for a surround sound experience, plus an HD+ webcam for better video calls and clearer streaming sessions. Freebies include pre-installed Windows 11 Pro, a pair of headphones, and an efficient gaming mouse.</p>
<p>To wrap it up, if you’ve been looking for a solid gaming laptop, this powerful ASUS ROG Strix G16 is an excellent option to consider. I<a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6391/">t usually goes for around $2,600, but you can snap it up for $1,800 today.</a> This is one of the lowest we have seen this machine drop to in a long while, but the offer ends soon. Grab it before the price shoots back up, or the stock runs out for good.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6391/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/asus-goes-on-clearance-with-its-rog-strix-g16-gaming-laptop-rtx-5060-32gb-ram-1tb-ssd-for-the-holidays-2000653340]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ARC Raiders Cold Snap and Flickering Flames Update Notes—Winter Hits Speranza]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/arc-raiders-cold-snap-flickering-flames-update-notes/</link>
            <guid>1383409</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Embark Studios has published all the information you could want to know about the upcoming Cold Snap update, which includes the Flickering Flames event and the new Raider Deck. The update drops on all platforms <strong>tomorrow</strong>, and there are stacks to learn about what’s coming next in ARC Raiders.</p>



<p>The update includes a new community challenge, a fresh series of Feats to complete to unlock free rewards, and map conditions that present a dire threat to Raiders everywhere.</p>







<h2 id="h-cold-snap-new-map-condition">Cold Snap: New Map Condition</h2>



<p>From December 16, ARC Raiders players will be able to jump onto maps blanketed with snow and featuring a new map condition: Cold Snap. This condition is harmful and poses a serious threat to players:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>During the&nbsp;<strong>Cold Snap&nbsp;</strong>condition<strong>,&nbsp;</strong>the clock is ticking. The freezing weather will cut your Raider down in minutes unless you get indoors, or heal up quickly. Bear this in mind when engaging other Raiders – getting pinned down in the open is a death sentence during a Rust Belt winter.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Flickering Flames is the new event coming to ARC Raiders tomorrow. The details have been outlined in a <a href="https://arcraiders.com/news/whats-coming-in-the-december-update">recent blog post</a> published by Embark Studios:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>Below ground, the tenacity of the human spirit endures. Despite food scarcity and rolling blackouts, survivors gather to light candles, swap war stories, and appreciate what little they have. The festival of&nbsp;<strong>Flickering Flames</strong>&nbsp;is about to begin.</p>



<p>The&nbsp;<strong>Candleberry</strong>&nbsp;<strong>Bush&nbsp;</strong>forms the centerpiece of these festivities. For Speranzans, this hardy plant is a versatile asset during the winter months: boiling the berry creates a wax that burns for hours. Crushing them yields a refreshing juice while the roots make for a tea that drives out the toughest colds. Candleberries make hearty stews, warming soups, and gifts of perfume and soap, while the wreaths can be fashioned into festive decorations that offer Speranzans a hint of Topside’s greenery. Speranza needs A LOT of them for the Candleberry Banquets!</p>



<p>Speranzans rely on other essential items through the winter too.&nbsp;<strong>Light and heat sources</strong>&nbsp;boost morale and help keep Speranzans comfortable, while giving them the best chance to fight through to the spring.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>When you collect Candleberries and ‘other special items’, you’ll receive Raider Tokens, new items, rare utility items, weapons, cosmetics, and merit tokens, so there’s some give and take there. Players can unlock Merits simply for playing ARC Raiders, but finding and extracting Candleberries will elevate their gains.</p>



<p>An all-new Raider Deck will be introduced from <strong>December 26th</strong>, featuring a series of exclusive <strong>and free </strong>unlocks:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>With our Winter Update, we’re also introducing our second<strong>&nbsp;free, permanent Raider Deck. Available from the 26th December</strong>, The Goalie Raider Deck lets you unlock a series of items, Raider Tokens, and Cosmetics as you earn Cred Topside.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The flagship skin of the new Raider Deck is an old world outfit that some Speranzans have claimed was worn by the world’s most fierce and respected gladiators. Who knows, really? But hey, it comes with a pretty cool new hockey stick Raider Tool.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>As explained, the new skin comes with the first new Raider Tool, which takes the form of a hockey stick, because why not?</p>



<p>Flickering Flames is a limited-time, winter-themed event that runs from December 16 until January 13, so be quick if you want to maximize your rewards.</p>







<p>Let us know on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW">Insider Gaming Discord server</a> if you’re looking forward to the Cold Snap update.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/stellar-bladed-director-recognition-president/">Stellar Blade’s director has received a presidential commendation</a></p>




    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/arc-raiders-cold-snap-flickering-flames-update-notes/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Parking Garage Rally Circuit DX announced for consoles, PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/12/parking-garage-rally-circuit-dx-announced-for-consoles-pc</link>
            <guid>1383406</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Browser version available today.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Walaber Entertainment" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/walaber-entertainment">Walaber Entertainment</a> has announced&nbsp;<em><a title="Games > Parking Garage Rally Circuit DX" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/parking-garage-rally-circuit-dx">Parking Garage Rally Circuit DX</a></em>, an enhanced version of its 2024-released&nbsp;<em><a title="Games > Parking Garage Rally Circuit" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/parking-garage-rally-circuit">Parking Garage Rally Circuit</a></em> with twice the amount of content. It is available today for $14.99 via the launched marketplace <a href="https://wavedash.gg/walaber-entertainment/pgrc" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Wavedash</a>, which allows you to play games in your browser with no client download or special hardware required. A release will follow for unspecified consoles and <a title="Platforms > PC [25,110 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via Steam in 2026. <span id="more-1015273"></span></p><p>“What started as the idea of delivering a little more content for <em>Parking Garage Rally Circuit</em> has expanded into what is effectively a whole new game that doubles the size of the original,” said Walaber Entertainment founder Tim Fitzrandolph in a press release. “I’m really excited that <em>Parking Garage Rally Circuit DX</em> is part of the launch of a new platform in Wavedash that reduces friction and complexity for players to discover and play games like mine. I look forward to coming back next year with more news on bringing <em>DX</em> and the European Tour to Steam and console players.”</p><div id="carousel_1015278"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Walaber Entertainment:</p><blockquote><p><em>Parking Garage Rally Circuit DX</em> doubles the content of the original release with the addition of the new European Tour, adding eight multistorey car parks to drift through on top of the original eight American parking garages to make a total of 16 tracks.</p><p>Visit multistory car parks in Paris (Art Car Park), York (York Castle Car Park), Turin (Car Factory), Montpellier (Double Loop), Hamburg (Concert Hall), Copenhagen (Power Plant), Geneva (Parking Tour), and Naples (<a title="Companies > CAVE Interactive [60 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/cave-interactive">Cave</a> Park) as you drift and boost your way to victory in the single-player mode, or against other players online. These locations are all inspired by real multistorey carparks, though the odd underwater tunnel or falling stalactites may suggest a touch of artistic liberty. Do it all to a full new soundtrack from The Holophonics, the band behind the catchy tunes that graced the original game.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Designed to look, feel and sound like a lost <a title="Companies > SEGA [2,724 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sega">SEGA</a> Saturn game that could have been released in 1998, <em>Parking Garage Rally Circuit DX</em> delivers delightfully fun <a title="Genres > Racing [313 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/racing">racing</a> that’s easy to pick up and play with its chainable <em>Mario Kart</em>-style boosts, but requires skill to master as you unlock new car classes and compete to top the leaderboards. Head online to create and join lobbies of up to eight players and race on any track, with any car class, gaining points after each race. The game also features an arcade-style “Endurance” mode where you keep doing laps until you run out of time and cheat codes to discover that unlock fun modifiers, as well as special cars and tracks.</p></blockquote><p>Watch the announcement trailer below. View the first screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/parking-garage-rally-circuit-dx/december-15-2025/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Parking Garage Rally Circuit DX - Announce Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/QyUQ-lkHjhw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/12/parking-garage-rally-circuit-dx-announced-for-consoles-pc]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tomb Raider Actor Shares Her Heartfelt Farewell To Lara Croft]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/tomb-raider-actor-shares-her-heartfelt-farewell-to-lara-croft/1100-6536958/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>1383403</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536958">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>At <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/the-game-awards-2025-all-the-biggest-announcements/2900-7341/" data-ref-id="2900-7341">The Game Awards</a>, the future of Tomb Raider was revealed in the form of two new games, and a new actor, Alix Wilton Regan, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/new-tomb-raider-games-recast-lara-croft-with-a-gaming-veteran/1100-6536948/" data-ref-id="1100-6536948">taking over the role of Lara Croft</a>. Now, Camilla Luddington--who voiced Lara in the 2013 <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/tomb-raider/" data-ref-id="5000-92054">Tomb Raider</a> reboot, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/rise-of-the-tomb-raider/" data-ref-id="5000-285252">Rise of the Tomb Raider</a>, and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/shadow-of-the-tomb-raider/" data-ref-id="5000-479759">Shadow of the Tomb Raider</a>--has shared her farewell to Lara as well as a nod to her successor.</p><p>In a post on <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DSLtUFOgTVj/?igsh=bnU3bDFscmh4amxq&amp;img_index=2" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">her Instagram account</a>, Luddington thanked Tomb Raider fans for their support and sent Wilton her best wishes.</p><p>"To join the list of Lara Crofts before me was an incredible honor and she will forever be a part of me," wrote Luddington. "The Survivor Trilogy was a decade of adventure I will never ever forget. I could not be prouder of what we created. And as always, a new actress receives this incredible gift to step into the boots. So with that said, [Alix Wilton Regan], if you’re ever in need of a [crossbow], I know the exact spot to look for one at Croft Manor."</p><p>"This is incredibly kind, gorgeous and gracious of you," wrote Wilton Regan in a comment under the post. "No Laras left behind in this world, all Laras are always welcome. From one Lara to another, I salute you and thank you."</p><p>Wilton also shared a video message with fans about her new role.</p><p>The next game in the franchise, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/tomb-raider-legacy-of-atlantis/" data-ref-id="5000-706367">Tomb Raider: Legacy of Atlantis</a>, is a remake of the original Tomb Raider and it will arrive in time for the franchise's 30th anniversary next year. Then in 2027, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/tomb-raider-catalyst/" data-ref-id="5000-562110">Tomb Raider: Catalyst</a> will be the first mainline sequel since Shadow of the Tomb Raider. Both games will be available on PC, PS5, and Xbox Series X|S.</p><p>Game of Thrones' <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/game-of-thrones-star-sophie-turner-confirmed-to-play-lara-croft-in-tv-series/1100-6534452/" data-ref-id="1100-6534452">Sophie Turner has been cast as Lara Croft</a> in the new Tomb Raider TV series for Prime Video. British actor <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/tomb-raider-tv-series-finds-another-actor-joining-sophie-turners-lara-croft/1100-6536605/" data-ref-id="1100-6536605">Martin Bobb-Semple has also been cast</a> in a currently unspecified series regular role. Sigourney Weaver has also <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/new-tomb-raider-games-recast-lara-croft-with-a-gaming-veteran/1100-6536948/" data-ref-id="1100-6536948">joined the series as a new character</a> who has been created for the show.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/tomb-raider-actor-shares-her-heartfelt-farewell-to-lara-croft/1100-6536958/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lords of the Fallen II Won’t Be ‘Politically Correct’, Will Feature ‘Attractive Females & Skimpy Armors’, Confirms CI Games CEO]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/lords-of-the-fallen-ii-wont-be-politically-correct-will-feature-attractive-females-skimpy-armors/</link>
            <guid>1383391</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>CI Games <a href="https://wccftech.com/lords-of-the-fallen-ii-gets-first-look-at-gameplay-in-new-trailer/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">debuted the first gameplay trailer of Lords of the Fallen II</a> at The Game Awards 2025, confirming the 2026 release window <a href="https://wccftech.com/lords-of-the-fallen-ii-debut-trailer-gamescom-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">mentioned earlier this year</a>. </p>



<p>The trailer showcased some of the improvements confirmed for this sequel, including the introduction of a brand new dismemberment feature, which enables players to neutralize their opponents in a more decisive and expedient manner. This feature is complemented by the addition of novel executions, which further refine the combat experience. The press release also promised an even greater diversity of enemy types and boss battles of such remarkable intricacy that they will challenge even the most hardcore player, whether engaging in solo play, shared progression co-op, or optional PvP multiplayer.</p>



<p>However, there are also some philosophical changes in Lords of the Fallen II. CI Games CEO Marek Tyminski discussed those, as well as his more active role in the development of the sequel, <a href="https://x.com/tyminski_marek/status/2000284433052758033" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">on X</a>:</p>



<p><em>Many of you asked why the game initially had body type A/B. Hexworks started early 2020 as an autonomous studio owned by CI Games. Early on, political correctness and filtering meant not every decision reached me on time. I got a lot more involved from late 2024 and now act as Head of Studio alongside my CEO role. Things are very different now and the studio got fully integrated. We reverted a lot of wrong decisions and will continue improving. Lords of the Fallen II is being built on real player feedback, and it’s crystal clear in the last two trailers.</em></p>



<p>Later in the X thread, a follower asked whether the game would feature attractive female characters and revealing armors, and the executive <a href="https://x.com/tyminski_marek/status/2000294076826997103" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">replied affirmatively</a>. In another response, he confirmed that enemy placement, one of the most common complaints levied against the predecessor, would be improved in the new title.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Lords of the Fallen - VERSION 2.5 (Deadlier Boss Battles, All-New Veteran Mode) | PC, PS5, Xbox X|S" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/BUTsB_cuDYA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>Alongside the Lords of the Fallen II trailer, publisher CI Games and developer Hexworks have also released a new update for Lords of the Fallen (2023). Enemies and bosses in particular received 'extensive behaviour updates' throughout the game, increasing the level of challenge. Several boss weapons also feature brand new signature attack animations. Lastly, Veteran Mode's bosses have been further empowered with faster transitions, highly aggressive behavior, and new attack patterns.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/lords-of-the-fallen-ii-wont-be-politically-correct-will-feature-attractive-females-skimpy-armors/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[LEGO Expands Its Star Wars Starship Clearance, The Dark Falcon Hits a Record Low After the Millennium Falcon]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/lego-expands-its-star-wars-starship-clearance-the-dark-falcon-hits-a-record-low-after-the-millennium-falcon-2000653383</link>
            <guid>1383388</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>The Millennium Falcon has gotten a dark, evil makeover by LEGO, something we witnessed in LEGO Star Wars: Rebuild the Galaxy series. You can now bring this sinister piece home for less, thanks to a nice 17% discount on Amazon.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5792/">The offer brings the price of the The Dark Falcon Buildable Starship set to $149, making it much more approachable.</a> Grabbing it right now will ensure it arrives before Christmas, which is ideal if you’re planning to surprise a fan of the galaxy far, far away with it. All shoppers get to enjoy free delivery, which adds even more value to the purchase.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5792/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Incredible Attention to Detail</h2>
<p>The set is designed for ages 10 and up. A total of 1,579 pieces bring it together, which includes some minifigures, too (more on that later). Over 1500 pieces means it’s not exactly going to be a small, quick build. This is honestly a good thing because this way, you can spend cozy holiday evenings by the fireplace building it with loved ones while talking about Darth Vader’s shenanigans.</p>
<p>You will be building the dark version of the Millennium Falcon as seen in the Rebuild the Galaxy Disney+ special, which features a removable cockpit for 2 LEGO minifigures, 2 spring-loaded shooters, 2 rotating cannons, a gunner post for 2 LEGO minifigures, and a radar dish. Speaking of minifigures, these include Darth Jar Jar, Bounty Hunter C-3PO, Darth Dev, Darth Rey, Beach Luke, and Jedi Vader, plus their cute accessories, lightsabers, and a blue milk carton.</p>



<p>The exterior looks absolutely stunning and realistic, and the interior is just as impressive. You can flip the top panels to play with the details inside. Maybe place Darth Jar Jar on his throne, or help Jedi Vader rescue Beach Luke from the jail cell. There’s a command center, a hyperdrive, and an entertainment area as well. Once put together, this set measures over 5 in. (12 cm) high, 17 in. (43 cm) long, and 12.5 in. (32 cm) wide. It’s going to look incredible as a display piece on your bookshelf with Star Wars books, or even in the kids’ room. The set comes with a detailed instruction book that takes you through each step of the process one by one. It’s quite easy to follow, so if you’re planning to let your kids build in, they can do it without your supervision. LEGO also has its own Builder app, which offers interactive 3D instructions for an even better building experience.</p>
<p>This set is part of the LEGO Star Wars: Rebuild the Galaxy collection. If you’re looking to go all out this holiday season, you might also want to grab the 75388 Jedi Bob’s Starfighter and 75393 TIE Fighter &amp; X-Wing Mash-up sets, too. There are quite a few options going for less right now, so it’s a good time to create an entire setup without spending a ton. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5792/">As for this discount, it’s better to grab it sooner rather than later. Holiday rush is already in full swing, and deals are moving fast.</a> This one (like many others) is likely not going to be around for too long. Snap it while it’s still live.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5792/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/lego-expands-its-star-wars-starship-clearance-the-dark-falcon-hits-a-record-low-after-the-millennium-falcon-2000653383]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Build To Climb Codes (December 2025)]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/roblox-build-to-climb-codes/</link>
            <guid>1383385</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Use these Roblox Build To Climb monthly redeem codes for December 2025 to get your hands on plenty of free rewards, including Stumps, Pets and much more.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Planting the tallest Stumps to reach the top and potentially to the next map is the primary goal of Build to Climb. Purchasing different Stumps will deplete your treasury and will take some time to earn all the money back. Plus, you will need the help of Pets to boost your Cash income. This is when you should use the active Build to Climb codes. Claim free Stumps and Pets using these codes. You’ll easily reach 9.6km and progress further within a few hours after redeeming the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/roblox-sorcerer-battlegrounds-codes/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Roblox</a> game codes.&nbsp;</p>







<h2 id="h-active-build-to-climb-codes-nbsp">Active Build To Climb Codes&nbsp;</h2>



<ul>
<li>WELCOMEBUILDTOCLIMB – Mint Stump and Cat</li>
</ul>



<h2 id="h-inactive-build-to-climb-codes">Inactive Build To Climb Codes</h2>



<p>There are no expired codes in Build to Climb. If any active code goes inactive, it’ll be added here. Redeem all the active codes in a single sitting as they risk going inactive at any moment.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 id="h-how-to-redeem-build-to-climb-codes">How To Redeem Build To Climb Codes</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Roblox Build To Climb Code Redemption Menu | Image By Insider Gaming</figcaption></figure>



<p>Redeem all the active codes by following these steps:&nbsp;</p>



<ol>
<li>Launch Build to Climb and spawn on the map.&nbsp;</li>



<li>Now, press the small Discord icon located in the top-right corner of the screen.&nbsp;</li>



<li>Enter the active code into the “Enter Code” text box.&nbsp;</li>



<li>Click the “CHECK” button to redeem the active code.&nbsp;</li>
</ol>



<h2 id="h-more-about-build-to-climb-codes">More About Build To Climb Codes</h2>



<p>Stumps are very important and contribute heavily to the Build to Climb gameplay. Players can easily increase the overall height of their giant stalks by using the free Stumps obtained from codes. The core principle of Build to Climb is that the more distance you cover, the more Cash you earn. You can easily earn thousands of Cash and invest it into new Stumps, however, note that certain Stumps must be unlocked by reaching specific height milestones.</p>



<ul>
<li>Blue Stump – 1km – 10,000$</li>



<li>Chocolate Stump – 2.8km – 40,000$</li>



<li>Purple Stump – 3.9km – 130,000$</li>



<li>Lemon Stump – 6.8km – 800,000$</li>
</ul>



<p>With that sorted, try purchasing Eggs to obtain Pets that provide Cash multipliers. The Cat, which is redeemed from an active code, is part of Egg 1. Below are all the Eggs, their Pets, and their hatch chances:</p>



<figure><table><thead><tr><th data-align="center"><strong>Egg</strong></th><th data-align="center"><strong>Cost</strong></th><th data-align="center"><strong>Pets (Cash Multiplier – Chance)</strong></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td data-align="center">Egg 1</td><td data-align="center">600$</td><td data-align="center">Zebra (x2 – 46%)&nbsp;<br>Panda (x3 – 28%)&nbsp;<br>Cat (x4 – 14%)&nbsp;<br>White Tiger (x6 – 9%)&nbsp;<br>Cow (x8 – 3%)</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Egg 2</td><td data-align="center">8k$</td><td data-align="center">Chick (x9 – 48%)&nbsp;<br>Ostrich (x11 – 29%)&nbsp;<br>Sharp (x14 – 14%)&nbsp;<br>Falcon (x19 – 7%)&nbsp;<br>Pelican (x25 – 2%)</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Egg 3</td><td data-align="center">600k$</td><td data-align="center">Ray (x31 – 50%)&nbsp;<br>Pinky (x35 – 31%)&nbsp;<br>Rabbit (x40 – 13%)&nbsp;<br>Lumine (x47 – 5%)&nbsp;<br>Green (x54 – 1%)</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>







<h2 id="h-faqs-on-build-to-climb-codes">FAQs On Build To Climb Codes</h2>



<h3 id="h-what-are-the-latest-codes-in-build-to-climb">What are the latest codes in Build To Climb?</h3>



<p>“WELCOMEBUILDTOCLIMB” is the only latest active code in Build to Climb.&nbsp;</p>



<h3 id="h-what-types-of-pets-can-be-redeemed-from-the-codes">What types of Pets can be redeemed from the codes?</h3>



<p>As of now, only the basic Cat is the only redeemable Pet.&nbsp;</p>



<h3 id="h-when-are-new-codes-released-nbsp">When are new codes released?&nbsp;</h3>



<p>You can expect new codes to drop during major events and special updates.</p>



<hr>




    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/roblox-build-to-climb-codes/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Blade Battle Codes (December 2025)]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/blade-battle-codes-december-2025/</link>
            <guid>1383379</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Use these Roblox Blade Battle monthly redeem codes for December 2025 to get your hands on plenty of free rewards, including Gems, Spins, EXP Buffs and much more.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Tired of barely lasting 5 minutes on the Blade Battle map? Then you need the active <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/roblox-midnight-chasers-codes/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Roblox</a> Blade Battle codes to grab free rewards like Gems, Spins, and Exp buffs. Use the free Gems to buy Boxes and unlock stronger Blades with higher Damage and Blade HP. Spins can give you Potions, Gems, Exp, and even the rare Hell Sickle if you’re lucky. New players can quickly become one of the strongest on the map and unlock better Blades just by redeeming the codes highlighted below.</p>







<h2 id="h-active-blade-battle-codes">Active Blade Battle Codes</h2>



<ul>
<li>UPD2 – 5000 Gems (Latest)</li>



<li>HAPPY – Spin</li>



<li>CODE – Spin</li>



<li>UPD1 – 3 minutes EXP Buff</li>
</ul>



<h2 id="h-inactive-blade-battle-codes">Inactive Blade Battle Codes</h2>



<p>There are no invalid codes for Blade Battle. If any code goes inactive, it’ll be added here. Players are advised to redeem all the active codes in a single session as they risk expiring at any time. You can also expect new codes during major events and big in-game updates.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 id="h-how-to-redeem-blade-battle-codes">How To Redeem Blade Battle Codes</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Blade Battle Code redemption menu | Image By Insider Gaming</figcaption></figure>



<p>Follow these steps to redeem all the active codes in Blade Battle:&nbsp;</p>



<ol>
<li>Launch Blade Battle and enter the server.&nbsp;</li>



<li>Select the “ABX” button to open the code box.&nbsp;</li>



<li>Enter any code into the “UPD1” text box.&nbsp;</li>



<li>Press the “Verify” button to redeem the code.&nbsp;</li>
</ol>



<h2 id="h-more-about-blade-battle-codes">More About Blade Battle Codes</h2>



<p>The free Gems, Spins, and Exp buffs help your character grow stronger and unlock new Blades faster. These free resources also solve your early-game financial issues, so you can start buying Common and Rare Boxes right after redeeming the Gem codes.</p>



<p>To use the free Spins, press the “Spin” button. The free Spins are added to your account automatically. The Spin chances and rewards in Blade Battle are:</p>



<ul>
<li>Hell Sickle – 1%</li>



<li>Speed Potion – 8%</li>



<li>+10,000 Gems – 10%</li>



<li>+5000 Gems – 17%</li>



<li>+10,000 Exp – 26%</li>



<li>+3000 Exp – 38%</li>
</ul>



<p>Here are all the starting stats and price of all the Upgrades:&nbsp;</p>



<ul>
<li>Luck 1 to 2 – 3k Gems</li>



<li>Double Gem Chance 1 to 2 – 3k Gems</li>



<li>Blade +1 Max – 8 to 9 – 10k Gems</li>



<li>Blade DMG Max – 8 to 9 – 10k Gems</li>



<li>Blade Speed Max – 8 to 9 – 10k Gems</li>



<li>Blade Recovery Max – 8 to 9 – 10k Gems</li>



<li>Blade HP Max – 8 to 9 – 10k Gems</li>



<li>Body HP Max – 8 to 9 – 10k Gems</li>



<li>Move Speed Max – 8 to 9 – 10k Gems</li>



<li>Increase Critical Max – 8 to 9 – 10k Gems</li>
</ul>







<p>Boxes are very important in the game. They give you different Blades, each with its own rarity and strength. Here are all the Boxes in Blade Battle, along with their chances and prices:<br></p>



<figure><table><thead><tr><th>Box Type</th><th>Cost (Gems)</th><th>Common</th><th><strong>Uncommon</strong></th><th><strong>Rare</strong></th><th><strong>Epic</strong></th><th><strong>Legendary</strong></th><th><strong>Mythic</strong></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>Common Box</td><td>1.25k</td><td>58%</td><td>32%</td><td>10%</td><td>–</td><td>–</td><td>–</td></tr><tr><td>Rare Box</td><td>7.5k</td><td>–</td><td>48%</td><td>43%</td><td>9%</td><td>–</td><td>–</td></tr><tr><td>Epic Box</td><td>30k</td><td>–</td><td>–</td><td>48%</td><td>43%</td><td>9%</td><td>–</td></tr><tr><td>Mythic Box</td><td>100k</td><td>–</td><td>–</td><td>–</td><td>63%</td><td>33%</td><td>4%</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<h2 id="h-faqs-on-blade-battle-codes">FAQs On Blade Battle Codes</h2>



<h3 id="h-what-are-the-latest-active-codes-in-blade-battle-nbsp">What are the latest active codes in Blade Battle?&nbsp;</h3>



<p>“UPD2” is the latest active code in Blade Battle.&nbsp;</p>



<h3 id="h-what-codes-can-be-redeemed-for-free-spins-nbsp">What codes can be redeemed for free Spins?&nbsp;</h3>



<p>Codes like “HAPPY” and “CODE” can be activated for free Spins.&nbsp;</p>



<h3 id="h-how-often-do-the-active-codes-expire-nbsp">How often do the active codes expire?&nbsp;</h3>



<p>There are no expiration timelines; hence, you can expect the codes to go inactive at any moment.</p>



<hr>



<p>Having fun using codes in Roblox games? Then check out the latest codes for&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-forge-codes-december-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The Forge</a>,&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/roblox-merge-and-fight-codes/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Merge And Fight</a>, and&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/roblox-uma-racing-codes/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Uma Racing</a>. Join the&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/channels/1416770944961220720/1416780218936463463" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord</a>&nbsp;community to stay up to date with the latest happenings in the gaming world.<br></p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/blade-battle-codes-december-2025/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lara Croft Survivor Trilogy Actor Camilla Luddington Passes the Baton to Alix Wilton Regan, Who Takes on the Role for Tomb Raider: Catalyst and Tomb R]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/lara-croft-survivor-trilogy-actor-camilla-luddington-passes-the-baton-to-alix-wilton-regan-who-takes-on-the-role-for-tomb-raider-catalyst-and-tomb-raider-legacy-of-atlantis</link>
            <guid>1383376</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Last week at The Game Awards, we learned that the next-gen Tomb Raider that developer Crystal Dynamics <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/new-tomb-raider-unreal-engine-5-crystal-dynamics"><u>announced</u></a> three years ago is titled <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/tomb-raider-catalyst"><u>Tomb Raider: Catalyst</u></a>. Published by Amazon Game Studios, it's set to release in 2027 on PC, PS5, and Xbox Series X and S.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Meanwhile, Tomb Raider: Legacy of Atlantis is a reimagining of the original Tomb Raider game, built with Unreal Engine 5 and due out next year. Both games will feature a new actor as Lara Croft: Alix Wilton Regan.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">While the news was a surprise for some, actor Camilla Luddington — who portrayed Lara Croft in the 2013-2018 reboot trilogy — shared a bittersweet Instagram post about her time as the lead, saying she loved the fans and Croft will "forever be a part of [her]."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"I thought I’d make a post since I’ve been hearing from so many of you," she wrote. "I want to let you know that I have loved this fandom. To join the list of Lara Crofts before me was an incredible honor and she will forever be a part of me. The Survivor Trilogy was a decade of adventure I will never ever forget. I could not be prouder of what we created.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"And as always, a new actress receives this incredible gift to step into the boots. So with that said — [new Croft actor Alix Wilton Regan] if you’re ever in need of a [bow and arrow], I know the exact spot to look for one at Croft Manor."</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Alix Wilton Regan has played a number of big video game characters over the years, including the Female Inquisitor in both Dragon Age: Inquisition and Dragon Age: The Veilguard, Samantha Traynor in Mass Effect 3, Alt Cunningham in Cyberpunk 2077, and Aya in Assassin's Creed Origins. Regan was set to play Joanna Dark in Microsoft's Perfect Dark reboot, but it was canceled as part of a major round of layoffs.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As spotted by <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/lara-croft-actress-camilla-luddington-bids-farewell-to-tomb-raider-as-alix-wilton-regan-teases-were-just-getting-started" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Eurogamer</u></a>, Regan also <a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DSKc_PVEX6y/?igsh=MWZmank3c2NkNGx2bw%3D%3D" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>shared a post</u></a> following The Game Awards announcement, claiming it was the "absolute highlight" of her career to date to have been cast, "surpass[ing] even my wildest dreams, quite frankly."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"We're. Just. Getting. Started," she wrote.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Here's the official blurb on Tomb Raider: Catalyst:</p><blockquote>Tomb Raider: Catalyst, which has been in development by Crystal Dynamics since the partnership with Amazon Game Studios was announced in 2022, marks a bold direction for the series as Lara Croft embarks on a new adventure across Northern India. Tomb Raider: Catalyst is set in the wake of a mythical cataclysm that has unleashed ancient secrets and awakened the mysterious forces that guard them. When the most notorious treasure hunters from around the world descend on the region, Lara races to uncover the truth buried beneath the fractured landscape and stop those who would use its power for their own gain. As the ancient world collides with the present, Lara must decide who to trust among rivals and allies to prevent a catastrophe and protect a secret that could reshape the future.<br>Powered by Unreal Engine 5, Tomb Raider: Catalyst delivers the largest Tomb Raider world yet where Lara will traverse a landscape full of secrets, delve into lost tombs packed with intricate puzzles, and solve ancient mysteries using her unmatched brilliance and richly customized adventure tech. Perfect for longtime fans and newcomers alike, players will experience an exhilarating story of trust and betrayal that tests Lara Croft in new ways. Tomb Raider: Catalyst is set to launch in 2027 for PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X|S and Steam.</blockquote><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Catalyst wasn’t the only Tomb Raider-related announcement at this year’s Game Awards. Catalyst’s first trailer was immediately followed by <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/tomb-raider-catalyst-announced-for-2027-and-tomb-raider-1-reimagining-announced-for-2026-the-game-awards-2025"><u>a surprise announcement</u></a> of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/tomb-raider-legacy-of-atlantis"><u>Tomb Raider: Legacy of Atlantis</u></a>, a “reimagining” of the original 1996 classic. It is due out for PC, PS5, and Xbox Series X and S sometime in 2026, as that’s when the franchise celebrates its 30th anniversary.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Here's the official blurb on Tomb Raider: Legacy of Atlantis:</p><blockquote>In a surprise announcement, Amazon Game Studios, Crystal Dynamics and Flying Wild Hog unveiled Tomb Raider: Legacy of Atlantis, a modern reimagining of Lara Croft's genre-defining 1996 debut. Developed in partnership between Crystal Dynamics and Flying Wild Hog, the game features stunning visuals powered by Unreal Engine 5, modern game design, and new surprises that honor the spirit and atmosphere of the original game. As Lara Croft, players will harness their wits and athleticism to explore exotic locations lost to time, traverse treacherous landscapes, solve deadly contraptions, and face lethal predators in their quest for the scattered pieces of the Scion — an artifact of immeasurable power.</blockquote><blockquote>Tomb Raider: Legacy of Atlantis sets a new standard for re-envisioning a classic by masterfully balancing innovation with gaming heritage, capturing the wonder and excitement that defined a genre while igniting a new sense of discovery through expanded storytelling. The game arrives in 2026 for PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X|S and Steam.</blockquote><p data-cy="paragraph">Be sure to check out <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-game-awards-2025-everything-announced"><u>everything announced at The Game Awards 2025</u></a> for more, as well as <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-game-awards-2025-winners-the-full-list"><u>the winners list in full</u></a>. </p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Vikki Blake is a reporter for IGN, as well as a critic, columnist, and consultant with 15+ years experience working with some of the world's biggest gaming sites and publications. She's also a Guardian, Spartan, Silent Hillian, Legend, and perpetually High Chaos. Find her at </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vixx.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>BlueSky</em></a><em>.</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/lara-croft-survivor-trilogy-actor-camilla-luddington-passes-the-baton-to-alix-wilton-regan-who-takes-on-the-role-for-tomb-raider-catalyst-and-tomb-raider-legacy-of-atlantis]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[In the Wake of Divinity's Gruesome Reveal Trailer, Larian Publishing Director Says It's Not Trying to Shock the Audience, Rather Treat Them 'With a Le]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/in-the-wake-of-divinitys-gruesome-reveal-trailer-larian-publishing-director-says-its-not-trying-to-shock-the-audience-rather-treat-them-with-a-level-of-intellectual-respect</link>
            <guid>1383370</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">It's the burning question.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Larian publishing director Michael Douse has explained the studio’s thinking in the wake of the gruesome reveal trailer for Divinity, the Baldur’s Gate 3 studio’s next big role-playing game.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/divinity">Divinity</a> was announced at The Game Awards with a CG trailer that features extreme gore and sex. It begins with medieval fantasy villagers preparing for a ritual sacrifice, which involves burning a man alive. The villagers celebrate the occasion by playing music and dancing, laughing and chatting, feasting and drinking. At one point, someone throws up into animal feed. A mother and child look on with anticipation.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The burning of the man begins, and here things get very gory indeed. As his flesh tears and he screams in pain, some of the villagers are seen having sex. Others whip themselves. There’s more vomiting. Everyone seems thrilled, but as the burning man dies, something goes horribly wrong.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Disgusting wounds appear on the man. As his arm rips off we get a quick cut to an extreme closeup of someone eating meat. More sex. More vomiting. More pigs eating the vomit. And then the burning man explodes in a shower of gore. Something terrible is pouring out of his body. This, clearly, is not what was supposed to happen, and the villagers flee in terror. In the aftermath we see <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/yup-that-weird-statue-was-teasing-a-new-divinity-game-the-game-awards-2025">the statue Geoff Keighley has teased ahead of The Game Awards itself</a>. It has not gone well for the villagers, but the pigs look like they're still having a good time mopping up.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s fair to say the trailer has sparked a great deal of debate. While some have praised the studio for not holding back when it comes to its dark themes (something Baldur’s Gate 3 won plaudits for), others have said the trailer goes too far. Indeed some have accused Larian of "pushing the morale line" with the trailer, labeling it “gore porn.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Now, Douse has explained what Larian was going for here. In a <a href="https://x.com/Cromwelp/status/2000000527409807405" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">tweet response</a> to illustrator and YouTuber Kala Elizabeth, who had praised the studio for refusing to “hold back or sanitize stories to make them more palatable,” Douse said the Divinity trailer wasn’t about shocking the audience, rather “treating the audience with a level of intellectual respect.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“The phrase ‘treating the audience with a level of intellectual respect’ came up a lot in planning,” he said. “It isn’t about trying to shock them, it's about trying to match their powers of comprehension so that it resonates. We know people are capable of appreciating a three dimensional world.”</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Divinity Trailer Screenshots</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">This appears to have gone down well with Larian's fans. "I love this," Elizabeth replied. "As someone who plays durge, evil and renegade options I'm sad that more games don't seem to push that nuance and trust the audience anymore. Can't wait to see what y'all do next."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">There’s still a great deal we don’t know about Divinity, of course, but <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/fans-think-they-know-who-the-burning-man-in-the-divinity-trailer-is-supposed-to-be">fans think they’ve worked out who the burning man in the trailer is supposed to be</a>. Larian has said Divinity is its next “major” game after Baldur’s Gate 3, and it is set in the world of Rivellon. Here’s the tagline: “the gods are silent. Rivellon bleeds. New powers stir.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Built by the team who brought you Baldur's Gate 3, Larian Studios unchains its ambitions to bring you an RPG with greater breadth and depth than ever before,” reads the official blurb.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">While Divinity is a brand new game that doesn’t require experience with previous Larian titles, those who’ve played Divinity: Original Sin and Divinity: Original Sin 2 will be able to enjoy “greater understanding and continuity,” Larian added.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Swen Vincke, founder and game director of Larian Studios, said: “Despite our long history with the series, this is our first game entitled Divinity. We’re ready to bring everything we’ve done previously into one place. This marks the beginning of something with more breadth, depth, and intimacy than anything we’ve created before. We’ve been building toward this moment ever since we took our fate into our own hands. This is the Divinity we’ve always wanted to make and you're going to have loads of fun with it.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Be sure to check out <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-game-awards-2025-everything-announced">everything announced at The Game Awards 2025</a> for more, as well as <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-game-awards-2025-winners-the-full-list">the winners list in full</a>. And if you’re wondering what all this Divinity business is about, check out <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/what-is-divinity-larian-studios-baldurs-gate-3">our handy explainer here</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is Director, News at IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/in-the-wake-of-divinitys-gruesome-reveal-trailer-larian-publishing-director-says-its-not-trying-to-shock-the-audience-rather-treat-them-with-a-level-of-intellectual-respect]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Star Wars Fate Of The Old Republic Director Says The Game Will Launch Within The Next 1,477 Days]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/star-wars-fate-of-the-old-republic-director-says-the-game-will-launch-within-the-next-1477-days/1100-6536957/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>1383367</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536957">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/next-star-wars-rpg-returns-to-the-old-republic/1100-6536905/">Star Wars: Fate of the Old Republic</a> was one of the big highlights of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/all-the-game-awards-2025-winners-nominees/2900-7258/">The Game Awards</a> last week, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/star-wars-fate-of-the-old-republic-is-probably-many-years-away-from-release/1100-6536942/">but will it launch before 2030</a>? Game director Casey Hudson has stepped in to address these reports--<span>which may stem from <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/jasonschreier.bsky.social/post/3m7sj6bcoxk2o" rel="nofollow ">Bloomberg reporter Jason Schreier's speculation about when the game will be released</a>--</span>confirming that the spiritual successor to Star Wars: Knights of the Old Republic will arrive before the current decade is up.</p><p>"Don't worry about the 'not till 2030' rumors," <a href="https://x.com/CaseyDHudson/status/1999652683972489385" rel="nofollow ">Hudson wrote online</a>. "Game will be out before then. I'm not getting any younger!"</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="1083171409" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6466576,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Star%20Wars%3A%20Fate%20of%20the%20Old%20Republic%3A%20Teaser%20Trailer&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:90,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/star-wars-fate-of-the-old-republic-teaser-trailer\/2300-6466576\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466576\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466576\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466576\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6466576&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6466576,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6536957&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;star-wars-fate-of-the-old-republic&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;role-playing&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;pc,xbox-series-x,playstation-5&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;lucasfilm-games&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;franchise&quot;:&quot;star-wars-knights-of-the-old-republic&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;franchiseRoot&quot;:&quot;star-wars&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6466576},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6466576\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;GameSpot&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1862\/18620770\/4621503-starwars.png&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/lv0sIuGO.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1765489560,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="lv0sIuGO" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> Star Wars: Fate of the Old Republic: Teaser Trailer</p>
      </div>
<p>There's no concrete release date yet for Star Wars: Fate of the Old Republic, and it's still very early days for the project. The reveal trailer at The Game Awards was a CGI teaser for the game--<span>similar to how Quantic Dreams <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/quantic-dream-announces-star-wars-eclipse-with-trailer/1100-6498850/">revealed Star Wars Eclipse at The Game Awards 2021</a>--and the developer behind Fate of the Old Republic is Arcanaut Studios, a company </span>founded by Hudson and his partners in July. While it's not impossible, properly staffing a new studio and developing a game expected to be a AAA Star Wars experience will be challenging.</p><p>In a post on the official Star Wars website, Hudson did touch on what fans can expect from the studio. "Our goal is developing the kind of games I love making: emotionally powerful, cinematic adventures driven by player agency, narrative depth, and immersive world-building," <a href="https://www.starwars.com/news/star-wars-fate-of-the-old-republic-trailer" rel="nofollow ">Hudson said</a>. "Conversations between our team and Lucasfilm Games led to an incredible opportunity to return to Star Wars, and once again, we can hardly believe we’re working on such a special project."</p><p>Billed as a "narrative-driven single-player action RPG," Fate of the Old Republic will see players take control of a Force-user during a turbulent time of rebirth in the galaxy.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/star-wars-fate-of-the-old-republic-director-says-the-game-will-launch-within-the-next-1477-days/1100-6536957/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Avatar: Frontiers Of Pandora Probably Won't Come To Switch 2 Anytime Soon]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/12/avatar-frontiers-of-pandora-probably-wont-come-to-switch-2-anytime-soon</link>
            <guid>1383349</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Pray to Eywa</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure data-uuid="82c604f2ca942"><a title="Frontiers of Pandora" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/82c604f2ca942/frontiers-of-pandora.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Ubisoft</em></figcaption></figure><p>Ubisoft's <a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/games/ps5/avatar_frontiers_of_pandora">Avatar: Frontiers of Pandora</a> has garnered some pretty positive reception since its release in 2023, with numerous updates providing more content and quality-of-life improvements, and graphics that stand as some of the best in the business.</p>
<p>If you were perhaps hoping to see Avatar on the Switch 2, however, then you might want to just temper your expectations somewhat. According to a brief interview at <a href="https://frvr.com/blog/could-avatar-frontiers-of-pandora-come-to-nintendo-switch-2-ubisoft-genuinely-dont-know-if-its-even-possible/">FRVR</a>, Ubisoft currently has no plans to bring the game to Nintendo's new console.</p>
<p>When asked about a potential port, Game Design Lead Amandine Lauer simply said “Honestly, I don’t really want to wonder there, because I don’t know". Director Aoife O’Friel then followed up with “That’s something we don’t know about" when asked whether Avatar would even be possible on the Switch 2.</p><div><figure data-videoid="yv59MOA4ebw" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/yv59MOA4ebw?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><div><iframe id="ytyv59MOA4ebw" title="YouTube Video" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/yv59MOA4ebw?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/yv59MOA4ebw?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed773c0etygmhk&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>841k</span></a></p>
</div></figure></div>
<p>So yes, if the director and game design lead don't know, then chances are it's probably not in the works at the moment. That's not to say it's completely off the table, mind you, with Ubisoft providing solid support for the Switch 2 since launch with the likes of <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/assassins-creed-shadows">Assassin's Creed Shadows</a> and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/star-wars-outlaws">Star Wars Outlaws</a>.</p>
<p>On 16th December 2025, Ubisoft will also be launching <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/rogue-prince-of-persia">The Rogue Prince of Persia</a> from developer Evil Empire, famed for its work on <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/dead_cells">Dead Cells</a>.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:193812,194970 @ 1765809050 -->
<p><em>Would you like to see Avatar: Frontiers of Pandora on Switch 2? Let us know your thoughts with a comment.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://frvr.com/blog/could-avatar-frontiers-of-pandora-come-to-nintendo-switch-2-ubisoft-genuinely-dont-know-if-its-even-possible/" rel="noopener" href="https://frvr.com/blog/could-avatar-frontiers-of-pandora-come-to-nintendo-switch-2-ubisoft-genuinely-dont-know-if-its-even-possible/">frvr.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-info/308e7ebd598f8f010a5b21440dd898ce @ 1765811000 --></div></article><div><p>Nintendo Life’s resident horror fanatic, when he’s not knee-deep in Resident Evil and Silent Hill lore, Ollie likes to dive into a good horror book while nursing a lovely cup of tea. He also enjoys long walks and listens to everything from TOOL to Chuck Berry.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Olliemar28"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/ollie-nl.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Olliemar28');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/12/avatar-frontiers-of-pandora-probably-wont-come-to-switch-2-anytime-soon]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Total War: Attila becomes Tolkien war, as a massive Lord of the Rings mod delivers its full campaign]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/total-war-attila-becomes-tolkien-war-as-a-massive-lord-of-the-rings-mod-delivers-its-full-campaign</link>
            <guid>1383343</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/total-war-attila-mod-lord-of-the-rings-full-release-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/total-war-attila-mod-lord-of-the-rings-full-release-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/total-war-attila-mod-lord-of-the-rings-full-release-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/total-war-attila-mod-lord-of-the-rings-full-release-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/total-war-attila-mod-lord-of-the-rings-full-release-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/total-war-attila-mod-lord-of-the-rings-full-release-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/total-war-attila-mod-lord-of-the-rings-full-release-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/total-war-attila-mod-lord-of-the-rings-full-release-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/total-war-attila-mod-lord-of-the-rings-full-release-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Jovan / Dain II Ironfoot</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>If you're in the mood for more TWar following the recent reveals of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/total-war-warhammer-40000-is-real-and-features-orks-space-marines-the-aeldari-and-for-some-reason-david-harbour">Total War: Warhammer 40,000</a> and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/total-war-medieval-3">Total War: Medieval 3</a>, one of Total War: Attila's most ambitious mods has finally made it to 1.0 release. It's taken a decade for Lord of the Rings conversion The Dawnless Days to deliver its full ring-warring campaign, but that day's arrived at long last.</p>
<!--more-->

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="THE CAMPAIGN IS OUT! – The Dawnless Days Beta v.1.0" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/-2E6Vd-oRTo?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>THE CAMPAIGN IS OUT! – The Dawnless Days Beta v.1.0</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/-2E6Vd-oRTo?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/-2E6Vd-oRTo?autoplay=1" title="THE CAMPAIGN IS OUT! – The Dawnless Days Beta v.1.0">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-2E6Vd-oRTo" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>


<p>As you can see in the trailer above, which is gloriously heavy on armies marching, The Dawnless Days version 1.0 went live on <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/totalwarattila/mods/1?tab=description">Nexus Mods</a> as of Friday. As spotted by our buds at <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/lord-of-the-rings-rts-total-war-attila-mod-dawnless-days">European Videogameplayer</a>, that appears to have contributed to a <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/325610/charts/#1w">bunch of folks</a> deciding to boot up Attila over the weekend just gone.</p>
<p>"Over ten years of passion and commitment. Countless people contributing to this project, all of them believing in it every step of the way. From the testers to the moderators, from the developers to the leads, to the interns, the scribes, the voice actors, and the translators...it all led to this moment," the mod's team wrote upon making it to this milestone.</p><p>This 1.0 update adds in the full War of the Ring campaign mode the modders have spent the past decade building up to, with nine factions for you to choose from as you take to the landscape of Middle Earth and battle to hold the thing Gollum's rather fond of. There's the option of single player or multiplayer campaignage. The modders say you should expect an experience that's "based on the books whilst relying on the visuals of the films". In line with that, cameos from Aragorn, Saruman, Sauron, and Gloin - all looking like their filmy selves - have been added to a list that already looks to include the likes of Legolas and Boromir. </p>
<p>The modders note that as of this release, the region of Eriador remains "desolate and not playable", but they do have plans to incorporate it into the campaign down the line. Extra playable factions, more "iconic settlements" and further fleshing out/polishing also remain on the to-do list.</p>
<p>As someone who's not yet taken the plunge and tried Tolking myself into sitting down to read all of the Lord of the Rings books, I'm no expert on whether this is the dream of every ringer worldwide. That said, even I can see how cool it'd be to lead some troops into TWar as Sean Bean, given how fun it was to fight the comparatively very titchy battles in Oblivion at his side.</p>
<p>For some much more expertly thoughts on TWar: Attila, you can re-read our <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-total-war">list of best TWars</a> from 2016.</p>

        </div>

      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/total-war-attila-becomes-tolkien-war-as-a-massive-lord-of-the-rings-mod-delivers-its-full-campaign]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Samsung Clears Out G50D Odyssey Gaming Monitor at 42% Off, the 32″ Model Is Now Cheaper Than the 27″]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/samsung-clears-out-g50d-odyssey-gaming-monitor-at-42-off-the-32%e2%80%b3-model-is-now-cheaper-than-the-27%e2%80%b3-2000653260</link>
            <guid>1383340</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Amazon is unloading its Samsung gaming monitors in a big way, with huge discounts for last-minute holiday shoppers. It’s working, too — supplies are dwindling so quickly that <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6186/">Amazon’s placed its big red “Deal Selling Fast” sign on this one that’s carving 42% from the price of the Samsung 32-Inch Odyssey G50D Series QHD Fast IPS gaming monitor</a>. The $250 price on a gaming monitor that’s considered a terrific deal at its full price of $430 is going go run out sooner than later, and it’s one you’d regret missing.</p>
<p>The Odyssey G50D is G-Sync compatible in addition to having AMD FreeSync built in, and it moves at a crisp 180Hz with a 1ms response time to keep you at peak performance in those fast action and shooter games. The QHD resolution delivers 1.7 times the pixel density of Full HD for amazing sharpness and color, and the VESA DisplayHDR 400 technology amps up the contrast levels to reveal details you’ve probably never noticed before in your favorite games.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6186/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Real-Time Action</h2>
<p>Nothing’s more frustrating than lag and delay when you’re in the middle of an action game or shooter. Pound that button as fast as you like, but if your monitor just a fraction of a second behind the action, you’re cooked. That’s why the 180Hz refresh rate and 1ms response time of the Odyssey G50D is so crucial. It keeps you completely on top of the action down to the microsecond and gives you a huge advantage over anyone who’s playing on a lesser screen.</p>
<p>The VESA DisplayHDR 400 tech is another valuable weapon in your arsenal. It gives you a field of view with deeper blacks and brighter whites, and an overall brighter, better look of the entire screen, so you can detect enemies lurking in the shadows, or snipe rivals from great distances that you would have missed entirely on your old monitor.</p>



<h2>Creature Comforts</h2>
<p>You might not immediately associate a gaming monitor with physical comfort, but when you’re able to make fine adjustments to the height and angle of your monitor to line it up precisely to where you’re seated, you’ll notice that your neck and shoulders aren’t barking at you nearly as quickly as before. The Odyssey G50D is able to swivel, tilt, and adjust to get exactly into your line of vision, and it also has Eye Saver Mode to minimize blue light and reduce flickering, thereby reducing eye strain and irritation. Settle into your gaming chair, get the Odyssey G50D lined up exactly where you want it, and prepare for a long, comfortable grind.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6186/">During this time-limited Amazon deal, the 32-inch model of the Samsung Odyssey G50D is $40 below the price of the 27-inch version</a>. That’s an invitation to swoop in and grab one, because it might be the last chance you get to grab a monitor of this size and quality for just $250.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6186/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/samsung-clears-out-g50d-odyssey-gaming-monitor-at-42-off-the-32%e2%80%b3-model-is-now-cheaper-than-the-27%e2%80%b3-2000653260]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stellar Blade Director Receives Recognition from South Korean President]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/stellar-bladed-director-recognition-president/</link>
            <guid>1383337</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Hyung-tae Kim, the CEO of Shift Up and the director behind Stellar Blade, has received a Presidential Commendation in South Korea. This prestigious awardwas presented by the South Korean President himself, and it was given for Kim’s services to the domestic game industry. </p>



<p>While Stellar Blade was mentioned, the award was also given amidst recognition of Shift Up’s other games, like Goddess of Victory: NIKKE.</p>







<h2 id="h-stellar-blade-was-a-game-changing-title">Stellar Blade Was a Game-Changing Title</h2>



<p>Stellar Blade first dropped in April 2024, before being released on PC a little more than a year later. The game would go on to sell millions of copies, with players being pulled in by the visuals and staying for the combat and intriguing story.</p>



<p>It’s no big secret that much of the attraction in Stellar Blade rests with the game’s protagonist, Eve. Her character model was built around a scanned representation of a South Korean glamour model, which gives you an idea of why the character was such a hit with gamers.</p>



<p>As revealed by <a href="https://automaton-media.com/en/news/stellar-blade-director-hyung-tae-kim-receives-award-from-president-of-south-korea-for-contributions-to-game-industry/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Automaton Media</a>, Hyung-tae Kim, the visionary director behind Shift Up’s Stellar Blade, recently received an award from the South Korean President, Lee Jae Myung. This commendation was bestowed upon Kim because of his contributions to the industry and ‘achievements in overseas expansion’.</p>



<p>In the report, it was stressed that Kim ‘humbly thanked his development teams and Shift Up’ for their pivotal work on bringing Stellar Blade to life.</p>



<p>In September, it was confirmed that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/stellar-blade-sequel-in-development-now/">a Stellar Blade sequel</a> was in development and moving along quite nicely. In November, reports were circulated suggesting that Shift Up was targeting more platforms for further Steller Blade expansion, eyeing up the likes of <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/stellar-blade-2-multiplatform-shift-up/">Xbox and Nintendo</a>.</p>







<p>Did you ever play Stellar Blade? Let us know what you thought about the game on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/phantom-blade-zero-isnt-a-ps5-exclusive-forever-could-come-to-xbox/">Phantom Blade Zero could come to Xbox</a></p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/stellar-bladed-director-recognition-president/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Red Bull Has Turned 2000 Drones Into the World’s Largest Game of Tetris]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/tetris-drones/</link>
            <guid>1383334</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Red Bull has created the world’s largest game of Tetris powered by 2000 drones as a part of the Red Bull Tetris World final.</p>



<p>The special event saw Red Bull use the iconic 150-metre high Dubai Frame, which opened in 2018, as the border for the Tetris game, which Red Bull says made the game the “world’s first open-air, live playable Tetris game”.</p>







<p>A grand total of 2800 drones were used for the game, with each player needing 1400 drones per game due to the drones’ battery life.</p>



<p>Fehmi Atalar of Türkiye went home as the champion of the game, achieving a score of 168,566 during the five-minute game. Leo Solórzano of Peru managed a score of 57,164.</p>



<p><a href="https://www.redbull.com/int-en/red-bull-tetris-world-final-recap-and-winner-fehmi-atalar" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Red Bull</a> described the event as “phone to drone, with Qualifiers featuring participants in 60 countries playing directly on their mobile devices. </p>



<p>“This event was one of a kind. It’s not a thing you can describe in words,” said Red Bull Tetris World final winner Fehmi Atalar.</p>







<figure><p>
<iframe title="Imagine playing Tetris on drones 🤯 #redbull #redbulltetris #gaming #esports #tetris" width="422" height="750" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/qF2kKn-Hl1I?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>“Over [my] five years of Tetris experience, this was the best moment, and this event was one of a kind. It’s not a thing you can describe in words,” Atalar concluded. “I managed to play like a machine, and although I could have done things a bit cleaner, I achieved a flawless run and did not miss a single point in any of my matches, so I am very happy.”</p>



<p>What do you think of 2000+ drones making the world’s largest game of Tetris? Share your thoughts on this update through the free-to-play&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/channels/1433093283558719611/1433112738133180426" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord Server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more IG news, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/lords-of-the-fallen-2-attractive-female-characters-revealing/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Lords of the Fallen 2’s CEO saying the game has ‘Attractive Female Characters’ in ‘Revealing Outfits,’</a>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-modern-warfare-4-multiplayer-is-reportedly-a-complete-copy-of-modern-warfare-2/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Call of Duty: Modern Warfare 4 multiplayer reportedly being ‘A Complete Copy of Modern Warfare 2.’</a></p>




    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/tetris-drones/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dragon Ball Z: Kakarot DLC ‘DAIMA: Adventure Through the Demon Realm – Part 2’ launches in early 2026]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/12/dragon-ball-z-kakarot-dlc-daima-adventure-through-the-demon-realm-part-2-launches-in-early-2026</link>
            <guid>1383331</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Playable Vegeta (Mini), Tamagami Number Two boss fight, and more.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><em><a title="Games > Dragon Ball Z: Kakarot [79 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/dragon-ball-z-kakarot">Dragon Ball Z: Kakarot</a></em> downloadable content “DAIMA: <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,794 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">Adventure</a> Through the Demon Realm – Part 2″ will launch in early 2026 with new content including Vegeta (Mini) as a playable character, a boss fight against Tamagami Number Two, and new enemies from the Demon Realm, publisher <a title="Companies > Bandai Namco Entertainment [6,808 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/bandai-namco-entertainment">Bandai Namco</a> and developer <a title="Companies > CyberConnect2 [624 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/cyberconnect2">CyberConnect2</a> <a href="https://en.bandainamcoent.eu/dragon-ball/news/dragon-ball-z-kakarot-daima-pack-part-2-arrives-early-2026-new-character-and-fresh" target="_blank">announced</a>. “Part 2” will follow between January and March 2026. <span id="more-1015236"></span></p><p>Here are the latest details:</p><blockquote><p>Vegeta (Mini) may be small, but his power is unmatched. His signature move, Armor Strike, delivers a devastating blow, while Arc Shot corners enemies and fires a high-speed shockwave to create openings for unstoppable follow-up attacks.</p><p>Prepare to face Tamagami Number Two, the relentless guardian of the Two-Star Dragon Ball. Harnessing the fury of tornadoes, he can nullify incoming attacks and hurl opponents away. His spear technique, Crosswave Slash, unleashes a fast, cross-shaped shockwave, and Vortex Strike summons a massive whirlpool to overwhelm foes.</p><p>New adversaries from the Demon Realm also await as player explore the First Demon World. The Gendarmerie Tank is a heavy hitter with powerful ranged and charge attacks, while Gendarmerie Officers are strong enemies that summon reinforcements and launch attacks from every angle.</p></blockquote><p><em>Dragon Ball Z: Kakarot</em> is available now for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [11,079 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [8,472 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [28,589 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox One [14,344 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch [18,107 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [25,110 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/851850/DRAGON_BALL_Z_KAKAROT/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a>.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>“DAIMA: Adventure Through the Demon Realm – Part 2” Battle Trailer</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><p><iframe title="DRAGON BALL Z: KAKAROT -DAIMA- Adventure Through The Demon Realm Part 2 – Battle Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9WfULjohDvg?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe title="『ドラゴンボールZ KAKAROT』DLC「追加シナリオ：-DAIMA- 魔界の大冒険！ PART2」バトルPV" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/OcpUbfK3ntY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/12/dragon-ball-z-kakarot-dlc-daima-adventure-through-the-demon-realm-part-2-launches-in-early-2026]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This Adorable Hand-Drawn Cat Adventure Looks Packed With Classic Disney Charm]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/12/this-adorable-hand-drawn-cat-adventure-looks-packed-with-classic-disney-charm</link>
            <guid>1383325</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Feline cosy</p>
</section></header><section>

<p>If you're after something cute and cosy to curl up with this Christmas, you may need to look no further than <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/stars_in_the_trash">Stars In The Trash</a>, a new cat platformer (<em>catformer</em>?) that looks like it's walked straight out of Disney's classic back catalogue.</p>
<p>Animated by a team of artists who have previously worked for the House of Mouse, this hand-drawn adventure sees you placed in the paws of Moka, a spoiled cat who decided to escape the creature comforts of home and see what life's like out on the streets.</p>
<p>Expect platforming puzzles, cat interactions, and claws-out combat, but the real selling point is that art style, which combines classic hand-drawn animations with lush watercolour backgrounds for a particularly cosy vibe.</p>
<p>You'll find a rundown of the game's key features and a handful of screenshots below:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>· Explore a beautiful hand drawn watercolor world<br>
· Feel the magic of the animated movie classics<br>
· Discover the power of friendship<br>
· Live an emotional journey<br>
· Be a cat</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Stars in the Trash is now available on the Switch eShop for <strong>£13.49 / 14,99€ / $14.99</strong>, and there's even a 30% launch discount now running until early January.</p>
<p><em>Does this look up your street? Pounce down to the comments and let us know.</em></p></section></article><div><p>Jim came to Nintendo Life in 2022 and, despite his insistence that The Minish Cap is the best Zelda game and his unwavering love for the Star Wars prequels (yes, really), he has continued to write news and features on the site ever since.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/JimNorman"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/jimnormann.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('JimNorman');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/12/this-adorable-hand-drawn-cat-adventure-looks-packed-with-classic-disney-charm]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Thief VR Review]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/12/15/thief-vr-review/</link>
            <guid>1383322</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
			
			<p>Thief is a series that I’ve always I loved as an idea, but lack the patience to play properly. They’re the kind of game where if you’re spotted by just one guard you are in a bit of trouble, and will likely be reloading a save if there are more than that. It’s the kind of hardcore stealth experience that encourages ghost runs whilst also hoovering up every last valuable you can find on the way. Thief VR isn’t that, really, but it is still pretty good. And it’s also incredibly immersive.</p>
<p><iframe title="Thief VR: Legacy of Shadow - Launch Trailer | PS VR2 Games" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/UvLlHUUmP9M?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Thief VR casts you as the wanted thief Magpie, completing jobs for your handler Cassandra. The voice acting for all the main parts is great, particularly Cassandra and returning classic Thief protagonist Garret, who quickly becomes a magical voice in your head. The story isn’t going to be the biggest draw here – it’s a touch predictable and some of the dialogue is poor – but it does its job well enough, giving you a variety of things to steal and a vague reason for doing it.</p>


<p>What this game nails is how you move through its levels. You grab a window and slide it open, grab the ledge and climb through, crouch and then walk over to a chest and pull out your lockpicks. It might not sound like much, but this sequence of actions can vary wildly between VR games. Thief VR just manages to make all of this feel slick and intuitive. The locomotion here is unobtrusive enough that just climbing through a window, peaking through a door, listening to a nearby pair of guards chatting feels incredibly immersive and natural.</p>


<p>The levels looks pretty good as well. They’re not the best visuals I’ve seen in VR, but certainly aren’t the worst either. I occasionally stopped to have a look at some of the views, which is a good sign. You will find some poor textures, especially if you stop and look at the foliage as I did exactly once, and the characters all look a bit odd. Even a main character like Cassandra feels a bit like a waxwork model come to life, though she specifically fares a little better than some characters in other games I could mention. Whilst it won’t blow your mind by any stretch of the imagination, the game looks good enough to be immersive.</p>
<p>But then there are the immersion breakers, and they’re everywhere. Locomotion is great, but opening drawers is a nightmare. Grabbing a drawer, you open it towards you, let go and… it slams shut again because your hand, which you didn’t move, caught it slightly. You open it again and the loot inside is jittering about and jerking side to side slightly. You collect the loot and try to close the drawer, but it bounces open again despite you being incredibly careful. In the worst case scenario, the loot is clipping through the bottom of the drawer, causing the drawer to either be stuck frozen in space or randomly opening and closing slightly, whilst also stopping you from collecting the loot because it’s stuck inside the wood. Each drawer is usually part of a cabinet that has one to three more drawers on it. It’s difficult to feel like a thief when it looks a lot like you’ve never encountered drawers before and are acting like my nan trying to work a computer.</p>

<p>This situation is a microcosm of Thief VR where smaller details break through the great work done elsewhere. Climbing up walls, you can actually grab empty space next to a handhold to keep climbing. If you use a horizontal rope to make your way over a gap, the angles that your in-game wrists stick out at are ridiculous. Sneak up behind a guard, bonk him on the head with your truncheon and he stops to draw his sword before falling to his knees. For everything Thief VR does right there is something else that dims your lantern of enjoyment, leaving you in moodily lit awkwardness.</p>
<p>If you can ignore the constant immersion breakers there is a pretty good thief game here, but that’s home brand thief, not Thief the series. The light gem on your hand is binary now, visible or practically invisible, where being lit just means “You are standing in the light, fool!”, which makes getting close to enemies without being spotted rather easy. You quickly get a bow with all the requisite arrows – water, fire, bludgeoning, rope, and those boring pointy ones that don’t do anything special – and your trusty truncheon hangs from your hip so you can sneak up on a guard and bonk them on the head once or twice, depending on whether they’re wearing a helmet.</p>

<p>The guard AI is, frankly, abysmal when it’s working, and then sometimes just breaks. A guard walked within a few feet of me while I was knocking out another guard and didn’t notice, but then another guard heard me doing the same one room over.&nbsp;You can hit guards in the legs to bring them down to their knees – handy to knock them out whilst crouching – but sometimes it doesn’t work and they still get their swords out before falling. You can turn the difficulty up, removing assists, but the AI is so poor it still isn’t the challenge it should be. Sometimes, when a guard spots you, he freezes in place, not approaching, attacking, or even speaking.</p>
<p>Upgrading your skills and gear doesn’t rely on the money you earn from stealing, but rather on rewards from Cassandra for stealing a certain amount and snagging a relic. These are upgrades like moving quicker whilst crouched (which is absolutely essential, obviously), making less noise when sprinting or landing, or starting a mission with two water arrows. That’s a big one, since you can’t buy more water arrows and have to instead find them lying around in levels, which is just three layers of silliness.</p>
<p>All that said, I have found that stealth in VR has made me far more patient than in non-VR games because I’m so much more immersed. I’m not staring at a screen waiting, I’m pressed up against the actual wall myself. The moments where you encounter a tolerable amount of quirks, meticulously sneak into a building, steal your prize, and get away without a sound are still very enjoyable. There are one or two good moments in the story as well, even if it isn’t overly impressive overall – I particularly enjoyed losing my equipment and having to reclaim it whilst escaping from a prison, which is an overused trope, but made it marginally more challenging and enjoyable.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/12/15/thief-vr-review/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>