<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 14:56:21 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MultiVersus adds The Matrix's Agent Smith, Jason Voorhees]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/multiversus-adds-the-matrixs-agent-smith-jason-voorhees</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/multiversus-adds-the-matrixs-agent-smith-jason-voorhees.875736/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/multiversus-adds-the-matrixs-agent-smith-jason-voorhees<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="content_above">



<p>
If you click on a link and make a purchase we may receive a small commission.  <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/editorial-policy">Read our editorial policy</a>.
</p>
    <div>
        <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-type="article">


<header>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>Ahead of relaunch next week.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/MultiVersus---Official-Launch-Trailer-_Stars-Collide.-Pies-Fly._-2-58-screenshot.png?width=1200&amp;height=1200&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Warner Bros.</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>    <div>



            <p>
Free-to-play platform fighter MultiVersus has confirmed the inclusion of Jason Voorhees from Friday the 13th and Agent Smith from The Matrix, ahead of the game going live (again) next week, on 28th May.
</p>
<p>
Warner Bros' take on Super Smash Bros originally launched in early access last summer, but has been <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/multiversus-to-shut-down-until-2024-with-no-refunds-for-paying-players">offline for the past 11 months</a> while it was upgraded to Unreal Engine 5. 
</p>
<p>
MultiVersus will arrive next week compatible with cross-platform and cross-progression play for PC (Steam and Epic), PlayStation 5, PS4, Xbox One and Xbox Series X/S. (No Nintendo support is a surprise, but at this point, it's probably best just to wait for <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-switch-2-everything-we-know">Switch 2</a>.)
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="MultiVersus - Official Launch Trailer &quot;Stars Collide. Pies Fly.&quot;" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/nuJzF1vE1GM?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>MultiVersus - Official Launch Trailer "Stars Collide. Pies Fly."</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/nuJzF1vE1GM?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/nuJzF1vE1GM?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>MultiVersus' launch trailer includes The Matrix's Agent Smith, plus Jason Voorhees.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nuJzF1vE1GM" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
27 unique <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/multiversus-characters-roster-unlock-free-rotation-9024">characters are playable in MultiVersus</a>, taking from a rollcall of Warner Bros-owned franchises (and characters not already snapped up by Fortnite). 
</p>
<p>
The roster includes Batman, Superman, Wonder Woman and Joker from DC Comics, Finn and Jake from Adventure Time, Gizmo and Stripe from Gremlins, Bugs Bunny, Marvin the Martian and Taz from Looney Tunes, LeBron James from Space Jam, Arya Stark from Game of Thrones, Shaggy and Velma from Scooby-Doo (but not actually Scooby-Doo himself), Rick and Morty from Rick and Morty, the Iron Giant from The Iron Giant, plus Tom and Jerry. 
</p>
<p>
As for the game's newest arrivals, Jason Voorhees will be available at launch, when Season 1: Puns &amp; Villainy begins. Agent Smith will then debut later in the season.
</p>
<p>In January, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/warner-bros-wants-always-on-game-success-for-dc-game-of-thrones">Warner Bros said it wanted "always on success" for its biggest franchises</a>, four of which (DC, Game of Thrones, Harry Potter and Mortal Kombat) are valued at worth a billion dollars each. Live service games such as MultiVersus are designed to provide just this, with Warner Bros saying it wanted to make "sure we get as much engagement and time with fans as possible".</p>



        </div>


        </article>

  
    </div>


  
      </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bluey Receives The Full Willy Wonka Experience, Making Kids Cry]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/bluey-facebook-event-meetup-costume-1851487929</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/bluey-receives-the-full-willy-wonka-experience-making-kids-cry.875733/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/bluey-facebook-event-meetup-costume-1851487929<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>This is a free country, or so I’m told. While that doesn’t mean your entitled to lifesaving healthcare without going bankrupt, it does mean that if you own a hot dog bar in Las Vegas, Nevada, you can host an unofficial meet-and-greet with <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/bluey-cartoon-season-four-release-date-streaming-1850857940&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/bluey-cartoon-season-four-release-date-streaming-1850857940">world famous cartoon pup Bluey</a></span> and piss off hundreds of children and their parents in the process. </p><div data-video-id="196923" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Kotaku’s Hopes For Spyro The Dragon’s (Reported) Comeback" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="355" data-playlist="196923,196922,196918" data-current="196923"><div><p>Kotaku’s Hopes For Spyro The Dragon’s (Reported) Comeback</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196923/196923_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196923/196923_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196923/196923_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196923/196923_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/22494.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><p>Dirt Dog Las Vegas did exactly this earlier this month when it advertised a special Bluey-themed hangout on May 11 featuring the hit Disney+ show streaming on TVs, free face painting, games, desserts, and most importantly Bluey herself waving to kids and posing for pictures. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.fox5vegas.com/2024/05/14/parents-outraged-by-massive-event-featuring-amateur-bluey-restaurant-apologizes/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.fox5vegas.com/2024/05/14/parents-outraged-by-massive-event-featuring-amateur-bluey-restaurant-apologizes/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">As local broadcast affiliate FOX5 reports</a></span>, the event exploded on Facebook with thousands of RSVPs, only for each family who actually showed up and waited in “lines out the door” to be met with the crushing disappointment of some dude in a Bluey tracksuit wearing a printed tarp hood on his head. </p><p> “I was mad,” one little girl told FOX5. “We could see his beard. He looked unexpected.” One mother told the news outlet that the kids were unsettled by the obvious imposter and some were visibly upset or crying on their parents’ shoulders. </p><p>The <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.facebook.com/events/736296668704370/?post_id=736296752037695&amp;view=permalink&amp;ref=110&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.facebook.com/events/736296668704370/?post_id=736296752037695&amp;view=permalink&amp;ref=110" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">event’s Facebook page</a></span> quickly filled up with warnings. “DO NOT GO! I repeat DO NOT GO!” wrote one person. “I got there and there were moms already coming out saying how bad it was,” wrote another. “I went over and saw the employees that have onesie on!!!” Photos showed an average-looking sports bar filled to the brim with kids while the Bluey in question stood behind a folding table. Some parents shared pictures of proper Bluey costumes the bar could have rented while one lone individual commented, “It was a free event. Stop whining.”</p><p>“We are truly sorry this event wasn’t the expected experience,” Dirt Dog <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.facebook.com/profile.php?id=100090172231289&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.facebook.com/profile.php?id=100090172231289" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">posted on Facebook</a></span> in the aftermath. “We hope to repair our relationship with all of you.” The comments were eclectic. One woman posted a before and after picture of her daughter to illustrate her soul-crushing disappointment. Another wrote, “I just hope the staff member that was in that onesie all day got extra compensation for the nightmare that was not his fault.”</p><p>How did things go so wrong? Dirt Dog management told FOX5 it often puts on themed events like this that are staffed by “regulars” who volunteer dress up and bake goods for the day. “We expected like maybe 50 to 60 people—not in the sense of like the whole city coming out,” Taj Wilder, a spokesperson for the restaurant, told the TV station. “Just now knowing who Bluey is, we would have planned ahead and would have had security.” </p><p>It’s all a bit reminiscent of the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://gizmodo.com/reimagined-willys-chocolate-experience-coming-america-1851404595&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://gizmodo.com/reimagined-willys-chocolate-experience-coming-america-1851404595">AI-generated Willy Wonka fiasco</a></span> in Glasgow earlier this year, minus the sad Oompa Loompa who ended up going viral after everyone fell in love with her <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.vulture.com/article/glasgow-sad-oompa-loompa-interview.html&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.vulture.com/article/glasgow-sad-oompa-loompa-interview.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">following a no-nonsense tell-all appraisal of the event</a></span>. As a parent myself who has on one occasion completely failed to manage the expectations of my children, I can sympathize with both the parents dealing with toddlers addled by the horror of witnessing imposter Bluey, and the food service workers unexpectedly thrust into the brutal gauntlet of a hundred families trying to kill a few hours before nap time during a Saturday lunch rush. For real life. </p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[INTERVIEW: Tom McKay on ‘Becoming Henry’ in Kingdom Come Deliverance]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/tom-mckay-interview-kingdom-come/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/interview-tom-mckay-on-%E2%80%98becoming-henry%E2%80%99-in-kingdom-come-deliverance.875730/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/tom-mckay-interview-kingdom-come/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>On April 18, Warhorse Studios lifted the lid on Kingdom Come: Deliverance II in the most epic way possible. With a stunning reveal trailer and a lengthy showcase that was equal parts explorative and regal, ‘KCDII’ was uncovered in full, filling fans worldwide with an immense sense of anticipation and excitement. It’s the direct follow-up to 2018’s Kingdom Come: Deliverance, and it has been in development for quite a while.</p>



<p>Recently, I had the pleasure of catching up with and interviewing <a href="https://www.instagram.com/thisistommckay/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Tom McKay</a>, the instantly recognisable actor and white-hot talent behind Henry of Skalitz, the lead in both Kingdom Come: Deliverance and the sequel, which is due to be released later this year. </p>



<p>This is what I’ve dubbed ‘Becoming Henry’.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="INTERVIEW: Actor Tom McKay Talks Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2" width="1200" height="675" src="about:blank" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/uZPsFrmOAoM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>







<hr>



<h2 id="h-on-the-road-to-kingdom-come">On The Road To Kingdom Come</h2>



<p>Kingdom Come: Deliverance is a stunning open-world game that’s rooted in realism. There is attention to detail in everything, from the period-accurate combat mechanics to the survival elements that make the game challenging. It’s even set in a real-world location that was painstakingly researched by what was once a very small team – <a href="https://www.instagram.com/warhorsestudios/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Warhorse Studios</a>. </p>



<p>I’ve come to learn that the studio has expanded massively since the first game, and it’s now backed by PLAION. In my chat with Tom McKay, I was eager to rewind and learn how he came across the role in the first place, given that Kingdom Come: Deliverance was the first (and still the only) game franchise McKay has worked on.</p>



<p><strong>McKay:</strong> ‘<em>It comes through the same channels as most of your acting work, and more and more in a way that I think is good and exciting, the worlds are kind of blending. Historically, they were very separate beasts, and a lot of TV, film, and theatre actors wouldn’t necessarily move between gaming and vice versa, but that’s happening more and more and there are lots of brilliant, big names doing it. </em></p>



<p><em>It was very much the same way that I would audition for any other job, and then I went out to Prague in like 2016 to meet everybody and do essentially a final audition, and that was it. Then they offered me the job. I don’t think anybody at that point, certainly not me, thought we’d be having this conversation eight years later – but the second game is so anticipated and I think that is absolutely brilliant.</em></p>



<p><em>I’m biased, but I’m seeing a lot of the work that the guys have done at Warhorse and it is completely mindblowing. It’s not just the kind of next level from the last game, it’s like fifty levels up from there, I think.</em>‘</p>



<h2 id="h-the-transition">The Transition</h2>



<figure></figure>







<p>I was interested to learn about the ‘switch’ between Kingdom Come: Deliverance and Kingdom Come: Deliverance II. It’s a different world to the one that existed several years ago when the first game was being pieced together, and that’s something that McKay confirmed as he broke down the intricacies of playing Henry of Skalitz.</p>



<p><strong>McKay: </strong><em>‘The biggest technical difference was the facial capture. We didn’t do live facial capture for the motion capture the first time around, and this time we did. We had big head cams, which make you look like stag beetles, which are technically challenging in a way – intimate scenes and fight scenes are more challenging because you can’t get that close to each other.&nbsp;In terms of suits and the studio – we were in a different studio but it felt very similar.</em></p>



<p><em>In terms of extracurricular training, there isn’t a tonne. Most of us have done a basic level to get us to a good enough level, but when it becomes stunts, <strong>it becomes stunts</strong>, like it would on any other production. In terms of weaponry, we’ve got loads of photos and we’ll show them at various points, but the actual weapons are just hilarious, like polystyrene. That’s how they’re supposed to look, that’s how they look in every other motion capture studio, but they don’t look like the kind of beautiful, ornate, intimidating weapons you’ll see.</em>‘</p>



<p>It was recently revealed that the voice acting portion of the production had wrapped up after a whopping 500 hours of studio time. Not being familiar with how that worked from an acting perspective, I engaged McKay with a question about the process:</p>



<p><strong>McKay: </strong><em>‘The first chapter of our involvement is the motion capture. We finished about two years ago, and on this occasion, it was two big chunks of roughly about six or seven weeks each. Those were separated by a period of maybe about four or five months. That was very much the kind of first brick in the wall from the acting perspective. From a developmental perspective, there’s a huge amount of work and a huge amount of people heavily involved well before any of us actors turn up. That was the same for the first time, it was even more so the case for this game because it’s much bigger. We’re relatively late to the party in that respect.</em></p>



<p><em>The guys at Warhorse were very considerate about everything, but particularly about sort of ‘vocal stamina’ because there were so many lines for Henry. Anything the player can say in any iteration of the game has to be recorded, which is why it’s such a huge volume of material. I had to do eight-hour sessions, whereas most actors would do four-hour sessions because it’s more manageable vocally, but in terms of just getting through it, we realised that the only way we’d hit the targets and the deadlines was to just do eight-hour days. We started with the more vocally smooth stuff and then if there was any intense barking or anything like that, that was at the end of the day. And actually, the last day was about an hour of just absolute full-on screaming and yelling.’</em></p>



<p>Naturally, McKay couldn’t reveal any details about the game, but he did mention that the core ‘feel’ of the product is relatively the same as the first title:</p>



<p><strong>McKay: </strong><em>‘I’m not going to speak too much about that because I’m not sure how much I’m allowed to say. I’m very much understood from all the feedback that the realistic element was key and a big part of its USP and it’s what made it harder but my understanding is that it’s what made it really enjoyable. My understanding is that the very realistic element, the immersive element, is still very much the heart of this game.</em>‘</p>



<h2 id="h-deliverance">Deliverance</h2>



<figure></figure>







<p>Kingdom Come: Deliverance II is reportedly ‘at least twice the size’ of the first game, both in terms of the map space available and the overall scope of the project. It’s an ambitious undertaking that is much more technically advanced than the first game, which was made evident by the stunning trailer that Warhorse Studios showcased little more than a month ago. </p>



<p>McKay confirmed he’d never played the first game as he ‘isn’t a massive gamer’, but he pledged to give Kingdom Come: Deliverance II a shot:</p>



<p><strong>McKay: </strong><em>‘Most of the staff I know very well on a personal level now, we’ve become very good friends, because you would never work with a team like this for that length of time at those close quarters in any other game. I see more consistently just by being in the office what’s being executed day in, and day out, and it’s absolutely mindblowing. Yeah, I will definitely be playing this game. In terms of my technical ability to play it well, that’s another matter.’</em></p>



<p>It isn’t yet known when Kingdom Come: Deliverance II will be released, but we’ve been given a window of 2024 – so within a few months, we’ll be back and in control of Henry of Skalitz, continuing the vast adventure that was kicked off way back in 2018.</p>



<p>If you want to stay connected with Tom McKay, you can <a href="https://www.instagram.com/thisistommckay/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">follow him on Instagram</a>. Alternatively, you can check out what <a href="https://x.com/WarhorseStudios/">Warhorse Studios is doing on Twitter</a>.</p>



<hr>





									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[With Two "Very Ambitious" Games In The Works, Baldur's Gate 3 Dev Opens New Office]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/with-two-very-ambitious-games-in-the-works-baldurs-gate-3-dev-opens-new-office/1100-6523563/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/with-two-very-ambitious-games-in-the-works-baldurs-gate-3-dev-opens-new-office.875727/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/with-two-very-ambitious-games-in-the-works-baldurs-gate-3-dev-opens-new-office/1100-6523563/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6523563">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Baldur's Gate 3 developer Larian Studios has announced the opening of its newest studio. Located in Poland, the company's seventh studio worldwide--Larian Studios Warsaw--will assist in the development of the company's upcoming unannounced games.</p><p>"With two very ambitious RPGs now starting development, what better way to see our visions realized than by growing the team and opening a seventh studio in the heart of Poland's lively gaming scene!" the company <a href="https://x.com/larianstudios/status/1792495491256664211" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">wrote on social media</a>.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="1906655105" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6461994,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;13%20Combat%20Tips%20For%20Baldur%E2%80%99s%20Gate%203&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:480,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/13-combat-tips-for-baldurs-gate-3\/2300-6461994\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6461994\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6461994\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6461994\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6461994&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6461994,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6523563&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;baldurs-gate-3&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;role-playing&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;pc,stadia,macintosh,playstation-5,xbox-series-x,xbox-one,playstation-4&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;larian-studios,spike-chunsoft&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;franchise&quot;:&quot;baldurs-gate&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;franchiseRoot&quot;:&quot;dungeons-dragons&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6461994},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6461994\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;GameSpot&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1823\/18237460\/4173866-bg3_combattips_site.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/BRYpS6Ux.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1691157600,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="BRYpS6Ux" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> 13 Combat Tips For Baldur’s Gate 3</p>
      </div>
<p>The new team in Warsaw joins Larian's existing studios in Ghent, Barcelona, Dublin, Guildford, Quebec, and Kuala Lumpur. There are <a href="https://larian.com/careers/location/warsaw?location=warsaw" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">numerous open positions available at the Warsaw office</a> across a variety of disciplines.</p><p>The announcement of Larian Studios Warsaw comes just days after Activision announced the opening of a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/activision-announces-new-studio-making-all-new-franchise/1100-6523503/" data-ref-id="1100-6523503">new studio Elsewhere Entertainment, which is also based in Warsaw.</a> Other gaming companies with offices in Warsaw include CD Projekt and 11 Bit.</p><p>Larian has not announced its next game, but it will not be another Dungeons &amp; Dragons title. Larian is <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/larian-isnt-making-baldurs-gate-4-next-thats-not-what-we-were-made-for/1100-6522049/" data-ref-id="1100-6522049">moving beyond the fantasy series and creating something new</a>, though <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/hasbro-hopes-next-baldurs-gate-game-is-here-before-2050/1100-6522712/" data-ref-id="1100-6522712">Hasbro has said it intends to do more with Baldur's Gate in the gaming landscape.</a></p><p dir="ltr">"That's not what we were made for," <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/larian-isnt-making-baldurs-gate-4-next-thats-not-what-we-were-made-for/1100-6522049/" data-ref-id="1100-6522049">Larian boss Swen Vincke said about making Baldur's Gate 4</a>. "That's literally the opposite of what Larian is about. We want to do big, new things. We don't want to rehash the thing that we've done already."</p><p dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/baldurs-gate-3-dev-is-working-toward-an-rpg-that-dwarfs-it/1100-6522051/" data-ref-id="1100-6522051">Speaking to GameSpot</a>, Vincke explained that Larian's next game won't actually be the company's super-ambitious "very big RPG," but will be a step toward realizing it.</p><p dir="ltr">"I think there is some tech that we don't have yet," Vincke said. "And I don't know what the specs are on the next-gen [of gaming systems] yet, but I hope that it's going to bring us closer."</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Early Access ImSim Gloomwood gets its next big content update this month]]></title>
            <link>https://www.destructoid.com/early-access-imsim-gloomwood-gets-its-next-big-content-update-this-month/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=early-access-imsim-gloomwood-gets-its-next-big-content-update-this-month</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/early-access-imsim-gloomwood-gets-its-next-big-content-update-this-month.875721/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.destructoid.com/early-access-imsim-gloomwood-gets-its-next-big-content-update-this-month/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=early-access-imsim-gloomwood-gets-its-next-big-content-update-this-month<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p data-characters="301" data-injectable="true" data-video="true">Immersive sims are an <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/weekly-kusoge-die-hard-nes-immersive-sim-retro/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">odd and exceedingly specific niche</a> that some players just don’t feel like dealing with, <em>but</em> those who enjoy them play all of them. If you’re a fan, too, then you’ll be thrilled to hear that <em>Gloomwood</em>‘s next major update is coming very, very soon. Kind of!</p> <p data-characters="558" data-current-count="558" data-injectable="true">More specifically, <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/gloomwood-is-a-fun-blend-of-survival-horror-and-immersive-sim/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Gloomwood</em> is an Early Access ImSim</a> that’s going through a slow and meticulous production process headed by the developer Dillon Rogers. The game’s next major update, titled ‘The Underport’ had been slated for mid-2024 for some time at this point, but plans have now changed, and the chunk of content featured in it was so substantial that <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1150760/view/6009568738059053793" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">it had to be sliced in half</a>. The Underport is now, therefore, <em>two</em> updates instead of one, and its first half, titled ‘The Power Station’ is coming later this month.</p>
 <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"><figcaption>Image via Dillon Rogers</figcaption></figure> <h2 id="h-gloomwood-s-power-station-level-is-coming-this-month-the-hive-is-on-the-horizon" data-injectable="false">Gloomwood’s Power Station level is coming this month, The Hive is on the horizon</h2> <p data-characters="374" data-current-count="674" data-injectable="true"><em>Gloomwood</em> first launched via Steam Early Access in <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/gloomwood-early-access-august-16-trailer-pc-new-blood/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">August 2022</a>, and the game has been iterating upon its immersive sim core ever since. While the fact that the Underport has bifurcated into two separate releases is a bit sad, the flip side of the equation is that we’ll soon have a sizeable new chunk of <em>Gloomwood</em> goodness to tide us over. A fair trade, I’d say.</p>
 <p data-characters="250" data-current-count="250" data-injectable="false">At this time, we don’t know when the second half of the Underport, now known as ‘The Hive’ might be coming out. Presumably, it’s still slated for 2024, but we’ll need to wait and see what Rogers has to say on that front.</p> <p data-characters="436" data-current-count="686" data-injectable="true">The bit that we do know for a fact, though, is that <em>Gloomwood</em> still has a fairly long and storied road ahead of it. As per <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1150760/view/4182228661134367002" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the previous bit of news about the Underdark update</a>, Rogers intends to focus on the aptly titled Research Update after all of its content comes out: “[Research] will allow the doctor to take body parts from enemies back to the lab at the lighthouse in order to study them and gain new abilities.” Fun!</p>
 <p data-characters="232" data-current-count="232" data-injectable="false">After the Research Update, Rogers explained his team will be working on the ‘Bank’ level, which is due to introduce a high-tech section of the city, which is a wholly different brand of excitement, all things considered.</p> <p data-characters="311" data-current-count="543" data-injectable="false">So, it’s slow going, but <em>Gloomwood</em>‘s been nothing short of great so far, and ImSim fans are used to waiting anyway. Especially now, with <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/the-people-making-the-games-keep-paying-the-price/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the studio behind the legendary <em>Prey</em></a> sadly about to close down. For those who’d like to play <em>Gloomwood</em> in its 1.0 form, all I can say is – stay tuned.</p>

<hr>
<p><i data-stringify-type="italic"> Destructoid is supported by our audience. When you purchase through links on our site, we may earn a small affiliate commission.&nbsp;</i><i data-stringify-type="italic"><a href="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-stringify-link="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" data-sk="tooltip_parent">Learn more</a></i> </p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[XDefiant is the perfect place for a modern take on Assassin’s Creed Assassins vs Templars]]></title>
            <link>https://www.destructoid.com/xdefiant-is-the-perfect-place-for-a-modern-take-on-assassins-creed-assassins-vs-templars/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=xdefiant-is-the-perfect-place-for-a-modern-take-on-assassins-creed-assassins-vs-templars</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/xdefiant-is-the-perfect-place-for-a-modern-take-on-assassin%E2%80%99s-creed-assassins-vs-templars.875718/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.destructoid.com/xdefiant-is-the-perfect-place-for-a-modern-take-on-assassins-creed-assassins-vs-templars/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=xdefiant-is-the-perfect-place-for-a-modern-take-on-assassins-creed-assassins-vs-templars<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p data-characters="358" data-injectable="true" data-video="true">In Ubisoft’s <em>XDefiant</em>, factions from across the publisher’s various video game franchises battle it out for supremacy using equipment and abilities unique to them based on the way they behave in their respective properties. But I’ve noticed a shocking lack of <em>Assassin’s Creed</em> factions, and I think they’d work incredibly well. </p> <p data-characters="391" data-current-count="391" data-injectable="false">Since the original <em>Assassin’s Creed</em>, the Assassins/Hidden Ones and Templars/The Order of the Ancients have been battling it out for control over Pieces of Eden and, in the greater scheme of things, the world. While the sci-fi elements of these Pieces of Eden give someone the power to influence the world, these factions have been fighting on a much more grounded level for centuries. </p> <figure data-current-count="691" data-injectable="true"><figcaption>Image via Ubisoft</figcaption></figure>
 <p data-characters="356" data-current-count="356" data-injectable="false">Each game sees those who are part of or who work with both factions use weapons from the current time period to head into battle against one another or strike on a much more personal level. Even the iconic Hidden Blades are melee weapons that are ever so slightly altered over time to provide an advantage for that period or the protagonist wielding them. </p> <p data-characters="348" data-current-count="704" data-injectable="true">The one aspect that many other fans and I think we don’t see enough of in the series is the modern-day Assassins and Templars going head-to-head. There are scenes where Templars are allegedly storming a building, or Assassins are coming to help, but we don’t often see the weapons they use or their tactics. <em>XDefiant</em> could change this. </p>
 <p data-characters="365" data-current-count="365" data-injectable="false">Every <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/xdefiant-all-factions-and-their-abilities-explained/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">faction in <em>XDefiant</em></a> exists in roughly the same time period. For example, <em>The Division</em>‘s Cleaners and <em>Far Cry 6</em>‘s Libertad are arguably on the low-tech end of the scale, while Echelon, the Phantoms, and DedSec all use high-tech equipment, but they’re all balanced when it comes to weapons and abilities so none of them has a clear advantage. </p> <figure data-current-count="665" data-injectable="true"><figcaption>Image via Ubisoft</figcaption></figure>
 <p data-characters="417" data-current-count="417" data-injectable="true">This means you can play as a guerrilla fighter with equipment held together with duct tape, hopes, dreams, and something sticky from the side of the road against modern-day ninjas who can become invisible. Each faction feels like it’s been pulled directly from its setting without being altered too much, and they feel as though they fit with their own lore but also bring the lore of their own games together. </p>
 <p data-characters="361" data-current-count="361" data-injectable="false">With <em>Assassin’s Creed</em>, we have two factions to choose from. The Assassins are definitely the more interesting of the two, so that’s the one I’d like to see implemented most. While they’d need guns to stand a chance in any match, they could follow Echelon and specialize in smaller, quieter weapons but double down on abilities and gear. </p> <p data-characters="444" data-current-count="805" data-injectable="true">For example, smoke grenades would provide a fantastic cover to get in close to enemies, especially if an altered camouflage can be used to hide them in their own smoke. From there, Assassins could use a stylized modern Hidden Blade to kill enemies, with a silenced pistol for close encounters that go wrong. At most, this faction should have a mid-range weapon, but it would need to be close-range focused to make the most of the Hidden Blade. </p>
 <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"><figcaption>Image via Ubisoft</figcaption></figure> <p data-characters="408" data-current-count="708" data-injectable="true">As for the Templars, they specialize in control, so a faction that somehow dominates the battlefield would be best. I imagine them using advanced weaponry, including sniper rifles, to give them an advantage no matter where they are. I also think that abilities that buff damage when surrounded by enemies would feel right because they’ve always attempted to topple civilizations in groups from within. </p>
 <p data-characters="324" data-current-count="324" data-injectable="false">What would tie these factions together well are powerful abilities that mirror one another. For example, the Templars could have deployable spawn points for their allies, and Assassins could have an ability that draws their teammates to them and protects them as they approach, like Ezio whistling for backup before a kill. </p> <p data-characters="283" data-current-count="607" data-injectable="true">Ubisoft could use dozens of potential abilities to bring<em> Assassin’s Creed</em> into the <em>XDefiant</em> universe, and I believe it would do a great job of it. Regardless of how they work, I know I would be incredibly excited to see and play around as a modern-day Assassin and/or Templar. </p>
 <p data-characters="377" data-current-count="377" data-injectable="false">That aspect of the universe feels like the best storyline in a good novel, the one that’s told through a few pages every three chapters or so and ends up being the only reason you finish the book. I always desperately want to see a fight between an Assassin with a laser-edged Hidden Blade and a Templar with a high-tech sword in each game, but we never quite get to it. </p> <p data-characters="367" data-current-count="744" data-injectable="false">I can understand developers wanting to keep that sort of thing out of a series that’s based on history, but <em>XDefiant</em> brings factions to life like never before. Just like how history is the playground for <em>Assassin’s Creed</em>, <em>XDefiant</em> could be the perfect playground for Assassins and Templars if Ubisoft is willing to take a leap of faith and throw them in. </p>

<hr>
<p><i data-stringify-type="italic"> Destructoid is supported by our audience. When you purchase through links on our site, we may earn a small affiliate commission.&nbsp;</i><i data-stringify-type="italic"><a href="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-stringify-link="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" data-sk="tooltip_parent">Learn more</a></i> </p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Is Rebirth Island leaving Warzone?]]></title>
            <link>https://www.destructoid.com/is-rebirth-island-leaving-warzone/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=is-rebirth-island-leaving-warzone</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/is-rebirth-island-leaving-warzone.875715/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.destructoid.com/is-rebirth-island-leaving-warzone/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=is-rebirth-island-leaving-warzone<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p data-characters="291" data-injectable="true" data-video="true"><em>Call of Duty</em> fans were delighted to see Rebirth Island return to <em>Warzone</em> in April 2024, but now fans are wondering if it will leave, and when it could disappear if true. That’s why we’ve put together everything we know about <em>Warzone</em>‘s Rebirth Island and its possible exit. </p> <p data-characters="315" data-current-count="315" data-injectable="false">Rebirth Island made its triumphant return to <em>Call of Duty</em>‘s battle royale on April 3, and <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/warzone-players-are-demanding-changes-to-sick-joke-rebirth-island-audio/">despite issues with audio</a>, has been welcomed back with open arms. However, some players fear that <em>Warzone</em>‘s map rotation system will mean that it will disappear for months at a time, leaving us unable to play it. </p> <figure data-current-count="615" data-injectable="true"><figcaption>Rebirth Island is only back, but it could disappear again. Image via Activision </figcaption></figure>
 <h2 id="h-is-rebirth-island-going-to-leave-warzone" data-injectable="false">Is <em>Rebirth Island </em>going to leave <em>Warzone</em>?</h2> <p data-characters="142" data-current-count="142" data-injectable="false">While it hasn’t been confirmed by Activision yet, <strong>we do expect that Rebirth Island will be included in the <em>Warzone</em> map rotation system.</strong> </p> <p data-characters="206" data-current-count="348" data-injectable="false">That means it could be swapped out for Fortune’s Keep, Ashika Island, or Vondel. This process also sees modes moved in and out of rotation, with Solo, Duos, Trios, and Quads all on the chopping list. </p> <h2 data-injectable="false">When could Rebirth Island leave <em>Warzone</em>?</h2> <p data-characters="323" data-current-count="671" data-injectable="true">We don’t know for sure, but we know that Rebirth Island won’t leave until at least May 23, when the next rotation is set to be announced. <strong>The most likely</strong> scenario is that it exits the game on May 29 when <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/when-does-mw3-and-warzone-season-4-start/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Warzone</em> Season 4</a> starts, but we’ll be sure to update this article when we get official confirmation. </p>
 <p data-characters="293" data-current-count="293" data-injectable="false">Don’t panic when it does eventually exit though, as the rotation system means it’s very likely to return before the next <em>CoD</em> game releases in autumn 2024. You’ll have plenty of opportunities to run Rebirth Island before the rumored return of Verdansk, that’s for sure. </p>
<hr>
<p><i data-stringify-type="italic"> Destructoid is supported by our audience. When you purchase through links on our site, we may earn a small affiliate commission.&nbsp;</i><i data-stringify-type="italic"><a href="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-stringify-link="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" data-sk="tooltip_parent">Learn more</a></i> </p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Life in Reterra is the highly replayable board game that now lives rent-free in my family room]]></title>
            <link>https://www.polygon.com/reviews/24158546/life-in-reterra-board-game-review</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/life-in-reterra-is-the-highly-replayable-board-game-that-now-lives-rent-free-in-my-family-room.875700/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.polygon.com/reviews/24158546/life-in-reterra-board-game-review<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>If you buy something from a Polygon link, Vox Media may earn a commission. See our <a href="https://www.polygon.com/pages/ethics-statement" target="_blank">ethics statement</a>.</p><div>
  <p id="I8gmhm">A good board game has a lot of layers to it. Narrative layers surround and define a board game’s storyline, while mechanical layers govern the moment-to-moment action. More complex games have a rich strategic layer, with players trying to outfox each other over multiple turns or games. There’s always a social layer as well, which can be as simple as gathering people together to play, or as nuanced as the communication and negotiation skills required to excel at <em>Catan</em>. But <a href="https://www.polygon.com/tabletop-games/24091734/life-in-reterra-eric-lang-interview"><em>Life in Reterra</em></a>, a new <a href="https://www.polygon.com/tabletop-games">board game</a> designed by <a href="https://www.polygon.com/2016/8/10/12416080/gencon-diana-jones-trophy-burned-book-eric-lang">Eric M. Lang</a> and Ken Gruhl with art by <a href="https://mendolaart.com/artists/hugo-cuellar/">Hugo Cuellar</a>, has a layer that many other games don’t — a creative layer. That makes it one of the year’s most interesting new titles.</p>

<p id="G257dd"><em>Life in Reterra</em> posits a far future where urban centers have been taken back by nature, and where notions of humanity’s past exist only as artifacts. It’s up to players to rebuild those cities as they see fit. The art style reflects that conceit well, with brightly colored tiles filled with different biomes as well as the occasional relic, like a smartphone. Players score points for organizing these biomes into contiguous sections, filling the table in front of them with green spaces, deserts, and cheerful lakes or streams.</p>
<p id="qAv3Ys">But the land itself is only the game’s first layer. As players place those tiles, they must constantly consider their orientation in order to create the largest and most valuable biomes that they can, but also to create the foundations needed to place specially shaped buildings on top. And it’s in the placement of these buildings that the game begins to show its true potential.</p>
<p id="cJEjm5">The buildings in <em>Life in Reterra</em> are organized into three different sets, each more complex than the last. In the game’s “starter set,” gardens are worth additional points, but only if you have the largest segment of contiguous terrain on the table. Schools are worth extra points for each different type of relic that you have on the board, and so on. There are three sets in all, presenting a total of 30 different buildings inside the box.</p>
<p>  <figure>
  <span>
    
    <span data-original="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25452810/B88A9940.jpg">
      
        <picture data-cid="site/picture_element-1716213618_5202_15504" data-cdata="{&quot;asset_id&quot;:25452810,&quot;ratio&quot;:&quot;*&quot;}">
  


  <source srcset="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/91-NV7RoaoLdOeXg-N6S9WVSbLc=/0x0:3000x1688/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x1688):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25452810/B88A9940.jpg 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/b7imiL9hZJUiMZuJ2T0iNtrAK0g=/0x0:3000x1688/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x1688):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25452810/B88A9940.jpg 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/lF4g3o5YPVdurh01A9DPsmvWlNw=/0x0:3000x1688/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x1688):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25452810/B88A9940.jpg 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hcDjRw6p5jHKfmdGv167oYTrQtc=/0x0:3000x1688/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x1688):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25452810/B88A9940.jpg 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/JE_6594krELYbI2bM3_USiRa9QY=/0x0:3000x1688/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x1688):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25452810/B88A9940.jpg 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/HtnM_IH2EqGjCB-8BNeFRpQS9xE=/0x0:3000x1688/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x1688):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25452810/B88A9940.jpg 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ONBPj4OVHN0_ltGfWCR_r1XZPiM=/0x0:3000x1688/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x1688):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25452810/B88A9940.jpg 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nnaPP1VWCXTjX7CMggMmD3eWfQw=/0x0:3000x1688/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x1688):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25452810/B88A9940.jpg 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/tWp0t5JrR-ABXgibEgvLYVUpAyc=/0x0:3000x1688/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x1688):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25452810/B88A9940.jpg 1920w" sizes="90vw" type="image/webp">




</picture>

      
    </span>
    
  </span>
  
    <span>
      
        <figcaption>The game board in <em>Life in Reterra</em>, shown in the upper right, helps merely to facilitate setup and play. All the action takes place in front of the players, with tiles that they lay out to create their own community from scratch.</figcaption>
      
      
        <cite>Photo: Charlie Hall/Polygon</cite>
      
    </span>
  
</figure>


</p>
<p id="OAhcCO">Beyond the starter set, the manual for <em>Life in Reterra</em> includes just four more “curated building sets.” The Unfriendly Neighbors Set is confrontational, with players using buildings in ways that dramatically impact the other players at the table. The Peace &amp; Quiet Set, has very very little interaction between players. Meanwhile, the Popularity Contest Set sits somewhere in between. In this way, the game’s mechanical layer can be swapped out at will. Once you make it deep enough into the manual, <em>Life in Reterra</em> becomes something of a platform, a system capable of being different games for different audiences at different times.</p>
<p id="4bZBp5">And then, on the 14th page of the manual, <em>Life in Reterra </em>does something remarkable: It asks players to curate their own sets of buildings to play with. “My Building Sets” reads the two-page spread, revealing a blank worksheet with room for four new ways to play that players can create all on their own.</p>
<p id="P7hNGX">With this final creative layer, <em>Life in Reterra</em> invites players to become designers themselves. The manual, as expertly written as it is, vanishes into the background to become merely a point of reference. The rules are there to facilitate play, not to dictate what the nature of that play should be. In the end, it’s up to individuals to make their own fun, rebuilding the game to meet their needs even as they rebuild the land itself. It’s a bold move — especially for a game targeted at mass market retailers.</p>
<p id="Z5xcKJ">At the same time that Lang, Gruhl, and publisher Hasbro have brought their multi-layered, open-ended design to the toy aisles at Target, they have also elected to bring some of high-end board gaming’s boutique fit and finish as well. <em>Life in Reterra</em> isn’t just a cheap box of cardboard bits and plastic movers. The cards are hefty with a nice linen finish, the wooden meeples are screen-printed, the elegant manual saddle-stitched, and all of the components are stored inside modular plastic trays with transparent lids. Cracking it open, this game looks and feels like something you’d get in the mail after a successful Kickstarter campaign.</p>

<p id="u4lsVb"><a href="https://www.polygon.com/tabletop-games/24091734/life-in-reterra-eric-lang-interview">When I interviewed Lang earlier this year</a>, he called <em>Life in Reterra </em>a “lifestyle game.” At the time, I took that to mean a game that would welcome novices into the larger board gaming hobby and encourage them to make board games a part of their lives. But something more like the opposite is true. <em>Life in Reterra</em> is an incredibly solid and resilient design, which like a collectible card game can be mixed and remixed into multiple different experiences. It is also a game that respects the player’s time, and a physical product that’s built to last. For that reason alone it’s found a permanent place in our home — not in the closet or on a shelf, but right in the middle of the coffee table.</p>
<p id="VnI7Ez">Now, mixed in with all the other urgent detritus of our modern lives — remote controls and smartphones, chewed-up pencils, junk mail, and half-finished homework — is our family’s new favorite board game. <em>Life in Reterra</em> has become something that we return to on a weekly basis, and even when we’re not playing, sometimes we just daydream about the building sets we might come up with for the next go-around.</p>
<p id="rH1MdH"><em>Life in Reterra</em> hasn’t changed our family’s lifestyle, but it has managed to worm its way into it. I think it might easily find a place in your home, too. </p>
<hr id="18E1fj">




  
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What is the Arena Breakout Infinite Release Date? – Answered]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/what-is-the-arena-breakout-infinite-release-date-answered/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/what-is-the-arena-breakout-infinite-release-date-%E2%80%93-answered.875697/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/what-is-the-arena-breakout-infinite-release-date-answered/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>If you were one of the lucky few—or many, considering they were handing out beta keys like candy—then you’re likely pretty excited about the Arena Breakout Infinite release date, right? It plays like a free-to-play shooter but with a lot more complexity that should entice casual players from Escape From Tarkov. Being F2P certainly helps, too. So, when’s it coming out?</p>



<h2 id="h-when-is-the-arena-breakout-infinite-release-date">When is the Arena Breakout Infinite Release Date?</h2>



<p>As of right now, we don’t know the official release date for Arena Breakout Infinite. The studio is still working through the closed beta period, which they said they’ll extend. It’ll likely run until some point this week, around May 22. As for an actual release date for the full version of the game, no one knows just yet.</p>



<p>Considering how well-optimized the beta experience felt from a gameplay perspective, I don’t imagine it’ll take long to iron out any bugs and tweak gameplay mechanics and loadouts. Developer Morefun Studios genuinely wants to compete with many of the big-name extraction shooters, namely <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/is-escape-from-tarkov-full-of-cheaters-answered/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Escape From Tarkov</a>, and they’re seemingly willing to put in the work.</p>







<h2 id="h-is-arena-breakout-infinite-like-escape-from-tarkov">Is Arena Breakout Infinite Like Escape From Tarkov?</h2>



<p>In many ways, yeah, Arena Breakout Infinite is quite similar to Escape From Tarkov. It’s an extraction shooter, albeit with a bit more casual playstyle, that heavily focuses on action and loot, like the latter. </p>



<p>Straight off the bat, Arena Breakout Infinite introduces a tutorial that guides you through many of the key systems, including how to properly prepare for a raid with the inventory and loadout mechanics. It’s a useful tooltip that should help many new players find their footing.</p>



<p>Secondly, the overall combat feels more fluid and action-oriented. Whereas Escape From Tarkov is more realistic and hardcore, which can alienate many first-person shooter fans who want something more accessible.</p>



<p>I think both will have their place in the gaming sphere. Arena Breakout Infinite, being free-to-play and casual-friendly, will entice newcomers to the extraction shooter genre. Escape From Tarkov, on the other hand, caters to more hardcore players who enjoy the complexity and realism.</p>



<hr>



<p>Insider Gaming publishes daily pieces about your favorite games; feel free to check out what we’re putting up lately:</p>



									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Baldur’s Gate 3 Developer Larian Studios Opening New Studio in Warsaw]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/baldurs-gate-3-developer-larian-studios-opening-new-studio-in-warsaw/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/baldur%E2%80%99s-gate-3-developer-larian-studios-opening-new-studio-in-warsaw.875694/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/baldurs-gate-3-developer-larian-studios-opening-new-studio-in-warsaw/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>In <a href="https://x.com/larianstudios/status/1792495491256664211" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a new post</a> on Twitter/X today, Larian Studios confirmed that it is opening a seventh studio located in Warsaw. </p>



<p>Larian plans to reveal more about Larian Studios Warsaw, including job openings, during the Digital Dragons event beginning today. The devs appear very interested in adding new talent to the Warsaw studio.</p>



<p>Larian Studios explains that it’s the right time to grow the team “with two very ambitious RPGs now starting development.”</p>



<figure><div>
<blockquote data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>*obtains condition Enlarged*</p><p>With two very ambitious RPGs now starting development, what better way to see our visions realised than by growing the team and opening a 7th studio in the heart of Poland’s lively gaming scene!</p><p>Welcome, Larian Studios Warsaw! <a href="https://t.co/hpm2aMdQmy">pic.twitter.com/hpm2aMdQmy</a></p></div>— Larian Studios (@larianstudios) <a href="https://twitter.com/larianstudios/status/1792495491256664211?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">May 20, 2024</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>



<p>Larian <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/larian-studios-is-working-on-two-new-games/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">officially confirmed</a> it began work on two new games last April in a community post. However, the devs consistently make it clear they are not planning to develop new material for Baldur’s Gate.</p>



<p>Despite the enormous success of Baldur’s Gate 3, the devs confirmed they will not work on DLC or a sequel <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/larian-studios-baldurs-gate/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">during a GDC panel</a>. </p>



<p>This will surely disappoint fans of the popular RPG. However, Hasbro did announce in April that it’s still interested in making <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/baldurs-gate-4-next-game/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">another Baldur’s Gate game</a>, even without Larian. In an interview, Hasbro’s Eugene Evans added that “we’re going to take our time and find the right partner.”</p>



<p>Larian Studios Warsaw will likely work on original IP, and the new studio marks a major opportunity as the industry continues to face layoffs. </p>



<p>Both large and small developers, such as Mighty Kingdom, recently reduced employees. Last month, GTA 6 publisher Take-Two announced it would lay off <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/gta-6-take-two-layoffs/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">5% of its workforce</a> and cancel anticipated games.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more of the latest Insider Gaming news, you can read about the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/multiversus-trailer-teases-jason-voorhees-agent-smith-more/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">new MultiVersus trailer</a> teasing Jason Voorhees and more, and sign up to receive <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/newsletter/">our official newsletter</a>.</p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Larian Studios opens Warsaw studio]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/05/larian-studios-opens-warsaw-studio</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/larian-studios-opens-warsaw-studio.875691/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/05/larian-studios-opens-warsaw-studio<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
        </ul>

    
    <p><span>Baldur's Gate III developer's seventh studio.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><em><a title="Games > Baldur's Gate III [24 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/baldurs-gate-iii">Baldur’s Gate III</a></em> developer <a title="Companies > Larian Studios [38 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/larian-studios">Larian Studios</a> has <a href="https://twitter.com/larianstudios/status/1792495491256664211" rel="noopener" target="_blank">announced</a> the opening of a new studio based in Warsaw, Poland. <span id="more-883604"></span></p><p>Larian Studios Warsaw is Larian Studios’ seventh studio, joining a global team of sister studios based in Quebec, Dublin, Guildford, Barcelona, Ghent, and Kuala Lumpur.</p><p>“The decision to open a permanent studio in Warsaw shows how serious we are about encouraging creativity, collaboration, and innovation in the heart of Poland’s lively gaming scene,” said Larian Studios Warsaw head of studio Ula Jach in a press release. “We’re thrilled for the opportunity to collaborate with the abundant talent and expertise of the region, especially considering Poland’s strong reputation as a hub for RPG and gaming enthusiasts.”</p><p>Larian Studios CEO Swen Vincke added, “Visiting the Game Industry Conference last year confirmed what I’d been thinking for a while—there’s a lot of talent here and a lot of devs who think like us. On top of that, many of them want to work on <a title="Genres > RPG [16,259 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg">RPGs</a>, so it’s a match made in heaven.</p><p>“Our plan for the Polish studio is very simple. Build a team that can work on our two—very ambitious—new RPGs and enjoy the fruits of their labor. We’re a very bottom-up company, so I’m eager to see what new things they’ll bring us. I think it’ll work really well.”</p><p>Job openings are available now on Larian Studios’ <a href="https://larian.com/careers/location/warsaw?location=warsaw" target="_blank" rel="noopener">careers website</a>.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[10 Years Later, Transistor's Artistic Rebellion Is More Necessary Than Ever]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/transistor-artistic-rebellion-is-more-necessary-than-ever/1100-6523517/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/10-years-later-transistors-artistic-rebellion-is-more-necessary-than-ever.875688/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/transistor-artistic-rebellion-is-more-necessary-than-ever/1100-6523517/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6523517">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr"><em>Transistor is celebrating its 10-year anniversary today, May 20, 2024. Below, we recall how its vision of the future was more prescient than we'd realized at first glance.</em></p><p dir="ltr">In 2014, a singer having her voice captured and digitized against her will was a novel sci-fi conceit. Ten years later, it sounds eerily familiar. With the ever-increasing presence of AI and deep fakes, as well as digital homogenization all around us, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/transistor/">Transistor's</a> tale of payback against the Camerata doubles back as a prescient artistic rebellion.</p><p dir="ltr">Designers, journalists, and painters were all targeted by the elite group one by one. The Camerata methodically ripped the city of Cloudbank of not just key citizens, but also character and grace. As protagonist Red cruises through the fading streets of Cloudbank, she witnesses how her surroundings lose color, progressively matching the Camerata's attire. Yet, despite the odds, Transistor reminds us of the importance of latching onto mundanity, and what represents us.</p><p dir="ltr">One of the first examples you encounter is the work of Amelia Garbur, an associate editor who covers the slow decay of Cloudbank. The story of Transistor is told in snippets, emphasizing environmental cues and bite-sized details for you to piece together what transpired in a disappearing district or inside a room before your arrival. Therein come the OVC Terminals, which are posted across the city and offer either surveys or news reported by Garbur, informing the citizens of the latest developments outside their homes.</p><p dir="ltr">"Incident at the Empty Set," reads a headline detailing the events that transpired at the venue where Red was attacked. "Postponed: Hammers vs. Clientele," says another later that day, indicating that the two popular sports teams won't be playing after all. Toward the evening, "Traverson Hall Is Gone" marks a poignant beginning of the end.</p><p dir="ltr">Most of the citizens you encounter are either soon-to-be or already deceased. Red, using the namesake sword that was originally held by the Camerata, is able to retrieve a fragment of theirs and take them inside. Mechanically, doing so gives you a new ability to mix and match during combat. But this process also adds them to a database, providing information about who they were and what influential role they had in the city.</p><p dir="ltr">Garbur is one of the few characters who avoids this digitization. Instead, her work speaks for herself, right until the bitter end. "As I stand here on the eastern perimeter awaiting the inevitable, I am surrounded by my community, and I am at peace," reads the entry for "Farewell to Cloudbank."</p><div tabindex="0" data-id="791335653" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6418869,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Transistor%20Video%20Review&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:332,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:false,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/transistor-video-review\/2300-6418869\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6418869\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6418869\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6418869\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6418869&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6418869,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6523517&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;transistor&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;action,role-playing&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;pc,playstation-4,macintosh,linux,ios-iphoneipad,nintendo-switch&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;supergiant-games,limited-run-games&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6418869},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6418869\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;GameSpot&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1533\/15333573\/2536339-review_transistor_20140515.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/mt-rv-v1.gamespot.com\/vr\/2014\/05\/19\/REview_transistor_20140515_600,1000,1800,3200,4000,master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;adaptive_dash&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/mt-rv-v1.gamespot.com\/vr\/2014\/05\/19\/REview_transistor_20140515_600,1000,1800,3200,4000,master.mpd&quot;,&quot;adaptive_hd&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/mt-rv-v1.gamespot.com\/vr\/2014\/05\/19\/REview_transistor_20140515_4000,master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;adaptive_high&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/mt-rv-v1.gamespot.com\/vr\/2014\/05\/19\/REview_transistor_20140515_1800,master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;adaptive_low&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/mt-rv-v1.gamespot.com\/vr\/2014\/05\/19\/REview_transistor_20140515_600,master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;adaptive_restricted&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/mt-rv-v1.gamespot.com\/vr\/2014\/05\/19\/REview_transistor_20140515_600,1000,1800,master.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1400601600,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="TvuQwCL4" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle" data-embed-type="video" data-ref-id="2300-6418869" data-src="/videos/transistor-video-review/2300-6418869/" data-width="100%" data-height="100%" data-video-start="0"><div><p>Transistor Video Review</p><div><p>         Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?       </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!       </p></div></div><p>       Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.     </p><p>       This video has an invalid file format.     </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div><p dir="ltr">In late 2023, <a href="https://futurism.com/sports-illustrated-ai-generated-writers" rel="nofollow ">Futurism</a> reported on a series of articles in Sports Illustrated that were written by fake writers, their personal information and their work being AI-generated. Despite <a href="https://www.vox.com/technology/2023/7/18/23798164/gizmodo-ai-g-o-bot-stories-jalopnik-av-club-peter-kafka-media-column" rel="nofollow ">resistance from staff</a> under its suite, G/O Media <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/7/6/23785645/go-media-ai-generated-articles-gizmodo-av-club-artificial-intelligence-bots" rel="nofollow ">rolled out AI tools</a> in mid 2023, which quickly proved to just churn <a href="https://www.msnbc.com/opinion/msnbc-opinion/ai-articles-disinformation-future-g-o-media-rcna95944" rel="nofollow ">factually inaccurate pieces</a>. Others like <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/cnet-published-ai-generated-stories-then-its-staff-pushed-back/" rel="nofollow ">CNET</a> and <a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/business/business-news/buzzfeed-ai-creators-news-shut-down-1235483607/" rel="nofollow ">BuzzFeed</a>, the latter shuttering its news division in the process, followed suit. The integrity of the reporters doing the work every day was compromised for the sake of producing articles en masse, even when readers would quickly notice incongruences, as well as a simple lack of human touch.</p><p dir="ltr">The seemingly imposing push for AI extends beyond journalism. <a href="https://news.microsoft.com/fr-fr/2024/05/13/microsoft-announces-the-largest-investment-to-date-in-france-to-accelerate-the-adoption-of-ai-skilling-and-innovation/" rel="nofollow ">Microsoft</a> recently announced a 4 billion euro investment in cloud and AI infrastructure. If you've been trying to search for something on Google and received a garbled response, it's possible that <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2024/05/13/google-ai-search-io-sge/">it wasn't written by a human being</a> at all. From dating apps like <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/tech/internet/ai-personas-are-future-dating-bumble-founder-says-many-arent-buying-rcna151738" rel="nofollow ">Bumble</a> to <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/sag-aftra-approves-ai-voice-acting-for-video-games/1100-6520224/">voice acting</a> and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/square-enix-intends-to-be-aggressive-with-ai/1100-6520074/">development tools</a> for video games, CEOs and corporations are betting on a future where they can further automate not only jobs, but our everyday lives, despite the proven <a href="https://fortune.com/2024/01/22/ai-jobs-humans-cost-mit-study/" rel="nofollow ">monetary</a> and <a href="https://www.theverge.com/24066646/ai-electricity-energy-watts-generative-consumption" rel="nofollow ">environmental</a> costs, workers' livelihoods notwithstanding.</p><p dir="ltr">Sadly, AI also goes hand in hand with deep fakes, which are digitally generated images or videos that mimic the likeness of a real person, whether it is their image or their voice. During the Met Gala, images of artists like Rihanna and Katy Perry went viral, despite being fake. In Arizona, <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2024/05/08/arizona-election-workers-trained-with-deepfakes-prepare-2024/">workers are being trained</a> to prepare themselves for misleading images ahead of the 2024 elections. In March, New York representative Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez <a href="https://www.rollingstone.com/politics/politics-news/aoc-deepfakes-defiance-act-1234979373/" rel="nofollow ">announced</a> she's co-leading the <a href="https://www.durbin.senate.gov/imo/media/doc/defiance_act_of_2024.pdf" rel="nofollow ">Defiance Act of 2024</a>, which would allow <a href="https://www.vox.com/24145522/ai-deepfake-apps-teens-ban-laws" rel="nofollow ">victims of deep-fake</a> creations to sue the people behind them.</p><p dir="ltr">The dystopian future depicted in Transistor isn't filled with one-on-one premonitions of our current reality. Yet, the parallels hit too close to home for comfort. There's an enemy type that "attacks" Red by taking pictures of her. During New Game Plus, one of the bosses sings a corrupted, digitized rendition of the song that was played during the fight originally, mimicking Red's voice. Witnessing Cloudbank being consumed by a rampant and uniform process resonates with <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/02/05/arts/video-games-internet.html">digital homogenization</a>, and how human interactions are being diminished by the <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/first-gen-social-media-users-have-nowhere-to-go/" rel="nofollow ">online spaces</a> we inhabit.</p><p dir="ltr">Revisiting these themes through a modern-day lens can leave us with a defeated feeling. But the central message of Transistor is one of hope, not despair, reminding us that the human touch can be mimicked, but never replaced.</p><p dir="ltr">Red leaves the sword outside a restroom before entering, being playful while maintaining a now begone boundary with his partner, who's stuck inside of the weapon. Further into the story, she uses one of the OVC Terminals to communicate with her companion, if only for a brief moment, twisting the original purpose of leaving a comment under an article. Even without her voice, she can't stop herself from humming over the heart-soothing songs that play in the background throughout her entire journey, refusing to abandon her artistic spirit.</p><p dir="ltr">As companies continue to be hellbent on attempting to replace human identities, obsessed with the idea of succumbing to a reality forged by algorithms and faux tech revolutions, Transistor remains inspiring 10 years later. It's comforting to know that the silk in Red's dress remains silk until the bitter end, despite the attempts to imitate her liking. There's a special solace in knowing she's reading news from an actual human being, even as the city collapses around her.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/115652868521335484896?rel=author">Diego Nicolás Argüello</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Zelda: Tears Of The Kingdom Link Figma Collectible Preorders Back In Stock At Amazon]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-legend-of-zelda-link-figma-collectible-figure-preorder/1100-6521945/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/zelda-tears-of-the-kingdom-link-figma-collectible-preorders-back-in-stock-at-amazon.875685/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-legend-of-zelda-link-figma-collectible-figure-preorder/1100-6521945/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6521945">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>At long last, a Figma figure of Link from <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Legend-Zelda-Breath-Wild-Nintendo-Switch/dp/B097B2YWFX?tag=gamespot-promos-20&amp;tag=gamespot-buybutton-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom</a> is on the way. Figma toys are some of the best when it comes to striking a pose, as they have an incredible range of articulation, plenty of accessories, and fantastic detail. Legend of Zelda fans can choose from two Link figures to add to their collection, as the standard version and the DX edition are both up for preorder. Amazon initially sold out of its preorders for the standard and DX versions of the figure, but the standard edition is back in stock for $70. The figure doesn't release until next summer, but you won't be charged for your preorder at Amazon until your order ships.</p><ul><li><strong>Amazon</strong><ul><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CY2HHTGZ?tag=gamespot-preorders-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom Link Figma (Standard edition)</a> -- $70</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CY2BTL28?tag=gamespot-preorders-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom Link Figma (DX edition)</a> -- $136</li></ul></li><li><strong>Goodsmile</strong><ul><li><a href="https://www.goodsmileus.com/product/figma-link-tears-of-the-kingdom-ver-12490" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom Link Figma (Standard edition)</a> -- $61</li><li><a href="https://www.goodsmileus.com/product/figma-link-tears-of-the-kingdom-ver-dx-edition-12489" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom Link Figma (DX edition)</a> -- $116</li></ul></li></ul><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1595/15950357/4275751-linkfigma.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4275751" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1595/15950357/4275751-linkfigma.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4275751"></a><figcaption>The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom - Link Figma figure</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1595/15950357/4275751-linkfigma.jpeg"></figure><figure data-embed-type="gallery" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4275574-figmatotklink%281%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4275575-figmatotklink%282%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4275576-figmatotklink%283%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4275577-figmatotklink%284%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4275578-figmatotklink%285%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4275579-figmatotklink%286%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4275580-figmatotklink%287%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4275581-figmatotklink%288%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4275582-figmatotklink%289%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4275583-figmatotklink%2810%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4275584-figmatotklink%2811%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4275585-figmatotklink%2813%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4275586-figmatotklink%2814%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4275587-figmatotklink%2815%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4275588-figmatotklink%2816%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4275589-figmatotklink%2817%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4275590-figmatotklink%2818%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4275591-figmatotklink%2819%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4275592-figmatotklink%2820%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4275593-figmatotklink%2821%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4275594-figmatotklink%2822%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4275595-figmatotklink%2823%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4275596-figmatotklink%2824%29.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4275574,1300-4275575,1300-4275576,1300-4275577,1300-4275578,1300-4275579,1300-4275580,1300-4275581,1300-4275582,1300-4275583,1300-4275584,1300-4275585,1300-4275586,1300-4275587,1300-4275588,1300-4275589,1300-4275590,1300-4275591,1300-4275592,1300-4275593,1300-4275594,1300-4275595,1300-4275596" data-resize-urls="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1601/16018044/4275574-figmatotklink%281%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1601/16018044/4275575-figmatotklink%282%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1601/16018044/4275576-figmatotklink%283%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1601/16018044/4275577-figmatotklink%284%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1601/16018044/4275578-figmatotklink%285%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1601/16018044/4275579-figmatotklink%286%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1601/16018044/4275580-figmatotklink%287%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1601/16018044/4275581-figmatotklink%288%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1601/16018044/4275582-figmatotklink%289%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1601/16018044/4275583-figmatotklink%2810%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1601/16018044/4275584-figmatotklink%2811%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1601/16018044/4275585-figmatotklink%2813%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1601/16018044/4275586-figmatotklink%2814%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1601/16018044/4275587-figmatotklink%2815%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1601/16018044/4275588-figmatotklink%2816%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1601/16018044/4275589-figmatotklink%2817%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1601/16018044/4275590-figmatotklink%2818%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1601/16018044/4275591-figmatotklink%2819%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1601/16018044/4275592-figmatotklink%2820%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1601/16018044/4275593-figmatotklink%2821%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1601/16018044/4275594-figmatotklink%2822%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1601/16018044/4275595-figmatotklink%2823%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1601/16018044/4275596-figmatotklink%2824%29.jpg"><p>Gallery</p>     <img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4275574-figmatotklink%281%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4275575-figmatotklink%282%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4275576-figmatotklink%283%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4275577-figmatotklink%284%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4275578-figmatotklink%285%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4275579-figmatotklink%286%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4275580-figmatotklink%287%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4275581-figmatotklink%288%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4275582-figmatotklink%289%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4275583-figmatotklink%2810%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4275584-figmatotklink%2811%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4275585-figmatotklink%2813%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4275586-figmatotklink%2814%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4275587-figmatotklink%2815%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4275588-figmatotklink%2816%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4275589-figmatotklink%2817%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4275590-figmatotklink%2818%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4275591-figmatotklink%2819%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4275592-figmatotklink%2820%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4275593-figmatotklink%2821%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4275594-figmatotklink%2822%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4275595-figmatotklink%2823%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4275596-figmatotklink%2824%29.jpg"></figure><p>Both figures feature the same overall design--a colorful and sharp sculpt from the talented hands of Shinji Koshinuma at Max Factory--and you can essentially make Link do any pose you want thanks to the wealth of joints on this figure. Want him to glide around your room, kneel on a rock to survey the land around him, or have him swing the Master Sword around to clear the space around him? You can do just that and more with this Figma figure.</p><p>Both figures come with three faces you can easily swap in or out--smiling, neutral, and shouting faces--a Master Sword, Hylian Shield, Hylian hood, and a base to pose Link on. The DX version comes with many extras, including a paraglider, rocket, rocket effect parts, Construct bow, arrows, Ascend ability effect parts, traveler's shield, rock hammer, and King Rauru's right arm. These are expected to ship out in 2025, but if you're looking for some other Legend of Zelda figures to help you pass the time, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=the+legend+of+zelda+figma&amp;crid=RWTCB7SFCJ67" rel="nofollow ">there are several options</a>.</p><p>The new Tears of the Kingdom Link figure isn't the only premium Zelda collectible on the horizon. Bandai Namco's Tamashii Nations collectible brand is releasing <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-legend-of-zelda-master-sword-replica-is-now-available-to-preorder/1100-6523376/" data-ref-id="1100-6523376">a beautiful replica of the Master Sword</a> later this year. The 41-inch Master Sword Proplica comes with a blue-and-gold sheath and display stand.</p><div data-embed-type="pinbox" data-ref-id="4304">  <ul>                              <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/apple-ipad-pro-ipad-air-2024-preorder-guide/1100-6523258/">Preorder Apple's 2024 iPad Pro And iPad Air - How To Get The Best Deal</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-world-championships-nes-edition-preorder-guide-nintendo-switch/1100-6523267/">Nintendo World Championships Deluxe Set Preorders Are Only Available At Select Retailers</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/playstation-portal-restock-guide/1100-6520876/">PlayStation Portal Is Back In Stock At Multiple Major Retailers</a></li>                          <li>         <span>+ Show More Best Gaming &amp; Tech Deals This Week Links (3)</span>       </li>          <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/grab-7-awesome-dungeon-crawlers-for-only-15/1100-6523253/">Grab 7 Awesome Dungeon Crawlers For Only $15</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/xbox-game-pass-ultimate-deal-saves-you-over-50-for-12-month-membership/1100-6523230/">Xbox Game Pass Ultimate Deal Saves You Over $50 For 12-Month Membership</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/new-star-wars-and-marvel-disney-plus-blu-rays-have-arrived-but-you-may-want-to-order-soon/1100-6521604/">New Star Wars And Marvel Disney Plus Blu-Rays Have Arrived, But You May Want To Order Soon</a></li>   </ul> </div>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/108490194306897153177?rel=author">Darryn Bonthuys</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Call Of Duty: Warzone And Modern Warfare 3 Season 4 Will See A Gundam Crossover]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-warzone-and-modern-warfare-3-season-4-will-see-a-gundam-crossover/1100-6523564/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/call-of-duty-warzone-and-modern-warfare-3-season-4-will-see-a-gundam-crossover.875682/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-warzone-and-modern-warfare-3-season-4-will-see-a-gundam-crossover/1100-6523564/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6523564">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">In what capacity remains to be seen, but Call of Duty: Warzone and Modern Warfare Season 4 will see mecha from Gundam appear in the game. A new teaser shows the shadow of one of the giant robots appearing on a building.</p><p dir="ltr">The official Call of Duty account <a href="https://x.com/CallofDuty/status/1792238845557133808" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">on X</a> (formerly known as Twitter) teased the Gundam crossover. Along with the short 10-second clip, the post says: "It's time for the shadows to rise up" with an emoji of crossed swords. No other specifics were detailed, so don't get your hopes up this will turn the FPS into a Titanfall competitor.</p><p dir="ltr">What we do know is that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cod-warzone-and-mw3-season-4-release-date-and-details/1100-6523547/" data-ref-id="1100-6523547">Season 4 will start May 29 for Call of Duty: Warzone and Modern Warfare 3</a>. The upcoming season will also <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cod-warzone-and-mw3-season-4-confirms-the-return-of-iconic-rifle/1100-6523524/" data-ref-id="1100-6523524">bring back an iconic rifle: the bolt-action Kar98k</a>. Currently, there's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cod-warzone-how-to-unlock-the-black-ops-6-sally-weapon-blueprint/1100-6523521/" data-ref-id="1100-6523521">a "Sally" weapon blueprint in the game that seemingly teases the rumored Black Ops 6</a>. In fact, there's a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-file-text-might-maybe-possibly-point-to-new-game-reveal-this-month/1100-6523127/" data-ref-id="1100-6523127">file text that could possibly, maybe hint at the next Call of Duty being revealed this month</a>.</p><p dir="ltr">In addition to Gundam, Season 4 could see collaborations with Fallout and The Crow, according to dataminers. These wouldn't be the first big-name crossovers for Call of Duty, either. Previously, the FPS <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-crossover-with-warhammer-40000-is-confirmed/1100-6521531/" data-ref-id="1100-6521531">has seen skins and modes based on Warhammer 40,000</a>, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-dutys-crossover-with-the-walking-dead-confirmed-for-season-2/1100-6520706/" data-ref-id="1100-6520706">The Walking Dead</a>, and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-has-a-superhero-mp-mode-with-the-boys-event-in-mw3/1100-6520392/" data-ref-id="1100-6520392">The Boys from Prime Video</a>.</p><p dir="ltr">Looking ahead, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/xbox-showcase-coming-june-9-with-new-call-of-duty-and-more-report/1100-6522450/" data-ref-id="1100-6522450">a Call of Duty showcase will supposedly take place on June 9</a>, following the Xbox Showcase.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GTA 6 Boss "Highly Confident" In Fall 2025 Release Window]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-6-boss-highly-confident-in-fall-2025-release-window/1100-6523562/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gta-6-boss-highly-confident-in-fall-2025-release-window.875679/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-6-boss-highly-confident-in-fall-2025-release-window/1100-6523562/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6523562">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Take-Two recently announced that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/grand-theft-auto-vi/" data-ref-id="5000-569323">Grand Theft Auto VI</a> is now targeting a release in Fall 2025, and CEO Strauss Zelnick is pretty sure the game will make it out on time.</p><p>"There is slippage in the industry, and we're not immune from that. However, we narrowed the timing [of GTA 6] because we are highly confident in that timing," he told CNBC.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=r4KEJAdVXzo" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/r4KEJAdVXzo" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>Previously, GTA VI was set for release at an unspecified point in 2025. It's worth noting that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-6-is-scheduled-for-2025-but-rockstar-has-a-history-of-delays/1100-6519700/" data-ref-id="1100-6519700">pretty much every Rockstar Games release gets delayed</a>, so it's possible GTA VI might slip, as Zelnick mentioned was possible.</p><p>Zelnick also recently talked about how GTA VI's release date <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-6-release-date-probably-doesnt-matter-anticipation-reaches-fever-pitch-take-two/1100-6523548/" data-ref-id="1100-6523548">"probably doesn't matter"</a> given the immense hype for it. However, he acknowledged that releasing in the fall--when people spend lots of money on gifts for the holidays--is <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-6-release-date-probably-doesnt-matter-anticipation-reaches-fever-pitch-take-two/1100-6523548/" data-ref-id="1100-6523548">advantageous for GTA VI.</a></p><p>In the CNBC interview, Zelnick was pressed to say more about what makes GTA VI a step up over GTA V. He declined to get into specifics but noted that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/grand-theft-auto-6-trailer-breakdown-easter-eggs-references-and-teases/2900-4973/" data-ref-id="2900-4973">the trailer</a>, released in December, teases a lot of what is "new and different" for GTA VI.</p><p>Zelnick also talked about how Rockstar's aim is to make GTA VI a game that <a href="https://x.com/videotechuk_/status/1792239837098996117" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">"no one has ever seen before."</a> He added, "Rockstar Games seeks perfection in what they do."</p><p>GTA VI's first trailer was described as "Trailer 1," so fans are expecting to see another trailer at some point in the future. There continue to be many unanswered questions about GTA VI, one of which is what will happen to GTA Online when the new game comes out. Keep checking back with GameSpot for more.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Larian to expand with Warsaw office]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamesindustry.biz/larian-to-expand-with-warsaw-office</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/larian-to-expand-with-warsaw-office.875676/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamesindustry.biz/larian-to-expand-with-warsaw-office<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="content_above">



<p>
If you click on a link and make a purchase we may receive a small commission.  <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/editorial-policy">Read our editorial policy</a>.
</p>
    <div>
        <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-type="article">


<header>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>New studio will be "dedicated to fostering an environment where developers can thrive creatively"</p>

    </div>


  

    

</header>  <div>



            <p>Baldur's Gate 3 maker Larian Studios has announced that it will be opening a new expansion in Warsaw, Poland.</p>
<p>The new office joins the developer's locations in Quebec, Dublin, Guildford, Barcelona, Ghent, and Kuala Lumpur.</p>
<p>Larian intends to expand its current 24-development cycle and ramp up development on its next titles with the addition of its seventh studio.</p>
<p>The game maker said that Larian Studios Warsaw "is dedicated to fostering an environment where developers can thrive creatively and reclaim their agency."</p>
<p>"We're a very bottom-up company, so I'm eager to see what new things they'll bring us. I think it'll work really well," said Larian Studios CEO Swen Vincke.</p>
<p>Last month, <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/larian-after-baldurs-gate-3-we-have-ambitions-to-make-really-good-rpgs-and-thats-sufficient">GamesIndustry.biz spoke with Swen Vincke on Baldur's Gate 3, moving on from the RPG and sustainability within the industry</a>.</p>



        </div>
        </article>

  
    </div>


  
      </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jason Voorhees and Agent Smith are joining the Joker in MultiVersus’ first proper season]]></title>
            <link>https://www.destructoid.com/jason-voorhees-and-agent-smith-are-joining-the-joker-in-multiversus-first-proper-season/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=jason-voorhees-and-agent-smith-are-joining-the-joker-in-multiversus-first-proper-season</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/jason-voorhees-and-agent-smith-are-joining-the-joker-in-multiversus%E2%80%99-first-proper-season.875673/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.destructoid.com/jason-voorhees-and-agent-smith-are-joining-the-joker-in-multiversus-first-proper-season/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=jason-voorhees-and-agent-smith-are-joining-the-joker-in-multiversus-first-proper-season<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p data-characters="344" data-injectable="true" data-video="true">It seems Player First Games is pulling out all the stops to convince people to give <em>MultiVersus</em> another chance when it re-launches. Aside from everyone’s <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/mark-hamill-set-to-voice-the-joker-in-his-multiversus-roster-debut/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">favourite clown criminal the Joker joining the roster</a>, a new launch trailer has confirmed two more additions: <em>Friday the 13th</em>‘s Jason Voorhees and <em>The Matrix</em>‘s Agent Smith.</p> <p data-characters="540" data-current-count="540" data-injectable="true">Jason’s inclusion had leaked over the weekend, but Agent Smith certainly took me by surprise. Given the <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/the-new-multiversus-joker-trailer-has-basically-confirmed-the-powerpuff-girls-are-on-their-way/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">recent teases for The Powerpuff Girls</a>, I’d have thought they’d be the next character reveal. Despite those three seeming like a guarantee, Player First Games has only confirmed Joker, Jason, and Agent Smith for <em>Multiversus</em>‘ first proper season of content, now titled Puns &amp; Villainy. Joker and Jason will be available at launch on May 28, while Agent Smith is only said to be releasing later into the season.</p>
 <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"><p> <iframe title="MultiVersus - Official Launch Trailer &quot;Stars Collide. Pies Fly.&quot;" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/qX5AUVIAg_o?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe> </p></figure> <p data-characters="679" data-current-count="979" data-injectable="true">The trailer doesn’t show how either Jason or Smith will play; in fact, it doesn’t have any gameplay at all and is another aggressive reminder of how many Warner Bros. IPs are being represented. The whole thing is still rather amusing (particularly Velma from <em>Scooby-Doo</em> using speech bubbles to fight Bugs Bunny and the Joker), and I can’t help but get a little hyped seeing Joker summon Jason and Smith to his side as he sits on the Iron Throne from <em>Game of Thrones</em>. The game is also meant to be getting Banana Guard from Adventure Time, as confirmed in <a href="https://youtu.be/sT1zXiYqcfA?si=huLHYDHJkaf8tuqR" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">a trailer from last week</a>, but there’s no mention of whether they’re part of season one as well.</p>
 <p data-characters="399" data-current-count="399" data-injectable="false">It’s not just new characters, though. Recently, Player First confirmed there’ll be PvE content for all the solo players in the form of Rift Mode. Rifts are essentially different types of challenges that follow a specific theme, and they’re not always traditional battles. Some fights will have modifiers, like infinite jumping, and there’ll be minigames and boss battles too.</p> <p data-characters="775" data-current-count="1174" data-injectable="false">All in all, <em>MultiVersus </em>seems to be doing everything right to try and curry back favour after it <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/multiversus-beta-officially-offline-to-return-early-2024-but-for-whom/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">unceremoniously went offline last year</a>. What’s important is what comes after launch. Having a bunch of new characters and additional modes is great for enticing players, but it’ll need to keep up a steady stream of content that keeps those players invested. I’m especially curious to see how often new characters will be rolled out. While it’s important not to keep fans waiting too long for them, having three or four in one season alone almost feels like too much at once, and risks making each new addition feel not as special. This is only the first season, though, so maybe Player First is starting big and will dial it back with subsequent seasons.</p>

<hr>
<p><i data-stringify-type="italic"> Destructoid is supported by our audience. When you purchase through links on our site, we may earn a small affiliate commission.&nbsp;</i><i data-stringify-type="italic"><a href="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-stringify-link="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" data-sk="tooltip_parent">Learn more</a></i> </p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MultiVersus Reveals Jason Voorhees and Agent Smith in New Trailer]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/multiversus-jason-agent-smith</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/multiversus-reveals-jason-voorhees-and-agent-smith-in-new-trailer.875664/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/multiversus-jason-agent-smith<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Warner Bros' crossover platform fighter&nbsp;<em>MultiVersus&nbsp;</em>has gained two more characters, and they're both iconic movie villains who should send a shiver up the spine of even the most stalwart hero.</p>

<p>In a new trailer released earlier today, Warner Bros and developer Player First Games revealed that&nbsp;<em>Friday the 13th&nbsp;</em>slasher Jason Voorhees and&nbsp;<em>The Matrix</em>'s Agent Smith will both be playable in&nbsp;<em>MultiVersus</em>.</p>

<p>They're introduced in the trailer as The Joker's accomplices; the Clown Prince of Crime, voiced once again by Mark Hamill, says he usually works alone, but he'll "make an exception" in this instance.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/multiversus-jason-agent-smith-the-joker.jpg?itok=lKxcPDLt 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/multiversus-jason-agent-smith-the-joker.jpg?itok=7WYr9Ri2 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>I wouldn't want to come across these three in a dark alley. Or a well-lit one, come to that.</figcaption></figure><p>We don't get to see much more of either Jason or Agent Smith, so we don't know how they'll play just yet, but Jason looks positively massive, so expect a juggernaut-style moveset from him.</p>

<p>If Agent Smith's portrayal is anything like it is in the movies, we can expect anything from martial arts through to fighting with an army of clones from him. We'll have to wait and see.</p>

<p>Jason and Agent Smith are the two latest characters to be revealed for&nbsp;<em>MultiVersus&nbsp;</em>since its <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/multiversus-release-date-full">full relaunch was announced back in March</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Scheduled for May,&nbsp;<em>MultiVersus&nbsp;</em>1.0 will include a host of changes, including new characters and stages, a shift to Unreal Engine 5, and rebuilt netcode that should improve the game's online stability a tad.</p>




<p><em>MultiVersus&nbsp;</em>was originally <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/multiversus-leaks-prove-true-as-wb-unveils-platform-fighter">revealed in 2021</a>, then subsequently released in beta the following year. Following its initial launch, the game's roster expanded to include characters like <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/latest-multiversus-update-adds-rick-sanchez-xp-nerf">Rick Sanchez</a>, his nephew <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/multiversus-season-1-patch-notes-includes-morty-release-date">Morty</a>, and <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/black-adam-multiversus-patch-changes-hierarchy-of-power">Black Adam</a>.</p>

<p>Other characters confirmed for the game's 1.0 release include The Joker and, um,&nbsp;<em>Adventure Time</em>'s <a href="https://x.com/multiversus/status/1791514032932814886" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Banana Guard</a>.&nbsp;<em>MultiVersus&nbsp;</em>also includes stages based on locations from&nbsp;<em>The Powerpuff Girls&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>Dexter's Laboratory</em>, so characters from those shows seem like a sure thing at this point.</p>

<p>In any case,&nbsp;<em>MultiVersus&nbsp;</em>launches across <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1818750/MultiVersus/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="noopener" target="_blank">PC</a>, <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-gb/games/multiversus/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">PlayStation</a>, and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/multiversus/9ndkxxbl90gf" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Xbox</a> on May 28th. It'll be free-to-play, so make sure to download it and check it out if you're looking for a distinctly Warner Bros-themed take on&nbsp;<em>Super Smash Bros</em>.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for five years, and in those five years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Death Stranding 2 Filming and Recording Completed, Kojima Says]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/death-stranding-2-filming-and-recording-completed</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/death-stranding-2-filming-and-recording-completed-kojima-says.875661/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/death-stranding-2-filming-and-recording-completed<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Death Stranding 2&nbsp;</em>mastermind and legendary auteur Hideo Kojima has revealed that the filming and recording process for the upcoming sequel is complete.</p>

<p>In a recent radio interview (via <a href="https://www.famitsu.com/article/202405/5569" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Famitsu</a>, with thanks to <a href="https://automaton-media.com/en/news/death-stranding-2-filming-completed-according-to-hideo-kojima/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Automaton Media</a> for additional reporting), Kojima said that the&nbsp;<em>Death Stranding 2&nbsp;</em>development team has finished recording and filming scenes with the game's cast.</p>

<p>That cast includes returning stars like Norman Reedus, Léa Seydoux, and Troy Baker, as well as new additions like&nbsp;<em>Mad Max: Fury Road&nbsp;</em>director George Miller and actress Elle Fanning.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/death-stranding-2-filming-completed-moon.jpg?itok=vYjVuHDt 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/death-stranding-2-filming-completed-moon.jpg?itok=54tgvcmj 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Kojima Productions has finished filming and recording on&nbsp;<em>Death Stranding 2</em>.</figcaption></figure><p>According to Kojima, now that filming and recording are complete,&nbsp;<em>Death Stranding 2&nbsp;</em>will enter what he calls an "adjustment phase", during which gameplay mechanics will be tightened up and scene transitions will be refined.</p>

<p>Kojima says this phase of the game's development will last for about a year. It's important to stress that this doesn't mean&nbsp;<em>Death Stranding 2&nbsp;</em>will launch in May next year; there may well be more work to do after this "adjustment phase" before the game is ready for release.</p>

<p>However, this does indicate that production on&nbsp;<em>Death Stranding 2&nbsp;</em>seems to be progressing smoothly, which, given a <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/prison-architect-2-delayed">spate</a> of recent <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/cities-skylines-2-ps5-xbox-delayed-apology">delays</a>&nbsp;in the <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/human-fall-flat-2-delayed">industry</a>, is pretty impressive.</p>

<p>In the radio interview, Kojima also says that the recent&nbsp;<em>Death Stranding 2&nbsp;</em>trailer, which was released during January's PlayStation <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/playstation-state-of-play-january-2024-recap-heck-out-all-news-trailers-and-reveals">State of Play showcase</a>, was intended to showcase what the game would inherit from its predecessor and what connections the characters would share.</p>

<p>You can take another look at that trailer below, just in case you missed it the first time around.</p>




<p><em>Death Stranding 2&nbsp;</em>is the upcoming sequel to 2019's open-world "walking simulator" (ahem)&nbsp;<em>Death Stranding</em>.</p>

<p>The game was officially <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/death-stranding-2-trailer-revealed-at-game-awards-2022">revealed during The Game Awards in 2022</a>, having already been <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/death-stranding-2-confirmed-by-norman-reedus">confirmed by returning star Norman Reedus</a>, who will once again play Sam Porter-Bridges in the sequel.</p>

<p>As well as&nbsp;<em>Death Stranding 2</em>, Hideo Kojima is also preparing to expand his new franchise into the world of cinema thanks to an upcoming&nbsp;<em>Death Stranding&nbsp;</em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/death-stranding-movie-a24">movie collaboration with celebrated indie house A24</a>.</p>

<p><em>Death Stranding 2&nbsp;</em>is currently slated for launch on PS5 sometime in 2025. Stay tuned for more info on this one.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for five years, and in those five years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Larian Studios Opens New Office in Warsaw to Help Make Its Two Very Ambitious New RPGs]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/larian-studios-opens-new-office-in-warsaw-to-help-make-its-two-very-ambitious-new-rpgs/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/larian-studios-opens-new-office-in-warsaw-to-help-make-its-two-very-ambitious-new-rpgs.875658/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/larian-studios-opens-new-office-in-warsaw-to-help-make-its-two-very-ambitious-new-rpgs/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Today, Baldur's Gate 3 developer Larian Studios announced the opening of a new office in Warsaw, Poland. Swen Vincke, CEO of Larian Studios, said:</p>
<p><em>Visiting GIC last year confirmed what I'd been thinking for a while - there's a lot of talent here and a lot of devs who think like us. On top of that, many of them want to work on RPGs, so it's a match made in heaven. Our plan for the Polish studio is very simple. Build a team that can work on our two - very ambitious - new RPGs and enjoy the fruits of their labor. We're a very bottom up company so I'm eager to see what new things they'll bring us. I think it'll work really well.</em></p>
<p>Ula Jach, Head of Studio, stated:</p>
<p><em>The decision to open a permanent studio in Warsaw shows how serious we are about encouraging creativity, collaboration, and innovation in the heart of Poland's lively gaming scene. We're thrilled for the opportunity to collaborate with the abundant talent and expertise of the region, especially considering Poland's strong reputation as a hub for RPG and gaming enthusiasts.</em></p>
<p>The studio website adds:</p>
<p><em>Larian Studios set up base in one of the greatest RPG development hubs in the world - Poland, where we opened our doors in the historic city of Warsaw. Like its sister studios across the globe, Larian Studios Warsaw is dedicated to fostering an environment where developers can thrive creatively and reclaim their agency. Systems-heavy RPGs need best-in-class developers, that’s why we've put the people who build those systems at the center of our culture.</em></p>
<p><em>As the team ramps up development on our next games, we’re excited to meet talented programmers, RPG designers, writers, and more who are local to Poland or interested in relocating. The studio’s location in the heart of Poland offers everything that you might want to enjoy: mountains, the sea, lakes, rivers, national parks, and even a desert. And it even provides direct flight access to many European destinations, connecting us to our sister studios across Europe, North America, and Asia.</em></p>
<p>The Warsaw office is Larian Studios' seventh, joining Ghent, Dublin, Guildford, Barcelona, Kuala Lumpur, and Quebec. There are currently seven open positions for this office, as you can read <a href="https://larian.com/careers/location/warsaw?location=warsaw&amp;mc_cid=ade0eaf425&amp;mc_eid=22f0f6c8d6" target="_blank" rel="noopener">on the official website</a>.</p>
<p>As a reminder, Larian Studios recently <a href="https://wccftech.com/baldurs-gate-3-no-sequel-dlc-larian-dropping-dungeons-and-dragons/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced</a> it is not going to make Baldur's Gate 3 DLC or Baldur's Gate 4. It is instead going to do its own thing <a href="https://wccftech.com/baldurs-gate-larian-studios-2-new-original-projects-best-work-ever/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">with the two original projects</a> mentioned in the statements above. Interestingly, CEO Swen Vincke <a href="https://wccftech.com/larian-ceo-has-a-lot-of-respect-for-bethesda-is-trying-not-to-grow-his-studio-too-much/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">said</a> a while ago he was resisting the studio's push to grow - looks like he lost that fight.</p>

				

			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Baldur's Gate 3 Devs Open Seventh Studio To Help With Two 'Very Ambitious RPGs']]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/baldurs-gate-3-larian-divinity-warsaw-1851487779</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/baldurs-gate-3-devs-open-seventh-studio-to-help-with-two-very-ambitious-rpgs.875655/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/baldurs-gate-3-larian-divinity-warsaw-1851487779<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Larian Studios, the enormous team behind recent smash hits <em>Divinity: Original Sin 2 </em>and the GOTY-sweeping RPG <em>Baldur’s Gate 3</em> <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/larianstudios/status/1792495491256664211&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/larianstudios/status/1792495491256664211" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">have announced</a></span> they’re opening a <em>seventh</em> studio, this one in Warsaw, Poland. The new recruits will be joining the efforts to work on at least two RPGs, which the studio (unsurprisingly) describes as “very ambitious.”<br></p><div data-video-id="195752" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Baldur's Gate 3's Karlach Actor On Playing The Beloved Barbarian" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="136" data-playlist="195752,195618,195376" data-current="195752"><div><p>Baldur's Gate 3's Karlach Actor On Playing The Beloved Barbarian</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195752/195752_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195752/195752_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195752/195752_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195752/195752_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21263.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><p>Larian has been around for an extraordinary 28 years, made all the more impressive when you realize that it’s been the same company all the way through, not some hedge fund-managed ghoul wearing the flayed skin of a long-dead developer. Founded by the man who’s still in charge, Swen Vincke, the Belgian company has expanded all around the world, with enough studios to warrant a bullet-pointed list.</p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li>Ghent, Belgium</li><li>Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia</li><li>Quebec City, Canada</li><li>Dublin, Ireland</li><li>Guildford, UK</li><li>Barcelona, Spain</li><li>Warsaw, Poland</li></ul><p>That’s the sort of spread you might expect from one of the major publishers, not a privately owned, independent company. (Shout-out to my home town of Guildford, the most mediocre place in all of England.) It’s downright peculiar that Larian is only making two games, given its scale, but it hasn’t announced the two games it’s working on, (though one of them is <em>obviously</em> a new <em>Divinity</em>), so it’s not like there’s a reason to fudge that number.</p><figure id="" data-id="aea19fb2409f6d1c50b888b0c1aec6d1" data-recommend-id="image://aea19fb2409f6d1c50b888b0c1aec6d1" data-format="jpg" data-width="2383" data-height="1340" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="My Baldur's Gate 3 character looking striking against a red background." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="My Baldur's Gate 3 character looking striking against a red background." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Larian Studios / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="aea19fb2409f6d1c50b888b0c1aec6d1" data-recommend-id="image://aea19fb2409f6d1c50b888b0c1aec6d1" data-format="jpg" data-width="2383" data-height="1340" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="My Baldur's Gate 3 character looking striking against a red background." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>The company’s success is even more impressive when you remember that its earliest three games, the <em>Divine Divinity</em> series, were pretty average. Not many game studios can build an empire on 6s and 7s, but then in 2014, Larian blew everyone’s expectations out of the water with the surprise brilliance of <em>Divinity: Original Sin</em>, a prequel to 2002's original <em>Divine Divinity</em>, and thus—counterintuitively—a fresh start. The Kickstarter-funded project was made for a budget of only €4 million ($4.3m), and was a big success. But nothing compared to its 2017 sequel, which earned $2 million from Kickstarter, and a protracted Early Access development that would shape how Larian approached <em>Baldur’s Gate 3</em>.</p><p>The fantasy threequel picked up where a now pretty bereft BioWare left off and had <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.ign.com/articles/josh-sawyer-would-make-pillars-of-eternity-3-if-given-a-baldurs-gate-3-sized-budget&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/josh-sawyer-would-make-pillars-of-eternity-3-if-given-a-baldurs-gate-3-sized-budget" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">a reported budget</a></span> of $100,000,000—more than 20 times the money behind <em>DOS.</em> Larian is obviously now an apocalyptically different company. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/baldurs-gate-3-revenue-microtransactions-trends-video-games-fortnite-hogwarts-legacy-2024-1&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.businessinsider.com/baldurs-gate-3-revenue-microtransactions-trends-video-games-fortnite-hogwarts-legacy-2024-1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">It’s reported</a></span> that <em>BG3</em> made over $650 million in 2023 alone, recovering its budget with half a billion to spare. Even assuming hefty chunks went to the Forgotten Realms license owners, Hasbro, you can see why Larian would be looking for ways to expand.<br></p><p>We know that neither of the projects the company says it’s currently working on has anything to do with the Forgotten Realms, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/baldur-s-gate-3-sequel-expansion-larian-studios-1851356964&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/baldur-s-gate-3-sequel-expansion-larian-studios-1851356964">Vincke having made that clear at 2024's GDC</a></span>, but assuming one is a <em>Divinity</em> sequel, that leaves open the exciting idea that there could be a new, completely original IP in the works. With no publisher above Larian pulling its strings, and no shareholders to demand numbers go up, it’s one of very few studios in a position to take such a risk, and clearly possesses the talent to deliver. It’d be a shame if it proved to be another licensed IP.</p><p>Right now, however, Larian has <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://larian.com/careers&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://larian.com/careers" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">an open call</a></span> for developers wanting to work in Warsaw, a city that just happens to be the headquarters of CD Projekt Red. I wonder if there might be a large supply of local expert RPG developers looking for a gig without brutal crunch (<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/witcher-4-cyberpunk-2077-cdpr-crunch-open-world-rpg-1848688469&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/witcher-4-cyberpunk-2077-cdpr-crunch-open-world-rpg-1848688469">though CDPR has “promised” that will never happen again</a></span>).</p><p>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Microsoft Destroyed Arkane Austin but the Studio’s Soul Is Indestructible]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/microsoft-destroyed-arkane-austin-but-the-studios-soul-is-indestructible</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/microsoft-destroyed-arkane-austin-but-the-studio%E2%80%99s-soul-is-indestructible.875652/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/microsoft-destroyed-arkane-austin-but-the-studios-soul-is-indestructible<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>15 minutes into Prey, the 2017 sci-fi thriller crafted by Arkane Austin, protagonist Morgan Yu shatters their apartment window with a wrench. As hundreds of glass shards fall away, a newly revealed truth changes Morgan’s life forever. This genuinely shocking, perspective-pivoting opening is one of the most incredible introductions to a game world ever made. </p><p>Seven days into May 2024, Microsoft took up its own metaphorical wrench and shattered Arkane Austin. A veteran of immersive sims – those first-person, highly interactive games where RPG, simulation, and action systems interlock – it was one of the casualties of Xbox’s brutal dismemberment of Bethesda Softworks. </p><p>This is a heartbreaking situation. Staff laid off from Arkane Austin have been thrown into the toughest conditions the games industry has ever seen. But, if you’ll permit me to search for the light in this darkness, the soul of the studio has already proven itself incredibly resilient. This is not the first time that financials and parent companies have dictated the course of the immersive sim in Austin, Texas. Despite multiple hardships, the genre always finds a way to survive in this city.  </p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/05/20/dishonored-brigmore-witches-dlc-1716202277783.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption>Dishonored's Brigmore Witches DLC doubled down on the strange and eldritch.</figcaption></figure></output><p>First, let’s reflect on what has been taken. The messy and misguided co-op shooter Redfall may be Arkane Austin’s most recent release, but the studio is built on a rich history of single-player innovation. It crafted two timeless classics: the eldritch stealth sim Dishonored (built cooperatively with Arkane’s surviving Lyon studio) and Prey, a modern day reinterpretation of the brilliant System Shock. And according to <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-05-08/xbox-studio-closures-microsoft-plans-more-cost-cutting-measures-after-layoffs" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Bloomberg</a>, before Microsoft’s guillotine fell, Arkane Austin was already drawing up the blueprints for a new single-player game that drew on the team’s proven skills.  </p><p>It’s impossible to know what that game would be, but if Dishonored and Prey are evidence of anything, then we’ve lost something with incredible potential. Dishonored demonstrates Arkane Austin’s talent for deeply interactive game worlds that respect and reflect player experimentation. Prey’s sprawling space station, meanwhile, is testament to the team’s vision when it comes to environment and campaign structure. Its roguelike DLC Mooncrash, with its overlapping stories of five protagonists, allows for inspired use of a single space depending on both who you play as and the order that you play their stories in. Both games also showcase Arkane’s unrivalled art design and fierce, anti-injustice narrative prowess – strengths even Redfall benefits from.  </p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>Arkane Austin's soul is a community; a growing collective of immersive sim designers that have endured success and hardship in the city of Austin for three decades. </p></div><p>Arkane Austin's approach to game design was genuinely beautiful – an elegance matched by few other studios. And, in a drive for soulless corporate number counting, Microsoft has destroyed it. </p><p>In Microsoft’s own multi-part documentary Power On: The Story of Xbox, a <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/microsoft-xbox-lionhead-studios-mistake">segment discussing the company’s woeful mistreatment of Lionhead Studios</a> saw Phil Spencer say “You acquire a studio for what they’re great at now, and your job is to help them accelerate how they do what they do, not them accelerate what you do.” </p><p>You’d assume, then, that Xbox would want to foster Arkane Austin. To help it overcome the failure of Redfall and resume – to quote <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/microsoft-closes-redfall-developer-arkane-austin-hifi-rush-developer-tango-gameworks-and-more-in-devastating-cuts-at-bethesda">Xbox’s own Matt Booty</a> – “making impactful and innovative games”. But if a highly profitable corporation worth over <em>$3 trillion</em> has no interest in absorbing one mistake and finding a way to shepherd its artists to success, then one thing is clear: that promise to help studios “accelerate” what they’re good at is empty. </p><p>Arkane Austin may be gone, but the people still remain. And that brings me back to the studio’s soul. That soul is a community; a growing collective of immersive sim designers that have endured success and hardship in the city of Austin for close to three decades.  </p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/05/20/redfall-1716202705586.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption>Redfall's online and open world ambitions may have faltered, but its art never did. </figcaption></figure></output><p>The city’s link to immersive sims began in 1995. Looking Glass Studios, the East coast-based creator of the genre’s formative trio – Ultima Underworld, System Shock, and Thief – tasked System Shock producer Warren Spector with opening a new office in Austin, Texas. But while Looking Glass’ games proved critical hits, financial difficulties eventually saw the company collapse in 2000. The design language it established proved indestructible, though, and had already fled the nest. </p><p>Spector had been coaxed away by John Romero, the rockstar designer of Doom. Recently fired by id Software, Romero had set up his own studio, Ion Storm, and he wanted Spector to take charge of the Austin office to make, well, pretty much whatever he wanted. That project was the landmark immersive sim Deus Ex. Hired to help Spector craft this conspiracy thriller were designers Harvey Smith, Steve Powers, Monte Martinez, and Ricardo Bare.</p><p>This new Austin studio didn’t just keep the immersive sim recipe alive. When Looking Glass collapsed, Ion Storm’s parent company, Eidos Interactive, secured the rights to Thief and helped Spector relocate many former Looking Glass staff to his Austin studio to continue work on the franchise. But this second home for the immersive sim wasn’t to last. In 2005, financial struggles at Eidos doomed Ion Storm to the same fate as its spiritual predecessor. </p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>Good art transcends board room statistics. And against all odds, the immersive sim has always found a way to bloom in Austin. </p></div><p>The demise of Ion Storm could have been the end of the road for the immersive sim community in Austin. Even worse, the genre was endangered. Few other studios were interested in making this style of game. One that was, however, was Arkane. A French studio founded by Raphaël Colantonio, its first title, Arx Fatalis, was a love letter to Ultima Underworld. And in 2006 Arkane expanded into the US. Austin was an obvious choice.  </p><p>Arkane Austin became a rally point to reunite key members of the Ion Storm team. Colantonio hired Harvey Smith as co-creative director, and he was soon followed by Powers, Martinez, and Bare. Once again, the city of Austin had another studio in which to foster and grow the creativity and ingenuity that began at Looking Glass Studios. </p><p>Thanks to Arkane’s two-studio system, the immersive sim mindset that made its home in Austin now extends across continents. Over at the thankfully unscathed Arkane Lyon, visionaries such as Dinga Bakaba, Sébastien Mitton, and Dana Nightingale are keeping the genre’s values alive, despite many of them not having direct ties back to Ion Storm or Looking Glass. Meanwhile, Raphaël Colantonio’s new company, WolfEye Studios (set up in 2019 following his departure from Arkane after directing Prey) is staffed by a variety of immersive sim veterans, including Monte Martinez, as well as enthusiastic newcomers. And beyond these headline developers, a multitude of indie games inspired by Arkane’s lineage, such as Gloomwood and Ctrl Alt Ego, are adding new voices to the fold. The genre endures because good art transcends board room statistics. </p><blockquote data-conversation="none" data-theme="light"><p lang="de" dir="ltr">Arkane Austin 2017 <a href="https://t.co/zDCB2vUitI" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/zDCB2vUitI</a></p>— Raphael Colantonio (@rafcolantonio) <a href="https://twitter.com/rafcolantonio/status/1792044354736902289?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">May 19, 2024</a></blockquote> <p>But what of Austin and its long-surviving immersive sim community? Harvey Smith, Steve Powers, and Ricardo Bare, creatives who have seen the city’s studios live and die, were all at Arkane Austin the day that Microsoft’s destruction order came through. Things are, admittedly, different this time. Arkane Austin’s shuttering wasn’t because of the so-called “immersive sim curse” of the genre being doomed to commercial failure. When a <em>$3 trillion</em> corporation won’t even support a studio whose game is <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/success-cant-save-your-favorite-game-studios-anymore">a success “in all key measurements and expectations”</a>, then it’s not about money. It’s sadly just cultural vandalism by capitalism, which is something of a new hurdle for immersive sims to navigate.</p><p>But, as I said earlier, good art transcends board room statistics. And against all odds, the immersive sim has always found a way to bloom in Austin. In a thread of thoughts <a href="https://x.com/Harvey1966/status/1788155208997970260" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">on X/Twitter</a>, Harvey Smith wrote “part of me is also wondering about team size, the role of certain types of creative groups, the role of bigger companies, etc. Maybe there is a sweet spot for the types of games I am driven to make in terms of team size?” Finding that sweet spot might be the first step to whatever comes next.</p><p>We can’t ignore that 2024 is the worst time for video game creatives in history, and Arkane Austin’s former staff face an uphill battle that can’t be solved with simple faith in the genre’s resilience. Nonetheless, the soul of Arkane Austin has roots that have been proven to be seemingly indestructible. And history does have a knack of repeating itself. </p><p><em>Matt Purslow is IGN's Senior Features Editor. <br>Header art: Fred Augis, Arkane Studios / Bethesda</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[V Rising for PS5 launches June 11]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/05/v-rising-for-ps5-launches-june-11</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/v-rising-for-ps5-launches-june-11.875649/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/05/v-rising-for-ps5-launches-june-11<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Vampire survival action RPG dated for console.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>The <a title="Platforms > PS5 [7,035 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a> version of vampire <a title="Genres > Survival [276 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/survival">survival</a> <a title="Genres > Action RPG [1,180 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg/action-rpg">action RPG</a> <em><a title="Games > V Rising [6 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/v-rising">V Rising</a></em> will launch on June 11 for $39.99, developer <a title="Companies > Stunlock Studios [5 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/stunlock-studios">Stunlock Studios</a> announced. Pre-orders are available now via <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/product/UP0779-PPSA16263_00-0000000000000001" rel="noopener" target="_blank">PlayStation Store</a>. <span id="more-883585"></span></p><p>In addition to the standard edition, the game will also be available in a $59.99 “Legacy of <em>Castlevania</em>” Edition and $99.99 Complete Edition. The latter includes the base game and the “Legacy of <em>Castelvania</em>” premium pack, while the latter includes the base game, “Legacy of <em>Castlevania</em>” premium pack, “Sinister Evolution” pack, “Dracula’s Relics” pack, and “Eldest Bloodline” pack.</p><p><em>V Rising</em> first launched in Early Access for PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1604030/V_Rising/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> on May 17, 2022, followed by a full release on May 8, 2024.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Stunlock Studios:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><a title="Companies > Experience [210 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/experience">Experience</a> a vampire survival action RPG <a title="Genres > Adventure [1,472 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a> like no other.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Awaken after centuries of slumber, weakened and thirsty for blood. Explore a vast open world of dark fantasy, humans, <a title="Genres > Horror [406 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/horror">horror</a>s, and worse… the deadly sunlight. Rise in power and conquer the world of the living.</p><p>Hunt alone or gather a clan. <em>V Rising</em> can be played solo, <a title="Genres > Co-Op [169 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer/co-op">cooperative</a>ly, or persistent online <a title="Genres > Multiplayer [314 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer">multiplayer</a>.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Dive Into a Gothic <a title="Genres > Open-World [407 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/open-world">Open-World</a></strong> – Explore a vast world teeming with mythical horrors and danger. Travel through lush forests, open countryside, and dark caverns to discover valuable resources, meeting friends and foes alike along the way. Traverse the world with vampire comrades or hunt solo as you pillage villages, raid bandits, and delve into the domains of supernatural beasts.</li><li><strong>Fear the Light, Rule the Night</strong> – Stick to the shadows during the daytime, or the burning sunlight will turn you to ashes. Roam the night and prey on your victims in the darkness. As a vampire, you must quench your thirst for blood while planning your strategies around the day and nighttime.</li><li><strong>Raise your Castle</strong> – Gather resources and discover ancient techniques to gain dark powers. Use your newly acquired knowledge to build a castle where you can store your loot and grow your army of darkness. <a title="Series > Persona [79 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/series/persona">Persona</a>lize your domain, exhibit your vampiric style and make sure to craft coffins for servants and friends. Strengthen your castle to protect your treasure hoard from vampire rivals.</li><li><strong>Compete or Cooperate</strong> – Travel alone or explore the world with friends. Fighting side by side with other vampires will give you an advantage in the fight to conquer the greatest threats of Vardoran. Raid other players’ castles or play the diplomat in the game of blood, power, and betrayal. Compete or cooperate – the choice is yours.</li><li><strong>Master your Vampire</strong> – Learn and master an arsenal of deadly weapons and unholy abilities. In V Rising, you aim skill-shots and dodge projectiles using​ precise​​ ​WASD controls ​and cursor-based​ ​aiming – no click to move. Tailor your vampire to fit your play style by combining weapons with a variety of spells earned through vanquishing powerful foes. Master your skills and unleash your wicked powers.</li><li><strong>Compete or Cooperate</strong> – Hunt solo or fight side by side with other players to slay heroes and monsters alike. Cooperate with your fellow Vampires, or choose to delve into more dangerous realms and face them as rivals.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>PlayStation 5 Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="V Rising - PlayStation 5 Date Reveal Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ASZKGX8ObEA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MultiVersus adds Jason Voorhees, Agent Smith]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/05/multiversus-adds-jason-voorhees-agent-smith</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/multiversus-adds-jason-voorhees-agent-smith.875646/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/05/multiversus-adds-jason-voorhees-agent-smith<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Jason Voorhees from the <em>Friday the 13th</em> <a title="Genres > Horror [406 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/horror">horror</a> movie franchise and Agent Smith from <em>The Matrix</em> film series will be playable characters in <a title="Genres > Free-to-Play [267 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/free-to-play">free-to-play</a> platform fighting game <em><a title="Games > MultiVersus [12 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/multiversus">MultiVersus</a></em>, publisher <a title="Companies > Warner Bros. Games [622 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/warner-bros-games">Warner Bros. Games</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Player First Games [12 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/player-first-games">Player First Games</a> announced. <span id="more-883557"></span></p><p>Both fighters will join the roster alongside DC Super-Villain The Joker as part of “Season 1: Puns &amp; Villainy.” Jason Voorhees will be available at launch, while Agent Smith will launch later in the season.</p><p><em>MultiVersus</em> is due out for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [7,035 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [5,330 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [26,704 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox One [13,160 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [20,103 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1818750/MultiVersus/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> on May 28.</p><p>Watch the launch trailer featuring Jason Voorhees and Agent Smith below.</p><h2><span>Launch Trailer: “Stars Collide. Pies Fly.”</span></h2><p><iframe title="MultiVersus - Official “Stars Collide  Pies Fly ” Launch Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Sv5dh3HkCrY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><!-- AD: content -->
        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jason Voorhees And Agent Smith Join MultiVersus In Villain-Themed Season 1]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/jason-voorhees-and-agent-smith-join-multiversus-in-villain-themed-season-1/1100-6523560/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/jason-voorhees-and-agent-smith-join-multiversus-in-villain-themed-season-1.875643/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/jason-voorhees-and-agent-smith-join-multiversus-in-villain-themed-season-1/1100-6523560/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6523560">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">Earlier this month, Warner Bros. and Player First Games announced they would be adding iconic Batman villain The Joker to the MultiVersus roster when it relaunches on May 28. Today, two more villainous additions--Friday The 13th's Jason Voorhees and The Matrix's Agent Smith--were revealed via a new launch trailer.</p><p dir="ltr">The trailer highlights matchups between previously featured members of the roster, like Finn from Adventure Time teaming with Velma from Scooby Doo and Wonder Woman doing battle with alternate versions of herself. The scene then shifts to the throne room from Game of Thrones, where The Joker taunts the heroes flanked by Jason and Agent Smith.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="309002541" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6464115,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;MultiVersus%20-%20Official%20Cinematic%20Launch%20Trailer%20%22Stars%20Collide.%20Pies%20Fly.%22&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:181,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/multiversus-official-cinematic-launch-trailer-stars-collide-pies-fly\/2300-6464115\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464115\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464115\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464115\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6464115&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6464115,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6523560&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;multiversus&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;2d,action,fighting&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;playstation-5,pc,xbox-series-x,playstation-4,xbox-one&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;warner-bros-games,warner-bros-interactive-entertainment,warner-bros&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6464115},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6464115\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;Publisher Asset&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4305391-11.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/DJHdW6My.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1716211140,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="DJHdW6My" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> MultiVersus - Official Cinematic Launch Trailer "Stars Collide. Pies Fly."</p>
      </div>
<p dir="ltr">Jason Voorhees is making his second-ever guest appearance in a fighting game, after he featured as a downloadable character in 2015's Mortal Kombat X. Agent Smith, meanwhile, has only featured in four video games total since the debut of The Matrix, with the most recent being a cameo appearance in Lego Dimensions as part of the Lego Batman Movie pack.</p><p dir="ltr">After being removed from online stores for nearly a year, MultiVersus will return with a completely revamped fighting system, new rollback netcode, a reworked economy and more. Along with the three new characters, two new stages--one set in Townsville from The Powerpuff Girls, the other in Dexter's Laboratory--will be part of the rotation, as well as a new PvE mode with branching paths and themed events.</p><p dir="ltr">MultiVersus will launch as a free-to-play title for Xbox Series X|S, Xbox One, PlayStation 4, PlayStation 5, and PC on May 28.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/115235460361630065469?rel=author">Jason Fanelli</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MultiVersus Launch Trailer Reveals Jason Voorhees And The Matrix's Agent Smith]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gameinformer.com/news/2024/05/20/multiversus-launch-trailer-reveals-jason-voorhees-and-the-matrixs-agent-smith</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/multiversus-launch-trailer-reveals-jason-voorhees-and-the-matrixs-agent-smith.875640/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gameinformer.com/news/2024/05/20/multiversus-launch-trailer-reveals-jason-voorhees-and-the-matrixs-agent-smith<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p>Developer Player First Games and publisher Warner Bros. Games have released the launch trailer for its upcoming platform fighter, <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/product/multiversus">MultiVersus</a>, seemingly revealing&nbsp;<em>Friday the 13th's&nbsp;</em>Jason Voorhees and <i>The Matrix's&nbsp;</i>Agent Smith as new roster additions. This trailer arrives just a few weeks after we learned <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/2024/03/11/multiversus-is-back-in-action-this-may">MultiVersus finally (re)launches next week</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p>After roughly two minutes of MultiVersus hijinks with various characters from the game, the Joker, <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/2024/05/08/the-joker-voiced-by-mark-hamill-joins-multiversus">which we recently learned is joining the game with a voice by Mark Hamill</a>, is seen sitting on&nbsp;the Iron Throne of&nbsp;<em>Game of Thrones&nbsp;</em>fame. Then, mysteriously, Jason and Agent Smith appear beside him, likely alluding to them joining the launch day roster.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Check it out for yourself in the MultiVersus launch trailer below</strong>:&nbsp;</p>

<p><iframe allow="autoplay" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/qX5AUVIAg_o" width="640"></iframe></p>

<p>MultiVersus is a free-to-play game and will launch on May 28 on PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X/S, PlayStation 4, Xbox One, and PC.&nbsp;</p>

<p>For more, read&nbsp;<a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/review/multiversus/packing-a-punch"><em>Game Informer's&nbsp;</em>MultiVersus review</a> after its first launch back in 2022, and then check out <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/2024/05/13/check-out-the-jokers-multiversus-gameplay-and-the-batman-who-laughs-alternate-costume">Joker's MultiVersus gameplay and his Batman Who Laughs alternate costume</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<hr>
<p><em>Are you jumping back into MultiVersus next week when it launches? Let us know in the comments below!</em></p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Serve the Taskmaster at Home When Taskmaster VR Releases this June]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/serve-taskmaster-at-home-when-taskmaster-vr-releases-this-june</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/serve-the-taskmaster-at-home-when-taskmaster-vr-releases-this-june.875625/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/serve-taskmaster-at-home-when-taskmaster-vr-releases-this-june<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>How comfortable are you with the destruction of hundreds of eggs and melons? Will you be able to make mundane household objects do mildly impressive things? We'll all have a chance when <em>Taskmaster VR</em> releases on June 13th.</p>

<p><em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/features/i-become-bit-more-annoying-alex-horne-talks-taskmaster-vr">Check out our interview with Alex Horne about making Taskmaster VR</a></em>.</p>

<p>A quick rundown for those unfamiliar with the show:&nbsp;<em>Taskmaster </em>sees five people compete in a series of oddball tasks -- like painting a horse while riding a horse --&nbsp; with no real idea how their performance may be judged. The Taskmaster views their attempts to complete a task and makes judgement on who did best and worst.</p>

<p>We'll soon have the opportunity to experience that ourselves, including the scorn or admiration from The Taskmaster himself, Lord Greg Davies. Of course, his trusty assistance Alex Horne will be featured heavily throughout the game as well.</p>

<p>Much like the show, the game will be structured around "episodes" of tasks over the course of a series to determine an overall winner.&nbsp;</p>




<p>Beyond these handcrafted tasks, by both the dev team at Scallywag Arcade with the help of Alex Horne, we can all make our own tasks, too. When the game first releases, you can set up tasks anywhere in or outside the Taskmaster house with all sorts of objects.</p>

<p>The task creation tools will only expand further as well, with the team at Scallywag stating they have big plans to expand the feature after the game's release.</p>

<p>In a release they said they want to add "enhanced sharing, more interactive objects and locations, crafting - and more" while asking the community to help identify what they want to see in the game.</p>

<p>Along with the release date, you can now <a href="https://scallywag.drawandcode.com/taskmaster/">pre-order <em>Taskmaster VR</em></a> if you wish.</p>

<p><em>Taskmaster VR</em> will be coming to Meta Quest and SteamVR. No word on if or when it may come to PlayStation VR at some point in the future</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Andrew is the Editor in Chief at TechRaptor. Conned into a love of gaming by Nintendo at a young age, Andrew has been&nbsp;chasing the dragon spawned by Super… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/andrew-otton">More about Andrew</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[V RIsing PS5 Release Date Revealed for Next Month]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/v-rising-ps5-release-date</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/v-rising-ps5-release-date-revealed-for-next-month.875622/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/v-rising-ps5-release-date<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Stunlock Studios has announced the&nbsp;<em>V Rising&nbsp;</em>PS5 release date, with the much-feted vampiric survival game landing on Sony's console next month.</p>

<p>After launching in Early Access all the way back in May 2022,&nbsp;<em>V Rising&nbsp;</em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/v-rising-10-patch-notes">finally got a 1.0 release on PC</a> earlier this month, but thanks to a brand new trailer, we now know the game will rise from its PC-exclusive coffin and hunt for PS5 players on June 11th.</p>

<p>When it launches on PS5,&nbsp;<em>V Rising&nbsp;</em>will have all of the same features as the PC's 1.0 release, including&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/v-rising-castlevania-crossover"><em>Castlevania&nbsp;</em>crossover content</a>, a range of new <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/v-rising-difficulty-levels-servers-launch">difficulty levels</a>, and much more.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/v-rising-ps5-release-date-wolves.jpg?itok=lzIQT1Dg 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/v-rising-ps5-release-date-wolves.jpg?itok=d-jLutxb 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>V Rising&nbsp;</em>is coming to PS5 very soon indeed.</figcaption></figure><p>Although&nbsp;<em>V Rising&nbsp;</em>will be available on both PC and PS5 by the time June 11th rolls around, developer Stunlock confirmed in <a href="https://wccftech.com/v-rising-1-0-qa-stunlock-on-the-future-of-the-hit-vampire-survival-game/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">an interview earlier this year</a> that&nbsp;the game won't support crossplay between the two platforms.</p>

<p>While Stunlock said in that interview that its current priority is bringing&nbsp;<em>V Rising&nbsp;</em>to PC and PS5, the developer seemed open to the idea of the game appearing on Xbox and Nintendo platforms, so we may well see&nbsp;<em>V Rising&nbsp;</em>making the leap to other consoles at some point in the future.</p>

<p>For now, though, you can check out the&nbsp;<em>V Rising&nbsp;</em>PS5 release date announcement trailer below. It'll give you a sense of what you can expect if you decide to delve into Vardoran on PS5 next month.</p>




<p>If you're not familiar with&nbsp;<em>V Rising</em>, it's an open-world survival game in which you must survive as a freshly-awakened vampire.</p>

<p>You can construct and decorate your very own castle, craft your own equipment, and learn a host of vampiric disciplines and powers to help you navigate the world of Vardoran and defeat its many enemies and bosses.</p>

<p><em>V Rising&nbsp;</em>is available right now on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1604030/V_Rising/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="noopener" target="_blank">PC</a>, and it's coming to <a href="https://store.playstation.com/concept/10007965/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">PS5</a> on June 11th. Watch this space for more info.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for five years, and in those five years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['I Become a Bit More Annoying' - Alex Horne Talks Taskmaster VR]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/features/i-become-bit-more-annoying-alex-horne-talks-taskmaster-vr</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/i-become-a-bit-more-annoying-alex-horne-talks-taskmaster-vr.875619/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/features/i-become-bit-more-annoying-alex-horne-talks-taskmaster-vr<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Taskmaster </em>has the perfect amount of whacky and chaotic that it feels like a no-brainer to see it coming to VR. To learn more about how the adaptation is going, we had the chance to talk to series creator Alex Horne.&nbsp;</p>

<h2>Designing Tasks in <em>Taskmaster VR</em></h2>

<p>Alex is not only the creator of the show but the mastermind behind most of the tasks, so my natural first question was just how much he was involved in designing the tasks for the game.</p>



<p>Alex said that it felt odd handing something over, but wanted to stress how brilliant the team at Scallywag Arcade is. He’s still heavily involved, though, and gave the team this sort of guidance:&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote>
<p>“With the show, when we come up with a task, we always want there to be variety in the responses, the same way that we want people to be able to come up with their own way of doing something that we didn't expect, as well as the four or five ways that we have written into it."</p>
</blockquote>

<p>A big part of the delight in <em>Taskmaster </em>is the completely unexpected ways many contestants will approach a task. While solutions or certain actions can often feel obvious at first, part of what has made the show work so well is how much out-of-the-box thinking is both rewarded and just how entertaining it can be.&nbsp;</p>

<p>For <em>Taskmaster VR</em>, preserving that essence is incredibly important.</p>

<p>With that particular philosophy in mind, how do you balance keeping things familiar with the newfound freedom of a virtual world?&nbsp;</p>

<h2><em>Taskmaster VR</em> is a "Slightly More Pure <em>Taskmaster </em>Experience”</h2>

<p>For Alex, moving into the virtual world was “quite liberating” just due to the fact that there is not a camera crew around. Logistically, they have to set up cameras, take up space, and if contestants run around, they need to have cameras following.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In a game, those physical limitations are gone, giving tasks a lot more freedom. No more are rooms cut in half for the crew -- we will have a lot more room for activities.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Beyond even those limitations, the virtual world doesn’t need to care for things like health and safety. Nor is it wasteful to smash hundreds of eggs or melons, something Alex tries to be conscious of so as to not waste food on the show.&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote>
<p>“You can climb up on the roof, and we're not allowed to with certain health and safety things. Every series the contestants say, 'Can I get on the roof of this?’ and we have to say, 'No, you’re not allowed to do that.’ You don't need to worry about that sort of thing in there.”&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>



<p>While <em>Taskmaster VR</em> is a more unshackled version of the show, Alex wanted to make sure it’s still grounded. I asked if there was any temptation to make something “otherworldly’ with the freedom being a game provides.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Alex said, “Right now, it's still household objects.” However, that in the future “there's a realm where you could go through a door and you're suddenly on a boat or whatever it is. But right now we think it’s important to make it faithful to the show.”&nbsp;</p>

<p>Part of that grounded mentality comes with some lessons Alex and the <em>Taskmaster </em>team have learned over the years making the show:&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote>
<p>“In the show, we actually went through a little phase of having quite big props, expensive things that you wouldn't have at home. And it was instantly obvious. It's much better when you can play it at home. So yeah, it's treating the house as if it was a real house.”&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>

<p><em>Taskmaster VR</em> is going to be recognizable, familiar, and grounded “like the real world, but just a slight twist on it.”&nbsp;</p>

<h2>Alex Horne: Game Designer&nbsp;</h2>

<p>Alex has actually been quite involved with game making in some form or another for a long time now. Obviously, <em>Taskmaster</em> itself is gameified and each individual task has its own set of rules and goals. In essence, each task is a little game itself within a game.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Going back many years before <em>Taskmaster</em>, however, Alex made some game shows and is involved in a complicated YouTube series called <em>No More Jockeys</em>. It’s about naming famous people with exceedingly more difficult rules the longer the game goes on.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Beyond those, Alex has already helped make a <em>Taskmaster </em>board game, card game, and made a book full of tasks for people to perform at home.&nbsp;</p>



<p>With that in mind, I asked Alex if he considered himself a game designer. He said, “I didn't realize I was and I think I would still deny it.” &nbsp;</p>

<p>However, he admits that his job is to essentially gamify things. In what is likely no surprise, Alex admires designers of escape rooms, as they are doing a lot of the same things he does in <em>Taskmaster</em>. It’s from talking with them he solidified the idea that he probably is a game designer, even though he doesn’t want to admit it.&nbsp;</p>

<p>“I really love talking to particularly escape room makers. I mean, they take it so seriously," he said. "I tend to just work things out in my head rather than write things down. But I think if things had gone a different way, I could see myself being in that world.”&nbsp;</p>

<p>Ever humble, Alex praised escape room makers for their serious approach, while minimizing his own work. But in the same breath of doing that, I think Alex really hit on one of the reasons <em>Taskmaster </em>is so appealing and relatable:&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote>
<p>“I think I've luckily got quite a good instinctive feel of how to turn something that’s quite routine into a game. And I think we all do that. We used to do that when we were kids. We used to be quite good at making up games on the spot. So that's what I do.”&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>

<p>While not “serious” like those escape room makers, we can all instantly think of some “dumb” game we made with our friends as a kid. That playfulness is key to <em>Taskmaster</em>’s charm, and I think that level of insight bodes well for both the VR game and the show’s future.&nbsp;</p>

<p>As a quick aside, Alex also said that they’re currently working on an in-person <em>Taskmaster</em> experience, sort of like an escape room. However, it will be something that will try to make it look and feel like you’re in the <em>Taskmaster</em> house and participating in the show.&nbsp;</p>

<h2>Becoming Little Alex Horne in Taskmaster VR&nbsp;</h2>

<p>Both Alex and the Taskmaster himself Lord Greg Davies feature heavily in the game, of course, so we talked about the process of bringing them to life in the game.&nbsp;</p>

<p>I asked Alex if it was strange to try to essentially portray himself when recording lines. “I put a suit on and become a bit more annoying, but not much more," Alex said. "So it wasn't that weird at all."</p>

<p>With so many tasks and possibilities of how people can accomplish them, I asked if some of what was recorded was some of him just reacting to seeing tasks done in front of him. &nbsp;</p>

<p>Alex said it was mostly written beforehand and “hopefully well thought through.” The team wrote a lot of responses and reactions for Alex and Greg trying to anticipate what players might do.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Though, Alex acknowledged there are some lines that may never be heard and likely actions in tasks that won’t get a proper reaction because they didn’t think of it at the time. &nbsp;</p>

<p>With that in mind, Alex said that, depending on what players do on certain tasks, he’ll be heading back in to record lines to account for what they may have missed.&nbsp;</p>

<p>They can only anticipate so much, after all. Plus, you never know what the public will do when they get something in their hands.</p>

<h2>“The Public Are a Nightmare”&nbsp;</h2>

<p><em>Taskmaster </em>the show is a controlled setting and Alex gets to pick or choose what gets seen. Once <em>Taskmaster VR</em> comes out, however, that’s all out the window and people can do whatever they want. &nbsp;</p>

<p>I was curious if Alex found that prospect a little daunting, as he’s been a gamemaker with very few players so far really. He’s going from a handful to thousands.&nbsp;</p>

<p>He had a taste of that experience during the COVID lockdowns, where Alex put out videos to give the public tasks to do at home that Greg would judge. They received a ton of fan feedback and response, and I asked Alex if that is helping him brace for the thousands of people about to play the game.&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote>
<p>“Yeah, I'm pleasantly surprised with that, the imagination out there. And also the lengths people go to. People are very clever... I did a book a couple years ago, a <em>Taskmaster</em> treasure hunt book with lots of clues to find a thing ... and they cracked it so quick. There were 100 clues, and it was cracked in about two hours... But, yeah, people are so smart. So, I think I think that will be annoying.”&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Part of it is exposure that maybe things weren’t quite as difficult or clever as first thought. Then there’s just the fear of people engaging with a creation, moreso than as just a viewer as Alex is mostly used to that sort of feedback.&nbsp;</p>

<p>And when it comes to people getting the game in their hands:&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote>
<p>“The public are a nightmare, aren't they? Who knows what they'll do. I think we'll hear a lot of feedback about first ways they've cracked things. Second ways that can be better, and hopefully, hopefully some positive feedback, as well.”&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>

<p><em>Taskmaster VR</em> releases June 13th for Meta Quest and SteamVR.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Andrew is the Editor in Chief at TechRaptor. Conned into a love of gaming by Nintendo at a young age, Andrew has been&nbsp;chasing the dragon spawned by Super… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/andrew-otton">More about Andrew</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Video game movies keep relying on the wrong kind of violence]]></title>
            <link>https://www.polygon.com/24158527/video-game-movies-violence-boy-kills-world</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/video-game-movies-keep-relying-on-the-wrong-kind-of-violence.875616/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.polygon.com/24158527/video-game-movies-violence-boy-kills-world<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  <div>
    
      <a href="https://www.polygon.com/">
        
  <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 355.3 128"><title>poly-lt-wire-logo</title><path fill="#fff" d="M92.4,54.8c10.2,0,13.9,1.6,16.9,4a18.79,18.79,0,0,1,6.5,14.5c0,5.6-2.3,11.4-5.8,14.4-3.8,3.2-7.5,4.8-16,4.8H88.5v17.2h-14V54.8Zm-4,25.4h5.1a13.87,13.87,0,0,0,5.4-.8c1.9-.8,3.3-2.5,3.3-5.8s-1.6-4.8-3.5-5.6a15.31,15.31,0,0,0-5.8-.8H88.3v13Z" transform="translate(0 0)"></path><path fill="#fff" d="M116.2,89c0-10,7.2-21.8,22.2-21.8S160.6,79,160.6,89.1,153.4,111,138.4,111,116.2,99.2,116.2,89Zm12.3.1a9.91,9.91,0,1,0,9.9-10.5C133,78.6,128.5,83,128.5,89.1Z" transform="translate(0 0)"></path><path fill="#fff" d="M164.5,54.8h12.3v54.9H164.5Z" transform="translate(0 0)"></path><path fill="#fff" d="M195.1,107.6,179.9,68.5H193l8.4,23.9,7.9-23.9h13l-20.6,54.9h-13Z" transform="translate(0 0)"></path><path fill="#fff" d="M266.5,104.7c0,6.2-.4,10.1-2.4,13.6-3.2,5.2-10.7,9.7-20.8,9.7-14.3,0-19.7-8.6-20.5-14.5H237a7.08,7.08,0,0,0,3.9,3.6,10.57,10.57,0,0,0,3.3.5c4.7,0,10-2.9,10-10v-2.4c-1.4,2.4-5,5.9-11.4,5.9-11.2,0-20.8-8.5-20.8-21.7,0-14.1,10.1-22.2,20.8-22.2,4.6,0,9.1,1.6,11.5,5.2V68.5h12.3v36.2ZM234.2,89c0,6.5,4.7,10.5,9.9,10.5a9.8,9.8,0,0,0,7.2-2.8,11.18,11.18,0,0,0,2.9-7.1,11.56,11.56,0,0,0-2.6-7.7,9.2,9.2,0,0,0-7.4-3.2,10,10,0,0,0-10,10q0,.15,0,.3Z" transform="translate(0 0)"></path><path fill="#fff" d="M270.3,89c0-10,7.2-21.8,22.2-21.8S314.7,79,314.7,89.1,307.5,111,292.5,111,270.3,99.2,270.3,89Zm12.3.1a9.91,9.91,0,1,0,9.9-10.5C287.2,78.6,282.6,83,282.6,89.1Z" transform="translate(0 0)"></path><path fill="#fff" d="M317.2,68.5h11.5v4.4c1.4-2,4-5.8,11.3-5.8,13.9,0,15.3,11.3,15.3,16.8v25.7H343V87.1c0-4.5-1-8.5-6.5-8.5-6.1,0-7,4.4-7,8.6v22.4H317.2Z" transform="translate(0 0)"></path><path fill="#fff" d="M73.9,37.3a1.09,1.09,0,0,0,.1-.5v-.1c0-.2-.1-.3-.3-.5h0L37.8.3a1.4,1.4,0,0,0-.9-.3h-.1c-.2,0-.3.1-.5.3h0L.4,36.1a.1.1,0,0,1-.1.1.1.1,0,0,1-.1.1l-.1.1a.6.6,0,0,0-.1.4H0V72.9a.55.55,0,0,0,.3.5h0l35.9,35.9a1.14,1.14,0,0,0,.8.3.6.6,0,0,0,.4-.1,1.2,1.2,0,0,0,.7-1V73.1L73.7,37.5C73.8,37.5,73.8,37.4,73.9,37.3ZM36,38V70.2L3.7,38ZM2.2,39.5,34.4,71.7H2.2ZM38.1,38H70.3L38.1,70.2Zm0-2.2V3.6L70.3,35.8Zm-2.1,0H3.7L35.9,3.6V35.8Zm0,70.3L3.8,73.9H36Z" transform="translate(0 0)"></path></svg>


        
      </a>
    
    
        
      
      <div>
        


        
        

        <p>Middling films like Boy Kills World have incredible fights, but they’re missing the point </p>

        <div>
  <p><span>
    
      By
      
      
        
          <span>
            
            <time data-ui="timestamp" datetime="2024-05-20T12:50:00">
  May 20, 2024,  8:50am EDT
</time>
          </span>
        
      
      
      
    
    
      <span>
        

      </span>
    
  </span>
  <span>
    <a data-entry-admin="23922568" data-cid="tools/entry_admin_button-1716216610_6870_27267" data-cdata="{&quot;id&quot;:23922568}"></a>

  </span>
</p></div>

        
      </div>
    </div>
    <p><span>
      
      
      
       <cite>Image: Roadside Attractions/Everett Collection</cite>
      
    </span>


    </p>
</div><div>
  <main id="content" tabindex="-1">
    
    


      
    

      



    







<div>
  <p id="ri9bAw">For most of their brief history, <a href="https://www.polygon.com/what-to-watch/23196727/best-video-game-movies-adaptations-tv-watch-streaming">video game movies</a> have been laughed at by fans and movie enthusiasts alike. Recent TV megahits like <a href="https://www.polygon.com/last-of-us"><em>The Last of Us</em></a> and Prime Video’s <a href="https://www.polygon.com/fallout"><em>Fallout</em></a> prove video games can be effectively adapted as TV shows, but video game movies mostly remain a blotchy chimera. From the neck down, they sport the lumps and limbs of action movies. But these films’ brains are merged with the source material. When a video game movie like the lackluster <a href="https://www.polygon.com/2013/7/18/4535878/at-comic-con-optimism-for-future-of-video-game-movies"><em>Street Fighter: The Legend of Chun-Li</em></a> confuses the original’s story or gets its ineffable <em>vibe</em> wrong, the whole thing collapses under its own weight. The catalyst for this failure, usually, is the specific way video game movies depend on violence: It’s hardly ever the right kind.</p>
<p id="UUL5QK">The filmmakers behind video game movies tend to <a href="https://www.polygon.com/2013/1/10/3863446/surveyusa-finds-that-89-percent-of-parents-nationwide-believe-violent">act like nervous parents</a>, peeking through their fingers at <em>Call of Duty</em> snipers and <em>Mortal Kombat</em> beheadings, guessing that all video games are essentially blood-and-guts time bombs. Assuming that all players want from games-turned-movies is to witness destruction, directors lean on impressive stunts and gore to make their movies. But they miss that the most successful video game violence is thoughtful, too.</p>
<p>  <figure>
  <span>
    
    <span data-original="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25451778/MCDSTFI_FE033.jpg">
      
        <picture data-cid="site/picture_element-1716216610_7962_27268" data-cdata="{&quot;asset_id&quot;:25451778,&quot;ratio&quot;:&quot;*&quot;}">
  


  <source srcset="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Mod95_X3qBzxHuVmO79MMZ9gEdw=/0x0:2700x1480/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:2700x1480):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25451778/MCDSTFI_FE033.jpg 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Bh6P8qLI_RgMiTX2IXd8Y8PFt2Y=/0x0:2700x1480/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:2700x1480):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25451778/MCDSTFI_FE033.jpg 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NnJxUu17CW_YMqh4NI7ZGVcVOow=/0x0:2700x1480/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:2700x1480):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25451778/MCDSTFI_FE033.jpg 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xpo2IHYtB-LMaj8s-G5GyBZsOQs=/0x0:2700x1480/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:2700x1480):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25451778/MCDSTFI_FE033.jpg 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/pVI5PDQ5jSPleuCbw4yoPFqFFms=/0x0:2700x1480/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:2700x1480):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25451778/MCDSTFI_FE033.jpg 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/CsptJG828ANoP2OfLqrys4A7QG8=/0x0:2700x1480/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:2700x1480):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25451778/MCDSTFI_FE033.jpg 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7A4PcQ0zZQsbpMGIR57Se34EYJU=/0x0:2700x1480/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:2700x1480):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25451778/MCDSTFI_FE033.jpg 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9MG4z1yPfi6CAWBbINjF8VwHN6I=/0x0:2700x1480/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:2700x1480):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25451778/MCDSTFI_FE033.jpg 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nqzNglv_RUK6S2ZVLA_C2vxhlEE=/0x0:2700x1480/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:2700x1480):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25451778/MCDSTFI_FE033.jpg 1920w" sizes="90vw" type="image/webp">




</picture>

      
    </span>
    
  </span>
  
    <span>
      
        <figcaption><em>Street Fighter: The Legend of Chun-Li</em></figcaption>
      
      
        <cite>Image: 20th Century Fox/Everett Collection</cite>
      
    </span>
  
</figure>


</p>
<p id="bWjzlF">Cinema knows violence well. Even <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=y3jrB5ANUUY">films from the birth of the medium</a> could make audiences sweat, showcasing train robbers with polite-looking pistols that still seemed menacing on screen. Artificial violence, <a href="https://theconversation.com/from-tarantino-to-squid-game-why-do-so-many-people-enjoy-violence-170251">scientists think</a>, provides us with safe, pleasurable adrenaline hits, and filmmakers have spent a century satisfying that innate craving for thrills. After a century of trial and error, perfecting tension and fake blood, we’re left with a modern movie landscape dominated by Marvel movies and expert action directors like Christopher Nolan, Quentin Tarantino, the Wachowskis, and John Woo. They serve up glass-shattering fight sequences as nonchalantly as baby food.</p>
<p id="I2FzFN">This landscape produces tons of video game films like <a href="https://www.polygon.com/reviews/23669990/super-mario-bros-movie-review-references"><em>The Super Mario Bros. Movie</em></a><em> </em>and 2016’s totally forgettable <a href="https://www.polygon.com/2016/12/19/13987362/assassins-creed-film-review"><em>Assassin’s Creed</em></a>, which feature notable fight sequences, but remove them so far from the worlds they take place in, they might as well be free-floating meteors. I’m thinking of 2022’s perplexing <em>Uncharted</em>, which <a href="https://www.polygon.com/reviews/22934933/uncharted-movie-review-tom-holland">disappointed fans</a> with its nonchalance toward the franchise’s usual zeal for history and mystery, but sends <a href="https://youtu.be/4WcFk3X-RYc?si=SYhjAPq0umTYvdIR&amp;t=177">a vintage Mercedes</a> barrelling out of a plane in an attempt to compensate. 2023’s <a href="https://www.polygon.com/reviews/23934016/five-nights-at-freddys-movie-review-horror-streamers"><em>Five Nights at Freddy’s</em></a> likewise forgoes the series’ trademark jump-scares and Chuck E. Cheese psychological horror. In their place, it offers a girl getting <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=m_jR08koqJA">chomped in half</a>, though the games rarely ever show blood.</p>
<p id="TThGcL">In games, fights do often function as plot benchmarks. But a video game fight can shine even without any context if it offers worthwhile imagery, immersion, or mechanics. The fighting-game genre offers the best examples — no one is forcing their roommate into another round of <a href="https://www.polygon.com/game/super-smash-bros-ultimate-nintendo-switch/40339"><em>Super Smash Bros. Ultimate</em></a> praying that it’ll finally reveal Villager and Dark Pit’s romantic tension. They’re playing <em>Smash</em> because its controls are rewarding, or because it offers a skill to master, and there are a million ways to bodyslam to victory. </p>
<p>  <figure>
  <span>
    
    <span data-original="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25451783/MCDASCR_FE008.jpg">
      
        <picture data-cid="site/picture_element-1716216610_6784_27269" data-cdata="{&quot;asset_id&quot;:25451783,&quot;ratio&quot;:&quot;*&quot;}">
  


  <source srcset="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/EXK_ljc23sDe73pXzSb4TWC3CaU=/0x0:5760x3840/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:5760x3840):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25451783/MCDASCR_FE008.jpg 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ddoKmUcnUpCmq82roXKaaZBr0O8=/0x0:5760x3840/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:5760x3840):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25451783/MCDASCR_FE008.jpg 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/KvpUAgzOMAaEGDbByiK87RhOZxA=/0x0:5760x3840/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:5760x3840):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25451783/MCDASCR_FE008.jpg 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7-Y4CjYhOFffzC-WfmFZLapWMWQ=/0x0:5760x3840/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:5760x3840):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25451783/MCDASCR_FE008.jpg 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1g89SXogaPaXlXxbeU0RGbtVdVM=/0x0:5760x3840/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:5760x3840):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25451783/MCDASCR_FE008.jpg 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qCIRI_Twac4ngvkL17Zq4Czc2lI=/0x0:5760x3840/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:5760x3840):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25451783/MCDASCR_FE008.jpg 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/L2iBoddtqvrM-tf49-ZKA78KEJo=/0x0:5760x3840/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:5760x3840):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25451783/MCDASCR_FE008.jpg 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ErxgIRMJQvTg99Yy76-Vw2TSL5Y=/0x0:5760x3840/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:5760x3840):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25451783/MCDASCR_FE008.jpg 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Dmp7tXJxExY8bE-zs_6FICrOzuY=/0x0:5760x3840/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:5760x3840):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25451783/MCDASCR_FE008.jpg 1920w" sizes="90vw" type="image/webp">




</picture>

      
    </span>
    
  </span>
  
    <span>
      
        <figcaption><em>Assassin’s Creed</em></figcaption>
      
      
        <cite>Image: 20th Century Fox/Everett Collection</cite>
      
    </span>
  
</figure>


</p>
<p id="mWAFV3">But video game movies need meaningful story framing for those same battles. The recent underwhelming video game thriller <a href="https://www.polygon.com/reviews/24141885/boy-kills-world-review-video-game-movie-bill-skarsgard"><em>Boy Kills World</em></a> is a useful example — its world-building is minimal, and its justification for its many fight scenes is sparse. That isn’t satisfying because we can’t interact with them. It’s impossible to separate a movie fight from its context — unlike a single <em>Mortal Kombat </em>match or a wrathful <em>Elden Ring</em> field boss, a movie fight needs the 90 minutes around it to be valuable. Movie-watching is inherently passive, and an absorbing one needs stakes, and a way to get the audience invested quickly. </p>
<p id="GZA6L7">So though <em>Boy Kills World</em>’s fight scenes are incredible — one brutal dining-room fight, amid red lobsters and pink macarons, is practically operatic — they don’t stop the film from feeling insubstantial. </p>
<p id="qyPVJd">The core of the film is intelligible enough: Boy (Bill Skarsgård) wants vengeance against despot Hilda Van Der Koy (Famke Janssen) and her equally evil family, who rule his jumbled Southeast Asian/Grecian/<em>Borderlands</em> jungle/slum/<em>Resident Evil</em> country through brutality and murder. Boy was mutilated in his youth, with hot pokers forced into his ears and his tongue snipped out, and he’s forgotten the sound of his own voice. His inner monologue (courtesy of H. Jon Benjamin) instead sounds like the protagonist of his favorite video game, the fictional <em>Super Dragon Punch Force 2</em>. (Though the game does exist now, as a <a href="https://www.polygon.com/24118252/boy-kills-world-game-super-dragon-force-punch-3">movie tie-in</a>.) As Boy battles through ranks of flunkies and destroys a series of Van Der Koys, Bob Belcher narrates with gravelly arcade-game enthusiasm: “Player two wins!” </p>
<p>  <figure>
  <span>
    
    <span data-original="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25451789/MCDBOKI_EC015.jpg">
      
        <picture data-cid="site/picture_element-1716216610_9765_27270" data-cdata="{&quot;asset_id&quot;:25451789,&quot;ratio&quot;:&quot;*&quot;}">
  


  <source srcset="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3VsHMAPTPLM0z5HuDnNLRhZQWTM=/0x0:3000x1905/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x1905):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25451789/MCDBOKI_EC015.jpg 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZGXFcbhzCsqEouaGL9LX8L4O0yM=/0x0:3000x1905/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x1905):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25451789/MCDBOKI_EC015.jpg 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/85uT8NkgvNVMjqrSt-fdwLr4Vw4=/0x0:3000x1905/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x1905):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25451789/MCDBOKI_EC015.jpg 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/04Y-wIiEC6s7X3Sj93VcmsfmvsE=/0x0:3000x1905/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x1905):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25451789/MCDBOKI_EC015.jpg 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-tvhRNtkwIcqILvrBjEG_D-mkuA=/0x0:3000x1905/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x1905):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25451789/MCDBOKI_EC015.jpg 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Ik0965XuFCu7GjUM-xdKwt_776A=/0x0:3000x1905/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x1905):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25451789/MCDBOKI_EC015.jpg 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/GCJ4Ann7irvJSEqL-yTPJjAh6Hc=/0x0:3000x1905/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x1905):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25451789/MCDBOKI_EC015.jpg 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cb4YzADxlrWv8CLy02WUVRl8kdk=/0x0:3000x1905/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x1905):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25451789/MCDBOKI_EC015.jpg 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rVkNXH8M7JR4ict5PojhTKMmMuw=/0x0:3000x1905/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x1905):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25451789/MCDBOKI_EC015.jpg 1920w" sizes="90vw" type="image/webp">




</picture>

      
    </span>
    
  </span>
  
    <span>
      
        <figcaption><em>Boy Kills World</em></figcaption>
      
      
        <cite>Image: Roadside Attractions/Everett Collection</cite>
      
    </span>
  
</figure>


</p>
<p id="TiQMSV">This revenge plot lies in a twisted nest, lazy with weak points. Even its most basic establishing factors are unclear. We don’t know where the bloodthirsty Van Der Koy family, which ritualistically murders citizens on TV in a <em>Hunger Games</em>-style “culling,” came from, or how they’ve made it this long without being overthrown. Hilda herself is apparently mentally ill, and she spends most of her time hiding ineffectually in a bunker. </p>
<p id="Mvkwjr">Their oppressed citizenry in Boy’s country doesn’t question any of this. They barely seem to exist: These NPCs took a couple hits to the head while being transported to the movie screen, and they’re only ever shown silently cowering or hobbling along dirty market streets. It’s hard to make sense of the apathetic, aesthetic mess that is <em>Boy Kills World</em>’s setting, so it’s equally hard to savor how Boy’s quest dismantles it. Despite the movie signals through post-apocalyptic-wasteland visuals and sort-of boss fights that it’s a movie as heartstopping as the best RPG video game, <em>Boy Kills World</em> skips the world-building that makes tonally similar franchises like BioShock and Fallout compelling.</p>
<p id="Ii2z7Z"><em>Boy Kills World</em> leans on elaborate fight sequences hoping that they’ll distract you from the fact that this is an empty stage, under too-bright white lights. Like a flat Diet Coke, it’s too artificial, even for something artificial. It’s missing the detail of a place you can imagine visiting — you can’t reach for your obedient puppy’s silky head, like you can in <em>Final Fantasy XVI</em>. You can’t happen upon a Super Mushroom and trample over grass as confidently as a bear, like you do in <em>Super Mario 64</em>. Audiences want to feel more of this kind of tactile fantasy in their entertainment, especially now that TV has given them an even bigger appetite for the pull-apart tension that comes with engrossing video game storytelling. </p>
<p>  <figure>
  <span>
    
    <span data-original="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25451796/MCDBOKI_RT017.jpg">
      
        <picture data-cid="site/picture_element-1716216610_1609_27271" data-cdata="{&quot;asset_id&quot;:25451796,&quot;ratio&quot;:&quot;*&quot;}">
  


  <source srcset="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ijIRC97v138qwhgX4rIrc3-I0x4=/0x0:3000x1247/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x1247):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25451796/MCDBOKI_RT017.jpg 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dSaxH-Muqgj7fGHSU35Dc50fe7Y=/0x0:3000x1247/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x1247):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25451796/MCDBOKI_RT017.jpg 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3CX4x4RVzNkA1pSnYG03uoGAXx4=/0x0:3000x1247/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x1247):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25451796/MCDBOKI_RT017.jpg 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0i_CwNaOQIrnnVQe6-jN6twZhps=/0x0:3000x1247/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x1247):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25451796/MCDBOKI_RT017.jpg 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/avfRM5-mFsTtVCF6-mfgX9VQHqs=/0x0:3000x1247/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x1247):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25451796/MCDBOKI_RT017.jpg 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4K9lM81JUIpsTjj9_SVyEiB6Kak=/0x0:3000x1247/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x1247):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25451796/MCDBOKI_RT017.jpg 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/HOcJmpQU1QTqQGRB4VFSZmKeBwc=/0x0:3000x1247/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x1247):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25451796/MCDBOKI_RT017.jpg 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/DBClSLuVpETU8XyGKzy5T5xpoak=/0x0:3000x1247/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x1247):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25451796/MCDBOKI_RT017.jpg 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_f0fFbfrSQs8RQlY4DYPKAEHa_k=/0x0:3000x1247/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x1247):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25451796/MCDBOKI_RT017.jpg 1920w" sizes="90vw" type="image/webp">




</picture>

      
    </span>
    
  </span>
  
    <span>
      
        <figcaption><em>Boy Kills World</em></figcaption>
      
      
        <cite>Image: Roadside Attractions/Everett Collection</cite>
      
    </span>
  
</figure>


</p>
<p id="NuuO4d">Through specifics — dirt collecting under its protagonists’ collars, the white sun turning their parched lips gray and cracked — Prime’s <em>Fallout</em> makes you feel like the game does, like the violence you’re witnessing will determine your own life or death. The drawn-out nature of TV makes it easier for video game IP to slowly spill its honey world and stick you in it, like it would during the course of an RPG video game’s 20-hour story. Movies have tighter confines, so they turn to violence to make their stories seem bigger and more urgent. Action is a quicker way to command attention — <em>Hey, look! Big explosion!</em> — than games’ more drawn-out pleasures, like puzzle-solving, or the endless horizon of open-world exploration. While film noir and <em>Planet Earth</em> demonstrate that these elements transfer beautifully onto a screen when directors pay them attention, filmmakers still seem to believe that nothing about video games is as important as crushing bosses with a katana.</p>
<p id="1LT4vp">As something constantly orchestrated and fine-tuned by players, video game violence often requires active attention and intervention. Video game movies, in turn, need to accept the limitations of a passive-viewing format, and commit to story over surface-level video game nods like “Fatality!” battle cries. They’re reductive, and they make games look like a perverse carnival attraction instead of a teeming ecosystem.</p>
<p id="UISHwf">Some filmmakers have already chosen more inspired methods of adapting games. 2019’s <em>Detective Pikachu</em> can stand as a true Pokémon spin-off, even though it almost completely avoids the games’ turn-based combat, because the creators went through the trouble of building a lived-in metropolis where Pokémon convincingly work and play alongside humans. Ryme City looks like London, and feels like a place where a Pikachu could reasonably perform some private investigating. Once the world and the setting fall into place, the rest of the movie can build on them, and you can sit back and enjoy it along with your salty popcorn.</p>
<p>  <figure>
  <span>
    
    <span data-original="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25451811/MCDEXIS_EC016.jpg">
      
        <picture data-cid="site/picture_element-1716216610_2849_27272" data-cdata="{&quot;asset_id&quot;:25451811,&quot;ratio&quot;:&quot;*&quot;}">
  


  <source srcset="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dRwApO2gounXrWhZF4k0__3e-g8=/0x0:4057x2700/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:4057x2700):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25451811/MCDEXIS_EC016.jpg 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rs5azE0JFYL7scsMQqyvgkTL7eY=/0x0:4057x2700/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:4057x2700):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25451811/MCDEXIS_EC016.jpg 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5NgZRVwpjatKI4cAE8m15HNbXLI=/0x0:4057x2700/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:4057x2700):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25451811/MCDEXIS_EC016.jpg 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wsIeeUhsN8lcghUZSCK_eo_TU58=/0x0:4057x2700/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:4057x2700):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25451811/MCDEXIS_EC016.jpg 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5XQU73LkCYi7yZgrJijuqgl541c=/0x0:4057x2700/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:4057x2700):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25451811/MCDEXIS_EC016.jpg 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/WIOs7Bq6dLz7-kCI94iiTakS_oE=/0x0:4057x2700/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:4057x2700):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25451811/MCDEXIS_EC016.jpg 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Zeq4P_wE7TTRmNM_HcdCLEftYYY=/0x0:4057x2700/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:4057x2700):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25451811/MCDEXIS_EC016.jpg 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/P229tB_30VyugzeKrjmtAd1jL1k=/0x0:4057x2700/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:4057x2700):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25451811/MCDEXIS_EC016.jpg 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/HZYh0KTUOPrG8uTSqjD1YwhOakI=/0x0:4057x2700/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:4057x2700):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25451811/MCDEXIS_EC016.jpg 1920w" sizes="90vw" type="image/webp">




</picture>

      
    </span>
    
  </span>
  
    <span>
      
        <figcaption><em>eXistenZ</em></figcaption>
      
      
        <cite>Image: Dimension Films/Everett Collection</cite>
      
    </span>
  
</figure>


</p>
<p id="NLUrdN">Twenty years earlier, David Cronenberg’s sci-fi horror movie <em>eXistenZ</em> also excelled at adopting the tone of games in order to texturize its unique story. It centers on hyper-powerful video game corporations, which dole out “bio-port” spinal injections and game controllers that move like kicking fetuses. It’s energetically tied to gloomy ’90s corporate apocalypse games like <em>Deus Ex </em>and <em>Doom</em>, but it extracts from them another challenge for viewers: Is this real, or is it a game? Sometimes it’s hard to tell the difference, because Cronenberg treats games like intense, passionate dreams, not as janky vehicles for shock-and-awe violence. </p>
<p id="MS4Zh6">That’s what rote, unemotional fight sequences take away from a film — the unmistakable wave of immersion, the sense that combat is an inextricable part of a story, not just an excuse for more blown-up cars. Video game movies would work much better if their creators acknowledged a truth, gamers tend to already know: Violence isn’t just about cool visuals. To engage, move, or even attract an audience, it needs to have a heart, too. </p>
  
</div>











  </main>
  

</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MultiVersus Trailer Teases Jason Voorhees, Agent Smith, & More]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/multiversus-trailer-teases-jason-voorhees-agent-smith-more/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/multiversus-trailer-teases-jason-voorhees-agent-smith-more.875613/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/multiversus-trailer-teases-jason-voorhees-agent-smith-more/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>In <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qX5AUVIAg_o" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a new trailer</a> today, Player First Games revealed that Agent Smith and Jason Voorhees are coming to MultiVersus for its long-awaited return. </p>



<p>There was also a peek at the city of Townsville, teasing that the Powerpuff Girls are also likely on the way. Fans also caught a glimpse of the Teen Titans Tower, suggesting the beloved team is coming too.</p>



<p>Rumors about these additions to the roster appeared very recently. Twitter/X user @AusilMV spotted related tags on the new trailer ahead of its premiere. The new MultiVersus characters certainly open the door to more related IP, and Jason was surely a welcome surprise in today’s trailer.</p>



<figure></figure>







<p>Fans are already speculating on the future of the MultiVersus roster using hints in today’s trailer.</p>



<p>Twitter user <a href="https://x.com/Shaggy_Leaks/status/1792542934073737564" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">@Shaggy_Leaks noticed</a> that the WB tower in the trailer featured a trident, katana, and more. This may imply that the devs are planning on introducing fan favorite characters like Samurai Jack.</p>



<p>It’s clear there’s a lot of investment behind the game’s collaborations, even adding an <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/multiversus-x-nhl-live-event-announced-featuring-real-time-animation/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">NHL Face Off event</a> last April that featured real-time animation.</p>



<p>MultiVersus <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/multiversus-to-shut-down-ahead-of-full-launch-in-2024/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">shut down its Open Beta</a> in June 2023, so the full release will arrive almost a year later. Last March, developer Player First Games finally announced that MultiVersus will <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/multiversus-release-date-announced-for-may-28th/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">launch on May 28, 2024</a>.</p>



<p>MultiVersus will be free to play for PC, PlayStation, and Xbox. It will also support cross-play and cross-progression.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more of the latest gaming industry news, you can read about the Call of Duty <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-to-release-october-25/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Black Ops 6 release date</a>, and sign up to receive the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/newsletter/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming newsletter</a>.</p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NeoSprint launches June 27]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/05/neosprint-launches-june-27</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/neosprint-launches-june-27.875610/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/05/neosprint-launches-june-27<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Arcade racing game <em><a title="Games > NeoSprint [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/neosprint">NeoSprint</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [7,035 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [5,330 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [26,704 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox One [13,160 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch [15,340 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>, <a title="Platforms > PC [20,103 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2217910/NeoSprint/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a>, and <a title="Companies > Atari [154 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/atari">Atari</a> VCS on June 27 for $24.99, publisher Atari and developer <a title="Companies > Headless Chicken [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/headless-chicken">Headless Chicken</a> announced. <span id="more-883559"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Atari:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Atari’s newest release, <em>NeoSprint</em>, has its roots in the <em>Sprint</em> series of arcade <a title="Genres > Racing [179 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/racing">racing games</a> from the late 70s. <em>NeoSprint</em> shifts from the original’s 2D to 3D isometric tracks, and injects some serious single-screen racing fun for up to eight players. There’s tons of gameplay across Campaign, Grand Prix, Obstacle Course and Time Trial modes, and building and sharing tools let you share your tracks and compete for the fastest times with players around the world.</p><p><em>NeoSprint</em> is a passion project, conceived by Atari’s long-serving art director John Kauderer and developed by the Costa Rican-based studio Headless Chicken. <em>Sprint 2</em> is a worthy-addition to the <em>Sprint</em> series bloodline and that is sure to satisfy speed demons and architects alike.</p><p><em>NeoSprint</em> was exclusively introduced as an early-access game on the Atari VCS during development. The team used feedback from the VCS community to refine and finesse many aspects of the game.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Isometric Arcade <a title="Genres > Action [1,841 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">Action</a></strong> – Precise controls with an arcade feel makes <em>NeoSprint</em> gameplay easy to pick up but hard to master. Learn the intricacies of drifting and drafting to pull ahead across a dazzling array of pre-made and player-created racetracks.</li><li><strong>Robust Track-Building and Sharing</strong> – Design twisting, turning tracks with a deep, customizable track builder. Build ramps, jumps, banks and more with easy-to-use drop and click track segments, and add an even more of a personal touch with scenery and decorations to make your track stand out. Choose from one of four different biomes—forest, desert, winter, and city—when building tracks, and group together or mix and match in your circuits. Easy-to-use tools allow you to share your tracks—-and try out tracks posted by other players.</li><li><strong>A Lineup Built for Speed</strong> – Featuring nice different car types, from muscle to sports cars, all with unique speed, acceleration and handling. Each car is customizable with different colors and Atari-themed decals. Create your dream car and get racing!</li><li><strong>It’s a Career</strong> – In the solo Campaign Mode, challenge eight unique AI rivals in <em>NeoSprint</em>‘s to be the circuit’s best driver. Travel through multiple Cups with increasingly difficult tracks. As you progress, unlock new decorations and car liveries.</li><li><strong>Alternate Game Modes</strong> – With Grand Prix mode you can build circuits from your own tracks, download tracks created by other players, or mix them together. Obstacle Courses and Time Trials provide hours of racing fun after completing the Campaign.</li></ul><p><strong>Background</strong></p><ul><li>According to one of the <em>Sprint 2</em> developers, Dan Van Elderen, it was the first racing game to use artificial intelligence. In a November 1997 interview, Can Eldren said <em>Sprint 2</em> “was the first game that actually introduced the concept of a computer car that had the intelligence to drive itself around the track—not necessarily just in a canned predetermined course, but in a semi-intelligent manner, depending on how you were doing.”</li><li>The <em>Sprint</em> series included <em>Sprint 2</em>, <em>4</em>, <em>8</em>, and <em>One</em> in that order, with the numbers indicating the number of players, not the order of release.</li><li>In the United States at release, <em>Sprint 2</em> was a top-three arcade industry earner for three years running. It was the second highest-earning <a title="Genres > Arcade [52 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/arcade">arcade video game</a> in 1977 and 1978, and the third highest in 1979.</li><li>Unlike many early racing arcade cabinets, the <em>Sprint</em> games offered a selection of tracks—four for <em>Sprint 8</em>, twelve for <em>Sprint 2</em>—which contributed to their success in <a title="Platforms > Arcade [371 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/arcade">arcades</a>.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="NeoSprint - Release Date Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/IK03pQlgXWc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Did video game investment hit rock bottom, and is it ready to go back up?]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamesindustry.biz/did-video-game-investment-hit-rock-bottom-and-is-it-ready-to-go-back-up</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/did-video-game-investment-hit-rock-bottom-and-is-it-ready-to-go-back-up.875607/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamesindustry.biz/did-video-game-investment-hit-rock-bottom-and-is-it-ready-to-go-back-up<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>A panel at Reboot Develop 2024 tackled the situation in terms of financing, with great focus on the indie scene</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/reboot-2024-financial-panel-(2).jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Andrea Maderna. Pictured left to right: Anders Leicht Rohde, Antonio Pašalić, Jussi Tähtinen, Jonas Antonsson, Shum Singh</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>After the annus horribilis that was 2023 and with the rough start that in many ways characterized 2024, it's probably fair to say that many people are worried about the state of the industry and how it could move forward. At Reboot Develop Blue 2024, a panel tackled this very topic and argued that, while the industry has hit rock bottom, it is ready to go back up.</p>
<p>The panel saw on stage Jonas Antonsson (CEO at Raw Fury), Anders Leicht Rohde (CCO of Funday Games), Jussi Tähtinen (CEO at Nitro Games) and Antonio Pašalić (Program Director at WN Media Group). The moderator was Shum Singh (Managing Director at Agnitio Capital).</p>
<p>The discussion kicked off by mentioning the fact that all the people on stage have been working in the industry for more or less two decades and how immensely the industry has grown and changed in that time frame.</p>
<p>"In 2007 there was no mobile market," said Tähtinen. "The PC segment had become really small and the video game industry was mostly focused on console. Today, PC is bigger than consoles."</p>
<p>But the tough times the industry is going through, with more than 15,000 announced layoffs so far, are the reason why this panel took place. The big question, the panelists said, is where all these people will go.</p>
<p>"The obvious answer is that the industry is going to lose most of those people, who will choose to give up game development and find a more secure job," said Tähtinen.</p>
<p>But the situation is not the same everywhere. The panelists mentioned how right now the situation is probably particularly harsh in territories like the USA, where the financing situation is much less favorable than in the past, but the turmoil is felt almost everywhere.</p>
<p>"Denmark is also seeing lots of layoffs and studio closure," said Funday Games' Anders Leicht Rohde, "and it's a particularly rough situation because it's a small market, so names are piling up on a huge waiting list made of people who lost their jobs and new arrivals who get out of school and hope to get hired somewhere."</p>
<p>Leicht Rohde added that, while a lot of people are leaving the industry, there are also new small independent studios being founded by those affected.</p>
<blockquote><p>"The games industry is going to lose most of those people [laid off], who will choose to give up game development and find a more secure job"</p>
<cite>Jussi Tähtinen, Nitro Games</cite>
</blockquote>
<p>WN Media Group's Antonio Pašalić tried to push a positive spin on the conversation by mentioning how Serbia is actually seeing a complete opposite trend. Apparently, in that territory "it’s better than ever, there’s a lot of investments going on and the local gaming industry is basically being born right now." Pašalić hopes that this will generate a positive influence in the Balkan area and push the development of gaming in those territories. On a similar note, it was mentioned how the Turkish market seems to be primed for a huge growth.</p>
<p>Picking up from what Rohde had said about younger people coming out of school, Raw Fury's Jonas Antonsson mentioned one more dire consequence of the current situation: "It makes jobs in the gaming industry much less desirable, with potential new talents probably deciding to look for more secure sectors from the get go."</p>
<p>At the same time though, he pointed out how the games industry has always functioned in a cyclical way, adding that past collapses, like the infamous 1983 U.S. market crash, "gave birth to companies that became and still are dominant."</p>
<p>The question is: has the industry hit rock bottom to a point where it can only go up? Panel moderator Shum Singh mentioned that some companies have reached historically low points in terms of market valuation and how people think that's the best time to invest.</p>
<p>"Some of the biggest game publishers like Ubisoft or many Asian companies have huge amount of cash available," he said, adding that the issue may not be the lack of funds but the fear of making mistakes.</p>
<p>Antonsson is quite convinced that things are starting to move again and even though investors are more cautious right now, the stock market will soon improve and tax interests will go down. That being said, he warned: "There will still be bad situations and sad news, with layoffs and studio closures, but the worst is behind us."</p>
<p>Generally speaking, the panel agreed on the fact that financing has already became more available than in the previous six months.</p>
<blockquote><p>"There will still be bad situations and sad news, with layoffs and studio closures, but the worst is behind us"</p>
<cite>Jonas Antonsson, Raw Fury</cite>
</blockquote>
<p>"Gamescom 2023 was when suddenly everybody stopped signing new games", Singh said, "but around Game Developers Conference in March it has started to get better, with news of signings and greenlights."</p>
<p>Antonsson pointed out this is also an opportunity to look at the past and try to grow as an industry.</p>
<p>"In the past few years we've seen a crazy way of doing business, with really irrational investments, and maybe this is a chance to start acting in a more rational way."</p>
<p>He added that he would like the industry to stop being dominated by outside investment thesis – "people from Silicon Valley and external investment funds telling video game publishers and developers what they should do, which trends they should follow." He thinks that people in the video games industry should go back to making their own decisions and doing what they know is right, instead of listening to foolish ideas coming from the outside.</p>
<p>So what about the future? The panel inevitably touched upon AI, with the the general consensus being that it shouldn't be particularly dangerous in terms of generating more layoffs and eroding job security. In fact, Tähtinen said, "It will probably be used mostly to simplify processes and it could generate new job opportunities for people who will be hired to manage and use it."</p>
<p>Leicht Rohde warned that AI could "be impactful on companies that specialize in outsourcing," but overall the panelists seemed to think there's not much to fear from this new boogeyman.</p>
<p>Singh observed that Keywords Studios saw a decrease in stock value when market researchers said that its competitors would be able to take advantage of AI, yet Keywords "still had a very profitable year."</p>
<p>Antonsson also pointed out how new disruptive technologies always change the industry structure: "With the introduction of Unity, big companies that employed armies of C++ programmers almost suddenly disappeared. But, of course, Unity also opened huge doors."</p>
<p>Elsewhere, Tähtinen believes that the Switch successor and the portable PCs segment kickstarted by Steam Deck could bring back portable gaming. "The mobile market is supposedly dead", he said, "but people still want to play portable."</p>
<p>Also, he pointed out how markets never really 'die' like we tend to think, adding: "PC was declared dead, now it's huge; mobile has been declared dead, but what actually happened is that it's not anymore over 50% of the market... it's only around 49%."</p>
<p>Tähtinen also seems to be pretty convinced that the next big splash will come from the indie scene. Sure, Grand Theft Auto VI is coming, but generally speaking, "big publishers are going to focus on safe projects and there's a real chance for indie game developers to assert themselves as an even bigger part of the industry."</p>
<blockquote><p>"There's twenty venture capital funds that are entirely dedicated to video games. That is something that simply didn't exist eight years ago"</p>
<cite>Shum Singh, Agnito Capital</cite></blockquote>
<p>And the whole panel agreed that the market has to find ways to protect and support independent game development. On this point, the almost complete lack of discoverability and curation is still a big issue in a market that is full of titles and choices and sees over half of the revenue generated by six-year-old games. This, the panel agreed, is a problem that needs to be tackled and, according to Singh, "constitutes a big opportunity for what still is a $200 billion market."</p>
<p>To reinforce the point, he mentioned how the scenery has changed in his line of work: "There's twenty venture capital funds that are entirely dedicated to video games. That is something that simply didn't exist eight years ago. It's a huge and very diversified industry that is going through an adjustment phase."</p>
<p>Singh also doubled down on the belief that the indie scene is primed to make big waves in the near future. He hopes that new authors will rise and "do what Quentin Tarantino did in the Nineties for the movie industry" by being a seminal and disruptive force.</p>
<p>The panel concluded with Jonas Antonsson talking about the Raw Fury philosophy and how they quite often "finance games that make no sense from a business point of view," that will never manage to double the investment or sometimes even just recoup. They do that because they can, they have enough money and they want to support creative people.</p>
<p>"It’s a mentality," he said. "It’s something that investors hate, but it’s much needed. Raw Fury acts like the music industry did decades ago, with talent scouts that went into bars, local concerts, and used intuition to find talented people."</p>
<p>He thinks that this way of operating still exists in games, but we see it less and less and there’s the risk that the video games industry "could end up doing exactly what happened in the movie industries by basing every single decision on analytics."</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Baldur's Gate 3 Dev Larian Opens New Studio As Development On Two 'Very Ambitious' RPGs Continues]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gameinformer.com/news/2024/05/20/baldurs-gate-3-dev-larian-opens-new-studio-as-development-on-two-very-ambitious</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/baldurs-gate-3-dev-larian-opens-new-studio-as-development-on-two-very-ambitious-rpgs-continues.875604/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gameinformer.com/news/2024/05/20/baldurs-gate-3-dev-larian-opens-new-studio-as-development-on-two-very-ambitious<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p>Larian Studios, the team behind last year's <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/product/baldurs-gate-3">Baldur's Gate 3</a>, has opened a new studio in Warsaw, Poland. Larian Studios Warsaw is the developer-publisher's seventh studio worldwide, and joins others in Barcelona, Dublin, Gent, Guildford, Kuala Lumpur, and Quebec.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"With two very ambitious RPGs now starting development, what better way to see our visions realized than by growing our team and opening a 7th studio in the heart of Poland's lively gaming scene," the company's announcement <a href="https://x.com/larianstudios/status/1792495491256664211">post</a> on X (formerly) Twitter reads.&nbsp;</p>

<p><iframe allow="autoplay" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/hpAGlgJMYLc" width="640"></iframe></p>

<p>As for what those two RPGs are, don't expect a sequel to Baldur's Gate 3. Despite <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/2024/04/11/every-winner-at-the-20th-bafta-games-awards">winning countless awards</a> last year, <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/the-game-awards-2023/2023/12/07/every-winner-at-the-game-awards-2023">including Game of the Year at The Game Awards 2023</a>, <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/2024/03/21/larian-ceo-says-the-studio-is-done-with-baldurs-gate-3-to-focus-on-something-new">Larian's CEO revealed back in March that the studio is done</a> with both Baldur's Gate 3 – so no expansions – and the Baldur's Gate series in general.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Over on a separate blog post about Larian Studios Warsaw, the company talks about its plans with seven worldwide studios open now.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Larian Studios set up base in one of the greatest RPG development hubs in the world – Poland, where we opened our doors in the historic city of Warsaw," the <a href="https://larian.com/careers/location/warsaw?location=warsaw">blog post</a> reads. "Like its sister studios across the globe, Larian Studios Warsaw is dedicated to fostering an environment where developers can thrive creatively and reclaim their agency. Systems-heavy RPGs need best-in-class developers; that's why we've put the people who build those systems at the center of our culture."&nbsp;</p>

<p>For more, read&nbsp;<a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/review/baldurs-gate-3/a-true-soul-stirrer"><em>Game Informer's&nbsp;</em>Baldur's Gate 3 review</a>, and then find out why it's on&nbsp;<a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/2024/01/26/top-10-rpgs-to-play-right-now"><em>Game Informer's&nbsp;</em>list of the top 10 RPGs to play right now</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<hr>
<p><em>What kind of RPG do you hope Larian Studios makes next? Let us know in the comments below!</em></p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Atari’s NeoSprint revives the cramped arcade racing series this June]]></title>
            <link>https://www.destructoid.com/ataris-neosprint-revives-the-cramped-arcade-racing-series-this-june/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=ataris-neosprint-revives-the-cramped-arcade-racing-series-this-june</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/atari%E2%80%99s-neosprint-revives-the-cramped-arcade-racing-series-this-june.875601/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.destructoid.com/ataris-neosprint-revives-the-cramped-arcade-racing-series-this-june/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=ataris-neosprint-revives-the-cramped-arcade-racing-series-this-june<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p data-characters="290" data-injectable="true" data-video="true">Atari <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=i6jXTy0_99I" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">has announced</a> that Headless Chicken Games’ <em>NeoSprint</em>, the successor to the classic-ish arcade series that I always get confused with <em>Super Off-Road</em>, will be launching on June 27. It will be released on Switch, PS4, PS5, Xbox Series X|S, PC, and Atari VCS (which still trucking).</p> <p data-characters="389" data-current-count="389" data-injectable="false">Okay, so think back. There were these arcade cabinets with (usually) three steering wheels. It was a top-down tilt-angled racing game. You and your friends would stand shoulder to shoulder and steer your cars around a track. If you remember it having a lot of dirt, that was probably 1989’s <em>Super Off-Road</em>. However, if it was F1-Racing on tarmac; that was probably 1986’s <em>Super Sprint</em>.</p> <p data-characters="184" data-current-count="573" data-injectable="true">I’m just finding out now that the two games weren’t really related. They’re not part of the same series. The arcade cabinets <a href="https://www.arcade-museum.com/Videogame/super-sprint" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">look functionally</a> <a href="https://www.arcade-museum.com/Videogame/ironman-ivan-stewarts-super-off-road" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the same</a>. I definitely played both.</p>
 <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"><p> https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=i6jXTy0_99I </p></figure> <p data-characters="260" data-current-count="560" data-injectable="true">If you’re a lot older than me, the series goes all the way back to 1977 with <em>Sprint 2</em>. That’s not a sequel. There was also <em>Sprint 4, 8, </em>and <em>One</em>, and the number is how many players each version was, and not the order in which they were released. Wild stuff.</p>
 <p data-characters="422" data-current-count="422" data-injectable="true">Since Atari is going back and resurrecting all their old classics, they’ve got a new entry to the series <em>NeoSprint</em>. It definitely looks like a <em>Sprint</em> game. It’s got a similar angle and eight players. The track is really tight. There’s a trailer for it that features some really bad drivers. Although to be fair, it’s kind of hard to judge your turn radius from that angle. You’d just kind of bump off each other.</p>
 <p data-characters="103" data-current-count="103" data-injectable="false">Weirdly, it refers to it as 8-player co-op racing. So, wait. What’s the objective? Is it not to race?</p> <p data-characters="261" data-current-count="364" data-injectable="false">It’s local co-op, so you’ll at least be on the same couch (in the same auditorium?) as each other. But, I don’t know. I think I’d miss being crammed up against the arcade cabinet in some hockey arena playing with whoever was hovering around at the time.</p> <p data-characters="197" data-current-count="561" data-injectable="true">I guess to make up for it, there’s a track builder which looks like a fantastic feature. I don’t think <em>NeoSprint’s</em> design really allows for some wild tracks, but at least you won’t run out.</p>
 <p data-characters="86" data-current-count="86" data-injectable="false"><em>NeoSprint </em>releases on June 27 on Switch, PS4, PS5, Xbox Series X|S, PC, and Atari VCS.</p>

<hr>
<p><i data-stringify-type="italic"> Destructoid is supported by our audience. When you purchase through links on our site, we may earn a small affiliate commission.&nbsp;</i><i data-stringify-type="italic"><a href="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-stringify-link="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" data-sk="tooltip_parent">Learn more</a></i> </p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Puzzle Game Lorelei And The Laser Eyes Should Be Played With A Buddy]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/lorelei-laser-eyes-tips-steam-nintendo</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/puzzle-game-lorelei-and-the-laser-eyes-should-be-played-with-a-buddy.875598/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://aftermath.site/lorelei-laser-eyes-tips-steam-nintendo<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><a href="https://annapurnainteractive.com/en/games/lorelei-and-the-laser-eyes" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Lorelei and the Laser Eyes</em></a> is a puzzle game that came out last week, which half of my Twitter timeline has been raving about since it was announced back in April’s Nintendo indie showcase. Now that I can play it myself, I can see what’s gotten so many people excited, but I think you need to play with a friend to <em>really</em> get it.</p><div><figure><p><iframe title="Lorelei and the Laser Eyes – Release Date Trailer – Nintendo Switch" width="710" height="399" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/SreQDMyQNHE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></figure></div><p>In <em>Lorelei and the Laser Eyes</em> (by the developers of the very good <em>Sayonara Wild Hearts)</em>, you play a woman who arrives at a mysterious hotel to meet an even-more-mysterious filmmaker, who wants… something from her. To make a movie? To find his missing script pages? To solve a murder? I’m not sure! The game’s story is obscure, and basically <em>everything</em> is gated behind puzzles. And these aren’t your standard “flip the switch” or “find the key” puzzles: they’re actual <em>math</em>, using both Roman and Arabic numerals, and they also involve rotating things or solving logic tricks or paying very very close attention to your environment. <em>Everything </em>is puzzles. Sometimes you solve a puzzle to unlock a room and inside the room is <em>another</em> puzzle! It’s puzzles all the way down!</p><p>The game advises you to play with a notebook, which is definitely a must-have for scratching out calculations and organizing your thoughts. (I‘ve found using my phone as a calculator or to take pictures of certain things on my computer screen to be helpful too.) The game automatically adds every task you discover and document you open to a menu that is comprehensive but a bit clunky to navigate. There are <em>a lot</em> of tasks and documents; when I first started playing, I decided to explore the hotel before trying to follow whatever the story is, wandering from room to room encountering puzzles. This means my menus are now <em>stuffed</em> with orders to unlock doors and find tapes and solve puzzle boxes and open document tubes and navigate a creepy maze and figure out an intimidating machine. </p><p>I’m worried that exploring first might have been the wrong approach, because now I’m thoroughly overwhelmed with things to do. I’m partially through a bunch of puzzles, which I abandoned when I wasn’t sure how to proceed or if it seemed like I hadn’t found some necessary piece of information yet. So now, in addition to my in-game notebook of tasks, my real-life notebook is full of notes about how far through those tasks I am, making for quite a bit of chaos.&nbsp;</p><p>Lest this all sound like a mess, there is <em>some </em>guidance in the form of red footprints on the floor, which are at least helping me realize I should prioritze the tasks related to those story beats. I’m a bit stuck on some of them, which have led to puzzles I don’t quite understand yet. The game <em>really</em> wants you to think for yourself, which makes it feel more like a “get up early and play with coffee” game than the “squeeze in some hours before bed” game my schedule’s had me treat it as so far. This is compelling–many games, following a sensible instinct to be broadly approachable, are careful to make their puzzles clear and not too hard. But <em>Lorelei</em> really goes for it, dumping a pile of headscratchers on you and trusting you to make your way through them. I know the answers are all in there somewhere, in my in-game notebook or scattered around the hotel or within my math abilities. It feels like a very <em>fair</em> game; I just have to figure out how to tackle it.</p><p>On social media, my friends have told stories of realizing solutions after talking them over with someone else. After a few nights of solo play sessions, that really seems like the way to go: having another person around to talk the logic through with, or just to help me pick a thread to pull on next. The game is also a little bit creepy, though not strictly speaking a horror game, and so the stress of doing math is compounded by the vibes to make the experience a little bit tense for me to be playing alone at night. (I am, it should be noted, <a href="https://aftermath.site/grown-adult-coward-im-ok-with-just-watching-alan-wake-ii" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">very much a horror wuss</a>; your mileage may vary.) It feels like the kind of game that really opens up with someone sitting next to you to share in the delight of discovery, narrate your thought process out loud, and help remember which document the clues to a puzzle are hidden away in.&nbsp;</p><p><em>Lorelei</em> is a very unique and intriguing game, and I’ve been turning it over in my head all weekend. I’m really excited to keep digging into it– with a little help. I have the perfect buddy in mind for this task, whom I am going to email this blog to after I publish it. Unfortunately, coordinating our schedules will be its own puzzle, a challenge very much on par with the challenges in the game. If you’re playing, alone or with a friend, I’d love to hear how you’re finding it.</p></div><div><h2>Stay in touch</h2><p>Sign up for our free newsletter</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Grand Theft Auto 6 publisher "highly confident" of autumn 2025 release window]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/grand-theft-auto-6-publisher-highly-confident-of-autumn-2025-release-window</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/grand-theft-auto-6-publisher-highly-confident-of-autumn-2025-release-window.875586/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/grand-theft-auto-6-publisher-highly-confident-of-autumn-2025-release-window<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="content_above">



<p>
If you click on a link and make a purchase we may receive a small commission.  <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/editorial-policy">Read our editorial policy</a>.
</p>
    <div>
        <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-type="article">


<header>
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Jason-GTA-6-trailer.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Rockstar</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>    <div>



            <p>Take-Two is "highly confident" <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/gta-6-everything-we-know-so-far-9357">GTA 6</a> will make that recently-promised autumn 2025 release window.</p>
<p>The company's CEO Strauss Zelnick was asked about the timing of GTA 6's release during an interview with CNBC. Here, the company exec said the team generally decides upon a release window by factoring in measurable elements, using the "number of bugs in a title" as an example.</p>
<p>"Every one of us will make sure we have as few bugs in a title as possible before we launch," Zelnick said. But, in the case of GTA 6 - or, in Zelnick's words, "an extraordinary title, for which there are extraordinary expectations" - it is less about bugs and more about "creating an experience that no one has seen before".</p>
<figure>
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<figcaption>Here's the first trailer for Grand Theft Auto 6. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZvqP6ziEQ3Y" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>"[Developer] Rockstar Games seeks perfection in what they do. Perfection is indeed hard to measure," Zelnick continued. "It really is more subjective than objective."</p>
<p>Zelnick was then asked further about GTA 6's release window, which <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/grand-theft-auto-6-coming-in-fall-2025-publisher-take-two-reveals">Take-Two recently narrowed down from a broad 2025 timeframe to simply "fall" of next year</a>. While the CEO said there is often "slippage" in the industry, and Take-Two is not immune from delays, he does not see this happening with GTA 6.</p>
<p>"We narrowed the timing because we are highly confident in that timing," Zelnick said. You can listen to the exchange via the post below.</p> <div>
<div data-domain="twitter.com"><blockquote><div dir="ltr" lang="en"><p>Strauss Zelnick (Take-Two CEO) was interviewed by CNBC on <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/GTA6?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#GTA6</a></p><p>- The game was internally delayed because rockstar seeks perfection, it’s going to be a game NO ONE has EVER seen before. <a href="https://t.co/6rMF374VgR">pic.twitter.com/6rMF374VgR</a></p></div>— Dyllie (@_Dyllie_) <a href="https://twitter.com/_Dyllie_/status/1792241924738285669?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">May 19, 2024</a></blockquote></div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>When it does make its highly-anticipated debut, GTA 6 will release across both <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/gta-6-will-release-on-xbox-series-xs-and-playstation-5-in-2025">Xbox Series X/S and PlayStation 5</a>. Rockstar is yet to give a timeframe for a PC release. </p>
<p>
For more on the game, here's <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/gta-6-everything-we-know-so-far-9357">everything we know about GTA 6 so far</a>.</p>



        </div>


        </article>

  
    </div>


  
      </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Baldur's Gate 3 Dev Larian Studios Opens New Location in Warsaw]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/baldurs-gate-3-dev-larian-studios-new-location</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/baldurs-gate-3-dev-larian-studios-opens-new-location-in-warsaw.875583/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/baldurs-gate-3-dev-larian-studios-new-location<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Baldur's Gate 3&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>Divinity: Original Sin 2&nbsp;</em>developer Larian Studios has opened a new studio location in Warsaw, and the studio is also beginning development on two new projects.</p>

<p>Per <a href="https://x.com/larianstudios/status/1792495491256664211" rel="noopener" target="_blank">a post on X (formerly Twitter)</a>, Larian's new location, which is its seventh worldwide studio, is located "in the heart of Poland's lively gaming scene". As if to demonstrate the point,&nbsp;<em>The Witcher&nbsp;</em>studio CD Projekt Red, which is also based in Warsaw, <a href="https://x.com/CDPROJEKTRED/status/1792519072690655655" rel="noopener" target="_blank">congratulated</a> Larian on the new studio.</p>

<p>In the aforementioned post, Larian also says that development work on "two very ambitious RPGs" is beginning in earnest.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/baldurs-gate-3-larian-new-studio.jpg?itok=DUQgWEzE 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/baldurs-gate-3-larian-new-studio.jpg?itok=zsmSuAH- 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Larian Studios is easily best-known for its work on&nbsp;<em>Baldur's Gate 3</em>.</figcaption></figure><p>This isn't the first time we've heard about these new projects. Last month, Larian said that rather than creating a sequel to&nbsp;<em>Baldur's Gate 3</em>, the studio would <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/baldurs-gate-3-mod-support-patch-7">focus on two upcoming projects</a>, both of which will be based on original IPs.</p>

<p>It sounds like the new games won't be based on&nbsp;<em>Divinity&nbsp;</em>either, so if you were hoping for a sequel to 2017's well-received&nbsp;<em>Divinity: Original Sin 2</em>, then you may well be just as out of luck as&nbsp;<em>Baldur's Gate 3&nbsp;</em>fans, sadly.</p>

<p>In any case, Larian will be in good company while it's developing these two new projects. CD Projekt Red is far from the only studio based in Warsaw; others include&nbsp;<em><a href="https://techraptor.net/games/frostpunk">Frostpunk</a>&nbsp;</em>developer 11 bit studios,&nbsp;<em><a href="https://techraptor.net/games/evil-west">Evil West</a>&nbsp;</em>creator Flying Wild Hog, and&nbsp;<em><a href="https://techraptor.net/games/outriders">Outriders</a>&nbsp;</em>dev People Can Fly.</p>

<p>The division of labor between Larian's studios for the new projects is unclear, but since Larian doesn't clearly define which of its locations have made its games (in a manner similar to Ubisoft, for instance), it's likely all of the developer's locations will be involved.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/evil-west-flying-wild-hog-warsaw.jpg?itok=Hi9wtPz2 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/evil-west-flying-wild-hog-warsaw.jpg?itok=2w29WSV8 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Other Warsaw-based studios include&nbsp;<em>Evil West&nbsp;</em>developer Flying Wild Hog.</figcaption></figure><p>Larian says it's looking for talented "programmers, RPG designers, writers, and more" who either live in Poland or who would be interested in relocating.</p>

<p>If you're one of those people, you can check out the careers page for Larian's new Warsaw-based studio <a href="https://larian.com/careers/location/warsaw?location=warsaw" rel="noopener" target="_blank">right here</a>. Stay tuned for more news on whatever Larian does next.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for five years, and in those five years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Keywords wants shareholders to accept £2.2 billion buyout offer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/keywords-wants-shareholders-to-accept-2-2-billion-buyout-offer</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/keywords-wants-shareholders-to-accept-%C2%A32-2-billion-buyout-offer.875580/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/keywords-wants-shareholders-to-accept-2-2-billion-buyout-offer<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="captioned-content"><p><span>Image via Game Developer / Chris Kerr</span></p></div><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Swedish investment company EQT Group has tabled a cash offer of £25.5 ($32.4) per share to acquire Keywords Studios. The </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.ft.com/content/75886c5a-0f4f-4573-8844-a62efd518a68">Financial Times</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> reports the overall deal would value Keywords at £2.2 billion ($2.8 billion).</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Keywords is a global service provider for the video game industry. It offers services covering audio development, production, QA testing, marketing, player engagement, localization, and more.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The company boasts over 70 studios in 25 countries and employs over 12,000 people worldwide. It has worked with clients including Nintendo, NetEase, Take-Two Interactive, Square Enix, Ubisoft, Supercell, EA, Riot Games, and Tencent.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Keywords confirmed it's currently in "advanced discussions" with EQT Group in an </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://irpages2.equitystory.com/websites/rns_news/English/1100/news-tool---rns---eqs-group.html?company=keywords&amp;article=34301848">update to investors</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. The company explained EQT previously made four "unsolicited proposals," which the board ultimately rejected. The latest offer, however, represents a "significant increase" on the initial proposal.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"The Board remains confident in the Company's growth strategy of building the only truly global platform providing solutions to the video games and entertainment industries, both organically and through acquisitions, and EQT is supportive of this strategy," reads a statement from Keywords.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"The Board of Keywords Studios has carefully evaluated the Possible Offer with its financial advisers and concluded the Possible Offer is at a value that the Board would be minded to recommend to Keywords Studios shareholders."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Keywords has expanded significantly in recent years to enhance its business portfolio, often spending millions on major acquisitions in the process. Last December, the company </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/keywords-acquires-improbable-s-multiplayer-group-studio">purchased The Multiplayer Group for £76.5 million</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> to bolster its ability to support live-service titles. A few months earlier, it bought Call of Duty and Fortnite support studio </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/keywords-acquires-call-of-duty-and-fortnite-support-studio-hardsuit-labs">Hardsuit Labs</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and PR agency </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/keywords-boosts-marketing-credentials-with-purchase-of-pr-agency-fortyseven">FortySeven</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author(s)</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">News Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer news editor Chris Kerr is an award-winning journalist and reporter with over a decade of experience in the game industry. His byline has appeared in notable print and digital publications including Edge, Stuff, Wireframe, International Business Times, and&nbsp;</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="http://pocketgamer.biz/">PocketGamer.biz</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. Throughout his career, Chris has covered major industry events including GDC, PAX Australia, Gamescom, Paris Games Week, and Develop Brighton. He has featured on the judging panel at The Develop Star Awards on multiple occasions and appeared on BBC Radio 5 Live to discuss breaking news.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>