<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 14:47:58 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PlayStation 6 Will Reportedly Have A Detachable Disc Drive At Launch]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/playstation-6-reportedly-have-detachable-disc-drive-at-launch-ps6/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/playstation-6-will-reportedly-have-a-detachable-disc-drive-at-launch.1291572/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>This coming November 7, 2025, will mark the first anniversary of the <a href="https://wccftech.com/playstation-5-pro-unboxing/">PS5 Pro's launch</a>, a console that, in a physical sense, marked the halfway point of the PlayStation 5 generation, and the deeper we get into the PS5's life cycle, the closer we get to PlayStation 6. While pretty much everything we've heard about the next generation of PlayStation is rumors and speculation, a new report from <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/exclusive-playstation-6-is-planned-to-have-a-detachable-disc-drive-on-launch/">Insider-Gaming</a> does make a good deal of sense, that the coming PS6 will launch with a detachable disc drive.</p>



<p>The reality of PlayStation consoles having <a href="https://wccftech.com/playstation-5-slim-drive-multiple-consoles/">a detachable disc drive is already here</a>, and has been the case since 2023, so it's not in the least surprising that Sony and PlayStation would look to make the next console generation compatible with its current manufacturing process, which, according to Insider-Gaming's report, is one of the reasons behind the decision. According to its sources, PlayStation will sell the PS6 the same way it currently sells the PS5.</p>



<p>You'll be able to buy a PlayStation 6 with a disc drive pre-attached and bundled in, or buy it without the disc drive, with the option to add it later if you wish, by buying the disc drive on its own.</p>



<p>Besides the manufacturing reasons, it's also been previously pointed out that <a href="https://wccftech.com/playstation-6-discless/">PlayStation isn't ready to release a digital-only console</a>. That said, the <a href="https://wccftech.com/playstation-6-handheld-specks-leaked-outperform-xbox-ally-x/">rumored handheld PlayStation</a> won't have a disc drive, and the fact that the drives are already an option shows how PlayStation is inching towards a digital-only future. At least for now, players who still care about buying physical discs still have that option.</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/playstation-6-reportedly-have-detachable-disc-drive-at-launch-ps6/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Don’t Let Hollow Knight: Silksong‘s First Boss Stop You From Playing]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/silksong-first-boss-bell-beast-guide-2000624015</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/don%E2%80%99t-let-hollow-knight-silksong%E2%80%98s-first-boss-stop-you-from-playing.1291560/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>There are ways in which <a href="https://kotaku.com/hollow-knight-silksong-steam-review-bomb-chinese-translation-2000623496"><em>Hollow Knight: Silksong</em></a> can be a bit more difficult than its predecessor. For players new to the Metroidvania Soulslike series, it can feel a bit like taking a plunge in a cold lake: bracing but unpleasant. The game’s first boss fight is against the Bell Beast. If you’re feeling a bit daunted at first, the good news is that the giant arthropod is easy to defeat once you’ve got the pattern down.</p> <h2>Where do I find <em>Silksong</em>‘s first boss?</h2> <p>The Bell Beast is located early in the game in The Marrow. You can’t get to him until you unlock the Silk Spear ability next door in Mosshome. After getting it, there’s a silk obstacle in The Marrow you can cut through to unlock the way to the Bell Beast’s layer.</p>  <p>Glad you asked? While many <em>Silksong</em> players probably won’t have much trouble with this guy, this is a judgement-free zone with the sole goal of trying to help as many <em>Hollow Knight</em> players break through that first barrier and be able to continue their journey to the Citadel.</p>

 <p>The Bell Beast has two phases and four attacks. In the first phase he’ll just appear from underground and run across the screen or jump over your head. If he’s running across, you can jump over him and hit him 2-3 times from the back before he burrows back under. If he’s about to jump over you, just stand in the middle of the screen underneath the peak of the arc and hit him in the back again.</p> <figure id="attachment_2000624024" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000624024"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000624024">Team Cherry</figcaption></figure> <p>The second phase is where things get slightly trickier. First, he’ll come up from the ground and spawn two bells that roll across opposite sides of the screen. These are easy to enough to jump over and get a few hits in. Later, he’ll start shaking the whole cavern and have bells drop from the ceiling that bounce while he’s rotating through his other three attacks. Sometimes these bells bounce toward you. Sometimes they bounce away.</p>

 <p>If you stand close to where they drop, they’ll miss you completely no matter which direction they’re going. Plus they disappear before the second bounce. But watch out because during this phase he’ll also spawn bells each time he comes out of the ground.</p> <h2>He keeps killing me in three hits!</h2> <p>Brutal, right? Even though he’s <em>Silksong</em>‘s first boss, Bell Beast, like everything else in the game, hits pretty hard. That leaves little time to memorize his attack pattern and not much room for error once you do. The biggest general tip for the boss fight, like lots of encounters in <em>Silksong</em>, is just to stay calm. Don’t move around more than you have to and don’t overreact to flashy attacks.</p> <p>Imagine instead of a giant, harrowing roly-poly bug constantly trying to squash you, he’s just a rectangle-shaped hit box moving around the screen in very predictable ways. Save at a bench nearby, hit enough enemies to have a full roll of silk to bind with/heal yourself at the start of the fight, and then stick to dodging each of the four attacks as they come. You’ll get to the end of the fight thinking, “How is he still alive?” but then after a few more hits he’ll be liberated and become your new best friend.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/silksong-first-boss-bell-beast-guide-2000624015]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hollow Knight: Silksong’s Platforming Has Players Crashing Out Harder Than Any Boss Fight]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/hollow-knight-silksong-crest-wanderer-reaper-location-2000624036</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hollow-knight-silksong%E2%80%99s-platforming-has-players-crashing-out-harder-than-any-boss-fight.1291557/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><a href="https://kotaku.com/hollow-knight-silksong-steam-review-bomb-chinese-translation-2000623496"><i><span>Hollow Knight: Silksong</span></i></a><span> is a tough game. Its bosses hit hard, your early arsenal of abilities can feel quite limiting in combat encounters, and its volatile level design can send you accidentally tumbling down into a chasm and losing an hour of progress. But while these kinds of challenges were arguably all to be expected from a sequel to the challenging original, there’s one brand of platforming segment whose sheer difficulty is catching players off guard, especially if they miss an optional upgrade early on in the game.</span></p> <p><span>Hornet, the needle-wielding hero of </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/hollow-knight-silksong-how-long-completionist-achievement-2000623157"><i><span>Silksong</span></i></a><span>, starts off the game with a downward diagonal aerial strike that is used as both an anti-air attack as well as a platforming tool in sections where she must basically bounce on pods to get some verticality and reach higher areas of the map, using her needle as a pogo stick. By default, this attack has a diagonal slant that makes it difficult to precisely strike these pods and position yourself in an optimal way to reach the next one. Though there’s an available, optional upgrade that can make traversing this section much easier, many players miss it,, and because getting through these sections without it is hard but not impossible to pull off, a lot of fans think these are simply mandatory skill checks for your timing and positioning, and are uploading clips of themselves trying, failing, and crashing out.</span></p>       <p><span>The thing is, these sections don’t have to be </span><i><span>as </span></i><span>hard as some folks have been making them out to be, but </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/silksong-demo-hands-on-price-hollow-knight-pax-west-2000621695"><i><span>Silksong</span></i><span>’s non-linear nature</span></a><span> means not everyone is finding the upgrade that makes them significantly easier. Crests are equippable items you’ll find throughout </span><i><span>Silksong </span></i><span>that allow you to swap between different builds, and the Crest of the Wanderer swaps out Hornet’s diagonal air attack for a standard downward strike similar to the one the Knight can perform in the original </span><i><span>Hollow Knight</span></i><span>, allowing you to more easily and precisely pogo your way through these sections. Getting them isn’t an easy task, however, as you’ll have to unlock a few areas, abilities, and items to do so. Here’s </span><i><span>IGN</span></i><span>’s</span> <span>rundown of how to find the Crest of the Wanderer:</span></p>  <p><span>Keep in mind that this will also cut down the range on Hornet’s attacks, so you’ll have to get in closer in combat. Switching out crests is all about give and take, so it’s up to you to decide which perks and drawbacks are worth it to you. But if you, like many others, are tired of falling into lava and spike pits while you’re trying to pogo on these pods, now you know there is a better way.</span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/hollow-knight-silksong-crest-wanderer-reaper-location-2000624036]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Digimon Story: Time Stranger – Our Thoughts After Playing 4 Hours]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/digimon-story-time-stranger-our-thoughts-after-playing-4-hours</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/digimon-story-time-stranger-%E2%80%93-our-thoughts-after-playing-4-hours.1291548/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Sometimes you sit down at a game with no idea what to expect. That was how I felt when I got my first hands-on time with Digimon Story: Time Stranger at Summer Game Fest. I’m a lapsed Digimon fan, someone who liked the franchise a lot as a kid and then just fell off as I got older. But when I played Time Stranger, I quickly realized I had to pay attention. This was a JRPG with some good ideas. So when I got the shot at an even longer preview (about four hours) at PAX West, I took it, because I wanted to see if that initial impression held water. And I’m happy to say that I think it does. Digimon Story: Time Stranger seems to get the Digimon series, but there’s also the foundation of a really good JRPG here, too. I mean the kind that you could spend a long time digging into. One that might be able to appeal to Digimon oldheads while creating new fans. If licensed games have a holy grail, it’s that. And Time Stranger might be able to find it.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Let’s get this out of the way before I go any farther: Digimon isn’t a &lt;ahem&gt; stranger to good licensed games. The last Digimon Story game, Cyber Sleuth, was pretty good, and Time Stranger is built on that foundation. After picking between a dude with anime hair and goggles and a woman with a very small hat, you step into the role of an ADAMAS agent. Whoever you don’t choose becomes your operator. You can call them Operator. Your job? Investigate anomalous phenomena in the city. Basically, you look into strange stuff that the public doesn’t even know about. </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">And man, there’s some strange stuff going on in this city. Things are shut down, and nobody can go anywhere. And what’s all this about being prepared for tremors? After taking my lady and her very small hat for a walk and chatting with some folks about what’s going down, I showed up at the Wall of Hope, which was built after there was an explosion in Nishi-Shinjuku eight years prior, which has been the site of many anomalies. After I snuck inside, I ran into my first Digimon, and it was time to choose my partner. I picked Gomamon – my other options were Patamon and DemiDevimon – and got to work clearing out the local Digimon.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>Time Stranger is, at its core, a turn-based RPG.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Time Stranger is, at its core, a turn-based RPG, a DVD Menu Game’s DVD Menu Game (complimentary). That means your Digimon come in three types – Data, Virus, and Vaccine. Virus beats Data, Vaccine beats Virus, and Data beats Vaccine. But Digimon also have elemental strengths and weaknesses, too, so you have to pick the right moves and Digimon for the fight, and manage your turn order, which is shown on the right side of the screen. If you hit another Digimon with an attack, you’ll be able to check whether that Digimon was weak against it (or resisted it) in the future. You can also check on everything you’ve learned about a Digimon at any time. And if you land a pre-emptive strike from the field, you start combat with a massive advantage or sometimes win the fight outright before it starts.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The most interesting in-battle choice Time Stranger makes is allowing you to use items or switch your Digimon on the fly without having it take a turn. While this also makes it easier to get the right Digimon in position and use In Case of Emergency, Break Glass items when you need one, it also means enemies can be a little meaner to you, which is cool. And if you lose a Digimon, you can pull in a replacement from your reserve team. Once you run out, though, that’s it. The battles I played in my time with Time Stranger generally weren’t hard unless I was fighting something I clearly shouldn’t have been, but they were engaging.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As you battle Digimon, you earn what’s called Scan Rate. Once it reaches 100%, you can convert that Digimon and make them a member of your team. Wait until you get to 200%, though, and you’ll get a stronger Digimon. It’s one of those “If you wait five minutes, you can have <em>two</em> marshmallows” things, but it’s an enticing incentive. In addition, you can also equip Digimon with Attachment Skills, providing access to moves they wouldn’t normally get. And of course, you can Digivolve (and De-Digivolve) your Digimon once you meet certain requirements. The coolest thing here, though, are personalities. Depending on how you interact with your Digimon, their personalities will change, which will change how their stats level. There’s quite a bit to it, but I like how much freedom to play around with it you have, and how easy it is to build the Digimon you want.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Of course, it’s not all battles here. There is a story, and I was intrigued by Time Stranger’s plot. I met up with a girl that seemed to know my character, but who neither I nor my operator recognized; befriended some Digimon; got chased by a really large Digimon, and mostly tried to figure out what was going on. We know Time Stranger is a time-travel story, but I didn’t get to see that during my playtime. I did, however, get to jump ahead a bit, and that’s where I really got to play with Time Stranger’s systems.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>It really made the world feel lived in, and like it existed outside of me, which is what you want in a game like this.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">After my jump, I found myself in the Digital World with a much higher level team. I was in a village of Digimon that had recently been attacked by a group called the Titans. I started off by helping Shellmon, the local healer, gather some materials to make medicine. Along the way, I found Digimon hanging out, listening to a concert, and just enjoying some time alone. It really made the world feel lived in, and like it existed outside of me, which is what you want in a game like this. After a jaunt around the village – where I discovered Digimon trading cards, something producer Ryosuke Hara told me was an homage to the original Digimon (if you know, you know) – only to discover Shellmon had been treating Divermon, who worked for the Titans and was wounded during the battle. After the village is attacked again, Divermon decides to try to get the Titans to stop. After all, anyone willing to help an enemy can’t be so bad.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Before I finished up that storyline, though, I took some time to explore what else there was to see. One of the coolest things was the In-Between Theater, a sort of pocket universe situated between the real world and the Digital World. Here, I could visit the Digifarm, where I could place Digimon on the farm to train them up, increase their Bond with me, or change their personality. There was a Digifarm in Cyber Sleuth, but the one in Time Stranger is much more customizable, allowing you to place more Digimon and customize the various tiles in the farm. Hara told me that they wanted a better Digifarm, but they also wanted it to be like an aquarium you could customize and where you could see your Digimon interact and mingle with one another. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">That sense of “this thing is yours” also speaks to why your character isn’t voiced and why they aren’t assigned a partner Digimon, like many of the other members of the cast are. This is your story, and you’re meant to put yourself in the shoes of your agent rather than playing a character that comes pre-built for you. Makes sense, right? About this time I also discovered I could change my outfit. And man, much as I loved my girl’s tiny hat, it was nice to be able to have her rock a t-shirt.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">After goofing off a bit, I found Shellmon’s friend Whalemon, who took me to the bottom of the sea to face off with the Titans. We tried diplomacy, for the record. It just didn’t work. So we threw down with Sharkmon and his boys. He was tough; I had to swap my team, use my items, and like every fight in my time with Time Stranger, I had a lot of fun going toe to toe (toe to fin?) with him; he just wasn’t a match for Aegiomon. Once he was little more than Sharkmon fin soup, my demo ended. </p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>I was impressed by how fast my four-hour hands-on session went by, how every little thing in Time Stranger fit together, and how thoughtful so many of its quality of life choices were.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">When my time with Digimon Story: Time Stranger wrapped, I was exhausted. When you get up after a four-hour demo, you feel it, especially at an event like PAX. But I was also impressed by how fast the time went by, how every little thing in Time Stranger fit together, and how thoughtful so many of its quality of life choices were. If you get enough Scan Rate to Convert a new Digimon, you’re notified and you can jump to that menu with the press of a button. The same is true of when a Digimon completes its training on the Digifarm. You can even speed up the battles if you want to move things along. </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Digimon Story: Time Stranger understands its genre, something Hara made clear to me when I sat down with him. A JRPG can’t just be about a great story and characters or a great battle system. It has to nail the little things, too, and that means investing in both quality of life choices that make life easier for the player while giving them enough depth to keep them interesting for the long haul.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Based on what I played at PAX, Digimon Story: Time Stranger is looking like it could pull that balancing act off. Like I said, I’m a lapsed Digimon fan, but if what I played is any indication, you kind of don’t have to be one to like what Time Stranger has to offer. You just have to want to play a cool JRPG with time travel in it. I’m still working out how that fits in here (we only got glimpses), but at this point, that just seems like a cherry on top of a beautiful cocktail. You’re here for the mixology, and Digimon Story: Time Stranger looks like a delicious concoction. Let’s hope the sips we’ve been provided are an accurate taste of the whole drink.</p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/digimon-story-time-stranger-our-thoughts-after-playing-4-hours]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['The Only People Not Involved Are the Creators,' Life Is Strange Writer Says of Amazon TV Adaptation]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/the-only-people-not-involved-are-the-creators-life-is-strange-writer-says-of-amazon-tv-adaptation</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-only-people-not-involved-are-the-creators-life-is-strange-writer-says-of-amazon-tv-adaptation.1291542/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Amazon's announcement of a <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/tv/life-is-strange-the-series">Life is Strange TV adaptation</a> has prompted the video game's original writer Christian Divine to <a href="https://x.com/Chris_divine/status/1963997205469016353" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">comment</a> that "the only people not involved are the creators."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Divine served as lead writer on <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/life-is-strange">Life is Strange</a>, which was created by French studio Don't Nod back in 2015. The narrative adventure launched to a warm response and earned itself a loyal fan audience, prompting Divine to return for the game's 2019 sequel.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">But no mention was made of Divine or anyone else who worked on the original game in Amazon's announcement last week, which instead noted that the adaptation would be produced by Square Enix, the publisher and rights owner of the Life is Strange franchise, as well as LuckyChap, a film and TV production company co-founded by Margot Robbie, and Story Kitchen, a company that describes itself as one that "specializes in Franchise Farming™ — adapting video games and other 'non-traditional' IPs into film and TV."</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Indeed, Amazon's Life is Strange TV series <a href="https://press.amazonmgmstudios.com/us/en/press-release/amazon-mgm-studios-orders-ilife-is-strangei-to-ser" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">press release</a> makes no mention of Don't Nod at all, despite discussing the studio's fan-favorite main characters Max and Chloe, and its beloved setting of Arcadia Bay. Instead, the release spends most of its time focused on the involvement of The End of the F***ing World's Charlie Covell as creator and showrunner.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Divine's comment seemingly confirms that Don't Nod is not involved in the adaptation at all, and the writer isn't the only former Life is Strange staff member to take note. "Seeing the game created by @DONTNOD_Michel, @RaoulBarbet, Jean-Luc Cano, and our @DONTNOD_Ent  team becoming a show is an incredible honor!" Don't Nod studio executive producer Luc Baghadoust <a href="https://x.com/luc_baghadoust/status/1964009888100622600" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">wrote</a> separately on social media, highlighting other key creatives behind Life is Strange. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">While a straightforward message, the fact Baghadoust chose to specifically highlight more of those responsible for the original game has raised a few eyebrows among fans, following the lack of acknowledgement towards Don't Nod by Amazon and Square Enix. (Despite being tagged, neither studio creative director Michel Koch or Life is Strange director Raoul Barbet have commented on the series' announcement so far.)</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Life is Strange Remastered Collection Trailer Screenshots</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">On the one hand, Don't Nod and publisher Square Enix parted ways rather publicly after the launch of Life is Strange 2, with the former team re-establishing itself as Don't Nod Montreal to work on the similar <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/lost-records-bloom-and-rage">Lost Records: Bloom &amp; Rage</a>. Square Enix, which has always owned the Life is Strange IP, has meanwhile continued the franchise on with multiple games developed by Deck Nine Games, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/how-hidden-nazi-symbols-were-the-tip-of-a-toxic-iceberg-at-life-is-strange-developer-deck-nine">to mixed success</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">But despite the original Life is Strange now being a decade old, and Don't Nod long having left the series' behind, many fans have commented on the lack of involvement or mention of the franchise's creators as odd, or discouraging.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"When it comes to adapting narrative-based games, someone from the game developer should be there," Life is Strange fan mirracz wrote on <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/lifeisstrange/comments/1na24us/no_spoilers_the_writer_of_lis1_had_something_to/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">reddit</a>, in a lengthy thread of opinions sparked by Divine's post. "If not as a writer, then at least as a consultant."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"I agree with that principle," added another fan, EdenH333. "Creators of adaptations should talk to the original creators when possible to get insight on the project. But as a rule, Hollywood doesn’t do this, and that isn't necessarily a death knell for a project.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"I don't remember Fallout's original creators being part of the Fallout TV show yet that turned out amazing," argued MagnusGallant23. "Both are Amazon MGM Studios."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"This series will piss off people regardless," concluded a fourth fan, alihou. "If there's one thing I've noticed with this fan base, they're quick to complain. They're very protective of this property and even slight deviations in the story will get a negative reaction."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Amazon's Life is Strange TV series looks set to follow the events of the original game closely, although fans have questioned how the adaptation will handle its choose-your-own-adventure-style gameplay, and particularly its multiple endings. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">"For years we've had so many people asking us to create a Life is Strange TV show," Square Enix External Studios bosses Jon Brooke and Lee Singleton said last week, "and we're so pleased to finally partner with Amazon MGM Studios who we trust will do an incredible job bringing our universe to life."
</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Tom Phillips is IGN's News Editor. You can reach Tom at tom_phillips@ign.com or find him on Bluesky </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/tomphillipseg.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@tomphillipseg.bsky.social</a></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/the-only-people-not-involved-are-the-creators-life-is-strange-writer-says-of-amazon-tv-adaptation]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Digimon Story: Time Stranger Is A Promising Comeback That I Didn't Want To Stop Playing]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/digimon-story-time-stranger-is-a-promising-comeback-that-i-didnt-want-to-stop-playing/1100-6534531/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/digimon-story-time-stranger-is-a-promising-comeback-that-i-didnt-want-to-stop-playing.1291536/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6534531">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">One of Digimon's biggest strengths has always been its ability to lean into nostalgia, and that's no different in <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/digimon-story-time-stranger/" data-ref-id="5000-663007">Digimon Story: Time Stranger</a>, the seventh entry in the franchise's role-playing-focused gaming series. Like past Digimon Story games, Time Stranger puts a big emphasis on narrative, but this time around, it was the creature collecting and turn-based battles that made me want to keep playing long after my three-hour preview session ended.</p><p dir="ltr">Instead of children and teens, Time Stranger's protagonist is an adult secret agent investigating Digimon-related phenomena. I started my playthrough right from the beginning of the story, where we see the effects of the Digital World on real-world Earth. You can choose whether the protagonist is male or female, and the other one becomes a character in the story: your partner who communicates with you through a pocket-sized hologram. The intro sets the stage for the clash between two worlds with regular citizens talking about news of unexplained disasters and protestors even accusing authorities of withholding secrets.</p><p dir="ltr">But that's all just a backdrop for the meat of what I got to play. The Digimon Story sub-series gets its name from its narrative-driven core which is, typically, complemented by turn-based gameplay. "Battle balance" is one of the main areas that producer Ryosuke Hara focused on, similar to what he did when working on Dragon Ball Z: Kakarot. At 36 years old, he was part of the target audience for the series when Digimon Adventure launched in 1999.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1587/15875866/4563382-en_beginningofthemainstory4.png" data-ref-id="1300-4563382" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="3840" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1587/15875866/4563382-en_beginningofthemainstory4.png" data-ref-id="1300-4563382"></a><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1587/15875866/4563382-en_beginningofthemainstory4.png"></figure><p dir="ltr">"So there's a few things that we wanted to improve on from the past installments of Digimon's Story, but one thing [in particular] was the battle balance,"he told me via a translator during my session. "I think in the past versions, people were relying on certain characters way more than their being balanced. So for this title, we wanted to really improve on the RPG battle aspect of the battles."</p><p dir="ltr">Time Stranger starts with introducing us to its main "type triangle," similar to the fire, water, grass triangle in Pokemon and axe, sword, and lance triangle in Fire Emblem. This works similarly to Digimon Story games before like Cybersleuth. While Digimon attacks could have secondary weaknesses behind elements, the main type behind a Digimon's classification heavily affects its strengths and weaknesses. To demonstrate this, Time Stranger gives you one of each type to choose from for your first Digimon: Patamon (Data), Gomamon (Vaccine), or Deviveemon (Virus).</p><p dir="ltr">I went with Patamon, since his partner in Digimon Adventure was one of my favorite characters growing up. Patamon was able to take on most of the enemies I saw within the first 30 minutes or so, but from there, I needed to rely on other Digimon like Koromon to take advantage of type weaknesses. With around 450 Digimon in the game, many of the ones older fans will remember from the shows and games are represented.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1587/15875866/4563383-en_beginningofthemainstory3.png" data-ref-id="1300-4563383" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="3840" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1587/15875866/4563383-en_beginningofthemainstory3.png" data-ref-id="1300-4563383"></a><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1587/15875866/4563383-en_beginningofthemainstory3.png"></figure><p dir="ltr">In just the first two hours, I recognized almost every Digimon from the random digital monsters seen only a few times in Digimon Adventure to the popular mascot characters like Agumon. One of the biggest targets for Time Stranger are older fans who watched Digimon Adventure, but it’s a completely new story, so you don’t need to know anything about past shows and games to play it.</p><p dir="ltr">When asked about what made Digimon different from other monster-taming series, Hara pointed to its evolution system. "Digimon's evolution system is not the same as other people's," he said. "If you were to take Agumon as an example, Agumon digivolves into multiple different forms. And then from there, again, multiple different forms. If we were to compare one player to another player, how they evolve their Digimon is going to be very different from another player."</p><p dir="ltr">That ties into the best part of Time Stranger: collecting Digimon. Digivolutions don't work like their Pokemon equivalent, where each Pokemon has set evolutions that don't change and rarely branch. Bulbasaur will only become Ivysaur, and even though Pokemon like Gloom can evolve into Vileplume or Bellossom, most Pokemon follow a singular line of evolution. In Digimon, a "baby" Digimon like Koromon can digivolve into Agumon, Guilmon, Dracomon, and others. You don't get to see which evolutions a Digimon has until they digivolve and you see how your treatment of the digital monster affected them.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1587/15875866/4563384-en_beginningofthemainstory1.png" data-ref-id="1300-4563384" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="3840" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1587/15875866/4563384-en_beginningofthemainstory1.png" data-ref-id="1300-4563384"></a><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1587/15875866/4563384-en_beginningofthemainstory1.png"></figure><p dir="ltr">You can capture multiple copies of a Digimon or de-digivolve the ones you have if you want to try and transform them into something else (I de-digivolved my Pagumon because I thought it was ugly). De-digivolving a Digimon poses its own challenges though. When my Pagumon turned back into its Kuramon baby form, I had to deal with it being level 1 again, so beware of that if you choose to de-digivolve on impulse.</p><p dir="ltr">Digimon also have one of 16 personalities now with their own "matrices," where you can influence their stats and what skills they learn based on how you raise them. For example, increasing your Digimon’s Valor can boost HP and attack growth. Personality Skills can strengthen attacks, reduce the number of skill points that attacks use, and more.</p><p dir="ltr">Your Digimon also <em>talk </em>to you. Your core team has up to three Digimon at once, each of which follows you around and asks you questions as they level up like how to be a good friend, what they should call their next special move, and so on. It adds a layer of endearingness to the gameplay and also some functionality, since your answers can affect which way their stats grow. This can also affect how they digivolve, since some evolutions have requirements like a high enough HP or INT stat.</p><p dir="ltr">The story took a backseat to the enjoyable battles and creature collecting in my preview, but that makes sense since we didn't get that far into the story or have a chance to bond with the characters. I could only hope that the characters hold up as well as the Digimon do, but even without that, I'd be compelled to play if only to explore the different ways I could raise my Digimon.</p><p dir="ltr">Time Stranger comes at a time where the Digimon series has been largely stagnant, mostly riding on the memories of Digimon Adventure rather than exploring new territory. However, the fact that it’s the first Digimon Story in a decade and introducing possibly the most comprehensive battle system the series has seen yet, I'm more excited to revisit the Digital World than I have been in years.</p><p dir="ltr">Digimon Story: Time Stranger launches on October 3, 2025. Pro tip: If you're impatient, I'd recommend going back to Digimon Story: Cybersleuth (and its side story follow-up, Hacker's Memory!) to see where the new game is coming from.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/digimon-story-time-stranger-is-a-promising-comeback-that-i-didnt-want-to-stop-playing/1100-6534531/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Keanu Reeves Would Come Back For Cyberpunk 2]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/keanu-reeves-would-come-back-for-cyberpunk-2/1100-6534536/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/keanu-reeves-would-come-back-for-cyberpunk-2.1291533/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6534536">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Actor Keanu Reeves played <a href="https://cyberpunk.fandom.com/wiki/Johnny_Silverhand" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Johnny Silverhand</a> in CD Projekt Red's Cyberpunk 2077, and with <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cyberpunk-2077-sequel-release-date-trailer-story/1100-6526333/" data-ref-id="1100-6526333">a sequel now in development</a>, many are wondering if Reeves might come back.</p><p>The Matrix actor told <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/johnny-silverhand-actor-keanu-reeves-says-he-absolutely-wants-to-be-in-cyberpunk-2" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">IGN</a> that he would "absolutely" be interested in reprising his role in the sequel.</p><p>"I'd love to play Johnny Silverhand again," he said.</p><p>Silverhand is a former rockstar who appears in the game in the form of a digital engram long after his physical body dies. The character's fate at the end of Cyberpunk 2077 can depend on the ending that players receive. Given that, it appears possible that he could return in Cyberpunk 2, but that's far from a guarantee that it would happen, as that would depend on a countless combination of factors.</p><p>We also don't know if Reeves could come back to play Johnny Silverhand again in something outside of a game. But what <em>is </em>clear is that Reeves is up for reprising the role in some form or another.</p><p>Cyberpunk 2, which is the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cyberpunk-2-is-officially-the-2077-sequels-name-at-least-for-now/1100-6531871/" data-ref-id="1100-6531871">game's official title (for now, at least)</a>, officially <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cyberpunk-2-is-officially-the-2077-sequels-name-at-least-for-now/1100-6531871/" data-ref-id="1100-6531871">entered pre-production earlier this year.</a> As of July 31, 2025, there were <a href="https://x.com/CDPROJEKTRED_IR/status/1961101604154720298" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">116 people at CD Projekt Red working on the game</a>, up from 96 people three months prior. The overwhelming majority of staff, however, are working on the studio's next big release: <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/the-witcher-4-release-date-trailer-news/2900-5228/" data-ref-id="2900-5228">The Witcher 4</a>.</p><p>Cyberpunk 2077 launched in December 2020 and its debut was marred by serious technical issues that proved so extreme that Sony removed the game from sale for a period of time. Despite those challenges, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cyberpunk-2077-sold-13-7-million-copies-in-21-days-30000-people-got-refunds/1100-6490486/" data-ref-id="1100-6490486">Cyberpunk 2077's sales at launch were massive</a> and have only grown higher since, <a href="https://www.cdprojekt.com/en/media/news/cd-projekt-wraps-up-the-third-quarter-of-2024/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">climbing to 30 million as of November 2024.</a> CD Projekt Red steadily supported and improved the game experience so extensively that the game became a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/watch-gamespots-cyberpunk-2077-documentary-to-get-an-inside-look-at-the-turnaround/1100-6519512/" data-ref-id="1100-6519512">prime example of a comeback story.</a></p><p>Very little is known about Cyberpunk 2 but developer Dan Hernberg said it will be a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cyberpunk-2077-sequel-will-be-more-authentically-america-dev-says/1100-6524584/" data-ref-id="1100-6524584">"uniquely American story." </a></p><p>"It's got a lot of like, punk energy, and [the tabletop game] was written by an American, so it just seems right to do it in America," he said, referencing how the lead developers on the sequel are based in Boston.</p><p>As for a release date, that's anyone's guess, but it won't be anytime soon considering The Witcher 4 is coming up next before Cyberpunk 2 is ready.</p><div data-embed-type="html"><p><i>Click the button below to add GameSpot as a preferred source on Google</i></p></div>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/keanu-reeves-would-come-back-for-cyberpunk-2/1100-6534536/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Digimon Story: Time Stranger Preview – It’s about time…]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/09/08/digimon-story-time-stranger-preview-its-about-time/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/digimon-story-time-stranger-preview-%E2%80%93-it%E2%80%99s-about-time%E2%80%A6.1291527/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>The Digital World and the real world are colliding once again in Digimon Story: Time Stranger, but with the world seemingly coming to an end, you’re thrown back in time to try and prevent the worst from coming to pass.</p>
<p><iframe title="Digimon Story Time Stranger | Story Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/bFEu9XOLmg0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>This latest entry in the Digimon Story series picks up with a snazzy intro anime for the ADAMAS agency, a group of somewhat ostentatiously dressed agents who’ve been galavanting around and trying to stop anomalous threats. It’s clear that this world has already been transformed by disasters, with a giant wall having been erected to hide a completely destroyed portion of the city, and now a military lockdown of the area that has the populace scared, confused and angry.</p>


<p>For you, there’s a path to sneak into, taking you underground to pass beneath the wall and discover what’s on the other side. As you do so, you encounter Digimon for the first time… or so it seems. ADAMAS has actually known of these creatures for a while, and can now grant you the ability to summon one, choosing between Demidevimon, Gomamon or Patamon as your partner Digimon through this opening.</p>
<p>What’s immediately apparent, as you battle through the opening areas, is the rather modern and freeing take on a turn-based JRPG. Enemies are visible in the open world, which gives you the chance to strike first or to try and avoid encounters entirely, but once you do end up in battle, you have a streamlined and effective combat system. Creatures go in turns, and you can have up to three active Digimon all slotting into the battle timeline based on speed stats. One nice element here is that using an item does not count as an action, and you can also swap Digimon in and out without foregoing a turn, which I feel will encourage using this feature during the run of the story. Elsewhere, you’ve got animation speed and auto-battling right in the main UI, which are great quality-of-life features.</p>


<p>You also have two categories to determine strengths and weaknesses in combat, with both the creature type and their elemental attacks giving you a deterministic readout of damage bonuses and buffs – whether it’s multiplied or reduced by 1.5x, 2x or both. At least, it will do so eventually, once you’ve learnt what works and what doesn’t against a new enemy.</p>
<p>You can boost these multipliers further with the Cross Arts, a techno-ability for your human character to use that builds up as you land attacks that can deal critical damage, and can then be set to buff your team or debuff and damage the opposition. it’s a fun cutscene animation, with your phone turning into a random gun-like contraption.</p>

<p>Oh, and then there’s adding creatures to your team, not by catching them, but rather by learning enough about them through combat to replicate them –&nbsp;able to do so from 100% learning, but then able to generate more powerful versions by waiting to 200%. As they gain experience, Digivolution comes into play, morphing them into more powerful forms, giving you clear paths to follow and letting you revert and choose alternate creature forms down the line. We only experienced this through the regular run of combat, but interacting with your Digimon to shape their personalities or nurturing them through a Digifarm are also options.</p>
<p>Many of these features were gradually revealed to us through the opening chapter, where the game throws mystery after mystery at you. A woman calls up ADAMAS and seems to know you, though you don’t know them in return, but whisks you along through devastated government buildings and with countless Digimon wandering around, some of immense power that you have to avoid, before building up to a final rooftop battle.</p>
<p>Let’s just say it doesn’t end too well and throws the narrative off in a temporal tangent!</p>

<p>Jumping ahead to a later portion of the game, we’re in the Abyss, and what could actually be a rather idyllic seaside part of the Digital World, were it not for the attacks being wrought upon this village by a group of Digimon known as Titans. You have to figure out a way to stop this from escalating and find that there’s already a personal connection that you can use to do so, as one of the Titans has switched sides.</p>
<p>Now, to be honest, my knowledge of Digimon is much less deeply ingrained than Pokémon. I remember watching some of the early Digimon Adventure anime, and Agumon was obviously the posterchild back then – he still is, to be fair! – but I maybe underestimated just how out-there some of the Digimon designs could be. Deltamon has a signature ability to shoot like a Death Star, combining energy beams from both arm weapons and his mouth, or there’s Leomon, the humanoid lion with a knife which is a fellow with a giant gun for a body, and Aegiomon is literally just a human with goat legs, which feels less like a digital monster and more like something out of Greek mythology.</p>
<p>Through this section, the combat really starts to come into its own. The prologue had a lot of single hit battles (or even just some creatures getting KO’d by a preemptive attack), but heading down below the water to the Titan’s lair, thankfully with an invisible macguffin that means you can still breath alright, and the encounters here need more effort to learn and exploit weaknesses. Just as handy is how your party has ballooned in size, so you still have your team of three active Digimon to call upon, but there’s a bunch of story characters alongside.</p>

<p>The fight against the big Sharkmon boss of the Titans was a really satisfying one to work through, plugging away at his weaknesses and switching team members to put the best foot forward, using Cross Arts to debuff and damage them, and also then trying to target his head when he dips down to build up for a charge attack. It’s a good battle.</p>
<p>I feel that there’s a real opportunity for Digimon Story: Time Stranger to take advantage of. After some difficult times for Pokémon games, which are now shifting to a new real-time battle system, Digimon Story is sticking to the tried and true turn-based battles that could bring traditional monster battling fans to its yard.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/09/08/digimon-story-time-stranger-preview-its-about-time/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Digimon Story Time Stranger Final Preview - I'm a Believer Now]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/digimon-story-time-stranger-final-preview-im-believer-now</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/digimon-story-time-stranger-final-preview-im-a-believer-now.1291521/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>A couple months ago, my colleague and our Senior Content Manager Andrew Stretch <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/digimon-story-time-stranger-shows-off-vibrant-digital-world-and-quality-of-life" rel="nofollow">played <em>Digimon Story Time Stranger</em> at Summer Game Fest</a> and enjoyed it. He's a longtime cheerleader of the <em>Digimon Story</em> franchise, but I never believed him enough to try it for myself.</p>

<p>After three hours with <em>Digimon Story Time Stranger</em> at PAX West, I'm a believer now. It pretty quickly shot up to near the top of my October wishlist.</p>

<p>This demo session started off with what was essentially the beginning of the game, and I got a bit of setup for the overall plot and an easy onramp for the gameplay. Then, we transitioned to a later point in the story with level 20 Digimon.</p>



<h2>Digivolving to a Better Quality of Life</h2>

<p>The first major aspects I noticed with <em>Digimon Story Time Stranger</em> is just how many quality-of-life features there are. While I haven't played previous ones in the series, I know my way around a classic JRPG, and this one had a lot of lovely shortcuts.</p>

<p>We previously reported on some of them, like how you can auto-defeat wild encounters if your average level is stronger and still earn XP—even for 'mons in your storage. Combat animations can also be sped up by up to five-times speed.</p>

<p>I noticed a few new ones in my hands-on time at PAX, too. You can stand still in the overworld to automatically regenerate health and stamina. Your storage for all your Digimon can also be accessed anywhere in the overworld, making it easy to swap your 'mons out as needed.</p>

<p>"We don't need to do all the wasteful movements that people in past Digimon story titles had to go through," Producer Ryosuke Hara told me through a translator. "And trust me, we know there are people that have spent hundreds, if not thousands of hours in <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/digimon-story-cyber-sleuth-review-digimon-are-champions" rel="nofollow"><em>Cyber Sleuth</em></a> and whatnot."</p>



<p>Battles are often determined by your understanding of type effectiveness, as you'd expect from a monster-taming game. I'm largely new to the franchise though, so learning the different attributes and elements felt like a lot to wrap my head around initially.</p>

<p>However, the combat UI makes it super easy to understand what's super effective and how strong (or weak) the multiplier will be. After all, this is a big monster-hunting turn-based RPG with hundreds of thousands of matchups to consider.</p>



<p>Overall, these quality-of-life improvements go a long way to making the game more convenient and streamlined, according Hara-san. He and the team iterated to find that perfect balance of ease without making it too easy. There's one big anchor that they used to balance this convenience against.</p>

<p>"In the end, we tried to balance it with the boss battles. We tried to make the boss battles more fun. We tried not to shake it up too much," Hara-san said through a translator. "Every boss battle is going to be appropriately hard for where you are in the story. That acts as the balancing in the game."</p>

<p>He assured us that while the boss battles ultimately serve as the skill checks, you likely will never be stuck in an impossible scenario. If your team isn't matching up well, you can always De-Digivolve and re-Digivolve your team to find new ways in.</p>



<h2>Digimon Gets Personal</h2>

<p>With the newly introduced Personality system, these conveniences feel like they'll go a long way to making <em>Digimon Story Time Stranger</em> a good time. Depending on which Personality a Digimon has, their stats will grow a certain way.</p>

<p>This system works on two levels, I've noticed. On the surface, you can really shape a Digimon's character and feel more of an attachment to them. If you feel like your Agumon is the brave, heroic type, you can foster that by interacting with him and answering questions with brave responses. It helps you develop more of a personal bond.</p>

<p>On a deeper level, understanding their Personality type will help you optimize their stats, allowing you to amplify their strengths and cover up their weaknesses. This creates a deeper endgame for players who really want to go that extra mile and make a team of absolutely perfect Digimon--or hell, even make a perfect version of all 450+ Digimon in the game.</p>



<h2>So What's the Digimon Story?</h2>

<p>In this universe, there's a Digital World that coexists with reality, and there's an ongoing war between Digimon that could lead to a cataclysmic apocalypse in both. You're part of ADAMAS, an investigation team that's trying to stop the calamity.</p>

<p>The protagonist is a Tamer that collects and controls Digimon to fight rogue Digimon and other threats. In the second part of my play session, a character mentioned something called the "Shinjuku Inferno," which sounds related to (or could be) whatever bad thing we're trying to prevent.</p>

<p>The game doesn't really waste time getting conflicts into motion; the opening hour or so throws you into the thick of a protest that goes wrong, and it ultimately leads what feels like a major inciting incident.</p>



<p>With a 40–50 hour campaign, there will be a lot to sink our teeth into when <em>Digimon Story Time Stranger</em> releases on Oct. 3. Personally, between the strong turn-based combat, quality-of-life upgrades, and intriguing apocalyptic story, I'm convinced I should've been a <em>Digimon Story</em> fan a long time ago.</p>

<hr><p><em><strong>Digimon Story Time Stranger</strong> was previewed after three hours of gameplay at PAX West courtesy of Bandai Namco.</em></p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Robert Scarpinito is the Features Editor of TechRaptor. With a Bachelor of Arts in Journalism from the Ohio State University, sharing compelling stories is… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/robert-scarpinito">More about Robert</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/digimon-story-time-stranger-final-preview-im-believer-now]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Former Xbox VP Says Game Pass Creates "Weird Inner Tensions" Among Devs]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/xbox-game-pass-shannon-loftis-comments</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/former-xbox-vp-says-game-pass-creates-weird-inner-tensions-among-devs.1291518/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Another former Xbox staffer has added their voice to criticisms surrounding Xbox Game Pass and other gaming subscription services, and this time, it's ex-Xbox VP Shannon Loftis' turn to cast a critical eye over the service.</p>

<p>Speaking on <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:7369880832481660928?commentUrn=urn%3Ali%3Acomment%3A%28activity%3A7369880832481660928%2C7369898365943218176%29&amp;dashCommentUrn=urn%3Ali%3Afsd_comment%3A%287369898365943218176%2Curn%3Ali%3Aactivity%3A7369880832481660928%29" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">LinkedIn</a>, Loftis first admits that Game Pass "can claim a few victories with games that otherwise would have sunk beneath the waves", citing <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/human-fall-flat-review-drunk-puzzling" rel="nofollow">breakout platformer&nbsp;</a><em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/human-fall-flat-review-drunk-puzzling" rel="nofollow">Human: Fall Flat</a>&nbsp;</em>as an example of this process in action.</p>

<p>However, Loftis goes on to say that "the majority of game adoption" on Xbox Game Pass "comes at the expense of retail revenue", with the exception of games that are "engineered from the ground up for post-release monetization".</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/human-fall-flat-xbox-game-pass.jpg?itok=vkFBFQPw 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/human-fall-flat-xbox-game-pass.jpg?itok=ADOraKxo 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Not every Game Pass game can be&nbsp;<em>Human: Fall Flat</em>, says ex-Xbox VP Shannon Loftis.</figcaption></figure><p>Loftis concludes by saying that she "could (and may someday) write pages on the weird inner tensions this creates" among developers whose games will be appearing on Game Pass.</p>

<p>It's worth noting that Loftis isn't the first former Xbox staffer to offer a colorful opinion on the Game Pass subscription service this month.</p>

<p>Her comments follow those of <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/former-bethesda-exec-says-gaming-subscription-services-worth-jack-s-without-proper-support-for-game-developers" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">ex-Bethesda exec Pete Hines</a>, who said last week that subscription services are "worth jack shit" without companies "figur[ing] out how to balance the needs of the service...with the people who are providing the content".</p>

<p>Indeed, Loftis' comment was posted in response to former PlayStation boss Shawn Layden <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/shawn-layden_former-bethesda-exec-says-gaming-subscription-activity-7369880832481660928-HhnQ/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">reposting Hines' comments</a> himself, adding that the question should not be whether subscription services are profitable for their owners, but whether they are "healthy and helpful" for devs.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/hollow-knight-silksong-xbox-game-pass.jpg?itok=MDF4q3v2 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/hollow-knight-silksong-xbox-game-pass.jpg?itok=R8iBpTLK 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Some games, like&nbsp;<em>Hollow Knight: Silksong</em>, almost certainly won't be hurt by launching on Game Pass on day one.</figcaption></figure><p>Launching on Game Pass on day one doesn't necessarily preclude a game from achieving financial success. Games like&nbsp;<em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/clair-obscur-expedition-33-sales-3-3m-33-days" rel="nofollow">Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</a>&nbsp;</em>and the <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/oblivion-remastered-sales-circana-april-2025" rel="nofollow">recent&nbsp;<em>Oblivion&nbsp;</em>remaster</a> debuted on Game Pass, but still seemingly managed to rack up very respectable sales for themselves.</p>

<p>Still, these execs' comments on Game Pass and other subscription services should give us pause for thought, especially when it comes to smaller indie devs (and even major first-party studios). Stay tuned for more on this.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/xbox-game-pass-shannon-loftis-comments]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Seagate’s 5TB Xbox Game Drive Costs Less Than the 4TB, Like Getting 1TB Free (3-Year Rescue Included)]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/seagates-5tb-xbox-game-drive-costs-less-than-the-4tb-like-getting-1tb-free-3-year-rescue-included-2000623483</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/seagate%E2%80%99s-5tb-xbox-game-drive-costs-less-than-the-4tb-like-getting-1tb-free-3-year-rescue-included.1291506/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Game file sizes just keep growing bigger and bigger, but consoles struggle to keep up. Just look at the Xbox Series X|S. The more robust Series X has an internal SSD with storage totaling 1TB. With the Series S, you get about half that at 512GB. Not all of that is usable storage though as much of it is holding the system software needed for your Xbox to work in the first place. Then we have games come out like last year’s&nbsp;<em>Call of Duty Black Ops 6</em> with a file size in the triple digits. If you play more than three or four games, you’re going to be in a constant struggle of deleting and redownloading software as you bounce between games.</p>
<p>Luckily, their are external options. <strong>The Seagate Game Drive for Xbox comes with a crazy 5TB of storage</strong> to put all of your file size worries to bed.<a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3958/"> It normally goes for $150, but right now it’s 13% off which brings the price down to just $130.</a> You’ll save a good $20 (which just so happens to be exactly enough to hop into&nbsp;<em>Hollow Knight: Silksong</em>).</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3958/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>More Gaming Ahead</h2>
<p>Ok so here’s the catch. This is an HDD, not an SSD. Hard disk drives are notably slower than solid state drives. So much so that the Seagate game drive is incapable of playing Xbox Series X|S games directly from it. You’ll have to move the game file from the HDD to your Xbox’s internal storage in order to play it—sort of the digital version of taking your game disc off the shelf and popping it into the console.</p>
<p>Transferring the files can be much faster than redownloading from Microsoft’s servers otherwise would be, especially if you live in an area with unreliable bandwidth.</p>



<p>The good news is that if you’re still playing a bunch of Xbox One, Xbox 360, or original Xbox titles, they can be loaded and played directly from the drive. The drive is also compatible with Xbox One and Xbox 360 directly if tho9se consoles still get regular action in your place.</p>
<p>The HDD is portable as well. You can have your games loaded onto it, then take it over to a friend’s house. Pop it into their Xbox and you’ll be able to load up or move over your games onto their console. The drive is simple plug and play making it pretty straight forward to use.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3958/">Right now, you can save $20 on the Seagate Game Drive for Xbox for a limited time. Get it for just $130.</a></p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3958/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/seagates-5tb-xbox-game-drive-costs-less-than-the-4tb-like-getting-1tb-free-3-year-rescue-included-2000623483]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MachineGames Hopes To Make Another Wolfenstein Game And Sees BJ's Story As A Trilogy]]></title>
            <link>https://gameinformer.com/2025/09/08/machinegames-hopes-to-make-another-wolfenstein-game-and-sees-bjs-story-as-a-trilogy</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/machinegames-hopes-to-make-another-wolfenstein-game-and-sees-bjs-story-as-a-trilogy.1291494/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p>Though MachineGames is likely basking in the great reception to last year's <a href="https://gameinformer.com/product/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle">Indiana Jones and The Great Circle</a>, as well as its Order of Giants DLC that launched last week, the studio is still thinking about BJ Blazkowicz and Wolfenstein. In a recently released <a href="https://youtu.be/E189QG28rnE?si=4-b6qJ9glHHbjGnv">Noclip documentary</a> about MachineGames, studio co-founder Jerk Gustafsson said the team sees BJ's story as a trilogy and hopes that it isn't done with Wolfenstein yet, as reported <a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/we-have-a-story-to-tell-machinegames-says-wolfenstein-is-a-trilogy-that-isnt-yet-finished/"><em>VideoGamesChronicle</em></a>.&nbsp;</p><p>"I think this is important to say because we have always seen this as a trilogy," Gustafsson says when describing BJ's journey from resistance fighter to family man. He later says, "...at least I hope that we're not done with Wolfenstein yet. We have a story to tell."&nbsp;</p><p>It sounds like we can expect a third Wolfenstein game, if MachineGames has any say over the matter.&nbsp;</p><p height="360" width="640" url="https://www.youtube.com/embed/E189QG28rnE"><iframe width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/E189QG28rnE" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay" allowfullscreen="true">&nbsp;</iframe></p><p>The last mainline Wolfenstein game was 2017's The New Colossus, although the team also helped develop 2019's&nbsp;<a href="https://gameinformer.com/review/wolfenstein-youngblood/making-the-best-of-change" target="_blank">Youngblood</a>, a co-op-focused spinoff set 19 years after <a href="https://gameinformer.com/product/wolfenstein-the-new-order">The New Order</a> and <a href="https://gameinformer.com/product/wolfenstein-ii-the-new-colossus">The New Colossus</a>. It's been eight years since the last mainline entry, and more than six years since MachineGames released any game related to Wolfenstein, so here's hoping the team is cooking something up now post-Indy.&nbsp;</p><p>In the meantime, read <em>Game Informer's </em><a href="https://gameinformer.com/games/wolfenstein_the_new_order/b/xboxone/archive/2014/05/19/wolfenstein-the-new-order-review.aspx">Wolfenstein: The New Order review</a>, <a href="https://gameinformer.com/games/wolfenstein_ii_the_new_colossus/b/playstation4/archive/2017/10/26/a-bloody-and-unforgettable-revolution.aspx">Wolfenstein II: The New Colossus review</a>, and <a href="https://gameinformer.com/review/wolfenstein-youngblood/making-the-best-of-change">Wolfenstein: Youngblood review</a>. After that, read <em>Game Informer's </em><a href="https://gameinformer.com/review/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle/worthy-of-a-museum">Indiana Jones and The Great Circle review</a>.&nbsp;</p><p>[<strong>Source</strong>: <a href="https://youtu.be/E189QG28rnE?si=4-b6qJ9glHHbjGnv"><em>Noclip</em></a> via <a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/we-have-a-story-to-tell-machinegames-says-wolfenstein-is-a-trilogy-that-isnt-yet-finished/"><em>VideoGamesChronicle</em></a>]</p><hr><p><em>What would you like to see in a third mainline Wolfenstein game? Let us know in the comments below!</em></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://gameinformer.com/2025/09/08/machinegames-hopes-to-make-another-wolfenstein-game-and-sees-bjs-story-as-a-trilogy]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PAX West 2025: 11 Games You Should Add to Your Wishlist]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/features/pax-west-2025-x-games-you-should-add-to-your-wishlist</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pax-west-2025-11-games-you-should-add-to-your-wishlist.1291476/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>PAX West has wrapped up this year, and our team on the ground spent the entire four-day weekend looking all the latest in gaming. From unexpected indies to eagerly anticipated titles, here's a roundup of all the cool games Editor in Chief Andrew Otton and Features Editor Robert Scarpinito saw in Seattle.</p>



<h2><em>Blocks for Babies</em></h2>

<p>Have you ever wanted to whip out a super shotgun to clear out some blocks in <em>Tetris</em>? Then <em>Blocks for Babies</em> is exactly what you're looking for. It blends <em>DOOM </em>with <em>Tetris </em>in more clever ways than you might think. Certain blocks can only be cleared in first-person gameplay, adding an extra layer of strategy while you're laying tiles.</p>

<p>Additionally, boss battles impact both gameplay modes. For example, the boss in the PAX demo moved like the old-school game <em>Snake </em>in <em>Tetris </em>mode, dropping specific blocks you have to clear quickly. Meanwhile, in first-person, you can shoot specific blocks in the snake to do more damage as the snake flies about.</p>

<p>You can find a demo for it <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2776770/Blocks_for_Babies/" rel="nofollow">(and add it to your wishlist) on Steam</a>.</p>



<h2><em>Unyielder</em></h2>

<p>This is the first of three games from Shueisha Games on this list, so strap in. <em>Unyielder </em>is all octane, no oxygen. This first-person shooter roguelike is all about quick reflexes, precise timing, and the rule of cool. You get power ups as you progress in a run, with basic ones like faster reload times and more interesting ones like the ability to infinitely reload a clip. Suddenly, that rocket launcher that loads one rocket at a time becomes an endless barrage of carnage.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The secret to satisfaction here, though, is the parry system. It's one giant boss rush, and each boss has multiple attacks that can be countered. If you time your shots correctly, you'll interrupt the enemy and make them vulnerable to damage. There are five playable characters, but the one I tried had a grappling hook that I used to zip around the battlefield.</p>

<p>I'm instantly sold, and it's looking like it'll come out within the year. You can <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/789940/UNYIELDER/" rel="nofollow">wishlist it on Steam here</a>.</p>



<h2><em>Ninja Gaiden 4</em></h2>

<p><em>Ninja Gaiden 4 </em>is the only AAA game on this list, solely because I didn't have enough time to finish the entire preview build. However, what I played was nothing short of refined and exciting. It continues the franchise's history of fast-paced, cutthroat action, and something that really caught my eye was the Bloodraven meter on the new extra-edgy protagonist Yakumo.</p>

<p>This meter can be tapped into by holding down a shoulder button, amplifying your damage and changing your combos. Unlike other action games, this isn't a one-time activation situation. It can be turned on or off at a whim as long as you have enough left, opening the door for some interesting strategies and—more importantly—sick-looking combos.</p>

<p>Throw in a dark, hyper-futuristic neo-Tokyo setting and I'll be there. <em>Ninja Gaiden 4 </em>will hit Xbox Game Pass along with PlayStation 5 on Oct. 21.</p>



<h2><em>Bakudo</em></h2>

<p>There's something so satisfying about a game that takes basic sports and cranks everything up to 11,000. <em>Bakudo </em>is still in early development by Sayil Games under Shueisha's publishing arm, and it's basically a sci-fi dodgeball boss rush. You play as a character who just entered Bakudo Academy, but there's a major conspiracy under it all.</p>

<p>The story and presentation give me <em>Kill La Kill</em> vibes, and the gameplay is merciless. Catching the enemy's ball requires you to read their movements and react quickly, and sometimes you'll need to curve the ball to get past their defenses. Certain attacks require you to parry instead of catching, opening the door for high-powered spikes if you can time it perfectly.</p>

<p><em>Bakudo </em>is equal parts charming and brutal, and <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2275860/BAKUDO/" rel="nofollow">you can wishlist it on Steam</a>—just don't expect it to release within the next year.</p>



<h2><em>Cat Secretary</em></h2>

<p>Cats have been having a moment in video games, and Good Story Guild is looking to ride that wave with its upcoming game <em>Cat Secretary</em>. It leans more toward the playfulness of <em>Little Kitty, Big City</em>, but it also has a little bite with its silly yet scathing commentary on capitalism.</p>

<p>You work as a cute little business cat in a company where almost everyone has been replaced with AI robots. Naturally, they need someone to do things that only organic creatures can handle, like sorting files and making coffee, which you do during the day. By night, it seems like you'll be skulking around and helping a rat potentially sabotage the company? Honestly, I'm unsure, but I'm along for the ride.</p>

<p>If you want to get your paws on <em>Cat Secretary</em>, <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2783280/Cat_Secretary/" rel="nofollow">you can wishlist it on Steam</a>.</p>



<h2><em>Arcane Eats</em></h2>

<p><em>Arcane Eats </em>takes a formula perfected by <em>Slay the Spire</em> and applies it to the culinary arts to fantastic results. There's a level of tongue-in-cheek humor here that makes everything feel light and breezy, and it's so mechanically sound that the rules of the game feel intuitive.</p>

<p>You have three burners to manage, and you can stack skillets of food on top of each other for a bigger "attack" against a customer's hunger. The longer they wait, though, the more mental damage they'll do to you, so you have to thread the needle between building up numbers and turn management.</p>

<p>This game is made by a small team in Seattle, and <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2640090/Arcane_Eats/" rel="nofollow">you can wishlist it on Steam</a>. After all, don't you want to beat the first food-judge boss, Guy Fairy?</p>



<h2><em>OPUS: Prism Peaks</em></h2>

<p>Visual-novel (adjacent?) fans might recognize the previous game from Taiwanese developers SIGONO, called <em>OPUS: Echo of Starsong</em>. I remember it being well received by critics, so I wanted to see what the hype was about with the new project from SIGONO, which is being published by Shueisha.</p>

<p>The demo I played was roughly 20 minutes, and the caliber of storytelling here felt next level. The protagonist goes through a lot of ups and downs in that short time, immediately creating an complex character that left me wanting to learn more about him. And that doesn't even get into the sudden appearance of a cursed girl he's reluctantly helping.</p>

<p><em>OPUS: Prism Peak</em> is giving <em>Life Is Strange</em> vibes with its third-person light puzzle solving and a focus on narrative, and I'm <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1947910/OPUS_Prism_Peak/" rel="nofollow">keeping an eye on its Steam page</a> as it gets closer to release.</p>



<h2>Rabbit Haul</h2>

<p>When I first heard about <em>Rabbit Haul</em>, it felt like the perfect mix of games made just for me. It's part farming sim, part tower defense, and you even have to restore a town as your "base" for upgrades. That's a trifecta that will get me more than interested immediately.</p>

<p>The overarching goal is to rebuild your hometown and you do so by growing crops on your farm to rebuild the town's economy and food reserves. The plants you grow all have different values and effects, which will come into effect when it turns to night.</p>

<p>At night, your farm is descended on by hungry raccoons hellbent and eating your food stores. Thankfully, you can fight back with weapons and the plants you grow will try to defend themselves as well.</p>

<p>It's an utterly charming game that was absolutely swarmed whenever I saw it at PAX West. <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2514330/The_Rabbit_Haul/" rel="nofollow">Wishlist <em>Rabbit Haul </em>on Steam</a>, I bet you won't regret it if these are your types of games.</p>



<h2>No Stone Unturned</h2>

<p>In <em>No Stone Unturned</em> you set out to answer the age old question: Why did the chicken cross the road? You play the squirrel Detective Cox who is there to investigate the murder of said chicken found right next to the road.</p>

<p><em>No Stone Unturned</em> is a detective game with a quirky story with funny characters and a lot of mystery. There's the overarching case of the chicken, but there's more to learn about the town you'll find yourself in.</p>

<p>While gathering clues, you'll encounter all kinds of people and puzzles, as well as a bunch of classic mini-games that will remind you immediately of WarioWare.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Everything I saw in the 20ish minute demo was clever and had more than a few chuckles in it. I love the way it looks, and I can't wait to sit down and soak it all in. <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2453640/No_Stone_Unturned/" rel="nofollow">Check it out on Steam</a>.</p>



<h2>War of the Western Deep</h2>

<p><em>War of the Western Deep</em> is a classic adventure game set in the graphic novel series, <em>Beyond the Western Deep</em>. It caught my eye last year at PAX West, and I was excited to see it return this year.</p>

<p>You play as Mirren (voiced by Samantha Béart, who you may know as Karlach from <em>Baldur's Gate III</em>), a royal courier sent out to send an important letter by the king. Your peaceful kingdom of Sunsgrove is about to be invaded secretly by your neighbors, and you need to travel into soon-to-be enemy territory to deliver that letter.</p>

<p>The first thing you'll notice it is visually striking, with absolutely gorgeous artwork. What's even better is how it's all hand-animated artwork, which makes for a beautiful image on screen.</p>

<p>There's also some combat that really shows off the beautiful animations. Combat is very reminiscent of something like Punch-Out!!, where it's about timing attacks and dodges with your opponent while managing a stamina bar for your movements. The crisp, flowing animations make it a delight to take in.</p>

<p>I'm a sucker for narrative heavy games and this looks amazing, so I can't wait to immerse myself in the world of Western Deep. I've certainly <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2976440/War_of_the_Western_Deep/" rel="nofollow">got it on my Steam wishlist</a>.</p>



<h2>Nocturnal 2</h2>

<p><em>Nocturnal 2</em> is the game that made us turn our head the most and we knew we had to check it out. Look through the game in motion on the <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2847780/Nocturnal_2/" rel="nofollow">Steam page</a> trailer and the other screenshots, and you'll get a good reason why.</p>

<p>Annoyingly, I had not heard or seen the first game, <em>Nocturnal</em>, which released in 2023. This is a sequel to that, and it looks to be a bigger and more beefed-up version of that game. The first was a sidescrolling action platformer, which the sequel also is but adds in some metroidvania elements on top.</p>

<p>It's obviously gorgeous to look at, but the combat has a decent amount going for it as well. It's more slow and deliberate, so don't go in thinking something like the speed of Dead Cells. Parrying and dodging out of the way to get your swings in is the key a lot of the times, as is knocking enemies into the air and slamming them into the ground. I didn't have a ton of time with the game, but I imagine juggling enemies and bouncing them off walls/the ground will play a big role into making big combos.</p>

<p>In any case, if you're looking for a new action platformer after, say, <em>Silksong</em>, keep an eye on <em>Nocturnal 2</em>. <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2847780/Nocturnal_2/" rel="nofollow">You can wishlist it here</a>.</p>
</div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/features/pax-west-2025-x-games-you-should-add-to-your-wishlist]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ex-Nintendo Dev Says Nintendo Has "No Real Need" for New Franchises]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/ex-nintendo-dev-new-franchises</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ex-nintendo-dev-says-nintendo-has-no-real-need-for-new-franchises.1291473/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>If you're wondering why Nintendo hasn't come up with a brand new franchise in a little while, an ex-Nintendo developer may well have an answer for you: it doesn't really need to.</p>

<p>Speaking to <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/newsletters/2025-09-05/nintendo-invents-new-ways-to-have-fun-with-old-characters" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Bloomberg</a>, Ken Watanabe, a former Nintendo developer who's worked on games like&nbsp;<em>Pikmin 3&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>Splatoon</em>, says new Nintendo franchises haven't appeared "simply because there's no real need to make them".</p>

<p>Rather than creating new franchises, Watanabe says the Japanese gaming giant focuses on "gameplay mechanics first", and then "pick[s] whatever fits that new gameplay best" as a franchise "skin or...wrapper".</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/donkey-kong-bananza-nintendo-new-franchises.jpg?itok=sCZpgHvL 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/donkey-kong-bananza-nintendo-new-franchises.jpg?itok=bP9_rAZx 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Donkey Kong Bananza&nbsp;</em>arguably demonstrates Nintendo's design philosophy as described by ex-developer Ken Watanabe.</figcaption></figure><p>Watanabe says that Nintendo's focus is on "creating a new way to play", and that the studio will pick the franchise that it thinks most applies to that "new way".</p>

<p>I'd argue this design approach is evident in this year's <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/donkey-kong-bananza-review-oohh-banana" rel="nofollow">rather excellent</a>&nbsp;<em>Donkey Kong Bananza</em>; the "new way" Nintendo found this time was to create <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/donkey-kong-bananza-switch-2" rel="nofollow">a 3D platformer</a> full of destructible terrain, and&nbsp;<em>Donkey Kong&nbsp;</em>best fit the idea of wanton destruction mixed with 3D platforming.</p>

<p>According to Watanabe, it's also common for Nintendo staffers to "secretly work on something without telling their boss", and if that idea is interesting, it "gets turned into a real product". He describes making a level in&nbsp;<em>Pikmin 3&nbsp;</em>in his spare time, only for Nintendo to include said level in the final product.</p>

<p>Artist and designer Takaya Imamura follows up by saying that Nintendo "lets [its staff] just focus on building what [they] believe to be fun, without distraction". That would go some way towards explaining the generally high standard of Nintendo's work.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/splatoon-3-nintendo-new-franchises.jpg?itok=3u5Kf1p3 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/splatoon-3-nintendo-new-franchises.jpg?itok=K9zHtMsF 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Splatoon&nbsp;</em>arguably represents the last major Nintendo franchise to debut.</figcaption></figure><p>This philosophy is also presumably why the <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/splatoon-raiders-splatoon-3-switch-2" rel="nofollow">recently-revealed&nbsp;</a><em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/splatoon-raiders-splatoon-3-switch-2" rel="nofollow">Splatoon Raiders</a>&nbsp;</em>is a&nbsp;<em>Splatoon&nbsp;</em>spinoff rather than a game belonging to an entirely new franchise, although exactly what shape the gameplay in&nbsp;<em>Splatoon Raiders&nbsp;</em>will take remains to be seen.</p>

<p>In any case, it does look like Watanabe's idea of how Nintendo operates hasn't done the company any harm at all; the Switch 2 has <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/nintendo-financials-q1-2026" rel="nofollow">sold very well indeed</a> thus far, so whatever Nintendo is doing, it's likely to continue into the near future, at the very least.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/ex-nintendo-dev-new-franchises]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Deus Ex Writer Says The Fact Elon Musk Loves It Is Its ‘Worst Legacy’]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/elon-musk-favorite-game-deus-ex-conspiracy-2000624003</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/deus-ex-writer-says-the-fact-elon-musk-loves-it-is-its-%E2%80%98worst-legacy%E2%80%99.1291470/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Great fiction can’t fix bad people. That’s one takeaway from the fact that <a href="https://kotaku.com/elon-musk-grimes-cyberpunk-elden-ring-twitter-1850858252">Elon Musk seems to love</a> the classic sci-fi immersive sim <em>Deus Ex</em> despite it being a game precisely about how people like him are ruining the world. One of the game’s writers recently explained how that’s the worst part of its legacy.</p> <p>Released in 2000, <a href="https://kotaku.com/deus-ex-25-years-ion-storm-looking-glass-warren-ellis-1851784985"><em>Deus Ex</em> follows</a><a href="https://kotaku.com/deus-ex-25-years-ion-storm-looking-glass-warren-ellis-1851784985"> anti-terrorism operative JC Denton,</a> who uses his cybernetic enhancements to uncover the conspiratorial forces trying to take control of a world ravaged by social upheaval, economic collapse, and a plague. It’s both an investigation of how propaganda shapes society and what it means to be human, in addition to being a really clever stealth action game about hacking people’s private email.</p> <p>“That kind of political weight and social satire is a real common thread between <em>Deus Ex</em> and <em>Dishonored</em>,” Austin Grossman, who co-wrote the Warren Spector-directed hit with Sheldon Pacotti and Chris Todd, <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/fps/deus-exs-influence-on-elon-musk-may-be-its-longest-worst-legacy-says-its-writer/">recently told <em>PC Gamer</em></a>. “It is the thing that Elon Musk likes, creepily. It is creepily in Elon Musk’s worldview. So that may be its longest, worst legacy.”</p>

 <p>Musk has repeatedly called <em>Deus Ex</em> one of his <a href="https://x.com/elonmusk/status/1321245225755512832">favorite games ever</a>. When the pandemic began in early 2020, he even described it as feeling <a href="https://x.com/elonmusk/status/1241104391706304512?">like something from the game’s plot</a>. Musk also happens to be one of the world’s richest people, on track to <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/09/05/business/elon-musk-tesla-pay-trillionaire.html">become the first trillionaire</a>, whose tech empire includes companies trying to implant devices <a href="https://www.npr.org/2024/01/30/1227850900/elon-musk-neuralink-implant-clinical-trial">directly into people’s brains</a>. Reading the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/deus-ex-at-20-the-oral-history-of-a-pivotal-pc-game">oral history of <em>Deus Ex</em>‘s creation</a>, there’s little doubt the <a href="https://kotaku.com/elon-musk-poe2-diablo-4-paid-boosting-fake-controversy-1851743670"><em>Diablo</em> cheater</a> would have been considered <a href="https://knowyourmeme.com/memes/are-we-the-baddies">one of the baddies</a> in its world.</p> <p>“It’s bizarre that Elon Musk would not recognize where he actually sits in the<em> Deus Ex</em> universe, because it is not in the JC Denton role,” Grossman said. “Musk plainly imagines he’s the JC Denton of this world—a plainspoken everyman, standing up to the elite. As is obvious to everyone, Musk is the one with power and he’s just pathologically incapable of honest introspection.”</p> <p>He continued, “I would say Musk is like a<em> Deus Ex</em> villain, except that the franchise doesn’t have any villains as whiny and self-servingly delusional as he’s shown himself to be.”</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/elon-musk-favorite-game-deus-ex-conspiracy-2000624003]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ghost of Yotei ‘Journey Through the Edge of Japan’ video]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/09/ghost-of-yotei-journey-through-the-edge-of-japan-video</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ghost-of-yotei-%E2%80%98journey-through-the-edge-of-japan%E2%80%99-video.1291458/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div role="main">
  
  <article>

    
<header>

  <div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>10 minutes showcasing the landscapes of Ezo.</span>
      </p></div>

  

</header>  

<!-- Moved from templates/posts/default.php -->

    <div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Sony Interactive Entertainment [5,049 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sony-group-corporation/sony-interactive-entertainment">Sony Interactive Entertainment</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Sucker Punch Productions [154 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sony-group-corporation/sony-interactive-entertainment/sucker-punch-productions">Sucker Punch Productions</a> have released a 10-minute video for <em><a title="Games > Ghost of Yotei [6 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/ghost-of-yotei">Ghost of Yotei</a></em> dubbed “Journey Through the Edge of Japan,” which showcases the landscapes of Ezo to an extended version of the original track “The North” composed by Toma Otowa. <span id="more-990415"></span></p><p><em>Ghost of Yotei</em> is due out for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [10,320 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a> on October 2.</p><p>Watch the video below.</p><h2><span>Journey Through the Edge of Japan</span></h2><p><iframe title="Ghost of Yōtei - Journey Through The Edge Of Japan Video | PS5 Games" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/kj6i1eCfIgA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div>

        
    
  </article>
</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/09/ghost-of-yotei-journey-through-the-edge-of-japan-video]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Pokemon TCG Expansion Is Coming In November]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/new-pokemon-tcg-expansion-is-coming-in-november/1100-6534534/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-pokemon-tcg-expansion-is-coming-in-november.1291455/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-main">

      
                    
  
              <header id="masthead"><nav></nav></header>      
                            <div id="site-wrapper" role="main">
          <div id="default-content">
        
          <p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p>
  
    <article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6534534">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>During this year's Pokemon World Championships, The Pokemon Company <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-pokemon-tcg-is-getting-a-new-type-of-rare-mega-evolution-cards/1100-6534035/" data-ref-id="1100-6534035">teased the Evolved Pokemon card, Mega Charizard X EX</a>, as well as Mega attack rare cards. Now, the new expansion for Pokemon Trading Card Game (TCG),  Mega Evolution — Phantasmal Flames, has been announced.</p><p>Mega Evolution — Phantasmal Flames will arrive on November 14 with new Mega Evolution Pokemon and an emphasis on fire-type and darkness-type cards. Some of the highlights are listed below.</p><ul><li>6 Mega Evolution Pokemon ex cards</li><li>4 ex cards</li><li>13 illustrated rare Pokemon</li><li>17 ultra rare Mega Evolution Pokemon ex Trainer and Energy cards</li><li>5 Mega Evolution Pokemon ex and Supporter cards</li></ul><p>Preorders for Phantasmal Flames haven't gone live yet. Players who want to try out the new expansion before launch will be able to do so during pre-release tournaments starting on November 1. Additionally, the Mega Evolution — Phantasmal Flames expansion will be available on the Pokemon TCG app starting on November 13 for iOS, Android, macOS, and PC. From there, players will be able to collect and battle with new Mega Evolution Pokemon ex cards. Players will also get in-game bonuses by logging into the app.</p><p>In other Pokemon-related news, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/pokemon-go/" data-ref-id="5000-449545">Pokemon Go</a>'s new <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/pokemon-go-tales-of-transformation-season-brings-fresh-content-in-september/1100-6534271/" data-ref-id="1100-6534271">Tales of Transformation season</a> recently began and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/pokemon-go-august-2025-events-raid-bosses-spotlight-hours-community-day-and-more/1100-6534461/" data-ref-id="1100-6534461">the events for September</a> have already been laid out. The countdown to <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/pokemon-legends-z-a/" data-ref-id="5000-619901">Pokemon Legends: Z-A</a>'s October 16 launch on Switch and Switch 2 will include <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/pokemon-legends-z-a-celebrates-upcoming-launch-with-lucha-libre-showdown/1100-6534371/" data-ref-id="1100-6534371">a special live lucha libre wrestling event in Mexico</a> on September 25. Outside of the official realm of Pokemon, the fan-made Pokemon: Close Combat fighting game <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fan-made-pokemon-fighting-game-adds-another-character/1100-6534064/" data-ref-id="1100-6534064">recently added a new character</a>.</p><div data-embed-type="html"><p><i>Click the button below to add GameSpot as a preferred source on Google</i></p></div>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article>

    
  

    
</div>
                      <meta itemprop="seamless-content-list-items" data-list-items="[{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6533384&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/pokemon-go-events-raid-bosses-spotlight-hours-community-day\/1100-6533384\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534528&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/new-starfield-expansion-potentially-teased-in-coded-message\/1100-6534528\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534498&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/disney-dreamlight-valley-is-getting-horseback-riding-in-its-next-expansion\/1100-6534498\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534497&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/new-the-sims-4-expansion-brings-vacation-getaways-and-imaginary-friends\/1100-6534497\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534439&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/classic-sci-fi-shooter-forsaken-64-is-coming-to-nintendo-switch-online\/1100-6534439\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534438&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/the-crew-is-coming-back-online-this-month-thanks-to-fan-made-mod\/1100-6534438\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534152&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/how-to-solve-the-hospital-chapel-puzzle-in-cronos-the-new-dawn\/1100-6534152\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534457&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/marvel-rivals-launches-on-ps4-in-season-4-two-new-heroes-confirmed\/1100-6534457\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534489&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/a-new-my-hero-academia-mmorpg-is-headed-to-roblox-very-soon\/1100-6534489\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534424&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/how-long-is-cronos-the-new-dawn-hours-to-beat-and-chapter-list\/1100-6534424\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534427&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/the-humanity-is-in-the-writing-destiny-2-lodi-actor-says\/1100-6534427\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534471&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/nintendo-cease-desist-letter-is-now-a-playable-character-in-smash-bros-mod\/1100-6534471\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534419&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/perfect-dark-reboot-almost-got-a-second-chance-at-take-two-report\/1100-6534419\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534418&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/get-wwe-2k25-and-seven-more-games-for-just-15-at-humble-this-month\/1100-6534418\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534412&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/lego-advent-calendar-2025-minecraft-harry-potter-star-wars-disney-deals\/1100-6534412\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534411&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/battlefield-battle-royale-mode-gameplay-shown-in-apparently-leaked-footage\/1100-6534411\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534416&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/battlefield-6-wont-have-ray-tracing-in-order-to-focus-on-performance\/1100-6534416\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534417&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/get-free-call-of-duty-double-xp-and-battle-pass-tier-skips-just-for-logging-in-soon\/1100-6534417\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534413&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/wow-most-ambitious-private-server-is-being-sued-by-blizzard\/1100-6534413\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534403&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/octopath-traveler-0-looks-massive-even-by-octopath-standards\/1100-6534403\/&quot;}]">
            </div>
              
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/new-pokemon-tcg-expansion-is-coming-in-november/1100-6534534/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["The Most Impressive Switch 2 Port To Date" - Digital Foundry Examines Star Wars Outlaws]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/the-most-impressive-switch-2-port-to-date-digital-foundry-examines-star-wars-outlaws</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-most-impressive-switch-2-port-to-date-digital-foundry-examines-star-wars-outlaws.1291437/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Gotta trace those rays</p>
</section></header><div><section>

<p><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/star-wars-outlaws">Star Wars Outlaws</a> is out now on the Switch 2 (a fact you might have missed thanks to last week's furore around <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/hollow-knight-silksong-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Hollow Knight: Silksong</a>) and now the tech experts over at Digital Foundry have provided their analysis of the game's performance on Nintendo's new hardware.</p>
<p>Despite some concerns pre-launch, Outlaws is kind of a technical marvel, with Digital Foundry calling it "the most impressive Switch 2 port to date", noting that despite the console being weaker than its console siblings – including the Xbox Series S – advancements within the architecture mean that Outlaws is able to punch well above its weight.</p>
<p>Looking at image quality, DLSS allows Outlaws to output at 1440p when docked, with comparisons to the Series S more favourable than Digital Foundry has initially expected. Similarly, frame rate remains pretty consistent at 30fps throughout, though some menus actually push this up to 60fps. Cutscenes and pre-rendered videos sometimes drop a few frames here and there, but the gameplay is where it counts, and this is solid.</p>
<p>Digital Foundry also highlights some solid use of ray-tracing, while also noting that volumetric lighting and fog has been decreased slightly when compared to other consoles.</p>
<p>In a rather curious comparison doing the rounds from <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@FactorofGames">Factor of Games</a> on YouTube, gameplay from the Switch 2 goes head-to-head with the Steam Deck. Context around exact performance parameters on the Steam Deck is missing, but otherwise the video demonstrates an obvious advantage for the Switch 2.</p>

<p>Overall then, it seems Outlaws is a pretty solid benchmark for what can be achieved on the Switch 2, and it seems to be an even more impressive port than launch title <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/cyberpunk-2077-ultimate-edition">Cyberpunk 2077: Ultimate Edition</a>. It's a good indication of what might be achieved in the future, should developers and publishers strive to put in the work and not cut corners. Fingers crossed.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:187348,187400,187479 @ 1757342754 -->
<p><em>Have you been playing Star Wars Outlaws on Switch 2? What do you make of it so far? Let us know with a comment.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XlKCBGzrB1I" rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XlKCBGzrB1I">youtube.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-info/c0958a6b8f7e4d85c307d5687f1e1f50 @ 1757340742 --></div></article><div><p>Nintendo Life’s resident horror fanatic, when he’s not knee-deep in Resident Evil and Silent Hill lore, Ollie likes to dive into a good horror book while nursing a lovely cup of tea. He also enjoys long walks and listens to everything from TOOL to Chuck Berry.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Olliemar28"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/ollie-nl.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Olliemar28');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/the-most-impressive-switch-2-port-to-date-digital-foundry-examines-star-wars-outlaws]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokemon Legends: Z-A Preview – Another Reason to Get a Switch 2]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/pokemon-legends-z-preview-another-reason-to-get-switch-2</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pokemon-legends-z-a-preview-%E2%80%93-another-reason-to-get-a-switch-2.1291434/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>I remember being fairly interested in what Game Freak was doing with its first stab at <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/pokemon-legends-arceus" rel="nofollow"><em>Pokemon Legends: Arceus</em></a>. It was a whole new way to play with Pocket Monsters, but dodgy frame rates and a repetitive rhythm lulled me away from really enjoying it.</p>

<p>Nonetheless, it had a certain quality that a lot of first tries have in this industry: it fell a little flat for me, but there was lots of potential for a sequel to really knock it out of the park. So I knew I had to try <em>Pokemon Legends: Z-A </em>while at PAX West.</p>

<p>The show floor demo was played on a Nintendo Switch 2, and it showcased two parts of the game: Battle Zones and a story encounter against a Mega Absol. After about 20 minutes with the game, I walked away from that demo excited for <em>Pokemon</em> like I was a kid waiting for <em>Pokemon Diamond </em>and <em>Pearl</em>&nbsp;again.</p>



<h2>Battle Zones Put the Focus on Trainers</h2>

<p>The first 10 minutes in the Battle Zone reminded me of a huge factor that I felt was missing from <em>Arceus</em>: trainer battles. Most of my memories with <em>Arceus </em>were roaming around wide open spaces, throwing balls at wild Pokemon with the occasional battle punctuated throughout.</p>

<p>In a Battle Zone, it's all about fighting opposing trainers. You can sneak up on their Pokemon by sending yours out from behind, giving you an advantage in the ensuing fight.</p>



<p lang="EN-US" paraeid="{773212e2-ce74-4f72-bc73-72ccdcf9ce45}{111}" paraid="115263152" xml:lang="EN-US">This time around, too, the old-school turn-based battles are no more. Everything is in real time now. You aim at an enemy while holding down a shoulder button, and all the face buttons are mapped to your Pokemon's abilities.</p>

<p>There were no agile or strong mode inputs from what I could see. Instead, each individual ability was on a cooldown, and as you'd expect, weaker attacks tend to cool down faster than others. I found myself settling into a rhythm of which attacks to rotate through, trying to minimize downtime as much as possible.</p>

<p>If you're in a poor matchup, you can quickly swap to another Pokemon by using the D-pad. It all felt seamless thanks to not having to pause the game, and the real-time menuing felt snappy and convenient.</p>



<h2>Living It Up in Lumiose City</h2>

<p><em>Pokemon Legends: Z-A</em> is set entirely in Lumiose City, the large city from <em>Pokemon X</em> and <em>Y</em>. When I first learned that, my immediate worry was performance. The Switch, <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/opinions/2017-was-magical-year-for-nintendo" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">as amazing as that system is</a>, was starting to feel its age in recent years.</p>

<p>Luckily, the demos for <em>Pokemon Legends: Z-A </em>ran on the Switch 2, and all my fears disappeared. Running around the Battle Zone was smooth as butter, and it looked pretty good to boot.</p>

<p>As a city boy, I always love when a game brings an entire urban landscape to life, <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/marvels-spider-man-2-review-2-spider-man-1-furious" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">like the&nbsp;<em>Spider-Man </em>games</a>. So I'm excited to see Pokemon's take on it, especially with the power of the Switch 2.</p>



<p>The final leg of the demo involved a boss fight with a rogue Mega Absol, which was provided a bit of story context. It seems there's some mysterious reason these random Mega Evolutions are happening, and in true Pokemon fashion, you're randomly roped into stopping them.</p>

<p>In the demo I played, the protagonist didn't have a Mega Ring at first, so this Mega Absol could be one of the early ones we'll run into in the full game.</p>



<p>The fight itself felt a bit like the bosses in <em>Arceus</em>, where the trainer themself has to dodge a bunch of attacks. However, this time around, instead of throwing weird items at them, you're ordering your Pokemon to do attacks.</p>

<p>An extra layer of strategy I enjoyed is that my Lucario had Protect mapped as one of its abilities. Using it at just the right time so it didn't take damage from a large area-of-effect attack felt so satisfying, in a way I wouldn't expect from a Pokemon game.</p>

<p>Overall, the boss fight wasn't difficult, but there were just enough plates spinning that it remained engaging throughout, which is more than I can say for my experience with some games in the franchise's past. Hopefully that momentum remains in the full release.</p>



<h2><em>Pokemon Legends: Z-A</em> Preview – Final Thoughts</h2>

<p>Pokemon is a franchise I've learned to temper my expectations with. The level of fun I had with it as a kid probably won't match whatever I'm looking for as an adult. However, <em>Pokemon Legends: Z-A</em> could be the game that makes me second guess that lesson.</p>

<p>I had so much fun with the little time I spent with it, and it instantly became something I'm looking forward to playing on my Switch 2. I hope the story remains interesting the long-term, but even if not, roaming around Lumiose City holds a lot of promise for me.</p>

<hr><p><em><strong>Pokemon Legends: Z-A </strong>was previewed on a Nintendo Switch 2 at PAX West.</em></p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Robert Scarpinito is the Features Editor of TechRaptor. With a Bachelor of Arts in Journalism from the Ohio State University, sharing compelling stories is… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/robert-scarpinito">More about Robert</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/pokemon-legends-z-preview-another-reason-to-get-switch-2]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battle of Hoth Review - Ice Cold Fun]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/battle-of-hoth-review-ice-cold-fun</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/battle-of-hoth-review-ice-cold-fun.1291431/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>AT-AT's stomp on the hard-packed ice of Hoth, shaking the ground and rattling the hidden bunkers underneath. Meanwhile, hordes of brave Rebel soldiers burst from the snow, sending torrents of well-aimed blaster fire. Does the fate of the galaxy hinge on this pivotal battle? It does when you and your friends pick up a copy of&nbsp;<em>Battle of Hoth</em>, a new strategic board game from Days of Wonder. Asmodee USA sent me a copy to check out, so let's fire up our snow-speeders and jump right in.</p>

<h2>What Is&nbsp;<em>Battle of Hoth</em>?</h2>

<p><em>Battle of Hoth</em>&nbsp;is a strategic skirmish board game for two players (with a team-mode to allow for three to four players), with one player taking on the role of the Rebel Alliance and the other taking on the Imperial army. The objective of the game is (usually, though there are many different scenarios to play through) being the first to claim a set amount of victory medals by meeting a specific scenario's victory conditions.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/battle-of-hoth-board.jpg?itok=Q6-GASz3 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/battle-of-hoth-board.jpg?itok=byl1tAD0 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>To do so, you'll assign orders to your forces around the board, roll dice to attack, and attempt to out-pace and out-think your opponent in this quick strategic game. Each scenario instructs players on how to set up the board, placing their units onto the battlefield as well as terrain hexes that alter the environment.</p>

<h2>Activating Activations</h2>

<p>I really like the way activating units is handled in this game. Instead of issuing order tokens, or secretly selecting units from your battlefield, you'll play a Command card from a hidden hand you draw. And the command cards (except for special leader cards) break up the battlefield into thirds.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/battle-of-hoth-command-card.jpg?itok=IsloiLGK 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/battle-of-hoth-command-card.jpg?itok=vruOD9mj 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>In this example, the Rebel player has played the command card seen on the board, meaning they can activate two units in the left shaded quadrant.</figcaption></figure><p>Your Command card may say you can activate two units in the middle of the board, or one on each of the left and ride sides of the board, or some other combination. I find this approach to the game extremely engaging, as I have to both work with what I've got on the board&nbsp;<em>and</em>&nbsp;decide which of my Command cards to use, and which to save.</p>

<h2>A Fast-Paced Blast</h2>

<p>One of the first things that caught my attention with&nbsp;<em>Battle of Hoth</em>&nbsp;is how little time it takes to actually set up the game and get rolling. Before I even opened the box, I admit I was expecting some hulking behemoth full of cards, rulebooks, miniatures, and tokens galore. But that's not the case with&nbsp;<em>Battle of Hoth</em>, with only a slim rulebook, a straight-to-the-action scenario book, 19 double-sided terrain hexes, 6 attack die, and miniatures for each side (the Rebels get 35 minis, and the Imperials get 39).</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/battle-of-hoth-rebel-minis.jpg?itok=Vaf846dt 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/battle-of-hoth-rebel-minis.jpg?itok=rzpKtTWr 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>The three types of Rebel miniatures included in the game.</figcaption></figure><p>Playing the game, I was equally surprised at how nicely it moved along. You move your units, roll dice to attack, and before you know it you're scoring hits, removing enemy units, and getting closer and closer to your goal of four victory points (or more or less, depending on scenario).</p>

<p>You achieve these victory medals by completely eliminating an enemy unit (though some scenarios may offer extra or different ways to achieve victory medals).</p>

<p>So what this creates is a truly feeling of chaotic warfare on the battlefield, with snow-speeders zooming around, AT-AT's lumbering through the battlefield, and hordes of little dudes running around trying to pick each other off. Aside from some of the more complicated scenarios, you'll be done a standard scenario within 35-45 minutes. That's fast for a strategy wargame!</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/battle-of-hoth-imperial-minis.jpg?itok=RRq71tI7 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/battle-of-hoth-imperial-minis.jpg?itok=n_QD63Cz 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>The three types of Imperial Miniatures available in the game.</figcaption></figure><h2>Deeper Than It Seems</h2>

<p>I'm doing a lot of praising the game's speed and simplicity, but it certainly is deeper than it seems. As I mentioned above, the Command card activations are a fun and engaging way to mobilize troops. Add to that the ability to slightly customize your deck by choosing a commander, and it's almost like a mini-game within the game.</p>

<p>The dice-resolution is great fun on this too, with custom symbols on the dice representing a soldier silhouette, a mechanical gear, and a starburst. To hit your opponent's unit, you have to get the proper symbols. Starbursts hit everything, but the other two symbols matter: you can only hit troops with a soldier silhouette and snow speeders and AT-AT's with the gear (probe droids and rebel artillery can&nbsp;<em>only</em>&nbsp;be hit with the starbursts).</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/battle-of-hoth-dice-roll.jpg?itok=TnM6ZC7a 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/battle-of-hoth-dice-roll.jpg?itok=xB5nQv1U 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>In this scenario, the Rebel player has rolled their three dice to attack the Imperial Unit. The blue symbol and the yellow starburst are both hits, so two Imperial minis would be removed from this unit.</figcaption></figure><p>And then there's the Scenario Book, which contains 18 different scenarios to play through - from a first assault on an Imperial Scouting mission to defending the shield generators, medevac'ing important officers out of the field, and a final mass showdown called "Assault on Hoth," there's just so much game in here.</p>

<h2><em>Battle of Hoth -&nbsp;</em>Final Thoughts</h2>

<p>You don't have to be a&nbsp;<em>Star Wars</em>&nbsp;fan to find a lot to love in&nbsp;<em>Battle of Hoth -&nbsp;</em>though I assume many <em>will</em>&nbsp;with its focus on the classic&nbsp;<em>Empire</em>&nbsp;set piece. With its fast-paced gameplay and pick-up-and-play rules, this might be one of the cleanest introductions to strategy wargaming I've ever played. Using simple, intuitive dice-roll mechanics, easy unit movement rules, and few other "Yes... but!" clauses that can clog up the gameplay, what we get is a clean, well-oiled machine of a strategy skirmish game that prioritizes player fun over fussiness.</p>

<p>Highly, highly recommended - get out there and give it a try for yourself!</p>

<hr><p><em>The copy of&nbsp;</em>Battle of Hoth<em>&nbsp;used in the creation of this review was provided for us by Asmodee USA.</em></p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Giaco Furino joined the TechRaptor team as a Staff Writer in 2019 after searching for a dedicated place to write and talk about Tabletop Games. In 2020, he… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/giaco-furino">More about Giaco</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/battle-of-hoth-review-ice-cold-fun]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Roku Clears Out Its Streaming Stick Plus 2025 at Nearly Free, While Amazon Fire TV Stick Stays Full Price]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/roku-clears-out-its-streaming-stick-plus-2025-at-nearly-free-while-amazon-fire-tv-stick-stays-full-price-2000623465</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/roku-clears-out-its-streaming-stick-plus-2025-at-nearly-free-while-amazon-fire-tv-stick-stays-full-price.1291422/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>How old is the TV in your living room? Is it absent of any smart features and streaming apps? Or maybe it is a smart TV, but you’re just not a fan of that particular manufacturer’s user interface (I’m looking at you LG with your wannabe Wiimote motion controls). You don’t need to be locked down to whatever your TV was capable of just out of the box. Pick up a Roku streaming stick for basically nothing and now you’ve got an intuitive, reliable way to stream content and navigate the apps. Usually, you can find<strong> the 2025 Roku Streaming Stick Plus with 4K and HDR support</strong> for $40. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3957/">However, right now Amazon is running a limited time deal that’s bringing its price down by 27% to just $29.</a></p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3957/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Jump Right In</h2>
<p>With a Roku streaming stick, you’ll have access to tons of different apps like Netflix, Hulu, and HBO Max (or whatever they’re deciding to call it this week). Customize the home screen to your preferences, putting the apps you use most frequently front and center. You’ll even be able to watch a good handful of Roku originals at absolutely no added cost. The service has shows like <em>Dinner Budget Showdown</em>,&nbsp;<em>Celebrity Family Food Battle</em>,&nbsp;<em>Martha Cooks</em>,&nbsp;<em>Emeril Cooks</em><em>,&nbsp;</em>and I’m sure a bunch of other stuff that aren’t cooking shows.</p>



<p>This streaming stick from Roku is capable of streaming content in 4K resolution and in HDR, so you won’t be sacrificing any image quality by making the jump from your 4K HDR TV’s interface to the more user-friendly Roku Plus. The streaming stick can even by synced up with your TV so it automatically turns on and off with one press. You can even control volume and navigate your Roku all with just the one remote. It even has a voice buttons which makes searching for your favorite TV shows or movies even easier. Just hold the button, say, “<em>My Cousin Vinny</em>,” and the next thing you know, you’ll be watching Marisa Tomei bang her foot on the ground as her biological clock ticks <em>like this</em>.</p>
<p>The Roku Streaming Stick Plus is designed to be unobtrusive. It’s compact form factor doesn’t block any other neighboring HDMI inputs. It’s powered by USB-A so you can just plug that end of it right back into your TV to run it. The whole thing will stay out of sight and you’ll avoid and extra cable running out, adding to the clutter.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3957/">Right now, you can grab the Roku Streaming Stick Plus for nearly 30% off for a limited time.</a></p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3957/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/roku-clears-out-its-streaming-stick-plus-2025-at-nearly-free-while-amazon-fire-tv-stick-stays-full-price-2000623465]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>