<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 03:06:58 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine 2 Campaign Length Explained]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/space-marine-2-campaign-length/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/warhammer-40-000-space-marine-2-campaign-length-explained.971382/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/space-marine-2-campaign-length/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>While a single-player campaign certainly isn’t the focal point for a horde shooter, especially when it includes PvE and PvP game modes, it’s nice knowing you’ll get your money’s worth on all fronts. That said, here’s what we know about the Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine 2 campaign length!</p>



<h2 id="h-how-long-is-the-single-player-campaign-in-space-marine-2">How Long is the Single-Player Campaign in Space Marine 2?</h2>



<p>You certainly shouldn’t expect a massive campaign of epic proportions, but it’s a comfortable size for a weekend romp. It takes approximately<strong> 8-10 hours to finish the campaign</strong> in Space Marine 2 on standard difficulty settings. If you lower the difficulty, it may take less time. If you increase the difficulty, expect up to 12 or so hours to finish the story mode.</p>



<p>Furthermore, as you can play through the campaign cooperatively, having a human partner by your side instead of the AI should help you finish the main missions a little quicker.</p>







<h2 id="h-how-many-pve-missions-does-space-marine-2-include">How Many PvE Missions Does Space Marine 2 Include?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Image via Saber Interactive</figcaption></figure>



<p>You can expect approximately five to six PvE missions on launch, with more to come in the future, as per the studio’s <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/space-marine-2-roadmap/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">year one roadmap</a>. Like in World War Z, PvE missions will likely be highly replayable in Space Marine 2. As you’ll want to unlock much of <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/warhammer-40000-space-marine-2-customization-details-released/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the game’s cosmetics</a>, including weapons and armor skins, you’ll likely play through each mission repeatedly to score points or currency necessary to unlock equipment. That’s how things worked in World War Z.</p>



<p>Of course, alongside the campaign and PvE missions, there’s also the PvP game mode, which will extend the lifespan of the third-person action game for many. If PvP isn’t your thing, there’s nothing wrong with moving on to another game while waiting for more PvE missions to release!</p>



<hr>



<p>Before you get too excited about the Space Marine 2 campaign length, <span>remember to check out the game’s&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/here-are-the-space-marine-2-pc-requirements/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">system requirements</a> to </span>ensure your computer can run it!</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>
    
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Persona 3 Reload Expansion Pass Wave 3 ‘Episode Aigis: The Answer’ opening movie]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/09/persona-3-reload-expansion-pass-wave-3-episode-aigis-the-answer-opening-movie</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/persona-3-reload-expansion-pass-wave-3-%E2%80%98episode-aigis-the-answer%E2%80%99-opening-movie.971361/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/09/persona-3-reload-expansion-pass-wave-3-episode-aigis-the-answer-opening-movie<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Featuring the Ryota Kozuka-composed theme song "Disconnected."</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > ATLUS [2,026 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/atlus">ATLUS</a> has released the opening movie for <em><a title="Games > Persona 3 Reload [43 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/persona-3-reload">Persona 3 Reload</a></em> Expansion Pass Wave 3 downloadable content “Episode Aigis: The Answer,” which is due out on September 10. It features the Ryota Kozuka-composed theme song “Disconnected.” <span id="more-912214"></span></p><p><em>Persona 3 Reload</em> is available now for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [7,858 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [6,024 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,160 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox One [13,460 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [21,151 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2161700/Persona_3_Reload/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-us/games/store/persona-3-reload/9nkk6z0k3rh2" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Microsoft Store</a>. It is also available via <a title="Platforms > Xbox [24,740 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox">Xbox</a> Game Pass.</p><p>Watch the opening movie below.</p><h2><span>Expansion Pass Wave 3: “Episode Aigis” Opening Movie</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><p><iframe title="Persona 3 Reload: Expansion Pass — Episode Aigis Opening Movie" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/3bbz23VPnOA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe title="『ペルソナ３ リロード: Episode Aegis』オープニング映像" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/RwiqfOl8hGE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fast-paced action platformer Corebreaker to be published by Astrolabe Games]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/09/fast-paced-action-platformer-corebreaker-to-be-published-by-astrolabe-games</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fast-paced-action-platformer-corebreaker-to-be-published-by-astrolabe-games.971358/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/09/fast-paced-action-platformer-corebreaker-to-be-published-by-astrolabe-games<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Run, jump, dash, and shoot the way through hordes of robots.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Astrolabe Games [38 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/astrolabe-games">Astrolabe Games</a> will publish <a title="Companies > aQuadiun Games" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/aquadiun-games">aQuadiun Games</a>-developed fast-paced <a title="Genres > Action [2,138 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a> platformer <em><a title="Games > Corebreaker" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/corebreaker">Corebreaker</a></em> when it launches for <a title="Platforms > PC [21,151 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2190920/Corebreaker/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a>, the companies announced. A release date was not announced. <span id="more-912076"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Astrolabe Games:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>Corebreaker</em> is a fast-paced action platformer with <a title="Genres > Roguelike [248 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/roguelike">roguelike</a> elements, featuring Nova, a robot designed to awaken when humanity is extinct. Players will unlock abilities, upgrades, and powerful weapons as they battle through four unique biomes filled with supreme robots. Expect snappy controls, satisfying gunplay, and epic boss fights!</p><p><strong>Break Through the Core in a <a title="Companies > Bullets [10 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/bullets">Bullets</a>torm!</strong></p><p><em>Corebreaker</em> is a fast-paced action <a title="Genres > Platformer [524 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/platformer">platformer game</a> with roguelike elements. You are Nova, a robot awakened at the brink of humanity’s extinction at the hands of machines. Your mission? To save, search, or destroy? The choice is yours, but you must get to the core first – Unlock abilities, upgrades and powerful weapons as you fight your way through supreme robots to find out your purpose!</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong>Crisp Controls, Fluid Movement, and Dynamic Combat!</strong></p><p>Run, jump, dash, and shoot the way through hordes of robots, combining various melee attack moves for maximum impact. While some battles may challenge you more than just shoot’em all, the satisfaction of overcoming tough enemy with smooth, skillful combat is what makes the game truly fun.</p><p><strong>Fail Fast, Fail Forward!</strong></p><p>No matter how many times Nova falls, it can be extracted, repaired, and sent right back into the fray. While progress resets, some of the power-up chips and resources collected deep within the ruins are preserved. Use these to permanently upgrade Nova’s systems, unlock stronger skills, power move punches, additional gadgets, and more powerful weapons.</p><p><strong>Go Deep into the Underground Ruins… All the way to the Core!</strong></p><p>The underground ruins are vast and ever-changing, with their structure shifting with each Nova’s deployment. As Nova delves deeper, both the types and configurations of enemies evolve. In addition to the bosses guarding each biome, powerful elite enemies different in sizes and skills await your challenge. Break down walls to discover hidden rooms filled with useful resources and treasures, arm yourself at power-up terminals and weapon shops, and fear not “death” — Remember? For with each journey, Nova will only grow stronger.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li>Crisp controls and fluid movement.</li><li>Satisfying gunplay.</li><li>Four biomes with unique enemies, mini-bosses and epic boss fights.</li><li>Over 20 permanent abilities to unlock.</li><li>Over 50 upgrades to combine and create your build in each run.</li><li>Over 40 weapons to unlock and destroy your enemies.</li><li>Global leaderboard. Improve your high score to be in the top 10 players.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Publisher Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Corebreaker - Publisher Announce Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/LESQ7neZ8wA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Concord: Internet Reacts To Sony Shutting Down The Game]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/concord-internet-reacts-to-sony-shutting-down-the-game/1100-6526250/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/concord-internet-reacts-to-sony-shutting-down-the-game.971352/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/concord-internet-reacts-to-sony-shutting-down-the-game/1100-6526250/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6526250">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Prior to its launch last month, Sony had high hopes that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/concord-has-no-battle-pass-you-own-concord-concord-doesnt-own-you/1100-6525272/" data-ref-id="1100-6525272">Concord</a> would be the latest hero shooter to become a breakout title. However, the reception has been so disappointing that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/sonys-new-game-concord-going-offline-after-just-over-a-week/1100-6526235/" data-ref-id="1100-6526235">Sony has decided to pull Concord</a> only two weeks after its release, with refunds going out to players who bought it. Now, gaming professionals, journalists, and fans have shared their response to the news online.</p><p>Gears of War creator Cliff Bleszinski expressed his empathy for Concord's quick demise. His first-person shooter, LawBreakers, met a similar fate in 2018.</p><p>Art director Michael Maurino also expressed his feelings of solidarity with the team that brought the game to life.</p><div data-embed-type="tweet" data-src="https://x.com/Iron_Stylus/status/1831084321811341816" data-has-image="true"><blockquote data-conversation="none" data-mce-disable-toolbar="true"><p dir="ltr">Extreme shame about Concord and I just want to say that you can have a world class team, clever and unique gameplay, super appealing art and characters, highly optimized performance, cross play, and a pandemic causing players to be home all the time and still face challenges. <a href="https://t.co/xbV09YsJtM" rel="nofollow ">pic.twitter.com/xbV09YsJtM</a></p>  — Michael go vroom (@Iron_Stylus) <a href="https://twitter.com/Iron_Stylus/status/1831084321811341816?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 3, 2024</a></blockquote>              </div><p>Ordinary gamers on social media also shared their thoughts on Concord's failure, and what it really means for the future of both live-service titles and original I.P. games.</p><div data-embed-type="tweet" data-src="https://x.com/OptimusHeim/status/1831105933960982748" data-has-image="false"><blockquote data-conversation="none" data-mce-disable-toolbar="true"><p dir="ltr">Hot take: It's bad that Concord failed. The PS5 era is known for sequels and remakes. The fact that a new I.P failed only means more sequels and remakes are coming.</p>  — Brandon S. (@OptimusHeim) <a href="https://twitter.com/OptimusHeim/status/1831105933960982748?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 3, 2024</a></blockquote>              </div><div data-embed-type="tweet" data-src="https://twitter.com/KrisWolfheart/status/1831066986312560838" data-has-image="false"><blockquote data-conversation="none" data-mce-disable-toolbar="true"><p dir="ltr">It isn't misguided or confused or destructive or any other stupid bullshit. Meanspirited? Maybe. But you know what's a lot more destructive in an actual material sense? Having hundreds if not thousands of people work on something for eight years that's been out of favor for four.</p>  — Kris Wolfheart (@KrisWolfheart) <a href="https://twitter.com/KrisWolfheart/status/1831066986312560838?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 3, 2024</a></blockquote>              </div><p>Meanwhile, Bloomberg reporter Jason Schreier and Christopher Dring took aim at gamers who celebrated Concord's demise because it featured a diverse lineup of characters.</p><div data-embed-type="tweet" data-src="https://twitter.com/jasonschreier/status/1831005817702670526" data-has-image="false"><blockquote data-conversation="none" data-mce-disable-toolbar="true"><p dir="ltr">Every time a live-service game with no hook or strong word of mouth fails to penetrate an oversaturated market, the most annoying people on the planet will be there to blame diversity</p>  — Jason Schreier (@jasonschreier) <a href="https://twitter.com/jasonschreier/status/1831005817702670526?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 3, 2024</a></blockquote>              </div><div data-embed-type="tweet" data-src="https://x.com/Chris_Dring/status/1831027939926069375" data-has-image="false"><blockquote data-conversation="none" data-mce-disable-toolbar="true"><p dir="ltr">Dear Fanboys. When a game on the console you don’t own doesn’t do very well, whether it’s Concord or Hellblade or NES World Championships, it’s not a win for you. Nobody won.</p>  — Christopher Dring (@Chris_Dring) <a href="https://twitter.com/Chris_Dring/status/1831027939926069375?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 3, 2024</a></blockquote>              </div><p>The prevailing theory among fans and some industry professionals is that Concord could eventually resurface as a free-to-play game.</p><div data-embed-type="tweet" data-src="https://x.com/GreyWolf513/status/1831105629517193262" data-has-image="false"><blockquote data-conversation="none" data-mce-disable-toolbar="true"><p dir="ltr">Thinking about this crazy Concord move i think it was the best for Sony. Pulling it and giving refunds, reskinning the game and relaunching next year as free to play is inevitable.</p>  — Superboy (@GreyWolf513) <a href="https://twitter.com/GreyWolf513/status/1831105629517193262?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 3, 2024</a></blockquote>              </div><p>In an ironic touch, Concord will be revisited in December as one of the episodes in Prime Video's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/deadpool-director-making-a-video-game-tv-series-and-its-not-what-you-think/1100-6525800/" data-ref-id="1100-6525800">Secret Level</a> anthology series.</p><div data-embed-type="tweet" data-src="https://x.com/ChristinaTasty/status/1831013555925098825" data-has-image="true"><blockquote data-conversation="none" data-mce-disable-toolbar="true"><p dir="ltr">This is just a reminder that when the Concord dedicated episode of this Amazon TV show releases, the game will have been dead and offline for three months. <a href="https://t.co/MvZoxLTi5P" rel="nofollow ">pic.twitter.com/MvZoxLTi5P</a></p>  — Christina Tasty (@ChristinaTasty) <a href="https://twitter.com/ChristinaTasty/status/1831013555925098825?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 3, 2024</a></blockquote>              </div><p>Some fans made jokes about Astro Bot taking over Concord's official page.</p><p>Washington Post video games reporter Gene Park notes that many of the remaining players in Concord are essentially killing their characters to level up and unlock the Platinum Trophy before it's unobtainable.</p><p>Concord will officially shut down on September 6.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Best Nintendo Switch Chargers to Power Your Console]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/best-nintendo-switch-charger</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-best-nintendo-switch-chargers-to-power-your-console.971343/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/best-nintendo-switch-charger<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>The Nintendo Switch is the most popular console out there. <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/with-switch-2-waiting-in-the-wings-nintendo-believes-the-og-switch-has-plenty-of-sales-left-in-it">Over 140 million units have been sold</a> to date worldwide, and the system is still pushing forward despite its age. With such a big presence in the market, there are naturally thousands of options to choose from when it comes to <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-nintendo-switch-accessories">Switch accessories</a>. That is especially true for chargers, as you cannot use your Nintendo Switch without one!</p><p>Whether you've just recently <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-times-to-buy-a-nintendo-switch">bought a Nintendo Switch</a> or recently lost the charger it came with, we've got you covered on which chargers are actually worth picking up. Whether you're constantly on the road or searching for something to use at home, check out our top picks for the best Nintendo Switch chargers below.</p><p id="best-overall"><h2 data-toc-title="Best Overall">1. Anker 67W USB-C Wall Charger</h2></p><h3>Best Overall Charger for Nintendo Switch</h3><div id="206651" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p><h3>Anker 67W USB C Wall Charger</h3></p></div><p>The Anker 67W USB-C Wall Charger is our pick for the best overall Nintendo Switch charger. At 67W, this charger is capable of charging your Switch in both handheld and docked mode. You can use this with either mode, which isn't the case for other chargers on this list outside of the official Nintendo Switch AC Adapter. </p><p>A big benefit of the 67W is this charger's use beyond the Switch console. You can use this to charge an iPhone, MacBook, laptop, and more. This can be a life saver when traveling, as you'll only need one charger block. It's worth mentioning that you will <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-usb-c-chargers-2024">need a USB-C cable</a> with this charger, as Anker does not provide one. </p><p id="best-official-charger"><h2 data-toc-title="Best Official Charger">2. Nintendo Switch AC Adapter</h2></p><h3>Best Official Charger for Nintendo Switch</h3><div id="206520" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p><h3>Nintendo Switch AC Adapter</h3></p><div><p>You can't go wrong with old reliable.</p></div></div>The Nintendo Switch AC Adapter is by far the best official charger for Nintendo Switch. This is the same exact charger that's bundled in with every Switch system, so it's easy to order a replacement if needed. Outputting at 39W, the Nintendo Switch AC Adapter connects to any 120V outlet with no issues.<p>Since the charger is made specifically for Nintendo Switch, you will never have to wonder or worry about a potential compatibility mismatch. Sometimes, using a third-party charger can hurt your charging port, or even brick your system if you aren't careful. Staying official when it comes to chargers is always recommended, with the exception of reputable and reliable third party brands like the ones we've listed here.</p><p id="best-portable-charger"><h2 data-toc-title="Best Portable Charger">3. Emperor of Gadgets Portable Power Bank</h2></p><h3>Best Portable Charger for Nintendo Switch</h3><div id="195733" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p><h3>Emperor of Gadgets Portable Power Bank</h3></p><div><p>Top off your Switch with a 10,000mAh portable battery that straps onto it while offering a built-in USB-C and additional ports to charge other devices. </p></div></div>As outlined in our picks for the <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-portable-charger">best portable chargers</a>, the Emperor of Gadgets Portable Power Bank is the best portable charger for Nintendo Switch. This device has the ability to directly clip on to the back of your system, so there's never any worry of a dangling cable tied to a power bank. While it adds some noticeable weight, the power bank is nowhere heavy enough to make long playing sessions uncomfortable.<p>The Emperor of Gadgets Portable Power Bank features a 10,000mAh capacity with an output of 15W, which is perfect for charging your Nintendo Switch while in use or in rest mode. Based on the Nintendo Switch power draw, you should be able to get around 10 extra hours of playtime depending on the game, which is a significant increase from the built-in Switch battery.</p><p id="best-battery-case"><h2 data-toc-title="Best Battery Case">4. Newdery External Battery Station</h2></p><h3>Best Battery Case for Nintendo Switch</h3><div id="181248" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p><h3>NEWDERY External Battery Station</h3></p><div><p>This case has an integrated 10,000mAh battery to keep the Switch topped up without interfering with your gameplay. </p></div></div>The Newdery External Battery Station is our pick for the <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-nintendo-switch-battery-case">best battery case for Nintendo Switch</a>. This case provides a 10,000mAh battery in addition to the Switch's built-in battery, allowing for up to eight hours of additional playtime in handheld mode. If you're someone who exclusively plays in handheld mode or likes to travel, this can be an absolute game changer, especially when you're in the middle of an RPG like <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2017/11/30/xenoblade-chronicles-2-review">Xenoblade Chronicles 2</a> or <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-legend-of-zelda-tears-of-the-kingdom-review">The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom</a>.<p>Beyond battery life, the Newdery External Battery Station is simply comfortable to hold. The grip behind the Joy-Cons is extended, allowing for all players to be comfortable during long play sessions. Additionally, the case features a built-in kickstand, which reveals a compartment to store extra game cartridges on the go.</p><p id="best-car-charger"><h2 data-toc-title="Best Car Charger">5. PowerA Nintendo Switch Car Charger</h2></p><h3>Best Car Charger for Nintendo Switch</h3><div id="206591" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p><h3>PowerA Nintendo Switch Car Charger</h3></p></div>The PowerA Nintendo Switch Car Charger is the ultimate charger if you're ready to break out your system on the road. First, the cable itself is braided, which is essential for use in a car. Plastic cables are often easily broken through regular wear and tear, but braided cables will last twice as long usually. Additionally, this product is officially licensed by Nintendo, meaning that you can trust the charger without worry of overvolting or damaging your system.<p>This cable is 6 feet long, which should be plenty to reach in either the passenger seat or backseat even. The 5V connector will plug into any 5V adapter, which is present on almost every single car manufactured. Whether you need to charge the Nintendo Switch itself or a <a href="https://www.ign.com/tech/nintendo-switch-pro-controller">Pro Controller</a>, the PowerA Nintendo Switch Car Charger is perfect for a speedy charge in the car.</p><h2>Nintendo Switch Charger FAQs</h2><h3>What type of charger works best for Switch?</h3><p>The regular and <a href="https://www.ign.com/tech/nintendo-switch-oled-model">OLED Nintendo Switch model</a> draw <strong>a max of 18W of power at a time</strong>, while the Nintendo <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/nintendo-switch-lite">Switch Lite</a> draws 13.5W. While this is the limit of the system in handheld mode, the official Nintendo Switch charger included with the system allows for up to 39W of power draw. This is largely used when the system is docked or charging controllers through the USB ports. </p><p>As a result, the Nintendo Switch is unable to draw more than the wattage outlined above. This means that even if you use a 65W charger or above, your Switch will not draw more than the 18W it needs to charge. </p><h3>Do Joy-Cons need a separate charger?</h3><p>Fortunately, the Switch Joy-Cons do not need any charger to charge. They will receive power from the Nintendo Switch itself, which is charged through the USB-C port. So, you only need to purchase one charger for both the <a href="https://www.ign.com/tech/nintendo-switch-joy-cons">Joy-Con controllers</a> and Nintendo Switch.</p><p>It is important to note, though, that the Joy-Con can only be charged when attached to the side of the Nintendo Switch. These controllers do not have a USB-C port, therefore you cannot use a Switch charger to charge them. If you'd like to charge the Joy-Con when not attached to the Switch, you will need to purchase a <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-switch-gets-official-joy-con-charging-stand-over-7-years-after-launch">Joy-Con charging dock</a>.</p><p><em>Noah Hunter is a freelance writer and reviewer with a passion for games and technology. He co-founded Final Weapon, an outlet focused on nonsense-free Japanese gaming (in 2019) and has contributed to various publishers writing about the medium. His favorite series include Xeno, Fate, and Final Fantasy.</em>
</p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dragon Age: The Veilguard Changes How Some Side Quests Work]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/dragon-age-the-veilguard-changes-how-some-side-quests-work/1100-6526246/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dragon-age-the-veilguard-changes-how-some-side-quests-work.971340/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/dragon-age-the-veilguard-changes-how-some-side-quests-work/1100-6526246/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6526246">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Later this fall, BioWare and EA's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/dragon-age-4-given-official-name-dragon-age-dreadwolf/1100-6504067/" data-ref-id="1100-6504067">Dragon Age: The Veilguard</a> will finally give gamers a look at how the world of Thedas has changed in the decade since <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/dragon-age-inquisition-the-descent-review/1900-6416222/" data-ref-id="1900-6416222">Dragon Age: Inquisition</a> took place. But if the latest extended gameplay preview is any indication, Thedas hasn't been changed for the better. However, the storytelling of the game itself appears to be more refined.</p><p>Via <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/dragon-age-the-veilguard-watch-22-minutes-of-exclusive-gameplay-diving-into-exploration-and-more-ign-first" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">IGN</a>, The Veilguard co-directors Corinne Busche and John Epler hosted a 22-minute gameplay video that takes place deep into the story. In this side quest, the player character, Rook, agrees to help his companion, Davrin, complete a personal mission of revenge. The directors also pick up two additional side quests to procure medical supplies for the Grey Wardens and to locate a few of their missing members. This was meant to illustrate that these missions are more organically placed in the story, rather than unrelated events.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xGMMK2I30-o" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/xGMMK2I30-o" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>Additionally, the Crossroads is no longer a place of refuge thanks to the war between the game's antagonist, Solas, and the gods. Rook and his companions have to fight their way through the area before they arrive at Hossberg, an area that has been overrun by the Blight.</p><p>Thanks to the Blight, the Darkspawn enemies are much more formidable in this preview, and Rook even perishes at one point before getting revived. The directors noted that they are giving the companions more autonomy in their character arcs, as demonstrated by Davrin separating himself from the player's party to go on ahead to confront his nemesis, the Gloom Howler.</p><p>Among the other details, faction shops--including the Grey Warden's--can be upgraded to give the players more enticing rewards. The areas are also designed to be revisited after the missions, if gamers are interested in searching for hidden secrets and treasures. </p><p>Dragon Age: The Veilguard will be released on Xbox Series X|S, PlayStation 5, and PC on October 31.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A New Sea Of Thieves Graphic Novel Released This Week]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/a-new-sea-of-thieves-graphic-novel-released-this-week/1100-6526228/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/a-new-sea-of-thieves-graphic-novel-released-this-week.971328/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/a-new-sea-of-thieves-graphic-novel-released-this-week/1100-6526228/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6526228">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Sea of Thieves fans who want to spend time in Rare's world of pirates, buried treasure, and high-sea hijinks can do just that with the latest official graphic novel published by Titan Comics. Sea of Thieves: Sea Dog's Search released today, September 3, and is available for $14 (was $15) at Amazon. Sea Dog's Search joins a varied lineup of books based on the hit game, including three other graphic novels as well as a pair of traditional novels.</p><h2>Sea of Thieves novels and story collections</h2><ul><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/1683834879?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Sea of Thieves: Athena's Fortune</a> -- $15 ($<strike>17</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Sea-Thieves-Heart-Chris-Allcock/dp/1803362065?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Sea of Thieves Heart of Fire</a> -- $16</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Tales-Sea-Thieves-Paul-Davis/dp/1785654314?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Tales from the Sea of Thieves</a> -- $22.40 ($<strike>30</strike>)</li></ul><p>Two full-length novels set in the world of Sea of Thieves have been published since the game's launch. Written by Chris Allcock, <strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/1683834879?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Sea of Thieves: Athena's Fortune (2018)</a></strong> tells the story of how the infamous pirate Ramsey and his shipmates sacrificed everything to embark on an impossible journey. Fast-forward to the modern era of the game, and the second part of the novel focuses on an ambitious stowaway determined to leave her mark on history, leading her to join forces with a wild and adventurous captain seeking the greatest treasure ever buried.</p><p>The second novel, <strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Sea-Thieves-Heart-Chris-Allcock/dp/1803362065?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Sea of Thieves: Heart of Fire (2022)</a></strong>, recounts the pulse-pounding origin story of Captain Flameheart, a ruthless warmonger and captain of the Burning Blade who haunts the seas. Both novels have been well-received by Sea of Thieves fans. Athena's Fortune is a 264-page paperback for $15 (was $17), while Heart of Fire is a 320-page paperback for $16.</p><p>If you haven't read it yet, <strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Tales-Sea-Thieves-Paul-Davis/dp/1785654314?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Tales from the Sea of Thieves</a></strong>, which launched alongside the game in 2018, is a fun read that's worth picking up. It's told from the perspective of three pirate captains and includes sea shanties, illustrations, and sketches by the pirates and their crew.</p><h2>Sea of Thieves tabletop games</h2><ul><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Sea-Thieves-MGP70000-Mongoose-Publishing/dp/1913076032?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Sea of Thieves RPG</a> -- $80</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Steamforged-Games-Thieves-Board-Game/dp/B0C6MY7XDM?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Sea of Thieves: Voyages of Legends</a> -- $43</li></ul><p>The Sea of Thieves franchise also includes two games that <em>aren't </em>video games. Released in 2020, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Sea-Thieves-MGP70000-Mongoose-Publishing/dp/1913076032?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Sea of Thieves RPG</a> is a tabletop role-playing game that comes with everything you need to start playing, including three books (Lore, Pirates, Voyages), a map, weapon and quest cards, personality cards, supply tokens, and six-sided dice. Created by Mongoose Publishing, Sea of Thieves RPG is designed to be a fast-paced and approachable tabletop game.</p><p>For a traditional board game, check out <strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Steamforged-Games-Thieves-Board-Game/dp/B0C6MY7XDM?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Sea of Thieves: Voyages of Legends</a></strong> from Steamforged Games. This competitive seafaring game released last year and is playable with two to four players. You can pick up Voyages of Legends for $42.62 at <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Steamforged-Games-Thieves-Board-Game/dp/B0C6MY7XDM?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Amazon</a>.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1595/15950357/4361193-seaofthievesrpg.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4361193" data-ratio="0.557" data-width="1000" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1595/15950357/4361193-seaofthievesrpg.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4361193"></a><figcaption>Sea of Thieves RPG</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1595/15950357/4361193-seaofthievesrpg.jpg"></figure>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/108490194306897153177?rel=author">Darryn Bonthuys</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BattleTech and Shadowrun studio Harebrained Schemes' first post-Paradox game is sci-fi horror RPG Graft]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/battletech-studio-harebrained-schemes-first-post-paradox-game-is-sci-fi-horror-rpg-graft</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/battletech-and-shadowrun-studio-harebrained-schemes-first-post-paradox-game-is-sci-fi-horror-rpg-graft.971325/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/battletech-studio-harebrained-schemes-first-post-paradox-game-is-sci-fi-horror-rpg-graft<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/graft-crop.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Harebrained Schemes</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
Battletech, <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/shadowrun">Shadowrun</a>, and The Lamplighters League developer Harebrained Schemes has announced its first project since parting ways with Paradox Interactive last year. It's a "post-cyberpunk survival horror RPG" called Graft and it's heading to PC.
</p>
<p>
Graft's story unfolds in the depths of a decaying continent-sized space station known as the Arc, home to forgotten technologies and unsettling wonders. Players must brave its horrors as they traverse "massive chasms, labyrinthine techno-catacombs, and self-replicating corridors", facing enemies in combat - including "ancient experiments, monstrous abominations, and relentless agents of a mad AI" - and Grafting as they go.
</p>
<p>
This is pretty much exactly what it sounds like, requiring players to scavenge body parts from fallen opponents and graft them onto themselves in order to alter their physical form, gaining new abilities and powers as they do. But Grafting a part also infuses players with its previous owner's memories, creating what Harebrained calls a "haunting interplay of survival, transformation, and self-discovery".
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="GRAFT by Harebrained — Official Announcement Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/YhQZYJkfe8w?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>GRAFT by Harebrained — Official Announcement Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/YhQZYJkfe8w?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/YhQZYJkfe8w?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Graft announcement trailer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YhQZYJkfe8w" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
"Form alliances, build trust, and face the reality that anyone still living could be both an ally and a threat," teases the studio. "Your decisions will shape your journey and determine the fate of those you encounter...  Will you escape the Arc with your humanity intact, or become something else entirely?"
</p>
<p>
There's no hint of a release date for Graft, but Harebrained is currently aiming to launch it via the <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/en-US/p/graft-c7e6c4">Epic Games Store</a> and <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3141390/GRAFT/">Steam</a>. It'll be the studio's first release since last year's <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-lamplighters-league-review-rip-roaring-tactical-adventure-let-down-by-dreadful-real-time-stealth">flawed by entertaining</a> turn-based strategy game The Lamplighter's League, which publisher Paradox Interactive <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/paradox-declares-pulp-strategy-the-lamplighters-league-a-22m-flop">later declared a $22m flop</a>.
</p>
<p>
That announcement was followed by the news Paradox was <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/paradox-and-harebrained-schemes-parting-ways-following-the-lamplighters-league-flop">parting ways</a> with Harebrained Schemes - which it had <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/paradox-interactive-acquires-battletech-developer-harebrained-schemes">acquired back in 2018</a> following the release of <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/battletech">BattleTech</a> - with the publisher retaining the rights to The Lamplighters League, BattleTech, <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/necropolis">Necropolis</a>, and the <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/shadowrun-trilogy">Shadowrun Trilogy</a>.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Concord Shows That The Triple-A Pivot To Live Service Was Always Doomed]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/sony-concord-shutdown-offline-refund-ps5-pc-live-service</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/concord-shows-that-the-triple-a-pivot-to-live-service-was-always-doomed.971319/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://aftermath.site/sony-concord-shutdown-offline-refund-ps5-pc-live-service<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Concord</em>, the latest game in Sony’s ongoing live service salvo, came out a week and a half ago. Already, the writing was on the wall. There was no buzz. It just didn’t have the juice. Still, nobody was prepared for what happened today: <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2024/09/03/an-important-update-on-concord/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Sony announced</a> that it plans to pull the game from stores and offer refunds to anybody who bought it. <em>Concord </em>was smothered as it clambered out of the cradle – the ultimate object lesson in what happens when triple-A behemoths commit to live service for live service’s sake, despite the ever-increasing production demands of big-budget video games.</p><p><em>Concord </em>faltered for many reasons. Despite what the most irritatingly ill-informed people on the internet are saying, <a href="https://x.com/jasonschreier/status/1831005817702670526" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">diversity didn’t do it in</a>. Instead, eight years ago the game set off down what would become an impossible path, iterating on hero shooter concepts that were in vogue at the time and arriving looking polished but <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/fps/concord-review/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">feeling rusty</a>. In the time since <em>Concord </em>began development, <em>Overwatch </em>rose and fell, the battle royale boom redefined multiplayer shooters and petered out, extraction shooters became a thing, and an endless procession of competitive shooter hopefuls crashed and burned while a small handful – <em>Valorant</em>, <em>Apex Legends</em>, and <em>Escape from Tarkov</em> among them – carved out enduring fiefdoms.&nbsp;</p><p><em>Concord </em>entered a massively competitive playing field feeling dated on day one, having to justify itself not just against other shooters, but popular live service games in general, whose audiences only tend to rove <a href="https://aftermath.site/aftermath-hours-podcast-concord-failure-sony-steam" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">when their friends start sniffing at greener pastures</a>. This is why Sony’s plan to release 12 live service games by 2026 – which <a href="https://www.polygon.com/23954006/sony-playstation-live-service-games-marathon-last-of-us-factions" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">got cut in half late last year</a> – never made much sense. Live-service games do not automatically print money. On the contrary, between regular upkeep and constant streams of new content, they are hugely costly, as <a href="https://x.com/cecianasta/status/1831050133439758576" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">even titans like <em>Roblox </em>can attest</a>. Attracting an audience – especially with no immediately-apparent hook beyond triple-A production values – is hard, and keeping it is even harder. Perhaps Sony imagined one or two smash live-service hits would ultimately balance out the odd miss here or there, but at this scale – with so many careers on the line – that’s an unconscionably risky gamble.&nbsp;</p><p>This is hardly a problem exclusive to competitive live-service games. <em>Starfield</em>, which shared a similarly lengthy incubation period to <em>Concord</em>, launched last year feeling like it emerged from a time capsule. <em>Suicide Squad</em>, which attempted to satisfy lovers of both traditional narrative-driven games and live-service grind-a-thons, only succeeded in <a href="https://aftermath.site/suicide-squad-discourse-impressions-live-service" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">letting everyone down</a>. Layoffs <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/rocksteady-hit-by-layoffs-after-suicide-squad-kill-the-justice-league-underperforms" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">recently followed</a>. The latter found itself clinging to the wreckage of basically the same Titanic as <em>Concord</em>: Beyond triple-A production values, it couldn’t justify its own existence.&nbsp;</p><p>And yet, it’s little wonder why major video game publishers keep trying to squeeze blood from this particular stone. With triple-A games taking <a href="https://aftermath.site/big-budget-game-development-is-not-sustainable" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">more time, money, and manpower than ever to make</a>, they want the biggest, longest-lasting return on investment possible. But big publishers’ approach to live service is an unsustainable solution born of unsustainable development practices. The arms race to make bigger, longer games – with more <a href="https://kotaku.com/star-wars-outlaws-stealth-bugs-ubisoft-1851637931" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">impossibly-detailed hallways</a> that most players won’t even blink at – is a dead end. It has been all along. Papering over that with a business model that only <em>appears </em>to generate infinite revenue will not, in the overwhelming majority of cases, fix this fundamental problem. Most games in this mold will struggle to break even, and even the success stories will fall into <a href="https://aftermath.site/helldivers-2-flamethrower-nerf-controversy-live-service" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the live-service death spiral</a>, a miasmatic pit of community toxicity that burns out developers and inspires reactive design decisions over anything truly inspired or forward thinking.</p><p>This is not to say that new live-service games cannot succeed; you just have to be creative about it in ways that big companies are loath to embrace. Most indies now launch ambitious, community-driven games in early access – <em>real </em>early access, where major features and chunks of content are missing, rather than money-grubbing “pre-order now!” early access that does not actually allow for feedback or substantial changes before release. Valve, which played a pioneering role in giving developers the tools to do this, is now taking cues from the scene it’s cultivated, stealth-dropping its own hero shooter, <a href="https://aftermath.site/valve-deadlock-verge" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Deadlock</em></a>, in earlier-than-early access and attracting a sizable player base in the process.&nbsp;</p><p>But this approach is antithetical to major publishers’ addictions to secrecy and long lead times, as well as endless marketing drip feeds and elaborate pre-order bundles. Moreover, it still doesn’t address the elephant in the room: Big-budget game development is not sustainable, nor does it serve an apparent need. Games don’t have to be enormous; most players only experience a fraction of them. Triple-A fidelity has become a fool’s errand; <a href="https://aftermath.site/call-duty-modern-warfare-impressions" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">games from more than a decade ago</a> still look great now. Developers at envelope-pushing studios like <em>Spider-Man</em> developer Insomniac <a href="https://kotaku.com/what-hacked-files-tell-us-about-the-studio-behind-spide-1851115233" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">do not believe players notice</a> the fruits of billowing budgets -- at least, not enough to make the additional investment worthwhile.</p><p>It’s <a href="https://knowyourmeme.com/memes/i-want-shorter-games-with-worse-graphics-and-im-not-kidding" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a cliche</a> to ask for shorter games with worse graphics, but I don’t think there’s any other <em>actual </em>solution to this problem. Triple-A games have become too costly, both in terms of money and a harder-to-measure though far more important human toll. As <em>Concord </em>and <a href="https://aftermath.site/bungie-layoffs-destiny" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">other games like <em>Destiny 2</em></a> have shown us, live service is not a silver bullet. In fact, it can <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/bungie-report-battle-soul-work-culture-harassment-crunch" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">exacerbate these issues</a>. Every major release is now a potential catastrophe – a bomb waiting to go off, the fuse of which was lit the better part of a decade ago. The triple-A video game industry can’t go on like this. If it keeps blowing up its own foundations, it will destroy itself. Change is still possible, but as we’ve learned from <em>Concord</em>, it needed to happen yesterday. That’s no longer possible, so I guess we’ll have to settle for tomorrow.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dragon Quest III HD-2D Remake Gamescom Hands-On Preview – Pixel Excellence]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/dragon-quest-iii-hd-2d-remake-gamescom-hands-on-pixel-excellence/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dragon-quest-iii-hd-2d-remake-gamescom-hands-on-preview-%E2%80%93-pixel-excellence.971310/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/dragon-quest-iii-hd-2d-remake-gamescom-hands-on-pixel-excellence/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p><a href="https://dragonquest.square-enix-games.com/games/en-us/dragon-quest-123-hd2d-remakes/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Dragon Quest III HD-2D Remake</a> has been in the works for quite some time, and it took a few years since its announcement to get a first proper look at the very first entry in a series of remakes that will allow players to experience the entirety of the Erdrick trilogy on modern gaming hardware. With the game right around the corner, Square Enix offered us a chance to try out the game during Gamescom in a short session that did not fail to show how the game is setting out to be among the best HD-2D games ever released.</p>
<p>The Gamescom 2024 demo threw players a few hours into the adventure into the town of Romaria, specifically in the Monster Arena, which has been overhauled for the remake to allow players to have a more active role in monster vs monster combat. Winning matches will provide the hero and his companions with some useful items, so I expect more than a few players will be spending quite a few hours here trying to get all the rewards.</p>
<p>Once I was done with my business at the Monster Arena, I had the chance to explore the town of Romaria, and speak with the king, who enlists the hero to recover his crown from the thieves that stole it. After accepting the task, I explored the town a little more, stocking on supplies, purchasing better weapons and gear for my party members, and appreciating the excellent recreation of the town in the HD-2D style. The game as a whole looked lively and positively vibrant, especially on the Nintendo Switch OLED, where the colors really looked incredible.</p>
<figure>
<div>

<div>
		
		
		<p><span>2 of 9</span>
	</p></div></div>
</figure>


<p>Despite having accepted the request of the king, I decided to wander around and see what else the Dragon Quest III HD-2D Remake demo had to offer. I ended up exploring a few dungeons briefly in the surroundings of Romaria and fighting against a few enemies. The original game's turn-based combat system has been left virtually untouched, though now the characters appear on screen when choosing commands. Some welcome additions include the ability to speed up combat, which is sure to help the game's pacing considerably, though I found the encounter rate to be fair, for the most part, and the ability to set up tactics and change auto-battle settings, which should make random encounters even faster to complete. As one of my party members came with the new Monster Wrangler vocation, I was able to briefly try some of its abilities out, and it felt powerful enough. Difficulty, in general, was on the low side, but that was most likely caused by the leveled-up characters that were provided for the demo. The final game will feature multiple difficulty settings, so players will easily be able to tailor the general difficulty level to their skill level.</p>
<p>Having only played through Dragon Quest III years ago, I really can't say if there have been big changes to locations, treasure chest locations, and the like in the remake, but even so, it is undeniable that Dragon Quest III HD-2D Remake is likely going to set a new bar for faithful remakes of classic JRPGs. Thankfully, it won't take much longer to be able to delve deeper into the story of Ortega and his child, as the game launches in just a few months, on November 14th on PC, PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X, Xbox Series S and Nintendo Switch worldwide.</p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Windows 11’s new gamepad keyboard lets you type with an Xbox controller]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2024/9/3/24235291/microsoft-windows-11-gamepad-keyboard-xbox-controller</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/windows-11%E2%80%99s-new-gamepad-keyboard-lets-you-type-with-an-xbox-controller.971307/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/2024/9/3/24235291/microsoft-windows-11-gamepad-keyboard-xbox-controller<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Microsoft has started testing a new gamepad keyboard layout in Windows 11 that’s designed for Xbox controllers. The gamepad keyboard layout improves the on-screen keyboard in Windows 11, so you can use an Xbox controller to type or navigate around the OS.</p><p>The gamepad keyboard is <a href="https://blogs.windows.com/windows-insider/2024/08/30/announcing-windows-11-insider-preview-build-22635-4145-beta-channel/">now in testing</a> as part of the beta channel for Windows 11 and even includes button accelerators so you can use the X button for backspace, the Y button for spacebar, and the menu button on an Xbox controller to hit enter. The keyboard keys have also been vertically aligned, so it’s easier to type with a controller.</p><div><figcaption><em>Microsoft’s new gamepad keyboard for Windows 11.</em></figcaption> <p><cite>Image: Microsoft</cite></p></div><p>It’s encouraging to see Microsoft add a feature like this, particularly as Windows-powered handheld devices need these types of improvements. I wrote last month that Microsoft is now in a <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/8/15/24221036/microsoft-xbox-handheld-pc-gaming-valve-steamos">handheld gaming PC race against Valve</a> as the Steam Deck maker gets ready to capitalize on its SteamOS work and bring it to more Windows-powered handhelds. </p><p>Microsoft still needs to address basic things, like not being able to log into Windows with a controller or not getting the on-screen keyboard when you tap into text fields. Hopefully, this new gamepad keyboard is a step in the right direction, but we still need to see a lot more. </p><p>Microsoft is also making its <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/8/13/24219741/microsoft-windows-game-bar-xbox-handheld">Windows Game Bar more handheld-friendly</a>, with a compact mode that’s designed for smaller screens. It follows a similar compact mode for the main Xbox app on PC. Microsoft has also made <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/5/8/24152252/microsoft-xbox-handheld-compact-mode-controller-improvements">controller improvements to the Xbox app</a>, making it easier to navigate around the app with just an Xbox controller.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NVIDIA GeForce RTX 50 Series To Consume More Power Than 40 Series]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/nvidia-geforce-rtx-50-series-to-consume-more-power-than-40-series/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nvidia-geforce-rtx-50-series-to-consume-more-power-than-40-series.971298/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/nvidia-geforce-rtx-50-series-to-consume-more-power-than-40-series/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>The upcoming NVIDIA GeForce RTX 50 series, including the 5080 and others, is rumored to consume more power than the current 40 series, with up to a 33% increase in power consumption in some of the graphics cards. </p>



<p>It has been rumored for quite some time now that the GeForce RTX 50 series would consume more power, but a well-trusted leaker recently revealed on Twitter that the new graphics cards most definitely would require more energy to run.</p>



<h2 id="h-twitter-leaker-reveals-that-geforce-rtx-50-series-will-consume-more-power-than-40-series">Twitter Leaker Reveals That GeForce RTX 50 Series Will Consume More Power Than 40 Series</h2>



<p>The GeForce RTX 4080 and other cards in the 40 series already consume quite a bit of power when in use, meaning the 50 series will really be pushing the boundaries with power consumption.</p>



<p>This has already provided a bit of backlash amongst NVIDIA GeForce fans, as many wish for the company to work on efficiency over power consumption.</p>



<figure></figure>







<p>“I know someone who got the details of GeForce of Blackwell recently,” said kopite7kimi, a Twitter leaker. “Both of them have some increase in power consumption, with higher SKUs.”</p>



<p>Then when a comment on his post said “I say 550W for 5090,” the leaker responded with “more.” This would mean more than a 100W increase from the 4090, which was at 450W. We are looking at some heavy increases in power usage for these new graphics cards.</p>



<h2 id="h-when-will-the-50-series-release">When Will The 50 Series Release?</h2>



<p>As of now, there is only a tiny bit of information out there regarding the NVIDIA GeForce 50 series. Despite the rumors that power consumption will be quite high, we do know that there is a possibility we will see the graphics cards showcased at CES 2025, next year.</p>



<p>For now, though, tech and gaming enthusiasts will have to wait for more additional details on the 50 series.</p>



<p>Stay tuned to Insider Gaming for more tech news.</p>




    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>
    
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shinji Mikami Thinks Modern Games Take Themselves Too Seriously, And Shadows Of The Damned Shows He's Right]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/shinji-mikami-thinks-modern-games-are-too-serious-shadows-of-the-damned/1100-6526245/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/shinji-mikami-thinks-modern-games-take-themselves-too-seriously-and-shadows-of-the-damned-shows-hes-right.971295/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/shinji-mikami-thinks-modern-games-are-too-serious-shadows-of-the-damned/1100-6526245/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="">

            
          
  

<section><p>Shadows of the Damned: Hella Remastered is a confident reminder that this 13-year-old cult classic still has life in an era of gaming that tends to take itself a bit too seriously.</p></section>
        
        
                    
              <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Shadows of the Damned is a game where protagonist Garcia Hotspur's gun is called the Boner, and he refers to vine-like blockades in the hell as "demon pubes." It's a game that confidently wears its video-game-y-ness on its purple leather studded sleeve, right next to Joy Division's lyrics "Love Will Tear Us Apart" painted in thick white paint. From demonic enemies whom burst with collectible diamonds after shooting their heads off, to bosses covered in big, obvious "please-shoot-here" weak points, Shadows of the Damned: Hella Remastered isn't just a reminder of its brash conviction in knowing its a video game or how un-seriously it takes itself, but a window into how far and <em>how little</em> video games have come since its original release in 2011.</p><p dir="ltr">Speaking with GameSpot at Gamescom 2024, producer and Resident Evil creator Shinji Mikami said, "[Shadows of the Damned] is aware that it's a video game, and it's not trying to be something else. There's a lot of games these days that tend to take themselves a bit too seriously."</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="1178101533" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6464955,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Shadows%20Of%20The%20Damned%3A%20Hella%20Remastered%20Is%20A%20Welcomed%20Reminder%20Of%20This%20Cult%20Classic%27s%20Confidence%20%7C%20gamescom%202024&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:503,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/shadows-of-the-damned-hella-remastered-is-a-welcomed-reminder-of-this-cult-classics-confidence-gamescom-2024\/2300-6464955\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464955\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464955\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464955\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6464955&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6464955,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;feature_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6526245&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;shadows-of-the-damned&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;action,adventure&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;playstation-3,xbox-360,nintendo-switch,pc,playstation-5,playstation-4,xbox-one,xbox-series-x&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;electronic-arts&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6464955},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6464955\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;GameSpot&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1823\/18237460\/4355744-shadowsofthedamned_site.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/JGQZd7Dl.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1724367600,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="JGQZd7Dl" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> Shadows Of The Damned: Hella Remastered Is A Welcomed Reminder Of This Cult Classic's Confidence | gamescom 2024</p>
      </div>
<p dir="ltr">When considering the state of action-horror games of recent, like last year's Resident Evil 4 remake or Alan Wake 2, there's an attention to detail and believability that both games feature in their combat and graphics. Both games have lifelike movement that add a sense of weight to your actions, offering realistic feedback regardless of if you're getting a hatchet to the face or shooting a hole through an enemy's head. The graphical fidelity of both games creates believable worlds that closely mirror our own. Shadows of the Damned: Hella Remastered has similar traits to both Resident Evil 4 remake and Alan Wake 2--the over-the-shoulder perspective, fending off enemy monstrosities, and even some puzzle elements--but it accomplishes it with a brighter color palette, cartoonish animations, and a don't-give-a-shit attitude that evokes its own flavor of confidence.</p><p dir="ltr">Shadows of the Damned adapted many of those traits from the original Resident Evil 4, also produced by Mikami, but it actually has more in common with Alan Wake 2 in terms of combat design. Both Alan Wake 2 and Shadows of the Damned require cleansing its enemies of a darkness-like presence before being able to deal damage, as well as have a dedicated melee attack and a dodge button. The difference is that Shadows of the Damned isn't mirroring a world we currently live in--instead, it's a colorful and vibrant hellscape, where you're drinking sake to heal yourself and feeding strawberries to demon babies to unlock doors.</p><blockquote data-size="large"><p>A lot of games, especially now with the specs available, they go for this sort of hyper-reality. We don't really care about hyper-reality.</p><cite>Goichi "Suda51" Suda</cite></blockquote><p dir="ltr">It was through this lens that it first occurred to me how little has actually changed in the action-horror genre in terms of combat over the last 13 years--an entertaining notion given how often some players regard the standard game-design practices from that era as "arcade-y."</p><p dir="ltr">"I feel that 13 years ago, when we were making the original [Shadows of the Damned], there were a lot of things in game development that were kind of just a given at the time," Mikimi-san explained. "'This is how you make games, this is what games are supposed to be like.' A lot of things have changed since then. There's a lot of stuff in Shadows of the Damned that's a lot more casual and comical, and it's just easy to enjoy without trying to take the game too seriously, or without the game taking itself too seriously as well. So hopefully that's something that'll resonate with modern-day players as something that isn't maybe seen as much as it used to be, because back in the day, that's just how video games were."</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1592/15929708/4361179-damned_screenshot_19_068eadd5.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4361179" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="3840" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1592/15929708/4361179-damned_screenshot_19_068eadd5.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4361179"></a><figcaption>Shadows of the Damned: Hella Remastered</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1592/15929708/4361179-damned_screenshot_19_068eadd5.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">Writer of Shadows of the Damned and founder of developer Grasshopper Manufacture Goichi "Suda51" Suda weighed in on the current state of realism in games today, saying, "I feel that a lot of games these days try really hard to go for a sense of reality. A lot of games, especially now with the specs available, they go for this sort of hyper-reality. We don't really care about hyper-reality."</p><p dir="ltr">For Grasshopper Manufacture, its philosophy is to present the game in "the most expressive way possible," according to Suda.</p><p dir="ltr">While Shadows of the Damned: Hella Remastered is getting a 4K overhaul to its resolution, it's hard to distinguish the game's visuals from its original 2011, and it's better off for it. The game's reliance on bright colors and exaggerated character movements has allowed it to stand the test of time. While deft art design can have that lasting effect, game design tends to show its age with time. But to my surprise, Shadows of Damned: Hella Remastered seems to be holding its own in this corner of the ring as well.</p><p dir="ltr">In the 30 minutes I played, I saw a wide array of enemy types, varied environmental puzzles, and a clever use of its light and dark mechanics that kept me on my toes. The whole chapter was carefully paced, and felt considerably honed in. All these elements were in the original, too, but I had forgotten over the 13 years since I last played it. It was a welcoming surprise--a feeling that Suda himself had as well when returning to his 2011 cult classic.</p><p dir="ltr">"There's definitely things that have changed the way I view the game and the things that I think I pick up on when I'm looking at the game now," Suda-san said. "One thing looking at the game now: I actually feel that it was a lot more well-made than I felt when it originally came out."</p><p dir="ltr">"We've got another project we're working on at the moment," Suda continued. "It's a new IP, and since we're working on that while also doing the remaster, you end up sort of comparing and contrasting. So when working on this new IP, going back to work on the [Shadows of the Damned] remaster at the same time, there's definitely things I picked up on now that I maybe didn't pick up on back at the time. Like, 'Oh, hey, this is maybe something we could have done a bit better, or this is something we could have changed.' And conversely, 'Oh, hey, this is something we can maybe take and kind of tweak to fit the new IP.'"</p><p dir="ltr">According to Suda, that was a "big nope" for Grasshopper Manufacturer.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1592/15929708/4361190-ss_73110f7c7c918d44d41659e03ed1ffd36004997e.1920x1080.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4361190" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1592/15929708/4361190-ss_73110f7c7c918d44d41659e03ed1ffd36004997e.1920x1080.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4361190"></a><figcaption>Shadows of the Damned: Hella Remastered</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1592/15929708/4361190-ss_73110f7c7c918d44d41659e03ed1ffd36004997e.1920x1080.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">"One of the main reasons that we wanted to put out the remaster was to get it on as many platforms as possible. Originally it was only on PS3 and Xbox 360, and if it was only gonna be on Origin, then that defeated the purpose, because it would further limit the number of people who would be able to play it."</p><p dir="ltr">It wasn't until Grasshopper Manufacture partnered with its current parent company NetEase--and after Origin was no longer a major focus for EA's distribution--that the studio was able to work out a deal that granted it both the rights for the remaster and the game's distribution.</p><p dir="ltr">Until now, Shadows of the Damned was only playable if you have a physical copy of the game, which severely limits its availability for new players to access the cult classic. Thankfully, Shadows of the Damned: Hella Remastered is expected to release October 31 for all modern platforms and PC.</p>
  
                                                              </div>
    

              <div>
  <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>
  
    </div>
      
        
        
  
              


  

    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vampire: The Masquerade's visual novel series concludes next week in Reckoning of New York]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/vampire-the-masquerades-visual-novel-series-concludes-next-week-in-reckoning-of-new-york</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/vampire-the-masquerades-visual-novel-series-concludes-next-week-in-reckoning-of-new-york.971292/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/vampire-the-masquerades-visual-novel-series-concludes-next-week-in-reckoning-of-new-york<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>On PlayStation, Xbox, Switch, and PC.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/vampire-the-masquerade-reckoning-of-new-york-crop.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Draw Distance/Dear Villagers</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
Vampire: The Masquerade's trilogy of New York themed visual novels is set to conclude next Tuesday, 10th September, with Reckoning of New York on PlayStation, Xbox, Switch, and PC.
</p>
<p>
Vampire: The Masquerade – Reckoning of New York, from developer Draw Distance, wraps up a tale that began with <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/vampire-the-masquerade-coteries-of-new-york-reveals-new-details-on-its-telltale-like-adventure">2019's Coteries of New York</a> and continued a year later in Shadows of New York. This time around, the story unfolds against a backdrop of the modern-day city, where "the delicate balance of power hangs by a thread".
</p>
<p>
"Navigate the treacherous waters of vampiric politics as you contend with the ever-shifting landscape between the Camarilla and Anarchs," teases Draw Distance. "In a city where every move could mean the difference between unlife and final death, will you carve out your own destiny amidst the chaos or will your ambition spell your doom?"
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="VAMPIRE: THE MASQUERADE - Reckoning of New York Reveal Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/-6Pyaj8mMp4?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>VAMPIRE: THE MASQUERADE - Reckoning of New York Reveal Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/-6Pyaj8mMp4?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/-6Pyaj8mMp4?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Vampire: The Masquerade – Reckoning of New York trailer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-6Pyaj8mMp4" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
Reckoning of New York promises a journey of "discovery and deception" from two different perspectives, as well as a range of new gameplay mechanics. "Harness the powers of Disciplines to overcome challenges or evade the relentless pursuit of Hunters hot on your trail," explains Draw Distance. "But beware the insatiable Hunger that gnaws at your very being, threatening to unleash the primal Beast within."
</p>
<p>
Vampire: The Masquerade – Reckoning of New York will be available for <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/vampire-the-masquerade-reckoning-of-new-york/9mwqhhn14b2r">Xbox One</a>, <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-gb/concept/10009973">PlayStation 4</a>, Switch, and PC <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2658720/Vampire_The_Masquerade__Reckoning_of_New_York/">via Steam</a> when it launches on 10th September. And if you haven't played its two previous instalments, both are currently heavily discounted on Steam: Coteries of New York is <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1096410/Vampire_The_Masquerade__Coteries_of_New_York/">90 percent off</a> at £1.54, while Shadows of New York is <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1279630/Vampire_The_Masquerade__Shadows_of_New_York/">80 percent off</a> at £2.05.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Fallout 76 Update Launches Milepost Zero]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/new-fallout-76-update-launches-milepost-zero/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-fallout-76-update-launches-milepost-zero.971277/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/new-fallout-76-update-launches-milepost-zero/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The latest update for <a href="https://wccftech.com/fallout-76-passes-20-million-players-milestone-bethesda-is-planning-future-games/">Fallout 76</a> has been released, with players now able to explore Milepost Zero, a completely free update for Fallout 76 players across all platforms. This update introduces Legendary Crafting as well as a new C.A.M.P. feature called Best Builds, as well as tweaks to the combat system to make it more enjoyable. In addition to these updates, there will be a new questline for Fallout 76 players to explore in Milepost Zero, where they have to go on a trek with their Brahmin and begin a caravan delivery service in Skyline Valley.</p>
<p><iframe title="Fallout 76 - Season 18: Milepost Zero - Country Road" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/MXrFWx_jwKo?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>The new questline will be named "A Bump in the Road," which, as explained above will take players on the journey to have their own delivery service across the Shenandoah region while having to fight off raiders and creatures. On this questline, players will get to recruit companions of varying professions where you can then go on to build your own personal outpost where you get rewards.</p>
<p>For players to be able to utilize Legendary Crafting, they will need to be able to obtain the Mods that can be equipped onto the gear by either trading the Legendary Mod with another player or by scrapping Legendary items that you don't want that have the desired mod on them. This will allow players to upgrade their gear and give them better utility from their upgrades.</p>
<p>In addition to Legendary Crafting, the Best Builds system allows players to submit, visit, and rate other players' C.A.M.P.s.</p>
<p>One of the final things to be added to this Fallout 76 update is Season 18: Country Road. in this season, players can unlock new rewards from the Seasons pages such as the Blue Ridge Power Armor as well as Weapon Points and new themed C.A.M.P items.&nbsp; This new update comes with a four-month road map with the next major update and season coming in December. Before that, players can expect to see the Fallout Day Festivities taking place in October and the invaders returning in November, making it a stacked quarter for Fallout 76 players.</p>

<figure></figure>

<p>To showcase the latest update, Bethesda Softworks has released a trailer just over a minute that shows players what to expect from the Milepost Zero update. <a href="https://fallout.bethesda.net/en/article/6a0zxH7H8KwFTa5b0OlFxJ/season-18-milepost-zero-country-road" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The community calendar</a>, which is available on the Bethesda website for players to look at, goes into more detail about some of the events players can expect in the near future.</p>


				

			
	<div>
		<h2>Products mentioned in this post</h2>
		
		<!--<p class="story-notice text-center">The links above are affiliate links. As an Amazon Associate, Wccftech.com may earn from qualifying purchases.</p>-->
	</div>

			
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Head Of Valorant Esports Reveals Teams In Talks To Join VCT Partner Leagues]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/head-of-valorant-esports-reveals-teams-in-talks-to-join-vct-partner-leagues/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/head-of-valorant-esports-reveals-teams-in-talks-to-join-vct-partner-leagues.971268/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/head-of-valorant-esports-reveals-teams-in-talks-to-join-vct-partner-leagues/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		<figure></figure>


<p>The VCT is known for partnering with big Valorant esports teams, as Riot Games partnered with 30 different teams across three different leagues back in 2022. The esports teams partnered with VCT back then signed four-year contracts, with the chance to possibly resign in 2026.</p>



<p>Riot Games, though, could choose to sign different teams instead. </p>



<h2 id="h-vct-to-possibly-partner-with-new-valorant-esports-teams">VCT To Possibly Partner With New Valorant Esports Teams</h2>



<p>While there is still more than a year left before the 30 teams partnered with the VCT’s contracts expire, Riot Games is already looking at different esports organizations that they now consider to be first in line to join VCT’s partner leagues.</p>



<p>Leo Faria, the Global Head of Valorant Esports, made it known on social media that the company has its eye on quite a few teams for 2026 when it will be time to create new contracts.</p>



<figure></figure>







<p>“Teams still need to meet our criteria for partnership, but there’s no question that orgs in Challengers are the first in line whenever slots open up,” said Faria.</p>



<p>With quite a bit more competition ahead of Valorant teams in the future, there is still the possibility that new teams and players enter Challengers and catch the eye of Riot Games. </p>



<p>Currently, The Challengers League has quite a few teams involved, with players from various countries around the world.</p>



<h2 id="h-valorant-challengers-2024">Valorant Challengers 2024</h2>



<p>As of now, the 2024 Challengers League has some of the biggest teams in Valorant esports on its roster. With many tournaments to be held over the next year, though, we could see other teams qualify their way into the spotlight, possibly giving them a chance at getting a VCT partnership in 2026.</p>



<p>Some large names, such as TSM, are a part of Challengers: North American Split. Will we see many large teams as such acquire VCT partnerships in 2026? Or will the league feature many unexpected teams?</p>



<p>Stay tuned to Insider Gaming for more <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/category/esports/">esports news</a>.</p>




    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>
    
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Here Are the Space Marine 2 PC Requirements]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/here-are-the-space-marine-2-pc-requirements/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/here-are-the-space-marine-2-pc-requirements.971265/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/here-are-the-space-marine-2-pc-requirements/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Have you seen how positively gorgeous Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine 2 looks? From a distance, you can watch as many hundreds of Tyranids flow from the jungles to assault your position. But up close, everything oozes detail. It’s going to take a powerhouse of a gaming computer to run this one. Or is it? Here are the Space Marine 2 PC requirements!</p>



<h2 id="h-warhammer-40-000-space-marine-2-system-requirements">Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine 2 System Requirements</h2>



<p>On the low end, running Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine 2 on PC doesn’t appear too troubling. There are many gaming laptops that should handle the horde shooter relatively easily. But on the high end, you’ll want a beefier system to ramp up the graphics so that you can check out the Tyranids in all their inhuman glory.</p>



<h3 id="h-minimum-system-requirements">Minimum System Requirements</h3>



<ul>
<li><strong>OS</strong>: Windows 10/11 (64-bit)</li>



<li><strong>Processor</strong>: Intel Core i5 6800K / AMD Ryzen 5 2600X</li>



<li><strong>Graphics</strong>: Nvidia GeForce GTX 1060 / AMD Radeon RX 580</li>



<li><strong>Memory</strong>: 8 GB RAM</li>



<li><strong>DirectX</strong>: Version 12</li>



<li><strong>Storage</strong>: 75 GB (SSD Recommended)</li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-recommended-system-requirements">Recommended System Requirements</h3>



<ul>
<li><strong>OS</strong>: Windows 10/11 (64-bit)</li>



<li><strong>Processor</strong>: Intel Core i7-12700 / AMD Ryzen 7 5800X</li>



<li><strong>Graphics</strong>: Nvidia GeForce RTX 3070 / AMD Radeon RX 6800 XT</li>



<li><strong>Memory</strong>: 16 GB RAM</li>



<li><strong>DirectX</strong>: Version 12</li>



<li><strong>Storage</strong>: 75 GB (SSD Recommended)</li>
</ul>



<p>Do you think your system can handle the game?</p>







<h2 id="h-what-warhammer-games-to-play-while-you-wait">What Warhammer Games to Play While You Wait</h2>



<p>Whether your current gaming PC can run the game or not, you might find yourself itching to do battle with heretics and Xenos in the Warhammer universe. In that case, here are a few recommendations to play while you wait for the Space Marine 2 release date:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine</strong></li>



<li><strong>Warhammer 40,000: Inquisitor – Martyr</strong></li>



<li><strong>Warhammer 40,000: Darktide</strong></li>



<li><strong>Warhammer: Vermintide II</strong></li>
</ul>



<p>While you don’t have to play Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine before Space Marine 2, it’s highly recommended as you’ll encounter numerous characters, including our main character, Titus, from the first game.</p>



<hr>



<p>As we all prepare for the launch of Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine 2, take a moment to learn <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/space-marine-2-twitch-drops/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">how to get the Twitch Drops</a> from the game so that you can start with a few quality cosmetics for your weapons!</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>
    
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Here's When You'll Be Able To Play Warhammer 40,000: Space Marines 2]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/heres-when-youll-be-able-to-play-warhammer-40000-space-marines-2/1100-6526244/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/heres-when-youll-be-able-to-play-warhammer-40-000-space-marines-2.971262/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/heres-when-youll-be-able-to-play-warhammer-40000-space-marines-2/1100-6526244/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6526244">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">Players will soon be able to serve the Emperor of Mankind and slay heretics on his behalf when Saber Interactives <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/warhammer-40000-space-marine-ii/">Warhammer 40,000: Space Marines II</a> fully drops later next week. Some may be able to play a little bit earlier if they purchased the game's premium version.</p><h2 dir="ltr">Pre-loading availability</h2><p dir="ltr">Those playing on the Xbox Series X|S can start pre-loading the game now, no matter which version of the game they purchased. Those who purchased the Gold or Ultra edition for PlayStation 5 can also start pre-loading it now. However, if they purchase the standard edition on PlayStation 5, pre-loading will be available on September 7 at 9 AM PT / 12 PM ET. Those playing on PC will not be able to pre-load the game.</p><h2 dir="ltr">Early access for PC</h2><p dir="ltr">Those who purchased the Gold or Ultra edition will have full access to the game on September 5 or 6, depending on where they live. Below is a list of when it'll be available.</p><p dir="ltr"><strong>September 5</strong></p><ul><li dir="ltr">Los Angeles - 9 AM</li><li dir="ltr">Austin - 11 AM</li><li dir="ltr">New York - 12 PM</li><li dir="ltr">London - 5 PM</li></ul><p dir="ltr"><strong>September 6</strong></p><ul><li dir="ltr">Sydney - 2 AM</li><li dir="ltr">Auckland - 4 AM</li></ul><h2 dir="ltr">Early access for Console</h2><p dir="ltr">Like their PC counterparts, console players will also have early access to Space Marines II if they purchase the Gold or Ultra edition on September 5 and 6, but the times will vary slightly. Below is a list of when it'll go live.</p><p dir="ltr"><strong>September 5</strong></p><ul><li dir="ltr">Los Angeles - 6 AM</li><li dir="ltr">Austin - 8 AM</li><li dir="ltr">New York - 9 PM</li><li dir="ltr">London - 2 PM</li></ul><p dir="ltr"><strong>September 6</strong></p><ul><li dir="ltr">Sydney - 11 PM</li><li dir="ltr">Auckland 1 AM</li></ul><h2 dir="ltr">Standard release for Console and PC</h2><p dir="ltr">Players who purchased the game standard edition will have access to the game next on September 9 and September 10. Below is a list of when it'll go live.</p><p dir="ltr"><strong>September 9</strong></p><ul><li dir="ltr">Los Angeles - 9 AM</li><li dir="ltr">Austin - 11 AM</li><li dir="ltr">New York - 12 PM</li><li dir="ltr">London - 5 PM</li></ul><p dir="ltr"><strong>September 10</strong></p><ul><li dir="ltr">Sydney - 2 AM</li><li dir="ltr">Auckland - 4 AM</li></ul><p>Before Warhammer 40,000: Space Marines II comes out, check out <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/videos/essential-lore-you-need-to-know-before-space-marine-2/2300-6465039/">our story detailing the essential lore you need to know</a> before jumping into the game.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Get This Inventive Twist On The Murder Mystery Game In Humble’s Latest Bundle]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/humble-detectives-bundle-overboard-murder-mystery-sale-1851638984</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/get-this-inventive-twist-on-the-murder-mystery-game-in-humble%E2%80%99s-latest-bundle.971241/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/humble-detectives-bundle-overboard-murder-mystery-sale-1851638984<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Let’s say, hypothetically, that you killed your husband on a cruise from the UK to New York. How would you get away with it and walk off a free woman when the boat arrives at port? That delightfully thrilling premise is only the start of 2021’s <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/my-new-switch-obsession-is-a-game-about-covering-up-a-m-1847062474&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/my-new-switch-obsession-is-a-game-about-covering-up-a-m-1847062474"><em>Overboard!</em></a></span> It’s a murder mystery game that gives you the rare chance to take on the role of the murderer as you seek to throw an eccentric detective off your scent. <em>Overboard!</em>—and six other thrilling mystery games—are available as a package deal for ten dollars in the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.dpbolvw.net/click-8335294-14555742?sid=KT-&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.humblebundle.com%2Fgames%2Fdetectives-bundle&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.dpbolvw.net/click-8335294-14555742?sid=KT-&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.humblebundle.com%2Fgames%2Fdetectives-bundle" target="_blank" rel="sponsored noopener noreferrer nofollow noskim" data-vtas-click="self:InlineUrl:inline-url-postbody">Humble Detectives Bundle</a></span>, running until September 12th. If you’ve ever gotten a little too into true crime and detective stories, this is a can’t miss deal.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="197209" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="The Boys Star Karen Fukuhara On Kimiko’s Character Arc, Karate, And More" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="319" data-playlist="197209,196923,196922" data-current="197209"><div><p>The Boys Star Karen Fukuhara On Kimiko’s Character Arc, Karate, And More</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197209/197209_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197209/197209_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197209/197209_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197209/197209_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/22759.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>The start of <em>Overboard!</em> Begins with you throwing your husband into the watery depths to his death. That happens in the early morning of your final day at sea. What follows are eight in-game hours during which you must talk with the rest of the passengers and crew, find out any secrets or potential motives outside of your own, and cast suspicion on anybody that isn’t you so that you can start a new life in America. </p><p>Your first day will never go as well as you hope. A maid might catch you having an affair with the ship’s captain, you could uncover a stowaway on board, and more permutations and opportunities arise thanks to an incredibly dynamic mesh of systems. Each passenger has their own schedule which they follow like clockwork, and you must choose your activities carefully as every conversation and even moving between sections of the ship will make time pass. Eventually you’ll get caught on your first day and find yourself right back where you started.</p><figure id="" data-id="905ebd242e976d9939cdf960072e37c5" data-recommend-id="image://905ebd242e976d9939cdf960072e37c5" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A woman glances in a mirror and talks to herself about a missing earing" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A woman glances in a mirror and talks to herself about a missing earing" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->inkle</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="905ebd242e976d9939cdf960072e37c5" data-recommend-id="image://905ebd242e976d9939cdf960072e37c5" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A woman glances in a mirror and talks to herself about a missing earing" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Yes, in addition to being a detective game where you are the killer, <em>Overboard! </em>Is also doing a <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://www.kotaku.com.au/2022/02/12-time-looping-video-games-youll-want-to-play-over-and-over/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.kotaku.com.au/2022/02/12-time-looping-video-games-youll-want-to-play-over-and-over/"><em>Groundhog Day</em> situation</a></span>. After every failed attempt you will be able to try new paths through the day, applying the knowledge from past lives to carve a perfect route through or choosing to scope out other options available to you. Eventually you collect so much spare knowledge on every person and item aboard that you can begin piecing together time sensitive puzzles. You may want to sneak into a passenger’s room, which means you need to know when they are on the deck taking in some air. However, you must also know when you can steal their key. It all becomes a complex web of movement and events that all fall like dominoes when you change a single choice.</p><p>That sounds overwhelming, but <em>Overboard!</em> keeps all of its time-loop shenanigans manageable by making every cycle last only 45 real-world minutes. This is perfectly timed so as not to make the loops feel too long, meaning they also don’t really require you to keep an exceedingly lengthy list of tasks in your head to be executed in perfect order. It’s bite-sized and easily digestible. Making loops this short also means you can do a lot in a relatively few sessions, which unlocks the truly surprising twists <em>Overboard! </em>keeps up its sleeve until the late game. But I won’t spoil any of that.</p><p>If <em>Overboard!</em> sounds like it’ll scratch that mystery itch for you then grab the <em>Humble Detectives Bundle</em>. You’ll also get 2022’s movie mystery <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/immortality-sam-barlow-horror-video-game-ps5-pc-1849470910&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/immortality-sam-barlow-horror-video-game-ps5-pc-1849470910"><em>Immortality</em></a></span>, the stunning vaporwave adventure that is <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/i-m-not-yet-sold-on-paradise-killer-but-its-soundtrack-1845846553&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/i-m-not-yet-sold-on-paradise-killer-but-its-soundtrack-1845846553"><em>Paradise Killer</em></a></span>, murder puzzle game <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/killer-frequency-best-survival-horror-game-steam-fnaf-1850410187&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/killer-frequency-best-survival-horror-game-steam-fnaf-1850410187"><em>Killer Frequency</em></a></span>, and three more titles. </p><p>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Internet Reacts To Sony's Unprecedented Unreleasing Of Concord]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/concord-shutdown-playstation-offline-delisted-store-1851638956</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-internet-reacts-to-sonys-unprecedented-unreleasing-of-concord.971223/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/concord-shutdown-playstation-offline-delisted-store-1851638956<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>If you hadn’t heard the big news of the day, Sony and developer Firewalk Studios <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/concord-shutting-down-closing-servers-refunds-ps5-1851638566&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/concord-shutting-down-closing-servers-refunds-ps5-1851638566">are shutting down <em>Concord</em></a></span>, the not-<em>Guardians of the Galaxy </em>hero shooter that has been <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/concord-flop-low-player-count-steam-psn-sales-fps-ps5-1851631800&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/concord-flop-low-player-count-steam-psn-sales-fps-ps5-1851631800">flopping hard</a></span> since its launch on August 23. The studio seems to be planning some kind of comeback, as the announcement says the shutdown on September 6 is so the team can “explore options” about what it will do next. In the meantime, anyone who purchased the game is eligible for a full refund.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196181" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="The Best Reveals From The Game Awards 2023" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="180" data-playlist="196181,196230,193348" data-current="196181"><div><p>The Best Reveals From The Game Awards 2023</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196181/196181_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196181/196181_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196181/196181_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196181/196181_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21718.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>Whether you like <em>Concord </em>or not, this should rattle you. Sony and Firewalk spent a lot of time and money on this game as part of its big live-service push, and it’s flopping so hard that Sony is pulling the plug before it can even hit its one-month anniversary. Somewhere in PlayStation business meetings, Sony was ready to invest heavily into the game and an extended universe spun off from it. There’s even an episode based on the game coming in Amazon’s upcoming anthology series <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/secret-level-amazon-armored-core-playstation-keanu-1851627812&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/secret-level-amazon-armored-core-playstation-keanu-1851627812"><em>Secret Level</em> coming in December</a></span>. That episode may be the last gasp from a game that was snuffed out in just two weeks.</p><p>How did we get here? People have a lot of theories, and the implications for PlayStation and the state of the video game industry at large aren’t pretty. Let’s get into some of the internet’s reactions to the (ostensibly temporary) death of <em>Concord</em>.</p><h2 id="h100120"><a id=""></a><strong>Sympathy for the developers</strong></h2><p>Plenty of people who have worked a corporate job, especially in creative fields, know the sting of big suits making decisions that will inevitably lead to the slow decay of something people love. As the public has become more aware of working conditions within the video game industry, some people’s natural inclination is to worry about the designers, artists, and programmers who will inevitably be affected by the management decisions that led to <em>Concord</em>.</p><h2 id="h100121"><a id=""></a><strong>Weeping for the state of PlayStation</strong></h2><p>Whether it’s fair or not, <em>Concord </em>has become synonymous with the pitfalls of PlayStation’s <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/playstation-live-service-delayed-tlou-factions-1851007495&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/playstation-live-service-delayed-tlou-factions-1851007495">live-service pivot</a></span>. Sony has been shutting down companies like Japan Studio and London Studio, while seemingly devoting swaths of its resources to live-service games like this one. It recently <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/last-us-online-factions-multiplayer-ps5-naughty-dog-1851101434&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/last-us-online-factions-multiplayer-ps5-naughty-dog-1851101434">canceled a service game based on <em>The Last of Us</em></a></span>, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/bungie-layoffs-destiny-2-final-shape-marathon-sony-ps5-1851609905&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/bungie-layoffs-destiny-2-final-shape-marathon-sony-ps5-1851609905">cut jobs at Bungie</a></span>, and just seems to have had an impossible time getting the PS5 era of first-party games off the ground. While <em>Astro Bot </em>is coming this week on September 6, things look bleak for PlayStation right now in terms of quality first-party games. It has folks wistful for games like <em>Gravity Rush</em>, which might not have been a big seller like <em>The Last of Us </em>or <em>God of War</em>, but was certainly more memorable than a live-service game that crashes and burns in mere days.</p><h2 id="h100122"><a id=""></a><strong>Could this have been prevented, or was this always <em>Concord</em>’s destiny?</strong></h2><p>There are a lot of reasons <em>Concord </em>turned out this way. The game was divisive on a few fronts, even <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/concord-playstation-5-pc-state-of-play-reaction-reddit-1851516496&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/concord-playstation-5-pc-state-of-play-reaction-reddit-1851516496">when it was first shown at the State of Play in May</a></span>. It’s jumping into an overcrowded genre that games like <em>Overwatch 2 </em>and <em>Apex Legends</em> dominate. It had a $40 price tag instead of being free-to-play like several of its competitors. But overall, it lacked that certain character-driven spark that you need to get people to play a hero shooter. It’s not enough to be mechanically sound if people aren’t drawn to the heroes they’re playing. PlayStation and FIrewalk clearly hoped <em>Concord </em>could become as ubiquitous as its contemporaries, and it failed to reach whatever internal metrics it had so badly that it’s going dark two weeks after launch.</p><p><em>Concord </em>was misguided, but considering the market it was entering, it would have been hard for even a much better game to penetrate the cultural consciousness, much less one that was so generic that it’s often only described in comparison to other works.</p><h2 id="h100123"><a id=""></a><strong>Is there hope?</strong></h2><p>Officially, Sony and Firewalk Studios are planning to bring <em>Concord</em> back at some point. I think most people probably figured the game would go free-to-play to get rid of the $40 barricade between the shooter and its potential player pool. That seems like a reasonable path forward, and would certainly be more sensible than dumping years of work and millions of dollars down a well. But we’ve also seen games like <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/how-biowares-anthem-went-wrong-1833731964&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/how-biowares-anthem-went-wrong-1833731964">BioWare’s looter shooter <em>Anthem</em></a></span> retreat for a retooling, only to end up dying anyway. How many live-service failures and missteps do we have to see this industry make before the suits realize this isn’t sustainable? I care more for the human cost of this failure, so I hope <em>Concord </em>gets a second chance at life in a better position for success. The PlayStation fan in me hopes that if it all comes crashing down regardless, someone at Sony realizes that this cannot continue and is righting the ship as we speak. <br></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ESL Announces ESL One Bangkok Dota 2 Tournament Series]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/esl-announces-esl-one-bangkok-dota-2-tournament-series/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/esl-announces-esl-one-bangkok-dota-2-tournament-series.971220/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/esl-announces-esl-one-bangkok-dota-2-tournament-series/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Dota 2, the popular esports title, will officially come to Bangkok later this year. ESL officially announced earlier today ESL One Bangkok will take place this December, ending 2024 esports with a bang.</p>



<h2 id="h-esl-one-bangkok-happening-this-december">ESL One Bangkok Happening This December</h2>



<p>The popular tournament series will take place in Bangkok this winter during these dates:</p>



<ul>
<li>December 9, 2024</li>



<li>December 10, 2024</li>



<li>December 11, 2024</li>



<li>December 12, 2024</li>



<li>December 13, 2024</li>



<li>December 14, 2024</li>



<li>December 15, 2024</li>
</ul>



<figure></figure>







<p>The event will take place in Bangkok, Thailand, and will be a continuation of the ESL Pro Tour, pitting 12 of the top Dota 2 esports teams against each other for a massive $1,000,000 prize pool. </p>



<p>Not only is this ESL FACEIT’s first event in Thailand, but it is also the largest Dota 2 tournament to ever be held in the country.</p>



<p>Thailand has been a host to various other large esports tournaments, such as Capcom and Valorant events.</p>



<h2 id="h-prize-pool-breakdown">Prize Pool Breakdown</h2>



<p>Here is an official breakdown of the tournament’s prize pool:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>1st</strong>&nbsp;– $300,000</li>



<li><strong>2nd</strong>&nbsp;– $175,000</li>



<li><strong>3rd</strong>&nbsp;– $120,000</li>



<li><strong>4th</strong>&nbsp;– $85,000</li>



<li><strong>5th &amp; 6th</strong>&nbsp;– $57,500</li>



<li><strong>7th &amp; 8th</strong>&nbsp;– $47,500</li>



<li><strong>9th &amp; 10th</strong>&nbsp;– $30,000</li>



<li><strong>11th &amp; 12th</strong>&nbsp;– $25,000</li>
</ul>



<p>Those looking to purchase tickets to the event can do so starting September 5, 2024. Tickets can be purchased <a href="https://www.esl-one.com/bangkok/">here</a>.</p>



<h6 id="h-related-the-international-2024-dates-prize-pool-and-more">Related: <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-international-2024-dates-prize-pool-and-more/">The International 2024: Dates, Prize Pool And More</a></h6>



<h2 id="h-format">Format</h2>



<p>ESL One Bangkok hangs on to the traditional Dota 2 tournament format with a pair of round-robin groups and then an eight-team playoff event. There will be a Group Stage event beginning on December 9, with every team facing off against each other before the official tournament begins.</p>



<p>With The International 2024 just around the corner, 2024 is looking to close out with some of the most intense and entertaining Dota 2 action in esports history. </p>



<p>Stay tuned to Insider Gaming for more <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/category/esports/">esports news</a>.</p>




    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>
    
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ubisoft Stock Tanks to 10-Year Low After Lukewarm Star Wars Outlaws Launch]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/ubisoft-stock-tanks/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ubisoft-stock-tanks-to-10-year-low-after-lukewarm-star-wars-outlaws-launch.971217/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/ubisoft-stock-tanks/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Ubisoft stock prices have tanked by over 10% in the past two days following a lukewarm reception to Star Wars Outlaws.</p>



<p>At the time of writing, Ubisoft Entertainment SA stock prices are at €15.50, a level not seen since December 2014. The <a href="https://www.google.com/finance/quote/UBI:EPA?sa=X&amp;ved=2ahUKEwiNvP-_w6eIAxU7VEEAHXOhMLsQ3ecFegQIPhAh" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">stock price</a> puts the company’s market cap just shy of €2B at €1.99B.</p>



<p>The stock price drop follows the release of Star Wars Outlaws, which released with a mere 4.9 user score out of 10 according to review aggregator <a href="https://www.metacritic.com/game/star-wars-outlaws/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Metacritic</a>. As a result, the tepid response led J.P. Morgan to slash sales forecasts by 2 million units, predicting 5.5 million units sold by March 2025. Combine a slash in sales with Disney’s hefty licensing and it’s not hard to see why investors are skittish on the company’s immediate future.</p>



<p>But that’s not all. Just last week, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/xdefiant-player-numbers-2/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming reported that XDefiant</a>, the publisher’s free-to-play hit that firmly contributed to the company’s Q1 financial success, was in big trouble. According to our sources, the game is on borrowed time, and it risks losing its much-needed post-launch support if the developers can’t bring back players by the end of Season 3. Ubisoft declined to comment on the report.</p>



<p>Still, investors remain optimistic about the publisher’s future. With the game set to release on November 15, Assassin’s Creed Shadows will be crucial to making this fiscal year a financial success. Despite the game already seeing its fair share of online discourse, our sources suggest its pre-order numbers are strong.</p>



<p>Looking ahead past this fiscal year, things look a little brighter for the company. Next year, we should hear about some huge titles, including the next mainline entries into Far Cry and Ghost Recon and the hotly anticipated Splinter Cell Remake. Who knows, perhaps one could even be announced later this year to perk up investors and, frankly, players, too.</p>



<p>What do you think of Ubisoft’s future? Let us know in the comments below!</p>



<hr>



<p>What do you think of PlayStation shutting down Concord after just two weeks? For more Insider Gaming, check out&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/madden-25-gets-first-major-title-update-but-doesnt-fix-defensive-issues/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">details of the first title update for Madden 25</a>.</p>












    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>
    
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dungeons & Dragons Lego Minifigure 6-Packs Available Now At Amazon]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/dungeons-dragons-lego-minifigure-6-packs-available-now-at-amazon/1100-6526226/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dungeons-dragons-lego-minifigure-6-packs-available-now-at-amazon.971214/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/dungeons-dragons-lego-minifigure-6-packs-available-now-at-amazon/1100-6526226/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6526226">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>You can never have too many Lego minifigures in your life, and if you dabble in Dungeons &amp; Dragons, you'll definitely want to check out the new minifigure collection that launched over the weekend. <strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CV2HV7WJ?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">The Lego Dungeons &amp; Dragons minifigure collection</a></strong> is now available to purchase. Fans of the classic tabletop RPG can try to collect all 12 D&amp;D characters by purchasing <strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CV2HV7WJ?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Lego D&amp;D minifigure six-packs for $30 at Amazon</a></strong> or singles for <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fclick.linksynergy.com%2Fdeeplink%3Fid%3DVZfI20jEa0c%26mid%3D13923%26u1%3Dsubid_value%26murl%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.lego.com%2Fen-us%2Fproduct%2Fdungeons-dragons-71047&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fdungeons-dragons-lego-minifigure-6-packs-available-now-at-amazon%2F1100-6526226%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">$5 at the Lego Store</a>.</p><p>The release of the D&amp;D minifigure collection comes just months after Lego released its first set based on the franchise: a <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CPYSLC64?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">3,745-piece kit dubbed Red Dragon's Tale</a>. You can add the minifigures to the scene depicted in Red Dragon's Tale.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4360659-lego-dnd-cast.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4360659" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4360659-lego-dnd-cast.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4360659"></a><figcaption>Lego Dungeons &amp; Dragons minifigures</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4360659-lego-dnd-cast.jpg"></figure><p>The catch here is that you won't know which character you're getting, as these are sold as mystery boxes. Amazon is offering a six-pack of random figures for $30, and it's very uncommon to get duplicates in Lego's pre-packaged minifigure boxes. Historically speaking, though, it's not impossible to get a duplicate, but you'd have to be pretty unlucky.</p><p>Here's the full line of D&amp;D minifigures:</p><ul><li>Tiefling Sorcerer</li><li>Elf Bard</li><li>Halfling Druid</li><li>Dwarf Barbarian</li><li>Dragonborn Paladin</li><li>Aarakocra Ranger</li><li>Gith Warlock</li><li>Mind Flayer</li><li>The Lady of Pain</li><li>Szass Tam</li><li>Strahd von Zarich</li><li>Tasha the Witch Queen</li></ul><p>All 12 Dungeons &amp; Dragons minifigures come in a sealed mystery box with at least one accessory per character--don't start your fantasy adventure without it--and if you're looking to plug any gaps in your collection, you can roll the dice and get a <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fclick.linksynergy.com%2Fdeeplink%3Fid%3DVZfI20jEa0c%26mid%3D13923%26u1%3Dsubid_value%26murl%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.lego.com%2Fen-us%2Fproduct%2Fdungeons-dragons-71047&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fdungeons-dragons-lego-minifigure-6-packs-available-now-at-amazon%2F1100-6526226%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">single random minifigure</a> for $5 at The Lego Store.</p><ul><li><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fclick.linksynergy.com%2Fdeeplink%3Fid%3DVZfI20jEa0c%26mid%3D13923%26u1%3Dsubid_value%26murl%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.lego.com%2Fen-us%2Fproduct%2Fdungeons-dragons-71047&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fdungeons-dragons-lego-minifigure-6-packs-available-now-at-amazon%2F1100-6526226%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Lego Dungeons &amp; Dragons single minifigures</a> -- $5</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CV2HV7WJ?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Lego Dungeons &amp; Dragons six-pack of minifigures</a> -- $30 | <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fclick.linksynergy.com%2Fdeeplink%3Fid%3DVZfI20jEa0c%26mid%3D13923%26u1%3Dsubid_value%26murl%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.lego.com%2Fen-us%2Fproduct%2Fdungeons-dragons-6-pack-66765&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fdungeons-dragons-lego-minifigure-6-packs-available-now-at-amazon%2F1100-6526226%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Also at Lego Store</a></li></ul><p>If you want your minifigures to feel the heat from a large dragon, you have to be prepared to part with significantly more cash. <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CPYSLC64?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Red Dragon's Tale goes for $360</a> and has yet to receive a discount from a major retailer. However, <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fshop-links.co%2F1812345578378023391%3Fu1%3Dsubid_value&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fdungeons-dragons-lego-minifigure-6-packs-available-now-at-amazon%2F1100-6526226%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">My Best Buy Plus/Total members</a> can <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fshop-links.co%2F1846675747936902595%3Fu1%3Dsubid_value&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fdungeons-dragons-lego-minifigure-6-packs-available-now-at-amazon%2F1100-6526226%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">get the set for $324</a>. This attention-grabbing building kit has 3,745 pieces, and once fully assembled, you'll have a lovely tavern and tower diorama full of small details that you can admire. The posable Cinderhowl the Red Dragon figure is perched overhead, but the minifigures below don't seem to be bothered by the dragon's presence</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4360657-dnd-dragon.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4360657" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4360657-dnd-dragon.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4360657"></a><figcaption>Lego Dungeons &amp; Dragons: Red Dragon's Tale</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4360657-dnd-dragon.jpg"></figure><ul><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/LEGO-Ideas-6474648-TBD-21348/dp/B0CPYSLC64?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Lego Dungeons &amp; Dragons: Red Dragon's Tale at Amazon</a> -- $360</li><li><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fshop-links.co%2F1812345578378023391%3Fu1%3Dsubid_value&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fdungeons-dragons-lego-minifigure-6-packs-available-now-at-amazon%2F1100-6526226%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">My Best Buy Plus/Total members</a> can <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CPYSLC64?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">get the D&amp;D set for $324 (<del>$360</del>)</a></li></ul><p>If you need another excuse to justify purchasing it, think of it as a fun way to spend an evening playing DnD! The set has magic items and traps, several minifigures, and it'll be great to theme a campaign around it.</p><div data-embed-type="pinbox" data-ref-id="4304">  <ul>                              <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/berserk-the-complete-1997-tv-series-is-only-37-at-amazon-best-price-yet/1100-6524954/">Berserk: The Complete 1997 TV Series Is Only $37 At Amazon, Best Price Yet</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/astro-bot-ps5-dualsense-controller-preorder/1100-6525376/">Astro Bot Preorders - PS5 DualSense Controller, Free Poster With Game, And More</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/star-wars-the-skywalker-saga-complete-digital-collection-is-only-20-at-amazon/1100-6526122/">Star Wars: The Skywalker Saga Complete Digital Collection Is Only $20 At Amazon</a></li>                          <li>         <span>+ Show More More Gaming, Tech, and Entertainment Deals &amp; Preorders Links (5)</span>       </li>          <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/lego-atari-2600-gets-huge-price-cut-at-best-buy/1100-6520830/">Lego Atari 2600 Gets Huge Price Cut At Best Buy</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/star-wars-outlaws-preorder-guide/1100-6522523/">Star Wars Outlaws Preorders - Where To Find The Best Bonuses</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/buy-two-get-one-free-nintendo-switch-games-and-preorders-my-best-buy-members/1100-6525928/">B2G1 Free All Nintendo Switch Games - Zelda: Echoes Of Wisdom, Mario &amp; Luigi, And More Preorders</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/dragon-age-the-veilguard-preorder-guide/1100-6525830/">Dragon Age: The Veilguard Collector's Edition Preorders Live Now</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/doom-anthology-preorders-quakecon-2024/1100-6525656/">Doom Anthology Preorders Are Live - Comes With 6 Games, Steelbook Case, And Replica BFG</a></li>   </ul> </div>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/108490194306897153177?rel=author">Darryn Bonthuys</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>