<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 17:06:16 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dark Sector, the 'original version' of Warframe, is currently free on Steam]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dark-sector-the-original-version-of-warframe-is-currently-free-on-steam</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dark-sector-the-original-version-of-warframe-is-currently-free-on-steam.1048200/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dark-sector-the-original-version-of-warframe-is-currently-free-on-steam<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
  

        <p>Returning from the glaive</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/1_uWrdD2P.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Digital Extremes</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>Back when Digital Extremes were largely known for collaborating with Epic Games on the Unreal Tournament series, they made a little game called Dark Sector. Released in 2008, it's part of the fine tradition of post-Gears double-A actioners that basically consist of taking a gruff man, throwing him into a world of grit, gravel and burning oil drums, and handing him a murderous gimmick. Dark Sector's gimmick was the glaive, a pointy boomerang you could use to scoop up objects, solve puzzles, and kill stuff in third-person view.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>The result? A pretty forgettable video game. This is the first time anybody at Rock Paper Shotgun has ever posted specifically about Dark Sector, in fact. But Dark Sector's stature, if not its quality, has swelled in hindsight - for it's sort of the 'original version' of <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/warframe">Warframe</a>, the absurdly over-dressed free-to-play shooter that hopefully needs no introduction. If you're a Warframer who's up for a roady-run down memory lane, Digital Extremes are <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/29900/Dark_Sector/">currently giving Dark Sector away on Steam</a>.</p>
<p>Dark Sector takes place in an approximately real-world, present-day setting, albeit one full of "Technocyte" bioweapons, but it was once envisaged as a sci-fi, outer-space affair in which you'd play a character with a fancy mechsuit.</p>
<p>Digital Extremes eventually dialled the sci-fi elements back to make the story more relatable to players of the era - this was the mid-noughties, don't forget, when every game had to vaguely resemble a less-good Bruce Willis film. But after releasing Dark Sector, they dug up their original notes and spun them out into the concept for Warframe. There are a few reverential nods to Dark Sector in the latter, including a fancier species of glaive.</p><p>If you're enticed by Dark Sector's sheer OK-ness, you'll want to get your skates on. It's free only till Saturday November 30th at 9am PT, 12pm ET, 5pm GMT and 6pm CET. The thinking behind the discount is to celebrate Warframe's forthcoming 1999 expansion, which takes the series back in time. Look out for that in December. I'm personally <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/soulframe-has-the-bones-of-a-great-action-rpg-but-im-enjoying-it-partly-because-it-feels-too-late-to-enjoy-warframe#comments">more interested in Digital Extremes' fantasy RPG Soulframe right now than Warframe</a>, largely because after 10 years of updates, Warframe feels too big and knotty to get my head around.</p>
<p>If you're unconvinced by Dark Sector, even at the low, low price of nada multiplied by nothing, I have a bonus ancient Digital Extremes game to share - The Darkness 2, which <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/67370/The_Darkness_II/">is currently 80% off</a>. This one's a sequel to the Starbreeze game about the trenchcoat gangster with snake hands, and it's actually quite decent - decent enough to make Alec Meer's (RPS in peace) old <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-average-action-games-on-pc">Celebration Of Perfectly Average Action Games</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Intel Battlemage Graphics Cards Release Date Leaked]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/intel-battlemage-graphics-cards-release-date-leaked/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/intel-battlemage-graphics-cards-release-date-leaked.1048191/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/intel-battlemage-graphics-cards-release-date-leaked/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-71265">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>The release date of the upcoming Intel Battlemage graphics cards has seemingly been leaked. According to <a href="https://videocardz.com/newz/exclusive-intel-arc-battlemage-to-launch-december-12th" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">VideoCardz</a>, the first set of next-gen GPUs from Intel are set to release on December 12.</p>



<p>The date would back up the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/intel-battlemage-gpu-to-be-announced-next-month-its-claimed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">recent rumors of a reveal</a> coming before the end of the year.</p>



<p>Videocardz’s report claims that the announcement of Intel Battlemage will happen on December 3. The first launch of the Limited Edition GPU along with first reviews will happen on December 12. That will be quickly followed by board partner reviews on December  13.</p>



<p>As far as what graphics cards are releasing, it’s expected to first be the Intel Arc B580 and B570. Over the last few weeks, specs for the Intel Arc B580 have regularly leaked out through various means. The GPU is expected to feature 20 Xe2 cores with a 2.8 GHz clock speed and 12GB GDDR6 VRAM. The Arc B570, on the other hand, has been relatively unknown aside from an expected core count of roughly 18 Xe2 cores. </p>



<p>While the Arc B580 and B570 are expected to be the mid-range offerings from Intel this generation, there’s been no mention of a lower-end or higher-end model from the company. Should those exist, they could either be revealed during the December 3rd announcement, or during a separate reveal altogether.</p>



<p>Insider Gaming has reached out to Intel for comment on the Battlemage release date claims. As of publishing, no response has been received. </p>



<figure><table><thead><tr><th>Specification</th><th>Intel Arc B580</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>GPU</td><td>Battlemage BGM-G21</td></tr><tr><td>GPU Clock Speed</td><td>2.8 GHz</td></tr><tr><td>Xe-Cores</td><td>20 Xe2</td></tr><tr><td>Compute Units</td><td>160</td></tr><tr><td>Memory</td><td>12GB GDDR6</td></tr><tr><td>Memory Bus</td><td>192-bit</td></tr><tr><td>Memory Speed</td><td>19 Gbps</td></tr><tr><td>Memory Bandwidth</td><td>456 GB/s</td></tr><tr><td>PCIe</td><td>5.0 x8</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming Tech, check out our review of the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/intel-core-ultra-9-285k-review-a-new-era-for-efficiency-but-is-it-right-for-you/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Intel Core Ultra 9 285K CPU</a>. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/stalker-2-101-patch-durability-difficulty-dead-zones/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/stalker-2-101-patch-durability-difficulty-dead-zones/">STALKER 2 1.0.1 Patch Addresses Durability, Difficulty, and Dead Zones</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>STALKER 2’s 1.0.1 patch is massive and addresses more than 650 issues in the game. Check out the breakdown of the most important points here.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-chapter-6-launch/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-chapter-6-launch/">Fortnite Chapter 6 Launch Trailer Reveals Godzilla, Bosses, and More</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>The new Fortnite Chapter 6 launch trailer has revealed that Godzilla and bosses will be making their way to the Battle Royale.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/16-minutes-of-light-of-motiram-gameplay/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/16-minutes-of-light-of-motiram-gameplay/">16 Minutes of Light of Motiram Gameplay Has Been Revealed</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Following a controversial reveal, Polaris Quest revealed 16 minutes of Light of Motiram gameplay.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/plague-inc-rebuild-after-inc/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/plague-inc-rebuild-after-inc/">12 Years After You Ended The World in Plague Inc., You Can Now Rebuild It in After Inc.</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Ndemic Creations has revealed After Inc., a game set in the aftermath of Plague Inc., one of the most popular mobile games ever.</p>
                    </div>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Final Fantasy 14 world first Ultimate Raid challengers busted for cheating thanks to single pixel]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/final-fantasy-14-world-first-ultimate-raid-challengers-busted-for-cheating-thanks-to-single-pixel</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/final-fantasy-14-world-first-ultimate-raid-challengers-busted-for-cheating-thanks-to-single-pixel.1048188/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/final-fantasy-14-world-first-ultimate-raid-challengers-busted-for-cheating-thanks-to-single-pixel<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>Third cheating scandal in a row.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/FINAL-FANTASY-XIV-Patch-7.1---Crossroads-1-34-screenshot.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Square Enix</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>Yet another <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/final-fantasy-xiv-a-realm-reborn">Final Fantasy 14</a> Ultimate Raid world first challenge has been scuppered by cheaters, who were busted due to a single pixel.</p>
<p>Ultimate Raids are the toughest missions in the MMORPG, with many groups competing to be the first to complete them in an unofficial, community-led challenge. The recent patch 7.1 added another Ultimate Raid, Futures Rewritten, which became the third in a row to be impacted by scandalous cheaters.</p>
<p>The winning team was<a href="https://x.com/FrostyMog/status/1862341016126124204"> GRIND</a>, as shared by MogTalk creator and World Race tracker Frosty, at least initially. It soon transpired the team had been using a cheat hack, which was spotted due to a single pixel.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="FINAL FANTASY XIV Patch 7.1 - Crossroads" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/tb08eqW1QQo?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>FINAL FANTASY XIV Patch 7.1 - Crossroads</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/tb08eqW1QQo?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/tb08eqW1QQo?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Final Fantasy 14 Patch 7.1 - Crossroads<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tb08eqW1QQo" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>The incriminating pixel, <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/final-fantasy/final-fantasy-14-world-first-raiders-busted-immediately-for-cheating-thanks-to-a-single-pixel-in-a-screenshot-making-it-the-3rd-scuffed-ultimate-race-in-a-row/">PC Gamer</a> explained, is indicative of the Pixel Perfect Plus plugin, which shows a character's exact hitbox. That's particularly useful when dodging AoE attacks in an Ultimate Raid, where the sheer number of attacks across battle arenas increases the difficulty dramatically.</p>
<p>Of course, third-party plugins are not allowed in Final Fantasy 14. As a result, Frosty has disqualified GRIND from the race.</p>
<blockquote data-embed-height="740"><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/ffxiv/comments/1h2eygo/the_memes_are_already_rolling_in/">The memes are already rolling in</a><br> by<a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/crotton989/">u/crotton989</a> in<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/ffxiv/">ffxiv</a></blockquote><p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span></p><p>"I had our team research the plugin that was used by the team and it's capabilities makes it eligible for disqualification from the MogTalk leaderboard," Frosty wrote on X. "GRIND did not approve this member to use the plugin and do not agree with the actions he took."</p>
<div>
<div data-domain="twitter.com"><blockquote><p dir="ltr" lang="en">I had our team research the plugin that was used by the team and it's capabilities makes it eligible for disqualification from the MogTalk leaderboard. GRIND did not approve this member to use the plugin and do not agree with the actions he took.</p>— Frosty 🥶 (@FrostyMog) <a href="https://twitter.com/FrostyMog/status/1862383221570216427?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 29, 2024</a></blockquote></div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>

<p>Instead, <a href="https://x.com/FrostyMog/status/1862403138772189577">Kindred</a> has been awarded the world first clear of Future Rewritten. Frosty does note, however, that conversations must be had around the community-led challenge. Not all challengers stream their attempts (they wouldn't want others to copy), but that certainly makes it harder to police cheaters.</p><p>What's remarkable is that this is the third Ultimate Raid challenge in a row to be impacted by cheaters. Last year's world first clear of The Omega Protocol was revoked once it transpired the raid group was using third-party mods; the year before's Dragonsong's Reprise was a similar story.</p>
<p>After both of those challenges, director and producer <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/personas/naoki-yoshida">Naoki Yoshida</a> shared his disappointment at the use of third-party mods.</p>
<p>"It is extremely disappointing for me personally to see this commotion surrounding third-party tools once again in the wake of what happened with Dragonsong's Reprise (Ultimate)," he <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/naoki-yoshida-extremely-disappointed-in-final-fantasy-14-mod-use">wrote last year</a>. "As the individual who is entrusted with full supervision over Final Fantasy 14, it is my responsibility to enact countermeasures and police the use of these tools, as well as educate people to not use these types of third-party tools - this is especially unfortunate when I, as a gamer, am cheering on everyone who is learning this content by trial and error and putting in the effort to clear."</p>
<p>No such statement has yet been made following this year's controversy.</p>
<p>Back in 2022, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/square-enix-cracks-down-on-final-fantasy-14-mods-as-director-promises-to-enhance-hud">Yoshida said the Final Fantasy 14 team</a> would "review the most prominent tools, and in order to discourage their use, endeavour to enhance the functionality of the HUD". And yet two years on, the use of these tools prevails.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tencent's Light of Motiram Has Strong "We Have Horizon at Home" Energy]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/light-of-motiram-announced-tencent-horizon</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/tencents-light-of-motiram-has-strong-we-have-horizon-at-home-energy.1048173/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/light-of-motiram-announced-tencent-horizon<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Tencent and subsidiary Polaris Quest have announced&nbsp;<em>Light of Motiram</em>, an open-world survival-crafter coming to PC, PS5, and mobile devices sometime next year, and it bears more than a passing resemblance to a certain PlayStation franchise.</p>

<p>In a press release, Polaris Quest and Tencent describe <i>Light of Motiram&nbsp;</i>as an "open-world multiplayer survival game" set in a "lush world dominated by mechanical beasts". I'm sure that you can guess <a href="https://techraptor.net/games/horizon-zero-dawn" rel="nofollow">which PlayStation franchise</a> it's <a href="https://techraptor.net/games/horizon-forbidden-west" rel="nofollow">jostling against</a> from that description.</p>

<p>Said press release also promises a "dynamic, impactful combat system" in&nbsp;<em>Light of Motiram</em>, as well as "saga-worthy boss fights" with elemental weaknesses you'll have to exploit alongside your "mechanimal" friends.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/light-of-motiram-tencent-horizon-creatures.jpg?itok=7HTzJn3g 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/light-of-motiram-tencent-horizon-creatures.jpg?itok=Uu3FjUHb 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Light of Motiram</em>'s PC and console release is on the...uh, the cards for next year.</figcaption></figure><p>It's probably worth pointing out at this stage that if you haven't figured it out already, the PlayStation franchise with which&nbsp;<em>Light of Motiram&nbsp;</em>seems to share its mechanical DNA is, of course, Guerrilla's&nbsp;<em>Horizon&nbsp;</em>series.</p>

<p>The game's "mechanimals" are strikingly similar to&nbsp;<em>Horizon</em>'s creatures, right down to the soothing blue light that appears to represent their vision and the articulated limbs and appendages the creatures seem to have.</p>

<p>However, gameplay-wise, it seems like&nbsp;<em>Light of Motiram&nbsp;</em>will differ quite a bit from Guerrilla's series; it won't be a single-player action-adventure game with RPG elements, but a free-to-play survival-crafter with base-building and a multiplayer focus. Whether that's an improvement, I'll leave up to you to decide.</p>

<p>Polaris Quest and Tencent are promising "realistic physics simulation" in which every object in the game is subject to a physics engine, as well as weather systems you'll need to respond to in order to emerge victorious against the mechanimals and survive in&nbsp;<em>Light of Motiram</em>'s world.</p>




<p>Tencent's game will also differ in a few other key ways; you can enlist mechanimals to help you in combat and crafting, for instance, and you'll also unlock new crafting recipes as you take down bosses, so it looks like you can throw&nbsp;<em>Palworld&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>Monster Hunter&nbsp;</em>into the mix as well. Jolly good!</p>

<p><em>Light of Motiram&nbsp;</em>is set to launch on PC and "console platforms" next year. Some reports based on Chinese social media&nbsp;<a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2024/11/mechanimal-open-world-survival-crafting-game-light-of-motiram-announced-for-pc" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">seem to indicate</a> this means PS5 only, and that the game is coming to mobile devices too, but the press release doesn't specify. You can <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3319630/LIGHT_OF_MOTIRAM/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">wishlist it on Steam right now</a> if you like.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kiera Mills is leaving RPS, come celebrate her time here and say goodbye]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/kiera-mills-is-leaving-rps-come-celebrate-her-time-here-and-say-goodbye</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/kiera-mills-is-leaving-rps-come-celebrate-her-time-here-and-say-goodbye.1048170/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/kiera-mills-is-leaving-rps-come-celebrate-her-time-here-and-say-goodbye<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
  

        <p>I promise I got her permission to use this image</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/kiera-mills-leaving-rps.jpg?width=1200&amp;height=1200&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Kiera Mills</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>If you don't secretly spend most afternoons plotting an eventual career change to one where you're surrounded by animals, then I'm sorry, but you're just not welcome in the RPS treehouse. Today, Kiera is taking a definitive step forward in that plan: she's departing RPS for a new playthrough of life, one where the animal sliders are all cranked up to max. Join us in saying fare-thee-well below.</p><!--more-->
<p>Kiera joined the guides branch of the treehouse just over a year ago, and along with fellow new hire Jeremy she was promptly baptised in that familiar river of hot magma known as "this year's Call Of Duty". <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/call-of-duty-modern-warfare-3-2023">50-odd gun guides later</a>, she solo-led our <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/avatar-frontiers-of-pandora-tips-and-tricks">Avatar: Frontiers Of Pandora</a> guides coverage with a series of clear and carefully-written guides that made it look like she'd been here for years, not weeks. I'm planning a playthrough of Avatar soon and I'll for sure be dipping into her guides for that.</p>
<p>Then the new year came around, and thank goodness Kiera was around so she could help us tackle the googly-eyed mammoth that was <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/palworld-tips-and-tricks">Palworld</a>. Kiera spent a brain-melting number of hours delving into that gigantic game, resurfacing only to send me a new link to another expansive guide on the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/palworld-best-ice-pals">best Ice Pals</a>, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/palworld-best-electric-pals">best Electric Pals</a>, even comprehensive lists on <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/palworld-pal-list">where to find all 137 Pal types</a>... It can't have been easy, nor particularly fun I'd wager, but the quality of her work never wavered. And then she went through the same thing with <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dragons-dogma-2-walkthrough">Dragon's Dogma 2</a>, churning out excellent guides like <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dragons-dogma-2-romance-gifts">this one on the game's romance and affinity systems</a>.</p>
<p>The same was true for the countless updates and refreshes of older guides that Kiera took care of over these past 12 months. Everything from our <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/starfield">Starfield</a> primers to our vast number of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/elden-ring">Elden Ring</a> guides has been improved over the past year, thanks largely to Kiera's tireless work to keep everything as up-to-date and easy to follow as possible. Juggling new releases, old update projects, and the ever-present burden of thinking up hints every day for our <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/wordle">Wordle</a> and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/connections">Connections</a> guides is far from easy, but she always got it done, and she did great work every time.</p><p>Despite the workload, she also found time for some lovely bespoke pieces on <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/i-made-the-witchy-cottage-of-my-dreams-in-tiny-glade">making a witchy cottage in Tiny Glade</a> and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/i-tried-to-recreate-stray-in-lethal-company-with-disastrous-results">attempting to recreate Stray in Lethal Company</a>. It's a shame that 2024 dropped so many gigantic bombshells of work upon us, like <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-best-weapons">Shadow Of The Erdtree</a>, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/star-wars-outlaws-best-syndicate">Star Wars Outlaws</a>, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dragon-age-veilguard-romance-options">Dragon Age: Veilguard</a>, because I'd have loved Kiera to have had more time to write more of these weird and wonderful posts throughout the year. That said, even in the midst of a stupidly busy and tumultuous year, Kiera still found time to write great guides on smaller games like <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/palia-money-making-tips">Palia</a> and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/lightyear-frontier-carrying-capacity-upgrade">Lightyear Frontier</a>, games which we can't often cover but still deserve love and attention.</p>
<p>Please join me in saying farewell to Kiera in the comments below. We usually say that once you leave the treehouse you're dead to us, but in this case, we'll welcome her back every so often in exchange for some good doggo photos, and more pictures of exquisitely painted miniatures with large froggy posteriors.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Venusaur Drop Event in Pokémon TCG Pocket—New Promo-A Cards, Rewards, Tasks & How it Works]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/venusaur-drop-event-in-pokemon-tcg-pocket-new-promo-a-cards-rewards-tasks-how-it-works/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/venusaur-drop-event-in-pok%C3%A9mon-tcg-pocket%E2%80%94new-promo-a-cards-rewards-tasks-how-it-works.1048164/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/venusaur-drop-event-in-pokemon-tcg-pocket-new-promo-a-cards-rewards-tasks-how-it-works/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Calling fellow trainers, the Venusaur Drop Event has landed in Pokémon TCG Pocket. We knew it was coming, and the content drop has graciously brought unreleased Promo-A cards, the chance to open more Packs, and a whole lot more—and this detailed guide covers everything you need to know.</p>



<p>The Lapras EX Drop Event in early November was a big success in Pokémon TCG Pocket. New battles were added, and we all had the chance to earn special Promo Cards—including a very viable Lapras card. As we head to the Christmas season, Pokémon TCG Pocket has dropped an early present with the Venusaur Drop Event, and we knew it was coming thanks to the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-tcg-pocket-next-expansion-rumors-leaks/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">future expansion leaks</a>.</p>



<p>It has lots in common with the Lapras Drop Event but offers entirely new rewards and opportunities in Pokémon TCG Pocket. </p>



<h2 id="h-what-is-the-venusaur-drop-event-in-pokemon-tcg-pocket">What is the Venusaur Drop Event in Pokémon TCG Pocket?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Let’s get these cards. Credit to The Pokémon Company</figcaption></figure>



<p>The Venusaur Drop Event is a limited-time promotion in Pokémon TCG Pocket offering new <strong>Solo Battles</strong>, <strong>rewards</strong>, and <strong>Promo-A cards</strong>, that haven’t been available until now, <strong>starting on Nov. 29</strong> and finishing on <strong>Dec. 12</strong>.</p>



<p>With the Venusaur Drop Event lasting two weeks, there’s plenty of time to get involved. FOMO shouldn’t apply here, but in any case, make sure you complete the battles and try to earn all possible rewards.</p>



<p>Keep an eye on your Event Stamina, because if you run out, <strong>you have to wait to try another battle!</strong></p>







<p>Five new Promo A cards can be gotten in Pokémon TCG Pocket: <strong>Venusaur, Greninja, Haunter, Onix, </strong>and <strong>Jigglypuff</strong>.</p>



<p>The <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-get-promo-10-mewtwo-card-in-pokemon-tcg-pocket/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Mewtwo 10 Promo Card</a> still isn’t ready; however, you can grab these new <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/all-promo-a-cards-in-pokemon-tcg-pocket-how-to-unlock/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Promo A cards</a> for your collection. Here’s a look at each card and its stats.</p>



<figure><table><thead><tr><th data-align="center">Promo Card Name</th><th data-align="center">Promo Card Number</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td data-align="center">Venusaur</td><td data-align="center">18</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Greninja</td><td data-align="center">19</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Haunter</td><td data-align="center">20</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Onix</td><td data-align="center">21</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Jigglypuff</td><td data-align="center">22</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<h2 id="h-all-venusaur-drop-event-rewards-in-pokemon-tcg-pocket">All Venusaur Drop Event Rewards in Pokémon TCG Pocket</h2>



<p>Completing Venusaur Drop Event Solo Battles rewards you with <strong>Promo Packs</strong>, <strong>Shinedust</strong>, <strong>Shop Tickets</strong>, <strong>Event Hourglasses</strong>, <strong>Pack Hourglasses</strong>, and <strong>Wonder Hourglasses</strong>.</p>



<p>Each difficulty level in the Venusaur Drop Event grants “First-time Rewards,” “Chance Rewards,” and goodies for successfully beating Battle Tasks. Regardless of the difficulty, the Chance Rewards stay the same:</p>



<ul>
<li>1x Promo Pack A Series Vol. 2</li>



<li>25 Shinedust</li>



<li>1 Shop Ticket</li>
</ul>



<p>Here’s every First-Time Reward listed for each difficulty level.</p>



<figure><table><thead><tr><th data-align="center">Battle Difficulty</th><th data-align="center">Deck Name</th><th data-align="center">First-Time Rewards</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td data-align="center">Beginner</td><td data-align="center">Ivysaur Deck (Genetic Apex)</td><td data-align="center">2x Pack Hourglasses<br>50x Shinedust<br>1x Shop Ticket</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Intermediate</td><td data-align="center">Venusaur &amp; Scyther Deck (Genetic Apex)</td><td data-align="center">4x Pack Hourglasses<br>100x Shinedust<br>1x Shop Ticket</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Advanced</td><td data-align="center">Venusaur EX Deck (Genetic Apex)</td><td data-align="center">6x Pack Hourglasses<br>150x Shinedust<br>1x Shop Ticket</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Expert</td><td data-align="center">Venusaur EX Deck &amp; Lillligant Deck (Genetic Apex)</td><td data-align="center">8x Pack Hourglasses<br>200x Shinedust<br>1x Shop Ticket</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<h2 id="h-every-venusaur-drop-event-task-in-pokemon-tcg-pocket-amp-rewards">Every Venusaur Drop Event Task in Pokémon TCG Pocket &amp; Rewards</h2>



<p>Here’s a detailed look at every Task reward and the amount you can earn for each.</p>



<figure><table><thead><tr><th data-align="center">Battle Difficulty</th><th data-align="center">Deck Name</th><th data-align="center">Battle Task Description</th><th data-align="center">Type of Reward</th><th data-align="center">Reward Amount</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td data-align="center">Beginner</td><td data-align="center">Ivysaur Deck (Genetic Apex)</td><td data-align="center">Knock Out your opponent’s Active Pokémon 1 time with an attack from a Fire-type Pokémon.</td><td data-align="center">Event Hourglass</td><td data-align="center">x3</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Beginner</td><td data-align="center">Ivysaur Deck (Genetic Apex)</td><td data-align="center">Put 3 Basic Pokémon into play.</td><td data-align="center">Event Hourglass</td><td data-align="center">x3</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Intermediate</td><td data-align="center">Venusaur &amp; Scyther Deck (Genetic Apex)</td><td data-align="center">Knock Out your opponent’s Active Pokémon 2 times with an attack from a Fire-type Pokémon.</td><td data-align="center">Event Hourglass</td><td data-align="center">x3</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Intermediate</td><td data-align="center">Venusaur &amp; Scyther Deck (Genetic Apex)</td><td data-align="center">Make your opponent’s Pokémon Asleep 1 time.</td><td data-align="center">Event Hourglass</td><td data-align="center">x3</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Intermediate</td><td data-align="center">Venusaur &amp; Scyther Deck (Genetic Apex)</td><td data-align="center">Win this battle by turn 14.</td><td data-align="center">Event Hourglass</td><td data-align="center">x3</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Advanced</td><td data-align="center">Venusaur EX Deck (Genetic Apex)</td><td data-align="center">Win 5 or more Battles.</td><td data-align="center">Wonder Hourglass</td><td data-align="center">x4</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Advanced</td><td data-align="center">Venusaur EX Deck (Genetic Apex)</td><td data-align="center">Win this battle using a deck where all the Pokémon cards are of a one-diamond, two-diamond, and/or three-diamond rarity.</td><td data-align="center">Wonder Hourglass</td><td data-align="center">x4</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Advanced</td><td data-align="center">Venusaur EX Deck (Genetic Apex)</td><td data-align="center">Win this battle by turn 14.</td><td data-align="center">Wonder Hourglass</td><td data-align="center">x4</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Advanced</td><td data-align="center">Venusaur EX Deck (Genetic Apex)</td><td data-align="center">Win this battle without your opponent getting any points.</td><td data-align="center">Wonder Hourglass</td><td data-align="center">x4</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Expert</td><td data-align="center">Venusaur EX Deck &amp; Lillligant Deck (Genetic Apex)</td><td data-align="center">Win this battle using a deck where all the Pokémon cards are of a one-diamond, two-diamond, and/or three-diamond rarity.</td><td data-align="center">Wonder Hourglass</td><td data-align="center">x5</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Expert</td><td data-align="center">Venusaur EX Deck &amp; Lillligant Deck (Genetic Apex)</td><td data-align="center">Win this battle by turn 12.</td><td data-align="center">Wonder Hourglass</td><td data-align="center">x5</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Expert</td><td data-align="center">Venusaur EX Deck &amp; Lillligant Deck (Genetic Apex)</td><td data-align="center">Win this battle without your opponent getting any points.</td><td data-align="center">Wonder Hourglass</td><td data-align="center">x5</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Expert</td><td data-align="center">Venusaur EX Deck &amp; Lillligant Deck (Genetic Apex)</td><td data-align="center">Win 10 or more Battles.</td><td data-align="center">Wonder Hourglass</td><td data-align="center">x5</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Expert</td><td data-align="center">Venusaur EX Deck &amp; Lillligant Deck (Genetic Apex)</td><td data-align="center">Win 20 or more Battles.</td><td data-align="center">Wonder Hourglass</td><td data-align="center">x5</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<hr>



<p>Are you happy with the Venusaur Drop Event? We think it’s cool, but let us know your thoughts. Plus, check out the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/rarest-cards-in-pokemon-tcg-pocket/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">rarest cards in Pokémon TCG Pocket</a>, and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-play-pokemon-tcg-pocket-on-pc/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">how to play Pocket on PC</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[UK's biggest mobile games fail to disclose loot boxes in advertising]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/uks-biggest-mobile-games-fail-to-disclose-loot-boxes-in-advertising</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/uks-biggest-mobile-games-fail-to-disclose-loot-boxes-in-advertising.1048161/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/uks-biggest-mobile-games-fail-to-disclose-loot-boxes-in-advertising<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        

        <p>BBC investigation shows just two of Play Store's 45 highest-grossing games adhered to ASA standards.</p>

    </div><div>



            <p>The most popular mobile games "are being advertised without disclosing they contain loot boxes".</p>
<p>That's according to the <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/articles/c748ww9y9nno">BBC</a>, which said an investigation into the top 45 highest-grossing games on the Google Play store discovered just two games correctly advertised that they contained randomised in-game purchases.</p>
<figure><div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div><figcaption>Is Sony buying FromSoftware's parent company the next big games industry acquisition?<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qvqusIyhV2M" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>Of the 45 investigated, 26 games were labelled in the online store as including loot boxes, 22 of which "were being actively advertised at the same time". Only two of those 22 games properly disclosed loot boxes in their advertising, with the Play Store's highest-grossing game, Monopoly Go, "among those not to mention random in-game purchases in its adverts".</p><p>"In the absence of robust regulation in gaming, it is essential for games to provide clear and transparent information about their features, allowing both parents and gamers to make informed decisions," said Dr Jane Rigbye, chief executive of Young Gamers and Gamblers Education Trust, adding the findings were "deeply concerning".</p>
<p>In a separate statement, the ASA told the BBC: "This is an ongoing area of our work, and we're closely monitoring the sector to discover the scale of compliance and act accordingly."</p>
<p>This time last year, the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/uk-games-industry-to-restrict-access-to-loot-boxes-for-children">UK games industry agreed to restrict access to in-game loot boxes for children</a> via a set of industry guidelines.</p>
<p>The industry's trade association UKIE worked with the UK government to draft 11 Industry Principles as part of "improved protections for children, young people and adults following concerns raised about loot boxes". The Principles include the need to flag the existence of loot boxes in a game prior to purchase, a clear list of the probabilities for loot box contents, and the need for an easy refund policy.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Best Buy Is Giving Away a $75 Gift Card When You Buy a Galaxy Black Xbox Series X for Black Friday]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/best-buy-free-gift-card-xbox-series-x-black-friday-deal-2024</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/best-buy-is-giving-away-a-75-gift-card-when-you-buy-a-galaxy-black-xbox-series-x-for-black-friday.1048140/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/best-buy-free-gift-card-xbox-series-x-black-friday-deal-2024<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/black-friday-2024">Black Friday</a> is finally here and deals are dropping left and right, especially some excellent gaming discounts and bundles. If you're looking to add a little extra cash to your wallet, Best Buy's offering a <a href="https://zdcs.link/Qrpxe5?object_uuid=d79a1789-5408-4caa-af1d-95ebf3152bd9&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">free $75 gift card when you purchase the new 2TB Galaxy Black Xbox Series X console for $599.99</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">You could put this extra money towards some new games - and there are some <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-buy-black-friday-sales-2024">fantastic discounts available right now</a> - another Xbox Wireless controller, or you can even jump the gaming ship entirely and spend it on one of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-buy-black-friday-sales-2024">Best Buy's many other Black Friday deals</a> instead. The choice is all yours.</p><div catalogid="172b5213-bff9-46db-bd4d-ec5fb493a39f" id="212405"><div id="212405" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Get Free $75 Gift Card With Purchase of 2TB Galaxy Black Xbox Series X Console</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">This Xbox Series X console is a worthy investment if you're an Xbox user with a growing library. This is mainly due to its 2TB SSD, which gives you double the storage capacity of the standard Series X. It also has a fresh new design, boasting a starry pattern of silver and green specs that lives up to its galactic name. This design also spreads over to the D-pad of the included controller which also features a vibrant green back.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">If you're looking for even more <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-xbox-deals-black-friday-2024">Xbox Black Friday deals</a>, there are plenty of deals available right now, from games to accessories to consoles. Some of our highlights include a discount on <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/metaphor-refantazio-black-friday-2024">Metaphor: ReFantazio</a>, a sweet <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/xbox-expansion-card-best-buy-black-friday-2024">deal on the WD C50 1TB Expansion Card</a>, and "No Xbox Required" streaming bundles that have gotten big discounts at Amazon.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">If you want to look outside of the Xbox ecosystem, there's even more discounts to enjoy right now. In our roundup of the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-video-games-black-friday-deals">best Black Friday video game deals</a>, you can see our top 10 picks from the sale event so far. And if you want an even broader look at some of the best deals overall this year, check out our breakdown of the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-black-friday-2024-deals">best Black Friday deals for 2024</a>.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">More Xbox Black Friday Deals</h2><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Hannah Hoolihan is a freelance writer who works with the Guides and Commerce teams here at IGN.</em></p></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Nov 29, 2024 2:28 pm</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fortnite Chapter 6 Adds a Roaming Godzilla and Much More]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/fortnite-chapter-6-adds-a-roaming-godzilla-and-much-more</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fortnite-chapter-6-adds-a-roaming-godzilla-and-much-more.1048137/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/fortnite-chapter-6-adds-a-roaming-godzilla-and-much-more<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/fortnite">Fortnite</a> developer Epic Games has pulled back the curtain on the Chapter 6 update, confirming the arrival of Godzilla.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Chapter 6, which kicks off on December 1, sees Godzilla terrorize the new Japan-themed map. The Fortnite Chapter 6 Season 1: Hunters trailer, below, shows a number of other, smaller Japan-inspired bosses as well as new weapons available to players, such as samurai swords. Also confirmed is the arrival of Big Hero 6's Baymax.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Earlier this month, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/fortnite-just-raised-its-battle-pass-price-for-the-first-time-ever">Epic Games announced changes to the Fortnite Battle Pass model that will see its standard pass getting a price increase for the first time</a>. Fortnite has long offered its standard pass for 950 V-Bucks, but starting December 1, the price will increase by 50, bringing the total asking number to 1,000 V-Bucks.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The real-world cost of V-Bucks will remain unchanged (you can pick up 1,000 V-Bucks on the Epic Games Store for $8.99 right now), and you’ll still be able to earn chunks of V-Bucks by reaching certain Battle Pass levels. Meanwhile, the price of the 25 Battle Pass Reward Bundle is going down from 1,850 to 1,800.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">These changes arrive ahead of the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/fortnite-confirms-og-experience-returns-in-december-but-this-time-its-here-to-stay"><u>highly anticipated launch of Fortnite OG: Chapter 1 – Season 1</u></a> on December 6.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dragon Age: Inquisition's final expansion originally forced you to blow up Skyhold]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/dragon-age-inquisitions-final-expansion-originally-forced-you-to-blow-up-skyhold</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dragon-age-inquisitions-final-expansion-originally-forced-you-to-blow-up-skyhold.1048134/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/dragon-age-inquisitions-final-expansion-originally-forced-you-to-blow-up-skyhold<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>



            <p>
An early plan for <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/dragon-age-inquisition">Dragon Age: Inquisition</a>'s climactic Trespasser expansion would have seen players forced to blow up their beloved base, Skyhold.
</p>
<p>
Skyhold is where the bulk of Inquisition is set - a towering, upgradable and expandable castle that fills up with your close companions and other followers, and acts as a hub for the Inquisitor in their fight back against Corypheus. It's the game's equivalent to <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/mass-effect">Mass Effect</a>'s Normandy, and is a big reason why many fans love the game.
</p>
<p>
Newly-posted concept art from Trespasser's early days shows Skyhold was once set to be sacrificed during the events of the expansion in dramatic style - something that would have fitted the add-on's narrative arc, perhaps, though would also have been heart-wrenching for players after 100 hours building it up.
</p>
<p>
Writing on social media, Dragon Age veteran Matt Rhodes <a href="https://x.com/mattrhodesart/status/1862140792527085614">revealed</a> that Skyhold was due to be blown up in "an earlier version of the story". 
</p>
<p>
"Sten would arrive to arrest you for meddling with magic, but Dagna has reverse engineering their explosives," Rhodes wrote. "You leave a trap for when they return, sacrificing Skyhold in the process."
</p> <div>
<div data-domain="twitter.com"><blockquote><p dir="ltr" lang="en">From Inquisition’s Trespasser DLC<br>An earlier version of the story. Sten would arrive to arrest you for meddling with magic, but Dagna has reverse engineering their explosives. You leave a trap for when they return, sacrificing Skyhold in the process. <a href="https://t.co/0gTrLB4fiI">pic.twitter.com/0gTrLB4fiI</a></p>— Matt Rhodes (@mattrhodesart) <a href="https://twitter.com/mattrhodesart/status/1862140792527085614?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 28, 2024</a></blockquote></div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>
Long-term Dragon Age fans will remember Qunari warrior Sten from earlier games. Ultimately, he did not appear in Inquisition or Trespasser at all.
</p>
<p>
At a guess, it sounds like this might have happened at the start of Trespasser, which ultimately still does not feature Skyhold. Instead, it begins with the action moved elsewhere from the off.
</p>
<p>
The launch of <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/dragon-age-the-veilguard-walkthrough-tips-and-tricks-guide">Dragon Age: The Veilguard</a> has brought back a wave of nostalgia from developers who worked on the series previously, with insight from franchise creator David Gaider recently shining a light on the characters of <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/dragon-age-writer-probably-cried-harder-than-i-ever-have-in-my-life-writing-dorians-story">Dorian</a> and <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/dragon-age-creator-discusses-taking-on-inquisitions-cassandra-after-original-writer-left-amidst-abuse">Cassandra</a>.
</p>
<p>
Rhodes, meanwhile, previously shared concept art showing <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/bioware-had-dragon-age-the-veilguards-look-nailed-10-years-ago">BioWare had the look of Dragon Age: The Veilguard's Minrathous nailed down a decade ago</a>.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Fortnite Chapter 6 Trailer Leaks Early, Shows Off Godzilla]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/new-fortnite-chapter-6-trailer-leaks-early-shows-off-godzilla/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-fortnite-chapter-6-trailer-leaks-early-shows-off-godzilla.1048113/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/new-fortnite-chapter-6-trailer-leaks-early-shows-off-godzilla/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>A new Fortnite Chapter 6 launch trailer has leaked early, and has revealed that Godzilla and some other bosses will be making their way into the incredibly popular Battle Royale. The trailer has yet to be officially released by Epic Games, but data miners did what they do best and found it within the game files, as seen on the <a href="https://x.com/Guille_GAG" target="_blank" rel="noopener">X account Guille_GAG</a>.</p>
<p><iframe title="Fortnite Chapter 6 Official Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/gwo6rD62Gsc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>In this new gameplay trailer, you get to see a glimpse at some of the new skins and bosses that will be available in the upcoming Chapter. You also get to see Godzilla, who is walking around the map, according to the trailer. At the moment, it's uncertain whether Godzilla is a boss that you'll be able to take down in Fortnite, but considering that the new map is Japan-inspired, it seems likely that he will be. Some of the other bosses you get to see in the trailer include a samurai, a demon mask, and a giant turtle. Although considering how cute the giant turtle is, it's more hopeful that it's a form of transportation rather than something you have to take down.</p>
<p>Chapter 6 is going to be a pretty big deal in the Fortnite community, as it's set to revamp the game significantly. However, there are some features that are being brought back in this chapter that are familiar and have been in the game previously. This includes Samurai swords. From what little is seen in the trailer of them, it seems that they are used functionally the same as they were when they were previously in the game.</p>
<p>A Japan-inspired map isn't exactly new to Fortnite either, as there was a Japanese-themed biome in Chapter 4, and some of the architecture seen in the trailer feels very similar to the buildings in Chapter 4.</p>
<p>Moving on from similarities, Big Hero 6's Baymax will also be coming to Fortnite and will be available via the <a href="https://wccftech.com/fortnite-crew-grants-all-fortnite-passes-and-more-from-december-1/">Chapter 6 Season 1 battle pass</a>, where you'll get to do his signature 'Balalala' as an emote. There also seem to be some new Mask items that players will be able to get, as well as the ability to wall jump. This all seems very much to do with the Samurai vibe that they have going on in this new Chapter and will allow a new way to engage in combat as players will be able to climb over a wall and immediately start shooting or swinging their swords, as seen in the trailer.</p>
<p>Chapter 6 is set to launch this weekend, and it's likely we'll see some more details emerge about the upcoming Chapter in the next day or so.</p>

				

			
	<div>
		<h2>Products mentioned in this post</h2>
		
		<!--<p class="story-notice text-center">The links above are affiliate links. As an Amazon Associate, Wccftech.com may earn from qualifying purchases.</p>-->
	</div>

			
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Star Citizen Funding Passes $750m Amid Layoff Rumors]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/star-citizen-funding-750m</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/star-citizen-funding-passes-750m-amid-layoff-rumors.1048107/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/star-citizen-funding-750m<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Crowdfunding for space sim&nbsp;<em>Star Citizen&nbsp;</em>has passed yet another mammoth milestone, but rumors are flying that suggest things may not be rosy at developer Cloud Imperium Games.</p>

<p>A quick look at&nbsp;<em>Star Citizen</em>'s <a href="https://robertsspaceindustries.com/funding-goals" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">funding page</a> shows that the game has passed the eye-watering $750 million mark, meaning that cumulatively, players have given almost a billion dollars to&nbsp;<em>Star Citizen&nbsp;</em>since its crowdfunding campaign began in 2012.</p>

<p>The funding page is insistent in its declaration that funding for&nbsp;<em>Star Citizen&nbsp;</em>"goes directly to the game's development", although frankly, I can't quite envision a game that costs over $750 million to make and still hasn't been properly released after over a decade of development.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/star-citizen-funding-firefight.jpg?itok=lQpIjkE- 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/star-citizen-funding-firefight.jpg?itok=mbon8Z5b 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Believe it or not, people are still giving money to&nbsp;<em>Star Citizen</em>.</figcaption></figure><p>Not only is <i>Star Citizen</i>'s development continuing with no real sign of a 1.0 release, but rumors are flying that developer Cloud Imperium Games may actually be laying staff off.</p>

<p>According to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/cloud-imperium-games-layoffs-report/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Insider Gaming's Tom Henderson</a>, who cites an ex-CIG employee <a href="https://x.com/Gillyburd1" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">on social media platform X</a>&nbsp;(whose posts are locked for non-approved followers), Cloud Imperium has let "a lot of staff go over the last two days with zero compensation" following its annual CitizenCon event.</p>

<p>That's after the developer <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/star-citizen-debacle-crunch-report" rel="nofollow">reportedly mandated</a>&nbsp;seven-day work weeks for staff in the runup to CitizenCon, promising time off in lieu in return for working the weekends of October 5th and 12th. That report didn't seem to suggest that Cloud Imperium had offered staff a choice in this matter.</p>

<p>This isn't the first time Cloud Imperium has been in trouble in the last few months, either. Back in July, a tribunal found that the studio had <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/star-citizen-discrimination-tribunal" rel="nofollow">discriminated against a disabled worker</a> for mandating a return to the office without making adequate preparations for that worker's disability.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/star-citizen-funding-ship.jpg?itok=EpBD3f4j 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/star-citizen-funding-ship.jpg?itok=zAZy5mdg 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Star Citizen&nbsp;</em>is an odd project indeed.</figcaption></figure><p>In any case, if you do want to follow the development of&nbsp;<em>Star Citizen&nbsp;</em>or you'd like to give money to Cloud Imperium for some reason, you can <a href="https://robertsspaceindustries.com/star-citizen" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">do so here via the official website</a>.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Neverness To Everness Gets Limited Chinese Closed Beta Test]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/neverness-to-everness-gets-limited-chinese-closed-beta-test/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/neverness-to-everness-gets-limited-chinese-closed-beta-test.1048089/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/neverness-to-everness-gets-limited-chinese-closed-beta-test/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The upcoming title by Hotta Studio, Neverness to Everness, has officially launched its limited-scale Chinese Closed Beta Test that begins on November 28, 2024. This will allow players in China to explore the upcoming supernatural urban open-world RPG, and get to see some of the fresh new content that has been added by Hotta Studio. While other countries are currently unable to participate in the Closed Beta, anyone interested in the game will be able to <a href="https://nte.perfectworld.com/en/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">pre-register for Neverness to Everness</a> on the official website. There is also the option to stay up to date with any news that is released by Hotta Studio by following them on X or joining their Discord server.</p>
<p>For those who are just hearing about this game for the first time, it is a fresh and lighthearted game that is full of comedy rather than a game with a lot of serious subjects and tones. By doing so, the developers are aiming to create a relaxed atmosphere for those who play Neverness to Everness. The game's character expressions and animations have been fine-tuned to enhance each scene that players will get to watch so that the emotional nuances of each scene and humorous details can shine through in the storyline.</p>
<p>In this game, players will get to explore the everyday life of Hethereau, a city where there are both anomalies and humans co-existing. There are three chapters of main storyline content thus far and multiple side quests that players can dive into, allowing them to explore the urban life of Hethereau and the secrets that come along with it.</p>
<p>Neverness to Everness is developed using Unreal Engine 5 to help provide beautiful realism with a ton of detail, giving the players an immersive experience as they traverse the city and get to experience the supernatural. There are drastic changes between environments, with some offering neon-lit streets and marketplaces, while others are mysterious and dark, full of anomalies.</p>
<p>The <a href="https://wccftech.com/neverness-to-everness-is-a-new-gacha-open-world-rpg-from-tower-of-fantasy-devs-powered-by-ue5-with-nvidia-dlss-rtx/">initial reveal for this game was back in July</a>, and the developers have since added more characters for Beta testers to meet and try out. This includes Adler, who is a playable character, and Edgar, who is a member of the Eibon Antique Shop and will be accompanying the protagonist throughout their adventure in Hethereau.</p>
<p>Those who get the chance to participate in the Closed Beta test will get to experience some new chapter bosses, anomaly commission bosses, and, of course, new storyline content to provide them with an in-depth experience of what's to come in the full release of the game.</p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lies of P DLC Coming In Q1 2025, Devs Confirm Brand New IP In the Works]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/lies-of-p-dlc-q1-2025-new-ip</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/lies-of-p-dlc-coming-in-q1-2025-devs-confirm-brand-new-ip-in-the-works.1048086/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/lies-of-p-dlc-q1-2025-new-ip<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Lies of P&nbsp;</em>developer Neowiz has revealed that the game's long-awaited DLC expansion will be arriving sometime during the first quarter of next year, and there's more exciting news for Neowiz fans as well.</p>

<p>In a <a href="https://www.ebn.co.kr/news/articleView.html?idxno=1644423" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">statement</a> issued by the studio (thanks, <a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/lies-of-p-dlc-is-coming-in-the-first-quarter-of-2025-as-developer-confirms-next-its-game/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">VGC</a>), Neowiz confirms the release window for the upcoming&nbsp;<em>Lies of P&nbsp;</em>DLC, which was <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/lies-of-p-dlc-sequel" rel="nofollow">teased last November</a> following the game's release in September 2023. We still don't know what the DLC will be about or exactly when we can expect it, however.</p>

<p>When the DLC was first teased, Neowiz showed a couple of pieces of concept art related to the expansion, including what appeared to be protagonist P exploring a shipwreck, as well as an industrial facility with a giant pillar at its center.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/lies-of-p-dlc-q1-2025-fight.jpg?itok=qvKqI82K 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/lies-of-p-dlc-q1-2025-fight.jpg?itok=1tTr3Wc1 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Lies of P</em>'s DLC is coming in the first quarter of next year.</figcaption></figure><p>As well as confirming the release window for the&nbsp;<em>Lies of P&nbsp;</em>DLC, Neowiz also reveals what it's working on next in the statement, although again, further details are rather scarce.</p>

<p>Per VGC's translation, the studio is working on an entirely new IP that will take the form of a sci-fi survival horror game. The statement specifically namechecks the likes of 2023's <i>Dead Space&nbsp;</i>remake and Striking Distance's&nbsp;<em>The Callisto Protocol</em>, although let's hope Neowiz emulates the former rather than the latter <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/callisto-protocol-crunch-is-problem-with-100-hour-work-weeks" rel="nofollow">in terms of development process</a>.</p>

<p>We'll likely have to wait a while for more info on the new survival horror IP being worked on by Neowiz; it's likely the studio will be focusing on the&nbsp;<em>Lies of P&nbsp;</em>DLC for the immediate future. Still, a reveal at next year's Summer Game Fest might not be too much to hope for.</p>




<p>In case you haven't come across&nbsp;<em>Lies of P&nbsp;</em>before, it's a Soulslike that serves as a loose adaptation of the classic children's novel&nbsp;<em>The Adventures of Pinocchio&nbsp;</em>(although the emphasis is very much on "loose" here).</p>

<p>You play as P, a puppet created by Geppetto who, unlike other puppets, has the ability to lie. You must explore the fictional city of Krat in order to discover what happened to it, why its puppets have gone insane, and what, if anything, you can do to make things right.</p>

<p><em>Lies of P&nbsp;</em>proved very popular indeed, selling <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/lies-of-p-sales" rel="nofollow">a million copies</a> within its first month on release despite being a day one Game Pass title.</p>

<p>It's still available there and on <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-GB/games/lies-of-p" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Xbox consoles</a> generally, as well as on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1627720/Lies_of_P/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC</a> and <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-gb/games/lies-of-p/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PlayStation</a>. You can <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/lies-of-p-review" rel="nofollow">read my review here</a>.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokémon TCG Pocket's New Venusaur Event Features The Most Beautiful Card]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/pokemon-tcg-pocket-venusaur-drop-event-full-art-card-1851710232</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pok%C3%A9mon-tcg-pockets-new-venusaur-event-features-the-most-beautiful-card.1048083/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/pokemon-tcg-pocket-venusaur-drop-event-full-art-card-1851710232<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>After getting stale for a bit too long for a launch month, <em>Pokémon TCG Pocket</em> has finally launched a new event into its rather echoey corridors—the Venusaur Drop Event. And oh wow, it comes with a winnable card that’ll go straight to the top of your binder.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196165" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="What’s Coming Out Beyond Pokémon: The Indigo Disk | The Week In Games" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="95" data-playlist="196165,193974,196663" data-current="196165"><div><p>What’s Coming Out Beyond Pokémon: The Indigo Disk | The Week In Games</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196165/196165_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196165/196165_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196165/196165_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196165/196165_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21711.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>Much like the earlier <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/pokemon-tcg-pocket-lapras-drop-event-gacha-1851689506&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-tcg-pocket-lapras-drop-event-gacha-1851689506">Lapras Drop Event</a></span>, the Venusaur version is a collection of player vs. CPU battles, in which the game will play increasingly more powerful builds of decks based on the OG grass-type starter’s final evolution. Beating these gains you a clutch of awards, with extra bonuses to unlock if you re-battle each stage to complete specific missions.</p><p>And, much like the Lapras event, it’s bogged down by yet another bullshit in-game currency limiting how much you can play it, in the form of “Event Stamina (Solo)“ hourglasses. However, this time out it seems to be an awful lot more generous with the prizes it offers, throwing out handfuls of the item everyone actually wants—Pack Hourglasses—along with Wonder Stamina, Shinedust, Shop Tickets, and more Event Hourglasses to let you keep playing. Oh, and most importantly, it’s far kinder when it comes to handing out packs of the new Promo Pack A Series Vol. 2, in which you can pull a new set of stamped promo cards, including a wonderful new Venusaur full-art illustrated by Kuroimori.</p><p><strong>Read More:</strong>&nbsp;<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/pokemon-tcg-genetic-apex-best-cards-charizard-ex-1851698865&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-tcg-genetic-apex-best-cards-charizard-ex-1851698865">The Best Cards from Pokémon TCG Pocket’s Genetic Apex Expansion</a></span></p><p>It’s pretty rudimentary to complete a first run through all four levels. Unlike the Lapras deck, Venusaur builds haven’t exactly entered the meta for good reason, and it’s hopelessly weak to a half-decent Fire Type build. (If you’ve got the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/pokemon-tcg-pocket-best-decks-mewtwo-charizard-1851696181&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-tcg-pocket-best-decks-mewtwo-charizard-1851696181">Charizard/Moltres deck built</a></span>, you’ll hammer through it in minutes.) But that’s no bad thing, given you’ll also get a total of 20 Pack Hourglasses, meaning you can tear open at least one extra pack for the day, <em>and</em> four chances to open the one-card promo packs.</p><p>My son, who blitzed the event, was grimly unlucky, although that serves him right after he got a Lapras ex first pack in the previous drop event. I, however, then made him furious by pulling the new Venusaur not just in my first pack, but my second too! Haha, that <em>that</em>, ten-year-old.</p><p>You can then keep replaying the tiers, finishing other tasks like “Make your opponent’s Pokémon Asleep 1 time,” or “Win this battle by turn 12,” which will reward you Wonder Stamina and Event Hourglasses, and given the “Win 20 or more battles” task on the top tier, also give you a new grind until the event is over on December 13.</p><p>There are five cards to pull from the promo packs, each with art that’s not been in <em>Pocket</em> before (although some familiar from the real-world cards). There’s Haunter, Jigglypuff, Onix, Greninja, and that splendid Venusaur. It’s just a shame the latter is spoiled by having the big, ugly blue box obscuring the image, madly overlapping the actual Venusaur itself. Dammit.</p><p>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[STALKER 2 1.0.1 Patch Addresses Durability, Difficulty, and Dead Zones]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/stalker-2-101-patch-durability-difficulty-dead-zones/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/stalker-2-1-0-1-patch-addresses-durability-difficulty-and-dead-zones.1048080/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/stalker-2-101-patch-durability-difficulty-dead-zones/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>STALKER 2’s massive 1.0.1 patch is here and it’s set to address 650 issues in the post-apocalyptic epic from GSC Game World. The update is live now on Xbox and PC and it effectively eradicates some of the biggest issues from the game, including controller dead zone problems, mutant difficulty, and weapon durability.</p>



<p>This is the second update of this size since STALKER 2 was released, and it stands as a testament to GSC’s desire to finesse the game as much as possible to appease the community.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-stalker-2-s-1-0-1-patch-is-insane">STALKER 2’s 1.0.1 Patch is Insane</h2>



<p>The full patch notes can be found on Steam, but I’ll sum up some of the most exciting changes coming with the STALKER 2 1.0.1 patch.</p>



<p>First, weapon and armour durability has been tweaked, which means that things won’t break as quickly and when they do, it won’t cost so much to fix things. That means you won’t be paying 20,000 Coupons to fix a single assault rifle anymore.</p>



<p>Also, GSC has addressed the monetary rewards you get from ‘most’ missions, giving you a few more Coupons in your pocket to play with.</p>



<p>Mutants have been tweaked – especially on lower difficulty levels – to make them much more bearable, including the Burer and Bloodsucker, which have been giving players headaches since day one.</p>



<p>This will please Xbox players: GSC has fixed the issue with gamepad dead zones. This has been a niggling problem since the game was released on November 20, and it can finally be put to bed.</p>



<p>Amongst the 650 bug fixes sits changes to almost every aspect of the game, from combat sequences to cutscenes, and from audio elements to quests. GSC has been hard at work to fix problems with AI interactions, UI problems, and blockers that prevent players from progressing through certain missions.</p>



<p>If you were concerned that STALKER 2 launched in a terrible condition, updates like the 1.0.1 patch should be starting to change your mind. </p>



<p>I still maintain this is my Game of the Year.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-chapter-6-launch/">Godzilla is coming to Fortnite</a>, and don’t forget to stop by the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sony May Find It Hard to Buy All of FromSoftware Parent Company Kadokawa, Financial Report Claims]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/sony-may-find-it-hard-to-buy-all-of-fromsoftware-parent-company-kadokawa-financial-report-claims</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sony-may-find-it-hard-to-buy-all-of-fromsoftware-parent-company-kadokawa-financial-report-claims.1048077/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/sony-may-find-it-hard-to-buy-all-of-fromsoftware-parent-company-kadokawa-financial-report-claims<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">As <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/fromsoftware-parent-kadokawa-confirms-sonys-buyout-intent-but-insists-no-decision-has-been-made-at-this-time">Sony’s pursuit of Kadokawa rumbles on</a>, financial experts have said the PlayStation maker may find it hard to buy the entirety of FromSoftware’s parent company.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Japan’s <a href="https://toyokeizai.net/articles/-/842757" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Toyo Keizai</a> (via <a href="https://automaton-media.com/en/news/the-cost-of-buying-out-kadokawa-entirely-could-discourage-sony-from-acquisition-deal-says-japanese-finance-outlet/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Automaton</a>) reported that Sony may be put off the deal due to the cost of having to acquire all of Kadokawa, rather than the parts it’s actually interested in.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Kadokawa is reportedly only interested in doing a deal with Sony if it buys the entire company. Sony, however, is reportedly only interested in “extracting” assets related to anime and video games, which presumably includes the developer of Elden Ring.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Buying all of Kadokawa would cost 640 billion yen (approx $4.3 billion), according to expert estimates. Sony’s cash for buyouts is apparently tight at the moment due to investments made elsewhere. As a point of comparison, Sony bought Destiny developer Bungie for $3.7 billion back in 2022. The studio has since suffered multiple rounds of layoffs and project cancelations.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">There’s also the apparent prospect of a bidding war that would cause Kadokawa’s sale price to soar beyond Sony’s limit. The alternative is for Sony to buy 50% of Kadokawa and turn it into a subsidiary it doesn’t wholly own.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Kadokawa’s business extends into areas that fit into Sony’s broader entertainment offering, which includes anime, manga, TV, and film. Kadokawa is a prolific publisher of anime, and Sony already owns anime streamers Crunchyroll and Funimation. As well as FromSoftware, Kadokawa owns Danganronpa developer Spike Chunsoft, Octopath Traveler developer Acquire, and RPG Maker and Pixel Game Maker developer Gotcha Gotcha Games. Kadokawa is the majority owner of FromSoftware, with around 70% of the company. Sony already owns around 14% of the developer, with Tencent owning around 16%.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Piers Harding-Rolls, Research Director at Ampere Analysis, told IGN that news of a potential deal isn’t that surprising. "Sony’s interest in Kadokawa’s games publisher FromSoftware was made more concrete in 2022 when it acquired a roughly 14% share of the company following up on its long-time collaboration with the company," Harding-Rolls said.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"At the time, Sony mentioned a broader interest in cross-media development of anime and games IP to support its other media businesses. So, in that sense any deal for the parent company Kadokawa, which also operates extensively in manga and anime, is a natural extension of this earlier deal. These other areas align nicely with Sony’s anime businesses.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"The market conditions for acquisitions have changed dramatically over the last two years but Sony will always be looking for opportunities that can fuel its growth and that bolster its IP portfolio, and that represent value. There may also be a defensive element to this move. FromSoftware is an important partner for Sony’s games business, and it will not want a competitor taking control of Kadokawa and potentially disrupting that relationship. It helps that Kadokawa is also active in areas which are a strong fit with Sony’s wider business."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">For Sony, its gaming business has already suffered significant layoffs this year and the closure of multiple studios, including <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/sony-says-it-should-have-done-user-testing-and-internal-evaluation-earlier-on-concord"><u>Concord developer Firewalk</u></a>. In February, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/sony-announces-significant-playstation-layoffs-affecting-900-staff-london-studio-to-close"><u>it announced a round of layoffs</u></a> affecting 900 staff, or about 8% of its global PlayStation workforce. The layoffs impacted a number of PlayStation studios, including Insomniac, Naughty Dog, Guerrilla, and Firesprite, but PlayStation's London studio was hit hardest with a notice of closure.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Photo by Yui Mok/PA Images via Getty Images.</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tencent Plans to Release Light of Motiram, Which Some Say Is a 'Rip-Off' of Sony’s Horizon Games, on PS5]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/tencent-plans-to-release-light-of-motiram-which-some-say-is-a-rip-off-of-sonys-horizon-games-on-ps5</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/tencent-plans-to-release-light-of-motiram-which-some-say-is-a-rip-off-of-sony%E2%80%99s-horizon-games-on-ps5.1048074/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/tencent-plans-to-release-light-of-motiram-which-some-say-is-a-rip-off-of-sonys-horizon-games-on-ps5<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Tencent has announced plans to release <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/new-tencent-game-accused-of-ripping-off-sonys-horizon-series">its controversial open-world survival crafting game Light of Motiram</a> on PS5 as well as mobile and PC.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As reported by <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2024/11/light-of-motiram-adds-ps5-ios-and-android-versions-reveal-trailer-and-16-minutes-of-gameplay" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Gematsu</a>, Tencent announced the PS5 version on PlayStation‘s Chinese social network accounts on Weibo and Bilibili.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Light of Motiram, from Shanghai-based Tencent subsidiary Polaris Quest, is a free-to-play survival game “where nature meets machine.” Screenshots and gameplay videos reveal a visual style remarkably similar to Guerrilla Games’ Horizon Zero Dawn and Forbidden West, complete with robot beasts in a post-apocalyptic setting. IGN has asked Tencent and Sony for comment.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Today, Tencent revealed a new seven-minute video showing more of Light of Motiram’s gameplay. After an intro that rekindles memories of Destiny’s famous Ghost ‘wake up, Guardian’ opening, we see gameplay that looks heavily inspired by the likes of Capcom’s Monster Hunter and Pocketpair’s Palworld, which itself was accused of “ripping off” Pokémon.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Light of Motiram lets players befriend and raise various ‘mechanimals’ alone or with friends. You need to set up a base camp and ride tamed mechanimals as mounts, getting them to help with logging, farming, and crafting. Mechanimals can serve as ground, air, and water mounts, help in combat, and assist with resource gathering.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Tencent said Light of Motiram has hundreds of realistic survival gameplay mechanics. “Trees need to be carefully cut down else they deliver a swift death, a shelter has to be ventilated before lighting a fire so as not to choke, and lightning may strike (more than a few times) if you’re caught wearing metal in a storm,” the company said. “These realistic details can be used to players’ advantage, as for example lightning damage can electrocute fishes and make the process of fishing much easier and faster.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">While this sort of multiplayer survival gameplay is not featured in the Horizon games, the look and feel of Light of Motiram’s characters, monsters, and world are undeniably similar. Guerrilla is of course working on <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/live-service-game-horizon-online-reportedly-guerrillas-next-project-horizon-3-might-be-a-ways-off"><u>a multiplayer, live service Horizon game</u></a> - Light of Motiram may be treading on its toes somewhat, although we’ll have to wait for a reveal to find out.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Riot Games will now ban creators for bad conduct even if it's not said in-game]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/riot-games-will-now-ban-creators-for-bad-conduct-even-if-its-not-said-in-game</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/riot-games-will-now-ban-creators-for-bad-conduct-even-if-its-not-said-in-game.1048071/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/riot-games-will-now-ban-creators-for-bad-conduct-even-if-its-not-said-in-game<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        

        <p>"If a creator uses hateful slurs on their stream but not in-game, we can still issue a penalty."</p>

    </div><div>



            <p>From 3rd January 2025, Riot Games will ban content creators for bad "off-platform conduct".</p>
<p>In a message posted to Valorant's social media channels, the developer said that "if a creator uses hateful slurs about an opposing player or teammate on their stream" - even if it's not via its in-game comms - it will "still issue a penalty as if that behaviour occurred in-game".</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Keeping Our Community Healthy // Dev Updates" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/B9A4L4ZoWN8?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Keeping Our Community Healthy // Dev Updates</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/B9A4L4ZoWN8?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/B9A4L4ZoWN8?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Keeping Our Community Healthy: Dev Updates.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=B9A4L4ZoWN8" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>"Our intention with this update is to help protect players from harmful behaviours they can experience across the various places that touch their gaming experience," Riot explained.</p>
<p>"This update applies very specifically and only to content where Riot's games are the background of the content produced. Though we aren't going to proactively monitor everything that happens across social media, it is now within our rights to issue penalties in-game when that content is brought to our attention."</p> <div>
<div data-domain="twitter.com"><blockquote><div dir="ltr" lang="en"><p>Riot Games will now ban content creators that engage in "Off-Platform Conduct" - specifically when Riot's games are in the background </p><p>Example: "if a creator uses hateful slurs about an opposing player or teammate on their stream, but not in game over chat or voice comms, we can… <a href="https://t.co/GBiKgx78A8">pic.twitter.com/GBiKgx78A8</a></p></div>— Valorant News (@ValorINTEL) <a href="https://twitter.com/ValorINTEL/status/1861902078261830090?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 27, 2024</a></blockquote></div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>"As an example, if a creator uses hateful slurs about an opposing player or teammate on their stream, but not in-game over chat or voice comms, we can still issue a penalty as if that behaviour occurred in-game.</p>
<p>"TL;DR - if you say or do things that break our Terms of Service while broadcasting or creating content about our games, we can restrict access to your Riot accounts (and suspend your Partner privileges if you are part of our Partner Program)."</p><p>This is just the latest initiative from Riot to clamp down on toxicity in its playerbase. In a frank discussion about the "current state of player behaviour" in Valorant earlier this year, Riot Games' head Anna Donlon <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/valorant-studio-head-tells-toxic-players-to-play-something-else-we-wont-miss-you">outlined upcoming changes designed "to make our community a better place"</a>.</p>
<p>Though Donlon acknowledged at the time that the development team had no plans to "sanitise gaming" or suppress harmless banter, she said players should not be expected to "grow a thicker skin" when playing video games.</p>
<p>"There's no room in our community for the most egregious behaviours, and we're not going to compromise on that point," she said.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Watch Dogs: Legion sequel is a choose your own adventure Audible series]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/watch-dogs-legion-sequel-is-a-choose-your-own-adventure-audible-series</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/watch-dogs-legion-sequel-is-a-choose-your-own-adventure-audible-series.1048065/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/watch-dogs-legion-sequel-is-a-choose-your-own-adventure-audible-series<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>Starring several people from Doctor Who.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/watch-dogs-truth-2400x2400-master-final-no-violator-1-1732790569026-(1).jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Ubisoft</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
<a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/watch-dogs">Watch Dogs</a>: Legion, the game which imagined a post-Brexit London that wasn't too far off from the truth, is getting a follow-up - but it's not a video game. 
</p>
<p>
Instead, Watch Dogs: Truth is an audio drama series available via Audible, with choose-your-own-adventure elements that let you pick various options at the end of every episode.
</p>
<p>
Truth once again delves into the London-based activities of hacktivist group DeadSec, featuring returning character Bagley - a sentient AI.
</p>
<p>
Joining the cast for Truth are a number of names you might have heard of or seen before: Doctor Who companion Freema Agyeman (she played Martha opposite David Tennant, and also popped up in Torchwood), Russell Tovey (who played Alonso in that Titanic episode with Kylie Minogue, though is really more famous for Being Human) and David Morrisey (yes, he was The Governor in The Walking Dead, but he also played someone who thought he was The Doctor in another David Tennant Doctor Who Christmas special).
</p>
<p>
Also in the cast are T'Nia Miller and Gary Beadle. I don't believe either of them have been in Doctor Who.
</p>
<p>
"Listeners of this thrilling story will once again join the fight for truth whilst guided by the self-aware AI, Bagley, as they make decisions at the end of each episode, with choices that shape the hacking collective's next move, profoundly impact character relationships and ultimately, the success of the resistance effort," Ubisoft says of Watch Dogs: Truth.
</p><p>
"Across the series, listeners will have the fate of the city in their own hands, as the government's cyber intelligence force (SIRS) orchestrates a sinister campaign of message manipulation and fake news, which leads DedSec to fight back using its revered tactics to battle against alarming disinformation."
</p>
<p>
<a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/assassins-creed-golds-blind-assassin-hero-provides-the-perfect-formula-for-audio-drama">Ubisoft previously partnered with Audible for Assassin's Creed Gold</a>, a series that cleverly featured a blind hero (played by Star Wars: Rogue One's Riz Ahmed), with Buffy the Vampire Slayer's Anthony Head as Sir Issac Newton. (Head was also in Doctor Who.)
</p>
<p>
While there's no sign at all that Ubisoft is working on a Watch Dogs 4, the publisher is clearly keen to keep the brand alive via other means. 
</p>
<p>
Nearly a decade after its first announcement, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/watch-dogs-movie-finally-finishes-filming">Ubisoft's mysterious Watch Dogs movie finally finished filming in September</a>.

</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lies of P DLC to Launch in Q1 2025; NEOWIZ Now Working on a Sci-Fi Survival Horror Game]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/lies-of-p-dlc-to-launch-in-q1-2025-neowiz-now-working-on-a-sci-fi-survival-horror-game/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/lies-of-p-dlc-to-launch-in-q1-2025-neowiz-now-working-on-a-sci-fi-survival-horror-game.1048050/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/lies-of-p-dlc-to-launch-in-q1-2025-neowiz-now-working-on-a-sci-fi-survival-horror-game/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The <a href="https://wccftech.com/lies-of-p-dlc-2024/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Lies of P DLC</a> isn't coming before the end of the year. We kind of guessed it due to the lack of news, but Korean website EBN now <a href="https://www.ebn.co.kr/news/articleView.html?idxno=1644423" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reports</a> today that NEOWIZ confirmed it will be available in the first quarter of 2025.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the studio is recruiting level designers and scenario planners for a new survival horror game set in a sci-fi universe. The title will be made with Unreal Engine 5 and released for PC and consoles.</p>
<p>The report also claims that NEOWIZ is in 'dire need' of a new success. While Lies of P <a href="https://wccftech.com/lies-of-p-sold-over-1-million-units-in-less-than-a-month-despite-being-on-game-pass/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">performed well last year</a>, selling a million units in less than a month despite being available on the Game Pass subscription service, this year the company did not have any major release in its lineup, which led to a 21% decrease in sales and a 68% decrease in operating profit.</p>
<p>Perhaps that's why the Korean studio recently <a href="https://wccftech.com/lies-of-p-studio-will-publish-an-upcoming-noir-western-rpg-from-ex-cdpr-developers/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">signed</a> a publishing deal with Polish developer ZAKAZANE, founded by former CD Projekt RED developers. NEOWIZ will publish their upcoming single-player noir Western roleplaying game.</p>
<p>Lies of P earned an 8 out of 10 score here on Wccftech from Francesco De Meo, who <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/lies-of-p-review/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">wrote</a>:</p>
<p><em>Wearing its influences on its sleeves, Lies of P is a solid imitation of FromSoftware's Bloodborne that manages to stay fun for the entire duration of a single playthrough of around 20 hours despite a marked lack of innovation. While the callbacks and nods to the game that inspired it may be a little too blatant, NEOWIZ has developed a solid game that all soulslike fans can enjoy if they can keep their expectations in check.</em></p>
<p><em>Not even attempting to hide the massive influence Bloodborne has had on it, Lies of P is a solid imitation of the game developed by FromSoftware. While it lacks the same combat and world design finesse of its illustrious inspiration, the action role-playing game by NEOWIZ is among the most accomplished soulslike game released this year, thanks to its dark retelling of the story of Pinocchio, combat and character customization tweaks and great enemy design.</em></p>

				

			
	<div>
		<h2>Products mentioned in this post</h2>
		
		<!--<p class="story-notice text-center">The links above are affiliate links. As an Amazon Associate, Wccftech.com may earn from qualifying purchases.</p>-->
	</div>

			
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Zelda: Ocarina of Time Unreal Engine 5.5 Fan Made Remake Demo Showcases Stunning Recreation of the Road to the Great Fairy]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/zelda-ocarina-of-time-unreal-engine-5-5-remake-download/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/zelda-ocarina-of-time-unreal-engine-5-5-fan-made-remake-demo-showcases-stunning-recreation-of-the-road-to-the-great-fairy.1048038/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/zelda-ocarina-of-time-unreal-engine-5-5-remake-download/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>A new playable demo of The Legend of Zelda: Ocarina of Time Unreal Engine 5.5. fan made remake by CryZENx is now available for download, allowing fans to experience another remade portion of the classic game by Nintendo.</p>
<p>The demo, which can be downloaded <a href="https://www.patreon.com/posts/116896739?utm_campaign=postshare_creator" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here</a>, features a short sequence starting with the Ging Dodongo fight and ending shortly after reaching the Great Fairy and getting the magic bar. What makes these short sequences impressive is the accurate recreation of both the visuals and gameplay mechanics of the classic, making this demo a must-play for those wanting to experience a small portion of the classic entry in the series in a modernized way.</p>
<p>The Zelda: Ocarina of Time Unreal Engine 5.5. remake creator CryZENx also shared a video showcasing the demo. You can find it right below.</p>
<p><iframe title="Unreal Engine 5 [5.5] Zelda Ocarina Of Time - Road To Great Fairy + Download link" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/G7gtm-pSW3Q?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>CryZENx has been working on this The Legend of Zelda: Ocarina of Time Unreal Engine 5 remake for a good while, showing time and time again what an <a href="https://wccftech.com/zelda-ocarina-of-time-remake-comparison/">excellent job they are doing</a>. While there's no doubt Nintendo would shut down the project if it were ever released as a full game, hopefully, the Japanese company will take note of it and release a proper, modern remake of the game for one of its future gaming systems.</p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dave the Diver Sales Top 5m]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/dave-diver-sales-5m</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dave-the-diver-sales-top-5m.1048035/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/dave-diver-sales-5m<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Developer and publisher Mintrocket has announced that&nbsp;<em>Dave the Diver&nbsp;</em>sales have crossed another big milestone, further cementing the diving adventure's popularity.</p>

<p>In <a href="https://x.com/DaveDiverGame/status/1862090754769998006" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">a post on social media platform X</a>, Mintrocket confirms that&nbsp;<em>Dave the Diver&nbsp;</em>has sold five million copies, thanking players for all of their "love and support". The studio also posts a lyric that appears to be a reference to&nbsp;Bruno Mars and Rosé's song "Apt", namely "sleep tomorrow but tonight go diving".</p>

<p>In January this year, Mintrocket revealed that&nbsp;<em>Dave the Diver&nbsp;</em>sales <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/dave-diver-sales-3-million" rel="nofollow">had hit three million</a>, so that means that in the intervening months (since not even a year has passed since that announcement), the game has gone on to sell another two million copies.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/dave-the-diver-sales-5m-diving.jpg?itok=N0Rs-DBQ 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/dave-the-diver-sales-5m-diving.jpg?itok=aQFuvLbS 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>It's been a strong year for&nbsp;<em>Dave the Diver&nbsp;</em>in sales terms, it seems.</figcaption></figure><p>That number is especially impressive if we consider two things. First,&nbsp;<em>Dave the Diver&nbsp;</em>isn't available on Xbox, so all of these sales have come from PC, Switch, and PlayStation.</p>

<p>Secondly, when&nbsp;<em>Dave the Diver&nbsp;</em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/dave-diver-ps5-release-date-ps-plus" rel="nofollow">launched on PS5 back in April</a>, it also hit PlayStation Plus on day one, so subscribers have the chance to play the game at no extra cost. Even still, many have clearly bought the game rather than taking to Sony's subscription service to check it out.</p>

<p>Of course, Mintrocket doesn't provide an exact breakdown of where the sales have come from in its post, so we don't know what proportion of those sales are PlayStation and how many are PC players.</p>




<p>If you're not familiar with&nbsp;<em>Dave the Diver</em>, it's an adventure game-come-management sim in which you play as the titular Dave. You must dive into the ocean to gather ingredients and explore the world by day, then manage your sushi restaurant by night.</p>

<p>The game, which was developed by Nexon division Mintrocket, sparked some debate when it was <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/game-awards-2023-nominees-announced-baldurs-gate-3-alan-wake-2-are-most-nominated" rel="nofollow">nominated for Best Indie Game</a> at the 2023 Game Awards, although it eventually lost to Sabotage's JRPG homage&nbsp;<em>Sea of Stars</em>.</p>

<p>Still, since Nexon <a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/nexon-spins-off-dave-the-diver-dev-mintrocket-into-a-full-corporation" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">spun Mintrocket off into its own entity</a> in September (albeit one that's still a subsidiary), perhaps that indie label is slightly more warranted now. I'd argue not, but there we are.</p>

<p><em>Dave the Diver&nbsp;</em>is available to check out now on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1868140/DAVE_THE_DIVER/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC</a>, <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-us/games/dave-the-diver/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PlayStation</a>, and <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/us/store/products/dave-the-diver-switch/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Nintendo Switch</a>.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Noisy shooter Selaco adds a new game mode, turns kitchenware into weaponry, and teases plans for chapter 2]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/noisy-shooter-selaco-adds-a-new-game-mode-turns-kitchenware-into-weaponry-and-teases-plans-for-chapter-2</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/noisy-shooter-selaco-adds-a-new-game-mode-turns-kitchenware-into-weaponry-and-teases-plans-for-chapter-2.1048032/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/noisy-shooter-selaco-adds-a-new-game-mode-turns-kitchenware-into-weaponry-and-teases-plans-for-chapter-2<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
  

        <p>The developers have been spinning plates</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/selaco-out-now-1.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Altered Orbit Studios</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>You can now knock down enemy dirtbags using a dinner plate as a violent frisbee in <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/selaco">Selaco</a>. Wonderful. The first-person shooter, which is replete with satisfying explosions, gunfire, bullet ricochets, smashing glass, sparks, goo, blood spatters, dust, ice particles, smoke, flecks of plaster, and bad guys yelling at one another about how <em>she's over there</em>, may be described as noisy, both in the aural and visual sense of the word. Which is how we like it, you understand. This latest update to the early access shooter leans into that by layering on even more juicy shootFX. It also adds a whole new game mode and plenty of other tweaks. The bad news is that some story bits are now delayed.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>First things first - the new "Special Campaign" mode is basically the shooter's equivalent of new game plus. It will let players replay the campaign (as it exists so far) "but with unique Endgame Content and Randomization," say developers Altered Orbit in <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1592280/view/4702411539870497570">the update post</a>. It'll add random enemy encounters and give weapons ARPG style rarity colours, among other tweakable settings.</p>
<p>There were plans to call this "Randomizer" mode but it seems the devs have redesigned and rebranded it. As with classic examples of new game plus, you'll need to have already completed the game to unlock this new special mode (or, in this case, chapter one of the campaign - what exists of the game so far). </p>
<p>But more fun than this new mode, for me, are the ways the <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/fear">F.E.A.R.</a>-like enemy patrol goons have been further improved. Like I've mentioned, they'll fall over when you throw a plate at them, but also now stumble if you blast them in the leg. They'll take increased damage when frozen by frosty grenades, and make more callouts to one another when looking for the player (for example, they will now yell about your flashlight giving you away). </p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Selaco - Launch Trailer (Early Access)" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/bFI1QSd4T2g?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Selaco - Launch Trailer (Early Access)</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/bFI1QSd4T2g?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/bFI1QSd4T2g?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bFI1QSd4T2g" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>There's a miscellany of other improvements, such as snappier Halo-style melee attacks, and a bunch of balancing to various firearms. There are also many bug fixes. "Throwing toilets against enemies no longer crashes the game," we're told. "Fixed a rare bug where enemies killed by electricity would instead become invincible." God, I love patch notes.</p><p>As for the noise - there's more of that too. "Improved oomph for Fire Extinguisher explosions," yell the patch notes enthusiastically. "Improved sound effect when walking over glass," another note screams. "Went nuts on the audio design for bullet impacts and whizzes," a third note whispers, but with a manic and delighted look that implies there is a landmine nearby. Don't worry, the mine's explosive radius has been nerfed by almost 50%. You'll be fine.</p>
<p>It's a fairly hefty update, which the developer cites as the reason for a delay in the story stuff that was planned to get players closer to their protagonist. Narrative additions they <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/noisy-shooter-selaco-is-steam-deck-verified-with-new-story-stuff-ai-improvements-and-randomizer-modes-in-the-works">previously mentioned</a> include "a major voice-over pass to flesh out Dawn as a character, the world of Selaco and the general plot". That was planned for the end of this year, but it's been pushed back a couple months to January or February next year, say the devs. In the meantime, work on the second chapter of the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-fps-games">FPS</a> "continues to progress rapidly," they say, dropping hints of deployable turrets, miniguns, and... is that a mech suit? Interesting.</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/selaco-chapter-2-tease-mech-suit.jpeg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Altered Orbit Studios</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>If Selaco's many additions and alterations are sometimes difficult to follow, it's partly because the devs don't use a roadmap like other studios might during early access. "Roadmaps tend to have a negative effect on development/work," they've <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/?emclan=103582791469846912&amp;emgid=4374768959778727710">said in the past</a>. "Experimentation with new ideas takes time, while roadmaps are schedule-focused and don't allow for such things."</p><p>However they're doing things, it seems to be working just fine. Ed liked Selaco when he <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/selaco-early-access-review">reviewed the first early access build</a>, calling it a work of impressive "GZDoom wizardry" and praising those cunning AI enemies. Here's what he had to say about the running and/or gunning.</p>
<blockquote>Firefights are a festival of debris, where it rains printer paper and computer monitors crackle and alien troops coat everything in a sticky purple gunk when you explode them. While the result of your bullets can be quite chaotic, gunfights straddle the line between tactical and balls-to-the-wall boomer shooter really well...</blockquote>
<p>It's currently <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1592280/Selaco/">discounted in Steam's Autumn sale</a>, if you like a bit of noise.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>