<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 16:21:08 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Poll: What's Your Favourite Gen 5 Pokémon?]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/features/poll-whats-your-favourite-gen-5-pokemon</link>
            <guid>1439392</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Unova one</p>
</section></header><section>
<figure data-uuid="9905e20379f68"><a title="Pokemon White 2" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/9905e20379f68/pokemon-white-2.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Jim Norman / Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure><p>Pokémon turns 30 on 27th February, and in honour of this momentous anniversary, we're running a series of polls leading up to the big day, asking you to vote for your favourite Pokémon from each generation. The nine winners will then go head-to-head in a final poll at the end of the month.</p>
<p>We're covering a generation a day until we've ticked off all nine, leading up to the ultimate showdown. <strong>Each poll will be open for five days</strong>.</p>
<p>It's Day Five, and Gen V (or 5 if the Roman numerals are a bit fancy-pants for your tastes) is up, meaning 'mon from Unova and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/ds/pokemon_diamond_and_pearl">Pokémon Black &amp; White</a> and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/ds/pokemon_black_and_white_2">Black &amp; White 2</a>. Let's check in with Team NL for their underdog picks.</p><div><figure data-videoid="Mh1U8qC_TUE" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Mh1U8qC_TUE?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><div><iframe id="ytMh1U8qC_TUE" title="YouTube Video" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/Mh1U8qC_TUE?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Mh1U8qC_TUE?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed38e70bitwoxq&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>842k</span></a></p>
</div></figure></div>




<p>Let's crack on. We've got a chunky 156 new Pokémon this generation, listed in National Dex order (use the search bar to quickly find a specific Pokémon). As always, <strong>you can only choose one!</strong></p>

<hr>
<p><em>Thanks for voting! Keep an eye out for further generations in the coming days as we cruise towards Pokémon's 30th anniversary.</em></p>
<p><em>And if you missed Gens 1, 2, 3, or 4, those polls are still live:<br></em></p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/pokemon/related-articles:197281,197283,197402,197536,197566 @ 1771430402 --></section></article><div><p>Gavin first wrote for Nintendo Life in 2018 before joining the site full-time the following year, rising through the ranks to become Editor. He can currently be found squashed beneath a Switch backlog the size of Normandy.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/dartmonkey"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('dartmonkey');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/features/poll-whats-your-favourite-gen-5-pokemon]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[People of Note Preview - Measuring Up Nicely]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/people-of-note-preview</link>
            <guid>1439389</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>I played <em>Guitar Hero 3: Legends of Rock</em> constantly as a kid. I was hopeless using the guitar controller, and even had to use a standard controller. But what I remember most was how it introduced me to so many different songs. It was my first introduction to rock artists like Rage Against the Machine, and an obvious love letter to the whole art form. I got similar vibes from my hour and a half hands-on demo and preview event with <em>People of Note</em>.&nbsp;</p><p>A turn-based RPG all about music, Cadence and her band use the power of music while traversing the aptly-named land of Note. After my time with the game, I'm intrigued by the high notes, but worried by a few miscues.</p><h2>Systems That Sing</h2><p><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/measures-pon-1.jpg?itok=gtRNko7w 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="1080">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/measures-pon-1.jpg?itok=hsCvSO3M 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture>It should be noted first and foremost, as it was at our preview event, that <em>People of Note </em>is a music RPG, not a rhythm RPG. Other games, like the recent <em>UNBEATABLE</em>, have music as a part of the plot and heavily as part of the gameplay. <em>People of Note </em>is all about music, but in the gameplay itself, rhythm is about as present as <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/clair-obscur-expedition-33-review-french-revolution" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="07f3b1f2-234f-4782-8556-c21c1fb23302" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow"><em>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</em></a><em> </em>attacks.</p><p>For a game all about creativity, I found the more technical parts of the game to be where it shone brightest. In the game's combat, I was really impressed by the game's turn order system. In a mechanic that <em>Final Fantasy X </em>seemed to solve, I felt there were some really creative things happening in <em>People of Note</em>.</p><p>Turns are measured in stanzas, and each turn is a measure. The number of turns you get is determined by a "time signature," where the top number is the amount of turns for your team and the bottom is for the enemy. Later fights in the demo even had modifications made to select measures. What at first seems to be a cosmetic choice seems to actually be one of its best mechanical ideas.</p><p>Management outside of combat allows a lot of creativity as well. <em>People of Note</em>'s Songstone system is a near one-to-one rip of <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/features/ranking-all-of-magic-gathering-final-fantasy-legendary-creatures-part-2" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="83fd60e7-1407-46f1-ac0b-60b876ec8285" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow"><em>Final Fantasy 7</em></a>'s Materia. That's not a bad thing at all, as it lets you build characters exactly as you want. Even in my hour and a half playtime, I was able to build characters with clear archetypes, with pop star Cadence as my primary damage dealer and the rocker Fret playing support with stat boosts and healing.</p><p>Speaking of characters, the character design is superb. The way Cadence's popstar look clashes with the rock-themed land the demo takes place in makes me really excited about the characters we've yet to meet. The developer at our preview event mentioned that each area in the game is themed after a different genre, and I'm really hoping we get to see a Classical crew decked out with powdered wigs and everything.</p><h2>A Few Sour Notes</h2><p><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/freebird-people-of-note-1.jpg?itok=fRe82oO5 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="1080">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/freebird-people-of-note-1.jpg?itok=AcBAziUR 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture>Outside of the combat, there were a few places that felt like a miss. The dungeon in the demo felt very ho-hum, and navigating it was a real chore. With a good amount of backtracking required, it was easy to get disoriented in similar looking rooms, and the environmental puzzles were pretty by the numbers. It was nice to look at, but it was mostly repetitive and frustrating.</p><p>My other gripe was with the humor. There are puns <em>everywhere </em>in Note, and they start as fun and make some great environmental gags. In dialogue and songs themselves, though, they don't land quite as well. It's clear there's a sincerity behind the jokes, but it just feels like they're far too frequent. Though perhaps it's a little fitting that a love letter to music has band kid humor.</p><h2>People of Note Preview | Final Thoughts</h2><p><em>People of Note </em>went from a relative unknown for me to a game I'm at least intrigued by. I could see its dungeon design and punny dialogue wearing me down quite a bit during its runtime. However, I think its sincerity and sharp systems are interesting and rife with potential.</p><p><em>Guitar Hero </em>was always a love letter to rock. <em>People of Note </em>is striving to be a love letter not to a genre, but to a medium, complete with full musical numbers and loads of variety. It's a huge undertaking, and a big swing for a small team to take. The one certainty I have after my time with <em>People of Note</em>: it's ambitious as hell, and that's enough for me to see it through.</p><hr><p><em><strong>People of Note</strong> was previewed on PC using a copy provided by the publisher over the course of an hour and a half of gameplay.</em></p></div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Parker is a freelance writer based in Iowa, and the co-founder and editor of gaming satire site Palette Swap. Before Palette Swap, he was an editor at Hard… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/parker-johnson">More about Parker</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/people-of-note-preview]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Love Eternal Review - Centuries of Damn]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/love-eternal-review-centuries-of-damn</link>
            <guid>1439386</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p dir="ltr" id="docs-internal-guid-f7cce43c-7fff-fe01-2497-c7469a27d0e0">One thing that constantly persisted in my playthroughs of&nbsp;<em>Love Eternal</em>, the self-proposed “horror platformer” published by Ysbryd Games and developed by Brika, was a perversion of wanting. What I wanted wasn’t entirely clear, whether it was an answer, a challenge, cohesion, or even attrition, and even now, 3 playthroughs later, what&nbsp;<em>Love Eternal</em>&nbsp;*<strong>is</strong>* doesn’t necessarily aim itself towards any of those. Could it? Should it? Well, let’s delve deeper.</p><p dir="ltr">What is <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/love-eternal-preview-stunning-precision-platformer" rel="nofollow"><em>Love Eternal</em></a>? Well, in many ways, it’s in the title, but to whom and to what end? Well, all manner of things, if you will. To companionship, creation, celebration, confusion, continuation, cycles, chores, and condemnations. As a product, it’s a buckling beast of wrath, all of it housed inside the cozy visual package of a freeware platformer from the Flash era.</p><p dir="ltr">It’s very unabashed about its inspirations, namely titles like <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/i-wanna-be-guy-remastered-fans-developer-blessing" rel="nofollow"><em>I Wanna Be The Guy</em></a> and <a href="https://techraptor.net/games/celeste" rel="nofollow"><em>Celeste</em></a>, as well as PICO-8 platformers like <em>Pullfrog </em>and… well, <em>Celeste</em>, I suppose, and its slew of mods. Narratively, it seeks to emulate elements of David Lynch’s work, while also somewhat unintentionally running parallel to Joe Dante’s segment in the&nbsp;<em>Twilight Zone</em>&nbsp;movie, which is enticing, but horse before the cart, eh?</p><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/loveeternal_level.jpg?itok=wrnPtgma 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="1080">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/loveeternal_level.jpg?itok=ml_jh8W2 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture><p dir="ltr"><em>Love Eternal</em> itself is an expansion of Brika’s previous hardcore platformer simply titled <em>Love </em>– not to be confused with Fred Wood’s 2008 2D platformer <em>Love</em>. While the latter is much more straightforward, Brika’s <em>Love</em>, and <em>Love Eterna</em>l, have a sneaky ace up their sleeve. At the push of a button, whether stationary or in mid-air, your character will invert their gravity and use the ceiling as their new platform.</p><p dir="ltr">How the game approaches this gimmick is largely through the use of increasing the length of stringing together how many times you can invert in one floating period through the use of red crystals, which refresh your one-time use. There are hazards like spikes and lasers, and these, in turn, close the timings tighter until it becomes more masochistic than precision. A meeting of the minds between its two main inspirations.</p><p dir="ltr">On the whole, this is the game. It is a maximum of three hours of this mechanic stretched to an atomically small width, where the margins get tighter, and the line of red crystals becomes longer. Is it fun? It is initially, before repeat playthroughs, which, due to the narrative, are outright encouraged, undermine how reliant the game is solely on one element of <em>Love Eternal</em>'s platforming possibilities. Instead, what we have is a story to sink our teeth into.</p><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/loveeternal_dog.jpg?itok=clKsZBku 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="1080">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/loveeternal_dog.jpg?itok=WleH1JOg 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture><p dir="ltr">You play as Maya, a young girl seemingly at odds with everything in her life, from her family and what they eat for dinner, to her friends and their failure to show up for events Maya’s scheduled. Her reactionary anger to friends like Lacey for failing to show up at an event with Maya, brings the wrath of a selfish god who, unbeknownst to Maya, invites her into a castle hosted of her memories, as fractured and as alien to Maya, as much as they are to the God itself.</p><p dir="ltr">What follows is a spotty, but nonetheless, consistently fascinating string of scenes detailing a lot of this nefarious God’s activity, and a lip service treatment of Maya’s history. Why she’s chosen is just down to bad luck on her part, and as such, <em>Love Eternal </em>is much more interested in detailing how this God interacts with the world around Maya – their new plaything – and their history of previous playthings. The result as a whole, is a memetic experience that is alluring, but aggravatingly impenetrable.</p><p dir="ltr">It’s branded as “an experimental narrative”, but in reality, it is an abstract story, almost completely detached from gameplay, and contextualized through two decades of internet history. If the screenshots fail to garner a reaction other than “buh?”, then just know that they DO make sense, in one very acute angle of how this game structures its writing. Otherwise, you mostly fall prey to this God's absurdist reactions to a world that has gone from temples to touchpads, the Baby Boomer to end all Baby Boomers.</p><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/loveeternal_shout.jpg?itok=JC2NGDQf 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="1080">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/loveeternal_shout.jpg?itok=bfxSM_QF 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture><p dir="ltr">It’s almost pointless trying to adequately compose a consistent chain of events that would make this even remotely make sense. The somewhat garbled memories of Maya intersecting with a previous victim of the God, Divesh, and why the two meet so frequently, when, even when it’s shown, Divesh shows nowhere near the same amount of ire towards his contemporaries like Maya does. Instead, what <em>Love Eternal</em> focuses on is Dadaism.</p><p dir="ltr">Watch! As the God assumes Maya is a girl wholly inspired by the use of 2010 rage comics, one Memebase watermark short of a negative vote rating on 9gag. Gasp! As they react to manga as if it is a coloring book! Chuckle! As the ending of&nbsp;<em>The Blair Witch Project</em>&nbsp;is referenced multiple times in the same scene, but with an irreverence of dopiness behind it! And finally, analog horror jumpscares that shut the game down when finished.</p><p dir="ltr">It should be noted that all of this takes place when the platforming is discarded for a genre switch to a point ‘n click, which falls just shy of being the worst kind of visual novel. Save for an ending which, without spoiling, throws an entirely new angle of commentary towards the player, the platforming element becomes a branch of the statement Brika is trying to make… I think.</p><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/loveeternal_meme.jpg?itok=p84nw1Yr 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="1080">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/loveeternal_meme.jpg?itok=Uz-Econt 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture><p dir="ltr">Is the mare meant to race? Should the child be coached? What follows these questions are historical context that no longer applies when we, as a collective, have fallen past the need for it. Marriage is no longer a bond of religious intent, but one with protections and privy to the human condition, ultra-modernized. A statement is a JPEG, a playground is a platformer, and you are still you, getting older, and with it, more despondent to a world that doesn’t want you. So you want it, more than food or water. You want it, never need it.</p><p dir="ltr">If that is the intent, it’s an absorbing diatribe, which deserves something a bit more welcoming to synchronicity. Towards the end, Brika seems to lament their creative intent, anger as progression is pushed into the player without the player actively engaging in it, almost furious that there’s a cage around them. Like all animals, they buckle, but to what end? Just living.</p><h2><em>Love Eternal </em>Review | Final Verdict</h2><p dir="ltr">I won’t say that <em>Love Eternal</em> is a great game. Despite its cost-effective batch of content, the reliance on its legitimately bewitching gimmick being one broad stroke of challenge leaves the player desiring more. While the story is a legitimately enthralling aspect, it betrays the supposed experimentation by just sitting alongside the gameplay, and never the two shall meet.</p><hr><p><em><strong>Love Eternal </strong>was reviewed on PC with a copy provided by the publisher over the course of 8 hours of gameplay. All screenshots were taken during the process of review.</em></p></div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Blair is a trans writer who got their start in 2016 by writing too many words about Tom Clancy’s The Division. What follows until now is a journey spent… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/blair-bishop">More about Blair</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/love-eternal-review-centuries-of-damn]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Feds Reportedly Want Discord, Reddit, And Others To Doxx Users Who Criticize ICE]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/ice-reddit-discord-doxxing-dhs-subpoena-2000670648</link>
            <guid>1439374</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>As the Trump administration continues to ramp up ICE raids across the country, the Department of Homeland Security is increasingly trying to subpoena personal information on anonymous internet users who are trying to protest the agency, <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2026/02/13/technology/dhs-anti-ice-social-media.html">according to <em>The New York Times</em></a>.</p> <p>It reports that Google, Reddit, Discord, and Meta have received hundreds of administrative subpoenas from the Department of Homeland Security in recent months. The goal is to get information on the identities of people behind accounts found to be tracking ICE agent movements or criticizing the group as it carries out its operations, during which officers have <a href="https://www.americanimmigrationcouncil.org/blog/ice-deaths-shootings-2026/">killed at least two people so far in 2026</a>.</p>

 <p><em>The New York Times</em> claims that Google, Meta, and Reddit have complied with “some” of the requests. It’s unclear if Discord has done the same.</p> <p>The gaming platform has frequently been subpoenaed by publishers looking for details on users sharing confidential information or pirating games. One of those was <em>Arc Raiders</em> distributor Nexon. <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/16/24271854/discord-nexon-dmca-subpoena-copyright-piracy">Discord argued in legal filings back in 2024</a> that user privacy was legally protected by the constitution. Complying with the order, the company wrote, could violate its users’ “decisions to remain anonymous, an aspect of their freedom of speech protected by the First Amendment.”</p>

 <p>Reddit, on the other hand, <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/minnesota/comments/1qd6qir/ice_trackers/">has been flooded</a> with people sharing information about ICE movements and facilities in their communities as people are disappeared off the streets. While agents remain masked and their identities kept hidden, ICE has been using <a href="https://www.404media.co/ice-is-using-a-new-facial-recognition-app-to-identify-people-leaked-emails-show/">facial scanning technology</a> and other surveillance tools to <a href="https://www.mprnews.org/story/2026/01/13/ice-using-private-data-to-intimidate-observers-and-activists-advocates-say">doxx people they don’t like in real time</a>.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/ice-reddit-discord-doxxing-dhs-subpoena-2000670648]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon Officially Drops Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles Booster Boxes to Just $125.99 to Preorder, Just Weeks Before Release]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/amazon-officially-drops-teenage-mutant-ninja-turtles-booster-boxes-to-just-12599-to-preorder-just-weeks-before-release</link>
            <guid>1439368</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content" data-autopogo="true"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/magic-the-gathering-trading-card-game"><u>Magic: The Gathering</u></a> is getting its new <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/magic-the-gathering-teenage-mutant-ninja-turtles-where-to-buy-updated-2026"><u>Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles set</u></a> next month (with prerelease even sooner), but Amazon isn’t waiting to drop the price of booster boxes.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">After some price fluctuations, the retailer has finally confirmed that the <a href="https://zdcs.link/aB8dVV?object_uuid=b9bab191-75c7-4dca-b294-39cdb5d1c031&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>TMNT Play Booster Box will be sold for $125.99</u></a>, which is only a dollar more than its all-time lowest price of $124.99 that we saw <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/magic-the-gathering-teenage-mutant-ninja-turtle-preorders-drop-to-new-record-low-price-amazon-just-weeks-after-last-discount"><u>a few weeks ago</u></a> as a sale item.</p><div id="235624"><div><p><span data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><div id="235624" data-cy="solo-product-card"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>TMNT Play Booster Box</h3></p></div></span></p></div><h2 data-cy="title2">The New Price For TMNT Play Boosters Is Almost Their Lowest Ever</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">With 30 packs per box of Play Boosters, you’re getting each one for $4.19, a discount that adds up and should give you a sizeable collection of TMNT cards right from the jump.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As a reminder, the set’s rarest alternative treatments will more likely be found in Collector Boosters (more on those in a moment), but Amazon setting this price means it should be relatively easy to get up to speed and build something playable for your next Magic night.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The price confirmation follows the arrival of Collector Boosters on the store, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/magic-the-gathering-teenage-mutant-ninja-turtles-collector-booster-boxes-are-in-stock-right-now"><u>which are (somehow) still available at the time of writing</u></a>, as well as discounts on a variety of TMNT Magic: The Gathering products, including <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/magic-the-gathering-teenage-mutant-ninja-turtles-set-launches-next-month-and-the-bundle-is-discounted-already"><u>the bundle</u></a>, the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/magic-the-gathering-next-precon-deck-is-teenage-mutant-ninja-turtle-themed-and-its-already-discounted-just-a-few-weeks-from-launch"><u>newest Commander Deck ‘Turtle Power’</u></a>, and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/magic-the-gathering-tmnt-draft-night-box-back-in-stock-and-discounted-at-amazon"><u>even the new Draft Night set</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">For more on Magic’s Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtle crossover, check out <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/tmnt-magic-card-is-a-dream-for-artifact-creature-decks-like-warhammer-40ks-necron-dynasties"><u>a card that pairs nicely with Warhammer 40K Necrons</u></a>, and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/magic-the-gathering-tmnt-commander-deck-is-a-video-game-homage-packed-with-classic-characters"><u>our early thoughts on the Commander precon</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">You can also read my colleague Scott's deep-dive on the set <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/magic-the-gathering-teenage-mutant-ninja-turtles-preview">in his full preview</a>, including the unique 'Turtle Team Up' co-op boxed game that's part of the lineup above.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Lloyd Coombes is an experienced freelancer in tech, gaming and fitness seen at Polygon, Eurogamer, Macworld, TechRadar and many more. He's a big fan of Magic: The Gathering and other collectible card games, much to his wife's dismay.
</p></div></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/amazon-officially-drops-teenage-mutant-ninja-turtles-booster-boxes-to-just-12599-to-preorder-just-weeks-before-release]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[People of Note launches April 7]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/02/people-of-note-launches-april-7</link>
            <guid>1439365</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch-2">Switch 2</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Musical turn-based RPG dated.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Turn-based <a title="Genres > RPG [18,048 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg">RPG</a> <em><a title="Games > People of Note [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/people-of-note">People of Note</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [11,451 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [8,753 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch 2 [1,018 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch-2">Switch 2</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [25,535 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1626170/People_of_Note/" target="_blank">Steam</a>, <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/p/people-of-note-e50325" target="_blank">Epic Games Store</a>, and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-us/games/store/people-of-note/9nb2tf2p011b" target="_blank">Microsoft Store</a> on April 7 for $24.99 with a 10 percent-off launch discount, publisher <a title="Companies > Annapurna Interactive [198 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/annapurna-interactive">Annapurna Interactive</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Iridium Studios [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/iridium-studios">Iridium Studios</a> announced. <span id="more-1025976"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Annapurna Interactive:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>In this bold <a title="Genres > Turn-Based RPG [1,415 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg/turn-based-rpg">turn-based RPG</a>, where musical numbers meet thrilling combat, join pop singer Cadence on her quest for stardom.</p><p><strong>Take the Stage</strong></p><p>After being shut out of the Noteworthy Song Contest, Cadence realizes that her solo act might not be enough for the judges. As she travels across Note to the Rock City of Durandis, the EDM City of <a title="Games > Lumina" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/lumina">Lumina</a>, and more, Cadence fills out her band with eclectic and powerful musicians from lands afar. But something’s brewing in the distance…the Harmonic Convergence is playing havoc with the world’s musical energies, and dark forces are working behind the scenes to disrupt Note’s natural harmonies. It wasn’t in the set list, but Cadence and the others need to step up and make sure music itself still has a future on stage.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>In <em>People of Note</em>, experience turn-based combat like never before: each battle is an interactive musical performance with evolving combat conditions, real-time rhythm-based attacks, and genre-bending mashup attacks!</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li>Enjoy full-length cinematic musical sequences spanning a wide variety of musical genres, performed by our main cast of characters.</li><li><a title="Companies > Experience [215 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/experience">Experience</a> turn-based <a title="Genres > Action [3,413 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a> combat as a dynamic, interactive musical performance.</li><li>Tempo-Based <a title="Genres > Rhythm [223 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rhythm">Rhythm</a> Combat: Time your attacks to the beat of the music for amplified damage against opponents.</li><li>Dynamic Combat Conditions: As the music in battle changes in real-time, strategize your attacks to synchronize with the current genre.</li><li>Musical <a title="Companies > Mas [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/mas">Mas</a>hups: Combine the unique musical genres of your team members to unleash electrifying musical mashup attacks.</li><li>Explore Note, a massive world where each genre of music is represented by a completely unique environment and culture.</li><li>Dive into vibrant dungeons full of offbeat enemies and clever environmental puzzles.</li><li>Play it your way: Don’t like environmental puzzles? Turn ‘em off. Not into turn-based combat? Don’t worry, we got you. The entire experience of <em>People of Note</em> is completely customizable.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="People of Note | Release Date Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8aM8gYssblw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/02/people-of-note-launches-april-7]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Frontier Legends launches in Early Access this spring]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/02/frontier-legends-launches-in-early-access-this-spring</link>
            <guid>1439362</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Wild West open-world survival crafting adventure game.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Wild West <a title="Genres > Open-World [831 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/open-world">open-world</a> survival <a title="Genres > Crafting [49 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/crafting">crafting</a> <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,893 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure game</a> <em><a title="Games > Frontier Legends" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/frontier-legends">Frontier Legends</a></em> will launch in Early Access for <a title="Platforms > PC [25,535 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3032150/Frontier_Legends/" target="_blank">Steam</a> and <a title="Companies > Epic Games [356 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/epic-games">Epic Games</a> Store this spring, developer <a title="Companies > Neojac Entertainment" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/neojac-entertainment">Neojac Entertainment</a> announced. It will also be part of Steam Horse Fest between February 19 and 23 ahead of a new demo due out in March. <span id="more-1027304"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3032150/Frontier_Legends/" target="_blank">Steam page</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>Frontier Legends</em> is an open-world adventure that combines survival, crafting and exploration in a Wild West setting. You arrive as a new settler on the frontier and are left to fend for yourself as you learn the ways of the West. Tend to your needs, manage resources and explore the wilderness; you just might unravel some of the land’s mysteries along the way.</p><p>Over time, you can build your own settlement, defend yourself from outlaws and bandits, form alliances, forge a reputation for good and bad and shape the path that will make you a legend. Do you have what it takes?</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <ul><li><strong>Build Your Own Frontier</strong> – Start with a small camp and grow it into a thriving frontier settlement shaped by your leadership. Recruit NPC settlers and assign daily work, farming, crafting, gathering and defense, to keep your town running. Lead well and your community thrives; neglect it and the frontier will catch up.</li><li><strong><a title="Genres > Survival [511 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/survival">Survival</a> on the Edge of Civilization</strong> – The frontier is unforgiving. <a title="Series > Mana [17 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/series/mana">Mana</a>ge core needs and resources as you brave a harsh wilderness where the elements, wildlife and outlaws can turn a day trip into a fight for survival. Dynamic weather, day-night cycles and changing conditions require you to adapt every time you ride out.</li><li><strong>Forge Your Own Path</strong> – Live your Wild West fantasy your way. Become a hunter, trader, builder, bandit, lawman or something in between. Your choices shape your reputation in the frontier.</li><li><strong>Tame and Ride Wild Horses</strong> – Discover wild horses roaming the land, then tame and train them into trusted companions. Each horse has unique attributes and abilities, making them valuable allies and key for traveling, surviving and thriving in the frontier. When in danger, a good mount can be the difference between making it home or meeting the business end of a barrel.</li><li><strong>Explore and Uncover <a title="Games > Myst (2020) [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/myst-2020">Myst</a>eries</strong> – Push beyond your settlement to explore the unknown and uncover the hidden secrets of the frontier. Take on quests, solve puzzles and hunt legendary treasures as you explore ancient ruins and forgotten camps. Every discovery can change your fate and get you closer to becoming a legend yourself.</li><li><strong>Work Together or Turn on Each Other</strong> – Team up with others to trade, build and survive, or take the darker route: raid, betray and fight your way to a bigger slice of the frontier. Embark on your adventure with other players via <a title="Genres > Co-Op [376 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer/co-op">cooperative multiplayer</a>, participate in community events and compete in seasonal challenges to earn unique rewards and recognition.</li></ul><p>Are you ready to become a legend in the Wild West? Forge your path, conquer the frontier and write your own story in <em>Frontier Legends</em>.</p></blockquote></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/02/frontier-legends-launches-in-early-access-this-spring]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["We weren't really paying attention" The Witcher's lead story designer reveals why the first game's final CG cutscene didn't involve the story team]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/the-witcher-1-lead-story-designer-talks-final-cg-cutscene</link>
            <guid>1439359</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>

  <figure>
      <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Witcher-1_ending-CG-cutscene.png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Witcher-1_ending-CG-cutscene.png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Witcher-1_ending-CG-cutscene.png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Witcher-1_ending-CG-cutscene.png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Witcher-1_ending-CG-cutscene.png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Witcher-1_ending-CG-cutscene.png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Witcher-1_ending-CG-cutscene.png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Witcher-1_ending-CG-cutscene.png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Witcher-1_ending-CG-cutscene.png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>CD Projekt Red</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>The long-awaited <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/the-witcher-remake">remake of the first Witcher game</a> is seemingly on the back-burner as CD Projekt Red has reportedly added support studio Fool's Theory to the massive development effort of <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/the-witcher-4">The Witcher 4</a>. Moreover, there have been recurring <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/witcher-3-expansion-rumours-analyst-100-percent-certain-cd-projekt-red-will-release-significant-new-content-this-year">rumours of an all-new Witcher 3 DLC</a> made by the same studio. Meanwhile, original lead story designer Artur Ganszyniec has been revisiting Geralt of Rivia's first big RPG adventure, giving longtime fans all-new insights into the game's making.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/@artur-ganszyniec">Ganszyniec's YouTube channel</a> already houses his complete playthrough of the game with valuable commentary, so we highly recommend diehards to slowly chew through it if they have the time. That said, the story designer's most shocking revelation (hat tip to <a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/that-was-a-mistake-i-think-the-witcher-1s-lead-writer-says-the-story-team-didnt-know-about-its-twist-ending/">VGC</a>) came near the very end, during the 26th and final episode of the series, which you can watch below:</p> <figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Ep. 26 –The Witcher with a designer's commentary: Epilogue" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fwRtKBkq0N8?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Ep. 26 –The Witcher with a designer's commentary: Epilogue</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fwRtKBkq0N8?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/fwRtKBkq0N8?autoplay=1" title="Ep. 26 –The Witcher with a designer's commentary: Epilogue">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fwRtKBkq0N8" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>At the 1:30:22 mark, once the 'artwork cutscene' in line with the rest of the game's ends, he talks about what happened between the story team and the rest of the studio. Apparently, a final CG cutscene (which is part of the game as we all know it) was added without the team knowing it. "That's where we wanted the game to end, with an open question and open future... But while we were finishing the game, someone decided – the board decided or Michał Kiciński (co-founder of CDPR) decided – that we needed an animated outro for the game," Ganszyniec says.</p>
<p>The CG cutscene introduced the idea of Witchers that are hunting down kings, which led directly into <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/the-witcher-2-assassins-of-kings">The Witcher 2: Assassins of Kings</a>. "The script for what we're seeing now, this animation, was created not really involving the story team. It was sort of... we weren't really paying attention," the lead story designer adds before elaborating on what the story team's original plans were. "That's why the second Witcher is very political and there's not really room for exploring who Geralt is, his family, his history and stuff like this." If you've played through the entire Geralt trilogy, the shift is obvious, but having more clarity on what went down behind the scenes definitely helps after all these years.</p><p>Regardless, even Ganszyniec concludes he's excited to see how the remake turns out. As for the different route The Witcher 2 took, it could be argued <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/the-witcher-3-wild-hunt">The Witcher 3: The Wild Hunt</a> went back to a more personal story with Geralt and his family at the centre of a high-stakes epic.</p>

        </div>

  
      </article>



  



  

  <section>
    <span>Related topics</span>

    
  </section>
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/the-witcher-1-lead-story-designer-talks-final-cg-cutscene]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Avowed Anniversary Update has arrived alongside the PS5 release]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/02/18/avowed-anniversary-update-has-arrived-alongside-the-ps5-release/</link>
            <guid>1439332</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Marking the first birthday of Obsidian’s <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/avowed">Avowed</a>, the game is out now for PlayStation 5, and a meaty anniversary update has been released for the game on PC and Xbox Series X|S. The game is also now available through the regular <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/xbox-game-pass">Xbox Game Pass</a> tier, having originally been tied to ‘Day One’ elligible tiers.*</p>
<p><iframe title="Avowed Anniversary Update" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NO_uAjEhEpU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>On a high level, the anniversary update has added three new races that you can create your character as – dwarves, orlan and aumaua – and there’s a new quarterstaff weapon that you can adopt.</p>
<p>While the game wasn’t designed with it in mind, New Game Plus has also been added for anyone that has a save that’s passed the point of no return and beaten the game. Starting over, the only real caveat is that weapon levelling will not persist, but that’s fine because you’ll be nice and mighty in other ways.</p>
<p>And you can show off how mighty you are with a photo mode to capture specific moments while you’re playing.</p>

<p>Avowed was one of the highlights for Xbox and PC gamers last year, though one a little overlooked for launching in February and perhaps not being as broad as some might have liked, following on from the PIllars of Eternity games. “Avowed is an incredible RPG,” we said in <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/02/13/avowed-review/">our review</a>. “Its vibrant world and stellar cast make every moment a joy to take part in, enhanced by a script that gives equal measure to drama, action and humour. Coming hot on the heels of Indiana Jones and The Great Circle, Microsoft’s software revival is well underway.”</p>



<p><wbr><br>
<b>New Game&nbsp;Plus</b>&nbsp;is now available after completing the main story. This mode is designed to reward mastery, experimentation,&nbsp;and making the all-powerful build.&nbsp;<wbr><br>
<b>When starting a New Game&nbsp;Plus&nbsp;save,&nbsp;players will bring along with them:</b>&nbsp;<wbr></p>
<ul>
<li>All&nbsp;unlocked abilities (with the exception of&nbsp;godlike abilities which are gained through story progression/world exploration)&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>All spent attribute points&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>All unique weapons and armors—but they are reset to level 1&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>All unlocked enchantments&nbsp;remain&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>All unique gloves and boots&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>All necklaces, all rings, and all trinkets&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Any&nbsp;<i>equipped</i>&nbsp;Common Weapons or Armor items are kept, but they are reset to level 1&nbsp;<wbr></li>
</ul>
<p><b>The following&nbsp;are&nbsp;removed from the player at the start of a New Game Plus:</b>&nbsp;<wbr></p>
<ul>
<li>All common weapons and armor that&nbsp;<i>aren’t</i>&nbsp;equipped&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Companions must be picked up via story progression&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Companions keep their talent points and start at level 1&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li><b>All resources that had been collected</b>&nbsp;<wbr>
<ul>
<li>Gold&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Upgrade materials&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Enchanting materials&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Food ingredients&nbsp;<wbr></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><b>All consumables that had been collected</b>&nbsp;<wbr>
<ul>
<li>All potions&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>All food&nbsp;<wbr></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><b>All quest items&nbsp;</b><wbr></li>
<li><b>All god totems/trinkets&nbsp;</b><wbr></li>
<li><b>Fast travel points/fog of war&nbsp;</b><wbr></li>
<li><b>The&nbsp;aforementioned godlike&nbsp;abilities</b>&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li><b>To ensure challenge scales alongside player power:</b>&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Enemy stats are increased across the board&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Enemies now have a chance to have modifiers applied to them&nbsp;<wbr></li>
</ul>
<p><b>Elemental Modifiers&nbsp;</b><wbr></p>
<ul>
<li>Fire: Immune to Fire damage and accumulation. Attacks also now deal Fire damage.&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Frost: Immune to Frost damage and accumulation. Attacks also now&nbsp;deal&nbsp;Frost damage.&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Shock: Immune to Shock damage and accumulation. Attacks also now deal Shock damage.&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Poison: Immune to Poison damage and accumulation. Attacks also now&nbsp;deal&nbsp;Poison damage.&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Bleed: Immune to Bleed damage and accumulation. Attacks also now&nbsp;deal&nbsp;Bleed damage.&nbsp;<wbr></li>
</ul>
<p><b>Physical Modifiers&nbsp;</b><wbr></p>
<ul>
<li>Haste: Increased movement speed, attack speed, and reduced cooldown timers<wbr></li>
<li>Glass Cannon: Increased damage dealt and damage received&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Colossal: Increased maximum health&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Life Steal: Attacks restore the enemy’s health by a percentage of the damage dealt&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Crippled: Reduced movement speed and attack speed&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Sturdy: Increased stability&nbsp; making it harder for them to be stunned<wbr></li>
<li>Natural Immunity: Immune to all status accumulations&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Forceful: Increased impact on attacks&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Vindictive: Increased damage dealt based on the amount of health lost&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Attribute&nbsp;stat cap&nbsp;rises&nbsp;from&nbsp;<b>15 to&nbsp;30</b>&nbsp;<wbr></li>
</ul>
<p><b>An important note for those who have already completed&nbsp;<i>Avowed</i></b>: Since New Game Plus is being added post release and the game was not initially designed with it in mind, a completion save will be necessary&nbsp;in order to&nbsp;take advantage of the mode. You will need to load a point of no return save or later and beat the game to make a proper New Game Plus save.&nbsp;<wbr></p>

<p>Included in the anniversary update is a major expansion to character creation:&nbsp;<b>three new playable species</b>&nbsp;join the existing Humans and Elves.&nbsp;<wbr></p>
<ul>
<li><b>Dwarves</b>&nbsp;–&nbsp;The most well-traveled species in Eora, the stout dwarves are known for their great strength and tenacity.&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li><b>Orlans</b>&nbsp;–&nbsp;Their two-toned skin, prominent ears,&nbsp;and&nbsp;hirsute bodies all in the smallest size of Kith&nbsp;make them stand&nbsp;outs&nbsp;in Eora.&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li><b>Aumaua</b>&nbsp;– Towering, powerfully built, and physically imposing.&nbsp;<wbr></li>
</ul>
<p>Not only do the&nbsp;different species&nbsp;change how you look,&nbsp;the team&nbsp;has also added in stat bonuses for all species adding another layer to character creation.&nbsp;<wbr></p>
<ul>
<li><b>Humans</b>&nbsp;<wbr>
<ul>
<li>+1 Might&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>+1 Resolve&nbsp;<wbr></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><b>Elves</b>&nbsp;<wbr>
<ul>
<li>+1 Dexterity&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>+1 Perception&nbsp;<wbr></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><b>Aumaua</b>&nbsp;<wbr>
<ul>
<li>+2 Might&nbsp;<wbr></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><b>Dwarves</b>&nbsp;<wbr>
<ul>
<li>+1 Might&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>+1 Constitution&nbsp;<wbr></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><b>Orlans</b>&nbsp;<wbr>
<ul>
<li>+1 Perception&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>+1 Resolve&nbsp;<wbr></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Additionally, players will receive stat bonuses depending on their chosen background.<wbr></p>
<ul>
<li><b>Arcane Scholar</b> – +2 to Intellect<wbr></li>
<li><b>Court Augur</b> – +2 to Resolve<wbr></li>
<li><b>Noble Scion</b> – +2 to Perception<wbr></li>
<li><b>Vanguard Scout</b> – +2 to Dexterity<wbr></li>
<li><b>War Hero</b> – +2 to Constitution<wbr></li>
</ul>
<p><b>Improved Character Creation</b><wbr><br>
Added new Godlike features, color variants, and presets<br>
<wbr></p>

<p>For players who want even finer control,&nbsp;<i>Avowed&nbsp;</i>now includes&nbsp;custom difficulty modifiers, allowing you to tune the&nbsp;game’s&nbsp;systems to your preferred experience.&nbsp;These new options are found by scrolling down through the “Game” tab of the settings menu.<wbr><br>
<b>Adjust player:&nbsp;</b><wbr></p>
<ul>
<li>Damage dealt&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Health, stamina, and&nbsp;essence&nbsp;resources&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Elemental status effect threshold&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Health and essence regeneration rates&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Potion and food restoration rates&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Interrupt or knockdown ease&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Second Wind cooldown time&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Carry capacity&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Parry window&nbsp;<wbr></li>
</ul>
<p><b>Adjust enemy:&nbsp;</b><wbr></p>
<ul>
<li>Damage output&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Health&nbsp;pool&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Stun, interrupt, or knockdown ease&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Attack speed&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Elemental status effect threshold&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Aggro&nbsp;threshold&nbsp;<wbr></li>
</ul>
<p><b>Adjust companion:&nbsp;</b><wbr></p>
<ul>
<li>Damage&nbsp;dealt&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Health max&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Elemental status effect threshold&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Aggro&nbsp;threshold&nbsp;<wbr></li>
</ul>
<p><b>As well as general adjustments:&nbsp;</b><wbr></p>
<ul>
<li><b>M</b>erchant prices&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Equipment upgrade material costs&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Fall damage&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Trap damage&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Item quality damage reduction&nbsp;<wbr></li>
</ul>
<p><b>Important note: While changing these options will not negate&nbsp;most&nbsp;achievements that you may be hunting down, they will&nbsp;invalidate a Path of the Damned achievement.&nbsp;That achievement must be done&nbsp;without&nbsp;use of&nbsp;the custom game options.&nbsp;</b><wbr><br>
<b></b></p>
<ul>
<li><b>Photo Mode</b><wbr><br>
Capture your envoy, companions, and the Living Lands from any angle and share your journey. Includes a free or fixed camera, filters, character rotation and toggle, post-process effects, and gradients. Photo Mode is accessed from the pause menu.<wbr><br>
<b></b></li>
<li><b>New Weapon</b><wbr><br>
A&nbsp;brand new&nbsp;weapon type is joining the arsenal with the quarterstaff. Designed with&nbsp;the&nbsp;archmage&nbsp;fantasy&nbsp;in mind, the quarterstaff&nbsp;is a new&nbsp;bludgeoning&nbsp;weapon that&nbsp;comes complete with wand style stun finishers.&nbsp;Unleash brutal physical&nbsp;combos along with a fury of spells that&nbsp;would make&nbsp;even&nbsp;Concelhaut&nbsp;jealous.<wbr><br>
<b></b></li>
<li><b>New Stun Finishers</b><wbr><br>
New stun finishers added for One-Handed Weapons and Two-Handed Weapons.<wbr><br>
<b></b></li>
<li><b>Respawning Encounters</b><wbr><br>
Respawning encounters have been added to Dawnshore, Emerald Stair, Shatterscarp, and Galawain’s Tusks.</li>
</ul>
<p><b>New Quality of Life Features</b><wbr></p>
<ul>
<li>Players can now change their Envoy’s appearance after character creation via the mirror in the party camp.<wbr></li>
<li>Newly placed workbenches allow players to upgrade gear without returning to party camp.<wbr></li>
<li>All player Backgrounds now have an added attribute bonus.&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Added option to end dream conversations early.<wbr></li>
<li>Powder keg chain reactions now occur with a short delay, instead of all exploding simultaneously.<wbr></li>
<li>Increased max Controller Vibration Intensity (in the Controller Settings menu) from 1.0 to 2.0.<wbr></li>
<li>Added keyboard-based turning in accessibility options.<wbr></li>
</ul>
<p><b>Improvements to Lighting</b><wbr></p>
<ul>
<li>The lighting has been improved across all regions.<wbr></li>
<li>Improved the lighting in conversations.<wbr></li>
</ul>
<p><b>Graphics</b><wbr></p>
<ul>
<li>Updated XeSS to 2.1. Xe Frame Generation, Xe Super Resolution, and Xe Low-Latency mode are now available to more GPUs.<wbr></li>
</ul>
<p><wbr><br>
<b>All Bug Fixes</b><wbr><br>
<wbr><br>
<b>Crashes and stability</b><wbr></p>
<ul>
<li>The game should now longer crash after Fog of War has been cleared.<wbr></li>
<li>Addressed an issue causing Barbaric Smash killing blow VFX to remain on the player indefinitely<wbr></li>
<li>Fixed an issue when creating save games that could cause NPCs to be stuck when reloading<wbr></li>
</ul>
<p><b>Performance and Optimizations</b><wbr></p>
<ul>
<li>Resolved an issue where NVIDIA Reflex Low Latency was missing “Off” option while upscaling is disabled.<wbr></li>
<li>Ray tracing is now off by default on Handheld PCs.<wbr></li>
<li>Added Mid Luminance values to HDR settings.<wbr></li>
<li>Various performance improvements.<wbr></li>
</ul>
<p><b>Animation</b><wbr></p>
<ul>
<li>Fixed an issue with the Two-Handed Axe special attack not being aligned while in third person view.<wbr></li>
<li>Companion animations no longer stutter during conversations and exploration.<wbr></li>
</ul>
<p><b>Audio</b><wbr></p>
<ul>
<li>All audio should now play properly when cooking.<wbr></li>
</ul>
<p><b>Quests &amp; Conversations</b><wbr></p>
<ul>
<li>Decals for puzzle in Sallow Steppe should now render properly.<wbr></li>
<li>The camera should behave normally during conversation with Tazaraak.<wbr></li>
</ul>
<p><b>UI/UX</b><wbr></p>
<ul>
<li>Ability and Grimoire Cost Discounts are now shown in the Character tab of the Ledger, as well as the maximum (-90%) available.<wbr></li>
<li>Fixed Tanglefoot’s icon on Player’s and enemy’s HUD.<wbr></li>
<li>New Icon added to help distinguish Flurry of Blows on enemy’s HUD.<wbr></li>
<li>Text should no longer overlap tabs in certain languages.<wbr></li>
<li>Fixed description for several active abilities that were incorrectly labeled as passive.<wbr></li>
<li>Resolved an issue where “confirm override” pop-up was not showing while switching presets in the Extras tab.<wbr></li>
<li>Fixed an issue where Marius’ Hunter Sense disappeared from hotbar after leaving Party Camp.<wbr></li>
<li>Vital bars are showing proper preview values for some skills when upgraded.<wbr></li>
<li>Fixed an issue where “Survivalist” ability did not reflect additional bonuses in UI.<wbr></li>
<li>Blunted hits no longer include blood VFX when “Combat Blood” is disabled.<wbr></li>
</ul>
<p><b>Combat/Systems Fixes</b><wbr></p>
<ul>
<li>Fixed issue where various Area of Effect sources like Arcane Veil interfered with aiming player spells.<wbr></li>
<li>Swinging guillotines in the Garden remain disabled after loading a save.<wbr></li>
<li>Fixed an issue where Yatzli’s Explosive Blast did not break destructibles.<wbr></li>
<li>Some unique weapon enchantments now work properly while Dual Wield Mastery is active.<wbr></li>
<li>Already broken destructibles no longer receive damage numbers.<wbr></li>
<li>Loot now directly drops at the feet of a shattered frozen enemy.</li>
</ul>
<p><em>* If you need Xbox Game Pass tiers to be explained for being too complicated, then I suggest writing to your MP and Satya Nadella to complain.</em></p>
<p><em>via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/2457220/view/511857117305504147">Steam</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/02/18/avowed-anniversary-update-has-arrived-alongside-the-ps5-release/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Skyrim Switch 2 Update 1.2 brings proper performance fixes and a 60fps mode]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/02/18/skyrim-switch-2-update-1-2-brings-proper-performance-fixes-and-a-60fps-mode/</link>
            <guid>1439329</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Bethesda has released update 1.2 for <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/skyrim">Skyrim</a> on <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/nintendo-switch-2">Nintendo Switch 2</a>, fully addressing the woeful performance that blighted the game’s latest port. It follows on from an update shortly after its December release that quickly removed the frame rate cap to improve latency, but now tackles this with a full 60fps performance mode, fixes to visual glitches, and more.</p>
<p>The game performance is the most significant improvement, a new toggle under the Display settings letting you prioritise visuals or performance. This tweaks visual settings and resolution targets in order to deliver 60fps, which from anecdotal online accounts seems to be pretty solid. Additionally, the 30fps visuals have been locked back to this frame rate and the graphics tweaked to give steadier performance.</p>


<p>It’s a huge shame that the game couldn’t have had this degree of performance and refinement at its original release, as it led to a lot of bad reviews – we ended up having to give it <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/12/11/the-elder-scrolls-v-skyrim-anniversary-edition-switch-2-review/">a 5/10 because of the issues</a>. However, it does give a glimmer of optimism for the Fallout 4 port to Switch 2 which is set to drop next week.</p>
<p>The Skyrim Switch 2 Update 1.2 patch notes are as follows</p>
<p><strong>Features:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Added a 60 Hz mode under Display settings that allows players to toggle between “Prioritize Visuals” or “Prioritize Performance”.</li>
<li>In addition, frame rate has been locked at 30 Hz in “Prioritize Visuals” mode for smoother gameplay.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Crashes and Performance Fixes:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Fixed a crash that occurred when reading “The Crimson Dirks Vol. 4” book for the “Tilted Scales” quest in German.</li>
<li>Fixed an audio-related crash.</li>
<li>Fixed a crash, infinite load, and game freeze that sometimes occurred when rapidly selecting “Load” multiple times in the pause menu.</li>
<li>Fixed a crash that occurred when the “Transmute Ore” spell was repeatedly cast outside of the Haltered Stream Camp.</li>
<li>Improved FPS performance drops that occurred in the following locations:
<ul>
<li>during the Hide and Seek quest in Kynesgrove</li>
<li>during combat at Secunda’s Kiss</li>
<li>when discovering the “Drelas’ Cottage” location</li>
<li>when engaged in combat with a giant at the Talking Stone Camp.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Visuals Issues Fixes:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Viewing water planes from a distance or within menus caused them to shift up and down.</li>
<li>Distant aspen trees appeared with a blue tint.</li>
<li>Transitioning out of caves caused an outline of the entrance to linger during the fade-to-back loading screen.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>User Interface Fixes:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Switching between mouse and controller mode while in dialogue or the Help menu, caused different options to be highlighted.</li>
<li>Switching between mouse and controller mode while in help menus or user hints, did not dynamically update callout prompts.</li>
<li>The “Ready/Sheathe” option was missing from the Joy-Con 2 Mouse Controls menu.</li>
<li>The “Delete” prompt remained grayed-out within the Load menu when swapping between mouse and controller mode.</li>
<li>Deleting a save in the Save/Load menus reset the highlighted selection to the top of the menu list.</li>
<li>While in mouse mode, the cursor remained stuck within a smaller section of the screen when changing between docked/undocked modes or interfacing with GameChat.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Controls Fixes:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The “Eagle Eye” Archery perk remained active after switching between mouse and controller mode.</li>
<li>Holding down the Right Joystick while reassigning a button caused that button to disappear from the Controls list.</li>
<li>The Joy-Con 2 controllers provided haptic feedback while in mouse mode.</li>
<li>Buttons became unresponsive when controls were remapped while moving the Joy-Con 2 controllers in mouse mode.</li>
<li>Rotating the map in mouse mode was slower and less smooth than in controller mode.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Audio Issue Fix:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Scrolling SFX continued to play while holding up or down on the Left Joystick or buttons at the top or bottom of the Save/Load menus.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Localization Fixes:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>“Amiibo” appeared as plural in Spanish.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Miscellaneous:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Added new translations for the features listed above and UI updates.</li>
<li>Updates were made to the game credits.</li>
</ul>
<p><em>Source: a social media hellhole we won’t link to.</em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/02/18/skyrim-switch-2-update-1-2-brings-proper-performance-fixes-and-a-60fps-mode/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hamster's Next 'Console Archives' Game Is Coming Later This Week]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/02/hamsters-next-console-archives-game-is-coming-later-this-week</link>
            <guid>1439323</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Dezaemon breaks free from the Famicom</p>
</section></header><div><section>

<p>Hamster has <a href="https://www.consolearchives.com/en/title/csa-0003/">revealed</a> the next game in its <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/guides/every-console-archives-game-on-nintendo-switch-2">Console Archives</a> line-up, and it's coming out tomorrow, 19th February 2026 (thanks <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2026/02/console-archives-dezaemon-launches-february-19">Gematsu</a>!).</p>
<p>The next game coming to the Switch 2's eShop is <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/console-archives-dezaemon">Dezaemon</a>, Athena's 1991 Famicom shmup that allows you to create your very own levels, ships, characters, music, and more. It's probably one of the earliest "game maker" games ever released, and this also marks the first time that Dezaemon has launched in territories outside of Japan</p>
<p>Interestingly, this wasn't included in the launch line-up <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/02/hamsters-console-archives-starting-lineup-revealed-includes-more-than-10-titles">announced by Hamster a few weeks back</a>, so this is a rather nice surprise! That means the PS1 Japanese-exclusive, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/console-archives-dezaemon-plus">Dezaemon Plus</a>, will be more of an expanded bonus at this point.</p>
<p>Here's a rundown of what Dezaemon's rerelease will entail when it lands tomorrow:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"Dezaemon" was released by ATHENA in 1991 for an 8-bit home console.<br>
It is a game creation tool that allows you to produce your very own original shooting game.<br>
You can design characters and backgrounds using pixel art, compose music with an 8-bit sound engine, and create a wide variety of enemy patterns by adjusting various parameters!</p>
<p>The "Console Archives" series is developed with the concept of faithfully reproducing masterpieces released on various home game consoles, allowing players to easily enjoy them on the latest hardware.<br>
The series is packed with convenient features, including customizable button layouts and screen settings, as well as the ability to save and load at any point.<br>
Whether you played them back in the day or are experiencing them for the first time, please enjoy the masterpieces that shaped the history of console gaming!</p>
</blockquote>


<p>So, this marks the third game in the Console Archives series hitting Switch 2. We've got at least eight more confirmed titles coming from Hamster on <em>top</em> of the Arcade Archives series, with <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/console-archives-doraemon">Doraemon</a> already dated for July 2026.</p>
<p>We can't wait to see what other surprises are in store for us.</p>
<hr>
<p><em>Are you excited for Dezaemon's release tomorrow? Get creating in the comments.</em></p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:197407 @ 1771431378 --></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://www.consolearchives.com/en/title/csa-0003/" rel="noopener" href="https://www.consolearchives.com/en/title/csa-0003/">consolearchives.com</a>, via <a title="External Link: https://www.gematsu.com/2026/02/console-archives-dezaemon-launches-february-19" rel="noopener" href="https://www.gematsu.com/2026/02/console-archives-dezaemon-launches-february-19">gematsu.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-info/054075fe8fc2176022ef9edc4a5fad57 @ 1771431615 --></div></article><div><p>Alana has been with Nintendo Life since 2022, and while RPGs are her first love, Nintendo is a close second. She enjoys nothing more than overthinking battle strategies, characters, and stories. She also wishes she was a Sega air pirate.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/AlanaHagues"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/alanahagues.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('AlanaHagues');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/02/hamsters-next-console-archives-game-is-coming-later-this-week]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[“Irresponsible and Offensive” Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 Ad Banned in UK for Joking About Sexual Violence]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/irresponsible-and-offensive-call-of-duty-black-ops-7-ad-banned-in-uk-for-joking-about-sexual-violence/</link>
            <guid>1439320</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>An ad for <strong>Call of Duty: Black Ops 7</strong> has been <strong>banned in the UK</strong> after the <strong>Advertising Standards Authority (ASA)</strong> deemed that it was "<em>irresponsible and offensive</em>" for centring around humour that was "<em>generated by the humiliation and the implied threat of painful, non-consensual penetration</em>" of a man in the ad. </p>



<p>Spotted by the <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/czd831elpz5o">BBC</a>, the ad in question is part of Call of Duty: Black Ops 7's 'Replacers' ad campaign, which featured Hollywood actors like <strong>Terry Crews</strong>, <strong>Nikki Glaser</strong>, and <strong>Peter Stromare</strong>. While there are several 'Replacers' ads, the one that got banned depicts Glaser and Stromare's characters as replacement airport security officers filling in for the actual officers who are too wrapped up in Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 to be at work.</p>



<p>When a man travelling steps up for his security check, Glaser and Stromare's characters are seen to take advantage of him, with Glaser seemingly stealing his watch, followed by Stromare stating that he had been "<em>randomly selected to be <strong>manhandled</strong></em>," before telling him that he'll need to remove his clothes, "<em>everything but the shoes</em>." Glaser's character then follows up with "<em>time for the puppet show</em>," before Stromare's character puts a body scanning device in the man's mouth, telling him to bite down on it because "<strong><em>she's going in dry</em>."</strong></p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 - The Replacer &quot;Airport Security&quot;" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/FH1csdj8oMk?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>Outside of the ad being available on YouTube, per the BBC's report, the ad ran ahead of the game's launch in November 2025 on Channel 5 and ITV, after which the ASA received at least nine complaints that the ad "<em>trivialized sexual violence</em>."</p>



<p>For <strong>Activision Blizzard's</strong> part, the company stated that the ad was reviewed by Clearcast before it aired, and that it wasn't aired around programming that would have appealed to children and youth under 16. It added that the situation shown was a "<em>deliberately implausible, parodic scenario</em>," that the humour referred more to the man's discomfort, and that it did not sexualize the invasive search. The company also pointed out that the search is not shown and that the ad does not include any explicit imagery.</p>



<p>That didn't fly with the ASA. While the organization acknowledged the lack of any explicit imagery, it did not come to the conclusion that the humour came from the man's discomfort, instead concluding that it was from "<em>the humiliation and implied threat of painful, non-consensual penetration</em>." The ad will not run again in the UK in its current form, though, now that Black Ops 7 has been out for the last few months, it's worth considering that Activision may simply sunset the ad campaign altogether, only leaving them up on YouTube.</p>



<p>It's worth noting that the ASA isn't the only one that came to the conclusion that the humour was centred around the man in the ad being non-consensually penetrated in public. A quick look at the YouTube comments under the ad shows you plenty of viewers got the 'joke,' and several wondered what the ad even accomplished in reference to making anyone want to buy or play Call of Duty: Black Ops 7. </p>



<p>Losing an argument with the ASA isn't the only thing Activision lost with regard to Black Ops 7. The latest entry in the annualized shooter series also lost to <strong>Battlefield 6</strong> on the sales charts, <a href="https://wccftech.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-trails-battlefield-6-eu-launch-sales-and-black-ops-6-launch/">both at launch</a> and overall for 2025, <a href="https://wccftech.com/battlefield-6-best-selling-game-in-us-2025/">when looking at the best-selling games in the US.</a></p>



<p>The game's launch was received so poorly that the team released a statement <a href="https://wccftech.com/call-of-duty-team-vows-no-more-back-to-back-releases-after-black-ops-7-flop/">vowing that it would no longer release back-to-back games in the same sub-series</a>. So, no more Black Ops 6 followed by Black Ops 7 runs of back-to-back Call of Duty titles. Instead, we can expect the back and forth of a Black Ops title one year and a Modern Warfare title the next.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/irresponsible-and-offensive-call-of-duty-black-ops-7-ad-banned-in-uk-for-joking-about-sexual-violence/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cyberpunk platformer Replaced catches another delay for "final tweaks" based on demo feedback]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/cyberpunk-platformer-replaced-catches-another-delay-for-final-tweaks-based-on-demo-feedback</link>
            <guid>1439317</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>"Reaching this final stretch has shown us that we need just a few more weeks to ensure the experience is exactly what you deserve"</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/replaced-delayed-following-demo-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/replaced-delayed-following-demo-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/replaced-delayed-following-demo-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/replaced-delayed-following-demo-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/replaced-delayed-following-demo-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/replaced-delayed-following-demo-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/replaced-delayed-following-demo-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/replaced-delayed-following-demo-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/replaced-delayed-following-demo-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Thunderful Publishing</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/replaced">Replaced</a>, the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/release-date-for-dystopian-platformer-replaced-slips-to-2024">long-in-development dystopian platformer from Sad Cat Studios</a>, has had its release pushed back a little further. The studio have taken on feedback from the demo they recently released on Steam - that's the one which kept surnaming me - and reckon a few more weeks of acting on it are in order to get the game ready to go.</p>
<!--more-->

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Replaced - Official Gameplay Demo Launch Trailer" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/-yHZA10PAl0?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Replaced - Official Gameplay Demo Launch Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/-yHZA10PAl0?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/-yHZA10PAl0?autoplay=1" title="Replaced - Official Gameplay Demo Launch Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-yHZA10PAl0" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>


<p>Sad Cat announced Replaced's new release date of April 14th in <a href="https://x.com/REPLACEDGame/status/2024122392310591889">a statement</a> posted to the socials. "As a small team working on our very first title, we've poured everything we have into this project," they wrote. "While the game is technically finished, reaching this final stretch has shown us that we need just a few more weeks to ensure the experience is exactly what you deserve. We want the version of Replaced you play on day one to be polished, stable, and true to the vision we've shared with you.</p>
<p>"The response to our Steam demo has been the ultimate fuel for us. To be honest, putting it out there was nerve-wracking, but seeing your gameplay, reading your reviews and hearing your excitement has been overwhelming in the best way possible. We are constantly reading your comments, and that feedback is helping us make the final tweaks that will make the full game shine."</p><p>The cyberpunk platformer's demo will be staying up on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1663850/REPLACED">Steam</a> in the meantime, so you can at least use the extra waiting to to give it another go or try it for the first time. If you want my thoughts on that demo, you can <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/cyberpunk-platformer-replaced-has-a-demo-out-and-its-wonderfully-atmospheric-when-youre-not-plummeting-a-short-distance">find them here</a>.</p>
<p>The short version is that I found Replaced plenty visually striking and with definite potential story-wise, if a bit repetitive when it came to the activities you get up to as an AI in a grizzled futuristic bloke's body. I also got shot in the head through a box by a giant evil light.</p>

        </div>

      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/cyberpunk-platformer-replaced-catches-another-delay-for-final-tweaks-based-on-demo-feedback]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jacksepticeye Apologizes For Criticizing Life Is Strange 2’s Political Message: ‘I’ve Learned A Great Deal In The Last 8 Years’]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/life-is-strange-2-jacksepticeye-playthrough-politics-2000670659</link>
            <guid>1439308</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><span>YouTuber and Let’s Player Seán William “Jacksepticeye” McLoughlin has apologized for criticizing </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/life-is-strange-2-is-about-finding-the-meaning-of-famil-1840491727"><i><span>Life Is Strange 2</span></i><span>’s</span></a><span> political commentary when he played the game on his channel back in 2019.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><span>When Don’t Nod released </span><i><span>Life Is Strange 2</span></i> <a href="https://kotaku.com/im-not-sure-if-binging-life-is-strange-2-is-the-right-m-1840392293"><span>episodically over the course of 2019</span></a><span>, it attempted to tackle a wide array of political issues such as police brutality, racism, and immigration through the eyes of two Mexican-American brothers named Sean and Daniel. The pair spend the episodic adventure game on the run from law enforcement after a Seattle cop kills their father and Daniel’s latent telekinetic powers activate and kill the officer. As they walk through the United States, they’re confronted with all sorts of racism, abuse, and systemic failures.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><i><span>Life Is Strange 2</span></i><span> throws any pretense of not being a political story out the window before the first episode is over, and while this was </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/you-should-play-life-is-strange-2-1840213387"><span>a subject of praise for a lot of critics</span></a><span> seven years ago, it was also a point of contention for players who thought its commentary was forced or heavyhanded. Well, a lot has happened in the years since, and it’s harder to deny just how true to life </span><i><span>Life Is Strange 2</span></i><span> was. McLoughlin, who played through the whole game in 2019, signed off on the final episode of his Let’s Play critiquing Don’t Nod’s writing as “pushing one very specific agenda,” though he admitted he was “not the type of person to tackle these sort of political issues” and wasn’t trying to “downplay” the realities of being brown in America.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <p><span>“I feel like there’s a lot more depth to this than you’re really tackling,” McLoughlin said. “I hope I’m not coming across as ignorant or anything because that’s not what I’m trying to say. If anything, I want to learn more about it. I want to get into it and I want to understand what’s going on a lot more but these things just don’t really shine a light on it that much. If anything it is just shining a light on it and then taking the light off immediately. It does suck that this stuff happens in the real world and I really wish it didn’t. Humans are complicated and a lot of humans are fucked up and have no empathy at all but hopefully we we get to a better place soon and hopefully things don’t get worse before they get better.”</span></p>  <p><span>Well, it seems the </span><i><span>Life Is Strange </span></i><span>community didn’t forget McLoughlin’s criticism, as a thread recently started circulating on X asking fans to offer up “the worst </span><i><span>Life Is Strange</span></i><span> takes” they’d seen, and </span><a href="https://x.com/D_I_D_I_A_Z/status/2023735659916063088?s=20"><span>one fan responded</span></a><span>, “White men playing</span><i><span> Life Is Strange 2</span></i><span> and calling it unrealistic and too political.” Another fan tagged McLoughlin and said they were still waiting for an apology from the YouTuber for his comments in 2019, and McLoughlin </span><a href="https://x.com/Jacksepticeye/status/2023875097749344713?s=20"><span>replied</span></a><span> by apologizing and admitting he had been “naive.”</span></p>

 <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">Did I really say that? Jesus! I'm sorry. How naive I was. I've learned a great deal in the last 8 years</p> <p>— Jacksepticeye (@Jacksepticeye) <a href="https://twitter.com/Jacksepticeye/status/2023875097749344713?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 17, 2026</a></p></blockquote>  <p><span>While McLoughlin said back in 2019 that he hoped things wouldn’t get worse before they got better in America, they unfortunately have, and as more stories have come out about ICE’s violent treatment of immigrants and the </span><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2026/feb/17/ice-holds-people-in-disgusting-conditions-now-its-turning-warehouses-into-camps"><span>abhorrent conditions of the camps where it’s holding detained individuals</span></a><span>, it’s become harder for anyone to deny the state of things in this country. </span><i><span>Life Is Strange 2</span></i><span> wasn’t overly political, </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/life-is-strange-2-is-a-heartbreakingly-accurate-brother-1840071123"><span>it was actually pretty honest</span></a><span> about how </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-responds-to-dhs-video-using-the-original-animes-theme-2000628222"><span>cartoonishly evil these people are</span></a><span>. It’s a shame things had to reach this level for so many people to realize that.</span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/life-is-strange-2-jacksepticeye-playthrough-politics-2000670659]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Does Resident Evil Requiem Have Early Access? Resident Evil 9 Demo Status, Explained]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/resident-evil-requiem-early-access-demo/</link>
            <guid>1439305</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>The wait between Resident Evil games is unbearable. In some ways, it’s great that the franchise isn’t an annual release, or it could taint the greatness. However, if you’re like everyone else, and in a Zombie-like state waiting for the ninth main game, this guide has the latest details on Resident Evil Requiem early access and if there’s a demo to play.</p>



<p>Are you excited for <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tag/resident-evil-requiem/" id="2693" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Requiem</a>? Of course you are. <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tag/resident-evil/" id="259" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Resident Evil</a> has sold an estimated 100-150 million copies worldwide and has both hardcore and mainstream appeal—it’s the best of both worlds. </p>



<p>But it’s T-Virus…sorry, T-minus one week and counting until Resident Evil Requiem, and the world is heading for an outbreak unless there’s early access or a demo.</p>







<h2 id="h-can-you-play-resident-evil-requiem-through-early-access">Can You Play Resident Evil Requiem Through Early Access?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>The halls remain locked for now. Credit to Capcom</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Capcom is breaking hearts by not allowing Resident Evil Requiem to have early access before launch.</strong></p>



<p>There are superior Deluxe and Collector’s Editions to enhance your overall Requiem experience, but you can only get your hands on the content on February 27, like everyone else.</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>More Insider Gaming: </strong><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/resident-evil-requiem-game-length/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">How Long To Beat Resident Evil Requiem? Game Length &amp; Hours</a></li>
</ul>



<p>No special edition has early access, there’s no cool promotion that gets you in a day early, and definitely, there’s no Resident Evil Requiem early access.</p>



<p>On the other hand, it’s well-known that Requiem’s physical copy street date has been broken by nearly two weeks! </p>



<p>That’s right, while you stare at the clock and mark the days on the calendar, some people will have already finished the game once or twice before you’ve even had a chance to install it! If you see people playing it early, this is why.</p>







<h2 id="h-does-resident-evil-9-have-a-demo">Does Resident Evil 9 Have A Demo?</h2>



<p><strong>There is no Resident Evil Requiem demo in sight, and this could be the first Resi title in a while to offer no downloadable hands-on demo.</strong></p>



<p>Resident Evil 7: Biohazard’s Beginning Hour demo was incredible. It managed to feature no discernible action, but delivered a riveting, claustrophobic-inducing snippet of what was to come, AKA Jack Baker trying to carve your face up.</p>



<p>Village’s demo stepped up the intensity a notch and served as an equally compelling chunk of the upcoming game.</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>More Insider Gaming: </strong><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/resident-evil-requiem-review-embargo-date/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Resident Evil Requiem Review Embargo Date</a></li>
</ul>



<p>As it stands, though, Resident Evil Requiem doesn’t have a demo. There was a belief that after the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tag/state-of-play/" id="1515" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">February 2026 PlayStation State of Play</a> show, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/studios/capcom/" id="87630" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Capcom</a> would drop a demo before launch. This didn’t happen, and the world felt like a sadder place because of this.</p>



<p>It’s not impossible that Capcom could still do this, and if the company drops a brief road into Requiem before February 27, we can all scream together in delight—and definitely scream at the demo.</p>



<p>Do you think it’s an odd decision by Capcom not to have a demo this time around? If you’re disappointed, say why through the free-to-join <a href="https://discord.com/channels/1433093283558719611/1433112738133180426" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord Server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>The only thing to keep you going is probably the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/resident-evil-requiem-live-action-trailer-is-as-tragic-as-it-is-terrifying/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Resident Evil Requiem live-action trailer</a>. Make sure to watch it if you haven’t.</p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/resident-evil-requiem-early-access-demo/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cozy puzzle exploration game Hakoniwa Electric announced for PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/02/cozy-puzzle-exploration-game-hakoniwa-electric-announced-for-pc</link>
            <guid>1439302</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Featuring 12 miniature world stages.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Japanese developer <a title="Companies > Anettai" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/anettai">Anettai</a> has announced <em><a title="Games > Hakoniwa Electric" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/hakoniwa-electric">Hakoniwa Electric</a></em>, a cozy puzzle exploration game about fixing electrical problems. It will launch for <a title="Platforms > PC [25,535 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/4422260/__Hakoniwa_Electric/" target="_blank">Steam</a> in 2026 with English and Japanese language support. <span id="more-1027536"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/4422260/__Hakoniwa_Electric/" target="_blank">Steam page</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>Hakoniwa Electric</em> is a cute relaxing puzzle game. Explore adorable isometric stages, solve puzzles, and light them up. Why not spend a leisurely year as <a title="Games > Aka [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/aka">Aka</a>ri, who’s taken over grandpa’s electronics shop, helping with the monthly troubles from the townsfolk?</p><p><strong>Welcome to <em>Hakoniwa Electric</em></strong></p><p><em>Hakoniwa Electric</em> is a relaxing isometric puzzle exploration game where you can unwind at your own pace.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Akari and her robot buddy Lamp take over grandpa’s electronics shop while he’s off vacationing in the tropics.</p><p>Light up the store, put up those job posters, and you’re good to go!</p><p>Tackle the little everyday woes from the townsfolk, and enjoy watching the seasons roll by and the shop slowly come alive over the course of a year.</p><p><strong>12 Adorable, Miniature World Stages</strong></p><p>Explore a charming little isometric world that captures the changing seasons.</p><p>Each stage is packed with delightful details just waiting for you to discover.</p><p><strong>Wiring Puzzles Tucked Away in Cute Isometric Stages</strong></p><p>Every stage hides a puzzle. Spot it, click to rotate the circuit pieces, and connect the wires.</p><p>Solve it, and watch the world light up.</p><p>No tough trial-and-error or math required—just gaze at the cuteness and relax in your own time.</p><p><strong>Akari’s Monthly Diary</strong></p><p><a title="Games > Clea [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/clea">Clea</a>r a stage, and Akari’s “Monthly Diary” updates with glimpses of her daily life. Peek in to see what she felt in that place and who she met…</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li>Nostalgic and adorable stages, like a miniature garden.</li><li>Absolutely no difficult calculations, time limits, or harsh penalties.</li><li>A healing time you can enjoy at your own pace, whenever and however much you like.</li><li>The pleasure of solving puzzles and illuminating a miniature world.</li><li>A gentle year-long story woven by novice shopkeeper Akari and her partner Lamp.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a trailer below.</p><h2><span>Steam Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Hakoniwa Electric - Steam Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Cqh7gVq0PGo?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/02/cozy-puzzle-exploration-game-hakoniwa-electric-announced-for-pc]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sony Plans To Minimize PlayStation 5 Hardware Price Increases By Focusing On “Monetizing” Existing Installed Base]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/playstation-5-price-increases-monetizing-install-base/</link>
            <guid>1439287</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>Although <a data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-style-link dracula-processed" href="https://wccftech.com/dram-nand-shortages-will-extend-beyond-2030-warns-phison-ceo/"><strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">soaring RAM prices</strong></a> haven't yet had a widespread impact on the prices of current-generation consoles, it's highly probable that console manufacturers will eventually be forced to raise hardware prices. However, <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">Sony</strong> has plans in place to minimize the effects of these high component costs, though it's definitely not good news for all current <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)"><em data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">PlayStation 5</em></strong> owners.</p>



<p>As reported by <a data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-style-link dracula-processed" href="https://automaton-media.com/en/news/sony-plans-to-minimize-effect-of-rising-playstation-5-memory-costs-by-boosting-software-and-network-service-revenue-according-to-cfo/"><strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">Automaton</strong></a>, during <strong><a href="https://www.sony.com/en/SonyInfo/IR/library/presen/er/pdf/25q3_sonypre.pdf">Sony's latest earnings call</a></strong>, <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">CFO Lin Tao</strong> addressed the current situation, stating that the company has secured the memory needed for the end-of-the-year sales season in the next fiscal year. However, the company plans to <em data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">"minimize"</em> the impact of rising <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">RAM prices</strong> by <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)"><em data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">"monetizing the installed base"</em></strong> while continuing to grow <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">software and network services revenue</strong>.</p>



<p>Needless to say, this doesn't sound like good news for the <strong>92.2 million current PlayStation 5 owners</strong>. While a direct price increase for games is unlikely, given the goal of growing software volume, the mention of <strong>network services revenue</strong> suggests that an<strong> increase in <a href="https://wccftech.com/marvels-spider-man-2-headlines-february-2026-ps-plus-extra-games-supported-by-a-few-strong-indies/">PlayStation Plus</a>&nbsp;subscription prices could be on the table</strong>. This would impact the vast majority of the user base, as a subscription is required to access <strong>online multiplayer</strong> for most titles.</p>



<p>While any price increase is unfortunate, dealing with soaring component costs driven largely by the <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed">AI-fueled chip crisis</strong> is the biggest challenge every hardware manufacturer will face for the next few years. The situation is reportedly impacting future systems as well, as the <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/playstation-6-delay-2028-2029-nintendo-switch-2-price-increase-2026/"><em data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">PlayStation 6</em> could launch as late as 2028 or 2029</a></strong> in the hopes that prices return to a more reasonable state.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/playstation-5-price-increases-monetizing-install-base/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Killing Stone Is A Roguelite Deckbuilding Game Where Story Is Key]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/killing-stone-is-roguelite-deckbuilding-game-where-story-is-key</link>
            <guid>1439284</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p dir="ltr">Where tough deckbuilding roguelite action and Shakespearean prose meet, you'll find <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/features/killing-stone-is-17th-century-occult-adventure-with-deckbuilding-at-its-core" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="0a9de301-2954-4425-82de-6eb858fd831f" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow"><em>The Killing Stone</em>, Question Games' new title</a>, where you are fighting against the devil to free the family of your newly deceased mentor from a sin-filled contract that she signed them up for.</p><p dir="ltr"><em>The Killing Stone</em> opens with the news of your master, Mariken's, death. Following their traditions, the rest of her family isolates to mourn the loss, but very quickly learns that they're all where One Eye, a faustian devil, wants them to be as he plans to collect on the souls owed to him.</p><p dir="ltr">As Maven, a master of the dark arts, you're able to read the contracts laid out by One Eye, and by participating in card-based battles, you can alter the contracts to benefit the different family members whose lives have unknowingly been put on the line.</p><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/the-killing-stone-preview-one-eye.jpg?itok=gwPWHuLJ 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="1080">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/the-killing-stone-preview-one-eye.jpg?itok=qaAl8Mgh 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture><p dir="ltr">The way that the story relates to the gameplay is that each member of the cursed family that you assist will start you with a deck, including some cursed cards. Over the course of a number of runs, you'll not only work to defeat One Eye and his lieutenants through playing the game, but upgrade your deck and even seek to remove the cursed cards to get the 'best' ending.</p><h2 dir="ltr">Play Your Cards In A One-Dimensional Deckbuilding Roguelite Game</h2><p dir="ltr">In <em>The Killing Stone</em>, the core gameplay is centered around a card battling system where you spend energy to summon creatures, try to take out your opponents health while preserving your own, and work your way through the different nodes of the contracts that can offer a variety of good or bad effects.</p><p dir="ltr">Beginning with the card game itself, each round you'll gain three energy to spend on your cards. These can be units that will deal damage or have other effects, or spells that can affect you or your opponent. You can only ever have three units on the main battle line, but there are spaces to fill in 'reserve' units, which sit above the main units on the board and take over their place if the main unit falls.</p><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/the-killing-stone-combat.jpg?itok=RBuUIIZx 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="1080">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/the-killing-stone-combat.jpg?itok=faJMApRQ 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture><p dir="ltr">There are a large number of abilities in play that will control how a unit might gain or lose attacking might or health, how they might be powered up depending on where they're played, or even how they might be able to be deployed behind enemy lines.</p><p dir="ltr">There are some excellent quality of life additions that you'll see when contemplating activating your spells or placing your units. You can always see when combat is activated which units will remain alive, which will take damage, and how much damage you might deal directly to your opponent. This is incredibly helpful when you've got to factor in up to six units a side, spells, reserves, and all kinds of other abilities.</p><h2 dir="ltr">Each Layer Of <em>The Killing Stone</em> Adds Additional Challenge</h2><p dir="ltr">Your deck and build will constantly be changing as you progress through the framework of each Ritual's contract.</p><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/the-killing-stone-preview-contract.jpg?itok=SfQLitjq 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="1080">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/the-killing-stone-preview-contract.jpg?itok=8xyaaq-5 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture><p dir="ltr">When you start each family member will have Curse cards, these are often negative cards that will force you to do something like sacrifice one of your creatures before you can do anything else or they could just sit in your hand and be useless. You'll have chances to get rid of these curses, but the game also finds a way to put more of them in front of you.</p><p dir="ltr">Forge events are nodes where you can alter sets of cards in your hands. These can include lowering the summoning costs of cards, getting new cards, or even getting rid of Curse cards. These also come in a variety of levels offering better cards, though those are normally behind riskier battles.</p><p dir="ltr">Outside of the cards in your hand there are also Boons and Banes that can be picked up, permanent modifiers that will grow as you spend time with the deck. Some of these are temporary, while others will have the opportunity to become permanent further refining your build.</p><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/the-killing-stone-preview-forge.jpg?itok=D4Cz_IyA 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="1080">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/the-killing-stone-preview-forge.jpg?itok=qgp2bwOI 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture><p dir="ltr">To cap it all off certain difficult battles even have additional rules that might just benefit your opponent, or could also force you both to act in certain ways. An early additional rule I ran into was that every turn I received a card that would let me draw two more cards at no cost, but I needed to sacrifice one unit every turn before I could play any other cards.</p><p dir="ltr">The style and speed of gameplay immediately shifted as I was drawing cards and playing with so many more opportunities, but it was also being forced to kill off powerful units just as quickly.</p><h2 dir="ltr">A Roguelite With A Heavy Emphasis On Story</h2><p dir="ltr">Each member of the family has their own deck that you'll be building over the course of their chapter. You'll learn about the family members through optional dialogue with them and the rest of the family, and even talk with the spirit of Mariken herself.</p><p dir="ltr">The game ties into the greater story by the state of each family member's deck coming back in the final act of the game, as a deck you return to, but also one that will decide the character's fate.</p><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/the-killing-stone-preview-save-deck.jpg?itok=DjCpxpRW 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="1080">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/the-killing-stone-preview-save-deck.jpg?itok=XlUIV1aT 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture><p dir="ltr">After completing the story of a family member, you'll be able to save the deck and continue on to the next family member, but if you think you could do better or want to craft a deck completely free of any curses then you can replay that chapter and just enjoy the deckbuilding gameplay.</p><p dir="ltr">It's in this way that there's still runs and getting better as you'd expect from a Roguelite, but also a point where you're going to narratively save the character by improving on their deck enough.</p><h2 dir="ltr"><em>The Killing Stone's</em> Dialogue Is Too Rich</h2><p dir="ltr">A key aspect of <em>The Killing Stone</em> is the dedication to the storytelling, and the way the story is told to the player. The game has a Modern English setting, that is something akin to enjoying modern media set in the past, and then there's a Period English that is much closer to classic Shakespearean.</p><p dir="ltr">Listening to Liam O'Brien's One Eye and Emma Gregory's Mariken being performed in the Period English has been so entertaining. Luckily, you can also set the spoken dialogue to one, while the written is set to the other. I most enjoyed it when I could hear the period english performances, while also making sure I missed nothing in the text.</p><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/the-killing-stone-preview-period-english.jpg?itok=BlMYK5Nq 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="1080">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/the-killing-stone-preview-period-english.jpg?itok=nwGC3ST2 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture><p>I know I could have made it by with just reading the Period English, but I likely would have wanted to be there with a highlighter and margin space to ponder and interpret.</p><p dir="ltr">While these two performances are spectacular, and they absolutely hold your attention while being performed, it is a bit disappointing that the other characters that you interact with aren't voiced at all. In scenes where your character, another member of the family, and One Eye are each taking turns to speak it's only even 1/3rd of the conversation that you're hearing instead of just reading.</p><h2 dir="ltr">Early Access Doesn't Skimp On The Content</h2><p dir="ltr"><em>The Killing Stone</em> is releasing in Early Access, but it was only a few weeks ago that today was intended to be the full date of release. A side-effect of this is that in its current state, you get to play, and replay, the main three story arcs for the different family members, have access to all of the optional missions, and the vast majority of the cards.</p><p dir="ltr">The only thing narratively that isn't available at present is the final arc, The Reckoning, that is going to be added later. While it's a shame a 1.0 release wasn't able to happen, this does give players plenty of chances to replay the story arcs and craft decks free of curses.</p><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/the-killing-stone-preview-curse.jpg?itok=fCSKAA87 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="1080">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/the-killing-stone-preview-curse.jpg?itok=wQnqSUzV 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="675">
                  

  </picture><p dir="ltr">Unlike a lot of Early Access titles that seem to launch in a 50% state and work their way up to 100%, my experience with <em>The Killing Stone</em> has felt more like 85% of the game, leaving me to anticipate the final 15%.</p><h2 dir="ltr">I'm Ready For More <em>Killing Stone</em></h2><p dir="ltr"><em>The Killing Stone</em> is a really enjoyable and complex deckbuilding roguelite. I wasn't too sure how I would feel about the emphasis that narrative has on the story, but it's woven in so nicely with the gameplay that you want to progress not just because the game gets more enjoyably complex, but also because you want to hear more of the stunning performances in the game.</p><p dir="ltr">While I've finished a number of rituals and crafted some fine decks, I can definitely see this as a quick roguelite to continue to return to and build towards that Reckoning so that I'm ready for its release.</p><hr><p><em><strong>The Killing Stone </strong>was previewed on PC via Steam with a code provided by the publisher over the course of 12 hours - All images were taken by the previewer.</em></p></div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Andrew has written Video Game and Entertainment news, reviews, and guides for 10+ years. As Senior Content Manager, he assists in creating and editing… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/andrew-stretch">More about Andrew</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/killing-stone-is-roguelite-deckbuilding-game-where-story-is-key]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[If you can't beat AI, become one in Hooded Horse strategy RPG Heart of the Machine, which hits 1.0 release in March]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/if-you-cant-beat-ai-become-one-in-hooded-horse-strategy-rpg-heart-of-the-machine-which-hits-10-release-in-march</link>
            <guid>1439281</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Devs Arcen boast of "mind-boggling" intricacies</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/heart-of-the-machine-release-date-1.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/heart-of-the-machine-release-date-1.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/heart-of-the-machine-release-date-1.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/heart-of-the-machine-release-date-1.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/heart-of-the-machine-release-date-1.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/heart-of-the-machine-release-date-1.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/heart-of-the-machine-release-date-1.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/heart-of-the-machine-release-date-1.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/heart-of-the-machine-release-date-1.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Arcen Games / Hooded Horse</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Why is everything rolling sideways on my desk all of a sudden? What’s this mysterious force, dragging my chair towards the wall? Why are all the cars in the vicinity tumbling and rolling in the direction of *checks press release* ...North Carolina, USA? It can only be gravitational disturbance caused by the impending 1.0 release of a massive <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-best-strategy-games-on-pc">strategy</a> project. This time it’s <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/heart-of-the-machine">Heart of the Machine</a>, a “4X-style”, “dimension-busting” sci-fi game developed by Arcen Games and published by Hooded Horse. 
</p><!--more-->
<p>
I’m always up for a new Hooded Horse gig, but I am <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/grand-strategy-game-terra-invicta-is-an-alien-invasion-sim-so-vast-and-slow-the-aliens-seem-lost-within-it">still trying to figure out spacewar in Terra Invictus</a>. And now, ladies and gentlebots, you would have me contend with a game in which I play a super-advanced AI trying to conquer a grim future civilisation from the inside. A game that will last an estimated 90-175 hours. A game that boasts of “a mind-boggling array of goals, story-threads, and opportunities for players to pursue as they seek to find their place amidst a crumbling society in desperate need of saving from itself.”
</p>
<p>
Still, at least this is the <em>fun</em> kind of AI, the homely 80s action movie breed of AI that simply wishes to weaponise bees, build android armies and hack fortified skyscrapers. Not the actually existing, present-day kind of AI that consists of a billion typewriter monkeys who want to summarise your emails so your boss can make your labour 1.2% more profitable, at least till the world runs out of silicon, water and fossil fuels. I exaggerate! I hope I’m exaggerating. Besides, there probably are typewriter monkeys in Heart of the Machine, which also promises “parkour bears”, velociraptors and cat palaces.
</p>
<p>
“The 1.0 update will usher in a whole new ending, with four potential variants that involve everything from wormholes to last-minute betrayals, to players winning control over the entire city,” explains the press release. The developer has a longer account of the changes (and post-1.0 plans) on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/2001070/view/742666698308452997?l=english">Steam</a>, which is quite interesting. I wasn’t expecting a Fire Emblem: Three Houses comparison. You can also find the game on <a href="https://www.gog.com/en/game/heart_of_the_machine">GOG</a> and <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/p/heart-of-the-machine-84306f">Epic Games Store</a>.
</p>

        </div>

      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/if-you-cant-beat-ai-become-one-in-hooded-horse-strategy-rpg-heart-of-the-machine-which-hits-10-release-in-march]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Highguard Devs ‘Focused On Delivering Updates’ Amid Radio Silence]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/highguard-update-roadmap-servers-discord-2000670633</link>
            <guid>1439275</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><a href="https://kotaku.com/highguard-the-kotaku-review-is-it-good-free-ps5-pc-5v5-3v3-update-patch-2000664646">As<em> Highguard</em></a> approaches its one-month anniversary, the hero shooter’s future is harder than ever to discern. But despite dwindling player numbers and recent layoffs, the developers are still working on getting the multiplayer game’s next update out.</p> <p>There’s been relative radio silence from Wildlight Entertainment since <a href="https://kotaku.com/highguard-studio-developer-layoffs-wildlight-entertainment-2000667841">mass layoffs</a> at the California-based studio last week. Then, when <em>Highguard</em>‘s website went down yesterday, <a href="https://kotaku.com/highguard-website-down-shutting-down-servers-free-to-play-shooter-steam-playercount-2000669734">people began to assume the worst</a>. The studio declined to comment on the status of the game when <em>Kotaku</em> reached out, but now a developer on the <em>Highguard</em> Discord has given remaining players a scrap of insight into where things are at.</p>

 <figure id="attachment_2000670636" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000670636"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000670636">Discord</figcaption></figure> <p>“Not sure on the timeframe, but basically needs to be transferred and simplified,” moderator WL_Coronach wrote in response to a fan asking about the website being down. “Low priority atm (reputational damage already done). Now we just need to focus on delivering updates and content to improve.”</p> <p>What exactly those updates consist of remains to be seen. Wildlight was in the midst of delivering on its “Episode 2” commitments when everyone outside of a “core” team was laid off last week. An ambitious, year-long roadmap shared at launch is likely being completely overhauled at this point. One of the big questions is just how much of this content was already pretty far along or sitting in queue versus having to be built from scratch.</p>

 <figure id="attachment_2000670634" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000670634"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000670634">Wildlight Entertainment</figcaption></figure> <p>The big additions to <em>Highguard</em> thus far have been a new playable hero and a 5v5 mode, as well as the option to do 3v3 ranked. While initial criticisms of the game have called for portions of its resource gathering and flag capturing phases to be reworked, what existing players probably want more than anything are additional characters and loot. The game launched with a starting roster of only eight. In 5v5, the more popular of the two modes, that’s a lot of repeats. The gun and gear pools are also pretty light.</p>

 <p>It’s hard to imagine any number of new guns or characters pulling <em>Highguard</em> out of its current live-service tailspin. With time and resources, there’s a strong foundation that Wildlight could build on. <a href="https://kotaku.com/highguard-wildlight-tencent-funding-layoffs-servers-2000669790">But if money</a> is already evaporating and players aren’t spending much on the free-to-play game’s marketplace, it’s hard to imagine it having the runway necessary to mount a real comeback.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/highguard-update-roadmap-servers-discord-2000670633]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[God of War: Sons of Sparta is the Worst-Rated Game in the Series]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/god-of-war-sons-of-sparta-is-the-worst-rated-game-in-the-series/</link>
            <guid>1439272</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>God of War: Sons of Sparta has the worst rating on Metacritic out of all the games from the God of War franchise. </p>



<p>The new 2D Metroidvania God of War title was shadowdropped during the latest PlayStation State of Play event. Since then, we have also seen the series’ original creator share harsh comments about the title. Now that the review numbers have popped up, it doesn’t seem to be performing well compared to the others. </p>







<h2 id="h-god-of-war-sons-of-sparta-rating-falls-under-70">God of War: Sons of Sparta Rating Falls Under 70</h2>



<p>Spotted by <a href="https://www.gamesradar.com/games/god-of-war/new-god-of-war-game-sons-of-spartas-early-metacritic-score-places-it-as-the-worst-in-the-series-with-even-the-divisive-ascension-over-10-points-higher/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">GamesRadar+</a>, if you head to <a href="https://www.metacritic.com/search/god%20of%20war/?page=1&amp;category=13" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">MetaCritic.com</a> and search for ratings for all God of War games, it is pretty evident that Sons of Sparta is falling short. The 2018 God of War and Ragnarok are at the very top, both with a score of 94. Additionally, all the titles from the Greek Trilogy also score above 90. What’s more, the PSP instalments, Ghost of Sparta and Chains of Olympus, are also considerably higher rated than the recently released game. </p>



<p>The worst-rated God of War game to date was God of War: Ascension, with a score of 80. However, Sons of Sparta falls even further with its score coming in at 69, which has a 69 rating based on critic reviews and a 6.6 score based on user reviews. Insider Gaming has also reviewed Sons of Sparta, giving it a score of 7 and calling it “a pretty good game that will cater more toward God of War fans than Metroidvania enthusiasts seeking the next big thing. Check out the full review <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/reviews/god-of-war-sons-of-sparta-review/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">here</a>. </p>







<p>In other news, God of War 2018 and Ragnarok have <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/god-of-war-2018-and-ragnarok-have-generated-over-1-4-billion-in-combined-sales/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">generated over $1.4 billion in combined sales</a>. Additionally, it’s claimed that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/santa-monica-developing-more-than-just-god-of-war-trilogy-remake-its-claimed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Santa Monica is developing more</a> than just the God of War Trilogy Remake. What are your thoughts on God of War: Sons of Sparta becoming the worst-rated game in the series? Leave your thoughts down in the comments, and join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/escape-from-tarkov-roadmap-new-boss-in-game-event/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Escape from Tarkov’s roadmap, including a new boss and a large in-game event</a>.&nbsp;Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/god-of-war-sons-of-sparta-is-the-worst-rated-game-in-the-series/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Call of Duty advert banned due to ‘implied painful penetration of a man’]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/02/18/call-of-duty-advert-banned-due-to-implied-painful-penetration-of-a-man/</link>
            <guid>1439251</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>A <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/call-of-duty-black-ops-7/">Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 </a>advert that screened on YouTube and on streaming services for ITV and Channel 5 has been banned by the UK’s advertising regulator, the Advertising Standards Authority (ASA).</p>
<p>The ad shows a ‘replacement’ airport security guard frisking a man and asking him to remove “everything but the shoes”, before a female guard snaps on a rubber glove and gleefully adds, “Here comes the puppet show.”</p>


<p>The Advertising Standards Authority received nine complaints from people who believed the ad trivialised sexual violence.</p>
<p>The ASA acknowledged that there was no explicit imagery in the advert, but the humour was “generated by the humiliation and implied threat of painful, non-consensual penetration of the man”.</p>

<p>They concluded the advert “trivialised sexual violence and was therefore irresponsible and offensive.”</p>
<p><iframe title="Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 - The Replacer &quot;Airport Security&quot;" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/FH1csdj8oMk?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Activision has clarified that the advert was not shown around children’s programming. Black Ops 7 has a PEGI 18 rating for “graphic violence, decapitations, dismemberment, strong language,” so it should not be sold to children.</p>
<p>We scored Call of Duty : Black Ops 7 a <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/11/25/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-review/">6/10 in our review.</a> “Black Ops 7 really demonstrates the difficulties of Call of Duty’s yearly release schedule and going back-to-back with its sub-series,” said Stefan.</p>
<p>“It’s not as rushed-feeling as Modern Warfare III was, that’s for sure, but it’s also not a consistent experience. The multiplayer and Zombies are solid continuations from last year, but there’s not too much excitement in that, especially after the energy-sapping co-op campaign and Endgame.”</p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/articles/czd831elpz5o" target="_blank" rel="noopener">BBC News</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/02/18/call-of-duty-advert-banned-due-to-implied-painful-penetration-of-a-man/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[“In My Head, Season Pass is Connected to F2P Games” – Star Wars: Galactic Racer Dev Explains Why There’s No Such Plan]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/star-wars-galactic-racer-dev-connects-season-pass-to-f2p-games/</link>
            <guid>1439245</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>The <a href="https://wccftech.com/star-wars-galactic-racer-the-game-awards-2025-fuse-games/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">reveal</a> of <strong>Star Wars: Galactic Racer</strong> at The Game Awards 2025 was a nice surprise for all those gamers who were dearly missing a Star Wars racing game. The last one to be released was <strong>Star Wars: Racer Revenge</strong>, launched in <strong>February 2002</strong> for the <strong>PlayStation 2</strong> console. It's been an age, at least as far as gaming goes.</p>



<p>Earlier this month, the developers at <strong>Fuse Games</strong> even <a href="https://wccftech.com/yes-star-wars-galactic-racer-has-podracing/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">confirmed</a> that <strong>podracing would indeed be featured in the game</strong>, alongside other vehicle types. Then, last week, a new promising gameplay trailer <a href="https://wccftech.com/now-this-is-podracing-star-wars-galactic-racer-gameplay-debuted-at-february-state-of-play/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">was shared during the State of Play broadcast</a>.</p>



<p>Now, <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-big-star-wars-galactic-racer-interview-why-its-not-open-world-how-its-story-mode-works-and-when-its-set" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">speaking to IGN</a>, Fuse Games founder and CEO <strong>Matt Webster</strong> and creative director <strong>Kieran Crimmins</strong> have revealed more details about approaching Lucasfilm to make the game and also confirmed that <strong>there are no current plans to adopt a Season Pass system</strong>, with Webster saying <strong>he immediately connects Season Passes to free-to-play games</strong>, while Star Wars: Galactic Racer is a premium offering.</p>



<p><em><strong>Webster:</strong>&nbsp;No. This is a premium release, right? We have our campaign and we have arcade mode and we have multiplayer, and it's a self-contained thing. But what we also recognize is that the landscape of Star Wars evolves and changes over time and so do games as they go. So we see an opportunity for us to tap into more Star Wars or new Star Wars over time, but in terms of us outlining what we think post launch is going to look like, that's not something that we see. The only reason I say a blind no to it is, in my head, season pass is connected to free-to-play games, and that's not what we are making.</em></p>



<p><em><strong>Crimmins:</strong>&nbsp;Our mindset right now is a premium release, to try and get an amazing experience out the box. Obviously we wouldn't close the door to doing something later, but that isn't what we are really thinking about right now. We just want it to be the very best game it can be, and we want it to be complete when it comes out.</em></p>



<p>That's certainly good news for everyone interested in playing Star Wars: Galactic Racer without having to purchase an extra Season Pass. Of course, if the game does well, <strong>Fuse Games will probably release some DLCs</strong>, but that's an entirely different matter.</p>



<p>In the interview, the developers from Fuse Games also <strong>revealed a unique boost system</strong> that they hope will make their racing game even more tactical. Star Wars: Galactic Racer features a two-phase boost, with the second phase called a <strong>ramjet</strong>, which is extremely fast, but also generates a lot of heat. Eventually, <strong>the player's vehicle could even explode if they're not careful enough</strong>, and the tracks will play a part, too: racing over lava will increase the heat even further.</p>



<p>The game has no release date beyond a <strong>generic 2026</strong>. It will be out on PC, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series S and X.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/star-wars-galactic-racer-dev-connects-season-pass-to-f2p-games/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>