<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 16:53:28 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[FuturLab's PowerWash Simulator 2 Gets A Switch 2 Release Date]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/10/futurlabs-powerwash-simulator-2-gets-a-switch-2-release-date</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/futurlabs-powerwash-simulator-2-gets-a-switch-2-release-date.1318885/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>

<p>As <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/powerwash-simulator-2-blasts-the-dirt-off-your-switch-2-this-autumn">we reported</a> not long ago, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/powerwash-simulator-2">PowerWash Simulator 2</a>, the cunningly-named sequel to <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/powerwash_simulator">PowerWash Simulator</a>, is winging its way to Switch 2, which is a very good thing indeed given how popular the first outing was.</p>
<p>Now, the folks over at Futurlab have announced that their cleaning sim sequel will release on <strong>23rd October 2025</strong>. Hey, that's this month!</p>
<p>To get us in the mood for the adventure to come, the Brighton-based UK dev has also released a training video, which you can find at the top of this very article, and you should definitely pay close attention to it. Power-washing is a very serious business, after all.</p>
<p>In this follow-up, besides the returning Muckingham, players will also be set base-building tasks and other unique activities in all-new locations, "from retro roller discos to campfires, mining trucks and a suspiciously large novelty teapot", it says here.</p>
<p>Here are some further deets from the developer:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"The jobs and water keep flowing in PowerWash Simulator 2. Play through a fresh new campaign, uncovering more of Muckingham’s mysteries. Plus, venture even further out to brand-new grime-coated locations like Sponge Valley, Power Falls and Lubri City.</p>
<p><strong>KEY FEATURES RECAP:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Split-Screen &amp; Online Multiplayer</strong> – Clean solo, with a friend on the couch, or with up to four players online – all with shared progression.</p>
<p><strong>Abseiling &amp; Scissor Lift</strong> – Scale buildings, hover over rooftops, and clean from every angle. Don’t worry – fall damage doesn’t exist here.</p>
<p><strong>Multi-Stage Jobs</strong> – Just when you think you’ve finished, surprise: there’s more to clean. Some jobs expand mid-wash, unlocking new areas on the fly.</p>
<p><strong>Home Base Customisation</strong> – Restore furniture, decorate your HQ, and keep your base clean(ish). You earned it.</p>
<p><strong>Career Mode</strong> – Take on 38 jobs across increasingly strange, sprawling, and oddly satisfying locations.</p>
<p><strong>Soap, Nozzles &amp; Tools</strong> – Upgrade your washer loadout with adaptable nozzles, surface cleaners, and yes, foamy soap.</p>
<p><strong>Cat Companions</strong> – Ulysses and her kittens are back, following you on jobs and expecting to be petted. Often."</p></blockquote><blockquote>
</blockquote>


<p>PowerWash Simulator 2 launches October 23rd and costs <strong>$24.99 / €24.99 / £19.99</strong> (or whatever that might equate to where you are).</p>
<hr>
<p><em>Looking forward to diving into more Power-washing goodness? Be sure to let us know in the comments!</em></p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:187796,179422,144417 @ 1759855502 -->
</section></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/10/futurlabs-powerwash-simulator-2-gets-a-switch-2-release-date]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Destiny 2’s Player Count on Steam Hit A Record Low Ahead of Coming Star Wars Expansion]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/destiny-2-player-count-steam-record-low-ahead-of-star-wars-expansion-bungie/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/destiny-2%E2%80%99s-player-count-on-steam-hit-a-record-low-ahead-of-coming-star-wars-expansion.1318882/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>To say that Bungie has had a bad couple of years would be an understatement, in many ways. Despite the small boost that came along with Destiny 2: The Final Shape,<a href="https://wccftech.com/bungie-makes-layoff-announcement-in-blog-post/"> layoffs</a>, scandals <a href="https://wccftech.com/bungie-confirms-that-marathon-includes-art-assets-taken-from-an-artist-without-permission/">around stolen work</a>, and <a href="https://wccftech.com/former-bungie-developers-point-to-leadership-for-the-studios-issues-everything-happening-to-bungie-is-because-of-greed/">reports of poor and greedy leadership</a> overshadow anything positive the studio has going on.</p>



<p>The latest negative tally to add to the pile comes from a report from <a href="https://thegamepost.com/destiny-2-lowest-player-count-steam-franchise-history-bungie-trust/">The Game Post</a>, which points to Destiny 2's <a href="https://steamcharts.com/app/1085660#1m">Steam Chart numbers</a>, which hit an all-time low for the game since its release on Steam in 2019. It should be said that Steam numbers aren't everything, but it's still not necessarily a good look for Destiny 2 to be in such a low place <a href="https://wccftech.com/destiny-2-edge-of-fate-out-now/">after the recent launch of its Edge of Fate expansion</a>, and ahead of a very major <a href="https://wccftech.com/destiny-2-star-wars-expansion-renegades-bungie/">Star Wars expansion called Renegades</a>, which is due out this coming December.</p>



<p>Per the Steam Charts, Destiny 2's monthly average was 18,349 players when The Game Post published its report. At the time of this writing, the average is listed at 18,100 players for the last 30 days.</p>



<p>Is a Star Wars expansion the medicine Bungie needs for Destiny 2 to turn player counts like this around? It could be. Technically, anything is possible. Whether it will is an entirely different question. Even if the idea of wielding a lightsaber gets players to pick Destiny 2 back up, or even to try it for the first time, one of the game's lasting issues has been how obtuse it is to get into or get back into, even if you are a returning player.</p>



<p>In other Bungie news, the studio just yesterday announced that it is hosting <a href="https://wccftech.com/bungie-marathon-not-dead-closed-technical-test-sign-ups-open/">a closed technical test for Marathon that players can sign up for</a>, and Pete Parsons, <a href="https://wccftech.com/bungie-studio-head-pete-parsons-leaves-23-years-justin-truman-take-over/">who was at the studio's helm for years, has left his role and retired</a>. </p>

			
			<p>Follow <a href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> or <a href="https://google.com/preferences/source?q=wccftech.com">add us as a preferred source</a>, to get our news coverage and reviews in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/destiny-2-player-count-steam-record-low-ahead-of-star-wars-expansion-bungie/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SanDisk MagSafe SSD Feels Practically Free at $0.10 per GB With Prime Day Discount, Works With iPhone]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/sandisk-magsafe-ssd-feels-practically-free-at-0-10-per-gb-with-prime-day-discount-works-with-iphone-2000632166</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sandisk-magsafe-ssd-feels-practically-free-at-0-10-per-gb-with-prime-day-discount-works-with-iphone.1318876/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Tell me if this has ever happened to you. You and you’re friends are out having fun and you want to snap a quick group photo, or maybe something crazy is happening in front of you and you feel the need to record it. You pull out your phone, open the camera app, and then a little pop-up says your storage is full and that it can’t take any new photos. Then you frantically scrub through your camera roll looking for things okay to delete only for them to still not be enough somehow, and then the moment has passed.</p>
<p>Managing phone storage can be a nightmare, especially for those of us still carrying pics from over 10 years ago. There is a solution that is not upgrading to a larger capacity phone or paying a huge monthly fee for cloud storage. SanDisk has an SSD designed for use with phones which happens to be on sale for Amazon’s Prime Big Deals Day. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4590/">On October 7 and October 8, you can save $25 on the 1TB SSD (comes to $110) or $37 on the 2TB SSD (comes to $170).</a></p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4590/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Record on Your Phone to the Drive</h2>
<p>This SanDisk external SSD has been made specifically for use with your phone. It connects over USB-C meaning its compatible on any iPhone 15 and up and can then record photos and videos directly to the drive. The drive uses exFAT formatting which means it’s compatible with Windows, Android, and macOS devices right out of the box.</p>
<p>The Creator Phone SSD is even shaped to fit snuggly on the back of your Phone without being visible from the front. It uses MagSafe so it actually magnetically connects to the back of your phone, staying firmly in place while in use.</p>



<p>Along with recording new footage or photography onto the drive, you can also transfer stuff already on your camera roll to the drive or vice versa. Great for if you want spend an afternoon clearing out some of your old photos without getting rid of them to just make room new ones.</p>
<p>The drive really shines for for creators who frequently record video using their phone be it for work or otherwise. You can shoot in Apple ProRes 4K at 60 fps when paired with an iPhone 15 Pro/Pro Max or iPhone 16 Pro/Pro Max. Great for long shoots and then you already have the video files on a drive that can easily be transferred to your PC or Mac.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4590/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/sandisk-magsafe-ssd-feels-practically-free-at-0-10-per-gb-with-prime-day-discount-works-with-iphone-2000632166]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo is “So Wrong It Hurts” About Mods Not Counting as Prior Art, Says Patent Expert]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-is-so-wrong-it-hurts-about-mods-not-counting-as-prior-art-says-patent-expert/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-is-%E2%80%9Cso-wrong-it-hurts%E2%80%9D-about-mods-not-counting-as-prior-art-says-patent-expert.1318870/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>During a new interview, a US patent expert stated that Nintendo is incorrect in its assertion that mods do not count as prior art. </p>



<p>For those unfamiliar, Nintendo and Pocketpair have been engaged in a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-has-acquired-2-more-anti-palworld-patents/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">patent infringement lawsuit</a> for some time now, with the former claiming that the latter has infringed multiple patents with Palworld. Now, a US Patent expert has provided their opinion on the ongoing lawsuit and also on mods not being considered as prior art. </p>



<h2 id="h-nintendo-saying-mods-not-counting-is-prior-art-is-the-most-asinine-thing-i-have-seen">Nintendo Saying Mods Not Counting is Prior Art “Is the Most Asinine Thing I Have Seen” </h2>



<p>Spotted by <a href="https://www.gamesradar.com/games/survival/nintendo-is-so-wrong-it-hurts-us-ip-expert-says-nintendo-claiming-mods-dont-invalidate-its-pokemon-patents-is-just-a-loser-argument-and-a-hail-mary-in-its-ongoing-legal-fight-with-palworld/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">GamesRadar+,</a> during a new interview with <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=V5Nusug2SfA&amp;t=211s" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">The Junglist</a>, Kirk Sigmon, an attorney from Banner Witcoff, and an expert in patent law, spoke about Nintendo’s defense on <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/palworld-argues-invalidity-and-non-infringement-against-nintendos-lawsuit/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">mods not counting as prior art</a>. Sigmon started off by stating that “Nintendo is so wrong it hurts”. Sigmon added that there might be some nuance in Japanese law that could dictate where Nintendo is coming from; however, for the world of prior art, it doesn’t have to be perfect, nor does it have to be functional either. </p>



<p>Sigmon then went on to explain instances where prior art has been used that isn’t a computer program in the first place. He also provided an example of an IPR case from 5-7 years ago, where a Dungeons and Dragons manual was used as prior art, as it included character sheets and other details. He adds that “you don’t have to find prior art that’s of a specific nature”, it doesn’t have to be marketed either. Most of the time, the only requirement is that “it was written down somewhere” to prove that it existed. </p>



<p>The patent expert goes on to say, “Nintendo’s argument that mods are somehow different, to me is the most asinine thing i have seen”. For it seems like it’s coming from someone “who doesn’t understand computers at all”. According to Sigmon’s POV, mods are essential, but they are a very dangerous space at the same time. However, “if you are creating a mod for a game that has certain functionality, that’s all that matters.” </p>



<p>Sigmon goes on to conclude that there have been several references used in patent offices as well as litigation that were never actually made and had numerous flaws, but that doesn’t prevent them from being prior art in the United States. There might be a nuance in Japanese law that he may not be aware of. In general, Sigmon thinks Nintendo’s argument about mods not being prior art “is a loser”. It is “fixated too highly on form over function” because where to we “end that dispute, as there are multiple Unreal Engine 5, are those mods too just cause they are running on a singular engine? </p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Owning Game Mechanics? Making Sense of Nintendo's Patents - Kirk Sigmon | grokludo 10" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/V5Nusug2SfA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>In other news, a former Capcom designer has stated that Palworld “<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/palworld-crossed-a-line-says-former-capcom-designer/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">crossed a line</a>” in relation to the ongoing lawsuit. Additionally, Nintendo has confirmed <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-confirms-they-havent-contacted-the-government-about-generative-ai/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">they haven’t contacted the government</a> about generative AI. Let us know through the official&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums</a>&nbsp;discussion.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/not-all-subscribers-will-be-hit-by-xbox-game-pass-price-increase/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">not all subscribers being hit by the Xbox Game Pass price increase</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-is-so-wrong-it-hurts-about-mods-not-counting-as-prior-art-says-patent-expert/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marathon Pricing And Launch Weapons Details Leak Online]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/marathon-pricing-and-launch-weapons-details-leak-online/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/marathon-pricing-and-launch-weapons-details-leak-online.1318867/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>New information on pricing and launch weapons for Bungie’s upcoming extraction shooter Marathon has been leaked online. These details from a known Destiny 2 and Marathon data miner include details on the game’s pricing, season pass, and even launch weapons.</p>



<p>In a series of posts on social media, Colony Deaks says that the game will launch with two editions and remain a premium-priced title. </p>



<p>According to their posts, Marathon’s <strong>base price will be $40</strong>—which has <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/latest-marathon-price-report-double-down/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">long been rumored</a>–while the Deluxe Edition of the game will be <strong>“around $60”</strong>. The Deluxe Edition, they say, will include more skins for players and possibly more. There’s also a pre-order bonus that includes a Destiny ship, ghost, and sparrow, along with a weapon skin. Lastly, the Deluxe Edition will give players “around $30-ish worth of season pass tokens,” though they are unclear what the tokens will be for. </p>



<p>In addition to the game itself, Bungie is planning a season pass for the game that will be cosmetic only and cost “around $10”.</p>



<h2 id="h-plenty-of-weapons">Plenty Of Weapons</h2>



<p>Aside from the pricing information, details on Marathon’s launch weapons were also provided. According to Colony Deaks, the game will launch with 28 weapons. </p>



<p>The weapons will be broken down as follows:</p>



<p><strong>AR</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Overrun AR</li>



<li>V75 Scar</li>



<li>Impact HAR</li>



<li>M77 AR</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>LMG</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Retaliator LMG</li>



<li>Demolition HMG</li>



<li>Conquest LMG</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Precision Rifles</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Hardline PR</li>



<li>Repeater PR</li>



<li>V66 Lookout</li>



<li>B33 Volley Rifle</li>



<li>Twin Tap HBR</li>



<li>Stryder M1T</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Pistols</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>V11 Punch</li>



<li>CE Tactical Sidearm</li>



<li>Magnum MC</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Railguns</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>V00 Zeus RG</li>



<li>Ares RG</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Shotguns</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Misriah 2442</li>



<li>V85 Circuit Breaker</li>



<li>WSTR Combat Shotgun</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Sniper Rifles</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Outland</li>



<li>V99 Channel Rifle</li>



<li>Longshot</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>SMG</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Copperhead RF</li>



<li>Bully SMG</li>



<li>V22 Volt Thrower</li>



<li>BRRT</li>
</ul>



<p>As with all rumors, even ones from usually reliable sources, please take the information with a grain of salt until it becomes official or Insider Gaming can independently confirm. Currently, Bungie is <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marathon-new-closed-technical-test-october-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">holding signups for a closed technical test</a> of Marathon, taking place from October 22-27. </p>



<p>What do you think of the pricing and possible launch weapons for Marathon? Leave your thoughts down in the comments below, and&nbsp;join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.gg/Bhv3AMa5a9" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/microsoft-addresses-rumors-surrounding-xbox-console-future/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Microsoft addressing recent rumors</a>&nbsp;surrounding the future of Xbox hardware. And make sure you&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">subscribe to the Insider Gaming Newsletter.</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/marathon-pricing-and-launch-weapons-details-leak-online/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Opinion: Ogre Battle 64: Person Of Lordly Caliber's Revolutionary Heart Still Burns Brightly]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/features/opinion-ogre-battle-64-person-of-lordly-calibers-revolutionary-heart-still-burns-brightly</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/opinion-ogre-battle-64-person-of-lordly-calibers-revolutionary-heart-still-burns-brightly.1318846/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>

<p>Has it really been 25 years? Yes, my wizened friends, it has. Back in the year of our lord 2000 (or 1999 if you're from Japan), if you weren't still calming down from the trauma of Y2K (still can't believe nothing happened) you may have been getting completely sucked into one of the few truly amazing RPGs on the Nintendo 64. Because <em>you</em> are a person of lordly caliber. A top of the range model. No skimping on the quality ingredients in your sauce, champ.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/n64/ogre_battle_64_person_of_lordly_caliber">Ogre Battle 64: Person of Lordly Caliber</a>, besides having a belter of a name, is also a game that had me — and I'm sure plenty more ancient N64 gamers besides — glued to my CRT screen when I should have been down the club dancing to...well, an S Club 7 remix or something.</p>
<p>This real-time strategy classic from Quest (who dissolved into Square Enix in 2003) sees players descend on the Holy Lodis Empire, where a bunch of bad guys are oppressing the people. It's up to you, through some delightful battling, to raise the revolutionary flag and fight back for the good of the people. Hey, we should try doing that in real life sometime!</p>

<p>The N64 had precious few outstanding RPG experiences of this type for players to enjoy, and certainly in comparison to other consoles of the time, so it's a good thing that Quest hit it so far out of the park we ended up giving it <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/n64/ogre_battle_64_person_of_lordly_caliber">a 10/10 here at Nintendo Life</a>. Heck that's <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/2009/03/ogre_battle_the_march_of_the_black_queen_virtual_console">one more than we scored</a> the first game, 1993's <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/snes/ogre_battle_the_march_of_the_black_queen">Ogre Battle: March of the Black Queen</a>, and the <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/snes/tactics_ogre_let_us_cling_together">same score</a> we gave the legendary <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/snes/tactics_ogre_let_us_cling_together">Tactics Ogre: Let Us Cling Together</a> (both reviews for the Virtual Console versions, of course).</p>
<p>There's a quality mix here of a top-notch story and a battle setup that excels. In fact, having sat through a few hours to get reacquainted with it recently, it really does remain highly playable and enjoyable today, even if it does look and sound distinctly of, well, the Nintendo 64 era. Maybe that's a good thing!</p>
<p>For an adventure that includes no voice-acting (<a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20010330072003/http://www.nintendo.com/n64/ogrebattle3/index.html">according to Nintendo</a>, it was already the second-biggest N64 game, so it's lucky they didn't try to squeeze that in) whilst presenting its surprisingly affecting story entirely in-game rather than through naff cutscenes, Ogre Battle 64 excels because it makes the clever decision at the offset to remain grounded. Well, as grounded as something called Ogre Battle can be; its story is still relevant today, focusing on politics and issues that still affect us. It's immediate, it gets to the point and it underscores the action perfectly.</p>
<p>Taking place in the mining colony of Palatinus, the game tells the tale of people who've been abused and set to work in terrible conditions to the point that they finally rebel against the empire that's keeping them down. Magnus (that's the fella you play as) is initially dispatched as part of a force sent to quell revolutionary disturbances. But things don't exactly go to the Military's plan...</p>

<p>From here there are twists and turns aplenty to keep you involved, and it's surprising to see just how well-handled some of the more difficult topics are. The story keeps things real and they aren't glazed over, providing an emotional core that keeps it all ticking along very nicely.</p>
<p>All of this is tied to cracking battles of the Ogre Battle variety. The real-time scraps here involve sending out your dinky little troops (up to 50 men, women and beasts in total by the end), made up of the usual array of classes, to locations to gather up treasure, take over settlements and fight as they go. You arrange your selection of troops into a unit or "legion" placing class-types that work best at the front and back in suitable positions and so on and assigning a leader. These legions will then scrap against enemy groups.</p>
<p>Once you've been given your orders at the start of each mission, you'll set out to achieve an objective, and the game is quite free-wheeling in letting you get to this your own way. Battles kick off as and when you happen upon foes, the action plays out automatically, and it's up to you to ensure that you have your units in a setup that gives them the best chance to come out on top.</p>

<p>There's a lot of depth here, with loads of moves and skills to use against your opponents; you don't even necessarily have to physically defeat the enemy, just do enough to push them back and stop them gaining any ground, as you work to take over strongholds and dominate the map you are on by assuming control of towns and such forth. The fact that the battles are real-time helps add a frisson of urgency, and you can feel the desperation as you struggle to keep things moving your way. This is all then strengthened further by a clever 'Alignment' system, where your decisions and actions determine what ending of three you get to see.</p>
<p>Are you a man of honour who lets a defeated enemy live, or are you a bit of a bloodthirsty bad'un? Alignment goes so far as to affect the towns and settlements that you take over, as each one has its own set alignment rating. Match this and you'll be considered to have liberated the peoples there, rather than just having captured them all by force.</p>

<p>This adds plenty of replayability and considered thought processes to proceedings, especially for folks who get properly into the story. And get into it you should, because, besides the fun fighting, it's really the story and its handling of political matters that keeps this one up top as an all-timer. Ogre Battle 64 doesn't shy away from things; it's willing to have you question morals, and as a result it's got much more to say politically than plenty of modern efforts seem bothered with.</p>
<p>Is it still worth a playthrough today? Absolutely. If you can get over the slightly weathered looks and underwhelming sounds, there's plenty to recommend here, with engaging gameplay and a narrative that gets the old revolutionary blood pumping. Not that you'd need much help with that these days, most likely.</p>
<hr>
<p><em>Played Ogre Battle 64: Person of Lordly Caliber? Let us know how you found it! (If you can still remember)</em></p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/retro/related-articles:9063 @ 1759855913 --></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/features/opinion-ogre-battle-64-person-of-lordly-calibers-revolutionary-heart-still-burns-brightly]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Frosthaven Awakening Protocol Update Brings New Storyline and More Later This Month]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/frosthaven-awakening-protocol-update</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/frosthaven-awakening-protocol-update-brings-new-storyline-and-more-later-this-month.1318843/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Developer Snapshot Games and publisher Arc Games have announced the first major&nbsp;<em>Frosthaven&nbsp;</em>Early Access update, and it's coming to the tabletop adaptation later this month.</p>

<p>As revealed in a press release, the Awakening Protocol update will serve as the first big content patch for the strategy RPG. Much of what it's bringing was first teased as part of the <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/frosthaven-early-access-roadmap" rel="nofollow">roadmap announcement</a> back in early September.</p>

<p>First up, you're getting a new storyline in the form of the Unfettered arc, which will give you a chance to confront a "machine uprising" headed by a "mysterious and formidable leader".</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/frosthaven-awakening-protocol-update-machine-uprising.jpg?itok=27OZZlwK 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/frosthaven-awakening-protocol-update-machine-uprising.jpg?itok=IEsVKu4u 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Frosthaven</em>'s first major Early Access update will have you challenging a machine uprising.</figcaption></figure><p>In addition to the new storyline (about which Arc and Snapshot are remaining very tight-lipped for now), you can also expect three new playable heroes to be added to&nbsp;<em>Frosthaven&nbsp;</em>in the Awakening Protocol update, and they come with "bold new strategies".</p>

<p>Five new bosses are coming as well, consisting of "mechanical and unknown horrors", so you'll need to make sure your squad is at its strongest if you want to beat them. That's in addition to over 18 new quests, a new building, and lots of other extras.</p>

<p>If you're not familiar with&nbsp;<em>Frosthaven</em>, it's a <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/frosthaven-video-game-adaptation-announced" rel="nofollow">video game adaptation</a> of the popular tabletop experience, which is itself a sequel to the iconic RPG&nbsp;<em>Gloomhaven</em>. For a time,&nbsp;<em>Frosthaven&nbsp;</em>was the <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/frosthaven-kickstarter-is-most-funded-board-game-on-platform" rel="nofollow">most-funded tabletop project</a> on Kickstarter, before being overtaken by <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/brandon-sandersons-cosmere-rpg-kickstarter-raised-5-million-in-one-day" rel="nofollow">Brandon Sanderson's&nbsp;<em>Cosmere&nbsp;</em>RPG project</a>.</p>

<p>The video game version of&nbsp;<em>Frosthaven&nbsp;</em>promises "challenging yet satisfying gameplay" across both its single-player and multiplayer offerings, as well as "deep mechanics" that should feel intuitive to both newcomers and experienced veterans of the tabletop game.</p>




<p>You can check out&nbsp;<em>Frosthaven&nbsp;</em>right now on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2347080/Frosthaven/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC via Steam Early Access</a>, and its Awakening Protocol update launches on October 23rd. You can check out our very own Andrew's preview from this year's Summer Game Fest <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/previews/frosthavens-video-game-adaptation-creates-no-fuss-experience-at-sgf-2025" rel="nofollow">right here</a>.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/frosthaven-awakening-protocol-update]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PowerWash Simulator 2 will release October 23, and here's a trailer to mock you for enjoying cleaning games]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/powerwash-simulator-2-will-release-october-23-and-heres-a-trailer-to-mock-you-for-enjoying-cleaning-games</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/powerwash-simulator-2-will-release-october-23-and-heres-a-trailer-to-mock-you-for-enjoying-cleaning-games.1318840/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Be sure to remember that "you've really achieved nothing"</p>

    </div>


  <p>


  <figure>
        <picture data-src-full="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/powerwash-simulator-2.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" src="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/powerwash-simulator-2.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/powerwash-simulator-2.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/powerwash-simulator-2.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/powerwash-simulator-2.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/powerwash-simulator-2.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/powerwash-simulator-2.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/powerwash-simulator-2.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/powerwash-simulator-2.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/powerwash-simulator-2.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/powerwash-simulator-2.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>FuturLab</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>The world is insufficiently clean and sparkly, so here comes Futurlab with <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/powerwash-simulator-2">Powerwash Simulator 2</a>. The floor-mopping bonanza will release on 23rd October, a few short weeks from now. The release date announcement accompanies one of those satirical "corporate training" videos, commonly used by videogame creators to sneer indirectly at the sad unfortunates trapped in their Skinner boxes. 
</p>
<p>The trailer comments of the sequel's new cleaning tools, for example, that "it all does basically the same thing, but it gives you a false sense of progression, even though you've really achieved nothing". Fine then, Futurlab. I was looking forward to your glorified adult colouring book. I was modestly anticipating the opportunity to absent myself from my personal squalor and while away some hours in your pseudo-therapeutic tribute to Mr Muscles. But now that you've ripped off the mask and explicitly told me that I'm an addled hamster, deserving only of contempt, I guess I'll buy <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3374840/Piss_Off/">this game about pissing on people instead</a>.
</p><!--more-->

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="PowerWash Simulator 2 | Release Date Announcement Trailer" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/RrFexXPbVuM?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>PowerWash Simulator 2 | Release Date Announcement Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/RrFexXPbVuM?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/RrFexXPbVuM?autoplay=1" title="PowerWash Simulator 2 | Release Date Announcement Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RrFexXPbVuM" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>


<p>For balance, the developers had plenty of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/powerwash-simulator-2-devs-tell-us-their-tips-for-real-life-house-cleaning">perfectly polite and genuinely helpful advice</a> to share with us about realworld cleaning in March. They all seem like lovely people. I cannot thank principal data analyst Russel Young enough for that tip about lemons and coffee mugs. I am less trustful of writer Mark Ginbey's comment about throwing ants on the floor.
</p>
<p>Satirical training video aside, the release date email includes a recap of the sequel's new features. Here you go.
</p>
<blockquote><ul>
<li>Split-Screen &amp; Online Multiplayer - Clean solo, with a friend on the couch, or with up to four players online - all with shared progression.</li>
<li>Abseiling &amp; Scissor Lift - Scale buildings, hover over rooftops, and clean from every angle. Don't worry - fall damage doesn't exist here.</li>
<li>Multi-Stage Jobs - Just when you think you've finished, surprise: there's more to clean. Some jobs expand mid-wash, unlocking new areas on the fly.</li>
<li>Home Base Customisation - Restore furniture, decorate your HQ, and keep your base clean(ish). You earned it.</li>
<li>Career Mode - Take on 38 jobs across increasingly strange, sprawling, and oddly satisfying locations.</li>
<li>Soap, Nozzles &amp; Tools - Upgrade your washer loadout with adaptable nozzles, surface cleaners, and yes, foamy soap.</li>
<li>Cat Companions - Ulysses and her kittens are back, following you on jobs and expecting to be petted. Often.</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>
<p>"A rare simulator that's focused on fun, not faff," wrote Ed Thorn (RPS in peace) in our original <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/powerwash-simulator">PowerWash Simulator</a> review from 2022. "I cannot stress enough how stress-less the experience is," he urged, stressfully. "This is a first-person soother you'll either think is an absolute bore or the best kind of meditative chore." I expect the second game will follow firmly in those soapy bootprints.</p>

        </div>
      </article>




        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/powerwash-simulator-2-will-release-october-23-and-heres-a-trailer-to-mock-you-for-enjoying-cleaning-games]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bose Is Clearing Out Its TV Soundbar, Now Selling for 4x Cheaper Than Any Direct Competitor]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/bose-is-clearing-out-its-tv-soundbar-now-selling-for-4x-cheaper-than-any-direct-competitor-2000632587</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/bose-is-clearing-out-its-tv-soundbar-now-selling-for-4x-cheaper-than-any-direct-competitor.1318819/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Quality soundbars for your TV can easily run $1,000 or more, which makes better audio feel like a luxury purchase. The Bose TV speaker breaks that pattern by delivering clear and improved sound at a fraction of that cost. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3727/">Normally priced at $279, this soundbar is now down to $199 for Prime Big Deal Day</a>, which marks an all-time low and only the second discount this year. Beyond improving your TV audio, <strong>it doubles as a Bluetooth speaker for your living room</strong> that you can control from your smartphone.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3727/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<p>The underlying issue it addresses is easy: built-in TV speakers sound thin and muddy which causes dialogue to be difficult to follow and diminishes your enjoyment of shows and films. The Bose TV Speaker fixes it by <strong>employing two angled full-range drivers that produce a broader and more natural soundstage</strong>. Rather than having sound directly emanate at your face from one point, angled drivers reflect sound off your walls and bring it to life and opening it up, as it were.</p>
<h2>Dialogue Mode Makes Every Word Crystal Clear</h2>
<p>The dedicated dialogue enhancement feature is where we really see this soundbar excel for everyday listening. Bose designed the speaker to expressly zero in on vocal and pronunciation, and lifts dialogue out of the mix so that you can clearly hear each word without having to turn it up too high. There’s a remote included that has a button for a dialogue mode, which amplifies speech even more when desired. There’s also a bass boost mode for times when you want a deeper sound during music scenes or action scenes.</p>



<p>Setup only takes minutes due to a single-cable connection: <strong>Use your optical audio cable included, or connect via HDMI ARC if your TV is capable</strong> (HDMI cable not included). HDMI ARC provides a benefit of controlling soundbar volume by your TV’s remote for a seamless experience. Ultra-slim at just 2.21 inches high, 23.38 inches wide, and 4.02 inches deep, <strong>it fits seamlessly in front of nearly all TVs</strong>, neither covering nor obstructing IR sensor nor your view of the picture. It’s <strong>also wall mountable</strong> if a cleaner aesthetic is your preference, though brackets are separately available.</p>
<p>The Bluetooth connectivity offers convenience apart from TV sound: You <strong>are allowed to connect your smartphone, tablet, or laptop to stream music</strong>&nbsp;or even audiobooks directly through the soundbar’s sound output. The <strong>speaker stores a total of three devices</strong> via its multiple inputs: HDMI, optical and auxiliary. Whichever device is turned on first actually connects to it automatically, thereby never having to switch inputs manually each time.</p>
<p>At $199 for this Prime Big Deal Day sale, you’re getting sound engineering and construction of Bose for fewer dollars than are many budget soundbars which aren’t even CLOSE to providing clear and stereophonic sound like this one does.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3727/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/bose-is-clearing-out-its-tv-soundbar-now-selling-for-4x-cheaper-than-any-direct-competitor-2000632587]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Not All Subscribers Will Be Hit By Xbox Game Pass Price Increase]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/not-all-subscribers-will-be-hit-by-xbox-game-pass-price-increase/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/not-all-subscribers-will-be-hit-by-xbox-game-pass-price-increase.1318816/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>On October 1, Microsoft announced that it was <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-raising-game-pass-ultimate-price-by-50-and-changing-tier-features/">rais</a><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-raising-game-pass-ultimate-price-by-50-and-changing-tier-features/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">i</a><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-raising-game-pass-ultimate-price-by-50-and-changing-tier-features/">ng the price</a> of Xbox Game Pass Ultimate by 50%. Now, less than a week later, news is coming out that not all subscribers will be subject to the price increase. </p>



<p>According to emails being sent out to Xbox Game Pass members within the European Union (EU) and other countries, the price increase from €18 to €27 will only be for new members and those who don’t have auto-renewal enabled.</p>



<p><span><strong>“Recently, you may have heard about changes to Xbox Game Pass subscription prices,”</strong> the <a href="https://x.com/Colteastwood/status/1975585850751844383" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">email reads</a>.<strong> “At this time, these increases will only apply to new purchases and will not affect your current subscription in your region, as long as you are on an auto- recurring plan. </strong></span></p>



<p><strong>“Should you choose to cancel <span>your plan and repurchase, you will be charged the new current rate. If for any reason there may be changes to your existing account, we will notify you at least 60 days in advance and you will have the option to cancel or change your subscription plan at any time.”</span></strong></p>



<p>After the emails went out, you’ve had <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/XboxGamePass/comments/1o04yjs/gp_price_hike_doesnt_seem_to_affect_people/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">many take to Reddit</a> to confirm that they received the same message.</p>



<p>“Same with PC Gamepass in Germany, signed up for it when it was 9,99€, still paying 9,99€ after the increase to 11,99€ and got an email that the price will remain at 9,99€ instead of the new 14,99€ for me,” <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/XboxGamePass/comments/1o04yjs/gp_price_hike_doesnt_seem_to_affect_people/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">said one user</a>.</p>



<p>It’s worth mentioning that <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/XboxGamePass/comments/1o04yjs/comment/ni8rd8z/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">others are getting emails</a> confirming a price increase, even if they have auto payments active.</p>



<p>As of publishing, Microsoft hasn’t made any sort of wide-ranging public comment on the matter. Insider Gaming has reached out to the company for clarification on prices for auto-renewal members and what regions are impacted. Should a response be received, it will be added to this story.</p>



<p>Are you going to turn on your auto-renewal to keep your Xbox Game Pass Ultimate price the same? Leave your thoughts down in the comments below, and&nbsp;join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.gg/Bhv3AMa5a9" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/microsoft-addresses-rumors-surrounding-xbox-console-future/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Microsoft addressing recent rumors</a>&nbsp;surrounding the future of Xbox hardware. And make sure you&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">subscribe to the Insider Gaming Newsletter.</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/not-all-subscribers-will-be-hit-by-xbox-game-pass-price-increase/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Save On Backbone One Controllers For iPhone And Android In Amazon’s Big Deal Days Sale]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/save-on-backbone-one-controllers-for-iphone-and-android-in-amazons-big-deal-days-sale/1100-6535267/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/save-on-backbone-one-controllers-for-iphone-and-android-in-amazon%E2%80%99s-big-deal-days-sale.1318813/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-main">

      
                    
  
              <header id="masthead"><nav></nav></header>      
                            <div id="site-wrapper" role="main">
          <div id="default-content">
        
          <p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p>
  
    <article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6535267">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Backbone recently revealed <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/new-backbone-colorways-give-the-smartphone-controllers-a-cozy-makeover/1100-6535164/">several new cozy colors</a> for its line of smartphone controllers, but if you'd prefer to stick to its regular colorways, then you can score one of these devices for up to 40% off during <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/amazon-prime-day-deals/">Amazon Big Deal Days</a>. Currently, you can get the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/BACKBONE-Mobile-Gaming-Controller-Android-iOS/dp/B0CCT2LWT8?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Backbone One with a USB-C connection</a> for $70 (was $100), and for people using older iPhones, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/BACKBONE-Mobile-Gaming-Controller-Lightning-iOS/dp/B0CT17GPNT?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">the Backbone One with a Lightning connection</a> is down to $60 (was $100). This deal starts today and runs through October 8.</p><div title="6535267 -- Backbone One Prime Day 2 Deals" data-embed-type="buylink" data-ref-id="4626" data-template="4" data-size="buylink__listicle" data-title="6535267 -- Backbone One Prime Day 2 Deals" data-collection="">                                                                     <div>             <h2>                    <a href="https://www.amazon.com/BACKBONE-Mobile-Gaming-Controller-Android-iOS/dp/B0CCT2LWT8?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/BACKBONE-Mobile-Gaming-Controller-Android-iOS\/dp\/B0CCT2LWT8?tag=gamespot-primeday-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/BACKBONE-Mobile-Gaming-Controller-Android-iOS/dp/B0CCT2LWT8?tag=gamespot-primeday-20">Backbone One Gen 2 (USB-C)</a>       </h2>                                   <h3>                      <a href="https://www.amazon.com/BACKBONE-Mobile-Gaming-Controller-Android-iOS/dp/B0CCT2LWT8?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/BACKBONE-Mobile-Gaming-Controller-Android-iOS\/dp\/B0CCT2LWT8?tag=gamespot-primeday-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/BACKBONE-Mobile-Gaming-Controller-Android-iOS/dp/B0CCT2LWT8?tag=gamespot-primeday-20">$70 (was $100)</a>         </h3>                                                                                                                      <div><p>This is the "Gen 2" version of the controller that has a reshaped D-pad and magnetic adapters that allow you to fit it to your phone without needing to remove the protective cover if it's standard-sized. These are designed to connect directly to an iPhone or Android smartphone, giving you an experience that transforms your device into your very own handheld gaming console. All the inputs you'd expect from a modern controller--analogue sticks, face and shoulder buttons, triggers, and more--are here and housed inside a compact frame. When not in use, the Backbone One can be folded up to reduce its size.</p><p>The USB-C version is available in black at this price, but it looks like the model that sports a PS5-inspired white finish is currently out of stock.</p></div>                      </div>                                                                     <div>             <h2>                    <a href="https://www.amazon.com/BACKBONE-Mobile-Gaming-Controller-Lightning-iOS/dp/B0CT17GPNT?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/BACKBONE-Mobile-Gaming-Controller-Lightning-iOS\/dp\/B0CT17GPNT?tag=gamespot-primeday-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/BACKBONE-Mobile-Gaming-Controller-Lightning-iOS/dp/B0CT17GPNT?tag=gamespot-primeday-20">Backbone One Gen 1 (Lightning)</a>       </h2>                                   <h3>                      <a href="https://www.amazon.com/BACKBONE-Mobile-Gaming-Controller-Lightning-iOS/dp/B0CT17GPNT?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/BACKBONE-Mobile-Gaming-Controller-Lightning-iOS\/dp\/B0CT17GPNT?tag=gamespot-primeday-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/BACKBONE-Mobile-Gaming-Controller-Lightning-iOS/dp/B0CT17GPNT?tag=gamespot-primeday-20">$60 (was $100)</a>         </h3>                                                                                                                      <p>The Lightning version of the Backbone One is designed for iPhone 14 and older smartphones. This deal is also for the Gen 1 model, which will require you to remove your protective cover from your iPhone to use it. Only the white version of the controller cradle is currently available for this deal. </p>                      </div>                                                                     <div>             <h2>                    <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Backbone-Gaming-Controller-Bluetooth-Pro-Level-Console/dp/B0DQM23MLZ?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/Backbone-Gaming-Controller-Bluetooth-Pro-Level-Console\/dp\/B0DQM23MLZ?tag=gamespot-primeday-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/Backbone-Gaming-Controller-Bluetooth-Pro-Level-Console/dp/B0DQM23MLZ?tag=gamespot-primeday-20">Backbone Pro</a>       </h2>                                   <h3>                      <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Backbone-Gaming-Controller-Bluetooth-Pro-Level-Console/dp/B0DQM23MLZ?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/Backbone-Gaming-Controller-Bluetooth-Pro-Level-Console\/dp\/B0DQM23MLZ?tag=gamespot-primeday-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/Backbone-Gaming-Controller-Bluetooth-Pro-Level-Console/dp/B0DQM23MLZ?tag=gamespot-primeday-20">$170</a>         </h3>                                                                                                                      <p>For more controller options, you can also check out the Backbone Pro. This is the premium edition of the smartphone controller, as it's equipped with redesigned ergonomics and high-quality components like a textured finish, quieter face buttons, full-sized ALPS analog sticks, Hall Effect triggers, and two remappable back buttons. This model is pricier, but if you'd like a premium cradle for your smartphone, you can get this for $170. </p>                      </div>   </div><p>The other big deal we've spotted is for 8BitDo's own Android smartphone controller. Normally $50, it's currently on sale for $22 for the black version, and $34 for the white version. It's compatible with a wide array of Android devices that can fit inside its 100mm to 170mm base, and you're getting some top-quality components here. This cradle has Hall Effect joysticks and triggers, back paddle buttons, a turbo function, and wear-resistant metal joystick rings. Since it's compatible with 8BitDo Ultimate Software V2, you can also customize it extensively.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4581501-8bitdoultimate.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4581501" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4581501-8bitdoultimate.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4581501"></a><figcaption>8bitDo Ultimate Mobile Controller</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4581501-8bitdoultimate.jpg"></figure><ul><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Ultimate-Gaming-Controller-Bluetooth-Joysticks-Console/dp/B0DK36N98Q?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">8Bitdo Ultimate Mobile Gaming Controller (Black)</a> -- $22 (<del>$50</del>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Ultimate-Gaming-Controller-Bluetooth-Joysticks-Console/dp/B0DK37CSHP?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">8Bitdo Ultimate Mobile Gaming Controller (White</a>) -- $34 (<del>$50</del>)</li></ul><p>If you use a tablet to play games, you can also save a few bucks on Razer's new line of Kishi controllers. The <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Kishi-Gaming-Controller-Android-Tablets-Smartphone/dp/B0DVKWZ5SX?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Kishi V3 Pro XL</a> is for users who run with larger tablets, as it can fit 11- and 13-inch iPad Pro and Air models inside its frame, and it has several high-end components in its construction.</p><p>This has large ergonomic handles, anti-drift TMR thumbsticks that Razer claims are superior to Hall Effect thumbsticks, and extremely responsive actuation in the triggers and face buttons. Normally $200, it's on sale for $170.</p><p>For more Prime Big Deal Days discounts, check out <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/amazon-prime-day-deals/">GameSpot's deals hub</a> as we continue to update it with the latest specials.</p><div data-embed-type="pinbox" data-ref-id="4304">  <ul>                              <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-powera-cheap-wireless-controller-super-mario-amazon-deals/1100-6535215/">Get Super Mario And Kirby Switch 2 Wireless Controllers For Up To 50% Off</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/amazon-audible-premium-plus-sign-up-prime-big-deal-days-black-friday-holiday-2025-deal/1100-6524536/">Audible Premium Plus Holiday Deal: Get 3 Audiobooks For $3</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/amazon-prime-big-deal-days-4k-blu-ray-best-deals/1100-6535093/">Prime Big Deal Days Movie Sale: Check Out Amazon's B2G1 Free 4K Blu-Ray Catalog</a></li>                          <li>         <span>+ Show More More Gaming, Tech, and Entertainment Deals &amp; Preorders Links (5)</span>       </li>          <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/rog-xbox-ally-preorder-guide/1100-6535007/">ROG Xbox Ally X Preorders In Stock At Best Buy, Sold Out Everywhere Else (September 27)</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/final-fantasy-magic-the-gathering-trading-cards-restock-where-to-buy-amazon-walmart-best-buy-target/2900-6271/">New Magic: The Gathering Final Fantasy Chocobo Bundle &amp; Scene Boxes Up For Preorder</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/lego-game-boy-restocked-at-amazon-and-its-shipping-early/1100-6533358/">You Can Get The $60 Lego Game Boy Early From Amazon</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/history-of-middle-earth-5440-page-box-set-drops-to-all-time-best-price-for-big-deal-days/1100-6526926/">Complete History Of Middle-Earth Collector's Box Set Restocked With $170 Discount</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-shining-movie-4k-blu-ray-special-edition-steelbook-the-film-vault/1100-6534223/">The Shining's New Numbered Limited Edition Is Up For Grabs At Amazon</a></li>   </ul> </div>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article>

    
  

    
</div>
                      <meta itemprop="seamless-content-list-items" data-list-items="[{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6532961&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/kindle-scribe-ereader-amazon-prime-day-sale-best-deal\/1100-6532961\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6535148&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/save-on-ps5-compatible-ssds-ahead-of-amazons-prime-big-deal-days\/1100-6535148\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6523832&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/harry-potter-monopoly-is-nearly-50-off-in-amazons-early-big-deal-days-sale\/1100-6523832\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6535093&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/amazon-prime-big-deal-days-4k-blu-ray-best-deals\/1100-6535093\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6535172&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/prime-big-deal-days-load-up-on-spongebob-squarepants-dvds-and-blu-rays\/1100-6535172\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6535280&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/tmnt-fans-can-save-big-on-the-last-ronin-graphic-novels-during-amazon-big-deals-days\/1100-6535280\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6535223&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/a-minecraft-movie-prime-big-deal-days-2025\/1100-6535223\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6519342&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/dd-visual-history-special-edition-box-set-is-only-45-for-big-deal-days\/1100-6519342\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6535113&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/this-toshiba-55-inch-4k-fire-tv-is-only-200-for-prime-big-deal-days\/1100-6535113\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6528508&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/twin-peaks-from-z-to-a-blu-ray-box-set-fire-walk-with-me-criterion-collection\/1100-6528508\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6535177&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/a-song-of-ice-and-fire-george-rr-martin-game-of-thrones-book-box-set-deals\/1100-6535177\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6535126&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/this-amazon-fire-max-11-bundle-is-over-100-off-ahead-of-prime-big-deal-days\/1100-6535126\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6515422&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/gorgeous-final-fantasy-art-book-box-set-is-nearly-50-off-for-prime-big-deal-days\/1100-6515422\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6532360&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/the-elder-scrolls-5-skyrim-library-book-box-set-amazon-deal\/1100-6532360\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6530148&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/god-of-war-20th-anniversary-retrospective-deluxe-edition-playstation-book-best-amazon-deal\/1100-6530148\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6535185&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/best-settings-for-cod-black-ops-7-controller-layouts-sensitivity-and-more\/1100-6535185\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6535184&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/disco-elysium-studio-za-um-gets-first-recognized-workers-union-in-uk-games-industry\/1100-6535184\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6535183&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/gta-5-celebrates-halloween-with-slasher-mode-and-zombies\/1100-6535183\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6535173&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/halo-tv-show-hits-netflix-quickly-becomes-one-of-the-most-popular-shows-on-the-platform\/1100-6535173\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529819&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/marvel-spider-man-magic-the-gathering-trading-card-restock-amazon-preorder\/1100-6529819\/&quot;}]">
            </div>
              
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/save-on-backbone-one-controllers-for-iphone-and-android-in-amazons-big-deal-days-sale/1100-6535267/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[London's Nintendo Store Pop-Up Tickets Are Now Live]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/10/londons-nintendo-store-pop-up-tickets-are-now-live</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/londons-nintendo-store-pop-up-tickets-are-now-live.1318792/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Get booking</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure data-uuid="efb3244b720fe"><a title="Nintendo Store" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/efb3244b720fe/nintendo-store.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Nintendo</em></figcaption></figure><p>After <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/nintendo-announces-first-ever-pop-up-store-in-uk-opens-next-month">announcing its existence</a> last month, Nintendo has today opened ticket reservations for the UK's first Nintendo Store Pop-Up.</p>
<p>The store will appear on the ground floor of the Shepherd's Bush <a href="https://www.westfield.com/en/united-kingdom/london" rel="noopener">Westfield London Shopping Centre</a>, and will be sticking around from <strong>22nd October - 16th November</strong>.</p>
<p>Those hoping to attend between the 22nd and the 26th will need to register for a free ticket via the <a href="https://experience.nintendo.com/#/events/10540">Nintendo Events website</a> (all those going from 27th onwards will not need to book in advance). The site is now live, with hour-long time slots available on all five opening days.</p>
<p>You'll need to be signed into a Nintendo Account to register for a free ticket, and if previous Pokémon Center pop-ups are anything to go by, we'd recommend getting in there fast.</p>

<p>The London pop-up will stock an extensive range of merch, including some exclusive pieces that are only available in the permanent stores in Japan.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/related-articles:188429 @ 1759854616 -->
<p><em>Have you nabbed a ticket to the Nintendo Store pop-up? Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://experience.nintendo.com/#/events/10540" rel="noopener" href="https://experience.nintendo.com/#/events/10540">experience.nintendo.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/related-info/d41d8cd98f00b204e9800998ecf8427e @ 1759853438 --></div></article><div><p>Jim came to Nintendo Life in 2022 and, despite his insistence that The Minish Cap is the best Zelda game and his unwavering love for the Star Wars prequels (yes, really), he has continued to write news and features on the site ever since.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/JimNorman"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/jimnormann.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('JimNorman');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/10/londons-nintendo-store-pop-up-tickets-are-now-live]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Yacht Club Games Delays Mina the Hollower, Says It’s Not “A Major Delay,” No New Release Date Given]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/mina-the-hollower-delayed-yacht-club-games/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/yacht-club-games-delays-mina-the-hollower-says-it%E2%80%99s-not-%E2%80%9Ca-major-delay-%E2%80%9D-no-new-release-date-given.1318789/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Mina the Hollower, the next game from Shovel Knight developer Yacht Club Games is no longer launching on its <a href="https://wccftech.com/mina-the-hollower-release-date-announced-demo-now-available-on-steam/">previously announced Halloween 2025 release date</a>. Instead, we no longer know when it is coming out on PC, PS5, PS4, Xbox One, Xbox Series X/S, Nintendo Switch, and Nintendo Switch 2.</p>



<p>Yacht Club Games announced the delay with <a href="https://www.yachtclubgames.com/blog/delay-extravaganza-ii-the-tail-continues/">a blog post on its website</a>, where it held that this would not be "<em>a major delay</em>," and that the team just needs "<em>a stretch of time to apply some final polish and balancing to make the game truly shine</em>."</p>



<figure><div>
<blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>This week, our team made a tough decision: we decided to delay Mina the Hollower. The entire crew has been working tirelessly day and night to finish development for release on Oct 31st, but we’re just not quite there yet.</p><p>Read the full announcement here➡️<a href="https://t.co/FsbHqoMlfs">https://t.co/FsbHqoMlfs</a> <a href="https://t.co/WXFqcbUl3x">pic.twitter.com/WXFqcbUl3x</a></p></div>— Yacht Club Games (@YachtClubGames) <a href="https://twitter.com/YachtClubGames/status/1975293906251296964?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 6, 2025</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>



<p>"<em>We don't want to announce another release date until it's submitted to platforms, so please hang tight as we reach the finish line</em>," Yacht Club continued. "<em>The game is so close to being done - we're playing it from start to finish every day.</em>"</p>



<p>Steam Next Fest for October 2025 is only days away from kicking off at the time of this writing, but in the most recent Steam Next Fest for the year this past June, Mina the Hollower was <a href="https://wccftech.com/steam-next-fest-june-2025-the-demos-i-loved-that-you-should-spend-the-weekend-playing/">one of Wccftech's call-outs for what people should spend their time playing while the festival is on</a>.</p>



<p>When we checked out the demo, we wrote, "<em>The burrowing is satisfying to execute, the layout of something more akin to old Zelda games is something I can easily get behind, and I love the pixel art on display here.</em>"</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> or <a href="https://google.com/preferences/source?q=wccftech.com">add us as a preferred source</a>, to get our news coverage and reviews in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/mina-the-hollower-delayed-yacht-club-games/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox Game Pass Price Increase Reportedly Won’t Affect Every Existing Subscriber]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/xbox-game-pass-price-increase-won-t-affect-every-existing-user/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/xbox-game-pass-price-increase-reportedly-won%E2%80%99t-affect-every-existing-subscriber.1318786/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The Xbox Game Pass price hike announced on October 1, 2025, reportedly will not affect every existing subscriber when it goes into effect next month.</p>



<p>On the <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/XboxGamePass/">official Xbox Game Pass subreddit</a> earlier today, users shared recent emails informing them of the price increase, noting that some subscriptions will not be affected. Most exempt subscriptions exempt from the automatic increase are for users in European countries like Poland, <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/XboxGamePass/comments/1o04yjs/comment/ni7d85l/">Germany</a>, <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/XboxGamePass/comments/1o04yjs/comment/ni7gokr/">Austria</a>, <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/XboxGamePass/comments/1o04yjs/comment/ni83ymw/">Italy</a>, and Asian countries like <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/XboxGamePass/comments/1o04yjs/comment/ni8url6/">Indonesia</a>. This is likely due to local laws preventing an automatic price increase without the user's consent, although Microsoft has yet to provide confirmation.</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>The Xbox Game Pass subscription service has seen significant changes besides a price increase this month, <a href="https://wccftech.com/xbox-game-pass-is-rumored-to-drop-pc-game-pass-get-cheaper-ad-supported-tier/">rearranging subscription tiers into Essential, Premium, and Ultimate</a>. <span>While the Ultimate tier will offer considerable value with the addition of the Ubisoft + Classics library, the Fortnite Crew subscription, and day-one access to Xbox-published games, its steep price increase to $29.99/month wasn't well-received, so much so that the page to&nbsp;<a href="https://wccftech.com/xbox-game-pass-profitable-business-good-creators/" target="_blank">cancel the subscription was briefly overwhelmed.</a></span></p>



<p>Although the Xbox Game Pass service has seen multiple price increases, it will remain a central pillar of Xbox's market strategy. According to Xbox president Sarah Bond, <a href="https://wccftech.com/xbox-game-pass-profitable-business-good-creators/">the service is a profitable business</a> that has reached a record high of $5 billion and is becoming more valuable for both users and creators.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> or <a href="https://google.com/preferences/source?q=wccftech.com">add us as a preferred source</a>, to get our news coverage and reviews in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/xbox-game-pass-price-increase-won-t-affect-every-existing-user/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Total War: Warhammer 3's developers are fighting to fix "a catastrophic failure in many of our AI systems"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/total-war-warhammer-3s-developers-are-fighting-to-fix-a-catastrophic-failure-in-many-of-our-ai-systems</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/total-war-warhammer-3s-developers-are-fighting-to-fix-a-catastrophic-failure-in-many-of-our-ai-systems.1318783/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Look out for a patch soon</p>

    </div>


  <p>


  <figure>
        <picture data-src-full="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/legendlord.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" src="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/legendlord.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/legendlord.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/legendlord.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/legendlord.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/legendlord.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/legendlord.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/legendlord.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/legendlord.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/legendlord.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/legendlord.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Sega</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>All is not well in the Warhammer world. All is seldom well in the Warhammer world, of course - get off my lawn, Chaos! - but in this case, all is specifically not well with <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/total-war-warhammer-iii">Total War: Warhammer 3</a>'s non-player campaign factions. Creative Assembly are postponing more details of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/total-war-warhammer-3-gets-the-best-bad-news-yet-about-future-updates">the delayed Tides of Torment pack</a> while they fix what the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-best-strategy-games-on-pc">strategy game</a>'s lead technical designer modestly calls "a catastrophic failure in many of our AI systems". 
</p>
<!--more-->
<p>These issues have apparently dogged Twarhammer 3 for weeks - they've been "highly visible" since <a href="https://community.creative-assembly.com/total-war/total-war-warhammer/blogs/78-total-war-warhammer-iii-patch-notes-6-3">update 6.3 in late August</a>, though the underlying problems pre-date that patch. Creative Assembly have yet to release a hotfix, however. "The issues with Campaign AI are unfortunately complex to resolve," the developer's head of community Adam Freeman <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1142710/view/519725729918748466?l=english">wrote on Steam yesterday</a>. "We haven't been able to deliver an immediate fix as we needed to conduct some very thorough investigations into the root causes, but we are working as quickly as the complexity allows."
</p>
<p>So what's the big deal with the busted campaign AI, then? Briefly, non-player factions aren't recruiting units properly due to mistaken "assumptions" about resources, which is causing rival empires to seize up like my knees on chilly October mornings. "We have found that the AI was building lists of units to recruit without taking caps into consideration, resulting in recruitment failing to occur and stalling the AI decision making process," Freeman writes. The issue has apparently been "compounded" by changes to the specialised resources Lizardmen and Tomb Kings need to recruit units.
</p>
<p>The post includes a deeper dive from lead technical designer Radoslav Borisov, explaining the effects of the AI failing to keep track of unit caps, while fleshing out some wider problems with the game's handling of "pooled resources".</p>
<p>"Should the AI decide that its next task should be to attack a settlement, it's generating a recruitment action and then expecting an increase in force strength to a level where it feels the settlement garrison that it's targeted for attack can be defeated," Borisov writes. 
</p>
<p>"Without the unit recruitment task's successful resolution, it holds up the subsequent task and leaves the AI in a paralyzed state. It's a cascade of failures that result in certain factions failing to complete any aggressive actions whatsoever."
</p>
<p>Borisov goes on to detail a few of the "assumptions" or "beliefs around the current state of the game world" that AI players rely upon to make decisions when recruiting units. "Any mistakes when constructing these assumptions has been found to lead to a catastrophic failure in many of our AI systems," he notes. 
</p><p>Right now, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/total-war-warhammer">Total War: Warhammer</a> 3's AI is having particular difficulty with the aforesaid <a href="https://tw-modding.com/wiki/Tutorial:Pooled_Resources_Updated">"pooled resources"</a> - broadly, a flexible type of in-game strategic resource that can be tethered to a "location" such as a region, faction or army. As Borisov goes on, "the AI's ability to understand, plan and budget pooled resources is not ideal. Lately, AI has not been factoring in pooled resource to its costs properly, leading to incorrect beliefs about what it can and cannot afford, resulting in action failure."
</p>
<p>According to Borisov, the past few weeks of investigation have shown Creative Assembly "that the majority of our internal systems were unprepared for actions that ostensibly could not fail, to fail." Difficulties with pooled resources have triggered an avalanche of other problems - "the AI couldn't change stances properly, attacking on the campaign failed, recruitment failed, laying siege failed, and so on".
</p>
<p>Creative Assembly have identified the "leading causes" of these issues, but Borislov says that "it's very likely there are other cases we are not yet aware of just yet". There are, he notes, "around 200 different pooled resources in the game and they are used in a large variety of ways". I have to confess, I'm not 100% clear on the link here between the pooled resource stuff and the unit cap issue, but the overall takeaway appears to be that now is a really great time to invade the Warhammer world, providing you're a human general capable of counting up spearmen without falling into a trance.
</p>
<p>Creative Assembly plan to begin addressing the problem with a hotfix next week. "It entered the first phases of our testing earlier today and is showing positive signs of providing an improved experience to the game," Freeman comments. The developers had originally planned to make fixes as part of the bulkier update 7.0, but they've decided that the issue needs to be addressed now. A glance at that canary in every Steam developer's coalmine, the user review box, reveals a Mostly Negative consensus over the past 30 days.</p>

        </div>
      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/total-war-warhammer-3s-developers-are-fighting-to-fix-a-catastrophic-failure-in-many-of-our-ai-systems]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Whether Samsung Likes It or Not, Amazon Just Slashed the 49″ Odyssey OLED Gaming Monitor by Almost 50% for Prime Day]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/samsungs-wildest-49-inch-odyssey-oled-curved-gaming-monitor-is-going-for-45-less-with-this-deal-2000631874</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/whether-samsung-likes-it-or-not-amazon-just-slashed-the-49%E2%80%B3-odyssey-oled-gaming-monitor-by-almost-50-for-prime-day.1318777/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Is there anything better than getting fully immersed in your favorite titles, feeling like you’re part of the game? A standard 16:9 screen is sadly not made for that, and if you don’t want to get pulled out right when things get good, going ultrawide is the solution.</p>
<p>We know upgrades like this can feel overwhelming, since a good-sized ultrawide screen from a known brand can easily run you over $1,600, <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4584/">but that changes today. Thanks to Prime Day, the Samsung 49-inch Odyssey OLED G93SC curved gaming monitor is 44% off on Amazon, dropping the price to $900.</a> That’s one of the lowest prices we’ve ever seen on this wild screen, and with a $700 discount, it’s not a deal that’s likely to last long.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4584/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Massive Screen With Lifelike Visuals</h2>
<p>It’s a beast at 49 inches, offering brilliant colors, deeper contrast, and richer tones for lifelike visuals. More pixels per inch give you better detail, so you’re not sacrificing sharpness for size. The screen is as wide as two QHD monitors side by side, minus the dual setup fuss, with the 1800R curve wrapping around your field of vision for a distraction-free gaming or streaming experience. Dark colors come through clearly as well, thanks to QD-OLED technology and DisplayHDR True Black 400 support. Translation: better visibility even in low-light scenes; perfect for spotting the bad guys hiding in the dark and keeping an eye on shadows.</p>
<p>You’re also getting a 240Hz refresh rate and a 0.03ms response time to keep things smooth. Plus, with both NVIDIA G-Sync compatibility and AMD FreeSync Premium Pro, screen tearing and input lag won’t be an issue either. Connectivity-wise, you’re covered with HDMI 2.1, DisplayPort, and a built-in USB hub. There’s also an Auto Source Switch+ that can detect when the connected devices are turned on and switch over automatically.</p>



<p>For when you’re in the mood for some multitasking, the Picture-by-Picture mode splits the screen in half. Maybe use one for video calls, while having work documents and the browser open on the second. Or maybe stream your favorite content on one side while editing on the other? The possibilities are endless.</p>
<p>Even with all this, the overall design stays minimal. It’s just 4.5mm thick at its thinnest point, which makes it one of the slimmest OLED panels in this range.<a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4584/"> It’s still a bit of an investment at $900, but this deal brings it into a much more approachable range than we usually see.</a></p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4584/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/samsungs-wildest-49-inch-odyssey-oled-curved-gaming-monitor-is-going-for-45-less-with-this-deal-2000631874]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[If You Have an iPhone, You Can Get Two Free AirTags on Amazon]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/if-you-have-an-iphone-you-can-get-two-free-airtags-on-amazon-2000632567</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/if-you-have-an-iphone-you-can-get-two-free-airtags-on-amazon.1318771/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Losing your keys, wallet or luggage ranks among the most frustrating daily experiences. Apple’s AirTag solves this problem in a way no competitor can match, thanks to the <em>Find My</em> network powered by hundreds of millions of Apple devices worldwide. This massive network means your lost item can be located almost anywhere, even if it’s miles away from your own iPhone.</p>
<p>For Prime Big Deal Day, Amazon has dropped AirTag prices to record lows. The <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3844/">4-pack now costs just $64, down from $99</a>: Since a single AirTag normally sells for $29, <strong>this deal essentially gives you almost two free AirTags</strong>. If you only need one, the single AirTag is <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4215/">also at an all-time low of $19, down from $29</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3844/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See 4-pack AirTags at Amazon</a></p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4215/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See Single AirTag at Amazon</a></p>

<p>AirTags function by using Apple’s Find My network, <strong>a group of all iPhones, iPads, and Macs with their location services running</strong>. When you flag an AirTag lost, other <strong>Apple devices running Bluetooth proximity</strong> to it can pick up its Bluetooth signal and report its location anonymously back to yours. It all occurs entirely behind the scenes without notification of the other device’s owner, and all of your location information stays encrypted and private. By virtue of its massive scale, your AirTag becomes locatable even in isolated regions, if someone running an Apple device wanders by.</p>
<h2>Precision Location Detection and Privacy-Aware Design</h2>
<p>Installing an AirTag is a matter of seconds. You just point it near your iPhone or iPad, tap to pair and tag it to an item like your keys or backpack. The U1 chip in newer iPhones powers Precision Finding employs ultra-wideband technology and walks you straight to your AirTag with onscreen arrows and haptic indicators. As you approach, your iPhone displays the exact distance and direction and turns a potentially frantic search into a mere follow-the-arrows endeavor.</p>



<p>Each AirTag uses a <strong>typical CR2032 replaceable battery</strong>, which runs for approximately a year with average use. You’ll receive a notification when it’s running low, and it’s a breeze to replace it by pressing down and twisting off the stainless steel back case. The <strong>AirTag is water- and dust-resistant IP67</strong> so it’s fine being submerged for 30 minutes for a distance of a meter of water.</p>
<p>Privacy features are built into the core design: If an unknown AirTag is traveling with you, your iPhone alerts you automatically. Android users can also detect nearby AirTags using Apple’s Tracker Detect app. The AirTag will also play a sound if it’s been separated from its owner for an extended period, preventing unwanted tracking. These safeguards address privacy concerns while maintaining the device’s usefulness for legitimate tracking.</p>



<p>The thin, lightweight design is just 1.26 inches across and 0.31 inches deep, tiny enough to slip into a wallet’s card slot or affix to a keychain. The shiny stainless steel face is customizable with free engraving if you order directly from Apple, but Amazon’s sale does not include it.</p>
<p>The 4-pack is nicely priced for families, couples, or individuals having several things they’d like to monitor. Put one on your keys, a second on your wallet, a third on your backpack, and maintain a fourth as a spare for your suitcase when traveling. For $64 for four during your Prime Big Deal Day sale, you’re really spending less money per AirTag than ever before.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3844/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See 4-pack AirTags at Amazon</a></p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4215/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See Single AirTag at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/if-you-have-an-iphone-you-can-get-two-free-airtags-on-amazon-2000632567]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Civilization 7 Has Crashed to Less Than $15 on Xbox for October Prime Day]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/civilization-vii-for-xbox-has-dropped-to-a-15-on-xbox-during-october-prime-day</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/civilization-7-has-crashed-to-less-than-15-on-xbox-for-october-prime-day.1318768/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Yes, really.</h2></p><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Amazon's <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/amazon-prime-big-deal-days-2025-best-sales-and-latest-news">Prime Big Deal Days sale event</a> has officially kicked off for Prime members, and there's already so much to look through. In particular, quite a few video game deals have popped up during the sale event, and this discount on <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/sid-meiers-civilization-vii">Sid Meier's Civilization VII</a> for Xbox Series X was one that immediately caught our eye (<a href="https://zdcs.link/aRM2g7?object_uuid=a3a53c5a-3cd9-42ad-99cd-88bdeae5ef00&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" data-aps-asin="B0DDR1DY7R" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">see it here at Amazon</a>).</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Save 81% on Civilization 7 for Xbox Series X</h2><div catalogid="8542ece8-69ae-4735-8f40-3562d92ff68e" id="229076"><div id="229076" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Sid Meier's Civilization VII - Xbox Series X</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Right now, Prime members can save a whopping 81% (yes, you read that correctly) on Civilization VII for Xbox Series X, which has dropped its price from $69.99 to $13.25. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">This is the <a href="https://camelcamelcamel.com/product/B0DDR1DY7R" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">lowest price it's ever been</a> - in comparison to its lowest-ever price outside of Prime-exclusive sale events like this one - so now is as good a time as any to grab it for your library.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">If you're on the fence about picking it up, our <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/civilization-7-review">review of Civilization 7</a> from Leana Hafer said it has, "improved warfare and diplomacy, a bit of added narrative flair, as well as mostly gorgeous graphics and sound." And at this price? It's a hard discount to ignore.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">This isn't the only video game deal to cross our radar, though. If you're looking to pick up PlayStation 5 games instead, there's a <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-ps5-game-deals-october-prime-day-2025">selection of PS5 games discounted right now at Amazon</a> that are worth checking out. The sales even include Death Stranding 2 at its lowest price yet, which is definitely worth taking advantage of.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Prime Big Deal Days runs through tomorrow, October 8, so there's still plenty of time to jump on the discounts that catch your eye. It's also worth checking out our big <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/amazon-prime-big-deal-days-2025-best-sales-and-latest-news#video-games">Prime Big Deal Days video game section</a> to see what other offers have jumped out during this sale event so far, so you can stock up on the items that interest you.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">More Video Game Deals</h3><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Hannah Hoolihan is a freelancer who writes with the guides and commerce teams here at IGN.</em></p></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Oct 7, 2025 2:18 pm</p></div></div><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/civilization-vii-for-xbox-has-dropped-to-a-15-on-xbox-during-october-prime-day]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo's New Animated Short Has Fans Baffled Whether It's a Super Mario Galaxy Movie Teaser — Or a Hint at Pikmin 5]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendos-new-animated-short-has-fans-baffled-whether-its-a-super-mario-galaxy-movie-teaser-or-a-hint-at-pikmin-5</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendos-new-animated-short-has-fans-baffled-whether-its-a-super-mario-galaxy-movie-teaser-%E2%80%94-or-a-hint-at-pikmin-5.1318762/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Nintendo has just released a mysterious animated short film with no explanation — leaving fans wondering whether it's a tease for the upcoming <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/movies/the-super-mario-galaxy-movie">Super Mario Galaxy Movie</a>, or a hint at a new Pikmin game.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">At just under four minutes in length, the dialogue-free animation titled "Close to You" sees a blonde toddler taking their first steps, as their pacifier is mysteriously picked up by an invisible force.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Nintendo fans will note several musical cues from the Pikmin series as the pacifier is picked up and seemingly carried away (though no Pikmin can actually be seen). At the same time, some Nintendo fans have said the child could be space princess Rosalina — who is surely set to debut in next year's Super Mario Galaxy Movie. </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Without any explanation at all from Nintendo itself, this is clearly something fans are being left to ponder about by themselves — though IGN has contacted Nintendo for more. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Certainly, the pacifier's movements really do look like they could be made by a band of Pikmin carrying the item aloft, and several Pikmin games have indeed tasked players with squirreling away household items. And indeed, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/pikmin-4">Pikmin 4</a> even tasked players with venturing inside a human house for the first time. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The Pikmin series has always been set on Earth, with Pikmin themselves suggested as always just being out of sight. Is this Nintendo making it clear that, to human eyes, Pikmin are indeed invisible?</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Leaving aside the Pikmin music and other clues, other fans have suggested the child here could be Rosalina, whose parentage — alongside that of Princess Peach's own — looks set to finally be explained in next year's big-screen Super Mario Galaxy Movie. Is this a scene from that film? We're not sure — the animation style doesn't look quite the same as Illumination's own — but it's also odd to see Nintendo launching its own, unconnected animated short just six months out from its next big animated movie.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Whatever this is, we'll update with more when we have it.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Tom Phillips is IGN's News Editor. You can reach Tom at tom_phillips@ign.com or find him on Bluesky </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/tomphillipseg.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@tomphillipseg.bsky.social</a></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendos-new-animated-short-has-fans-baffled-whether-its-a-super-mario-galaxy-movie-teaser-or-a-hint-at-pikmin-5]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Grab The Acer Nitro VG270 Gaming Monitor For Under $100 At Walmart]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/grab-the-acer-nitro-vg270-gaming-monitor-for-under-100-at-walmart/1100-6535270/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/grab-the-acer-nitro-vg270-gaming-monitor-for-under-100-at-walmart.1318759/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-main">

      
                    
  
              <header id="masthead"><nav></nav></header>      
                            <div id="site-wrapper" role="main">
          <div id="default-content">
        
          <p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p>
  
    <article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6535270">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>A great PC gaming setup allows for more than one display to linked in, and if you've been looking for a second screen that won't break the bank, then you can get a 27-inch monitor right now for just $99. Normally priced at $180, the <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?fntitle=Grab+The+Acer+Nitro+VG270+Gaming+Monitor+For+Under+%24100+At+Walmart&amp;fnauthor=darranged&amp;fndate=2025-10-07+08%3A43%3A00&amp;fnupdated=2025-10-07+08%3A43%3A42&amp;fnarticle_id=6535270&amp;fntype1=Tech&amp;fntype2=News&amp;fntype3=Deals&amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Fgoto.walmart.com%2F3J12LK&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fgrab-the-acer-nitro-vg270-gaming-monitor-for-under-100-at-walmart%2F1100-6535270%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Acer Nitro VG270</a> is a low-budget but reliable display that's on sale at Walmart. The retail chain is looking to match <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/amazon-prime-day-deals/">Amazon's Big Deals Days</a> with its own sales event, <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?fntitle=Grab+The+Acer+Nitro+VG270+Gaming+Monitor+For+Under+%24100+At+Walmart&amp;fnauthor=darranged&amp;fndate=2025-10-07+08%3A43%3A00&amp;fnupdated=2025-10-07+08%3A43%3A42&amp;fnarticle_id=6535270&amp;fntype1=Tech&amp;fntype2=News&amp;fntype3=Deals&amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Fgoto.walmart.com%2FVxXqMA&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fgrab-the-acer-nitro-vg270-gaming-monitor-for-under-100-at-walmart%2F1100-6535270%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">as it offers deals on PC hardware and much more</a>.</p><div title="6535270 - Acer and Samsung monitors (Prime Day 2)" data-embed-type="buylink" data-ref-id="4628" data-template="4" data-size="buylink__listicle" data-title="6535270 - Acer and Samsung monitors (Prime Day 2)" data-collection="">                                                                     <div>             <h2>                    <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?fntitle=Grab+The+Acer+Nitro+VG270+Gaming+Monitor+For+Under+%24100+At+Walmart&amp;fnauthor=darranged&amp;fndate=2025-10-07+08%3A43%3A00&amp;fnupdated=2025-10-07+08%3A43%3A42&amp;fnarticle_id=6535270&amp;fntype1=Tech&amp;fntype2=News&amp;fntype3=Deals&amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Fgoto.walmart.com%2F3J12LK&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fgrab-the-acer-nitro-vg270-gaming-monitor-for-under-100-at-walmart%2F1100-6535270%2F&amp;event_type=click" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/clicks.trx-hub.com\/xid\/fandom_32094_gamespot?fntitle=Grab+The+Acer+Nitro+VG270+Gaming+Monitor+For+Under+%24100+At+Walmart&amp;fnauthor=darranged&amp;fndate=2025-10-07+08%3A43%3A00&amp;fnupdated=2025-10-07+08%3A43%3A42&amp;fnarticle_id=6535270&amp;fntype1=Tech&amp;fntype2=News&amp;fntype3=Deals&amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Fgoto.walmart.com%2F3J12LK&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fgrab-the-acer-nitro-vg270-gaming-monitor-for-under-100-at-walmart%2F1100-6535270%2F&amp;event_type=click&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?fntitle=Grab+The+Acer+Nitro+VG270+Gaming+Monitor+For+Under+%24100+At+Walmart&amp;fnauthor=darranged&amp;fndate=2025-10-07+08%3A43%3A00&amp;fnupdated=2025-10-07+08%3A43%3A42&amp;fnarticle_id=6535270&amp;fntype1=Tech&amp;fntype2=News&amp;fntype3=Deals&amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Fgoto.walmart.com%2F3J12LK&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fgrab-the-acer-nitro-vg270-gaming-monitor-for-under-100-at-walmart%2F1100-6535270%2F&amp;event_type=click">Acer Nitro 27" IPS 144Hz Gaming Monitor</a>       </h2>                                   <h3>                      <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?fntitle=Grab+The+Acer+Nitro+VG270+Gaming+Monitor+For+Under+%24100+At+Walmart&amp;fnauthor=darranged&amp;fndate=2025-10-07+08%3A43%3A00&amp;fnupdated=2025-10-07+08%3A43%3A42&amp;fnarticle_id=6535270&amp;fntype1=Tech&amp;fntype2=News&amp;fntype3=Deals&amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Fgoto.walmart.com%2F3J12LK&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fgrab-the-acer-nitro-vg270-gaming-monitor-for-under-100-at-walmart%2F1100-6535270%2F&amp;event_type=click" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/clicks.trx-hub.com\/xid\/fandom_32094_gamespot?fntitle=Grab+The+Acer+Nitro+VG270+Gaming+Monitor+For+Under+%24100+At+Walmart&amp;fnauthor=darranged&amp;fndate=2025-10-07+08%3A43%3A00&amp;fnupdated=2025-10-07+08%3A43%3A42&amp;fnarticle_id=6535270&amp;fntype1=Tech&amp;fntype2=News&amp;fntype3=Deals&amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Fgoto.walmart.com%2F3J12LK&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fgrab-the-acer-nitro-vg270-gaming-monitor-for-under-100-at-walmart%2F1100-6535270%2F&amp;event_type=click&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?fntitle=Grab+The+Acer+Nitro+VG270+Gaming+Monitor+For+Under+%24100+At+Walmart&amp;fnauthor=darranged&amp;fndate=2025-10-07+08%3A43%3A00&amp;fnupdated=2025-10-07+08%3A43%3A42&amp;fnarticle_id=6535270&amp;fntype1=Tech&amp;fntype2=News&amp;fntype3=Deals&amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Fgoto.walmart.com%2F3J12LK&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fgrab-the-acer-nitro-vg270-gaming-monitor-for-under-100-at-walmart%2F1100-6535270%2F&amp;event_type=click">$99 ($180)</a>         </h3>                                                                                                                      <div><p>The Acer Nitro VG270 offers a 144Hz refresh rate, AMD FreeSync, and a full HD 1920 x 1080 resolution. This makes it ideal for a starter PC or as a second screen, as the fast 1ms response time and refresh rate alongside AMD FreeSync means that you won't have to worry about input lag or screen tearing. Essentially, this display is worth considering if you want to keep an extra display hooked up for various tasks, or if you're looking to buy a PC that will become the household Fortnite machine for younger members of the family.</p><p>One other worth mentioning here is the physical setup of the monitor, as Acer's ZeroFrame design allows for an almost seamless view. At this price, it might be worth picking up two of these to get a multi-monitor setup that looks aesthetically pleasing.</p></div>                      </div>                                                                     <div>             <h2>                    <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?fntitle=Grab+The+Acer+Nitro+VG270+Gaming+Monitor+For+Under+%24100+At+Walmart&amp;fnauthor=darranged&amp;fndate=2025-10-07+08%3A43%3A00&amp;fnupdated=2025-10-07+08%3A43%3A42&amp;fnarticle_id=6535270&amp;fntype1=Tech&amp;fntype2=News&amp;fntype3=Deals&amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Fgoto.walmart.com%2FgOd94r&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fgrab-the-acer-nitro-vg270-gaming-monitor-for-under-100-at-walmart%2F1100-6535270%2F&amp;event_type=click" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/clicks.trx-hub.com\/xid\/fandom_32094_gamespot?fntitle=Grab+The+Acer+Nitro+VG270+Gaming+Monitor+For+Under+%24100+At+Walmart&amp;fnauthor=darranged&amp;fndate=2025-10-07+08%3A43%3A00&amp;fnupdated=2025-10-07+08%3A43%3A42&amp;fnarticle_id=6535270&amp;fntype1=Tech&amp;fntype2=News&amp;fntype3=Deals&amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Fgoto.walmart.com%2FgOd94r&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fgrab-the-acer-nitro-vg270-gaming-monitor-for-under-100-at-walmart%2F1100-6535270%2F&amp;event_type=click&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?fntitle=Grab+The+Acer+Nitro+VG270+Gaming+Monitor+For+Under+%24100+At+Walmart&amp;fnauthor=darranged&amp;fndate=2025-10-07+08%3A43%3A00&amp;fnupdated=2025-10-07+08%3A43%3A42&amp;fnarticle_id=6535270&amp;fntype1=Tech&amp;fntype2=News&amp;fntype3=Deals&amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Fgoto.walmart.com%2FgOd94r&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fgrab-the-acer-nitro-vg270-gaming-monitor-for-under-100-at-walmart%2F1100-6535270%2F&amp;event_type=click">Samsung Odyssey 25" IPS 240Hz Gaming Monitor</a>       </h2>                                   <h3>                      <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?fntitle=Grab+The+Acer+Nitro+VG270+Gaming+Monitor+For+Under+%24100+At+Walmart&amp;fnauthor=darranged&amp;fndate=2025-10-07+08%3A43%3A00&amp;fnupdated=2025-10-07+08%3A43%3A42&amp;fnarticle_id=6535270&amp;fntype1=Tech&amp;fntype2=News&amp;fntype3=Deals&amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Fgoto.walmart.com%2FgOd94r&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fgrab-the-acer-nitro-vg270-gaming-monitor-for-under-100-at-walmart%2F1100-6535270%2F&amp;event_type=click" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/clicks.trx-hub.com\/xid\/fandom_32094_gamespot?fntitle=Grab+The+Acer+Nitro+VG270+Gaming+Monitor+For+Under+%24100+At+Walmart&amp;fnauthor=darranged&amp;fndate=2025-10-07+08%3A43%3A00&amp;fnupdated=2025-10-07+08%3A43%3A42&amp;fnarticle_id=6535270&amp;fntype1=Tech&amp;fntype2=News&amp;fntype3=Deals&amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Fgoto.walmart.com%2FgOd94r&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fgrab-the-acer-nitro-vg270-gaming-monitor-for-under-100-at-walmart%2F1100-6535270%2F&amp;event_type=click&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?fntitle=Grab+The+Acer+Nitro+VG270+Gaming+Monitor+For+Under+%24100+At+Walmart&amp;fnauthor=darranged&amp;fndate=2025-10-07+08%3A43%3A00&amp;fnupdated=2025-10-07+08%3A43%3A42&amp;fnarticle_id=6535270&amp;fntype1=Tech&amp;fntype2=News&amp;fntype3=Deals&amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Fgoto.walmart.com%2FgOd94r&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fgrab-the-acer-nitro-vg270-gaming-monitor-for-under-100-at-walmart%2F1100-6535270%2F&amp;event_type=click">$169 (was $280)</a>         </h3>                                                                                                                      <p>Walmart's other budget option is the <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?fntitle=Grab+The+Acer+Nitro+VG270+Gaming+Monitor+For+Under+%24100+At+Walmart&amp;fnauthor=darranged&amp;fndate=2025-10-07+08%3A43%3A00&amp;fnupdated=2025-10-07+08%3A43%3A42&amp;fnarticle_id=6535270&amp;fntype1=Tech&amp;fntype2=News&amp;fntype3=Deals&amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Fgoto.walmart.com%2FgOd94r&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fgrab-the-acer-nitro-vg270-gaming-monitor-for-under-100-at-walmart%2F1100-6535270%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Samsung Odyssey gaming monitor</a>. This model is more expensive--and slightly smaller at 25 inches--but it does have an impressive array of specs. The 1920 x 1080p screen features a 240Hz refresh rate and a 1ms response time. Nvidia G-Sync and AMD FreeSync compatibility, and an ultrawide 21:9 form factor. The screen also has a futuristic design with its bevels, and the included stand can be adjusted to meet your preferred viewing angle.</p>                      </div>   </div><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/best-walmart-deals-october-2025-big-deal-days/1100-6535261/" data-ref-id="1100-6535261">This is just the tip of the Walmart iceberg</a>, as there are hundreds of other deals on a variety of goods right now from the company. We've gathered together Walmart's <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?fntitle=Grab+The+Acer+Nitro+VG270+Gaming+Monitor+For+Under+%24100+At+Walmart&amp;fnauthor=darranged&amp;fndate=2025-10-07+08%3A43%3A00&amp;fnupdated=2025-10-07+08%3A43%3A42&amp;fnarticle_id=6535270&amp;fntype1=Tech&amp;fntype2=News&amp;fntype3=Deals&amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Fgoto.walmart.com%2FRGVz57&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fgrab-the-acer-nitro-vg270-gaming-monitor-for-under-100-at-walmart%2F1100-6535270%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">top 100 tech deals</a>, and you can also check out specials on <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?fntitle=Grab+The+Acer+Nitro+VG270+Gaming+Monitor+For+Under+%24100+At+Walmart&amp;fnauthor=darranged&amp;fndate=2025-10-07+08%3A43%3A00&amp;fnupdated=2025-10-07+08%3A43%3A42&amp;fnarticle_id=6535270&amp;fntype1=Tech&amp;fntype2=News&amp;fntype3=Deals&amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Fgoto.walmart.com%2FQj1BJz&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fgrab-the-acer-nitro-vg270-gaming-monitor-for-under-100-at-walmart%2F1100-6535270%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">laptops</a>, <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?fntitle=Grab+The+Acer+Nitro+VG270+Gaming+Monitor+For+Under+%24100+At+Walmart&amp;fnauthor=darranged&amp;fndate=2025-10-07+08%3A43%3A00&amp;fnupdated=2025-10-07+08%3A43%3A42&amp;fnarticle_id=6535270&amp;fntype1=Tech&amp;fntype2=News&amp;fntype3=Deals&amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Fgoto.walmart.com%2F9LoNAY&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fgrab-the-acer-nitro-vg270-gaming-monitor-for-under-100-at-walmart%2F1100-6535270%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">TVs</a>, <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?fntitle=Grab+The+Acer+Nitro+VG270+Gaming+Monitor+For+Under+%24100+At+Walmart&amp;fnauthor=darranged&amp;fndate=2025-10-07+08%3A43%3A00&amp;fnupdated=2025-10-07+08%3A43%3A42&amp;fnarticle_id=6535270&amp;fntype1=Tech&amp;fntype2=News&amp;fntype3=Deals&amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Fgoto.walmart.com%2F55JRb2&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fgrab-the-acer-nitro-vg270-gaming-monitor-for-under-100-at-walmart%2F1100-6535270%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">toys</a>, and much more.</p><p><strong>Walmart Deals: Most Popular</strong></p><ul><li><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?fntitle=Grab+The+Acer+Nitro+VG270+Gaming+Monitor+For+Under+%24100+At+Walmart&amp;fnauthor=darranged&amp;fndate=2025-10-07+08%3A43%3A00&amp;fnupdated=2025-10-07+08%3A43%3A42&amp;fnarticle_id=6535270&amp;fntype1=Tech&amp;fntype2=News&amp;fntype3=Deals&amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Fgoto.walmart.com%2FVxXn4k&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fgrab-the-acer-nitro-vg270-gaming-monitor-for-under-100-at-walmart%2F1100-6535270%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow"><strong>Top 100 Walmart Deals</strong></a></li><li><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?fntitle=Grab+The+Acer+Nitro+VG270+Gaming+Monitor+For+Under+%24100+At+Walmart&amp;fnauthor=darranged&amp;fndate=2025-10-07+08%3A43%3A00&amp;fnupdated=2025-10-07+08%3A43%3A42&amp;fnarticle_id=6535270&amp;fntype1=Tech&amp;fntype2=News&amp;fntype3=Deals&amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Fgoto.walmart.com%2F55JRb2&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fgrab-the-acer-nitro-vg270-gaming-monitor-for-under-100-at-walmart%2F1100-6535270%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Top 100 Toy Deals</a></li><li><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?fntitle=Grab+The+Acer+Nitro+VG270+Gaming+Monitor+For+Under+%24100+At+Walmart&amp;fnauthor=darranged&amp;fndate=2025-10-07+08%3A43%3A00&amp;fnupdated=2025-10-07+08%3A43%3A42&amp;fnarticle_id=6535270&amp;fntype1=Tech&amp;fntype2=News&amp;fntype3=Deals&amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Fgoto.walmart.com%2FRGVz57&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fgrab-the-acer-nitro-vg270-gaming-monitor-for-under-100-at-walmart%2F1100-6535270%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Top 100 Tech Deals</a></li><li><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?fntitle=Grab+The+Acer+Nitro+VG270+Gaming+Monitor+For+Under+%24100+At+Walmart&amp;fnauthor=darranged&amp;fndate=2025-10-07+08%3A43%3A00&amp;fnupdated=2025-10-07+08%3A43%3A42&amp;fnarticle_id=6535270&amp;fntype1=Tech&amp;fntype2=News&amp;fntype3=Deals&amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Fgoto.walmart.com%2FQj1BJz&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fgrab-the-acer-nitro-vg270-gaming-monitor-for-under-100-at-walmart%2F1100-6535270%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Top 100 Laptop Deals</a></li><li><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?fntitle=Grab+The+Acer+Nitro+VG270+Gaming+Monitor+For+Under+%24100+At+Walmart&amp;fnauthor=darranged&amp;fndate=2025-10-07+08%3A43%3A00&amp;fnupdated=2025-10-07+08%3A43%3A42&amp;fnarticle_id=6535270&amp;fntype1=Tech&amp;fntype2=News&amp;fntype3=Deals&amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Fgoto.walmart.com%2F9LoNAY&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fgrab-the-acer-nitro-vg270-gaming-monitor-for-under-100-at-walmart%2F1100-6535270%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Top 100 TV Deals</a></li></ul><div data-embed-type="pinbox" data-ref-id="4304">  <ul>                              <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-powera-cheap-wireless-controller-super-mario-amazon-deals/1100-6535215/">Get Super Mario And Kirby Switch 2 Wireless Controllers For Up To 50% Off</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/amazon-audible-premium-plus-sign-up-prime-big-deal-days-black-friday-holiday-2025-deal/1100-6524536/">Audible Premium Plus Holiday Deal: Get 3 Audiobooks For $3</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/amazon-prime-big-deal-days-4k-blu-ray-best-deals/1100-6535093/">Prime Big Deal Days Movie Sale: Check Out Amazon's B2G1 Free 4K Blu-Ray Catalog</a></li>                          <li>         <span>+ Show More More Gaming, Tech, and Entertainment Deals &amp; Preorders Links (5)</span>       </li>          <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/rog-xbox-ally-preorder-guide/1100-6535007/">ROG Xbox Ally X Preorders In Stock At Best Buy, Sold Out Everywhere Else (September 27)</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/final-fantasy-magic-the-gathering-trading-cards-restock-where-to-buy-amazon-walmart-best-buy-target/2900-6271/">New Magic: The Gathering Final Fantasy Chocobo Bundle &amp; Scene Boxes Up For Preorder</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/lego-game-boy-restocked-at-amazon-and-its-shipping-early/1100-6533358/">You Can Get The $60 Lego Game Boy Early From Amazon</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/history-of-middle-earth-5440-page-box-set-drops-to-all-time-best-price-for-big-deal-days/1100-6526926/">Complete History Of Middle-Earth Collector's Box Set Restocked With $170 Discount</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-shining-movie-4k-blu-ray-special-edition-steelbook-the-film-vault/1100-6534223/">The Shining's New Numbered Limited Edition Is Up For Grabs At Amazon</a></li>   </ul> </div>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article>

    
  

    
</div>
                      <meta itemprop="seamless-content-list-items" data-list-items="[{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534223&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/the-shining-movie-4k-blu-ray-special-edition-steelbook-the-film-vault\/1100-6534223\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6535265&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/transformers-optimus-prime-converting-rc-vehicle-sees-major-price-drop-at-walmart\/1100-6535265\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6535162&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/game-pass-ultimate-is-still-20-at-gamestop-and-many-other-retailers\/1100-6535162\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6509331&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/lego-transformers-optimus-prime-soundwave-bumblebee-2-in-1-building-sets\/1100-6509331\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6535158&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/this-guy-got-rog-xbox-ally-x-early-thanks-to-amazons-mistake\/1100-6535158\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534727&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/the-long-walk-4k-blu-ray-limited-edition-steelbook-stephen-king-movie-adaptation\/1100-6534727\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534016&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/attack-on-titan-final-season-complete-blu-ray-steelbook-edition-amazon-preorder\/1100-6534016\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6535138&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/game-pass-price-hike-announced-now-costs-30-month-for-ultimate\/1100-6535138\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6535218&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/hunger-games-novel-box-set-deluxe-illustrated-editions-best-book-movie-deals-sunrise-on-the-reaping\/1100-6535218\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6535038&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/one-battle-after-another-paul-thomas-anderson-leonardo-dicaprio-4k-blu-ray-preorders\/1100-6535038\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6535185&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/best-settings-for-cod-black-ops-7-controller-layouts-sensitivity-and-more\/1100-6535185\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6535177&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/a-song-of-ice-and-fire-george-rr-martin-game-of-thrones-book-box-set-deals\/1100-6535177\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6535184&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/disco-elysium-studio-za-um-gets-first-recognized-workers-union-in-uk-games-industry\/1100-6535184\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6535183&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/gta-5-celebrates-halloween-with-slasher-mode-and-zombies\/1100-6535183\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6535173&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/halo-tv-show-hits-netflix-quickly-becomes-one-of-the-most-popular-shows-on-the-platform\/1100-6535173\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529819&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/marvel-spider-man-magic-the-gathering-trading-card-restock-amazon-preorder\/1100-6529819\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534523&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/lord-of-the-rings-tales-of-middle-earth-magic-the-gathering-commander-deck-restock-deals\/1100-6534523\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6532961&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/kindle-scribe-ereader-amazon-prime-day-sale-best-deal\/1100-6532961\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6530145&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/lord-of-the-rings-tolkien-illustrated-deluxe-special-edition-amazon-deals\/1100-6530145\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6535191&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/new-sora-2-ai-mario-and-pikachu-videos-seem-primed-for-nintendo-lawsuits\/1100-6535191\/&quot;}]">
            </div>
              
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/grab-the-acer-nitro-vg270-gaming-monitor-for-under-100-at-walmart/1100-6535270/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Treyarch Explains Why Call Of Duty: Black Ops 7 Doesn't Have Wall-Running]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/treyarch-explains-why-call-of-duty-black-ops-7-doesnt-have-wall-running/1100-6535279/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/treyarch-explains-why-call-of-duty-black-ops-7-doesnt-have-wall-running.1318756/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6535279">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>While Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 is adding wall-jumping to players' repertoire of advanced movement options, developer Treyarch isn't taking a page from its 2015 futuristic title Black Ops 3 by incorporating wall-running or Thrust Jumps for one simple reason: It's too early for that.</p><p>Speaking to <a href="https://www.gamesradar.com/games/call-of-duty/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-devs-say-that-you-can-blame-the-black-ops-timeline-for-the-wall-jump-not-being-a-wall-run-black-ops-2-really-gave-us-a-foundation-for-the-technology-available/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">GamesRadar</a>, Treyarch associate creative director Miles Leslie reiterated that Black Ops 7, which takes place in the year 2035, is more of a direct follow-up to 2012's Black Ops 2, which took place in the then-far-fetched future of 2025.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="503653912" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6466271,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Call%20of%20Duty%20Black%20Ops%207%3A%20First%20Impressions&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:679,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-first-impressions\/2300-6466271\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466271\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466271\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466271\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6466271&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6466271,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6535279&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;call-of-duty-black-ops-7&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;action,first-person,shooter,tactical&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;xbox-series-x,pc,playstation-5,playstation-4,xbox-one&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;activision&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;franchise&quot;:&quot;call-of-duty&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;franchiseRoot&quot;:&quot;call-of-duty&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6466271},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6466271\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;GameSpot&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4553476-cod_site.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/tODiIHBE.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1755719340,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="tODiIHBE" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> Call of Duty Black Ops 7: First Impressions</p>
      </div>
<p>"Since we knew we were going back into that timeline, Black Ops 2 really gave us a foundation for the technology available," Leslie said. Meanwhile, Black Ops 3 takes place further into the future in the year 2065, giving Treyarch some canonical limitations on where to take its Omnimovement systems. In other words, wall-running just isn't possible in the time Black Ops 7 takes place in.</p><p>"We are really precious to our own canon; we have to respect that. So that meant we couldn't have Thrust Jump, because the tech didn't exist in 2035," Leslie said. "Wall-running made sense when we were further in the future but, with our return to the Black Ops 2 era, that world just didn't have that sort of technology so it made sense not to do it."</p><p>You can <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/heres-how-wall-jumping-works-in-black-ops-7/1100-6534910/" data-ref-id="1100-6534910">wall-jump in Black Ops 7</a> on certain surfaces to get some additional vertical height. Each subsequent wall jump will reduce momentum, but you can chain three wall jumps together before hitting the ground.</p><p>The ability to wall-run first appeared in the Call of Duty franchise in Black Ops 3 and returned in Infinity Ward's space-faring 2016 game Infinite Warfare. Famously, removing wall-running and Thrust Jumps was one of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-black-ops-4-revamps-multiplayer-for-a/1100-6459058/" data-ref-id="1100-6459058">Treyarch's selling points for Black Ops 4</a>, which released in 2018 and was set in the year 2045, before Black Ops 3. Though, that implies that soldiers forgot how to wall-jump by the time Black Ops 4 happens.</p><p>To try the wall-jump yourself, you can jump into the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-beta-extended-now-wraps-up-right-before-battlefield-6-launch/1100-6535266/" data-ref-id="1100-6535266">Black Ops 6 open beta, which has just been extended</a> to end on Thursday, October 9, at 9 AM PT / 12 PM ET. That's a full 24 hours after the beta was originally set to conclude, and on the heels of the launch of EA's Battlefield 6. While you're playing the beta, check out <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-best-weapon-loadouts/2900-7108/" data-ref-id="2900-7108">GameSpot's recommended weapon loadouts</a> for some extra help.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/treyarch-explains-why-call-of-duty-black-ops-7-doesnt-have-wall-running/1100-6535279/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PowerWash Simulator 2 is releasing this month]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/10/07/powerwash-simulator-2-is-releasing-this-month/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/powerwash-simulator-2-is-releasing-this-month.1318741/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>FuturLab has announced that it will be releasing PowerWash Simulator 2 on October 23rd, making the announcement with a new trailer. The follow up to PowerWash Simulator is going to be available on &nbsp;Steam, Epic Games, Windows Store, Xbox Series X|S, PS5 &amp; Nintendo Switch 2 with a price of $24.99 / €24.99 / £19.99 / JP¥2970.</p>
<p><iframe title="PowerWash Simulator 2 | Release Date Announcement Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/RrFexXPbVuM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>PowerWash Simulator 2 expands massively on the original game, with powerwashing just being one of the activities in the game. The town of Muckingham &nbsp;will have multi-stage jobs, home case customisation, and even some mysteries to uncover around Muckingham. There will be additional locations to explore too including &nbsp;Sponge Valley, Power Falls and Lubri City. You will have access to new tools including an abseiling rig and cherry picker to reach those hard to reach spots.</p>
<h2><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/08/06/powerwash-simulator-2-preview-twice-the-cleaning-power/">PowerWash Simulator 2 Preview – Twice the cleaning power?</a></h2>
<p>In our PowerWash Simulator 2 preview, Stefan said, <em>“There’s plenty more to PowerWash Simulator 2 that we didn’t really get to toy with, from the customisable home base, to designing van liveries, to playing co-op online or in split-screen, and the career story, though we did at least get to give Ulysses the cat and some random kittens a little tickle every now and then. What’s most important, though, is that this retains that soothing essence of the reverse colouring book gameplay, with a few new options and tools just adding a smidgeon more variety.”</em></p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RrFexXPbVuM">FuturLab</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/10/07/powerwash-simulator-2-is-releasing-this-month/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PowerWash Simulator 2 Release Date Revealed for Later This Month]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/powerwash-simulator-2-release-date</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/powerwash-simulator-2-release-date-revealed-for-later-this-month.1318738/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>PowerWash Simulator 2&nbsp;</em>developer FuturLab has revealed the upcoming cleaning sim's release date, and it's much closer than you might think, so it won't be long before you can load up your power washer once again.</p>

<p>As announced via a brand new trailer,&nbsp;<em>PowerWash Simulator 2&nbsp;</em>will be launching on October 23rd. As far as we know, the game is due to launch on day one for Game Pass as well, although given <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/xbox-game-pass-tiers-reworked-2025" rel="nofollow">recent developments</a>, that might not be quite such an enticing prospect anymore.</p>

<p>Announced back in March this year,&nbsp;<em>PowerWash Simulator 2&nbsp;</em>is, as the name suggests, the sequel to 2022's relaxing cleaning sim&nbsp;<em>PowerWash Simulator</em>. Like its predecessor, this followup will let you loose on a variety of filthy environments, and it's up to you to make them clean once more.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/powerwash-simulator-2-release-date-grime.jpg?itok=tqaHQAwT 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/powerwash-simulator-2-release-date-grime.jpg?itok=4urDB8zd 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>There's so much grime and dirt in here it's practically painful.</figcaption></figure><p>Of course, it wouldn't be much of a sequel if there weren't improvements and new features galore, and so you can expect to explore not only Muckingham but the environs beyond its borders this time around.</p>

<p>Those locations will be part of a brand new campaign that will take you to such aptly-named locations as Sponge Valley, Power Falls, and Lubri City. I wouldn't think too hard about that last one if I were you.</p>

<p>New multi-stage jobs will test your cleaning prowess over several different stages, and naturally, you can expect a range of new tools to help you tackle those jobs, including a new abseiling rig, a cherry picker, and a surface cleaner for bigger areas.</p>

<p>You can check out the new&nbsp;<em>PowerWash Simulator 2&nbsp;</em>release date trailer, which shows off some of the game's satisfying-looking cleaning action (as well as its <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/new-powerwash-simulator-2-gameplay-trailer" rel="nofollow">frankly criminally adorable cat</a>), right here.</p>




<p><em>PowerWash Simulator 2&nbsp;</em>launches for <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2968420/PowerWash_Simulator_2/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC</a>, <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/concept/10011314" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PlayStation 5</a>, <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/powerwash-simulator-2/9p45ggdtfnsm" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Xbox Series X|S</a>, and Nintendo Switch 2 on October 23rd. While you wait, you can refresh your memory of the first one with <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/powerwash-simulator-review" rel="nofollow">our very own Blair's review</a>.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/powerwash-simulator-2-release-date]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>