<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 12:26:40 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Achilles: Legends Untold free DLC Fates of Moira out today]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/09/18/achilles-legends-untold-free-dlc-fates-of-moira-out-today/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/achilles-legends-untold-free-dlc-fates-of-moira-out-today.984195/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/09/18/achilles-legends-untold-free-dlc-fates-of-moira-out-today/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Achilles: Legends Untold is getting free DLC content today in the shape of Fates of Moira, a collection new gameplay modes that are available to play once the main story campaign is completed. The name is reference to the character Moira, who becomes a central part of this mode, and it also deals with the fates with different challenges awaiting Achilles.</p>
<p><iframe title="Achilles Legends Untold: Fates of Moriai - Update 1.5" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/q2ytN7qanH0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>The three modes that Achilles: Legends Untold Fates of Moira brings are:</p>
<ul>
<li dir="ltr" role="presentation"><em>Inevitable Fate of Atropos: Precision and caution are your greatest allies. Every melee hit you land instantly kills any non-boss enemy, but the stakes are equally high for you—one hit and Achilles falls.</em></li>
<li dir="ltr" role="presentation"><em>Fate of Clotho the Spinner: Achilles constantly loses HP, pushing you to play aggressively to stay alive. Using Hades Vision pauses the life drain, and you can heal by killing enemies with Drain Souls. However, you can’t attack or use weapon skills in Hades Vision, adding tension and strategy to every move.</em></li>
<li dir="ltr" role="presentation"><em>Fate of Lachesis The Allotter: A relentless Laistrygon hunts you on every map, immune to conventional damage but can be slowed or debuffed. It grows stronger over time, forcing you to survive through strategy and cunning. The Ariadne’s Thread can temporarily remove the threat, but be prepared—it will return stronger than before.</em></li>
</ul>
<p>In addition to the announcement of the free DLC, Dark Point Games has also confirmed that Achilles: Legends Untold is available from today on PS4 and Xbox One, with a Nintendo Switch release following later this year. Paweł Waszak, CEO of Dark Point Games, said, <em>“Given the strong demand and numerous requests we’ve received from our community, we decided it was important to make our game accessible to a wider audience. That’s why we’re excited to announce that we will be releasing the game on older-generation consoles, including Xbox One, PS4, and Nintendo Switch. We want everyone to be able to enjoy the experience, no matter what platform they’re on.”</em></p>


<p>In our Achilles: Legends Untold review, Adrian said, <em>“The Greek Myths have been plundered by video game developers to such a degree it’s hard to conceive that a fresh take could be even possible. Remarkably, Achilles: Legends Untold offers just that. This action-adventure might be a little rough around the edges, but that arguably adds to its charm. If you can put up with some nasty difficulty spikes then you’ll find a remarkable world of myths and legends to explore.”</em></p>
<p><em>Source: Press Release</em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battlefield Fans Reckon They’ve Worked Out the Real-World Location Shown in the New Concept Art]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/battlefield-fans-reckon-theyve-worked-out-the-real-world-location-shown-in-the-new-concept-art</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/battlefield-fans-reckon-they%E2%80%99ve-worked-out-the-real-world-location-shown-in-the-new-concept-art.984189/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/battlefield-fans-reckon-theyve-worked-out-the-real-world-location-shown-in-the-new-concept-art<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>EA finally started talking about the new Battlefield game this week, with head of Respawn and group GM for EA Studios Organization Vince Zampella telling <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/exclusive-first-battlefield-concept-art-revealed-vince-zampella">IGN</a> it will use a modern setting. IGN also exclusively revealed the first concept art for the new Battlefield, below, which in turn set the game’s community off on a detective hunt to work out where in the real world it was set.</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/09/16/battlefield-concept-art-1726502144551.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p>Now, fans reckon they have a pretty good idea where the concept art takes place.</p><p><em><strong>Warning!</strong></em><em> Potential Battlefield spoilers follow:</em></p><p>Video game content creator TacticalBrit tweeted to say the concept art shows a war-torn Gibraltar. Various points of interest in the concept art line up with shots of the real world Gibraltar, making this one nailed on.</p><p>“Makes perfect sense for any game with a theoretical conflict as Gibraltar acts as a strategic bridge between Europe and Africa,” TacticalBrit added.</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>After doing more takes at the Battlefield Concept art.</p><p>I feel almost 80% certain this is infact Gibraltar.</p><p>Makes perfect sense for any game with a theoretical conflict as Gibraltar acts as a strategic bridge between Europe and Africa. <a href="https://t.co/RodDI4zq68" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/RodDI4zq68</a></p></div>— TacticalBrit (@TheTacticalBrit) <a href="https://twitter.com/TheTacticalBrit/status/1836116916806783077?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">September 17, 2024</a></blockquote> <p>Gibraltar appeared in 2006’s Battlefield 2142 via the Camp Gibraltar Conquest-only map, so the franchise has featured the British Overseas Territory before. That’s all we really have on the new Battlefield though, save snippets of information Zampella gave to IGN, such as the unpopular Specialists system being ditched in favor of more traditional classes. The concept art also suggests ship-to-ship and helicopter combat will be part of the new game, and that it will feature natural disasters like wildfires.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3>Every IGN Battlefield Review</h3></div></output><p>Four EA-owned studios are working on Battlefield: DICE for multiplayer, Criterion for single-player and multiplayer, Motive for single-player, and Ripple Effect for a "new experience." There’s no release date or launch platforms yet. Also in out interview, Zampella offered his thoughts on the recently announced PS5 Pro, <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/vince-zampella-defends-the-ps5-pro-price-battlefield">including on its $700 price</a>.</p><p><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[After Helldivers 2’s Game-Changing Update Made Everything Easier, Some Hardcore Fans Want a New Harder Difficulty — and the Devs Agree]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/after-helldivers-2s-game-changing-update-made-everything-easier-some-hardcore-fans-want-a-new-harder-difficulty-and-the-devs-agree</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/after-helldivers-2%E2%80%99s-game-changing-update-made-everything-easier-some-hardcore-fans-want-a-new-harder-difficulty-%E2%80%94-and-the-devs-agree.984186/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/after-helldivers-2s-game-changing-update-made-everything-easier-some-hardcore-fans-want-a-new-harder-difficulty-and-the-devs-agree<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p><a href="https://www.ign.com/games/helldivers-ii">Helldivers 2</a> received a shot in the arm this week with the release of <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/helldivers-2s-crucial-01001100-update-completely-reworks-weapons-adds-new-galactic-war-feature-and-changes-much-more-in-bid-to-make-the-game-easier">update 01.001.100</a>, a patch that completely reworked weapon balance, added a new Galactic War feature, and made loads more changes aimed at making the PC and PlayStation 5 co-op shooter easier and more fun.</p><p>The update came after a troubling period for the game and for developer Arrowhead that saw its disgruntled playerbase complain that nerfs had gone too far and as a result had stripped the fun out of Helldivers 2.</p><p>Early indications are that this latest patch has brought fans back on-side, and even sparked a modest increase in concurrent players on Steam (Sony does not make PlayStation player numbers publicly available).</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>But now, after complaining that Helldivers 2 offered too tough of a challenge, or, more specifically, did not provide players with the right tools to reasonably face touch challenges in the game, some of Helldivers 2’s most hardcore fans are saying the game is too easy.</p><p>Creative director Johan Pilestedt took to social media to ask fans what they thought of the Helldivers 2 patch, and a recurring theme was that the game perhaps needs an even harder difficulty level, given how easy it had become overnight.</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Maybe a tad too easy? 🤣</p>— Pilestedt (@Pilestedt) <a href="https://twitter.com/Pilestedt/status/1836327250066571339?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">September 18, 2024</a></blockquote> <p>“We are going to look at the challenge of the game for those high tier players, it's in the pipe,” Pilestedt confirmed. Then, in response to one fan who said, “Everything is great but we need a new harder difficulty now,” Pilestedt replied: “I agree!”</p><p>Arrowhead now faces the prospect of having successfully tweaked Helldivers 2 for the majority of its playerbase, but also having to provide that rock hard challenge for its hardcore fans. A rock hard difficulty should help.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>It just didn't feel enjoyable or believable to hit a Charger with an RR and it brushing it off.</p></div><p>One fan wondered why Helldivers 2 players didn't simply play on easier difficulties rather than complaining about the game or leaving it behind (a comment that disregards the fact that some of Helldivers 2's most coveted resources are locked behind the harder difficulties). "Now any level is a walk in the park," they said. "Even big bugs get thrashed sooo fast, it's kinda sad."</p><p><a href="https://x.com/Pilestedt/status/1836083116328305135" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Pilestedt's reply</a> to this got to the heart of the problem with Helldivers 2 pre-patch: "Right, It's because it just didn't feel enjoyable or believable to hit a Charger with an RR and it brushing it off."</p><p>What Arrowhead is unlikely to do is return to drastically nerfing Helldivers 2’s stratagems and weapons, given that’s what got the game into trouble in the first place.</p><p>“I swear to god if yall start nerfing this stuff…,” worried one fan. “Agree,” <a href="https://x.com/Pilestedt/status/1836082615843246219" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Pilestedt replied</a>. “Especially when it comes to damage; nerfing is an unimaginative way of tweaking a game.”</p><p>Helldivers 2’s next Premium Warbond, dubbed <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/helldivers-2s-next-premium-warbond-adds-chemical-weapons-new-stratagems-and-a-pull-my-finger-emote"><u>Chemical Agents</u></a>, launches tomorrow, September 19. While Chemical Agents does not include any new weapons, it adds two stratagem variants — the TX-41 Sterilizer, which lets you spray a gas at the Terminids and Automatons, and the Guard Dog's ‘Dog Breath,’ which is a corrosive gas sprayer — and, in keeping with the alien exterminator theme, the G-4 Gas grenade, which covers the whole area in a cloud of noxious fumes.</p><p>Arrowhead will be hoping update 01.001.100 is the first step on Helldivers 2’s road to recovery, a road that will keep the game going for years to come.</p><p><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Final Fantasy XVI, Final Fantasy VII Rebirth Heavily Underperformed, as Square Enix Reports Disappointing Profits]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/final-fantasy-xvi-underperformed-disappointing-profits/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/final-fantasy-xvi-final-fantasy-vii-rebirth-heavily-underperformed-as-square-enix-reports-disappointing-profits.984174/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/final-fantasy-xvi-underperformed-disappointing-profits/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Final Fantasy XVI and <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/final-fantasy-vii-rebirth/">Final Fantasy VII Rebirth</a> have heavily underperformed compared to previous entries in the series, further highlighting the flaws of Square Enix console-exclusive's strategy.</p>
<p>In its latest <a href="https://www.hd.square-enix.com/eng/ir/library/pdf/24q4outline.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">financial report</a>, the publisher reports that profits in its HD Games sub-segment for the current fiscal year did not meet expectations despite the release of Final Fantasy XVI and Final Fantasy VII Rebirth. Net sales in the MMO and Games for Smart Devices / PC were also lower than in the previous fiscal year.</p>
<p>Talking specifically about Q4 of the current fiscal year, the report highlights how the two major publisher releases, the initial sales for Foamstars and the already mentioned Final Fantasy VII Rebirth, were not as strong as expected. In addition, an <em>"impairment made to the content production account"</em> resulted in an operating loss.</p>
<p>While Square Enix generally has sometimes unreasonable expectations, it seems like this is one of the rare cases when the publisher is reasonable, as both Final Fantasy XVI and Final Fantasy VII Rebirth really underperformed compared to previous entries in the series, as highlighted by analyst Daniel Ahmad on X.</p>
<blockquote>
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">This is one of the rare cases where Square Enix is being reasonable, as both games really did underperform compared to past entries.</p>
<p>— Daniel Ahmad (@ZhugeEX) <a href="https://twitter.com/ZhugeEX/status/1836334410477527294?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 18, 2024</a></p></blockquote>

<p>It is a real shame that both games have underperformed on the market, as they are both very solid entries in the series. However, things could be turned around by their PC and potential Xbox console release. Final Fantasy XVI has been released this week on PC and seems to be doing well on Steam according to the current Top Sellers list, so hopefully, sales will end up being strong enough for the game not to be considered a commercial failure in the end. You can learn why the game deserves more in terms of sales by checking out Kai's <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/final-fantasy-xvi-the-planets-dyin-clive/">review.</a></p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Helldivers 2 needs higher difficulty level, agrees creative director, following latest buff update]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/helldivers-2-needs-higher-difficulty-level-agrees-creative-director-following-latest-buff-update</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/helldivers-2-needs-higher-difficulty-level-agrees-creative-director-following-latest-buff-update.984171/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/helldivers-2-needs-higher-difficulty-level-agrees-creative-director-following-latest-buff-update<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>Player numbers begin to return.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Helldivers-2-art.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Arrowhead</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p><a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/helldivers-2-review">Helldivers 2</a> yesterday received its latest update that massively buffs player weapons and rebalances the game in their favour.</p>
<p>However, players still aren't completely satisfied and are requesting a new harder difficulty level to compensate. And, creative director and Arrowhead CEO Johan Pilestedt agrees.</p>
<p>A Helldivers 2 fan responded to Pilestedt's call for feedback on X (formerly Twitter), stating: "Everything is great but we need a new harder difficulty now." Pilestedt responded simply: "I agree!"</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Helldivers 2 - Escalation of Freedom Announcement Trailer | PS5 &amp; PC Games" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fcJ2_MfteBw?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Helldivers 2 - Escalation of Freedom Announcement Trailer | PS5 &amp; PC Games</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fcJ2_MfteBw?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/fcJ2_MfteBw?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Helldivers 2 - Escalation of Freedom Announcement Trailer | PS5 &amp; PC Games<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fcJ2_MfteBw" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>As part of re-balancing efforts, many primary weapons have received a damage boost, an increase to their magazine size, or a shorter cooldown, while support weapons and Stratagems have received significant damage boosts.</p>
<p>Further, partial damage dealt to enemies has been increased and <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/helldivers">Helldivers</a> now take less damage from headshots.</p>
<p>"With these changes, along with an upgraded Helldiver arsenal, enemy adjustments, and more consistent damage, the overall difficulty may slightly decrease. We'll be monitoring this closely and will listen to the community on how you think it feels," wrote the developers in the <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/553850/view/7147864422081646859">update's extensive patch notes</a>.</p> <div>
<div data-domain="twitter.com"><blockquote><p dir="ltr" lang="en">Everything is great but we need a new harder difficulty now.</p>— Bunny Asap (@BunnyAsap) <a href="https://twitter.com/BunnyAsap/status/1836081872532541853?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 17, 2024</a></blockquote></div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>The update also brings a new Galactic War feature where strategically important assets are displayed on the map, as well as a new Emote Wheel feature, and other changes and bug fixes.</p>
<p>What's more, the update has brought back a surge in players.</p>
<p>In May, we reported the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/helldivers-2-sees-huge-drop-in-player-numbers-since-release">game's peak concurrent players had taken a significant hit</a> and its average players had dropped by 62 percent.</p>
<p>Yesterday, with the update's release, Helldivers 2 reached a peak of 68,380 players (according to <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/553850/charts/#1m">SteamDB</a>). That's a far cry from its launch days of 458,709 peak concurrent players, but still double the number of players from the last couple of months.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch 2 Alleged First Pictures Showcase Console’s Design, Bigger Screen; Specs Also Leaked Out]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-design-pictures-specs/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-switch-2-alleged-first-pictures-showcase-console%E2%80%99s-design-bigger-screen-specs-also-leaked-out.984168/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-design-pictures-specs/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Thanks to some alleged pictures of factory prototypes, the first look at the&nbsp;<a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-official-name-production/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nintendo Switch 2</a> design may have finally arrived.</p>
<p>The pictures, as reported on the <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GamingLeaksAndRumours/comments/1fjp352/photos_of_switch_2_factory_prototypes_have_leaked/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Gaming Leaks and Rumors subreddit</a>, were shared to an unspecified Discord server by a Chinese user who received them from someone under NDA, possibly a factory worker. Judging from the pictures, the console's design seems to line up with the rumors we have heard so far, as it is bigger than its predecessor, features a bigger screen, and has magnetic side rails for the new Joy-Con controllers.</p>
<p>Together with the pictures allegedly showing the system, the <a href="https://imgur.com/a/Le8OI2i">Nintendo Switch 2 specs</a> were also leaked, and <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GamingLeaksAndRumours/comments/1fjp352/comment/lnpntd5/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">they</a>, too, line up with some of the rumors we have heard in the past few months, such as the 12 GB of LPDDR5X @7500 MT/s RAM and the 256 GB of flash memory. Sadly, no information can currently be gleaned from the SoC model name, but if all these specs are real, we are surely going to hear more about the system's capabilities shortly.</p>
<p>As the pictures and the leaked specs come from an anonymous source, we have to take everything above with the biggest grain of salt, especially as it seems to line up a little too well with the vast majority of Nintendo Switch 2 leaks from the past few months. Thankfully, the console is likely going to be revealed soon, so it won't take much longer to see what Nintendo has been working on for its next-generation system.</p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Skate heelflips into my calendar with an early access release some time in 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/skate-heelflips-into-my-calendar-with-an-early-access-release-some-time-in-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/skate-heelflips-into-my-calendar-with-an-early-access-release-some-time-in-2025.984165/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/skate-heelflips-into-my-calendar-with-an-early-access-release-some-time-in-2025<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
  

        <p>but. still. has. a. dumb. full. stop. after. its. name.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/skate-game-release-date-early-access-2025.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Electronic Arts</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>The upcoming <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/skate">skate</a>. game now has an (admittedly vague) early access release date of 2025, according to <a href="https://x.com/skate/status/1836065157027402235">a post by the developers</a> on Xitter. It's difficult to write about the new skate. game because if you choose to write skate. with the imposed stylings which skate. publishers Electronic Arts insist, you end up putting a full stop after every instance of skate., which makes your sentences about skate. sound fucking stupid. and. belaboured. with. pauses. Game makers, please stop putting punctuation in your game names.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>"we're incredibly stoked to announce that skate. will be launching in Early Access in 2025. we'll share more details on what to expect in the coming months," say developers Full Circle, fully embracing the lower case, except for the words "Early Access". </p>
<p>Punctuation chaos aside, the skateboarding game looks like great fun. The <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/skates-chaotic-playtest-videos-are-the-best-marketing-the-game-could-ask-for">footage we've been shown</a> so far shows wonderful prototype sandboxes, and dozens of skaters bailing off rooftops and sailing down skyscrapers set up like a big human pachinko machine (see below). There's also whole <a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLVjkBnQ2B1pIQWlUDDQLU_2Cnfzv3Cuxu">playlist of full of highlights from testers</a> and some <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Hu0MY53Hz00">excellent bail compilations</a>. Meanwhile the developers have <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EaDU2afjG-w">regular informal chitchats</a> about what's happening in-house. </p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Still Working On It | skate." data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Y2XddTE08rI?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Still Working On It | skate.</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Y2XddTE08rI?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/Y2XddTE08rI?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Y2XddTE08rI" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>That sense of transparency hasn't always been 100% voluntary, mind. A multiplayer version of the game's alpha was <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/a-multiplayer-version-of-the-leaked-skate-4-build-is-out-in-the-wild">leaked online in 2022</a>. But even this doesn't seem that big a deal for a studio who appears to lean into semi-open development. I quite like seeing blockouts of unfinished levels and work-in-progress animations that twist and contort in alien ways. It's a nice reminder that video games don't just appear fully baked. For a long time, they look like hilarious ad-hoc playgrounds made out of cardboard and brightly coloured string. It looks incomplete, yes. But there's something appealing about a level in prototype. Sometimes a sketch can be as pleasing as a finished piece. I once blocked out <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=azxLKXgH8bs">a  construction site</a> for skateboarding sim <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/session">Session</a>. It was basic as hell, but I was happy with my big cubes and simple colours.  </p>
<p>If EA's new game can replicate some of that fun - of building your own skate park - I'll be happy. For now, I have cautious hopes. Session was great for realistic foot physics. And the arcade high-scoring of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/olliolli-world">OlliOlli World</a> gave me <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/olliolli-world-review-so-good-it-will-give-you-blisters">thumb blisters</a>. But the return of this series will hopefully offer a wacky world somewhere between hardcore sim and cartoon kickflipper. The big caveat is that this remains <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/skate-4-is-now-just-skate-and-will-be-free-to-play-with-microtransactions">a free-to-play game by EA with microtransactions</a>, and the live service model is <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/we-should-redefine-live-service-games-as-the-living-dead">not always wholesome</a>. </p>
<p>All that said, I'm not doing "skate." anymore. It's just Skate now. I don't care if that causes people to confuse this new entry with the original Skate from 2007. You should have thought about that when you decided Skate 4 wasn't good enough, EA. I am sticking to the longstanding RPS principle: if your game's name is formatted stupidly, we will either fix it, or make fun of it, or both.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Horizon Zero Dawn Remastered Rated for PS5 and PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/horizon-zero-dawn-remastered-rated-for-ps5-and-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/horizon-zero-dawn-remastered-rated-for-ps5-and-pc.984156/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/horizon-zero-dawn-remastered-rated-for-ps5-and-pc<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>Sony’s stretch of remasters is set to continue with the release of Horizon Zero Dawn Remastered for PlayStation 5 and PC.</p><p>Confirmation comes from an ESRB rating for the unannounced game, which was heavily rumored to be in the works <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/sony-is-pulling-horizon-zero-dawn-from-ps-plus-amid-ps5-remaster-rumors">after Sony pulled Horizon Zero Dawn from PS Plus earlier this year</a>.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3>The Best PS4 Games (Summer 2020 Update)</h3></div></output><p>The rating, <a href="https://www.esrb.org/ratings/40023/horizon-zero-dawn-remastered/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">still live at the time of this article’s publication</a>, reads:</p><blockquote>This is an action/role-playing game in which players assume the role of a hunter (Aloy) surviving through a post-apocalyptic world. Players guide Aloy as she learns to hunt robotic creatures and animals in the wild. Aloy uses arrows, spears, and explosive traps to injure and kill machines, boar, and occasional human enemies. Animals and humans emit small puffs of red blood when struck; one sequence depicts an abandoned camp with large blood stains on rocks and trees. The game contains a brief reference to sexual material (e.g., “Eighteen months hard labor in exchange for thirty years lounging around Elysium watching porn?”). In text/audio files, characters sometimes reference fictional drugs, overdoses, and getting high: “...not even out of junior high and already a drug addict”; “...I ran across a pusher who was selling Razorwing for eight bucks a tab”; "I'd spend a few days getting high, then OD on Overcast." The word “sh*t” appears in the text/dialogue.</blockquote><p><a href="https://www.ign.com/games/horizon-zero-dawn">Horizon Zero Dawn</a> is Guerrilla Games’ action role-playing game that launched in 2017 on PlayStation 4 and then on PC in 2020. It stars Aloy who battles dinosaur machines in a post-apocalyptic world. Horizon Zero Dawn is one of the best-selling PlayStation Studios games of all time, shifting over 24 million units since launch.</p><p>This remaster is sure to spark a vociferous debate about whether it’s needed in the first place, not just because Horizon Zero Dawn remains one of the most impressive-looking PlayStation games around, but because <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/horizon-zero-dawn-60-fps-patch-ps5">it received a PS5 update</a> in 2021 that added a 60 frames per second mode and 4K checkerboard resolution. Word of the remaster’s imminent release comes ahead of the launch of the <a href="https://www.ign.com/tech/playstation-5-pro">PS5 Pro</a> in November. Guerrilla may be updating Horizon Zero Dawn as part of that console’s release.</p><p>It's a busy time for the Horizon series. Spin-off <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/lego-horizon-adventures">LEGO Horizon Adventures</a> launches later this year, and Guerrilla is still working on a <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/horizon-multiplayer-game-confirmed-by-guerrilla">multiplayer Horizon game</a>.</p><p><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Report: Behaviour Interactive shutters Midwinter Entertainment after scrapping Dead by Daylight spinoff]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/report-behaviour-interactive-shutters-midwinter-entertainment-after-scrapping-dead-by-daylight-spinoff</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/report-behaviour-interactive-shutters-midwinter-entertainment-after-scrapping-dead-by-daylight-spinoff.984153/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/report-behaviour-interactive-shutters-midwinter-entertainment-after-scrapping-dead-by-daylight-spinoff<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Midwinter Entertainment, the Behaviour Interactive subsidiary behind Dead by Daylight spinoff Project T, has reportedly been shuttered.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://x.com/Behaviour/status/1836103012575781262/photo/1">In a statement shared yesterday</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, Behaviour confirmed Project T has been cancelled following a playtest and analysis that "yielded unsatisfactory results."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Now, multiple people who worked on Project T claim Midwinter has been shut down as a result of the cancellation.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Sadly, after nearly seven years my time with Midwinter Entertainment has come to an abrupt end due to the studio closure," </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/dansalexander_sadly-after-nearly-7-years-my-time-with-activity-7241896961732182017-D77M/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=member_desktop">wrote one former Midwinter developer on LinkedIn</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. "Midwinter has been an amazing place to work, with a group of amazingly talented, wonderful people."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Another person who </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:7241867580527804417/">provided audio support on Project T</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> explained that "after four years the studio I have been working with on multiple titles shut down." They subsequently named Midwinter and called it a "great place to work."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Notably, they also challenged Behaviour's assessment of Project T. "One of the crazy things is that in the most recent playtest we got a 92/100 score in fun and playability–and it is being sold that the game was not liked by the players," they added.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Behaviour's statement doesn't mention Midwinter but acknowledges a "number of players expressed appreciation for what they played." Despite that positive feedback, Behaviour noted concerns about the title's "commercial perspective."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">This wouldn't be the first time Behaviour has cut jobs in 2024. The company </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/report-dead-by-daylight-developer-behaviour-laying-off-staff-in-montreal">laid off under 3 percent of its workforce in January</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> before </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/behaviour-interactive-cuts-95-jobs-in-strategic-corporate-change-">making 95 people redundant in June</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Behaviour attributed those cuts to the need for a "strategic corporate change" that would allow it to focus on its "historical strengths." The publisher recently released </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>The Casting of Frank Stone</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, an interactive horror title from Supermassive Games set in the world of Dead by Daylight. It's unclear how well it has performed.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer has reached out to Behaviour for comment.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">News Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer news editor Chris Kerr is an award-winning journalist and reporter with over a decade of experience in the game industry. His byline has appeared in notable print and digital publications including Edge, Stuff, Wireframe, International Business Times, and&nbsp;</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="http://pocketgamer.biz/">PocketGamer.biz</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. Throughout his career, Chris has covered major industry events including GDC, PAX Australia, Gamescom, Paris Games Week, and Develop Brighton. He has featured on the judging panel at The Develop Star Awards on multiple occasions and appeared on BBC Radio 5 Live to discuss breaking news.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Square Enix admits Final Fantasy 7 Rebirth and Final Fantasy 16 profits "did not meet expectations"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/square-enix-admits-final-fantasy-7-rebirth-and-final-fantasy-16-profits-did-not-meet-expectations</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/square-enix-admits-final-fantasy-7-rebirth-and-final-fantasy-16-profits-did-not-meet-expectations.984150/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/square-enix-admits-final-fantasy-7-rebirth-and-final-fantasy-16-profits-did-not-meet-expectations<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>Multiplatform strategy seemingly underway.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/ff7-rebirth-aerith-rubbing-her-head.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Eurogamer/Square Enix</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p><a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/companies/square-enix">Square Enix</a> has admitted that profits of <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/final-fantasy-7-rebirth-guides-tips-tricks-9403">Final Fantasy 7 Rebirth</a> and <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/final-fantasy-xvi">Final Fantasy 16</a> "did not meet expectations".</p>
<p>The comment comes from its <a href="https://www.hd.square-enix.com/eng/ir/library/explanatory.html">financial results briefing</a> held in May and finally made public today.</p>
<p>Square Enix president Takashi Kiryu shared the results, stating: "In the HD Games sub-segment, we released multiple new titles, including major titles such as Final Fantasy 16 and Final Fantasy 7 Rebirth, but profits unfortunately did not meet our expectations."</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="FINAL FANTASY XVI “DELIVERANCE” - PC Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/zxPT1sQIPfA?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>FINAL FANTASY XVI “DELIVERANCE” - PC Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/zxPT1sQIPfA?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/zxPT1sQIPfA?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Final Fantasy 16 "Deliverance" - PC trailer<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zxPT1sQIPfA" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>Further, he stated initial sales of Foamstars and Final Fantasy 7 Rebirth - released in Q4 of the last financial year - were "not as strong as expected".</p>
<p>It's important to note these comments were made in May, at the same time Square Enix announced it was <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/square-enix-aggressively-pursuing-new-multiplatform-strategy-after-reports-ff7-rebirth-underperformed-on-playstation">"aggressively pursuing" a multiplatform strategy</a>. Shortly after, reports it <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/square-enix-impacted-by-unknown-number-of-layoffs-across-us-and-european-offices">laid off a number of employees in its US and European offices</a> emerged.</p>
<p>At this point in time, Final Fantasy 16 had been out for a year and Final Fantasy 7 Rebirth less than three months.</p>
<p>Still, there has been much speculation around the sales of Final Fantasy 7 Rebirth and its <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/final-fantasy-7-rebirth-is-underperforming-says-industry-analyst">reported underperformance according to industry analysts</a>.</p>
<p>Sales tracking from Circana previously stated <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/final-fantasy-7-rebirth-fourth-top-selling-game-in-the-us-this-year-but-reportedly-remains-far-behind-remake">Final Fantasy 7 Rebirth is the fourth top-selling game in the US</a>, but remains far behind sales of previous entry <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/final-fantasy-7-remake-review-a-faithful-remake-with-a-few-missteps-along-the-way">Final Fantasy 7 Remake</a>.</p>
<p>The release of Kiryu's statement today, then, is the first official acknowledgement of the game's sales. Still, it's unclear by how much the game "underperformed" and Square Enix is notorious for its high expectations.</p>
<p>Much has also happened since this financial report. Firstly, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/final-fantasy-14-dawntrail-review">Final Fantasy 14 expansion Dawntrail</a> was released in July, which will likely have had a positive impact on overall company profits. We'll find out in the next financial briefing.</p>
<p>Secondly, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/final-fantasy-16-producer-doesnt-want-offensive-or-inappropriate-mods-on-pc-release">Final Fantasy 16 was released yesterday on PC</a>, continuing the company's push towards multiplatform releases.</p>
<p>And while Final Fantasy 7 Rebirth remains a PS5 console-exclusive for now, it's likely it will follow Final Fantasy 7 Remake with a PC release in future.</p>
<p>Could these games also come to Xbox? Final Fantasy 14 producer and director <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/square-enix-to-further-deepen-the-relationship-with-xbox-gamers-says-final-fantasy-14s-naoki-yoshida">Naoki Yoshida told Eurogamer</a> the company would like to "further deepen the relationship with Xbox gamers" following the release of the MMORPG on Microsoft's console.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Demon’s Mirror Review – Puzzle Quest matched with Slay the Spire]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/09/18/demons-mirror-review-puzzle-quest-meets-slay-the-spire/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/demon%E2%80%99s-mirror-review-%E2%80%93-puzzle-quest-matched-with-slay-the-spire.984135/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/09/18/demons-mirror-review-puzzle-quest-meets-slay-the-spire/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="gp-content-wrapper">

	<article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/Article">

		<meta itemprop="mainEntityOfPage" itemtype="https://schema.org/WebPage" itemscope="" content="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/09/18/demons-mirror-review-puzzle-quest-meets-slay-the-spire/">
		<meta itemprop="headline" content="Demon’s Mirror Review – Puzzle Quest matched with Slay the Spire">			
		
		<meta itemprop="author" content="Jason Coles">			
		<meta itemprop="datePublished" content="2024-09-18">
		<meta itemprop="dateModified" content="2024-09-18">
		
		
			
		
								
		
			

																		
		<div itemprop="text">
			
			<p>The deckbuilding roguelike genre has been solved at this point. I don’t mean that in a bad way; it’s just that we’ve had a lot of takes on it since Slay the Spire really boosted the genre into the stratosphere. Demon’s Mirror, then, has a fairly large obstacle to overcome, because how do you stand out when there are already so many options to choose from? It turns out the answer is by also throwing in a match-3 game.</p>
<p><iframe title="Demon's Mirror - Launch Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/cmwM3g188q8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>It takes a little bit of time to adjust to the way that Demon’s Mirror does things, and it initially feels as though the card game and the puzzle game are essentially separate. The only thing that appears to connect them is that a couple of your cards can interact with the board, and that everything costs energy, which means you need to decide if you’re better off matching a bunch of tiles to attack, get energy, get armour, or get willpower, or if you should use a card to do one of those same things or something else.</p>


<p>However, as you get to grips with not only the three characters available, but also the core mechanics each of them has, and then start properly building around them, everything starts to mesh together to make for a smoother experience. My favourite character of the three is one who can apply a unique status effect called influence, which basically represents them talking to the enemies you’re fighting, and if you can apply more influence than they have health remaining, they get taken out of the fight.</p>


<p>Despite being my favourite, this was also the character I had the hardest time finishing the game with. I could see an incredibly cool build in there based on skill cards that cost 0 energy, a card that applied influence X amount of times (where X was the number of skill cards you’d played), and a card that allowed you to put any 0 energy cards back into your hand from your discard pile if you matched green tiles. I then just needed the right relics, which ended up being ones that could reduce the cost of green tile chains, and a couple of others that let you match for free if you played enough cards.</p>
<p>Once I had this working, it took maybe four runs for everything to properly coalesce in both my head and my hand, until I suddenly had a build that actually beat everything within the first two turns. I just needed to keep thinning out my deck until the combo was guaranteed, and then just play a lot of cards to draw more cards and keep doing so for free, until the card that allows you to inflict three influence for each skill card would hit upwards of 200 in total.</p>

<p>The reason I spent two paragraphs detailing that one specific combo is because Demon’s Mirror is full to the brim with different builds to explore and combinations to mess around with, and you can make the game harder or easier with special modifiers you unlock, as well. There’s not as much to do here as there is in some other examples of the genre, but what is here is a delight.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

			
		</div>

		
				
	<div id="gp-summary">
		<p>Summary</p><p>
		Demon's Mirror is a wonderfully refreshing take on the whole deckbuilding genre, and well worth a look if you want something that genuinely feels new. If you've never played one of these before, however, then it's probably going to feel pretty tough to begin with, but it'll be worth it.	</p></div>
		

	<div id="gp-review-results">

									<div id="gp-good-points">
						<p>Good</p>
						<ul>
														
								<li><i></i>Wonderfully satisfying mechanics</li>
														
								<li><i></i>Great build potential</li>
														
								<li><i></i>Unique concept</li>
													</ul>
					</div>
				
									<div id="gp-bad-points">
						<p>Bad</p>
						<ul>
														
								<li><i></i>Tough to wrap your head around to begin with</li>
														
								<li><i></i>Feels short for a roguelike</li>
													</ul>
					</div>
							
			</div>

					
	
						
			
			

			
						
		<div>

			<h3>Related stories from TSA			
			</h3>
			
				
				
		</div>

	
		
					
 
	
	
				
	</article>

</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[There shall be no Sims 5, you insolent fools, only a Sims universe]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/there-shall-be-no-sims-5-you-insolent-fools-only-a-sims-universe</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/there-shall-be-no-sims-5-you-insolent-fools-only-a-sims-universe.984132/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/there-shall-be-no-sims-5-you-insolent-fools-only-a-sims-universe<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

        <p>A universe that includes a film and Project Rene, which is sort of Sims 5, maybe</p>

    </div><div>



            <p>
People waiting impatiently for <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/the-sims-5">The Sims 5</a>: you have sinned against Simming and must do penance. In your temerity and ignorance, you have cried out unto developers Maxis and publisher EA for another sequential helping of the cuddly/sociopathic neighbourhood-building game - a "sequel", if you will. Know ye not that we live in the time of Disrupted Models? Sequels are archaisms devised by the old gods in their dotage. Let us all join hands and set forth into the sunny uplands of the Connected Cross-Media Cross-Platform Universe.
</p><!--more-->
<p>
"The Sims will move beyond linear, sequential Sims releases and offer more options for players than ever before," explains <a href="https://www.ea.com/en-gb/games/the-sims/news/the-future-of-the-sims">an EA blog post about the future of the series</a>, published yesterday. "We're focused on creating a variety of games and experiences that will touch different categories across the simulated life genre including cozy games, social and collaborative based gameplay, mobile narrative games and continued depth, improvements, and modernization of The Sims 4, which will continue to be a foundational Sims experience."
</p>
<p>
Speaking to <a href="https://variety.com/2024/gaming/news/the-sims-5-update-multiplayer-creator-content-ea-interview-1236142010/">Variety</a> (ta <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-sims-5-not-happening-as-ea-moves-beyond-linear-sequential-sims-releases">Eurogamer</a>), The Sims franchise general manager Kate Gorman explained the thinking in slightly more detail. "The way to think about it is, historically, The Sims franchise started with Sims 1 and then Sims 2, 3, and 4," she began, in a useful refresher for those of us still wrestling with the whole "sequel" concept. "And they were seen as replacements for the previous products. [But now,] we are not going to be working on replacements of previous projects; we're only going to be adding to our universe." 
</p>
<p>
But what could this mean??? "What this means is that we will continue to bring HD simulation experience and what people would want from a 5," Gorman continued, "but it doesn't mean that we're going to start you over... As we think about the future of it, we want you to continue all of those families and generations. Those creations are your progress, your attachment. 
</p>
<p>
"We don't want to reset your progress. And so it's not about... what the numbers are in the games, but know that the future of the franchise looks more like keeping your progress, keeping things across titles, and really having an ongoing experience, and not a start-and-stop experience between products." 
</p>
<p>
Beyond this point, the brain of the writer buckles and cannot reassemble the majesty of EA's vision into cogent paragraphs. I am forced to resort to the simplified, World War-era medium of bulletpoints. Here's roughly what the Sims universe will encompass, based on the blog post and the interview above.
</p>
<p>
- The mysterious Project Rene, which "is focused on building ways for friends to meet, connect, and share while playing together in an all-new world". There's a small invite-only playtest happening later this year, which will give "an early look at a multiplayer experience that explores joining friends and other players at a shared location". I guess this could be something approximating a "Sims 5", if you're desperate. EA have previously said that <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-next-sims-game-will-be-free-to-play-with-paid-dlc">Project Rene would co-exist with The Sims 4</a>, and would be a free-to-play game with DLC and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-sims-5-devs-definitely-want-to-have-multiplayer-are-looking-at-animal-crossing-for-inspiration">multiplayer inspired by Animal Crossing</a><a></a>
</p>
<p>
- a Hollywood movie adaptation in partnership with Amazon MGM Studios, with Loki director Kate Herron directing and Dr Who scribe Briony Redman on the writing team. I think Margot Robbie is involved somehow. Make it like the Barbie film, please
</p>
<p>
- Continuing to improve and maintain The Sims 4, a venerable but very popular game. EA are "investing in meaningful new features and base game updates", so as "to evolve the game in both appearance and gameplay experience"
</p>
<p>
- expanding The Sims FreePlay, a mobile game spin-off, while developing another mobile experience or game, Project Stories
</p>
<p>
- "Reinvigorating the MySims product line, beginning with two lovable games available soon on Nintendo Switch", Nintendo's charming cut-price Steam Deck - the games in question are MySims and MySims Kingdom, which together form the MySims: Cozy Bundle. It burns, it burns!
</p>
<p>
- A set of creator tools, a player content gallery, a marketplace, and a social network, to be shared across Sims games
</p>
<p>EA <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/project-rene-aka-the-sims-5-shows-prototype-lighting-animation-routines-in-latest-video">revealed some strictly WIP footage of Project Rene last year</a>, with prototypes of daily routines around the neighbourhood and new animations for moods and reactions. I've popped a screenshot from one of those prototypes at the top of the page, there. Again, it does <em>sort</em> of feel like Project Rene will be something approximating a traditional Sims sequel, but I reckon I'll be struck by righteous lightning if I spell that out too avidly.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[More SNES games arrive on Nintendo Switch]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/more-snes-games-arrive-on-nintendo-switch</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/more-snes-games-arrive-on-nintendo-switch.984129/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/more-snes-games-arrive-on-nintendo-switch<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>Battletoads! Dodgeball! Big Run!</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Play-Battletoads-Double-Dragon-and-more-with-Nintendo-Switch-Online!-0-11-screenshot.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Nintendo</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>Four more SNES games have arrived on Switch for Nintendo Switch Online subscribers.</p>
<p>Once again, though, Japanese subscribers have received different releases to America, UK, and Europe.</p>
<p>The four SNES games available on Nintendo Switch Online from today are:</p>
<ul>
<li>Battletoads Double Dragon</li>
<li>Kunio-kun no Dodgeball da yo Zen'in Shūgō!</li>
<li>Cosmo Gang The Puzzle</li>
<li>Big Run</li>
</ul>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Play Battletoads Double Dragon and more with Nintendo Switch Online!" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/M3ZHNzTEtFM?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Play Battletoads Double Dragon and more with Nintendo Switch Online!</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/M3ZHNzTEtFM?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/M3ZHNzTEtFM?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Play Battletoads Double Dragon and more with Nintendo Switch Online!<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=M3ZHNzTEtFM" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5obF4u-2qc0">Japanese subscribers</a> will receive the latter two and, in addition, Neo Romance game Angelique - the first in the series, released in 1994.</p>
<p>Battletoads Double Dragon sees the muscular toads joining forces with the warriors from Double Dragon in another beat 'em up. Big Run is a rally racing game, Cosmo Gang The Puzzle is a falling-block puzzle game (better known here as Pac-Attack), and Kunio-kun no Dodgeball da yo Zen'in Shūgō! is a dodgeball sports game.</p>
<p>You can see gameplay of all four games in the above video.</p>
<p>Check out our <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/all-nintendo-switch-online-games-available-to-play-right-now">full list of all games available on Nintendo Switch Online</a> to see what other SNES games are available, including classics like <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/legend-zelda-link-to-past">A Link to the Past</a>, Super Metroid, and Super Mario World.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fairy Tail 2 Interview With Producer Hiroshi Kataoka – Discussing the Series, New Combat System, Additional Content]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/fairy-tail-2-interview-with-producer-hiroshi-kataoka-discussing-the-series-new-combat-system-additional-content/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fairy-tail-2-interview-with-producer-hiroshi-kataoka-%E2%80%93-discussing-the-series-new-combat-system-additional-content.984123/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/fairy-tail-2-interview-with-producer-hiroshi-kataoka-discussing-the-series-new-combat-system-additional-content/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>In many ways, the announcement of Fairy Tail 2 was an unexpected but welcome surprise. While there's no denying the popularity of the series by Hiro Mashima, Koei Tecmo and Gust gave no indication that the franchise would continue to bring a close to the original manga's storyline.</p><div>
<p>During Gamescom 2024, I had the chance to try out the game before its <a href="https://wccftech.com/fairy-tail-2-december/">December release</a> and speak with Producer Hiroshi Kataoka, discussing the setting, characters, battle system, future content, and more. Enjoy!</p>
<p><em>The interview was conducted via an interpreter and has been edited for clarity.</em></p>
<p><strong>The original Fairy Tail was almost universally praised for being a very good adaptation of the manga by Hiro Mashima, but many found it difficult to keep up with the story and characters without any prior knowledge. Is there anything in the new game that addresses this issue?</strong></p>
<p>We have a few systems in place to address this issue. For starters, at the beginning of the game, there's an event that is specifically focused on looking back at the past story. We also implemented a glossary in the main menu, which allows players to check terminology as well as learn more about characters and their past, so it's easy to learn what happened before the Alvarez Empire Arc. During dialogues, there are also words highlighted in yellow, which can take the player straight to the glossary, even during gameplay. So, to enjoy Fairy Tail 2, it's not necessary to play the original.</p>
<p><strong>Fairy Tail 2 features an all-new original story called Key to the Unknown, set after the events of the Alvarez Empire Arc and the original story. Is there more original story besides this new epilogue?</strong></p>
<p>There is more original story, but it's not a lot, and it's mostly found in sidequests and optional content. Fairy Tail 2 is all about respecting the original IP, and we didn't want to break the flow of the original narrative. When it comes to the original story we added, including the epilogue, Mashima-sensei checked everything, so players and fans can look forward to it.</p>
<p><strong>One of the biggest changes featured in Fairy Tail 2 over the original is the battle system. Why go from a classic turn-based system to the new real-time one?</strong></p>
<p>There are a few reasons for the change. The first game featured a turn-based battle system to help newcomers to the genre and let them have fun right away, but its slow pace wouldn't have been suitable for what happens in the second game. The Alvarez Empire arc, which is the last arc of the original manga, features a lot of combat against some very powerful enemies, and I felt that a faster, more action-based combat system was better suited to properly adapt these battles. Being the final battle, it just had to be faster.</p>
<p><strong>Many role-playing game series are moving away from turn-based combat and employing more action-oriented systems. Do you think there's still a market for classic turn-based games?</strong></p>
<p>I don't think the market is shifting towards one or the other. It all depends on what kind of battles someone wants to have in their games. You can do interesting things with both turn-based and action-focused combat systems. Personally, I still find turn-based combat fun, but for Fairy Tail 2, I felt that an action-oriented combat system would have been best. It really depends on the game.</p>
<p><strong>Are there multiple difficulty settings?</strong></p>
<p>Fairy Tail 2 features multiple difficulty settings. We have an easy mode for beginners to enjoy the story, but we also have more battle-focused difficulties for those who find the other difficulties too easy. There's a total of four settings, so it's not either easy mode or normal mode.</p>
<p><strong>Fairy Tail features a lot of characters. How did you pick the playable characters? Are more coming after release?</strong></p>
<p>The playable characters were picked based on their role in the final battle against the Alvarez Empire. We picked those involved in the battle in the original story. There will be some additional characters coming after launch, but we can't specifically say who is coming right now.</p>
<p><strong>Speaking about additional content, will there be more story added to the game after release?</strong></p>
<p>We will release additional free and paid content after the release. We're still deciding what to release specifically, but I can confirm that more content is coming.</p>
<p><strong>Looking ahead, will the Fairy Tail series continue? If so, would a new entry in the series feature an all-original story, or will it adapt the 100 Years Quest story?</strong></p>
<p>There's definitely the chance of more Fairy Tail in the future, but right now, it's hard to say if there's going to be another entry in the series and if it will adapt the new story or feature original content. It all depends on how Fairy Tail 2 is received. If players want more sequels, we will consider developing them and speak with Kodansha, who holds the IP, on how to proceed. So, there's definitely a possibility.</p>
<p><strong>If you could adapt any other manga series, which would it be?</strong></p>
<p>I like old manga series, and I would love to adapt some works from Leiji Matsumoto. I really like Space Battleship Yamato, and I would love to make a game based on it.</p>
<p><strong>Thank you for your time!</strong></p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EA CEO Says Generative AI Is the Very Core of Business, Not a Buzzword]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/ea-ceo-says-generative-ai-is-the-very-core-of-business-not-a-buzzword/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ea-ceo-says-generative-ai-is-the-very-core-of-business-not-a-buzzword.984120/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/ea-ceo-says-generative-ai-is-the-very-core-of-business-not-a-buzzword/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>During the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hsvX8NMGUxI" target="_blank" rel="noopener">EA Investor Day</a>, which also saw the <a href="https://wccftech.com/star-wars-jedi-series-to-get-final-chapter-of-the-trilogy/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">confirmation</a> of the third installment in the Star Wars Jedi series, Electronic Arts CEO Andrew Wilson outlined the core importance of generative AI for the company's future. Following up on <a href="https://wccftech.com/generative-ai-will-allow-bigger-more-immersive-worlds-says-ea-and-developers-were-hungry-for-it/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">his previous statement</a> that generative AI will allow bigger and more immersive worlds, Wilson explained how EA is using this technology for its upcoming projects as part of its bid to outpace market growth through 2027 and double the audience to over a billion users.</p>
<p><em>AI in its different forms has always been central to this creative journey. We all remember playing against the AI, and it has evolved into today's innovations in generative AI. This remarkable technology is not merely a buzzword for us; it's the very core of our business. Beyond writing or coding AI to ensure the believability of our characters, we have always used forms of machine learning and AI across our games and processes. Right now, we have over 100 active novel AI projects across three strategic categories: efficiency, expansion, and transformation.</em></p>
<p><em>Let me first talk about efficiency. This does not just mean cost savings today. Efficiency is doing what we do today faster, cheaper, and at a higher quality. That means driving more iterations, more testing and high quality content for our communities. It means removing obstacles for our game developers. It means culturalizing content across geographies so they can focus on finding more fun for more players around the world. The lowering of these friction points leads to deeper gameplay experiences.</em></p>
<p><em>Expansion is about giving our creative teams an exponentially bigger canvas upon which to create and richer colors so they might paint more brilliant worlds. It's about our incredible teams creating characters with more depth and intelligence, telling stories that are more personal and nuanced, and bringing more authenticity and deeper immersion. For years, we at EA have talked about our games delivering experiences that are always new and different. We predict that with generative AI, we will truly be able to fulfill this promise for billions of people and billions of hours.</em></p>
<p><em>Transformation is about looking much farther into the future and finding new ways to play, watch, create, and connect that aren't imagined today. We believe AI will greatly expand and transform the entertainment experience for user generated content. It will accelerate how innovators and creators in entertainment are building and delivering experiences rooted in self-expression, content creation, curation, and instant gratification, the kind of entertainment that today's players and fans deeply crave.</em></p>
<p>Bold words indeed from the EA CEO, although Electronic Arts is not at all the only big company to believe in generative AI's potential to disrupt the gaming industry. Microsoft, for instance, partnered with <a href="https://wccftech.com/the-big-inworld-ai-qa-everyone-in-gaming-sees-the-potential-of-generative-ai/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Inworld AI</a> to create a <a href="https://wccftech.com/xbox-partners-with-inworld-ai-to-empower-game-creators-through-generative-ai/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">multiplatform AI-powered toolset for game developers</a>. Ubisoft also <a href="https://wccftech.com/inworld-ai-blows-up-at-gdc-2024-between-ubisofts-neo-npcs-xboxs-narrative-graph-tool-and-more/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">showed</a> off an interesting demo at GDC 2024 powered by Inworld AI tech.</p>
<p>Electronic Arts appears to be developing an in-house solution rather than relying on a third party. Either way, we might be looking at an influx of games featuring some sort of generative AI implementation in the next few years.</p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Final Fantasy XVI’s wobbly Steam Deck performance gets it a failing grade from Valve]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/final-fantasy-xvis-wobbly-steam-deck-performance-gets-it-a-failing-grade-from-valve</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/final-fantasy-xvi%E2%80%99s-wobbly-steam-deck-performance-gets-it-a-failing-grade-from-valve.984117/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/final-fantasy-xvis-wobbly-steam-deck-performance-gets-it-a-failing-grade-from-valve<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Final-Fantasy-XVI-Steam-Deck.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Rock Paper Shotgun</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>Having gone to bed last night with <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/final-fantasy-xvi">Final Fantasy XVI</a> installed yet unplayed on a <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-steam-deck-games">Steam Deck</a>, I awoke to find Valve have slapped the moody <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-rpgs">RPG</a> with Unsupported status for the handheld. Its crime: an inability to "run well" on the Steam Deck’s internals, regardless of settings changes. Dammit, Clive.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>I’ve given it a whirl myself this morning, and while a literal interpretation of "unsupported" arguably doesn’t apply to FFXVI – the Steam Deck can still launch and run it without detonating in one’s hands – it does ask a little too much of the hardware. The Low quality preset and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/amd-fsr-3-demystified-how-the-next-gen-upscaler-could-upgrade-performance-on-any-gpu">FSR 3</a> on Ultra Performance is enough to keep me above 30fps in plenty of fights, but other areas will easily knock that down into the 20-25fps range, or even into the teens. Which ain’t particularly nice to play, even if you are still technically playing. FSR 3 can provide frame gen as well as upscaling, but this manages to make things worse, introducing heavy stuttering in exchange for only a tiny handful of extra generated frames.</p>
<p>(Strangely, nothing performs worse than the cutscenes, which I’ve repeatedly seen collapse to around the 17-20fps region for no clearly apparent reason. Though at least this pre-empts any potential annoyance about them also being capped at 30fps on PC.)</p>
<p>Also, and this isn’t part of Valve’s Steam Deck verification criteria but I can and will moan about it anyway: it’s a 152GB install. 152GB! So even if you decide the tough out the framerate dips, FFXVI is going to devour the lion’s share of any <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/how-to-install-ssd-steam-deck">Steam Deck SSD</a> or <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-microsd-cards-for-steam-deck">microSD card</a>. 152GB, honestly. You could fit twelve copies of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/dark-souls-ii">Dark Souls II</a> in that. Or six <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/metal-gear-rising-revengeance">Metal Gear Risings</a>.</p>
<p>Incidentally, after <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/warhammer-40000-space-marine-2-pc-performance-best-settings">Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine 2</a>, this makes it two Big Budget Action Games Where You Play a Grumpy Man With a Sword in a row that fall just short on Steam Deck performance. As for how Final Fantasy XVI’s new PC port takes to more traditional PC hardware, I’m currently locked in the benchmark dungeon trying to find out, though I suspect you won’t want to take your chances with anything below the minimum requirements of a RX 5700 or GTX 1070.</p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Announces 4 SNES Games for Switch Online Library]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-announces-4-snes-games-for-switch-online-library</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-announces-4-snes-games-for-switch-online-library.984114/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-announces-4-snes-games-for-switch-online-library<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Including Battletoads Double Dragon.</h2></div><section><p>Nintendo has announced four Super NES games from the early ‘90s are now live via the Nintendo Switch Online library.</p><p>First up, we have Battletoads Double Dragon, a crossover beat-’em-up developed by legendary studio Rare and released in 1993. Here’s the official blurb, from Nintendo:</p><blockquote>The warriors from Double Dragon join forces with the toad-acious Battletoads trio to form the ultimate team in this 1993 beat-’em-up! Tussle with terrific twins Billy and Jimmy Lee as they team up with Zitz, Rash and Pimple to defend the Earth against the combined might of the Dark Queen and the Shadow Boss! Leap from the Battlecopter onto the tail of the Colossus spaceship and fight your way through beastly baddies and lethal objects using the Battletoads’ arsenal of Smash Hits or the Dragons’ array of Dragon Force Techniques – each provides incredible attacking combos, including kicks, punches, throws and more! You’ll also put your driving skills to the test with the Speeder Bike and high-speed Space Pod. How will this struggle for Earth’s future end?</blockquote><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/09/18/unnamed-4-1726648535968.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption>Battletoads Double Dragon.</figcaption></figure></output><p>Next, we have Jaleco’s Big Run, a racing game originally released for the Super Famicom in 1991. Check out what the game is about, per Nintendo:</p><blockquote>Race across the vast landscape of Africa – from Tripoli to Dakar – over the course of nine stages in this racing game originally released for the Super Famicom system in 1991. This monumental task isn’t only about putting pedal to the metal, though! First, you’ll need to select a sponsor and then use those funds to hire staff. Next, you’ll need some spare parts to replace tires and engines when they get damaged or worn out. The glory of victory awaits if you can combine precise tactics and bold driving to weather the brutal driving conditions that stand between you and your goal.</blockquote><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/09/18/unnamed-5-1726648565847.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption>Big Run.</figcaption></figure></output><p>Cosmo Gang the Puzzle is a 1993 action puzzle game developed by Namco and originally released for the Super Famicom.</p><blockquote>The Cosmo Gang take on falling-block-style puzzles across three modes in this 1993 action-puzzle game that was originally for Super Famicom. Focus on clearing blocks to get the high score in 1P Mode, play competitive battles in VS Mode and put yourself to the test in 100 Stage Mode, where you can solve stage after stage of strategic challenges. In each of the modes, progress is made by removing containers and Cosmos that fall from the top of the screen. You can remove the containers by lining six up in a horizontal row — and Cosmos are removed when they touch the blue orbs that occasionally make their way down. Though the two types of blocks are cleared in different ways, try to see if you can perform a combo by clearing both types at once!</blockquote><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/09/18/unnamed-6-1726648607092.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption>Cosmo Gang the Puzzle.</figcaption></figure></output><p>And finally, Technōs Japan’s sports game Kunio-kun no Dodgeball da yo Zen'in Shūgō!, which came out on the Super Famicom in 1993, is available. The Kunio-kun series, known as River City outside Japan, is now in the hands of Guilty Gear developer Arc System Works, with recent revivals from WayForward.</p><blockquote>This sports game, released for the Super Famicom system in 1993, features Kunio-kun (who you may recognize from the River City series!) and his striking dodgeball moves. Take the field and square off against teams from various countries and employ a variety of jumps, passes and dynamic knockout shots as you aim to become the greatest dodgeball team in the world. Plus, each stage has hidden gimmicks to discover, so your matches may even take some unexpected turns! Build your ideal team, power up with in-game items and train your teammates to be the best they can be. Can you take the dodgeball championship by storm?</blockquote><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/09/18/unnamed-7-1726648723391.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption>Kunio-kun no Dodgeball da yo Zen'in Shūgō!.</figcaption></figure></output><h2>Super NES – Nintendo Switch Online library additions for September 2024:</h2><ul data-cy="list"><li><a href="https://www.ign.com/games/battletoads-double-dragon-the-ultimate-team">Battletoads Double Dragon</a></li><li>Big Run</li><li><a href="https://www.ign.com/games/cosmo-gang-the-puzzle">Cosmo Gang the Puzzle</a></li><li><a href="https://www.ign.com/games/nekketsu-kunio-kuns-dodgeball">Kunio-kun no Dodgeball da yo Zen'in Shūgō!</a></li></ul><p>All four games are now part of the Super NES – Nintendo Switch Online library, and are available for all Nintendo Switch Online members to play today.</p><p><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EA desperately wants investors to know it's on the generative AI bandwagon]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ea-desperately-wants-investors-to-know-it-s-on-the-generative-ai-bandwagon</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ea-desperately-wants-investors-to-know-its-on-the-generative-ai-bandwagon.984108/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ea-desperately-wants-investors-to-know-it-s-on-the-generative-ai-bandwagon<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">EA really wants people to know it's truly, madly, deeply invested in generative AI.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Taking the stage during the company's recent investor day, EA CEO Andrew Wilson spoke about how the technology is driving innovation within EA studios and said it has become "the very core of our business."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Wilson previously claimed 60 percent of EA's development processes </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/production/ea-ceo-60-percent-of-dev-processes-could-be-impacted-by-generative-ai-">could be "impacted" by generative AI</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, and said the technology is something the publisher is "embracing deeply." </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ea-will-spend-over-125-million-laying-off-5-percent-of-its-workforce">Those remarks came shortly after EA laid off 5 percent of its workforce</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Doubling down on that narrative, Wilson said AI isn't a "buzzword" for EA and noted the company currently has over "100 novel AI projects" in development across three categories: efficiency, expansion, and transformation.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Discussing the former, Wilson said efficiency isn't just about delivering "cost savings," but rather "doing what we do today faster, cheaper, and at a higher quality."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"That means driving more iterations, more testing and high quality content for our communities. It means removing obstacles for our game developers," he added. "It means culturalizing content across geographies so they can focus on finding more fun for more players around the world. The lowering of these friction points leads to deeper gameplay experiences."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Underlining that point, Wilson said EA couldn't have created </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>College Football 25 </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">without leaning on AI tools to build 150 unique stadiums and over 11,000 player likenesses. That sort of expansion is what he claims EA is driving towards.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Expansion is about giving our creative teams an exponentially bigger canvas upon which to create, and richer colors so they might paint more brilliant worlds. It's about our incredible teams, creating characters with more depth and intelligence, telling stories that are more personal and nuanced, and bringing more authenticity and deeper immersion to our already unrivalled sports experiences," he continued.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"For years, we have talked about our games delivering experiences that are always new and different. We predict that with generative AI we will truly be able to fulfill this promise for billions of people, for billions and billions of hours."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">As for transformation? Wilson believes that concept is about gazing into the distant future and considering how AI can deliver experiences that cannot be "imagined today."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"We believe AI will greatly expand and transform the entertainment experience for user generated content," he added. "It will accelerate how innovators and creators in entertainment are building and delivering experiences rooted in self expression, content creation, curation and instant gratification–the kind of entertainment that today's players and fans deeply crave."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">He said that when EA's biggest franchises have been "supercharged by AI," the company will be able to cultivate massive online communities, tell compelling stories, and harness player power "beyond the bounds" of video games. Admittedly, that doesn't sound too different from what many studios are already doing.&nbsp;</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="EA ponders a generative AI future where players and developers form 'symbiotic relationship'">EA ponders a generative AI future where players and developers form 'symbiotic relationship'</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">EA Entertainment and Technology president Laura Miele was singing from the same hymn sheet. Taking over from Wilson, she explained EA is in the middle of a multi-year effort to centralize decades of 3D data and assets to bolster its development teams and Frostbite game engine.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">She said that "Smithsonian" scale library has allowed EA to train its machine learning and large language models with its own proprietary data. Those models can then be used by internal teams like the Search for Extraordinary Experiences Division (SEED), which Miele described as an "innovation lab."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">SEED is currently focused on areas such as "AI-enabled game development, generative arts, and procedural content," including a tool called "Script to Scene" capable of aggregating multiple workflows to help devs build characters, direct performances, and craft worlds using text or voice inputs.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">She explained EA teams could use the tool to instantly generate a "four storey Parisian apartment building," before requesting tweaks with additional prompts such as "add more floors to the building" (as shown below). Miele said the tech could be deployed to create entire neighbourhoods, cities, and "eventually worlds."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">During a later portion of the presentation, EA chief strategy officer Mihir Vaidya grabbed the baton and said EA envisions handing tools like 'Script to Scene' over to players so they can "convert their imaginations into creations without coding expertise."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">He went on to clarify that "Imagination to Creation" won't enable players to create and release and support entire video games (at least, not at first), but will rather allow them to build robust user-generated experiences (UGX).</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Debuting a brief concept video that stitched together some of EA's more "exciting experiments", Vaidya showed how the company's AI tools could be deployed to create impossible, previously incomprehensible realities like a "game made out of cardboard boxes."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Make a maze of cardboard boxes," says a disembodied player voice during the demo video. That prompt resulted in the creation of simple level made from everybody's favourite shipping material.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Disappointed with their original cardboard labyrinth, the nameless players then ask their AI enabler to make the level "more complex" and "multi-level." The below image is what EA imagines its 'Imagination to Creation' toolkit might then churn out.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The video ends with two players engaging in a custom 1v1 deathmatch where only grenades are lethal. Both players were shown choosing between weapons and characters from existing EA franchises like Battlefield and Apex Legends, suggesting EA views its 'Imagination to Creation" toolkit as an open sandbox filled with remixable gameplay systems, assets, and logic from its biggest series.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Vaidya said EA wants players to be able to use that triple-A content as a "foundation" for those UGX experiences, perhaps eventually turning those creations into "chart-topping IPs."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"This would create a new level of symbiotic relationship between our own developers and UGX creators, and one with our own IPs being the launchpads for new experiences and businesses," he added.&nbsp;We'll let you decide whether that's a positive.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://eainvestorday2024.q4ir.com/home/default.aspx">You can watch EA's full investor day presentation right here</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">News Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer news editor Chris Kerr is an award-winning journalist and reporter with over a decade of experience in the game industry. His byline has appeared in notable print and digital publications including Edge, Stuff, Wireframe, International Business Times, and&nbsp;</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="http://pocketgamer.biz/">PocketGamer.biz</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. Throughout his career, Chris has covered major industry events including GDC, PAX Australia, Gamescom, Paris Games Week, and Develop Brighton. He has featured on the judging panel at The Develop Star Awards on multiple occasions and appeared on BBC Radio 5 Live to discuss breaking news.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EA wants The Sims film to have Barbie's impact]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/ea-wants-the-sims-film-to-have-barbies-impact</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ea-wants-the-sims-film-to-have-barbies-impact.984105/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/ea-wants-the-sims-film-to-have-barbies-impact<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>Freezer Bunnies confirmed.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Sims-4-(Luxury-Party)-Roof-Table.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>EA</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>EA has officially announced a film adaptation of <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/video-game-franchises/the-sims">The Sims</a> is in the works and aims for it to have an impact like the Barbie film.</p>
<p>The film will be <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/barbies-margot-robbie-to-produce-the-sims-movie-adaptation">produced by Barbie actress Margot Robbie's production company LuckyChap</a>, with Loki director Kate Herron at the helm.</p>
<p>In an interview with <a href="https://variety.com/2024/film/news/the-sims-movie-plot-details-amazon-ea-margot-robbie-1236142126/">Variety</a>, EA's vice president and general manager of The Sims Kate Gorman discussed the company's plans for the film and the inclusion of fan-favourite Easter Eggs.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Eurogamer Newscast: When it costs £700, who exactly is the PS5 Pro for?" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Qb7vhF2ELZg?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Eurogamer Newscast: When it costs £700, who exactly is the PS5 Pro for?</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Qb7vhF2ELZg?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/Qb7vhF2ELZg?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>When it costs £700, who exactly is the PS5 Pro for?<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Qb7vhF2ELZg" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>"What I will tell you is it's very much rooted in The Sims universe," said Gorman. "And what we want is to have a truly authentic Sims experience brought to a theatrical release. So what you'll see from us is that we have been wanting to get this right. We wanted the right partners and to make an impact the size of something like a Barbie movie is exactly what we want.</p>
<p>"And we know there's so much love and nostalgia, probably beyond what we would even realise, for The Sims and so many people like us have played throughout generations. So we want this to be an experience that reflects all that amazing history and play of so many people in this world, but also is something that you can share across generations and to be part of pop culture and culturally relevant."</p>
<p>Gorman has promised an "authentic Sims experience" that will see its universe "come to life" with "classic experiences".</p>
<p>"There will be Freezer Bunnies," Gorman confirmed. "I'm sure a pool without a ladder is somewhere in there, but we haven't finalised any of those details. But that's the idea, is to say that it lives within this space. It's a nod to all of the amazing play and creation and fun that people have had over the last 25 years within The Sims."</p>
<p>Freezer Bunnies, for those who haven't played The Sims, have recurred in the games since <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/the-sims-2">The Sims 2</a> as cute toys spotted in freezers, toy boxes and more.</p>
<p>Herron not only directed the first season of Disney+ series Loki, but wrote a script for an episode of Doctor Who and will be directing episodes of HBO's The Last of Us season two.</p>
<p>Yesterday, EA shared a blog post explaining <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-sims-5-not-happening-as-ea-moves-beyond-linear-sequential-sims-releases">the future of The Sims</a>. The company confirmed it's not working on <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/the-sims-5">The Sims 5</a> and is instead moving "beyond linear, sequential Sims releases".</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Horizon Zero Dawn Remastered has Been Rated for PS5 and PC]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/horizon-zero-dawn-remastered-rating/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/horizon-zero-dawn-remastered-has-been-rated-for-ps5-and-pc.984099/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/horizon-zero-dawn-remastered-rating/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-57492">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>Horizon Zero Dawn Remastered has been rated by the ESRB for the PlayStation 5 and PC.</p>



<p>The rating comes following the announcement of the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ps5-pro-pre-order-details-revealed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">PlayStation 5 Pro</a> and rumours suggesting that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/september-2024-state-of-play/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">PlayStation will have a State of Play</a> coming by the end of the month.</p>



<p>The <a href="https://www.esrb.org/ratings/40023/horizon-zero-dawn-remastered/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">ESRB rating</a> summary reads, “This is an action/role-playing game in which players assume the role of a hunter (Aloy) surviving through a post-apocalyptic world. Players guide Aloy as she learns to hunt robotic creatures and animals in the wild. Aloy uses arrows, spears, and explosive traps to injure and kill machines, boar, and occasional human enemies. Animals and humans emit small puffs of red blood when struck; one sequence depicts an abandoned camp with large blood stains on rocks and trees. The game contains a brief reference to sexual material (e.g., “Eighteen months hard labor in exchange for thirty years lounging around Elysium watching porn?”). In text/audio files, characters sometimes reference fictional drugs, overdoses, and getting high: “…not even out of junior high and already a drug addict”; “…I ran across a pusher who was selling Razorwing for eight bucks a tab”; “I’d spend a few days getting high, then OD on Overcast.” The word “sh*t” appears in the text/dialogue.”</p>



<p>It’s unclear when PlayStation could announce Horizon Zero Dawn Remastered, but the rating suggests it’s likely very soon and could be used to show off the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/sony-reveals-the-ps5-pro/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">PS5 Pro features</a>.</p>



<p>Horizon Zero Dawn was first released in 2017 and, as of April 2023, has sold over 24.3 million units. On Metacritic, the game received an 89/100 for the PlayStation 4.</p>



<p>What do you think of Horizon Zero Dawn Remastered coming to the PS5? Let us know in our <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forums</a>. </p>



<p>For more from Insider Gaming, don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a> and check out the news that&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/xdefiant-not-dying-ubisoft-says/">Ubisoft says XDefiant isn’t dying</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/witcher-sirens-of-the-deep-release-date/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/witcher-sirens-of-the-deep-release-date/">The Witcher: Sirens of the Deep Release Date Revealed by Netflix</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>The Witcher: Sirens of the Deep is set to be released next year on Netflix. Check out everything you need to know here.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/xdefiant-not-dying-ubisoft-says/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/xdefiant-not-dying-ubisoft-says/">‘The Game Is Absolutely Not Dying’: Ubisoft on XDefiant’s Year-One Roadmap</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Ubisoft has published a blog post regarding the first year of XDefiant content, stressing that the game is absolutely not dying.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fans-battlefield-6-concept-art-setting/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fans-battlefield-6-concept-art-setting/">Fans Have Figured Out Where The Battlefield 6 Concept Art is Set</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Eagle-eyed fans have compared maps and images to figure out where the Battlefield 6 concept art is set – and then we confirmed it.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dead-by-daylight-spinoff-project-t-cancelled-due-to-poor-reception/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dead-by-daylight-spinoff-project-t-cancelled-due-to-poor-reception/">Dead By Daylight Spinoff Project T Cancelled Due To Poor Reception</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Midwinter Entertainment and Behaviour Interactive has announced that Project T, the Dead By Daylight spinoff, has been cancelled.</p>
                    </div>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Horizon Zero Dawn Remastered rated for PS5 and PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/horizon-zero-dawn-remastered-rated-for-ps5-and-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/horizon-zero-dawn-remastered-rated-for-ps5-and-pc.984093/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/horizon-zero-dawn-remastered-rated-for-ps5-and-pc<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>



            <p><a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/horizon-zero-dawn">Horizon Zero Dawn</a> Remastered has been <a href="https://www.esrb.org/ratings/40023/horizon-zero-dawn-remastered/">rated by the ESRB</a>, listing PC and PlayStation 5 as its platforms.</p>
<p>A <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/horizon-zero-dawn-playstation-5-remaster-reportedly-in-the-works">remaster of Guerrilla's first Horizon game was rumoured</a> back in 2022, but is yet to be officially announced by Sony.</p>
<p>This rating brings fresh credibility to the remaster's existence, though no indication of a release date has been provided. Could this be some sort of <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/a-700-ps5-pro-is-an-argument-against-pro-consoles-altogether">PS5 Pro</a> launch title?</p>
<figure>
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<figcaption>LEGO Horizon Adventures - Announce Trailer | PS5 Games<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=20gjEuTiWug" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>The game is already playable on PS5 via backwards compatibility, but there's no native version available. It's also already out on PC (since 2020), but again this is based on the PS4 version.</p>
<p>Horizon Zero Dawn was released on PS4 in 2017. A remaster for PS5 would presumably bring the game in-line with its sequel, Forbidden West, which released across both platforms in 2022.</p>
<p>Zero Dawn was previously available on PS Plus, before <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/playstation-is-pulling-its-own-blockbuster-game-from-ps-plus">being removed from Sony's subscription service earlier this year</a>. That's added speculation towards this remaster.</p>
<p>Specifically, it was the Complete Edition including the game's The Frozen Wilds DLC that was available.</p>
<p>Notably, the rating is for PC as well as PS5, following in the footsteps of remasters like The Last of Us Part 2 and Marvel's Spider-Man. <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/god-of-war-ragnarok-pc-release-date-time">God of War Ragnarök is also heading to PC this week</a>.</p>
<p>Despite Sony releasing more of its games on PC in recent years, joint CEO Hideaki Nishino stated earlier this week <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/consoles-to-remain-the-core-of-playstations-business-ceo-says">consoles would remain at the "core" of Sony's business</a>.</p>
<p>"I think that with mobile devices, there are many games that show advertisements, and PCs are difficult to set up, but with PlayStation, once you turn it on, you can experience the content you bought straight away," said Nishino.</p>
<p>Later this year, the Horizon series will continue with <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/lego-horizon-adventures-is-a-perfect-match-a-breezy-light-hearted-approach-the-series-has-perhaps-always-needed">Lego Horizon Adventures</a>, turning Aloy and her robotic dinosaur enemies into bricks.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Horizon Zero Dawn Remastered Rated by ESRB for PS5, PC]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/horizon-zero-dawn-remastered-rated-by-esrb-for-ps5-and-pc/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/horizon-zero-dawn-remastered-rated-by-esrb-for-ps5-pc.984081/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/horizon-zero-dawn-remastered-rated-by-esrb-for-ps5-and-pc/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Horizon Zero Dawn Remastered is real. We haven't got an official announcement from Sony and Guerrilla Games yet, but the ESRB has already <a href="https://www.esrb.org/ratings/40023/horizon-zero-dawn-remastered/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">rated</a> the game for PlayStation 5 and PC, hinting at an imminent release:</p>
<p><em>This is an action/role-playing game in which players assume the role of a hunter (Aloy) surviving through a post-apocalyptic world. Players guide Aloy as she learns to hunt robotic creatures and animals in the wild. Aloy uses arrows, spears, and explosive traps to injure and kill machines, boar, and occasional human enemies. Animals and humans emit small puffs of red blood when struck; one sequence depicts an abandoned camp with large blood stains on rocks and trees. The game contains a brief reference to sexual material (e.g., “Eighteen months hard labor in exchange for thirty years lounging around Elysium watching porn?”). In text/audio files, characters sometimes reference fictional drugs, overdoses, and getting high: “...not even out of junior high and already a drug addict”; “...I ran across a pusher who was selling Razorwing for eight bucks a tab”; "I'd spend a few days getting high, then OD on Overcast." The word “sh*t” appears in the text/dialogue.</em></p>
<p>We first <a href="https://wccftech.com/a-horizon-zero-dawn-playstation-5-remake-is-in-the-works-alongside-a-multiplayer-game-rumor/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">heard</a> about Horizon Zero Dawn Remastered in October 2022, when two different sources suggested that the 2017 game would return with an improved lighting system, overhauled textures, improved animations, and new character models. Additionally, the new version of the game is believed to include the many accessibility options introduced in Horizon Forbidden West, multiple display modes, and various quality-of-life improvements. That rumor mentioned a 'remake', but that would have been very weird, as the game is so recent that a remake didn't make sense at all.</p>
<p>Honestly, I'm not so sure even a remaster does, especially since Horizon Zero Dawn is also available on PC and was already <a href="https://wccftech.com/horizon-forbidden-west-delayed-2022-horizon-zero-dawn-60fps-patch/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">enhanced</a> for PlayStation 5 with a patch. We'll have to wait for the official details to understand whether this new version is worth buying.</p>
<p>Later this year, fans can look forward to the spin-off game <a href="https://wccftech.com/lego-horizon-adventures-reportedly-launching-on-november-14/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">LEGO Horizon Adventures</a>. On the other hand, the Netflix TV show was reportedly put on hold due to allegations against showrunner Steve Blackman.</p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[LYMBUS is hostile to my existence and keeps demanding brain cells I haven’t grown yet]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/lymbus-is-hostile-to-my-existence-and-keeps-demanding-brain-cells-i-havent-grown-yet</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/lymbus-is-hostile-to-my-existence-and-keeps-demanding-brain-cells-i-haven%E2%80%99t-grown-yet.984078/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/lymbus-is-hostile-to-my-existence-and-keeps-demanding-brain-cells-i-havent-grown-yet<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/LYMBUS-1.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Happy Accident Studios</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>What are you <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/lymbus">LYMBUS</a>? In what vat were you grown? I feel like I’ve sluggishly ambled my way down to the fridge and tried to scoop a gherkin from the jar, only to find a disconcertingly tasty sliver of my own brain - like a creature from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Flatland">Flatland</a> trying to play 4D chess, and all the pieces are just tiny carvings of my face with “lol get a load of this prick” whittled into the forehead. I quite like it.</p>
<p>“We combined your favorite genres into one grotesque piece of software! You're welcome, game journalists,” reads the <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3190880/LYMBUS_Incomplete_Edition/">Steam page</a> for the demo. That is a very polite way to kick me in the head and call me a bitch, LYMBUS.</p>
<!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="LYMBUS: Demo Out Now!" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/RrL4sf4j3jQ?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>LYMBUS: Demo Out Now!</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/RrL4sf4j3jQ?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/RrL4sf4j3jQ?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RrL4sf4j3jQ" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>Right, let’s give this a go. LYMBUS: Incomplete Edition, as the demo is called, is from Happy Accident Studios. Earlier this year, they put out <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2815800/Anomalytics_From_the_Files_of_the_Arcane_Statistics_Authority/">Anomalytics</a>, which is partly billed as a boomer shooter but also arms you with a calculator. LYMBUS itself is a roguelike bullet hell where you need to play cards to do anything except move. The cards, which cost a real-time replenishing resource to play, let you do things like shoot, slash, parry, dodge, and shoot again but bullet-ier. Cards get burned on use, but you can find more by passing over tiles scattered around.</p>
<p>The tricksiness comes in the fact you’ll need to ready cards by switching between them, while also scrambling around like a terrified little wombat avoiding a lawnmower made of guns. Here’s the setup:</p>
<blockquote><p>The year is 19XX. Great strides in neuromechanical research have allowed the most common human actions to be transcribed onto memory cards. Great oversights in said research have also made it so nobody remembered to save a backup. After a catastrophic crash renders most of the population comatose, you are tasked with diving into humanity's collective unconscious to retrieve the memories that may hold the key to ending the blackout.</p></blockquote>
<p>Where are you in all this? You are here:</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/LYMBUS-2.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Happy Accident Studios</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Thanks for that. Here's some more info:</p>
<blockquote><p>Move around with your keyboard. Do everything else with your cards. In LYMBUS, exercise maximum strategy in building your deck, then throw that strategy out the window in screen-shaking, bullet hell-style battles. Combat happens in real time with no turns or slowdowns, meaning resources are tight and every moment matters.</p></blockquote>
<p>LYMBUS is out later this year. Don't let it bully you.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PS5 Pro Support Confirmed for Horror Game Retrieval]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/ps5-pro-support-confirmed-for-horror-game-retrieval/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ps5-pro-support-confirmed-for-horror-game-retrieval.984072/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/ps5-pro-support-confirmed-for-horror-game-retrieval/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Alongside the <a href="https://wccftech.com/playstation-5-pro-specs-release-date/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announcement</a> of the PS5 Pro, Sony confirmed thirteen games that will be optimized for the new console: Alan Wake 2, Assassin’s Creed: Shadows, Demon’s Souls, Dragon’s Dogma 2, Final Fantasy 7 Rebirth, Gran Turismo 7, Hogwarts Legacy, Horizon Forbidden West, Marvel’s Spider-Man 2, Ratchet &amp; Clank: Rift Apart, The Crew Motorfest, The First Descendant, and The Last of Us Part II Remastered.</p>
<p>Of course, this is only a preliminary list, and many more will be confirmed throughout the coming weeks. One more can already be added to the list: it's the upcoming horror game Retrieval. Originally announced at Gamescom 2023, the game received a new trailer at Gamescom 2024. At the same time, it was added to the <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2999120/Retrieval/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> and <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/concept/10011723" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PlayStation</a> stores for wishlisting and quickly passed the milestone of 20K users adding the game to their wishlists.</p>
<p>Following the reveal of the PS5 Pro, Barcelona-based developer 333Studios confirmed some of the improvements players will see when playing the game on the more powerful console.</p>
<p><em>While Retrieval will look stunning on the PS5, the PS5 Pro version will offer even better visuals and smoother gameplay. Here’s a breakdown of what to expect:</em></p>
<p><em><strong>Improved Graphics:</strong> Expect sharper resolution with the newly announced PSSR technology, more detailed environments, and higher fidelity ray-traced reflections.</em></p>
<p><em><strong>Higher Frame Rates:</strong> The PS5 Pro will push Retrieval to run at higher, more stable frame rates, ensuring smoother gameplay and more responsive controls.</em></p>
<p>The studio even provided a preliminary screenshot comparison between the base PS5 and the PlayStation 5 Pro version.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/retrieval-ps5pro-2-HD-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>

<p>Retrieval is set on a distant planet where protagonist Hana Loshe gets stranded in a subway base, uncovering all sorts of secrets and terrifying creatures within. The Dead Space inspiration seems pretty clear. The Gamescom 2024 trailer (embedded below) showed off NVIDIA RTX Direct Illumination tech, which will likely only be available on PC.</p>
<p><iframe title="Retrieval - Official 2024 Gamescom Reveal Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/QZ2NXIEu1JE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>The full game is also expected to launch on Xbox Series S|X consoles. There's no release date yet, but we'll let you know when that changes.</p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rockstar leak more clues of a Red Dead Redemption PC remaster]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/rockstar-leak-more-clues-of-a-red-dead-redemption-pc-remaster</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/rockstar-leak-more-clues-of-a-red-dead-redemption-pc-remaster.984069/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/rockstar-leak-more-clues-of-a-red-dead-redemption-pc-remaster<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/red-dead-redemption-1-pc-remaster-leaks-again.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Rockstar Games</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>It's been long suspected (if not officially confirmed) that the first <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/red-dead-redemption">Red Dead Redemption</a> will be getting a PC remaster some time in the near future. We've already seen a description for the PC version <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/playstation-store-lists-red-dead-redemption-as-now-on-pc-for-the-first-time-ever">appear briefly</a> on the PlayStation store (of all places). And earlier this year a snoopy fan of the studio who monitors the backend of Rockstar's launcher <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-first-red-dead-redemption-could-finally-be-coming-to-pc-and-soon-according-to-a-fresh-datamine">found similar game descriptions</a> buried amid metadata. Yesterday, that same practice yielded yet another clue - the game's Steam app number.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>The tidbit comes from Xitter user <a href="https://x.com/TezFunz2/status/1836029927751032876">"TezFunz2"</a>, who has committed to a kind of cyber stakeout of Rockstar's online properties. The Steam app number in itself is not much information. You can view and track the game now <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/2668510/">via Steamdb</a>, if you're so inclined. But it won't show any real info until the store page is actually live (in theory, anyway). Even so, it counts as another step towards the 2010 open world western finally hitting PC. We already know from the PlayStation store leak that the port will include "PC specific enhancements including support for increased resolutions and framerates." </p>
<p>There was a brief moment when it looked like the rootin' tootin' remaster <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/red-dead-redemption-and-gta4-remasters-reportedly-scrapped-after-gta-trilogy-debacle">would be shelved</a>, following the lacklustre release of the remastered GTA Trilogy, which came out horrendously buggy and visually garbled (it even had to be briefly taken down from sale to remove unlicensed music). But it seems like work is resuming on it after all.</p>
<p>It's worth noting that a developer can add apps to Steam as unnamed items long before release. So this doesn't necessarily mean the remaster will be out soon. But a year has now passed since similar ports were released for PlayStation 4 and Nintendo Switch. And 14 years since the game's first appearance on PS3. Maybe that's enough time to get a PC version sorted?</p>
<p>Anyway, yes. Leaks are fun. The PC version of Red Dead Redemption 2 was itself <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/red-dead-redemption-2-existence-on-pc-possibly-leaked-via-linkedin">leaked on LinkedIn</a> back in 2018 (more like LEAKEDIn, amirite?). </p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[You're now much stronger against tanks and armour in Helldivers 2, as Arrowhead patch for "more versatile" tactics]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/youre-now-much-stronger-against-tanks-and-armour-in-helldivers-2-as-arrowhead-patch-for-more-versatile-tactics</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/youre-now-much-stronger-against-tanks-and-armour-in-helldivers-2-as-arrowhead-patch-for-more-versatile-tactics.984066/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/youre-now-much-stronger-against-tanks-and-armour-in-helldivers-2-as-arrowhead-patch-for-more-versatile-tactics<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
  

        <p>The forever war continues</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/joel_MGI4bUg.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>PlayStation/Rock Paper Shotgun</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>Last month, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/helldivers-2">Helldivers 2</a> studio Arrowhead <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/arrowhead-emerge-with-a-bullet-pointed-peace-offering-to-pacify-mutinous-helldivers-2-players">thrust a white flag out</a> from their shelled position in an attempt to placate mutinous fans of the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-co-op-games">co-op </a>shooter. In response to a community sentiment best summed up by a popular Reddit <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Helldivers/comments/1ep9bq9/let_the_bots_advance_let_the_super_earth_burn/">post titled</a> “Let the super earth burn”, Arrowhead released <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Helldivers/comments/1erc9w5/the_message_to_the_community_from_our_game/">a statement</a>. “In short, we didn’t hit our target with the latest update…what matters most now is action. Not talk.” Said action (which, it must be pointed out, felt a bit troublingly reactive to the loudest and most histrionic voices in the roo..uh, subreddit) was foreshadowed in a list of issues to be tackled over the coming months.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>That list's gist, if you missed the list, was a promise to fix “our approach to balance. Our intention is that balance should be fun, not “balanced” for the sake of balance." Yesterday, Patch 1.001.100 dropped, accompanied by a video that I can only describe, in a professional capacity, as long as fuck. </p> <figure>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/1cCIOlSQIT0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" height="113" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" title="Helldivers 2 Patch Notes - Patch 01.001.100" width="200"></iframe><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</figure>
<p>In case you have better things to do with the next 35 minutes, here’s a summary of the patch notes, the full list of which you can <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/553850/view/7147864422081646859">find here</a>.</p>
<blockquote><ul>
<li><p>Major Overhaul of Anti-Tank, Armor Penetration, Health and Armor Values</p></li>
<li><p>Weapon &amp; Stratagem Balancing</p></li>
<li><p>Enemy Reworks</p></li>
<li><p>Helldiver Health and Damage Mechanics Tweaks</p></li>
<li><p>Gas Gameplay Mechanic Rework</p></li>
<li><p>New Galactic War feature</p></li>
<li><p>Emote Wheel feature</p></li>
<li><p>Crash &amp; Bug Fixes</p></li>
</ul>
</blockquote>
<p>“Thank you for your valuable feedback. Many players have expressed feeling constrained in how they approach challenges, often relying on a limited set of tools while other options seem less effective,” reads the blog. “To address this, we've reworked armor penetration, anti-tank weapons, enemy armor and health values."</p>
<p>"Our goal is to improve the effectiveness of weapons such as the Autocannon, Heavy Machine Gun, Flamethrower, and Anti-Materiel Rifle against heavily armored enemies," it continues. "Although they may not be as effective as specialized anti-tank weapons, they are now more viable choices making your loadouts more versatile, fostering better team collaboration and planning.”</p>
<p>It’s a hefty list in all, and Arrowhead say they aren’t done yet - they “plan to conduct another balance pass by Day 60 of our commitment”. The general gist of these changes seems to be that players are now more powerful, and the bugs, especially, are less oppressive. As noticed by cheery RPS fanzine PC Gamer, the game’s director agrees that a <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/third-person-shooter/arrowhead-creative-director-agrees-helldivers-2-needs-a-harder-difficulty-mode-after-the-buff-everything-patch/">harder difficulty is now needed.</a> Truly, the real sisyphean eterna-war was the constant rush to try and please the entire fanbase, all the time, along the way.</p>
<p>Arrowhead have also been <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/sightings-of-helldivers-2-illuminate-faction-on-galactic-war-map-are-fake-news-says-arrowhead-boss">not-teasing the game's third faction</a> recently. </p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Freedom Wars Remastered is coming to PC and consoles January 10th]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/09/18/freedom-wars-remastered-is-coming-to-pc-and-consoles-january-10th/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/freedom-wars-remastered-is-coming-to-pc-and-consoles-january-10th.984051/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/09/18/freedom-wars-remastered-is-coming-to-pc-and-consoles-january-10th/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Freedom Wars will no longer be a PS Vita exclusive, with Bandai Namco announcing that it is releasing Freedom Wars Remastered for PS5, PS4, Switch, and PC via Steam. Freedom Wars was originally released for the PS Vita in 2014. The remastered version brings with it support for 4K visuals and 60fps, adjusted difficulty options, gameplay balances, and new updates to weapon crafting and upgrading.</p>
<p><iframe title="FREEDOM WARS REMASTERED — Announcement Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/feD7epA4CBk?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>Freedom Wars is set in the fictional world of Panopticon where your character has been sentenced to a one million year prison sentence, and the only way to reduce that sentence is to serve the state. That is done through fighting the enemies of Panopticon out in the wasteland, where the action is mixed between attacking with melee and range weapons, as well as using the Thorn grappling hook to get in close. When not in battle, players return to prison where they have to follow the rules or be pulled up on infractions. Behave and you are given additional liberties to help cope with your prison sentence. You will also meet a range of characters, and it is from this pool you can select who will venture into battle with you.</p>
<h2><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2014/11/10/freedom-wars-review/">Freedom Wars Review</a></h2>
<p>In our review for the original Freedom Wars release, Jim said, <em>“Freedom Wars is far from being the Vita flagship fans were hoping for. Though it makes a sound first impression it’s ultimately held back by a forced narrative and gameplay segments that fall by the wayside. Thanks to its unique tone and approach to gameplay, Freedom Wars manages to distance itself from Monster Hunter, yet it’s difficult not to compare the two. After all, Capcom’s power-selling franchise didn’t just popularise the genre, it single-handedly created it. Though Freedom Wars’ appeal is limited, there will doubtlessly be many who find themselves hooked. For them, the game has a lot to offer, even beyond the limitless hours of content thanks to a suite of online features. Those who aren’t willing to put in the time, however, may find themselves short-changed.”</em></p>

<p>Freedom Wars Remastered will be released on January 10th, 2025.</p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=feD7epA4CBk">YouTube</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Witcher: Sirens of the Deep Release Date Revealed by Netflix]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/witcher-sirens-of-the-deep-release-date/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-witcher-sirens-of-the-deep-release-date-revealed-by-netflix.984039/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/witcher-sirens-of-the-deep-release-date/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Netflix has issued an update on The Witcher: Sirens of the Deep, the upcoming feature-length anime starring Doug Cockle reprising his role as Geralt of Rivia. It was confirmed that the animated feature will be released on Netflix on February 11, 2025.</p>



<p>It’s a canonical injection of content that lands between the fifth and sixth episodes of the first season of the Netflix live-action adaptation. To that end, both Anya Chalotra and Joey Batey return to play the roles of Yennefer and Jaskier — but Henry Cavill, who previously played Geralt of Rivia in the Netflix series, is long gone.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-cockle-is-back">Cockle is Back</h2>



<p>The Witcher: Sirens of the Deep marks a return to the franchise for Doug Cockle after almost a decade. The iconic voice actor was more than happy to step back into the role of Geralt of Rivia after recently admitting that he’d gladly represent the famed monster hunter forever if he could.</p>



<p>Sirens of the Deep will see Geralt take on a contract involving ‘merpeople’ in a seaside village. It’s a story pulled from A Little Sacrifice, a shorter Witcher text from Andrzej Sapkowski, the creator of The Witcher. In the story, Geralt will become intertwined in a conflict that eventually pulls in other characters from in and around The Witcher’s wider universe.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="The Witcher: Sirens of The Deep | Official Clip | Netflix" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/x8P2Nodqzpc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>







<p>At 1 hour and 29 minutes, Sirens of the Deep is the longest adaptation of The Witcher to make it to screens. As CD Projekt continues to work on the next Witcher game, fans of the franchise can use productions like this to ‘plug the gap’. It’ll likely be a few years before we see the next Witcher game surface, even if it is the chief focus of the team right now.</p>



<p>The Witcher: Sirens of the Deep will be released worldwide on Netflix on February 11, 2025.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/xdefiant-not-dying-ubisoft-says/">Ubisoft says XDefiant isn’t dying</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Famitsu Review Scores: Issue 1866]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/09/famitsu-review-scores-issue-1866</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/famitsu-review-scores-issue-1866.984036/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/09/famitsu-review-scores-issue-1866<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>    

    <!-- AD: footer -->
           
            

    <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/" title="Gematsu"><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" width="302" height="39.731" viewBox="0 0 302 39.731"><g transform="translate(0 0)"><g transform="translate(0 0.001)"><path d="M39.49,10.82c.13,0,.2-.05.2-.17V.17c0-.1-.07-.15-.2-.17H4.28A4.28,4.28,0,0,0,0,4.28V35.4a4.29,4.29,0,0,0,4.28,4.29H39.49c.13,0,.2-.06.2-.17V14.75c0-.11-.07-.17-.2-.19H15.94c-.09,0-.15.06-.17.19v10.3a.17.17,0,0,0,.17.16H27.7v3.65H12v-18Z" fill="#ed1d3b"></path><path d="M43.69.17A.17.17,0,0,1,43.88,0H83.29a.15.15,0,0,1,.16.17V10.65c0,.12,0,.17-.16.17H55.7v3.65H83.29a.155.155,0,0,1,.16.17V25.13a.14.14,0,0,1-.16.16H55.7v3.57H83.29a.155.155,0,0,1,.16.17V39.52c0,.11,0,.17-.16.17H43.88c-.13,0-.19-.06-.19-.17Z" fill="#fff"></path><path d="M103.26,25.27V10.93H99.44V39.52a.15.15,0,0,1-.17.17H87.65c-.13,0-.2-.06-.2-.17V.17a.19.19,0,0,1,.2-.17H127a.158.158,0,0,1,.17.17V39.52a.15.15,0,0,1-.17.17H115.32c-.11,0-.16-.06-.16-.17V10.93h-3.91V25.27Z" fill="#fff"></path><path d="M170.63,0h-39.3a.18.18,0,0,0-.19.17V39.52c0,.11.06.17.19.17H143c.11,0,.16-.06.16-.17V25.29h15.72V39.52a.15.15,0,0,0,.17.17h11.62c.13,0,.19-.06.19-.17V.17A.229.229,0,0,0,170.63,0ZM158.84,14.47H143.12V10.82h15.72Z" fill="#fff"></path><path d="M188.3,11.1H175c-.13,0-.2-.06-.2-.17V.17A.19.19,0,0,1,175,0h39.41a.15.15,0,0,1,.16.17V10.93c0,.11-.05.17-.16.17H201V39.52c0,.11-.07.17-.2.17H188.49c-.12,0-.19-.06-.19-.17Z" fill="#fff"></path><path d="M258.08,0c.13,0,.2.07.2.17V10.65c0,.12-.07.17-.2.17H229.41v3.54h28.67a.189.189,0,0,1,.2.2v25c0,.11-.07.17-.2.17h-39.3c-.12,0-.19-.06-.19-.17V29a.18.18,0,0,1,.19-.17h28.68V25.29H218.78c-.12,0-.19-.05-.19-.16V.17a.18.18,0,0,1,.19-.17Z" fill="#fff"></path><path d="M301.77,0H290.14c-.09,0-.14.06-.16.17V28.75H274.26V.17c0-.1-.06-.15-.17-.17H262.47a.17.17,0,0,0-.19.17V39.52c0,.11.06.17.19.17h35.21A4.29,4.29,0,0,0,302,35.4V.17C302,.07,301.9,0,301.77,0Z" fill="#fff"></path></g></g></svg></a>

    <section>
      <nav>
        <div><ul id="menu-footer-menu-one"><li id="menu-item-691230"><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo">Nintendo</a></li>
<li id="menu-item-691231"><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation">PlayStation</a></li>
<li id="menu-item-691232"><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox">Xbox</a></li>
<li id="menu-item-691233"><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>
<li id="menu-item-691234"><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/c/industry">Industry</a></li>
</ul></div>      </nav>
      <nav>
        <div><ul id="menu-footer-menu-two"><li id="menu-item-691235"><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/about">About</a></li>
<li id="menu-item-691236"><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/about#contact">Contact Us</a></li>
<li id="menu-item-691237"><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/about#advertising">Advertising</a></li>
<li id="menu-item-691238"><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/about#staff">Staff</a></li>
<li id="menu-item-691239"><a rel="privacy-policy" href="https://www.gematsu.com/privacy">Privacy Policy</a></li>
</ul></div>      </nav>
    </section>

    <section>
      <ul>
        <li><a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://www.facebook.com/gematsucom"><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" width="24" height="24" viewBox="0 0 24 24"><path d="M9 8h-3v4h3v12h5v-12h3.642l.358-4h-4v-1.667c0-.955.192-1.333 1.115-1.333h2.885v-5h-3.808c-3.596 0-5.192 1.583-5.192 4.615v3.385z"></path></svg></a></li>
        <li><a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://twitter.com/gematsu"><svg viewBox="0 0 16 16"><path d="M12.6.75h2.454l-5.36 6.142L16 15.25h-4.937l-3.867-5.07-4.425 5.07H.316l5.733-6.57L0 .75h5.063l3.495 4.633L12.601.75Zm-.86 13.028h1.36L4.323 2.145H2.865z"></path></svg></a></li>
        <li><a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://bsky.app/profile/gematsu.com"><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 -3.268 64 68.414" width="2232" height="2500"><path d="M13.873 3.805C21.21 9.332 29.103 20.537 32 26.55v15.882c0-.338-.13.044-.41.867-1.512 4.456-7.418 21.847-20.923 7.944-7.111-7.32-3.819-14.64 9.125-16.85-7.405 1.264-15.73-.825-18.014-9.015C1.12 23.022 0 8.51 0 6.55 0-3.268 8.579-.182 13.873 3.805zm36.254 0C42.79 9.332 34.897 20.537 32 26.55v15.882c0-.338.13.044.41.867 1.512 4.456 7.418 21.847 20.923 7.944 7.111-7.32 3.819-14.64-9.125-16.85 7.405 1.264 15.73-.825 18.014-9.015C62.88 23.022 64 8.51 64 6.55c0-9.818-8.578-6.732-13.873-2.745z"></path></svg></a></li>
        <li><a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCcaswDIh-nrXYofcYQm6KTg"><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" width="24" height="24" viewBox="0 0 24 24"><path d="M9 15V8.26l6.48 3.38L9 15zm14.76-7.8a5.17 5.17 0 0 0-1-2.38 3.46 3.46 0 0 0-2.41-1C17 3.56 12 3.56 12 3.56s-5 0-8.4.24a3.46 3.46 0 0 0-2.41 1 5.17 5.17 0 0 0-.95 2.4A36.53 36.53 0 0 0 0 11.09v1.82a36.22 36.22 0 0 0 .24 3.88 5.17 5.17 0 0 0 1 2.38 4.08 4.08 0 0 0 2.65 1c1.92.18 8.16.24 8.16.24s5 0 8.4-.25a3.46 3.46 0 0 0 2.41-1 5.17 5.17 0 0 0 1-2.38 36.22 36.22 0 0 0 .14-3.87v-1.82a36.28 36.28 0 0 0-.24-3.89"></path></svg></a></li>
        <li><a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://www.gematsu.com/rss/"><svg viewBox="0 0 32 32" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"><path d="M 5 5 L 5 9 C 14.93 9 23 17.07 23 27 L 27 27 C 27 14.85 17.15 5 5 5 z M 5 12 L 5 16 C 11.07 16 16 20.93 16 27 L 20 27 C 20 18.72 13.28 12 5 12 z M 8 21 A 3 3 0 0 0 8 27 A 3 3 0 0 0 8 21 z"></path></svg></a></li>
      </ul>
    </section>

    

    <section>
      <p>© Copyright Gematsu 2008 to 2024. All rights reserved.</p>
      <p>Reproduction in whole or in part in any form or medium without acknowledgment of Gematsu is prohibited. Use of this site is governed by all applicable laws.</p>
    </section>

    <section>
      <p>Website by <a title="44 Bytes Ltd - Intelligent Internet Services" href="https://www.44bytes.net/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">44 Bytes</a></p>
    </section>

  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘The Game Is Absolutely Not Dying’: Ubisoft on XDefiant’s Year-One Roadmap]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/xdefiant-not-dying-ubisoft-says/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/%E2%80%98the-game-is-absolutely-not-dying%E2%80%99-ubisoft-on-xdefiant%E2%80%99s-year-one-roadmap.984027/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/xdefiant-not-dying-ubisoft-says/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Ubisoft has published a sizeable roadmap that covers XDefiant’s first year on the market, outlining the next three seasons of content. In a blog post, the team highlighted the key development focuses going forward, including ‘bandwidth reduction efforts’ and improvements to XDefiant’s netcode and ‘hitreg’.</p>



<p>In the relatively transparent blog post, the team stated quite clearly that ‘<strong>the game is absolutely not dying</strong>‘, addressing recent community-driven concerns that XDefiant is already on shaky ground mere months after release.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-but-it-kind-of-is">But It Kind of Is</h2>



<p>When it was released in May, XDefiant soared up the charts, quickly becoming regarded as the first Ubisoft title to hit substantial milestones as rapidly as it did. As a free-to-play, multiplatform shooter, it was essentially guaranteed that XDefiant would do well at launch, but the numbers quickly paled as gamers moved on to bigger and better things.</p>



<p>Today, the player count is wavering, the sentiment around the game has faded, and viewership on social and streaming platforms is slim to nothing.</p>



<p>But Ubisoft is determined to keep the game afloat, despite recent claims that it has a brief window to turn things around <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/xdefiant-player-numbers-2/">before the game enters dangerous territory</a>.</p>



<p>In <a href="https://www.ubisoft.com/en-au/game/xdefiant/news/5uIKnSBuGp6nEszPe9NlfG" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">a blog post</a> written by Mark Rubin on the Year-One Roadmap, it was said:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>I just want to quickly address the status of the game. i.e. is the game dying? No, the game is absolutely not dying. We know there are things we need to improve like Netcode/Hitreg and adding more content to progression, but the game is doing well. We just want it to do better. </p>



<p>And we do that by addressing the concerns of our community which has always been the plan. Ubisoft is very much behind us and has allocated more resources to the team in order for us to do that.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Today, the team will reveal what’s coming in season two of XDefiant, but until then, users can leaf through the graphic provided by Ubisoft for the road ahead:</p>



<figure></figure>







<p>The driving focus of the team right now is stabilising the game’s networking elements, which have long been a sticking point for players worldwide. Plenty of content sits on the horizon, and the folks at Ubisoft are still determined to produce an esports ecosystem for XDefiant, but will there be enough players to keep the game afloat until then?</p>



<p>Are you still playing XDefiant? Let us know on the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/">Insider Gaming Forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fans-battlefield-6-concept-art-setting/">location of the Battlefield 6 concept art</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Handbook of Esports’: 764-Page Deep Dive Into the Esports Industry Unveiled]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/handbook-of-esports-routledge/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/%E2%80%98handbook-of-esports%E2%80%99-764-page-deep-dive-into-the-esports-industry-unveiled.984024/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/handbook-of-esports-routledge/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Routledge has announced the impending release of ‘Handbook of Esports’, a comprehensive and gargantuan deep-dive title into the full breadth of the esports industry. This monster of a handbook is marked as being ‘the first fully comprehensive, interdisciplinary study of esports’, and it’s designed to give even the most uninformed readers the full scope of the wider market.</p>



<p>It’s available to pre-order now with Routledge and will be released on September 24.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-learn-everything-about-esports">Learn Everything About Esports</h2>



<p>The <a href="https://www.routledge.com/Routledge-Handbook-of-Esports/Jenny-Besombes-Brock-Cote-Scholz/p/book/9781032531502" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Routledge Handbook of Esports</a> is a hefty title, numbering 764 pages and 62 chapters, and featuring contributions from almost 100 industry experts and academics. It’s not cheap, though – buying the book from Routledge will set you back more than $200 for the hardback edition or $40 for the eBook. </p>



<p>If you were looking for the most comprehensive breakdown of the entire esports industry, you’ll be hitting the mark with this handbook, though.</p>



<p>The Handbook of Esports covers everything from the global history of the industry to the key stakeholders, genres, and games that make up the broader business. Hundreds of pages are dedicated to the career process, the skills required to be an esports pro player or a coach, and what goes into dealing with esports injuries.</p>



<p>For those currently studying an esports course at university or college, there’s an entire section that covers esports business and organisation management. This goes into everything from sponsorship to PR, and from organising events to financing a business in esports.</p>



<p>It also covers:</p>



<ul>
<li>Esports gambling</li>



<li>Toxicity in esports</li>



<li>Esports law</li>



<li>Environmental sustainability</li>
</ul>



<p>You’ll be hard-pressed to find a better resource to catch up on the last thirty or forty years of esports history.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming Esports, check out the news about <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/who-won-the-international-2024/">the winners of The International 2024</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>