<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 20:06:29 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Diablo IV Spiritborn Class Revealed in Blizzard Livestream]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/diablo-iv-spiritborn-class-revealed-in-blizzard-livestream/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/diablo-iv-spiritborn-class-revealed-in-blizzard-livestream.931260/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/diablo-iv-spiritborn-class-revealed-in-blizzard-livestream/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>It's been over a year since <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/diablo-iv-great-albeit-safe-hack-n-slash-action/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the release of Diablo IV</a>, while the Vessel of Hatred expansion was <a href="https://wccftech.com/diablo-iv-vessel-of-hatred-gets-october-date-new-cinematics-trailer/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced</a> at BlizzCon 2023. Today, an official livestream shared the first details on the upcoming brand-new Spiritborn class.</p>
<p>Spiritborn hail from Nahantu, a brand-new area players will explore and campaign through in the DLC. They can swap between the realm of the living and the spirit realm. Their mission is to sustain the harmony between Sanctuary and the Spirit Realm. However, for young, living Spiritborn, stepping into the Spirit Realm is not recommended, as it is a dangerous journey predominantly left to the elders.</p>
<p>In this<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VjVUD8eLCFY" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> live stream</a>, players see a trailer of the Spiritborn and how they came to be. Additionally, you get to witness their combat style. The Spiritborn utilizes martial arts and can also connect with Spirit Guardians and summon them to fight alongside you in small bursts. Depending on what abilities you are focusing on, it can change your fighting style completely.</p>
<p>Depending on the Spirit Guardian, it can change how you deal your damage. As explained in the live stream by Art Director Nick Chilano, they all have unique fighting styles. The Gorilla uses blunt force damage and is intensely strong. The Jaguar utilizes cleave attacks, multi-hit combos, and agility, and the Centipede uses open-palm strikes and applies poison. Finally, the Eagle is a precision-based guardian who focuses on repositioning on the battlefield as and when needed.</p>
<p>With the addition of the Spiritborn, Diablo will see a mount that isn't a horse added to the game. There will also be the addition of pets, where you can get the Alkor Snow Leopard, Hralti Canine, and Natalya the Tiger pets.</p>
<p>During the live stream, the developers showcased some of the abilities players can expect to see and utilize when experimenting with the Spiritborn. Unlike some other classes available in Diablo IV, Spiritborn will be a highly agile, fast-attacking class, regardless of what Guardian you use.</p>
<p>This will become an ultimate ability for those who want to see their Spirit Guardian on the battlefield. While you may catch glimpses of them in your abilities, they will instantly be summoned to your side once you cast your Ultimate.</p>
<p>Going for a Jaguar (Rezoka) build will have fast-paced attacks, multi-attack combos, and plenty of fiery flair. Players must focus on attack speed to get as many cleave attacks as possible to get the most out of the Jaguar. Additionally, the Jaguar provides a buff that will increase attack speed to all Jaguar abilities, give them even more power, and reduce cooldowns to allow you to use abilities more often. One of the primary Jaguar skills showcased in the live stream is an ability called "Rushing Claws," where the player will dash through the target and slash at everything in its path. Rezoka's abilities all do Fire damage.</p>
<p>The Gorilla (Wumba) focuses its energy around protection and is a slightly tankier build than some others. You'll be able to retain the damage taken, buff your attacks using it, and return it to the enemy. The primary attribute of the Gorilla is damage reduction. An example of one of the primary abilities of the Gorilla is called "Crushing hands," which is very self-explanatory. It crushes all enemies on the spot in a small circle. Wumba's abilities do physical damage only.</p>
<p>The Eagle (Kwatli) is a highly agile guardian who enables freedom of movement with dashes, blinks, and more. Its primary attribute is movement speed. One of the main abilities of the Eagle is "Soar," which allows you to pick a target area to fly to, come down on enemies, and apply Vulnerable to them to enhance your attacks. Kwatli's abilities do Lightning damage.</p>
<p>The Centipede (Balazan) is about persistence and applying poison where possible. This build is one to look out for if you like damage-over-time builds and applying stacks of poison. In addition, the Centipede can also leech health back off of their enemies. One of the primary abilities of the Centipede is called "Stinger," and it causes a large amount of damage in a small circle area. However, it has the unique concept of pseudo-range, which can also echo damage onto nearby enemies who have been poisoned. In the live stream, Centipede's primary attribute is not mentioned. Balazan's abilities inflict Poison damage.</p>
<p>Each Spirit Guardian has their own key passive, which can help you decide on what build you want to choose and allow for a wider range of flexibility.</p>
<ul>
<li>Eagle: 30% Movement Speed</li>
<li>Gorilla: 30% Damage Reduction</li>
<li>Jaguar: 30% Attack Speed</li>
<li>Centipede: 30% Life Steal</li>
</ul>
<p>The Spiritborn class in Diablo IV is shaping up to be one of the most in-depth classes in the game, offering a wide range of abilities and ways to play the new DLC for those excited to get stuck into Diablo IV: Vessel of Hatred, the DLC releases on October 8, 2024. Once immersed in Nahantu, Spiritborn will have a class quest to complete, which unlocks the Spirit Hall, which is the brand-new mechanic for Spiritborn.</p>
<p><iframe title="Diablo IV | Vessel of Hatred | Spiritborn Reveal [English]" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/VjVUD8eLCFY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Utilizing the Spirit Hall will allow players to deepen their connection with the Guardians of their choice. You can select one as your Primary Spirit and either choose the same spirit again or a different Guardian for your secondary spirit at level 30. For even more info on the Spiritborn, check out <a href="https://news.blizzard.com/en-us/diablo4/24107497/awaken-the-ferocity-of-a-new-class-spiritborn" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Blizzard's blog post</a>.</p>

				

			
	<div>
		<h2>Products mentioned in this post</h2>
		
		<!--<p class="story-notice text-center">The links above are affiliate links. As an Amazon Associate, Wccftech.com may earn from qualifying purchases.</p>-->
	</div>

			
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Diablo 4: Vessel of Hatred Spiritborn Class Hands-On: Everything You Need to Know]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/diablo-4-vessel-of-hatred-spiritborn-class-hands-on-everything-you-need-to-know</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/diablo-4-vessel-of-hatred-spiritborn-class-hands-on-everything-you-need-to-know.931257/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/diablo-4-vessel-of-hatred-spiritborn-class-hands-on-everything-you-need-to-know<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>It doesn’t take all that much to get me to dive back into Blizzard’s stellar ARPG, Diablo 4, which has had a fantastic run of seasonal content and updates in the year since it made its devilish debut. But after an extensive hands-on with its upcoming character class, the Spiritborn, I might be kissing my free time goodbye altogether. This jack of all trades impressively mixes up the Diablo ecosystem with its most customizable and varied class yet, opens up a whole new unexplored aspect of Diablo lore, and most importantly, lets you summon a giant spectral gorilla to Hulk-smash demons into pink giblets. By the end of my time exploring Vessel of Hatred’s spooky jungles and dark dungeons, I was ready to forsake my roguish ways and declare myself a Spiritborn main, and that’s no small feat.</p><p>A quick housekeeping note: my time playing Diablo IV: Vessel of Hatred was focused almost exclusively on the Spiritborn character class. After choosing my preferred Spiritborn warrior, I was dropped right into the action in the new region of Nahantu to craft my build and dismember everything in sight. Though all of the following things are in there, I didn’t see any story, meet any NPCs (aside from vendors), or get to check out the new hireable mercenaries feature. That said, my access to the Spiritborn class and all it offers was pretty exhaustive, so I’ll be focusing on that. Let’s dive in!</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>The Spiritborn are an entirely new class to the Diablo series, complete with their own lore that’s tied up in the ancient civilization of Nahantu – as seen in the Act 3 jungles of Diablo II – and the ethereal spirits with which they commune. Unlike the other Diablo IV classes, where you dive quite deep into a specific fantasy like tanking with the Barbarian or doing mad DPS with the Rogue, the Spiritborn is much more customizable and varied, thanks to the four guardian spirits you can choose to build into. Those four spirits are: the eagle, which focuses on mobility, evasion, and lightning damage; the gorilla, which is all about survivability and physical damage; the jaguar, which is the king of DPS, attack speed, and fire damage; and my personal favorite, the centipede, which uses poison, debuffs, and lifesteal to control the battlefield and feed off your foes’ misfortune.</p><p>Each of those spirit guardians is represented by a massive ghostly avatar that imbues you with power and occasionally takes to the battlefield itself to lay waste to your enemies, like how the centipede bursts onto the scene to start spitting giant globs of venom at everything in sight, or the eagle, which swoops in to zap your foes into dust. The skills and abilities that correspond with each of these spirits appear on the Spiritborn skill tree as color-coded nodes, so you can easily identify which you might want to focus on depending on your chosen spectral BFF.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>These four distinct styles, and the divergent builds you can create from them as a result, make the Spiritborn feel like four new classes in one. For example, a slow-moving, extremely resilient gorilla build will feel very different from a jaguar build where you’re teleporting around the map. But although you’ll need to choose one of them to be your primary patron, one of the most defining characteristics of the character class is the ability to hybridize your build with some of the powers offered by other guardian animals. So, for example, if your jaguar build is feeling a bit squishy, you can reach across the aisle to your gorilla spirit and add a few of his tanky abilities to your repertoire, making yourself significantly more durable.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>The four distinct styles, and the divergent builds you can create from them as a result, make the Spiritborn feel like four new classes in one.</p></div><p>That’s a whole new ball game from the much more specific fantasies the other character classes offer, and at first I was worried that would make it feel like a jack of all trades and master of none. But the longer I played, the less I was concerned about the class feeling underpowered, as I went deep into a centipede-eagle (centipeagle?) build that had me filling the battlefield with life-sapping poison, then dashing out of reach when things got too hot. “You would think that it would have some kind of identity crisis, but if you play the build it doesn't – it works,” Diablo IV Game Director Brent Gibson told me. “And I think the team has done a great job at picking the right things inside of each of the lanes that make it so unique and distinct without trying to turn it into giant cream corn.” From what I’ve played so far, I tend to agree.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>After trying out half a dozen different builds, I’m very much sold on this extremely unorthodox class, and I really got a kick out of how different each of the spirits felt and how flexible the class was in allowing me to take on different roles depending on my current need or flight of fancy. It remains to be seen if any of these builds will be able to compete with the five existing and much more focused classes, but so far I’m really encouraged by what I saw, and have a feeling I’ll be running as a Spiritborn exclusively when I tackle Vessel of Hatred later this year.</p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mario Kart Wii's Rainbow Road Is Apparently Canonically Positioned Over a Large Part of Canada]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/mario-kart-wiis-rainbow-road-is-apparently-canonically-positioned-over-a-large-part-of-canada</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mario-kart-wiis-rainbow-road-is-apparently-canonically-positioned-over-a-large-part-of-canada.931254/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/mario-kart-wiis-rainbow-road-is-apparently-canonically-positioned-over-a-large-part-of-canada<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>Mario Kart’s Rainbow Road holds a special place in the hearts of many, and it also happens to hover over very specific parts of our planet.</p><p>X/Twitter account <a href="https://x.com/MarioBrothBlog/status/1813963215778533380" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@MarioBrothBlog</a> highlighted the placement of the racing series’ most iconic track in a series of posts. Those who have put in some time into the Nintendo spinoff franchise might have noticed that Earth can be seen below some versions of Rainbow Road in-game. Mario Broth offers an in-depth analysis of the size and location of both the Mario Kart 8 and Mario Kart Wii iterations of Rainbow Road, revealing that they both cast shadows over very different parts of the planet.</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Mario Kart Wii's and Mario Kart 8's Rainbow Roads are both depicted as floating above the Earth. By examining the skyboxes, we can map their real-world locations. The Wii Rainbow Road is over Canada, while the Mario Kart 8 Rainbow Road is over the Mediterranean. <a href="https://t.co/MUoHwhYiOL" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/MUoHwhYiOL</a></p>— Supper Mario Broth (@MarioBrothBlog) <a href="https://twitter.com/MarioBrothBlog/status/1813963215778533380?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">July 18, 2024</a></blockquote> <p>Mario Kart Wii’s Rainbow Road is massive, covering a large portion of Canada and even a sliver of Greenland. Quebec and Nunavut get the most coverage, with the starting line placed just above the former. Mario Kart 8, meanwhile, seems to be positioned above the Mediterranean Sea and Tyrrhenian Sea, centered between Sardinia, Sicily, and Tunisia. It’s also much smaller than its Nintendo Wii counterpart. Mario Broth notes that the Booster Course Pass re-release of the Wii track uses this same skybox, putting it in same place.</p><p>But wait, there’s more! X user <a href="https://x.com/SB2749/status/1813970883037593864" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@SB2749</a> was able to track down a 3D model of the Mario Kart Tour version of Wii Rainbow Road, which comes with a few small changes. Notably, the gargantuan course hovers above Southeast Asia instead of Canada in the mobile entry, swallowing more than half of Japan with one sharp turn.</p><blockquote data-conversation="none" data-theme="light"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Addendum: reader <a href="https://twitter.com/SB2749?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@SB2749</a> has provided the location of the Mario Kart Tour version of the Wii Rainbow Road track, which is in yet another location, covering Japan, China and Southeast Asia: <a href="https://t.co/2xD73iMtYR" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://t.co/2xD73iMtYR</a></p>— Supper Mario Broth (@MarioBrothBlog) <a href="https://twitter.com/MarioBrothBlog/status/1813972175600423090?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">July 18, 2024</a></blockquote> <p>Nintendo likely didn’t intend for any version of its Rainbow Road to be built to scale, but it’s still fun to imagine you might catch a glimpse of Mario and co. if you break out a telescope. Meanwhile, Nintendo’s Mario Kart series is currently between releases. The last numbered entry arrived on the Wii U in 2014, though Nintendo’s managed to make the most of that experience with a Deluxe re-release for the Switch in 2017. A long list of DLC additions have since arrived over the course of the last few years via the Booster Course Pass, which wrapped up with <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/mario-kart-8s-final-wave-of-booster-course-pass-content-lands-next-week"><u>its final wave of content late last year</u></a>.</p><p>There’s no word on when another installment will appear. However, fans are patiently awaiting any news regarding <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-confirms-it-will-announce-switch-successor-console-within-this-fiscal-year"><u>Nintendo’s Switch successor</u></a>. It’s <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/dont-expect-the-nintendo-switch-2-before-april-2025"><u>not expected to launch anytime before April 2025</u></a>. You can see what little we know about the mysterious device <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-everything-we-know"><u>here</u></a>.</p><p><em>Michael Cripe is a freelance contributor with IGN. He started writing in the industry in 2017 and is best known for his work at outlets such as The Pitch, The Escapist, OnlySP, and Gameranx.</em></p><p><em>Be sure to give him a follow on Twitter @MikeCripe.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Overwatch 2 Reveals Newest Support Hero, and She'll Be Playable This Weekend]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/overwatch-2-reveals-newest-support-hero-and-shell-be-playable-this-weekend</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/overwatch-2-reveals-newest-support-hero-and-shell-be-playable-this-weekend.931251/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/overwatch-2-reveals-newest-support-hero-and-shell-be-playable-this-weekend<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>Blizzard has officially revealed Overwatch 2’s newest support hero, Juno. She’ll be available to play for a limited time from July 19 through July 21.</p><p>Juno, then known as Space Ranger, was first teased at Blizzcon 2023 alongside Venture. At the time, all players could gleam about Juno’s abilities was that she was armed with a blaster and Death Stranding-esque shoulder attachments to her space suit. Thanks to her gameplay trailer, we know they aren’t just for show. In fact, they can target heal her allies, and attack her enemies. </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>Here’s Blizzard’s official breakdown of her abilities:</p><p>"Juno is equipped with Pulsar Torpedoes that can lock onto multiple targets. Her Glide Boost ability allows her to swiftly maneuver the battlefield to provide critical support wherever she’s needed. Juno's Hyper Ring propels the team into action, while her Ultimate Orbital Ray boosts damage and replenishes health."</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>Juno is one highly mobile Martian 🛸👩‍🚀</p><p>💥 Primary Fire: Mediblaster<br>🎯 Secondary Fire: Pulsar Torpedoes<br>💫 Abilities: Glide Boost &amp; Hyper Ring<br>🚀 Ultimate: Orbital Ray</p><p>Check out her kit and try it out for yourself during her limited-time trial July 19 through July 21 ✨ <a href="https://t.co/OenFBF5R2X" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/OenFBF5R2X</a></p></div>— Overwatch (@PlayOverwatch) <a href="https://twitter.com/PlayOverwatch/status/1813974518924230984?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">July 18, 2024</a></blockquote> <p>In a <a href="https://x.com/PlayOverwatch/status/1813968475674861771" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>separate tweet</u></a>, Blizzard also revealed Juno’s voice actor, Xanthe Huynh. You might’ve heard Huynh’s voice in anime and video games like Alluka Zoldyck in Hunter x Hunter, Haru Okumura in Persona 5, Haruka Sawamura in Like A Dragon: Infinite Wealth, and Inutade and Fleki in Delicious in Dungeon. </p><p>“We’re SO excited to have her in the game and can’t wait to hear even more Juno,” Blizzard wrote. </p><p>Juno’s arrival also bolsters the free-to-play hero shooter’s roster a tad more in favor of its support players. As of the time of writing, Overwatch 2 has 12 tank characters, 18 attack characters, and 10 support characters. Hopefully, once Juno is fully integrated into the game, support mains will find her added mobility and her orbital laser-esque ultimate ability will give both seasoned and newbie healers a much-needed assist pushing the payload. </p><p>Isaiah Colbert is a freelance writer for IGN. You can follow them on Twitter @ShinEyeZehUhh.</p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Endzone 2 launches in Early Access on August 26]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/07/endzone-2-launches-in-early-access-on-august-26</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/endzone-2-launches-in-early-access-on-august-26.931248/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/07/endzone-2-launches-in-early-access-on-august-26<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>Endzone 2</em> is a post-apocalyptic survival colony builder, where you embark to secure humanities survival after a cataclysmic disaster. Discover and repopulate the last habitable grounds, while the survival of your people hinges on your wits, foresight, and resilience in a harsh and unforgiving world.</p><p>Survivors,</p><p>The time has come to surpass the confining limits of these lands. Our brightest minds have constructed machinery that allow us to break free and venture beyond our borders!</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Let there be no doubt—even after centuries, Mother Nature’s anger remains unbroken. She is the same untamed beast she was when our ancestors stepped out of the Endzone. Our way will be filled with obstacles, misery, and death. Yet, we are pioneers, born with a unwavering curiosity to expand, rebuild, and thrive. Together, we will rekindle humanity.</p><p><em>—Jeremiah Sawchyn, Leader of Expedition 01</em></p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li>Survive amidst a relentless and ever-changing environment in a world of constant threat.</li><li>It’s your turn to freely choose your starting point by taking direct control of your settlement bus.</li><li>Venture into the treacherous badlands, a terrain riddled with ancient ruins, hidden loot, and daring missions.</li><li>Explore habitable zones full of unique resources and daunting challenges, giving rise to multiple settlements under your command.</li><li>Build, develop, and expand your settlements, forging a remarkable landmark with many buildings and upgrades.</li><li>Secure your economic progress by researching new buildings, technologies, and refined resources as well as optimized production lines.</li><li>Master your trade skills as you establish and manage trade routes between your zones and traders that are essential for your survival.</li></ul><p><strong>Develop Your Settlement</strong></p><p>Survive in a world of constant threats, including radioactively contaminated ground, droughts, toxic rain, and sandstorms. Grow and expand your settlement, research technologies, refine resources, and manage your economy by building an efficient infrastructure.</p><p><strong>Stabilize Your Legacy</strong></p><p>Nurture your settlement by thoughtfully caring about the needs of your people. Forge trading routes between your zones and traders, facilitating the exchange of vital goods. Transcend mere survival and usher your settlement into an era of flourishing prosperity.</p><p><strong>A Motorized Takeoff</strong></p><p>In <em>Endzone 2</em>, you hit the road with your trusty bus, navigating through the badlands — an uninhabitable and treacherous terrain scattered with ruins, loot, and missions. Yielding to your curiosity and exploring these areas may reward you with special resources, technologies, and new trading partners. However, it can also place you in deadly peril, triggering disasters or jeopardizing the lives of your explorers.</p><p><strong>Discover the Unknown</strong></p><p>As you journey through the badlands, you’ll encounter habitable zones — expansive plots of land ripe for settlement and scarce resource harvesting. Each zone boasts its own unique array of resources, so choose your next settlement location wisely and let your journey flow.</p><p><strong>An Unforgiving World</strong></p><p>In <em>Endzone 2</em>, the landscape and environment are in constant flux, presenting ever-changing challenges just around the corner! Behold as sandstorms ravage the surroundings and droughts deplete your water supplies, leaving your zones parched and transformed into deserts.</p><p><strong>Key Changes and Additions</strong></p><p><em><a title="Games > Endzone: A World Apart [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/endzone-a-world-apart">Endzone: A World Apart</a></em> veterans, please read!</p><ul><li><strong>Zones</strong> – In <em>Endzone: A World Apart</em>, you played on one vast map where you could build a global settlement. But in <em>Endzone 2</em>, the world expands as you uncover different zones, each offering exclusive resources to plunder. <a title="Series > Mana [10 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/series/mana">Mana</a>ge multiple settlements and unlock a vast amount of possibilities.</li><li><strong>New Settler Behavior</strong> – We’ve tackled and refactored settler paths and job distribution issues from the ground up. Embrace the new and improved system, now more comprehensible and balanced, supporting thriving settlements with thousands of inhabitants.</li><li><strong>Vehicles</strong> – Your wish for vehicles back in <em>Endzone: A World Apart</em> has been heard! Now, you can freely choose your starting location by moving your settlement bus. As the game progresses, you’ll have the opportunity to construct additional vehicles, perfect for establishing trade routes or venturing into the treacherous badlands.</li><li><strong>Expedition System Overhaul</strong> – Exciting changes! The updated expeditions system introduces detailed ruins waiting to be explored by directly controlling and guiding your explorers. They consist of less text and more <a title="Genres > Action [2,018 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a>! Uncover clues, unlock secrets, and discover valuable loot on your journeys.</li><li><strong>New Graphics</strong> – Our rendering system has undergone a complete overhaul, bringing you a more detailed and visually stunning environment. The animations have received a makeover too, resulting in breathtaking graphics that will immerse you like never before.</li></ul></div><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Companies Distance Themselves As Players Recreate Trump Assassination Attempt In Fortnite, Roblox, And Minecraft]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/fortnite-roblox-minecraft-steam-trump-assassination-attempt</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/companies-distance-themselves-as-players-recreate-trump-assassination-attempt-in-fortnite-roblox-and-minecraft.931239/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://aftermath.site/fortnite-roblox-minecraft-steam-trump-assassination-attempt<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>We live in interesting times, even if many of us wish we didn’t. On Saturday, a shooter attempted to <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/possible-shots-fired-at-trump-rally-in-butler-pennsylvania/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">take the life of Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump</a>. Milliseconds later, the internet was awash with memes making light of the situation. This clockwork cycle plays out following almost any event of significance; the modern internet has been engineered for it. But the attack on Trump has backed companies behind games like <em>Fortnite</em>, <em>Minecraft</em>, and <em>Roblox </em>into an odd corner. Memes are one thing, but full-on recreations of the moment in iconic game settings are something else.</p><p>The past few days have seen recreations of Trump’s brush with death circulate in and around multiple games. Whether in <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/search?lang=en&amp;q=trump%20fortnite&amp;t=1721158876652" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Fortnite</em></a>, <a href="https://x.com/shitpost_2077/status/1812566883951915435" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Minecraft</em></a>, or <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/search/video?lang=en&amp;q=trump%20roblox&amp;t=1721158888735" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Roblox</em></a>, the most popular clips – which have amassed <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@brazquil/video/7391641361079864582?is_from_webapp=1&amp;sender_device=pc&amp;web_id=7342598075528398379" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">hundreds of thousands</a> or in some cases <a href="https://x.com/TheCumpound/status/1812889886841520472" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">millions of views</a> – all tend to take the same form: visuals of a game character futilely sniping a recognizably Trumpian target while a digital audience looks on and real-life audio of the incident plays. These clips are adorned with text like “Bro’s aim is so bad” and “Trump rally be like.”&nbsp;</p><p>It’s the kind of thing that shocks for a split second by catapulting a violent political event into a candy-colored playpen before almost immediately receding into the back of your mind, more grist for the endlessly churning meme mill. But these videos also rely on popular, kid-friendly games’ characters and settings, and what they depict is against those games’ rules.&nbsp;</p><p>“Depictions of real-world violence are clearly prohibited by our Support-A-Creator rules and the creator of the video has been actioned accordingly,” an Epic spokesperson told Aftermath in response to <a href="https://x.com/TheCumpound/status/1812889886841520472" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a popular video</a> I asked the company about. “We’ve also confirmed that the island shown in the video was never publicly available (published) in <em>Fortnite</em>.”&nbsp;</p><p>However, according to <a href="https://globalextremism.org/post/fortnite-to-platform-violent-content/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a new report</a> from the Global Project Against Hate and Extremism (via <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/fortnite-has-a-political-violence-problem/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Wired</a>), multiple player-made attempts at a "Trump vs Assassin" game type appeared in <em>Fortnite </em>following the assassination attempt, before being removed by Epic. Additionally, the organization was able to find numerous other player-created islands that propagated political violence, racism, and antisemitism, many of which it reported and some of which remain accessible despite that.   </p><p>A spokesperson from Roblox Corporation replied similarly to Epic, noting that creators can use the company’s Roblox Studio tool to create scenarios that they don’t actually publish, which then serve as fodder for these sorts of videos.&nbsp;</p><p>“While we value friendly debate about issues and topics that matter to our community, we prohibit the discussion or depiction of certain political content in order to maintain a civil and respectful environment,” the spokesperson told Aftermath, noting that prohibited topics include current candidates running for political office, sitting elected officials, political parties, and flag burning. "Many developers use Roblox Studio, our free application to create an experience, and don’t publish on Roblox platform, but often share the experience/gameplay on social media platforms."</p><p>Roblox will intervene in some cases where off-platform behavior is especially egregious, the spokesperson added: "If a developer created content in Roblox Studio that violated that policy – for example, making a credible real world threat and then posted it to another platform – Roblox can take action."&nbsp;</p><p>The spokesperson also noted that ten percent of Roblox Corporation’s full-time workforce – plus “thousands” of contractors – are dedicated to content moderation, a net which is meant to prevent experiences that center around real-world political figures, among other things, from slipping through. But <em>Roblox</em> has <a href="https://corp.roblox.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">over 70 million daily active users</a> spread across over 5 million experiences. Sometimes rule-breaking experiences manage to make the cut, including – among others – one about the JFK assassination, as <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vjEjU9uFUhk&amp;t=470s" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">highlighted by YouTuber Schlep</a> late last year. The Roblox spokesperson told Aftermath that the JFK experience is no longer accessible. As of yesterday evening, a small handful of Trump-themed experiences existed on the platform, but they did not appear to focus on the assassination attempt.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><p>Microsoft, which owns <em>Minecraft</em>, did not reply to a request for comment.</p><p>This all rests against a backdrop of companies and institutions <a href="https://aftermath.site/how-should-we-talk-about-the-trump-thing" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">awkwardly fumbling to figure out</a> how to talk about the attempt on Trump’s life. Democrats have <a href="https://abcnews.go.com/Politics/after-trump-assassination-attempt-biden-campaign-pauses-ads/story?id=111930384" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">paused campaign-crucial efforts</a>. Tenacious D <a href="https://variety.com/2024/music/news/jack-black-cancels-tenacious-d-tour-trump-assassination-kyle-gass-1236073486/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">canceled a tour</a> after a joke from one of its members. Kick, the Twitch rival typically known for its almost-anything-goes approach to moderation, <a href="https://www.dexerto.com/kick/kick-bans-streamer-destiny-for-hate-speech-after-trump-shooting-backlash-2827880/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">banned controversial streamer Steven “Destiny” Bonnell</a> following inflammatory comments about Corey Comperatore, a 50-year-old firefighter who <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/07/14/politics/corey-comperatore-trump-shooting-victim/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">died at Trump’s rally</a>.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><p>The responses from Epic and Roblox Corporation paint a similar picture: Companies, despite providing the tools that form the backbone of these videos, largely believe themselves responsible while creations are within their games’ ecosystems. This makes a degree of sense, as even massive companies cannot be everywhere at all times. However, with engagement-thirsty platforms like Twitter, TikTok, and YouTube seemingly uninterested in damming up these streams of content, we end up in an odd spot where <em>nobody </em>is wholly responsible for videos that use popular IP to recreate the attempted murder of a former United States president and current presidential candidate. Game companies could probably cease-and-desist offending material if they really wanted to, but so far, it does not appear that any have opted to do so.</p><p>That’s not to say that somebody <em>should </em>be in a position to unilaterally do something about video game recreations of the assassination attempt. Online platforms continue to struggle to figure out where to draw the line when it comes to political content, with many <a href="https://www.npr.org/2024/03/26/1240737627/meta-limit-political-content-instagram-facebook-opt-out" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">opting to suppress it</a>. Meanwhile, the United States government keeps on pushing a TikTok ban for reasons that register as Awfully Sus whether you view them through <a href="https://www.rollingstone.com/politics/politics-news/lawmakers-tiktok-ban-pro-palestinian-content-1235016101/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">political</a> or <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2024/04/24/tiktok-ban-benefits-meta-google/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">economic</a> lenses. By comparison, some meme-y videos of a blocky Donald Trump ducking behind a podium – or in particularly minimalist interpretations, nothing – are the least of our problems. And while one could make the argument that this kind of content further raises the heat of the political cauldron that boiled over into last weekend’s assassination attempt, that’s fixating on a symptom rather than the root cause, which is – <a href="https://aftermath.site/how-should-we-talk-about-the-trump-thing" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">as Riley recently put it</a> – “the Right’s violent rhetoric looping around to bite them in the ass.” People should be able to discuss these issues freely, even if only to joke about them.&nbsp;</p><p>We're not in open-season territory here, however. Companies have a responsibility to proactively take down content that is hateful in its aims or associations, like the kind uncovered by the Global Project Against Hate and Extremism in <em>Fortnite</em>, lest it be used to lure young users down the internet's darkest corridors. On this front they have routinely come up short, over-relying on user reports and broad rule sets that fail to catch savvily-packaged hate.</p><p>For the time being, at least, games will remain a thread in the larger tapestry of our engagement with these escalating events. People are stuck on a ride they desperately wish would stop or at least slow down, powered by online engines designed to siphon away negative feelings and turn them into fuel for a machine that exists simply to devour more fuel. So people rage at their own powerlessness – or just gawk, for fun – in the language of the time: nihilistic memes. As The New Yorker's Kyle Chayka recently <a href="https://www.newyorker.com/culture/infinite-scroll/the-trump-assassination-attempt-meets-the-internets-brain-rot-era?fbclid=IwZXh0bgNhZW0CMTAAAR11cMlY7UcXR8pnMNnBKKIFcJuy77JbOP_3LI4iy6hmxPCgdvNYLHihGe8_aem_lj5pNBNqheOq9SGZTYUGiQ" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">described the phenomenon</a>:&nbsp;</p><blockquote><p>"The form of the content — its production value and valence, like a subatomic particle’s spin — surpasses the underlying raw material. The attempted assassination of a former President is treated with the same catholic flippancy as a pop album or a Chinese glycine factory’s ads. … The result is not quite satire; it is absurdism without insight, our new lingua franca online. What qualifies as important is inextricable from what goes viral, and vice versa. ‘Brat summer’ has the same weight as an act of political violence, and thus the two are inevitably mixed to create something even more clickable. Meaning matters less than recognizability, the split second of understanding the joke."</p><span><blockquote></blockquote></span></blockquote><p>But some with years of experience creating memes argue that meaning does still matter, that memes can outlive their moment. In the days following the assassination attempt, <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/507010/MrPresident/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a 2016 game called <em>Mr President!</em></a> – in which you play as a bodyguard attempting to fling themselves in front of sniper bullets hurtling at a “bankrupt billionaire” who is obviously Donald Trump – received hundreds of new Steam reviews. “This game aged amazingly,” reads one. “Well damn,” reads another.</p><p>At the time of its release, <em>Mr President!</em> was largely regarded as a gimmick. Now it seems downright prescient. Despite the game’s wacky physics and short runtime, its developer, who goes by the handle Game Developer X, says it was always meant as a cautionary tale – not just a cheap meme.</p><p>"When I originally created <em>Mr.President!</em> before the 2016 election, it was built around the logical conclusions of this megalomaniac figure who has openly expressed deep xenophobic rhetoric, admiration for dictators, blatant sexist history, and just a non-stop compulsive liar,” Game Developer X told Aftermath. “People can write it off as a dumbass physics game propped up and broadcasted by YouTubers, but that is the vehicle I chose to get my message across. … In many ways this game was built as a warning sign or a monument to a dark path our country missed. Eight years later this game is more relevant than the day it was made because of the lack of foresight and compassion this country has lost."</p></div><div><h2>Stay in touch</h2><p>Sign up for our free newsletter</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mamma Mia, Luigi's Mansion 2 HD For Switch Has Already Received A Big Discount]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/mamma-mia-luigis-mansion-2-hd-for-switch-has-already-received-a-big-discount/1100-6525114/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mamma-mia-luigis-mansion-2-hd-for-switch-has-already-received-a-big-discount.931209/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/mamma-mia-luigis-mansion-2-hd-for-switch-has-already-received-a-big-discount/1100-6525114/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6525114">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>The Switch has seen several HD remasters and remakes released on it lately, and if you didn't pick up Luigi's Mansion 2 HD at launch last month, you can get a pretty good discount on it right now. Over at Woot, <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.anrdoezrs.net%2Fclick-100770772-13142092%3Fsid%3Dsubid_value%26url%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Felectronics.woot.com%2Foffers%2Fluigis-mansion-2-hd-international-version-region-free-1&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fmamma-mia-luigis-mansion-2-hd-for-switch-has-already-received-a-big-discount%2F1100-6525114%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">you can save 25% on the game</a>, as the retailer is offering it for the frightfully good price of $45.</p><p>Woot's listing shows the US box art, but the URL mentions "international version," so it's possible you'd get an imported copy from a different region. However, this wouldn't change the playability of the game, as the Nintendo Switch is a region-free console. The only difference here would be the ESRB rating on the box would be replaced with another region's ratings board logo.</p><p>But back to the game itself. Originally released on the Nintendo 3DS in 2013 as Luigi's Mansion: Dark Moon, Luigi's Mansion 2 HD stars Mario's taller brother as he finds himself in another haunted neighborhood. Fortunately, the plumber is equipped with some ghostbusting gear and can hoover up the pesky phantoms haunting Evershade Valley. This remaster updates the game for the Switch, and while the old-school tank controls do take some getting used to, Luigi's Mansion 2 HD is full of charm and humor that gives it a quirky personality.</p><p>"Luigi's Mansion 2 HD isn't as essential as some other recent Switch remasters, but it's a charming look at how the ghostly adventure series found its footing," Steve Watts wrote in GameSpot's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/luigis-mansion-2-hd-review-weegee-board/1900-6418246/" data-ref-id="1900-6418246">Luigi's Mansion 2 HD review</a>.</p><p><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.dpbolvw.net%2Fclick-100770772-13142092%3Fsid%3Dsubid_value%26url%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Felectronics.woot.com%2Fplus%2Fvideo-game-summer-sale&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fmamma-mia-luigis-mansion-2-hd-for-switch-has-already-received-a-big-discount%2F1100-6525114%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Woot is also holding a big sale</a> on video games and accessories, so if you're looking to save some more cash, there's a great selection of things to check out right now on that site. Other games like <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.kqzyfj.com%2Fclick-100770772-13142092%3Fsid%3Dsubid_value%26url%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Felectronics.woot.com%2Foffers%2Frobocop-rogue-city-1%3Fref%3Dw_cnt_wp_0_121&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fmamma-mia-luigis-mansion-2-hd-for-switch-has-already-received-a-big-discount%2F1100-6525114%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">RoboCop: Rogue City</a>, <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.tkqlhce.com%2Fclick-100770772-13142092%3Fsid%3Dsubid_value%26url%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Felectronics.woot.com%2Foffers%2Foctopath-traveler-ii%3Fref%3Dw_cnt_wp_0_122&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fmamma-mia-luigis-mansion-2-hd-for-switch-has-already-received-a-big-discount%2F1100-6525114%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Octopath Traveller 2</a>, and <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.tkqlhce.com%2Fclick-100770772-13142092%3Fsid%3Dsubid_value%26url%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Felectronics.woot.com%2Foffers%2Flike-a-dragon-infinite-wealth-1%3Fref%3Dw_cnt_wp_0_139&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fmamma-mia-luigis-mansion-2-hd-for-switch-has-already-received-a-big-discount%2F1100-6525114%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Like a Dragon: Infinite Wealth</a> have received big discounts, and for hardware, you can pick a nice <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.jdoqocy.com%2Fclick-100770772-13142092%3Fsid%3Dsubid_value%26url%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Felectronics.woot.com%2Foffers%2Fhori-wireless-horipad-controller-for-nintendo-switch%3Fref%3Dw_cnt_wp_0_5&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fmamma-mia-luigis-mansion-2-hd-for-switch-has-already-received-a-big-discount%2F1100-6525114%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Hori wireless controller</a> for the Switch for just $30 or the retro-influenced <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.jdoqocy.com%2Fclick-100770772-13142092%3Fsid%3Dsubid_value%26url%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Felectronics.woot.com%2Foffers%2Fnew-8bitdo-arcade-stick-for-xbox-series-xs-xbox-one-and-windows-10z-6%3Fref%3Dw_cnt_wp_0_11&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fmamma-mia-luigis-mansion-2-hd-for-switch-has-already-received-a-big-discount%2F1100-6525114%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">8BitDo Fight Stick</a> for Xbox for $75.</p><div tabindex="0" data-id="249831856" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6464477,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Luigi%27s%20Mansion%202%20HD%20Review&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:528,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:false,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/luigis-mansion-2-hd-review\/2300-6464477\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464477\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464477\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464477\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6464477&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6464477,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6525114&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;luigis-mansion-dark-moon&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;action,adventure&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;3ds,nintendo-switch&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;nintendo&quot;,&quot;franchise&quot;:&quot;luigis-mansion&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;franchiseRoot&quot;:&quot;mario&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6464477},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6464477\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;GameSpot&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1823\/18237460\/4324301-luigi_site.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/lAcTySIZ.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1719327600,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="lAcTySIZ" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle" data-embed-type="video" data-ref-id="2300-6464477" data-src="/videos/luigis-mansion-2-hd-review/2300-6464477/" data-width="854" data-height="480" data-video-start="0"><div><p>Luigi's Mansion 2 HD Review</p><div><p>         Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?       </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!       </p></div></div><p>       Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.     </p><p>       This video has an invalid file format.     </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div><div data-embed-type="pinbox" data-ref-id="4304">  <ul>                              <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/dozens-of-blu-ray-box-sets-are-still-on-sale-after-prime-day/1100-6525099/">Dozens Of Blu-ray Box Sets Are Still On Sale After Prime Day</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/studio-ghiblis-the-boy-and-the-heron-4k-limited-edition-restocked-and-discounted-at-amazon/1100-6523029/">Studio Ghibli's The Boy And The Heron 4K Limited Edition Restocked And Discounted At Amazon</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-wonderfully-cheesy-resident-evil-movies-are-on-sale-in-this-post-prime-day-deal/1100-6525100/">The Wonderfully Cheesy Resident Evil Movies Are On Sale In This Post-Prime Day Deal</a></li>                          <li>         <span>+ Show More Best Deals Still Available After Prime Day 2024 Links (1)</span>       </li>          <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-dark-knight-trilogy-4k-blu-ray-is-on-sale-for-best-ever-price-of-30-at-amazon/1100-6524931/">The Dark Knight Trilogy 4K Blu-Ray Is On Sale For Best-Ever Price Of $30 At Amazon</a></li>   </ul> </div>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/108490194306897153177?rel=author">Darryn Bonthuys</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Two Hours With Diablo 4: Vessel Of Hatred's Spiritborn Reveals A Diablo Class Unlike Any Other]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/two-hours-with-diablo-4-vessel-of-hatreds-spiritborn-reveals-a-diablo-class-unlike-any-other/1100-6525108/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/two-hours-with-diablo-4-vessel-of-hatreds-spiritborn-reveals-a-diablo-class-unlike-any-other.931203/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/two-hours-with-diablo-4-vessel-of-hatreds-spiritborn-reveals-a-diablo-class-unlike-any-other/1100-6525108/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="">

            
          
  

<section><p>A class that doesn't feel like anything seen in the series before, Spiritborn channel the gods themselves to decimate foes in visceral fashion.</p></section>
        
        
                    
              <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/diablo-iv/" data-ref-id="5000-504255">Diablo 4</a> launched with only returning classes from past entries to choose from, all instantly familiar to fans of fantasy RPGs: Barbarian, Rogue, Sorcerer, Necromancer, and Druid. One class that was notably missing was a Paladin-type--some kind of holy warrior to dole out divine punishment to demons and evildoers in kind. Many fans expected Diablo 4's first expansion would look to fill that gap in the base game's roster. Instead, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/diablo-4-vessel-of-hatred-coming-october-4-new-trailer-revealed/1100-6524085/" data-ref-id="1100-6524085">Vessel of Hatred</a> will introduce a brand-new class to the franchise, one that is fast, frenetic, and fun: the Spiritborn.</p><p dir="ltr">I got the chance to spend two hours putting the Spiritborn through its paces at a preview event, using four premade, level-30 builds and talking to Blizzard about how the new class came to be. The Spiritborn isn't a Paladin, but that's for the best--it's something entirely new, and a class that doesn't feel like anything fans have ever seen before in Diablo. That being said, it does provide some of the same power-fantasy those who had hoped for a holy warrior might find appealing, as the Spiritborn channel the power of gods themselves to rip their foes apart.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="1859296051" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6464621,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Diablo%204%3A%20Vessel%20of%20Hatred%20-%2024%20Minutes%20Of%20Spiritborn%20Gameplay&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:1480,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/diablo-4-vessel-of-hatred-24-minutes-of-spiritborn-gameplay\/2300-6464621\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464621\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464621\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464621\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6464621&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6464621,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;feature_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6525108&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;diablo-iv&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;action,role-playing&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;pc,playstation-4,xbox-one,xbox-series-x,playstation-5&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;blizzard-entertainment,activision&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;franchise&quot;:&quot;diablo&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;franchiseRoot&quot;:&quot;diablo&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6464621},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6464621\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;GameSpot&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4336197-gp_site.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/oErYmAwJ.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1721329200,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="oErYmAwJ" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> Diablo 4: Vessel of Hatred - 24 Minutes Of Spiritborn Gameplay</p>
      </div>
<h2 dir="ltr"><strong>Welcome To The Jungle</strong></h2><p dir="ltr">Spiritborn are deeply tied to the new region being introduced in Vessel of Hatred: the dense jungles of Nahantu that players may remember from <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/diablo-ii/" data-ref-id="5000-798">Diablo 2</a>. During Diablo 4's development, Blizzard knew where the story would take Neyrelle and the soulstone of Mephisto. Rather than shoehorn in a class that had little to do with the new part of Sanctuary players were set to explore in the expansion, Blizzard instead opted to create a new one that would have a deep connection to Nahantu and establish a strong sense of cohesion with the expansion as a whole. It was from that goal the idea of the Spiritborn was conceptualized.</p><p dir="ltr">Before unlocking their full power, those seeking to become Spiritborn undergo a coming-of-age ritual deep in the forest, one that the vast majority of participants don't survive. Those who come out the other side undergo a metamorphosis in the Spirit Realm after communing with powerful Spirit Guardians: massive, ghost-like animals that are the embodiment of the laws of Nahantu's unforgiving jungles. Ever since the events of Diablo 2, the Spiritborn have been lying in wait, anticipating the return of evil to Nahantu. The arrival of Mephisto's soulstone to the region sees them pushed into battle against the forces of Hell once more.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4336249-diablo4spiritbornarmor.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4336249" data-ratio="0.5622641509434" data-width="1855" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4336249-diablo4spiritbornarmor.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4336249"></a><figcaption>Spiritborn wield glaives, polearms, and quarterstaffs while channeling their Spirit Guardians to devastating effect.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4336249-diablo4spiritbornarmor.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">The Spiritborn channel the power of the Spirit Guardians, but they are formidable martial warriors as well, wielding glaives, polearms, and quarterstaffs to attack enemies with a rapid flurry of blows. Their fighting style is inspired by different real-world martial art styles, bringing a dash of Diablo 3's Monk to the class. Meanwhile, their look takes inspiration from a number of pre-Columbian civilizations like the Aztec and Mayans. Eleni Rivera-Colon, associate narrative designer on Diablo 4, said Blizzard made sure not to "copy and paste" an existing culture. Instead, Blizzard imagined what such a culture might look like in the dark world of Sanctuary. Spiritborn don't wear armor in the traditional sense, as their clothing is not meant to protect them so much as to help honor and channel the Spirit Guardians, while also enabling the acrobatic and rapid movements seen in the class' gameplay.</p><p dir="ltr">"[Spirit Guardians are] not just protecting the Spirit Realm, but they're also protecting the Spiritborn that's calling upon them, [so Spiritborn] don't really need this heavy armor," Rivera-Colon said. "They need something that's going to make them very fast and can move very well. All of those things played into [the look of the class]."</p><h2 dir="ltr"><strong>Choose Your Spirit Guardians</strong></h2><p dir="ltr">It's hard to overstate how big an impact the Spirit Guardians have on the Spiritborn's gameplay. Each Spiritborn skill is associated with one of the four guardians, and players can choose to focus on skills of one particular type or mix and match for a playstyle all their own.</p><ul><li dir="ltr">Jaguar abilities are aggressive and mobile, with combo attacks that deal fire damage and generate Ferocity, a stacking attack-speed buff.</li><li dir="ltr">Skills channeling the stalwart Gorilla Spirit Guardian are designed for frontline warriors who want to absorb damage and dish it out in equal measure, with many Gorilla skills generating Resolve, an additional form of damage mitigation.</li><li dir="ltr">Eagle Spirit Guardian skills revolve around precision, movement, and lightning damage while also generating Focus, a buff improving evasion and increasing movement speed.</li><li dir="ltr">Most terrifying is the Centipede Spirit Guardian, the embodiment of decay and rebirth in the jungle, and whose skills deal poison damage to enemies and restrict their movements.</li></ul><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4336255-diablo4spiritborncentipede.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4336255" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="3456" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4336255-diablo4spiritborncentipede.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4336255"></a><figcaption>The Centipede Ultimate skill blasts enemies with beams of concentrated poison.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4336255-diablo4spiritborncentipede.jpg"></figure><p>These Spirit Guardians truly are the star of the show. Basic abilities and core abilities give players just a glimpse of each Spirit Guardian's power as their essence is channeled through the Spiritborn's weapon. Unleashing one of the class's four Ultimate skills (one for each Spirit Guardian) brings the gods of the Spirit Realm crashing down onto foes in their full glory.</p><ul><li dir="ltr">The Centipede Ultimate ability executes low-health enemies and fires beams of poison at distant threats.</li><li dir="ltr">The Jaguar unleashes a fiery hurricane of attacks.</li><li dir="ltr">The Gorilla's Ultimate mimics its "stand your ground" playstyle, pummeling a designated area repeatedly.</li><li dir="ltr">For the Eagle's Ultimate, the bird of prey crashes down and unleashes a storm of lightning in a location, knocking down foes.</li></ul><p dir="ltr">In my two hours with the expansion, I spent time playing a number of different builds, fighting my way through some of Nahantu's new strongholds and dungeons. Some builds featured skills that focused largely on only one Spirit Guardian. Others featured a combination of skills from two or three Spirit Guardians, shoring up the weaknesses of one Spirit Guardian with the strengths of another. Even for those who go all-in on one Spirit Guardian, the Spiritborn's unique class mechanic, the Spirit Hall, allows players to access some of the strengths or unique features of other Spirit Guardians without necessarily having abilities native to those Guardians on their action bar. Players can pledge devotion to two Spirit Guardians in the Spirit Hall, the first at level 15 upon completing the Spiritborn's class quest (which is said to be longer and more involved than the class quests seen in the base game) and another at level 30.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4336257-diablo4spiritbornjaguar.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4336257" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="3456" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4336257-diablo4spiritbornjaguar.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4336257"></a><figcaption>The Jaguar Ultimate skill deals massive fire damage to nearby enemies, and, if you're lucky, can be used multiple times in quick succession.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4336257-diablo4spiritbornjaguar.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">Diablo 4 class designer Bjorn Mikkelson said the team wants to give players the tools to make whatever build they want to make, whether it's sticking largely to one Spirit Guardian or branching out into multiple.</p><p dir="ltr">"From the start, something we were interested in was really exploring what it would look like for a class that kind of has the ability to mix-and-match," Mikkelson said. "That was something we always really wanted. 'Play Your Way' has always been something we've said for Diablo 4, and Spiritborn was like, 'Can we take that to another level?'"</p><h2 dir="ltr"><strong>Deadly Build Possibilities</strong></h2><p dir="ltr">Combat can feel wildly different depending on which Spirit Guardian's abilities players opt to use. Playing an all-Gorilla build feels slow and steady, focusing less on mobility or evading damage and instead on standing your ground before pounding enemies into the dirt. Conversely, a Jaguar build feels kinetic and frantic. Many Jaguar skills dash to enemies and can be used multiple times in quick succession, including the Jaguar Ultimate ability, resulting in a combo-like flow state. Eagle builds are more ranged-focused and extremely mobile, but require careful positioning and ability usage. Centipede, meanwhile, debuffs enemies with slows and poison, offering a more passive playstyle as enemies die all around you, in turn creating more death and decay.</p><p dir="ltr">Of the four, I found myself drawn most to Jaguar, largely due to its quick-paced gameplay and the ability to chain attacks together. Especially fun was that, thanks to a talent point, there was a decent chance of the Jaguar Ultimate abilty's cooldown being instantly reset whenever I killed an enemy while it was active. That allowed me to continue summoning the Spirit Guardian repeatedly for a limited number of times, after which all surrounding enemies had been reduced to ash.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4336258-diablo4spirithall.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4336258" data-ratio="0.5627931214174" data-width="1919" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4336258-diablo4spirithall.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4336258"></a><figcaption>The Spiritborn's class mechanic, the Spirit Hall, lets players gain additional benefits from up to two different Spirit Guardians.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4336258-diablo4spirithall.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">While I didn't have time to dive into the deep end and meticulously theorycraft my own unique build featuring skills from multiple Spirit Guardians, I can already see the potential. Jaguar builds are more fast-paced and fragile, but splashing in a few defensive Gorilla skills might help to make the build sturdier. Meanwhile, combining the evasiveness of Eagle skills with the debilitating effects of Centipede skills could result in a build that would allow players to run circles around their slowed and poisoned enemies, all the while picking them off at range. There are tons of possibilities, but players can certainly stick to one particular playstyle (made simple by the color-coated nature of each Spirit Guardian's abilities displayed in the skill tree) and find success doing so. However, the true potential of the class comes from blending different Spirit Guardian skills. Mixing in different abilities to help eliminate some of the weaknesses inherent to builds that focus on a single Spirit Guardian is entirely the point, associate class designer Stephen Stewart said.</p><p dir="ltr">"That's where the beauty of the class really starts to sing," Stewart said.</p><p dir="ltr">From my time playing it, I'm inclined to agree. The Spiritborn makes for a fascinating cocktail of gameplay variety. I was never bored trying out the different builds, and as I saw more of what the class had to offer, lightbulbs began to go off in my head as I started piecing together ideas for how I could combine my favorite elements of each playstyle into one all my own. Mixing together abilities from different categories already exists in Diablo 4, but the strongly defined identities of each Spirit Guardian and their corresponding skills make it even easier at a glance to understand how a particular skill could slot into a build.</p><p dir="ltr">Those who had hoped to see a class from Diablo's past make a return for Diablo 4's first expansion may initially be disappointed, but even as a huge Paladin fan, I found it refreshing to see a new idea brought to life. Creating a new class that feels right at home in the gothic fantasy world of Diablo while also not relying on standard fantasy archetypes is no small task, but I came away impressed at the attention to detail and thought that had gone into the worldbuilding, visuals, and gameplay for the Spiritborn. There is still much we don't know about the story of the Spiritborn and the expansion as a whole, but I'm excited to dive in and see if Blizzard can stick the landing. As for the Diablo 4 team behind the class, the Spiritborn is a chance for them to put their own stamp on the franchise, rather than simply following in the footsteps of what came before.</p><p dir="ltr">"It's the idea of the open space of creativity, right?" Stewart said. "Because the five existing classes are ones that we've seen in the Diablo world before, but getting that opportunity to just go free your mind... We've done a really good job of being stewards of the franchise, and now let's add our footprint, our DNA, to a brand-new class. For me, there's a lot of reverence and apprehension and fear and excitement and all that, because I was a fan of these games before I worked on these games. And so it's cool to say, 'I made that, the new thing,' rather than taking a thing that had already existed and putting a new spin on it."</p><p dir="ltr">Diablo 4's Vessel of Hatred expansion, and its new Spiritborn class, launch on October 8.</p>
  
                                                              </div>
    

              <div>
  <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>
  
    </div>
      
        
        
  
              


  

    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apex Legends' Steam Review Score Plummets In The Wake Of New Battle Pass Changes]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/apex-legends-steam-review-score-plummets-in-the-wake-of-new-battle-pass-changes/1100-6525121/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/apex-legends-steam-review-score-plummets-in-the-wake-of-new-battle-pass-changes.931200/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/apex-legends-steam-review-score-plummets-in-the-wake-of-new-battle-pass-changes/1100-6525121/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6525121">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/apex-legends/">Apex Legends</a>' Steam page has been inundated with negative user reviews following the announcement that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/apex-legends-will-now-have-two-battle-passes-per-season-says-respawn/1100-6524756/">Season 22 will feature two battle passes</a>. Prior to the July 8 announcement, the game was earning roughly 150 to 300 negative user reviews (and a similar amount of positive user reviews) daily. But in the days following the announcement of the battle pass changes, the game has earned a <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1172470/Apex_Legends/#app_reviews_hash" rel="nofollow ">total of 35,035 negative reviews</a>, dropping its score for the month of July to "overwhelmingly negative." Only 1,997 of the user reviews posted since July 8 are positive.</p><p dir="ltr">Starting with Season 1: Wild Frontier (which launched in March 2019), Apex's battle passes have stuck to an unchanging recipe. Each season has featured a new battle pass with 110 levels of cosmetics and in-game currency for players to unlock after purchase. Previously, Apex's seasonal battle passes cost 950 Apex Coins ($9.50 USD) each, though players could spend 2,800 AC ($28 USD) to automatically unlock the first 25 levels of the battle pass. But starting in Season 22, Respawn will be releasing two 60-level battle passes per season, with the first battle pass launching alongside the new season, and the second arriving at the season's midpoint.</p><div data-embed-type="tweet" data-src="https://x.com/PlayApex/status/1810330029265420515" data-has-image="true"><blockquote data-conversation="none" data-mce-disable-toolbar="true"><p dir="ltr">Starting with Season 22, we’re evolving the Apex Legends Battle Pass to improve your experience and progression goals.<br>Read on to learn everything to know about the upcoming changes or check out the infographic below to learn more. <br>📃: <a href="https://t.co/kg5NhlFfVq" rel="nofollow ">https://t.co/kg5NhlFfVq</a> <a href="https://t.co/i516ktP9ma" rel="nofollow ">pic.twitter.com/i516ktP9ma</a></p>  — Apex Legends (@PlayApex) <a href="https://twitter.com/PlayApex/status/1810330029265420515?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 8, 2024</a></blockquote>              </div><p dir="ltr">Additionally, there's been a price change: Each battle pass will now cost $10 USD ($20 USD for the upgraded version), and battle passes will no longer be available to purchase with Apex Coins, a change that players are especially displeased with. Previously, each battle pass included enough Apex Coins to purchase the next season's battle pass, meaning that once players purchased and completed a single battle pass, the next season's pass would effectively be available for free, provided they didn't spend their Apex Coins on something else.</p><p dir="ltr">With the new changes to the battle-pass system, players who wish to complete an entire season's worth of battle-pass content will be paying over twice as much per season as they previously were, will not be able to use Apex Coins to obtain the battle pass for free, and will be faced with 120 levels of content to unlock instead of 110. The mid-season split also means there will be less time to unlock those rewards. Each season of Apex Legends lasts roughly three months, and it's common for players to wait until the end of the season to finish grinding out the XP needed to finish their battle pass. Now, players who want to get their money's worth and stay up-to-date with the game's cosmetics will need to ensure they've unlocked all 60 levels of each battle pass every month-and-a-half.</p><p dir="ltr">"​​Buying the battle pass for free with the money from older ones is literally the only thing that makes you feel rewarded as an older player and they removed that from us," reads one negative review from a player who has spent over 1,500 hours playing the game.</p><p>In total, Apex has earned 879,014 user reviews in its lifetime, and the game currently holds a "mostly positive" overall rating, with 73% of user reviews giving the game a thumbs up. Respawn has yet to comment on player feedback regarding the new battle-pass system, but the studio did unveil <a href="https://x.com/PlayApex/status/1813953109993083061" rel="nofollow ">a new collection of premium cosmetics</a> via the game's social media channels on July 18.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Warhammer 40,000: Speed Freeks roars into Early Access August 6th]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/07/18/warhammer-40000-speed-freeks-early-access-august-6/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/warhammer-40-000-speed-freeks-roars-into-early-access-august-6th.931170/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/07/18/warhammer-40000-speed-freeks-early-access-august-6/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p data-sourcepos="3:1-3:28">Warhammer 40,000: Speed Freeks, the free-to-play vehicular combat game, has had its early access release date confirmed, and that date is August 6th. The announcement comes after a successful open beta was held in May 2024. Players who participated in the beta got a taste of the brutal races and explosive combat that Speed Freeks had to offer. It featured a game mode called Kill Konvoy, where two teams of eight players battled it out to get their Stompa to the finish line first.</p>
<p><iframe title="Warhammer 40,000: Speed Freeks – Release Date Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/BLRTsjrCP00?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p data-sourcepos="9:1-9:154">In Warhammer 40,000: Speed Freeks, players take control of different warbands of Orks, with the two modes confirmed as the aforementioned Kill Konvoy, and Deff Rally. The latter has teams of 8 battle against each other, or race to capture points. The game is entirely free to play, with developer Caged Element Inc stating that there will be no pay to win elements. All paid content will be optional and just customisation options. The progress players make in Early Access will carry over to the full release, which is expected later this year. When that full version releases a new map and new vehicle will be added, along with significant gameplay upgrades.</p>
<p data-sourcepos="9:1-9:154">To play Warhammer 40,000: Speed Freeks, players will need to create a Speed Freeks account. The dev team explain the reason, saying, <em>“We understand that some gamers are tired of making accounts, we get it. But collecting anonymous user data allows us to improve the game, and the ability to get in touch with players directly impacts the number of users that will be playing it. Free to play games have always survived with the assistance of user accounts, and we’re asking you to make one so that it helps create a better, free experience that you guys can possibly enjoy for years.The Speed Freeks account takes a few minutes to create, but we hope that you’ll take that time to quickly sign up and try our game.”</em></p>
<p data-sourcepos="9:1-9:154"><em>Source: <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2078450/Warhammer_40000_Speed_Freeks/">Steam</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[KONAMI Is at Gamescom, But Only for the Yu-Gi-Oh! TCG]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/konami-is-at-gamescom-but-only-for-the-yu-gi-oh-tcg/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/konami-is-at-gamescom-but-only-for-the-yu-gi-oh-tcg.931167/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/konami-is-at-gamescom-but-only-for-the-yu-gi-oh-tcg/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Earlier this week, the Gamescom staff sent out an email to the press mentioning some of the confirmed exhibitors, and that list included KONAMI. Indeed, when checking the Gamescom biz app, I could verify that KONAMI has secured a booth in Hall 4.1, A071/D080, which is in the business area.</p>
<p>You could be forgiven for thinking that they'd bring their highly anticipated remakes: Silent Hill 2 and Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater. However, that's not at all what KONAMI is showing there this year: as I confirmed with their PR agency, the Japanese publisher will be focusing solely on the popular Yu-Gi-Oh trading card game.</p>
<p>Needless to say, that's extremely disappointing both to us as press members and especially for you as readers, since there won't be any new impressions or information to be shared for either game. It is surprising, to say the least, especially for Silent Hill 2, which is <a href="https://wccftech.com/silent-hill-2-remake-new-2024-trailer-gameplay-release-date/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">scheduled to launch just a month and a half after Gamescom</a> on PC and PlayStation 5.</p>
<p>We don't have a release date yet for Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater, but KONAMI has already <a href="https://wccftech.com/metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater-opens-pre-orders-confirms-battle-scars-will-remain-on-snake/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">opened</a> pre-orders for the retail editions. As such, it is unlikely that the game is more than a few months away from its launch.</p>
<p>Both remakes are powered by Unreal Engine 5 technology. While MGS is being made at an internal studio (with some additional help from Virtuos), Silent Hill 2 has been developed by Bloober Team, the Polish studio behind Layers of Fear, Observer, Blair Witch, and The Medium.</p>
<p>While Gamescom attendees and fans all over the globe will be inevitably disappointed with this news, it's still possible KONAMI is keeping new info and/or trailers for one or even both games in store for the Tokyo Game Show event, which will take place between September 26 and 29 this year.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, look forward to our live coverage from the German event in about a month from now.</p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Diablo 4 Reveals New Spiritborn Class]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/diablo-4-reveals-new-spiritborn-class/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/diablo-4-reveals-new-spiritborn-class.931146/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/diablo-4-reveals-new-spiritborn-class/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>When Diablo 4 Vessel of Hatred launches on October 8, players will get to experience an all new class for the first time known as Spiritborn. In a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VjVUD8eLCFY" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">live stream on its official channels</a> on Thursday, Blizzard unveiled Spiritborn for the first time to the world.</p>



<p>This <a href="https://news.blizzard.com/en-us/diablo4/24107497/awaken-the-ferocity-of-a-new-class-spiritborn" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">reveal gave players a look</a> at the design, gameplay, items, lore, and more. You can check out the reveal trailer below. You can also see all of the details you need to know about Spiritborn below.</p>



<h2 id="h-diablo-4-spiritborn-features">Diablo 4 Spiritborn Features</h2>



<h3 id="h-lore">Lore</h3>



<ul>
<li>Calls upon spirits to assist in combat. </li>



<li>Spirit guardians include the gorilla, jaguar, centipede, and eagle.</li>
</ul>



<h3>Design</h3>



<ul>
<li>The design of the class was inspired by the jungles of Nahantu in Diablo 4. </li>



<li>Rather than wear its armor, it fuses armor within the character itself.</li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-gameplay">Gameplay</h3>



<ul>
<li>It centers on dexterity and will be the fastest class in Diablo 4.</li>



<li>Spirit guardians are summoned, each having their own skills while summoned</li>



<li>Jaguar spirit guardian is designed around movement, AoE damage, and attack speed</li>



<li>Gorilla is more of a tank with a focus on damage reduction, damage reflection, and defense</li>



<li>Eagle focuses on movement speed, range, and being precise with attacks</li>



<li>Centipede “represents the abstract concept of life and death” that focuses on persistence. It utilizes life steal, poison damage, and crowd control. </li>



<li>You can go all-in on one spirit guardian or choose to mix and match with a combination of the four.</li>



<li>“All about personalization and expressing yourself,” the developers say.</li>



<li><strong>Spirit Hall Mechanic</strong> – gives you more customization options in the form of various bonuses.</li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-itemization">Itemization</h3>



<ul>
<li>Hybridization, Power Augmenting, Sub Power, and Unique Items are the four primary focuses</li>



<li>Hybridization are items that will allow stats to work together</li>



<li>Power Augmenting that will allow you take skills and boost it to a higher level</li>



<li>Sub powers are similar to skills but don’t exist in your treet</li>



<li>Unique Items such as the Score of the Earth boots allow you to build your character in the way you see fit within the class.</li>
</ul>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Diablo IV | Vessel of Hatred | Spiritborn Class Trailer" width="1200" height="675" src="about:blank" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/dsv8YGqw-hU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<hr>



<p>What do you think of Diablo 4’s new Spiritborn class for Vessel of Hatred? For more Insider Gaming, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/college-football-25-team-builder-launches-thursday-night-details-revealed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">read about Team Builder in College Football 25</a>. Also,&nbsp;<a href="https://www.youtube.com/@insider_gaming?sub_confirmation=1" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">subscribe to our YouTube channel</a>&nbsp;for exclusive shows, news, interviews, reviews, and more.</p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[College Football 25 Launch Guide - How To Get Release-Day Delivery, Free Gift Card, And Discounts]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ea-sports-college-football-25-release-day-preorder-buying-guide/1100-6525115/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/college-football-25-launch-guide-how-to-get-release-day-delivery-free-gift-card-and-discounts.931143/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ea-sports-college-football-25-release-day-preorder-buying-guide/1100-6525115/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6525115">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>At long last, there's a new officially licensed college football video game. It's been more than a decade since the last one hit the market, and now the aptly named <a href="https://www.amazon.com/EA-SPORTS-College-Football-25-PlayStation/dp/B0D3PBB78P?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">EA Sports College Football 25</a> is once again letting you take to the gridiron with your favorite collegiate teams. If you haven't yet preordered the game or didn't get early access via the deluxe/MVP editions, <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fclick.linksynergy.com%2Fdeeplink%3Fid%3DVZfI20jEa0c%26mid%3D38733%26u1%3Dsubid_value%26murl%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.samsclub.com%2Fp%2Fea-sports-college-football-25-playstation-5%2FP990348433&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fea-sports-college-football-25-release-day-preorder-buying-guide%2F1100-6525115%2F%3Fftag%3DCAD-01-10abi2f&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Sam's Club</a> is running a nice price cut that lets you pick it up for just $62.98 (down from $70). That's the first real discount we've seen for the game. If you want the fastest delivery, though, you should check Walmart's site, as <strong><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fgoto.walmart.com%2Fc%2F1804712%2F565706%2F9383%3Fveh%3Daff%26sourceid%3Dimp_000011112222333344%26u%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fsearch%3Fq%3Dea%2Bsports%2Bcollege%2Bfootball%2B25%2Bpreorder%26subId1%3Dsubid_value&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fea-sports-college-football-25-release-day-preorder-buying-guide%2F1100-6525115%2F%3Fftag%3DCAD-01-10abi2f&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Walmart is the only major retailer still offering free release-date delivery for July 19</a></strong> (as of July 18 at 11:45 AM PT / 2:45 PM ET).</p><p>All preorders come with the Alma Mater Ultimate Team Pack, Cover Athlete Team Ultimate Team Pack, and Bring Glory Home Ultimate Team Uniform Item bonuses.</p><h2>Where to Buy EA Sports College Football 25</h2><h3>PS5</h3><ul><li><strong><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fgoto.walmart.com%2Fc%2F1804712%2F565706%2F9383%3Fveh%3Daff%26sourceid%3Dimp_000011112222333344%26u%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FEA-Sports-College-Football-25-PlayStation-5%2F5900356133%3Ffrom%3D%2Fsearch%26subId1%3Dsubid_value&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fea-sports-college-football-25-release-day-preorder-buying-guide%2F1100-6525115%2F%3Fftag%3DCAD-01-10abi2f&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Buy at Walmart</a></strong> -- $70 - Free release-day delivery</li><li><strong><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fclick.linksynergy.com%2Fdeeplink%3Fid%3DVZfI20jEa0c%26mid%3D38733%26u1%3Dsubid_value%26murl%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.samsclub.com%2Fp%2Fea-sports-college-football-25-playstation-5%2FP990348433&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fea-sports-college-football-25-release-day-preorder-buying-guide%2F1100-6525115%2F%3Fftag%3DCAD-01-10abi2f&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Buy at Sam's Club</a></strong> -- $62.98 ($<del>70</del>)</li><li><strong><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fshop-links.co%2F1842405879371169978%3Fu1%3Dsubid_value&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fea-sports-college-football-25-release-day-preorder-buying-guide%2F1100-6525115%2F%3Fftag%3DCAD-01-10abi2f&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Buy at Best Buy</a></strong> -- $70 (Free $5 Gift Card) - Free $5 gift card with preorder, release-day store pickup</li><li><strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/EA-SPORTS-College-Football-25-PlayStation/dp/B0D3PBB78P?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Buy at Amazon</a></strong> -- $70</li></ul><h3>Xbox Series X</h3><ul><li><strong><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fgoto.walmart.com%2Fc%2F1804712%2F565706%2F9383%3Fveh%3Daff%26sourceid%3Dimp_000011112222333344%26u%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FEA-Sports-College-Football-25-Xbox-Series-X%2F5891016708%3Ffrom%3D%2Fsearch%26subId1%3Dsubid_value&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fea-sports-college-football-25-release-day-preorder-buying-guide%2F1100-6525115%2F%3Fftag%3DCAD-01-10abi2f&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Buy at Walmart</a></strong> -- $70 - Free release-day delivery</li><li><strong><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fclick.linksynergy.com%2Fdeeplink%3Fid%3DVZfI20jEa0c%26mid%3D38733%26u1%3Dsubid_value%26murl%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.samsclub.com%2Fp%2Fea-sports-college-football-25-xsx%2FP990348434&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fea-sports-college-football-25-release-day-preorder-buying-guide%2F1100-6525115%2F%3Fftag%3DCAD-01-10abi2f&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Buy at Sam's Club</a></strong> -- $62.98 ($<del>70</del>)</li><li><strong><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fshop-links.co%2F1848258863919379996%3Fu1%3Dsubid_value&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fea-sports-college-football-25-release-day-preorder-buying-guide%2F1100-6525115%2F%3Fftag%3DCAD-01-10abi2f&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Buy at Best Buy</a></strong> -- $70 - Free $5 gift card with preorder, release-day store pickup available</li><li><strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/EA-SPORTS-College-Football-25-PlayStation/dp/B0D3PB2DBS?tag=gamespot-promos-20&amp;tag=gamespot-buybutton-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Buy at Amazon</a></strong> -- $70</li></ul><p>While everyone can cash in on the deal, only Sam's Club members get free shipping. You'll also want to check your zip code for eligibility, though most will find this to be the cheapest way to pick up College Football 25.</p><p>If you have a Sam's Club nearby, consider signing up for a <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fstacksocial.sjv.io%2Fc%2F1804712%2F1168624%2F14766%3FsubId1%3Dsubid_value%26u%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.stacksocial.com%2Fsales%2Fsams-club-1-year-membership-with-auto-renew&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fea-sports-college-football-25-release-day-preorder-buying-guide%2F1100-6525115%2F%3Fftag%3DCAD-01-10abi2f&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">1-Year Membership</a>, which is only $25 via Stack Social and gets you free shipping on hundreds of other items throughout the year plus several other perks.</p><p>Sam's Club isn't the only place to snag College Football 25, as you'll also find it at <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fshop-links.co%2F1842405879371169978%3Fu1%3Dsubid_value&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fea-sports-college-football-25-release-day-preorder-buying-guide%2F1100-6525115%2F%3Fftag%3DCAD-01-10abi2f&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Best Buy</a>, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/EA-SPORTS-College-Football-25-PlayStation/dp/B0D3PBB78P?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Amazon</a>, and <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fgoto.walmart.com%2Fc%2F1804712%2F565706%2F9383%3Fveh%3Daff%26sourceid%3Dimp_000011112222333344%26u%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FEA-Sports-College-Football-25-PlayStation-5%2F5900356133%3Ffrom%3D%2Fsearch%26subId1%3Dsubid_value&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fea-sports-college-football-25-release-day-preorder-buying-guide%2F1100-6525115%2F%3Fftag%3DCAD-01-10abi2f&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Walmart</a>. Preordering at <strong>Best Buy will get you a free $5 gift card</strong>. You can order online and pick up your copy tomorrow, July 19, at your local Best Buy.</p><p>Walmart was offering a stylish steelbook edition--but it has since sold out. Still, the <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fgoto.walmart.com%2Fc%2F1804712%2F565706%2F9383%3Fveh%3Daff%26sourceid%3Dimp_000011112222333344%26u%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fsearch%3Fq%3Dea%2Bsports%2Bcollege%2Bfootball%2B25%2Bpreorder%26subId1%3Dsubid_value&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fea-sports-college-football-25-release-day-preorder-buying-guide%2F1100-6525115%2F%3Fftag%3DCAD-01-10abi2f&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">base game is available at the retailer</a>, and some locations are still <strong>eligible for free launch-day delivery with online orders</strong>.</p><p>Amazon doesn't have any special bonuses, though you can get free shipping (not release-day delivery, though).</p><p>Keep in mind that <strong>you can only get the preorder bonuses</strong> until the game launches tomorrow, so consider purchasing it today if you want a couple of extra in-game goodies.</p><div tabindex="0" data-id="1680054920" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6464553,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;EA%20Sports%20College%20Football%2025%20%7C%20Official%20Gameplay%20First%20Look%20Trailer&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:1264,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:false,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/ea-sports-college-football-25-official-gameplay-first-look-trailer\/2300-6464553\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464553\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464553\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464553\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6464553&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6464553,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6525115&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;ea-sports-college-football-25&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;playstation-5,xbox-series-x&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;electronic-arts&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6464553},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6464553\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;Publisher Asset&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4329788-11.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/loAqRu9R.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1720452480,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="loAqRu9R" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle" data-embed-type="video" data-ref-id="2300-6464553" data-src="/videos/ea-sports-college-football-25-official-gameplay-first-look-trailer/2300-6464553/" data-width="100%" data-height="100%" data-video-start="0"><div><p>EA Sports College Football 25 | Official Gameplay First Look Trailer</p><div><p>         Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?       </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!       </p></div></div><p>       Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.     </p><p>       This video has an invalid file format.     </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div><div data-embed-type="pinbox" data-ref-id="4304">  <ul>                              <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/dozens-of-blu-ray-box-sets-are-still-on-sale-after-prime-day/1100-6525099/">Dozens Of Blu-ray Box Sets Are Still On Sale After Prime Day</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/studio-ghiblis-the-boy-and-the-heron-4k-limited-edition-restocked-and-discounted-at-amazon/1100-6523029/">Studio Ghibli's The Boy And The Heron 4K Limited Edition Restocked And Discounted At Amazon</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-wonderfully-cheesy-resident-evil-movies-are-on-sale-in-this-post-prime-day-deal/1100-6525100/">The Wonderfully Cheesy Resident Evil Movies Are On Sale In This Post-Prime Day Deal</a></li>                          <li>         <span>+ Show More Best Deals Still Available After Prime Day 2024 Links (1)</span>       </li>          <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-dark-knight-trilogy-4k-blu-ray-is-on-sale-for-best-ever-price-of-30-at-amazon/1100-6524931/">The Dark Knight Trilogy 4K Blu-Ray Is On Sale For Best-Ever Price Of $30 At Amazon</a></li>   </ul> </div>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/105566936584242225941?rel=author">Jon Bitner</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shadow Of The Erdtree: Where To Find The Rolling Sparks Ash Of War]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-shadow-of-erdtree-rolling-sparks-1851598889</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/shadow-of-the-erdtree-where-to-find-the-rolling-sparks-ash-of-war.931125/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-shadow-of-erdtree-rolling-sparks-1851598889<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="1bbd6278abca5f34315b75c327291a64" data-recommend-id="image://1bbd6278abca5f34315b75c327291a64" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="The Tarnished stands before ancient ruins." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="The Tarnished stands before ancient ruins." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->FromSoftware / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="1bbd6278abca5f34315b75c327291a64" data-recommend-id="image://1bbd6278abca5f34315b75c327291a64" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="The Tarnished stands before ancient ruins." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>Rolling Sparks is an Ash of War added in <em>Elden Ring</em>’s <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.dpbolvw.net/click-8335294-14555742?sid=KT-&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.humblebundle.com%2Fstore%2Felden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree%3Fhmb_source%3Dsearch_bar&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.dpbolvw.net/click-8335294-14555742?sid=KT-&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.humblebundle.com%2Fstore%2Felden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree%3Fhmb_source%3Dsearch_bar" target="_blank" rel="sponsored noopener noreferrer nofollow noskim" data-vtas-click="self:InlineUrl:inline-url-postbody"><em>Shadow of the Erdtree</em></a></span><em> </em>expansion. It’s a powerful ability on its own, but when combined with the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-shadow-erdtree-lightning-perfume-bottle-1851588909&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-shadow-erdtree-lightning-perfume-bottle-1851588909">Lightning Perfume Bottle</a></span> and the right loadout, it can provide devastating damage to bosses. Learn more about it in our Lightning Perfumer build guide.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196673" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Putting An AI-Powered Gaming Aromatherapy Device To The Smell Test" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="244" data-playlist="196673,195502,195624" data-current="196673"><div><p>Putting An AI-Powered Gaming Aromatherapy Device To The Smell Test</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196673/196673_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196673/196673_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196673/196673_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196673/196673_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/22230.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p><strong>Read More:</strong> <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-shadow-erdtree-lightning-perfumer-build-1851589470&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-shadow-erdtree-lightning-perfumer-build-1851589470">Harness The Power Of Lightning With This Electrifying <em>Shadow Of The Erdtree</em> Build</a></span></p><p>Here’s what you need to know about the Ash of War: Rolling Sparks and where to find it.</p><h2 id="h20923"><a id="stat"></a>Ash of War: Rolling Sparks stats and features</h2><p>The Ash of War: Rolling Sparks can be applied only to Perfume Bottles. Using this skill will scatter perfume around you causing explosions based on the property of whatever Perfume Bottle you currently have it assigned to. </p><h2 id="h20924"><a id="desc"></a>Ash of War: Rolling Sparks item descriptions</h2><p>The Ash of War: Rolling Sparks’ item description reads:</p><blockquote data-type="BlockQuote"><p>“This Ash of Wars grants no affinity to an armament, but imparts the following skill:</p><p>Rolling Sparks: Scatter perfumed powder before you, triggering rolling explosions of deadly sparks. The properties of the spark are determined by the bottle used.</p><p>Usable on perfume bottles.”</p></blockquote><h2 id="h20925"><a id="find"></a>Where to find the Ash of War: Rolling Sparks</h2><p>You can find the Ash of War: Rolling Sparks in Scadu Altus just southeast of the entrance to the Shadow Keep legacy dungeon. The easiest way to reach it is by starting at the Highroad Cross Site of Grace and then heading north to a large encampment. If you haven’t defeated the Furnace Golem in this area yet, you may want to do so.</p><figure id="" data-id="d4c686a9bdd054a8b2c56a84aeec39c5" data-recommend-id="image://d4c686a9bdd054a8b2c56a84aeec39c5" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A map shows the location of the Highroad Cross." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A map shows the location of the Highroad Cross." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->FromSoftware / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="d4c686a9bdd054a8b2c56a84aeec39c5" data-recommend-id="image://d4c686a9bdd054a8b2c56a84aeec39c5" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A map shows the location of the Highroad Cross." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>To the east of the encampment are multiple smaller Perfumer encampments. High above one of these is a flying scarab that can be easily missed if you don’t know to look for it. When you spot it (using the image below to pinpoint its location if needed), use a ranged attack to bring it down.</p><figure id="" data-id="263de6552a57af585e8c0007fb96ac66" data-recommend-id="image://263de6552a57af585e8c0007fb96ac66" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A screenshot of a map shows a specific location." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A screenshot of a map shows a specific location." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->FromSoftware / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="263de6552a57af585e8c0007fb96ac66" data-recommend-id="image://263de6552a57af585e8c0007fb96ac66" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A screenshot of a map shows a specific location." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>When the flying scarab lands on the ground and perishes, you’ll automatically receive the Ash of War: Rolling Sparks as a reward. When you’re ready to apply it to one of your Perfume Bottles, go to Roundtable Hold and speak with Blacksmith Master Hewg.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Someone Ported The Best Simpsons Game To PS Vita]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/simpsons-hit-run-remake-port-remaster-ps-vita-switch-1851598852</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/someone-ported-the-best-simpsons-game-to-ps-vita.931122/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/simpsons-hit-run-remake-port-remaster-ps-vita-switch-1851598852<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="dc93d553e31d7a7644df23a980180eec" data-recommend-id="image://dc93d553e31d7a7644df23a980180eec" data-format="gif" data-width="800" data-height="450" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A gif shows someone playing The Simpsons Hit and Run on a Vita. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><span data-id="dc93d553e31d7a7644df23a980180eec" data-recommend-id="image://dc93d553e31d7a7644df23a980180eec" data-format="gif" data-width="800" data-height="450" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A gif shows someone playing The Simpsons Hit and Run on a Vita. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/games/the-simpsons-hit-run&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/games/the-simpsons-hit-run">The best <em>Simpsons </em>game ever made</a></span> has been ported to Sony’s old but still beloved portable console, the PS Vita. And it looks like a pretty awesome way to replay the classic game. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196411" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="A Typical Day On Persona 3 Reload’s Tatsumi Port Island" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="378" data-playlist="196411,196055,196626" data-current="196411"><div><p>A Typical Day On Persona 3 Reload’s Tatsumi Port Island</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196411/196411_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196411/196411_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196411/196411_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196411/196411_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21958.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>Released in 2003 to positive reviews, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/impressive-simpsons-hit-run-remake-was-made-by-one-f-1847530115&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/impressive-simpsons-hit-run-remake-was-made-by-one-f-1847530115"><em>The Simpsons: Hit &amp; Run</em></a></span> was a semi-open-world <em>GTA</em>-like video game set in Springfield and starring characters from the long-running animated series. It was developed by Radical Entertainment and sold incredibly well and was beloved by fans of the show.<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/simpsons-hit-and-run-2-sequel-remake-remaster-planes-1851038958&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/simpsons-hit-and-run-2-sequel-remake-remaster-planes-1851038958"> It almost got a sequel with planes</a></span>, but sadly, that never happened. While we never got a new <em>Hit &amp; Run,</em> fans have spent the past 20 years modding and porting the original game. For example, someone has done the work and got this popular open-world game running nicely on a PS Vita.  </p><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://youtu.be/SBh2i6aUAz8&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://youtu.be/SBh2i6aUAz8" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">As seen in a new video from <em>Good Vibes Gaming</em></a></span>, you can now play <em>The</em> <em>Simpsons: Hit &amp; Run</em> on a PS Vita thanks to fan dev <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://github.com/ZenoArrows&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://github.com/ZenoArrows" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">ZenoArrows</a></span>. Here’s the game in action on a Vita. </p><p> It’s not a perfect experience—sometimes the game’s world doesn’t fully render for a bit and there’s a bit of slowdown here and there—but it’s nothing awful and it still looks very playable. </p><p>Now, to get this running on your PS Vita you’ll need to <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://github.com/ZenoArrows/The-Simpsons-Hit-and-Run&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://github.com/ZenoArrows/The-Simpsons-Hit-and-Run" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">download some files from Github</a></span> and you’ll also need the OG files from <em>Hit &amp; Run</em>’s PC version, too. Follow the instructions and you’ll be driving around Springfield as Homer in no time. </p><p>This new port was built using code from the leaked<em> Simpsons Hit &amp; Run</em> source code. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/SwitchPirates/comments/1746wp3/simpsons_hit_run_homebrew_port_for_switch/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/SwitchPirates/comments/1746wp3/simpsons_hit_run_homebrew_port_for_switch/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">ZenoArrows actually was behind a previous port</a></span> of the classic game to Switch, and this Vita port seems to be built off that work. </p><p>While it continues to be great that fans are keeping <em>Hit &amp; Ru</em>n alive in 2024, it’s bonkers to me that Disney, Fox, and everyone else involved have yet to pay some studio to <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.ign.com/articles/simpsons-hit-and-run-designer-wants-remake&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/simpsons-hit-and-run-designer-wants-remake" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">port or remaster</a></span> the beloved <em>Simpsons </em>game ASAP. It seems like money sitting on the table. Can you imagine how well a Nintendo Switch port of <em>Hit &amp; Run </em>would do? And after it sold a bazillion copies, well then maybe we’d finally get a sequel. For now, though, I’ll just replay <em>Hit &amp; Run</em> on my Steam Deck via <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://modbakery.donutteam.com/releases/view/6&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://modbakery.donutteam.com/releases/view/6" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer">Lucas’ <em>Simpsons Hit &amp; Run</em> Mod Launcher</a></span> and keep dreaming of an official port. Maybe one day...</p><p>Or hey, just play the brand new <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/tiny-terry-turbo-trip-review-simpsons-hit-run-steam-pc-1851517168&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/tiny-terry-turbo-trip-review-simpsons-hit-run-steam-pc-1851517168"><em>Tiny Terry’s Turbo Trip</em></a></span> as it’s about the closest thing to a modern <em>Simpsons Hit &amp; Run</em> game we’ve gotten in the last 20 years. </p><p> .<br> </p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[College Football 25 Only Trails Call Of Duty And Fortnite On Popularity Chart]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/college-football-25-only-trails-call-of-duty-and-fortnite-on-popularity-chart/1100-6525116/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/college-football-25-only-trails-call-of-duty-and-fortnite-on-popularity-chart.931116/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/college-football-25-only-trails-call-of-duty-and-fortnite-on-popularity-chart/1100-6525116/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6525116">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>EA's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ea-sports-college-football-25-release-date-trailer-news/1100-6523761/" data-ref-id="1100-6523761">College Football 25</a> hit the ground running this week, it seems, as the game's early player statistics are proving to be extremely impressive.</p><p>Circana analyst Mat Piscatella <a href="https://x.com/MatPiscatella/status/1813973638275850649" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">shared on social media</a> that on July 17, College Football 25 ranked No. 3 in the US for daily active users on Xbox Series X|S, trailing only Call of Duty and Fortnite. On PS4, College Football 25 was No. 4, trailing Call of Duty, Fortnite, and Grand Theft Auto V.</p><p>Impressively, College Football 25 is putting up these numbers prior to the game's official release on July 19. So far, the game is only available to people who bought the $100 deluxe edition or tried the game via the EA Play 10-hour trial. The standard edition arrives on July 19.</p><div data-embed-type="tweet" data-src="https://x.com/MatPiscatella/status/1813974268520354121" data-has-image="false"><blockquote data-conversation="none" data-mce-disable-toolbar="true"><p dir="ltr">Looks like EA Sports College Football 25 may indeed be the mass market breakout hit this console gen really needs right now.</p>  — Mat Piscatella (@MatPiscatella) <a href="https://twitter.com/MatPiscatella/status/1813974268520354121?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 18, 2024</a></blockquote>              </div><p>The best that EA's college football games has ever performed was in 2006, <a href="https://x.com/MatPiscatella/status/1813979110164881682" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">when NCAA Football 2007 ranked No. 3 for sales in the US</a>, trailing only Madden NFL 07 and Gears of War. Piscatella has predicted that College Football 25 <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/college-football-25-passes-700000-concurrent-players-during-early-access/1100-6525040/" data-ref-id="1100-6525040">could land within the top 10 for US video game sales in 2024.</a></p><p>College Football 25 blasted off with <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/college-football-25-passes-700000-concurrent-players-during-early-access/1100-6525040/" data-ref-id="1100-6525040">more than 700,000 concurrent players earlier this week</a>. It's the first new entry in the series since 2013's NCAA Football 14. Since then, EA broke off its partnership with the NCAA and is now making the game through other licensing arrangements. The college athletes featured in the game are <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ea-offering-college-athletes-600-to-appear-in-new-football-game/1100-6521289/" data-ref-id="1100-6521289">being paid for their appearance thanks to NIL deals.</a></p><p>If you're just getting started with College Football 25, you can check out our guide for <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/how-to-do-all-celebrations-in-ea-sports-college-football-25/1100-6525088/" data-ref-id="1100-6525088">how to do all the celebrations</a> and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/which-coach-backstory-to-pick-in-ea-sports-college-football-25-dynasty/1100-6525026/" data-ref-id="1100-6525026">how to succeed in the dynasty mode.</a></p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vultures - Scavengers Of Death is a turn-based roguelike that looks like a vintage Resident Evil game]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/vultures-scavengers-of-death-is-a-turn-based-roguelike-that-looks-like-a-vintage-resident-evil-game</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/vultures-scavengers-of-death-is-a-turn-based-roguelike-that-looks-like-a-vintage-resident-evil-game.931083/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/vultures-scavengers-of-death-is-a-turn-based-roguelike-that-looks-like-a-vintage-resident-evil-game<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
  

        <p>Regretfully, you do not play a bird</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/vultures-scavengers-header.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Vultures Games</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p><a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/crow-country">Crow Country</a>, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/conscript">Conscript</a>, and now <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/vultures-scavengers-of-death">Vultures - Scavengers Of Death</a>. We really do seem to be living through a craze for PS1-style <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-best-horror-games">horror games</a>. Vultures is different to the others, though, in that it's turn-based zombie crunching combined with <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-roguelike-games-pc">roguelike</a> scavenging to survive and get more powerful. It's arriving on Steam sometime soon and it's probably worth a looksy if you're after biohazard disposal with a tactical twist.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>In Vultures, you play as a Vulture. No, not a grizzled bird that picks apart corpses with its beak and sits atop rocks for the vast majority of its lifecycle, but a human special operative - an operative who must clean up an infested metropolis through the power of turn-based clicking.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Vultures Scavengers of Death - TactiCon 2024 trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9u3rOafyFe8?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Vultures Scavengers of Death - TactiCon 2024 trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9u3rOafyFe8?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/9u3rOafyFe8?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9u3rOafyFe8" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>Vultures is neither a linear story like Resident Evil nor an open world. Instead, it's a roguelike where you're attempting to survive increasingly difficult scenarios and "get out alive with the target". At the beginning of each mission, you'll choose from a number of agents with their own combat styles, customise their loadouts, and grow stronger by scavenging things along the way. From my experience with survival horror: take the shotgun and everything will right itself.</p>
<p>Going off the trailer, it looks like blowing off limbs to thwart zombie approaches in tight spaces is the move. Otherwise, there's a strong Resi feel to the item rotating, keycode smashing, and inventory Tetris. I'd imagine with this roguelike, the horror element lies more in the fear of impending death by turn-based RNG or a gaggle of zombies you can't quite outmuscle. If you're after genuine scares and persisting in a space that only gets spookier and scarier, I can't see the bittiness of a roguelike being conducive to that. But then again, I don't think this is what it's going for and/or I'm very happy to be proven wrong!</p>
<p>You can keep up with Vultures - Scavengers Of Death over on its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2537470/Vultures__Scavengers_of_Death/">Steam page</a>.</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ubisoft Says xDefiant Helped With Early 2024 Financial Success]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/ubisoft-says-xdefiant-helped-with-early-2024-financial-success/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ubisoft-says-xdefiant-helped-with-early-2024-financial-success.931080/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/ubisoft-says-xdefiant-helped-with-early-2024-financial-success/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>Ubisoft released its first quarter financials for the 2025 fiscal year on Thursday. With the financial results came praise for the launch of the free-to-play shooter xDefiant.</p>



<p>According to the <a href="https://staticctf.ubisoft.com/8aefmxkxpxwl/3J1aM8p3bRqk3oSBRQPkFY/e2642b7dafe168b5c4ebb4acc9006f5f/Ubisoft_FY25_Q1_Sales_EN_vFinal.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">company’s release</a>, xDefiant had what it viewed as an “encouraging” start to its life since launch on May 21.</p>



<p>“The game outperformed expectations thanks to acquisition and strong average revenue per<br>session day,” the studio said.</p>



<p>After its launch, xDefiant reached 10 million players in its first two weeks. The game also saw multiple updates, including the addition of two game modes in Capture the Flag and Team Deathmatch.</p>



<h2 id="h-it-s-not-just-xdefiant">It’s Not Just xDefiant</h2>



<p>In addition to the success of xDefiant, Ubisoft says that Rainbow Six Siege, The Crew, and Assassin’s Creed have all helped with early financial success. That success comes in the form of $316.5 million in revenue. That is up 8.3% year-over-year as well as up 5.5% from initial target numbers.</p>



<p>The company also says that it’s expecting the upcoming launch of Star Wars Outlaws and Assassin’s Creed Shadows to add to that yearly revenue. For the second quarter, Ubisoft expects its net bookings or revenue to be about $545 million (€500m).</p>



<p>Lastly, the studio, once again, reaffirmed its push to expanding its Games as a Service (GaaS) offerings. They specifically mentioned the upcoming Year 2 roadmap for The Crew Motorfest as well as the Season 3 content for Skill and Bones.</p>



<p>Two games that will no longer be coming in fiscal year 2025 are Rainbow Six Mobile and The Division Resurgence due to the teams “taking the necessary time to ensure that these experiences deliver on expectations with optimized KPIs in the context of a demanding yet very large market.”</p>



<hr>



<p>What do you think of Ubisoft’s financial report and the success it attributes to xDefiant? For more Insider Gaming, check out the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/college-football-25-team-builder-launches-thursday-night-details-revealed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">full breakdown of Team Builder</a> in EA Sports College Football 25.</p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[College Football 25 Team Builder Launches Thursday Night, Details Revealed]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/college-football-25-team-builder-launches-thursday-night-details-revealed/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/college-football-25-team-builder-launches-thursday-night-details-revealed.931077/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/college-football-25-team-builder-launches-thursday-night-details-revealed/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>Ahead of the game’s global release, <a href="https://www.ea.com/games/ea-sports-college-football/college-football-25/news/college-football-25-team-builder" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">EA Sports has released</a> full details on College Football 25 Team Builder. </p>



<p>First thing’s first, Team Builder will launch on Thursday night for College Football 25 for everyone. It’ll be accessible via <a href="https://www.ea.com/games/ea-sports-college-football/team-builder" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the official website</a> when it goes live.</p>



<p>As far as what you’ll be able to create, it appears that almost nothing is off limits for players. Features of the mode include:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Logo and identity creation</strong> — You can create a primary, secondary, and tertiary logo. You can upload your own or choose and edit a generic logo</li>



<li><strong>Choose your uniform provider </strong>— Nike, Under Armor, or Adidas can be selected. The choice will impact the equipment available to your team as well as patterns on the jerseys and more.</li>



<li><strong>Multiple Uniform Combinations </strong>— You can have up to five total presets. To break it down, that’s five helmets, five jerseys, five pants, and five socks. This gives you 625 different combination options for your school.</li>



<li><strong>Helmet Freedom </strong>— There are matte, shiny, and chrome options for your helmets; custom logo placement, multiple color options, and more.</li>



<li><strong>Custom Layers </strong>— Rather than all one flat image, the designs for your uniform are individual custom layers. On helmets, you can have up to seven layers.</li>



<li><strong>Stadium and Field </strong>— There are eight components overall to choose from. For your stadium, there is no custom stadium creation. Instead, you select one of the 134 team stadiums within the game. From there, you create the name, how the crowd looks, the type of playing surface, the colors of the surface, logos, endzone design, benches, and sidelines.</li>



<li><strong>Custom Roster </strong>— With your team made, you get to modify your roster and set your playbooks.</li>
</ul>



<p>Team Builder Teams can only be used in private Online Dynasties. You can import up to 16 teams per Dynasty.</p>



<figure></figure>



<hr>



<p>What do you think of the Team Builder details in College Football 25? For more Insider Gaming, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/mortal-kombat-developer-netherrealm-studios-hit-with-mass-layoffs/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">read about the layoffs at Mortal Kombat developer NetherRealm</a>.</p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>