<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 21:16:20 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battlefield 6 Feels Like a Safe, Explosive Return to the Shooter’s Past]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/battlefield-6-preview</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/battlefield-6-feels-like-a-safe-explosive-return-to-the-shooter%E2%80%99s-past.1259004/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Considering we’re living through a period where it feels like every other game is a remake, remaster, or throwback of some sort, perhaps I should be less surprised that Battlefield 6 feels a lot like Battlefields 3 and 4. They were, of course, the glory years for EA and DICE’s large-scale multiplayer shooter – excellent maps, engaging objective-based modes, spectacular destruction, and the all-important class system. It seems like Battlefield 6 replicates all of that, at least as far as I can tell after having played two hours and change of the new, contemporary-set FPS across a number of maps and modes. That is a good thing, of course, especially since recent Battlefield history has been a bit of a rocky ride. But is this resurrection of past glories actually <em>exciting</em>? In the moment, absolutely. But on a grander scale? That’s a more difficult question. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Those exciting moments are often the result of the well-defined class system, which returns in a comfortingly familiar guise following Battlefield 2042’s missteps with its hero shooter-like Specialists. The Assault class can use their grenade launcher to breach through walls and then turn the startled soldiers who once huddled behind it into swiss cheese. The Engineer is the vital cog in a tank battle, using their acetylene torch to repair friendly armour and keep the cannon fire rolling, even as an entire building collapses around them. The Support is the squad’s literal lifeline, diving onto the objective with bags of spare ammo and soldier-reviving defibrillators at the ready. And finally there’s the Recon, the tactitician who marks enemies for all to see before scoring a hattrick of headshots with a sniper rifle.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">There’s nothing revolutionary about these classes, but they are much clearer in their parameters than they have been in the past. You won’t find the team’s dedicated infantry killer fulfilling anti-tank or medic duties, for instance, as the Assault has been forced to do in the likes of Battlefields 4 and 5. But as clean and traditional as these roles are, there is a minor shake-up. Like Battlefield 2042, any class can use any weapon, but now each role has a “signature” specialism designed to encourage you into the specific loadouts of yesteryear. For example, the Recon is able to hold their breath while aiming sniper rifles, making them the clear choice for long-range engagements, while the Engineer benefits from improved hip-fire control when using SMGs. As someone who would score a low-end grade in a sniper exam, this means I can play Recon while swinging around an assault rifle or LMG, which fully opens up the class roster. But I can’t help but wonder why I should brute-force my way into playing Recon when I could find my specialism elsewhere. Isn’t that what class play is all about? </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The odd, freeform elements of 2042’s weapon system saw their fair share of criticism, and I agree that tighter restrictions would have been of benefit both there and here in Battlefield 6, especially since there’s real strength in the design of the prescribed specialist gadgets for each class. The Support’s deployable cover is a solid example – it’s great for hiding behind while resurrecting fallen squaddies, provides a safe space for allies to restock on the ammunition bags you can drop, and acts as a surface to mount the LMG that the class specialises in. In short, the components of each kit can harmonise wonderfully, and I think the interesting choice is finding which class kit provides the best melody for your playstyle, rather than adjusting the individual notes within that.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Ultimately the weapons system is a small wrinkle in a very familiar package, and that applies to basically all the new ideas present in Battlefield 6’s demo. A new movement system (ridiculously dubbed the “Kinesthetic Combat System”) promises smoother leaning around corners, bracing against cover to reduce recoil, combat rolls as you land from high jumps, and several other improvements, but I can’t say I found these valuable additions – especially the contextual lean, which rarely seemed to activate. Like the omnidirectional movement in last year’s Call of Duty: Black Ops 6, I wonder how much genuine impact this will have on the experience of regular players. The one addition that I do love is the ability to grab a fallen soldier by the scruff of their neck and drag them to safety before reviving them. It’s a useful ability that everyone has access to (which admittedly does infringe on the Support’s duties, but it’s far from the instant revive of the defibrillator.) More importantly, it’s something that creates a “moment” – there’s few things more heroic than dragging a buddy to cover while machine gun fire kicks up dust around you. If all the small additions add up to something that feels as good as that, then maybe Battlefield 6 will develop a more distinct character in time. </p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>This is a series that needed to find secure footing after a couple of wobbly outings, and it certainly feels like this new iteration is standing on reinforced concrete. </p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">But what about the battlefields themselves? The series has always had to find its own formula when it comes to level geography, simply because the classic three-lane design doesn’t work for 64-player chaos. Thankfully that rule still applies, which means Battlefield still feels unlike any other shooter out there. The flagship Conquest maps retain that almost open-world feel – much more expansive than Call of Duty arenas, with an eye for real-world authenticity. City streets feel like genuine (albeit thankfully evacuated) population centres, and buildings are realistically laid-out with coherent stairwells and floorplans. The designer’s hand <em>can </em>be felt when you realise that there are maps nested within maps, but they leave a good impression. The broad edges of Empire State replicates the wide, tank-friendly streets of New York City, but push further into the centre and there’s rabbit warren-like alleys and a large concrete multi-storey building that’s perfect for claustrophobic, close-quarters fighting. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">One or two matches simply isn’t enough time to understand the nuances of a map, and so I can’t say where exactly the few on offer would rank among the all-time greats. But Liberation Peak, set along the slopes of the Pamir Mountains in Tajikistan, provides the ideal amount of wide, rocky terrain for land vs air battles alongside pocketed military bases that give birth to desperate infantry fights, while Siege of Cairo has the dense street networks ideal for luring tanks into RPG ambushes. With no demolition centrepieces there’s nothing that instantly becomes a map’s signature element, but I hope that continued play will reveal carefully-placed details in each street, room, and capture point. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Talking of demolition, Battlefield’s trademark chaos remains very much in-tact. It is somewhat restrained in comparison to the map-shifting “levolution” system that powered Battlefield 6’s most obvious touchstones, but the alternative is much more useful in the minute-to-minute play. Entire building facades crumble away under cannon fire, opening up buildings like sardine cans to reveal the fleshy fiends hiding within. You can breach floors, allowing for Rainbow Six Siege-like downward assaults… or simply blow the support from beneath a pesky sniper. This late into Battlefield’s lifespan it’s hard to be truly excited about all this – this is the series’ schtick and likely always will be now – but it’s nonetheless impressive. As much as it is a technical feat to be boasted about alongside the most photo-realistic graphics in the series’ lifetime, it’s also a foundational tool that makes Battlefield its own distinct beast.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">If it seems odd that we’ve reached this far into the preview without mentioning the multiplayer modes – you know, the things you actually <em>play </em>– then it’s only because they almost blend into the background among the explosions and squad roles. The hands-on session provided matches of Conquest, Breakthrough, and Squad Deathmatch, and they’re exactly as Battlefield tradition dictates. Personal preference naturally applies, but at least from my perspective it’s the classic story of the objective-focussed modes reigning supreme and the smaller-scale, kill-everything-in-sight games still feeling like a square peg in Battlefield’s round hole. It’s not that they’re a bad time, it’s just that the “Battlefield Moments” EA likes to shout about seem to only happen when you’re desperately holding down Point C during a close game of Conquest, or pushing tooth-and-nail through the fiercest defence in Breakthrough. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">As part of what seems like a project attempting to recapture the glory days of Battlefields 3 and 4, I don’t hold any grudge against these modes feeling like business as usual. This is a series that needed to find secure footing after a couple of wobbly outings, and it certainly feels like this new iteration is standing on reinforced concrete. But I can’t help but feel that those old, faithful objectives could have been freshened up a little, perhaps with unconventional capture point designs or equipment used specifically for objectives. Perhaps new thrills lie in the new Escalation mode, which was unavailable to sample at my hands-on demo, although considering the official description provided to press claims that it “sees two teams fight to capture strategic control points,” I’m not expecting it to add too much extra fizz to the established formula. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">When <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/battlefield-6-suffers-significant-leaks-ahead-of-official-multiplayer-reveal">Battlefield 6’s open betas go live across a couple of weekends in August</a>, I expect there will be a lot of fans who will be relieved to find a package that largely seems focussed on returning Battlefield to its peak years. And I can’t deny that the modern combat aesthetic, equipment, and classes speak to me in a way that the series’ near-future and pseudo-historical guns never could. I had a good time. More than a decade after Battlefields 3 and 4, though, it doesn’t fill me with the same sense of adrenaline it once did. But nostalgia’s still a hell of a drug, and maybe that’s just what the medic ordered.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Do you have any questions about Battlefield 6? Tell us what you want to know in the comments, and we’ll do a follow-up soon to bring you as many answers as we can.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Matt Purslow is IGN's Senior Features Editor. </em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/battlefield-6-preview]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Roblox UGC game Grow a Garden had nearly 22 million concurrent users in July]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/roblox-s-grow-a-garden-had-nearly-22-million-concurrent-users-in-july</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/roblox-ugc-game-grow-a-garden-had-nearly-22-million-concurrent-users-in-july.1259001/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-testid="article-base-contributors"><div data-component="contributors"><p><a data-testid="contributor-name" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/author/diego-arguello" data-discover="true">Diego Argüello</a><span data-testid="contributor-title">, <!-- -->Contributing Editor, News</span><span data-testid="contributor-title">, <!-- -->GameDeveloper.com</span></p><p data-testid="contributors-date">July 31, 2025</p></div><p><span data-component="icon" data-name="Clock"></span><span>4 Min<!-- --> <!-- -->Read</span></p></div><div data-component="captioned-content" data-testid="featured-image"><p><span>Image via Roblox / Splitting Point Studios</span></p></div><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Roblox-based game </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Grow a Garden</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> has tipped the scales in the company's financials during Q2 2025, becoming the top experience based on spending within one month of release.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">As reported in today's </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://ir.roblox.com/financials/quarterly-results/default.aspx">financial results</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Grow a Garden</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> surpassed </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Fortnite's</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> existing record of 15.3 million concurrent players with nearly 22 million users in July. The free-to-play farming simulator idle game was released on March 25, originally created by a 16-year-old anonymous user, has been an important addition to </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Roblox's</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> portfolio.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Roblox Corporation said that its platform experienced "broad-based strength," highlighted by the emergence of what it considers to be viral hits. "The success of </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Grow a Garden</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> is not an accident," the company's shareholder letter reads. "</span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Grow a Gardenʼs</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> tremendous growth and engagement benefited from investments and innovations weʼve made on a consistent basis. Our ongoing focus on raw performance and quality, discovery, and investments in the virtual economy continue to create conditions for creators to succeed at this scale."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">According to </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://s27.q4cdn.com/984876518/files/doc_financials/2025/q2/Q2-25-SH-Letter.pdf">the announcement</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, three out of the company's top 10 experiences (as measured by player spending via in-app currency Robux) were released in the last 12 months, including </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Grow a Garden</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> as well as </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Steal a Brainrot</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Dead Rails</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/turkey-based-mobile-dev-good-job-games-raises-60m-series-a-round" target="_self" data-discover="true">Turkey-based mobile dev Good Job Games raises $60M Series A round</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">At a quick glance, the impact of those games is noticeable in the financial report, with revenue being $1.1 billion (up 21 percent year-over-year) and daily active users across the whole platform around the staggering 111.8 million figure, up 41 percent year-over-year. But there was a significant net loss as well, with losses being higher than predicted: $279.8 million compared to $207.2 million in Q2 2024. In regard for the guidance of the 2025 fiscal year, the projected consolidated net loss sits at around $1.2 billion, which is also higher than prior guidance.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The company added disclaimers for each of the latter two points, attributing net loss due to a "timing mismatch of deferred revenue recognition and immediate operating expense recognition."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">According to Roblox, the vast majority of Q2 bookings outperformance is "deferred and will be recognized as revenue over the estimated average lifetime of a paying user," which was 27 months during Q2 2025. Meanwhile, the primary operating costs "outpaced" recognized revenue as the company's business scaled, resulting in a net loss increase. Regarding the consolidated net loss, the company points to this being the result of the raise in bookings outlook for the 2025 fiscal year.</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/battlefield-6-s-ugc-mode-is-the-heart-of-ea-s-live-service-aspirations-for-the-series" target="_self" data-discover="true">Battlefield 6's Godot-powered UGC mode is the heart of EA's big live service swing for the series</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">It's interesting to compare the use of these disclaimers against the </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://s27.q4cdn.com/984876518/files/doc_financials/2025/q1/Q1-2025-Shareholder-Letter.pdf">financials report</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> of Q1 2025. Back then, the company pointed out that its consolidated net loss ($216.3 million) was "better than the high end" of its guidance range of $287 million-$267 million, and "an improvement" over consolidated net loss in Q1 2024 of $271.9 million.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Meanwhile, also in Q1 2025, the net cash and cash equivalents by operating activities were $443.9 million, up 86 percent year-over-year, while free cash flow totalled $426.5 million and up 123 percent year-over-year. But the company attributed a benefit from the delay of a $30 million payout to a developer, which was moved to Q2. "Had we made this particular payment in Q1 2025 as originally intended, operating cash flow for the quarter would have been $413.9 million and free cash flow would have been $396.5 million," the company said at the time."</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="The rise of ">The rise of <span>Grow a Garden</span> isn't a one-person success story</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">While it's clear that Roblox is relying on hits like </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Grow a Garden</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, there are some important facts to take into consideration outside of financials alone. In the case of </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Grow a Garden</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Roblox</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> developer Janzen "Jandel" Madsen acquired part of the game to continue developing it with a team of developers. Then, Florida-based company Do Big Studios acquired a minority share. This, according to </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.businessinsider.com/grow-a-garden-roblox-robux-why-most-popular-explained-how-2025-6">Business Insider</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, led to a bigger focus on monetization, with in-app purchases offering the chance to increase the pace of its idle element.</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/yes-reality-labs-is-still-losing-billions" target="_self" data-discover="true">Yes, Reality Labs is still losing billions</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">When taking into consideration that roughly 40 percent of the playerbase is below the age of 13, the push for monetization raises ethical questions. Last year, Sky News reported that a network of illegal casinos was </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://news.sky.com/story/illegal-casinos-are-using-roblox-to-draw-children-into-online-gambling-13273519">allowing children to gamble</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> using their </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Roblox</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> accounts. Inside the platform itself, as </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2025/apr/14/parents-describe-children-roblox-problems">The Guardian</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> reported, people have claimed that children have been exposed to grooming, pornography, violent content, and abusive speech. In August 2024, the Turkish government </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/turkish-government-bans-roblox-over-alleged-child-exploitation">banned </a></span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/turkish-government-bans-roblox-over-alleged-child-exploitation">Roblox</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> over alleged child exploitation.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Speaking to the </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c5yrjkl7dd6o">BBC</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, co-founder and CEO Dave Baszucki insisted that the company is vigilant in protecting its user base, with "tens of millions" having "amazing experiences" across the platform. When asked about parents' concerns about letting their children use the platform, Baszucki said: "My first message would be, if you're not comfortable, don't let your kids be on </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Roblox</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Grow a Garden</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> is definitely the kind of success story Roblox Corporation sells about its users—making games that attract millions of players and that can be the foundation for their career or financial future. It will be worth watching if any developers can achieve that success without selling their game to someone like Madsen or Do Big Studios.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Contributing Editor, News, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Diego Nicolás Argüello is a freelance journalist and critic from Argentina. Video games helped him to learn English, so now he covers them for places like The New York Times, NPR, Rolling Stone, and more. He also runs Into the Spine, a site dedicated to fostering and supporting new writers, and co-hosted Turnabout Breakdown, a podcast about the Ace Attorney series. He’s most likely playing a rhythm game as you read this.</span></p></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/roblox-s-grow-a-garden-had-nearly-22-million-concurrent-users-in-july]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Monte Cook Games Has Announced New Edition of their Cypher RPG System]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/monte-cook-games-has-announced-new-edition-of-their-cypher-rpg-system</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/monte-cook-games-has-announced-new-edition-of-their-cypher-rpg-system.1258980/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Monte Cook Games has announced a new edition of their award-winning TTRPG system. Their new Cypher RPG system, which will provide a streamlined experience, complete with GM narrative and creative freedom, will be arriving via crowdfunding campaign.</p>

<h2>The New Cypher RPG System Announcement</h2>

<p>In an <a href="https://www.montecookgames.com/announcing-cyphers-new-evolved-edition/" rel="nofollow">official post</a> on Monte Cook Games' website, Charles Ryan explains the reasoning behind introducing the new Cypher RPG system.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/cypher-rpg-rulebook-artwork.jpg?itok=Bl3pyJqO 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/cypher-rpg-rulebook-artwork.jpg?itok=vSTi3_MW 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>Ryan mentions that the Cypher system has been around for twelve years, garnering a passionate fanbase thanks to its accessible but rewarding gameplay system. He even mentions the game's malleability, bringing to life games like the far future fantasy of <em>Numenera</em>, the existential far fantasy of <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/return-to-actuality-with-invisible-sun-electric-and-indigo-by-monte-cook-games" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"><em>Invisible Sun</em></a>, and the disturbing cosmic horror of <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/magnus-archives-roleplaying-game-review-leitner-worthy" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"><em>The Magnus Archives Roleplaying Game</em></a>.</p>

<p>But with all TTRPG systems, feedback from players has led to certain parts of the system being streamlined or changed. Certain changes or additions may have been featured in certain licensed products and are being grandfathered into this new system. Furthermore, a new edition allows a studio to reformat their core rules for readability and clarity.</p>

<p>Some of the changes coming to the new Cypher RPG system have been long requested. Damage will no longer drain the player character's different stat pools. An armor system is being introduced, granting players more defensive options. New, genre-specific character generation options will be available, and there will be a greater focus on subtle cyphers: the imperceptible aids players can call upon in times of crisis.</p>

<p>But the pillars of the Cypher RPG system will still in place. Characters are still created with a combo of a Type, Descriptor, and Focus. Tasks are still assigned in difficulty from 1-10 and can be eased with a mix of Effort, Assets, and Skills. Also, enemy statblocks will remain easily readable and quick to implement for GMs.</p>

<p>The new Cypher RPG system will be released as two books. The first is the Cypher Character Rulebook, which will contain rules for making characters in a wide variety of genres, including high-fantasy, space opera, cyberpunk, and post-apocalyptic future. The second book, the Cypher GM's Guide, will contain rules and aids to help GMs run the game.</p>

<p>Both of these books will be available through a crowdfunding campaign that will launch in late summer, with a retail release set for mid-2026.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Ever since he was small, Tyler Chancey has had a deep, abiding love for video games and a tendency to think and overanalyze everything he enjoyed. This… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/tyler-chancey">More about Tyler</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/monte-cook-games-has-announced-new-edition-of-their-cypher-rpg-system]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battlefield 6's full multiplayer reveal sees EA trying to rebottle the lightning of Battlefield 3 and 4]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/battlefield-6s-full-multiplayer-reveal-sees-ea-trying-to-rebottle-the-lightning-of-battlefield-3-and-4</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/battlefield-6s-full-multiplayer-reveal-sees-ea-trying-to-rebottle-the-lightning-of-battlefield-3-and-4.1258977/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Out in October with nine maps and the famous four classes</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>EA</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
EA have given us our first proper look at <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/battlefield-2025">Battlefield 6</a>'s multiplayer, after revealing the game with <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/battlefield-6-has-finally-been-revealed-with-a-firmly-anti-helicopter-trailer-and-no-release-date">a single player trailer last week</a>. They've also confirmed the new <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-fps-games">shooter</a>'s release date - 10th October 2025 -  and announced dates for a series of beta weekends in August. 
</p>
<p>
The game they're pitching is a return to the contemporary warring of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/battlefield-3">Battlefield 3</a> and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/battlefield-4">Battlefield 4</a>, after the mildly futuristic disappointments of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/battlefield-2042">Battlefield 2042</a>. It's got four familiar classes, the old Battlefield mode trinity of conquest, breakthrough and rush, and maps that incline towards close quarters combat or wide-open vehicular blasting or some blasphemous hybrid of the twain. It seems fine. And loud.
</p><!--more-->

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Battlefield 6 Official Multiplayer Gameplay Reveal Event" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/c_BRbvYxgOY?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Battlefield 6 Official Multiplayer Gameplay Reveal Event</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/c_BRbvYxgOY?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/c_BRbvYxgOY?autoplay=1" title="Battlefield 6 Official Multiplayer Gameplay Reveal Event">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=c_BRbvYxgOY" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>


<p>
You've likely already heard about the returning classes, thanks to <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/ea-let-battlefield-6-players-lock-weapons-to-classes-in-latest-scuffle-over-how-much-battlefield-should-enforce-teamwork">all those Battlefield Lab bulletins</a>, but let's give them a proper intro. Assault is your kamikaze jarhead, able to equip an extra primary weapon and armed with an adrenaline shot for those last-ditch offensives. The RPG-packing engineer is great at fragging vehicles or fixing them. The MG-toting support can heal and revive people and deploy cover. Recon, finally, is about sniping, spotting foes with a quadrotor drone, mining heavy armour and obstacles with C4, and guiding missiles safely home with a laser pointer.
</p>
<p>
The handling looks familiar - slower than Call Of Duty and Halo, but nippy enough to sustain a killstreak, with a mixture of familiar and novel moves. You can drag downed friendlies by the collar while reviving them, which I think is rather sweet - like yanking a dog away from a barbecue. You can lean and peek, and mount guns on walls for stability. You can roll on landing after a big jump to preserve your momentum, a spectral homage to <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/mirrors-edge">Mirror's Edge</a>. You can also hitch a ride on tanks, so there will hopefully be fewer tantrums when six players all vie for the same gunner seat.
</p>
<p>
The game will have nine maps at launch, including a glossy restoration of Operation Firestorm from Battlefield 3. The Egypt map is built for infantry and land vehicles, while Gibraltar seems fairly claustrophobic, the kind of place where rocking an APC is seriously asking for it. Tajikistan is about big views and air war, and Brooklyn is designed to cater to every style. The maps are made up of different combat zones built with different modes in mind.
</p>
<p>
As for those modes, they are conquest, breakthrough, rush, team deathmatch, squad deathmatch, domination, king of the hill, and escalation. The latter sounds strongly like <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/battlefield-6-rumoured-to-get-a-battle-royale-mode-as-leaker-finds-footage-of-an-exploding-dam">Battlefield 6's rumoured battle royale mode</a>, pushing the opposed parties towards a gruelling final encounter, though EA danced around the details in their presentation.
</p>
<p>
Needless to say, you will be able to perforate and demolish a lot of architecture. It's hard to discern the granularity of the destruction physics from the reveal video's montage of eviscerated apartment blocks, but individual playable scenarios include smashing through floors with a sledgehammer to ambush campers below, or rigging the ceiling to take out snipers above. It makes me wonder if the game's developers - that's DICE, Criterion, Motive, and Ripple Effect - have been playing a lot of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/tom-clancys-rainbow-six-siege">Rainbow Six: Siege</a>.
</p>
<p>
Last and maybe best, there's a new version of Battlefield 2042's Portal editor on the way, which lets you tinker with maps extravagantly and apply special rules such as one-shot-kills. The options include propping a motorway against a skyscraper and sliding a bunch of tanks down it, like roaring metal children made of bombs. 
</p>
<figure>

<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>EA</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>
As ever with Battlefield multiplayer trailers, and FPS multiplayer trailers in general, it's worth noting that the average match will look nothing like the balletic bloodshed and giddy demolition combos on display here. In my experience, the average match is going to be a mixture of dying immediately when you spawn, hiding forever in a basement while enemy artillery try to burrow through the roof like a giant with a ladle, commandeering a tank only to immediately wedge it under a bridge, and being vigorously told off by your squad leader when you go for a nice walk beyond the map perimeter. Oh, and there will doubtless be <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ajh9e3PDAOc">a few bugs</a>.
</p>
<p>
Those betas? The first one starts August 7th-8th, and you can get access by watching a select few hundred streamers as part of today's multiplayer showcase. Then there are general access betas on August 9th-10th and August 14th -17th.
</p>
<p>
Concluding verdict: still fine. Channelling the BF3/BF4 energy should work for them; whether it's enough to get them <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/battlefield-6-reportedly-has-a-100-million-player-albatross-around-its-neck-and-its-single-player-is-running-massively-late">100 million players</a> is another matter. Smaller complaint: I would quite EA to lay off the percussion just a little in their Battlefield videos. I realise that bangs and booms are Battlefield's vital fluids, but if there are too many bangs and booms it makes the game seem almost constipated, like it's trying to find that one bang or boom that will finally shatter the viewer's reservations.</p>
<p>The livestream above is on-going at the time of publication - let me know if you have any thoughts.

</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/battlefield-6s-full-multiplayer-reveal-sees-ea-trying-to-rebottle-the-lightning-of-battlefield-3-and-4]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battlefield 6's Class System Is A Welcome Return To Basics]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/battlefield-6s-class-system-is-a-welcome-return-to-basics/1100-6533614/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/battlefield-6s-class-system-is-a-welcome-return-to-basics.1258971/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6533614">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/battlefield-6-release-date-trailer-news/1100-6526583/">Battlefield 6</a> will mark a return to the franchise's hallmark character classes after controversially changing the system in Battlefield 2042.</p><p dir="ltr">During Battlefield 6's multiplayer reveal, the developers emphasized, "We heard you loud and clear: You want the class system back," before confirming the return of Battlefield's four typical archetypes: the assault, engineer, support, and recon classes.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="532639259" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6466221,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Battlefield%206%20-%20Combat%2C%20Classes%20%26%20Destruction%20Breakdown%20Overview%20Trailer&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:310,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/battlefield-6-combat-classes-destruction-breakdown-overview-trailer\/2300-6466221\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466221\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466221\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466221\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6466221&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6466221,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6533614&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;battlefield-6&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;action,shooter,tactical,third-person&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;playstation-5,xbox-series-x,pc&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;electronic-arts&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;franchise&quot;:&quot;battlefield&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;franchiseRoot&quot;:&quot;battlefield&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6466221},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6466221\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;Publisher Asset&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4541502-22.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/jW3zJobZ.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1753987980,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="jW3zJobZ" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> Battlefield 6 - Combat, Classes &amp; Destruction Breakdown Overview Trailer</p>
      </div>
<p dir="ltr">Each class will feature a signature weapon set, as well as gadgets and traits exclusive to them, and clearly the developers have shuffled around some of the familiar tools in Battlefield 6's revamped take on the system.</p><p dir="ltr">The assault class will wield flashbangs and grenade launchers to punch holes in defenses, use an adrenaline shot to improve resistance to stun effects, sprint speed, and provide various combat boosts, and will even be able to wield a second primary weapon in battle.</p><p dir="ltr">The engineer class will, as usual, deploy rockets and mines to hound vehicles down and will be the only class with the ability to fix friendly armor. This class seems the most familiar, and seems to have shed some of the bloat that was added to it over time.</p><p dir="ltr">The support class has many of its familiar skills, such as the returning ability to heal, revive, and provide ammo to their squad and teammates.  In a change for the support class though, players will now be able to deploy cover.</p><p dir="ltr">Recon remains the ideal class for lone-wolf types that want to skulk around and pop enemies with headshot via their sniper rifle. However they have added utility in a squad now that they can also deploy drones that mark enemies and use a laser designator that helps guide friendly missiles. They are also now the exclusive owners of C4, making them essential to the elimination of ground vehicles like tanks.</p><p dir="ltr">These changes, which in some cases return these classes back to their most basic essence, comes on the heels of Battlefield 2042, which was released back in 2021. At the time, Battlefield 2042 shook up the class system by introducing specialists, who were hero-like characters with unique abilities, and as a result, many of the formerly strict design principles surrounding classes were made more lenient and flexible. This meant that classes could use weapons and gadgets they previously couldn't, which in turn subtly eroded the squad-based gameplay of the series, which the existing class system promoted.</p><p dir="ltr">Battlefield 6 will continue the open-ended approach to loadouts and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/battlefield-6-brings-back-controversial-change-from-battlefield-2042/1100-6531734/">share weapons between classes</a>, but now each class will have a form of proficiency with their signature weapon types, which will unlock signature game-changing traits when used in concert.</p><p dir="ltr">Players won't have to wait long to get their hands on Battlefield 6 and sample the revamped class system for themselves. An <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/battlefield-6-open-beta-release-date-time/1100-6533515/">open beta</a> is set to run across multiple weekends in August, and the game itself is <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/battlefield-6-multiplayer-trailer-shows-off-chaos-and-destruction-with-limp-bizkit-too/1100-6533607/">set to arrive on October 10</a> on PS5, Xbox Series X|S, and PC.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/battlefield-6s-class-system-is-a-welcome-return-to-basics/1100-6533614/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Switch 2 is off to a speedy start for big third-party games]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/games/716859/nintendo-partner-direct-july-cronos-star-wars</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-switch-2-is-off-to-a-speedy-start-for-big-third-party-games.1258962/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>With the Switch 2, Nintendo seems to be closing the release date gap with some of its third-party games. It’s a problem that plagued previous Nintendo consoles, which often received games years after other platforms, if at all.</p><p>While <a href="https://www.theverge.com/games/716586/nintendo-partner-direct-july-2025-news-trailers">today’s Nintendo Direct Partner Showcase</a> may have lacked the splash of anticipated third-party games like <em>Hades 2</em> or FromSoftware’s <em>The Duskbloods</em>, what was on display offered some interesting insight.</p><p>Showcases like this one offer Nintendo’s second- and third-party development and publishing partners the chance to show off what they’ve got on the way. In the original Switch days, multiplatform games like <em>Control</em> would get Switch release dates months or even years after their initial launch, if they came to the Switch at all. And even then, the game <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/28/21538173/control-cloud-version-nintendo-switch-release-remedy-entertainment">might sometimes be the cloud version</a>, requiring it to be streamed on the console, and these were generally hated for their inconsistent graphics and performance issues.</p><p>With this Direct, it seems like Nintendo is working to bring third-party games to the Switch 2 faster and, hopefully, with gameplay experiences similar to the other consoles. During this Direct, we got a look at <em>Cronos: The New Dawn</em>, a new game from <em>Silent Hill 2</em> remake studio Bloober Team. <em>Cronos</em> looks like the kind of game that would have struggled on the original Switch, but it’s releasing across all three consoles and PC on September 5th.</p><p><em>Madden NFL 2026</em> is also launching across the Big 3 at the same time — August 14th — a feat of note considering the last time a Madden title was on a Nintendo console was <em>Madden NFL 13 </em>more than a decade ago.</p><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/24230628/star-wars-outlaws-review-ps5-xbox-pc"><em>Star Wars Outlaws</em></a> has been out since August of last year. Its arrival on the Switch 2 in September represents Ubisoft’s most graphically and technically complex game on the platform since the <a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=1025X1701640&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.nintendo.com%2Fus%2Fstore%2Fproducts%2Fassassins-creed-anniversary-edition-mega-bundle-switch%2F" rel="sponsored"><em>Assassin’s Creed Anniversary Edition Mega Bundle</em></a>. (And the most recent game in that collection was released more than 10 years ago.) <em>Borderlands 4</em>, while not launching exactly day and date, will come out on the Switch 2 a mere three weeks after its PC/Xbox/PlayStation launch.</p><p>Even the third-party games that weren’t shown today still represent exciting new prospects for the Switch 2. <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/641985/nintendo-switch-2-every-game-announced-direct">During the Switch 2 Direct in April</a>, <em>Elden Ring</em> was shown as one of the games coming to the new console. With the way the original Switch struggled with more complex games, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23420732/bayonetta-3-review-nintendo-switch">even ones designed with that console in mind</a>, a big-ass, pretty-ass, particle-y effect-ass game like <em>Elden Ring</em> running on it was unthinkable. But <a href="https://en.bandainamcoent.eu/elden-ring/news/elden-ring-tarnished-edition-among-slate-of-three-bandai-namco-games-coming"><em>Elden Ring Tarnished Edition</em></a>, along with <em>The Duskbloods</em>, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/641335/the-duskbloods-fromsoftware-nintendo-switch-2-exclusive-announcement">a totally original FromSoftware<em> multiplayer</em> joint</a>, are both coming to the Switch 2.<em> Final Fantasy VII Remake</em>, a game with the same kind of, if not higher, technical complexity as <em>Elden Ring</em>, is on the way too.</p><p>Nintendo’s always been the kind of company to do what it wants rather than chase market trends, and that strategy has served the company very well. The original Switch wasn’t at the bleeding technical edge and, because of the high quality of its games, it didn’t have to be. The Switch 2, similarly, isn’t pushing the same kind of power as Xbox and PlayStation, but the console has evolved just enough that it can support some of the still-popular recent games of its competitors.</p><p>And even if not everything new will come to the Switch 2, the console still has a robust back catalog to bring forward. During today’s Direct we saw that Sega’s Ryu Ga Gotoku Studio is bringing the <em>Yakuza Kiwami</em> series to the Switch 2.</p><p>We don’t know how any of these games will perform when they’re finally released on the Switch 2. We’ll have to wait and see if the console fulfills the promise of bigger and better games running on improved hardware. We also don’t know if the trend will continue beyond the initial excitement of a new console’s launch window. But if <a href="https://www.siliconera.com/review-cyberpunk-2077-ultimate-edition-is-a-switch-2-stunner/">the</a> <a href="https://www.polygon.com/nintendo-switch-2/604269/switch-2-cyberpunk-2077-ultimate-edition-best-title">critical</a> <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/cyberpunk-2077-nintendo-switch-2-review-update">acclaim</a> of the Switch 2 edition of<em> Cyberpunk 2077</em> is anything to go by, the ports won’t just be coming faster; they’ll be good, too.</p><div><p><span><strong>Follow topics and authors</strong> from this story to see more like this in your personalized homepage feed and to receive email updates.</span></p><ul><li id="follow-author-article_footer-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTAy"><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span><span>Ash Parrish</span></span></span></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li></ul></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/games/716859/nintendo-partner-direct-july-cronos-star-wars]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Assassin’s Creed Actor Says Ubisoft Threatened To Sue Him For Hinting At Black Flag Remaster]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/assassins-creed-black-flag-remake-remaster-matt-ryan-1851787469</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/assassin%E2%80%99s-creed-actor-says-ubisoft-threatened-to-sue-him-for-hinting-at-black-flag-remaster.1258947/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="95968bc66428697bae18b9514c6178dd" data-recommend-id="image://95968bc66428697bae18b9514c6178dd" data-format="jpg" data-width="960" data-height="540" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Edward walking away from a ship." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Edward walking away from a ship." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Ubisoft</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="95968bc66428697bae18b9514c6178dd" data-recommend-id="image://95968bc66428697bae18b9514c6178dd" data-format="jpg" data-width="960" data-height="540" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Edward walking away from a ship." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>Matt Ryan, the actor behind <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/lets-rank-the-assassins-creed-games-worst-to-best-1844019813?_gl=1*5o1ks5*_ga*NzE0NzM5NTc5LjE3Mjk4Njg5MzU.*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTc0MjMwOTA2MS4yNDkuMS4xNzQyMzEwMDQyLjYwLjAuMA..&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/lets-rank-the-assassins-creed-games-worst-to-best-1844019813?_gl=1*5o1ks5*_ga*NzE0NzM5NTc5LjE3Mjk4Njg5MzU.*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTc0MjMwOTA2MS4yNDkuMS4xNzQyMzEwMDQyLjYwLjAuMA.."><em>Assassin’s Creed: Black Flag</em>’s</a></span> main character Edward Kenway, recently told a fan that they <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/assassins-creed-4-black-flag-voice-actor-teases-remake-1851785327&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/assassins-creed-4-black-flag-voice-actor-teases-remake-1851785327">might have a reason to replay the 2013 pirate game</a></span>. The <em>Constantine </em>actor said this at a convention signing, and fans took this as a tease of a <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/assassin-s-creed-4-black-flag-remake-skull-bones-1850596271&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/assassin-s-creed-4-black-flag-remake-skull-bones-1850596271">potential remake or remaster</a></span>. However, it sounds like Ryan wasn’t in the clear to even say this much to a fan, as Ubisoft apparently threatened legal action against him after video of the interaction spread online.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="197554" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="GTA 6 Delay Has Enormous Implications For The Industry" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="113" data-playlist="197554,197556,196299" data-current="197554"><div><p>GTA 6 Delay Has Enormous Implications For The Industry</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197554/197554_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197554/197554_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197554/197554_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/23078.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>TikTok user kylo_hd659 posted a video of them meeting with Ryan at Comic Con Manchester at his signing table. When the topic of the <em>Black Flag </em>remaster came up, Ryan explained that he didn’t realize the previous interaction was being recorded, and now that it’s put him in hot water with Ubisoft, he’s keeping his mouth shut on the matter.</p><p>“The thing is, when that happened, someone was doing this and I was being very free and open and I didn’t know that they were actually recording me on their phone,” Ryan said. “Then the company threatened to sue me. So I say nothing.”</p><p>Ryan points to the camera during this back and forth, so it seems like he’s well aware of it this time. I guess that’s one way to get the word out for people to stop asking about something you aren’t supposed to be talking about. We’ve reached out to Ubisoft for comment and will update the story if we hear back.</p><p>While Ryan hasn’t returned to <em>Assassin’s Creed </em>or video games since <em>Black Flag</em>, he’s spent much of the decade since playing John Constantine in several DC Comics projects, both in live-action shows like <em>Legends of Tomorrow</em> and in animated shows and movies. Hey James Gunn, if you’re gonna bring the warlock to <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/superman-israel-palestine-woke-clark-kent-punk-rock-1851786212&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/superman-israel-palestine-woke-clark-kent-punk-rock-1851786212">the new DC Universe movies</a></span>, you should bring Ryan back as a personal favor to me. Please, and thank you.</p></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/assassins-creed-black-flag-remake-remaster-matt-ryan-1851787469]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Heartworm: Abandoned House And Neighborhood Walkthrough]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/heartworm-abandoned-house-and-neighborhood-walkthrough/1100-6533608/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/heartworm-abandoned-house-and-neighborhood-walkthrough.1258935/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">Retro-style horror title <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/heartworm/" data-ref-id="5000-510267">Heartworm</a> takes place across three acts, each featuring distinct areas to explore and puzzles to solve before capping things off with a challenging boss encounter. The first of these acts takes place within the Abandoned House and Neighborhood areas. Whether you need help with a single puzzle, or would like to follow a step-by-step walkthrough of the critical path in Heartworm's opening act, we've got you covered below.</p><div data-embed-type="toc"><p><span><strong>Table of Contents</strong> [<a data-toggle="collapse" href="#toc_list">hide</a>]</span></p><ul id="toc_list"><li><a href="#Abandoned_House">Abandoned House</a><ul><li><a href="#Grandfather_clock_puzzle_solution">Grandfather clock puzzle solution</a></li><li><a href="#Abandoned_house_locked_door_solution">Abandoned house locked door solution</a></li></ul></li><li><a href="#Archive">Archive</a></li><li><a href="#Neighborhood">Neighborhood</a><ul><li><a href="#Chess_puzzle_solution">Chess puzzle solution</a></li><li><a href="#Garage_fuse_box_solution">Garage fuse box solution</a></li><li><a href="#Funeral_parlor_candles_puzzle_solution">Funeral parlor candles puzzle solution</a></li></ul></li><li><a href="#Spider_Boss">Spider Boss</a></li><li><a href="#Archive">Archive</a></li></ul></div><h2 dir="ltr" id="Abandoned_House">Abandoned House</h2><p dir="ltr">When you first gain control, grab the <strong>Camera</strong> sitting on top of the car.</p><p dir="ltr">Make your way down the road until you reach an abandoned house. Enter it through a door on the far left side.</p><p dir="ltr">Inside, walk forward and enter the door on the left to find a Safe Room. While you're here, <strong>drop the Cigarettes from your inventory into the storage box</strong>, as they're not necessary for progression and take up a slot unnecessarily.</p><p dir="ltr">Leave the Safe Room and enter the other door beside it on the back wall.</p><p dir="ltr">In this large room, enter the door on the wall right before you reach the kitchen.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4541489-1257030_20250728204247_1.png" data-ref-id="1300-4541489" data-ratio="0.56323708824725" data-width="2459" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4541489-1257030_20250728204247_1.png" data-ref-id="1300-4541489"></a><figcaption>Enter this door right before you reach the kitchen.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4541489-1257030_20250728204247_1.png"></figure><p dir="ltr">This is the dining room. Walk forward here and through a door on your left to find a staircase. Head upstairs.</p><p dir="ltr">At the top of the staircase, wrap all the way around the loft until you reach a door on another screen. Enter this door.</p><p dir="ltr">Read the paper here and <strong>take note of the number 12:15</strong>.</p><p dir="ltr">Go back into the last room, then walk up and enter the open door on the back wall.</p><h3 dir="ltr" id="Grandfather_clock_puzzle_solution">Grandfather clock puzzle solution</h3><p dir="ltr">Inside this next room, move the hands of the clock to match the time from the paper you read in the other room. The correct time is <strong>12:15</strong>.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4541488-1257030_20250728204625_1.png" data-ref-id="1300-4541488" data-ratio="0.56183017312448" data-width="2426" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4541488-1257030_20250728204625_1.png" data-ref-id="1300-4541488"></a><figcaption>Set the time to 12:15 to reveal a closet on the left.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4541488-1257030_20250728204625_1.png"></figure><p dir="ltr">When the closet to your left opens, enter inside and walk through the room to find an <strong>Emblem Piece</strong>. While you're here, <strong>take note of the word ROSE</strong>.</p><p dir="ltr">Leave this room. Before you return downstairs, first head over to the room to the right of the open door you just came through. Navigate through the bedroom and pick up the <strong>Attic Key</strong>.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4541487-1257030_20250728204833_1.png" data-ref-id="1300-4541487" data-ratio="0.5564870259481" data-width="2505" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4541487-1257030_20250728204833_1.png" data-ref-id="1300-4541487"></a><figcaption>Take the Attic Key from the master bedroom.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4541487-1257030_20250728204833_1.png"></figure><p dir="ltr">Return to the first room of the house.</p><h3 dir="ltr" id="Abandoned_house_locked_door_solution">Abandoned house locked door solution</h3><p dir="ltr">There's a door here with a lock on it. Enter the letters <strong>R-O-S-E</strong> to unlock the door.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4541485-1257030_20250728205055_1.png" data-ref-id="1300-4541485" data-ratio="0.56152584085316" data-width="2438" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4541485-1257030_20250728205055_1.png" data-ref-id="1300-4541485"></a><figcaption>Enter ROSE to open the door.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4541485-1257030_20250728205055_1.png"></figure><p dir="ltr">In the basement, push a sequence of shelves out of your way until you reach a back room. In here, you'll find another <strong>Emblem Piece</strong>.</p><p dir="ltr">With two of these pieces found, go into your inventory and combine them to create the <strong>Heart Emblem</strong>.</p><p dir="ltr">Return to the first room of the house again.</p><p dir="ltr">Go up the stairs, then wrap around and enter the door on the far end of the loft.</p><p dir="ltr">Walk through the room and up another set of stairs, then use the Attic Key to unlock the door here. Discard the Attic Key.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4541490-1257030_20250728231358_1.png" data-ref-id="1300-4541490" data-ratio="0.55813953488372" data-width="2494" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4541490-1257030_20250728231358_1.png" data-ref-id="1300-4541490"></a><figcaption>Enter this door with the Attic Key.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4541490-1257030_20250728231358_1.png"></figure><p dir="ltr">Walk through this room until you reach the end, then <strong>use the Heart Emblem on the red door</strong>.</p><p dir="ltr">Go through the door.</p><p dir="ltr">Follow the path down the stairs here, then onward down a very long and winding staircase.</p><p dir="ltr">At the end of the winding staircase, you'll find a locked door. Return up the stairs.</p><p dir="ltr">Near the top, you'll be attacked. Run back down to the door again to finally get through.</p><h2 dir="ltr" id="Archive"><strong>Archive</strong></h2><p dir="ltr">When you have control again, you'll be in the Archive, which is Heartworm's hub of sorts.</p><p dir="ltr">Head forward into a room with a giant book.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4541482-1257030_20250729004118_1.png" data-ref-id="1300-4541482" data-ratio="0.56320346320346" data-width="2310" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4541482-1257030_20250729004118_1.png" data-ref-id="1300-4541482"></a><figcaption>The Archive is essentially the game's hub.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4541482-1257030_20250729004118_1.png"></figure><p dir="ltr">There's a computer behind the book, just like the ones in Safe Rooms, so use that if you want to save.</p><p dir="ltr">To the left of the book is a machine. Throughout the game, you can collect up to three photos to put inside this machine.</p><p dir="ltr"><strong>The next part</strong> <strong>influences the ending</strong>, so we've placed it inside a spoiler block. If you don't wish to know how your actions may change the ending, skip the below section hidden behind the spoiler block.</p><div data-embed-type="spoiler"><p dir="ltr">How many photos you enter will affect whether you get the <strong>bad ending (0 photos), good ending (1-2 photos), or true ending (3 photos)</strong>.</p></div><p dir="ltr">When you're ready to move on to the next area, go down the hallway left of the book until you reach static blocking your path. Take a picture of the static to remove it.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4541481-1257030_20250729004509_1.png" data-ref-id="1300-4541481" data-ratio="0.56211812627291" data-width="2455" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4541481-1257030_20250729004509_1.png" data-ref-id="1300-4541481"></a><figcaption>Take a photo of the static to remove it.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4541481-1257030_20250729004509_1.png"></figure><p dir="ltr">Interact with the red static a bit further inside this area.</p><h2 dir="ltr" id="Neighborhood">Neighborhood</h2><p dir="ltr">When you gain control again, don't bother wasting your ammo on the ghost here.</p><p dir="ltr">If you want to save, there's a Safe Room in the first house on the left (past some chainlink fence). Otherwise, head to the right toward a store.</p><p dir="ltr">Go inside the store and pick up the <strong>House Key</strong> on the counter in the back.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4541495-1257030_20250730001123_1.png" data-ref-id="1300-4541495" data-ratio="0.56452392460126" data-width="2069" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4541495-1257030_20250730001123_1.png" data-ref-id="1300-4541495"></a><figcaption>Go to the store up the street, then head inside and get the House Key from the back counter.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4541495-1257030_20250730001123_1.png"></figure><p dir="ltr">Go back to the house you started in front of. Use the House Key to open the front door, then go inside.</p><p dir="ltr">Head into the living room. There's a door here, so enter it and walk down the long and winding path to Sam's bedroom.</p><h3 dir="ltr" id="Chess_puzzle_solution">Chess puzzle solution</h3><p dir="ltr">In Sam's bedroom is a chessboard. Sit down at the table and <strong>move the Bishop from E3 to G5</strong>.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4541493-1257030_20250730002222_1.png" data-ref-id="1300-4541493" data-ratio="0.58950914340712" data-width="2078" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4541493-1257030_20250730002222_1.png" data-ref-id="1300-4541493"></a><figcaption>Move the Bishop from E3 to G5.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4541493-1257030_20250730002222_1.png"></figure><p dir="ltr">Correctly solving this puzzle will earn you the <strong>Burst Mod</strong> for your camera. Open the inventory and click the camera, then add the mod to it. This will allow you to take three pictures at a time, which is helpful for dealing quicker damage to enemies.</p><p dir="ltr">When you've finished the chess puzzle, go back outside and wrap around the house to the garage, then open the door there. Discard the House Key.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4541494-1257030_20250730002516_1.png" data-ref-id="1300-4541494" data-ratio="0.56296296296296" data-width="2025" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4541494-1257030_20250730002516_1.png" data-ref-id="1300-4541494"></a><figcaption>Enter the garage on the left side of the house.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4541494-1257030_20250730002516_1.png"></figure><p dir="ltr">Head around the hole in the floor to find a shelf you can push out of the way to reveal a fuse box.</p><h3 dir="ltr" id="Garage_fuse_box_solution">Garage fuse box solution</h3><p dir="ltr">Move the first, third, and fifth switches to the right to turn the fuse box green and drop a set of stairs.</p><p dir="ltr">Go up the stairs to find the <strong>Camera Bag</strong>. Open your inventory and use it to increase your inventory space to eight slots. Excellent!</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4541498-1257030_20250730002727_1.png" data-ref-id="1300-4541498" data-ratio="0.56405353728489" data-width="2092" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4541498-1257030_20250730002727_1.png" data-ref-id="1300-4541498"></a><figcaption>The Camera Bag increases your inventory size.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4541498-1257030_20250730002727_1.png"></figure><p dir="ltr">Leave the garage, then head back in the direction of the store where you got the House Key. This time, take a right at the intersection, then follow the street down to an opening on the right that will lead you to a baseball field.</p><p dir="ltr">Take the <strong>Baseball Bat</strong> from the bleachers here, then leave.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4541503-1257030_20250730003559_1.png" data-ref-id="1300-4541503" data-ratio="0.55961995249406" data-width="2105" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4541503-1257030_20250730003559_1.png" data-ref-id="1300-4541503"></a><figcaption>Take the Baseball Bat from the bleachers.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4541503-1257030_20250730003559_1.png"></figure><p dir="ltr">Return to Sam's bedroom. Place the Baseball Bat on a plaque on the wall here to receive the <strong>Model Train</strong>.</p><p dir="ltr">Go back to the garage. Head back upstairs where you got the Camera Bag and look on the opposite side of the room for a model train set. Use the Model Train here to the <strong>Padlock Key</strong>.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4541505-1257030_20250730003805_1.png" data-ref-id="1300-4541505" data-ratio="0.57200694042799" data-width="1729" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4541505-1257030_20250730003805_1.png" data-ref-id="1300-4541505"></a><figcaption>Use the Model Train to get the Padlock Key.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4541505-1257030_20250730003805_1.png"></figure><p dir="ltr">Leave the garage and approach the chainlink fence behind the house. Use the Padlock Key on the door here to unlock it. Discard the Padlock Key.</p><p dir="ltr">Enter the door. Shoot the static here to gain access to the <strong>Garden Photo</strong>, which is the first of the three photos needed for the true ending of the game.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4541506-1257030_20250730004317_1.png" data-ref-id="1300-4541506" data-ratio="0.56019184652278" data-width="2085" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4541506-1257030_20250730004317_1.png" data-ref-id="1300-4541506"></a><figcaption>Take the Garden Photo here.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4541506-1257030_20250730004317_1.png"></figure><p dir="ltr">Leave this area and return to the street. Head all the way to the end and enter the last house on the right by interacting with the static-filled window.</p><p dir="ltr">Inside, walk straight and enter the door ahead of you. You'll exit onto a snowy street.</p><p dir="ltr">Directly across the street is a funeral parlor, so head there and take note that there are three unlit candles in the window. A note beside the candles will indicate that you need to find and light three candles in the neighborhood, so let's get on that.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4541507-1257030_20250730004822_1.png" data-ref-id="1300-4541507" data-ratio="0.56517509727626" data-width="2056" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4541507-1257030_20250730004822_1.png" data-ref-id="1300-4541507"></a><figcaption>You need to light three candles around the neighborhood to open the funeral parlor.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4541507-1257030_20250730004822_1.png"></figure><h3 dir="ltr" id="Funeral_parlor_candles_puzzle_solution">Funeral parlor candles puzzle solution</h3><p dir="ltr">Leave the funeral parlor and walk all the way down the street until you see a stop sign. Take a right, then go up some stairs to enter an apartment.</p><p dir="ltr">Kill the enemy (or just keep your distance from it) and make your way through the apartment's various rooms until you find the <strong>first candle</strong>. Use the Lighter from your inventory to light it.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4541508-1257030_20250730005204_1.png" data-ref-id="1300-4541508" data-ratio="0.56070209653827" data-width="2051" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4541508-1257030_20250730005204_1.png" data-ref-id="1300-4541508"></a><figcaption>First candle </figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4541508-1257030_20250730005204_1.png"></figure><p dir="ltr">Backtrack to the street, then return to the house across from the funeral parlor and go back to the main street.</p><p dir="ltr">Go all the way down the street and into the house to the left of the store.</p><p dir="ltr">The inside of this house is flooded. Be careful of the enemy here and head up the stairs, then enter the door at the top.</p><p dir="ltr">At the end of the hallway is a door on the right, and inside is the <strong>second candle</strong>. Use the Lighter from your inventory to light it.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4541510-1257030_20250730010106_1.png" data-ref-id="1300-4541510" data-ratio="0.56446991404011" data-width="2094" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4541510-1257030_20250730010106_1.png" data-ref-id="1300-4541510"></a><figcaption>Second candle</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4541510-1257030_20250730010106_1.png"></figure><p dir="ltr">Return to the baseball field.</p><p dir="ltr">On the field, you'll notice a candle in a cage on the pitcher's mound. To unlock this cage, you need to start from home base and run the bases quickly before the lights go out. Do that, and you'll have access to the <strong>third candle</strong>. Use the Lighter from your inventory to light it.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4541512-1257030_20250730010823_1.png" data-ref-id="1300-4541512" data-ratio="0.56255969436485" data-width="2094" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4541512-1257030_20250730010823_1.png" data-ref-id="1300-4541512"></a><figcaption>Third candle</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4541512-1257030_20250730010823_1.png"></figure><p dir="ltr">Return to the house at the end of the street with the static window and make your way back to the funeral parlor.</p><p dir="ltr">Go inside the funeral parlor. Inside a room in this building is a casket you can interact with to be taken downtown.</p><p dir="ltr">Head out into the downtown area and take the street around to the right. Follow it for a while until you finally reach a door on the right leading to a Safe Room.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4541514-1257030_20250730011740_1.png" data-ref-id="1300-4541514" data-ratio="0.56327307326356" data-width="2102" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4541514-1257030_20250730011740_1.png" data-ref-id="1300-4541514"></a><figcaption>This Safe Room is somewhat easy to overlook.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4541514-1257030_20250730011740_1.png"></figure><p dir="ltr">Enter the Safe Room and save, as there's a boss coming up shortly. While you're there, <strong>toss the Lighter in the storage box</strong>, as it has no further use.</p><p dir="ltr">Leave the Safe Room and walk straight down the street until you reach a right turn. Go down this street until you reach an alleyway with a bunch of lights, then follow it all the way through until you reach a fork.</p><p dir="ltr">Go up toward the warehouse door with a red light above it. Interact with this door to enter.</p><p dir="ltr">Walk into the next room and go up the stairs in the back right corner. Follow the walkway all the way around until you reach a blue door. Unlock the door to create a shortcut back to the Safe Room.</p><p dir="ltr">Inside the warehouse, head down the stairs in front of the blue door, then wrap around and enter the space between the two giant shelves.</p><p dir="ltr">An enemy will spawn here that will chase you through a series of screens filled with dimly-lit shelves. Weave in and out through here until you reach the end, and some boxes fall behind you to end the chase. If this enemy catches you, you'll die, so here's to hoping you saved recently.</p><p dir="ltr">Head down a few screens to reach a door in a fence. Enter it, then take the <strong>Crowbar</strong> in this area.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4541515-1257030_20250730211052_1.png" data-ref-id="1300-4541515" data-ratio="0.56569517439083" data-width="2093" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4541515-1257030_20250730211052_1.png" data-ref-id="1300-4541515"></a><figcaption>Take the Crowbar here.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4541515-1257030_20250730211052_1.png"></figure><p dir="ltr">Return to where you first emerged from the chase through the shelves and use the Crowbar to remove the wood on the door nearby to reveal a path back to the beginning of the warehouse.</p><p dir="ltr">Leave the warehouse the way you originally entered, then go back through the alleyway until you reach the street again.</p><p dir="ltr">Go north here to see a bus.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4541516-1257030_20250730212318_1.png" data-ref-id="1300-4541516" data-ratio="0.56333333333333" data-width="2100" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4541516-1257030_20250730212318_1.png" data-ref-id="1300-4541516"></a><figcaption>Look for this bus, and be aware that entering it will begin a boss encounter.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4541516-1257030_20250730212318_1.png"></figure><p dir="ltr"><strong>Use the Crowbar on the bus to begin the game's first boss encounter</strong>.</p><h2 dir="ltr" id="Spider_Boss">Spider Boss</h2><p dir="ltr">The game's first boss is a large spider. Make sure you have your Burst Mod equipped, as it'll take about 40 hits with your camera to kill this beastly arachnid. The fight itself is pretty straightforward, but it can be a bit frustrating due to having limited mobility.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4541517-1257030_20250730212750_1.png" data-ref-id="1300-4541517" data-ratio="0.56076555023923" data-width="2090" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4541517-1257030_20250730212750_1.png" data-ref-id="1300-4541517"></a><figcaption>The first boss in the game is a giant spider.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4541517-1257030_20250730212750_1.png"></figure><p dir="ltr">The spider can do a basic melee attack when it's close by you, which can be difficult to avoid due to how quickly it attacks. And it can shoot webs at you, which doesn't do much damage but will still knock you down. Again, this can be dodged if you move fast enough.</p><p dir="ltr">Sometimes, it will charge at you for a big attack. This can be interrupted by taking a picture when it gets close.</p><p dir="ltr">After doing some damage to the spider, it will sometimes leave the arena briefly and spawn a lot of smaller spiders that chase you down and explode. Just stay mobile and try not to get stuck in any corners. The explosions won't do a ton of damage individually, but getting hit multiple times adds up.</p><p dir="ltr">There are multiple rolls of film and a healing item in the arena, so make sure to pick those up if and when you need them.</p><p dir="ltr">You'll receive the <strong>Neighborhood Page</strong> for defeating the spider.</p><h2 dir="ltr" id="Archive">Archive</h2><p dir="ltr">You'll awaken in the Archive. Head to the left to a machine and <strong>enter the Garden Photo into it if you choose</strong>. </p><p dir="ltr">Now, use the Neighborhood Page on the giant book in the center of the Archive to open a huge gate to the north.</p><p dir="ltr">Go through the gate and follow the path to a door. Open the door to enter the second act of Heartworm.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/heartworm-abandoned-house-and-neighborhood-walkthrough/1100-6533608/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Turkey-based mobile dev Good Job Games raises $60M Series A round]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/turkey-based-mobile-dev-good-job-games-raises-60m-series-a-round</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/turkey-based-mobile-dev-good-job-games-raises-60m-series-a-round.1258932/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-testid="article-base-contributors"><div data-component="contributors"><p><a data-testid="contributor-name" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/author/diego-arguello" data-discover="true">Diego Argüello</a><span data-testid="contributor-title">, <!-- -->Contributing Editor, News</span><span data-testid="contributor-title">, <!-- -->GameDeveloper.com</span></p><p data-testid="contributors-date">July 31, 2025</p></div><p><span data-component="icon" data-name="Clock"></span><span>2 Min<!-- --> <!-- -->Read</span></p></div><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Turkey-based studio Good Job Games, known for its match-three mobile game </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Match Villains,</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> has raised $60 million in a Series A round.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The Series A round follows a seed round of $23 million that took place six months ago, making for a total investment of $83 million to date. The latest round was co-led by Menlo Ventures and Anthos Capital, with additional participation by Bessemer Venture Partners.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"When we first invested, the early metrics were already among the best we’d seen in the industry - and they’ve only improved since," Menlo Ventures partner Amy Wu Martin said in the announcement. "The team has a long vision for what they're building and we’re excited to double down."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">This was echoed by Anthos Capital partner Zack Zaharis, who said the firm is thrilled to support Good Job Games as the studio scales "</span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Match Villains </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">into a generational franchise."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">According to a post by Wu Martin on the </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://menlovc.com/perspective/villains-and-vision-why-we-backed-good-job-games/">official Menlo Ventures site</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Match Villains</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> is Good Job Games' third release, although it's the only game </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.goodjobgames.com/games">currently featured</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> on the studio's site. According to the </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.goodjobgames.matchvillains">Google Play Store page</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Match Villains </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">had over a million downloads, currently sitting at a 4.7-star rating with 64.8 thousand reviews.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Investors have been pouring cash into the Turkish game industry.">Investors have been pouring cash into the Turkish game industry.</h2><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/battlefield-6-s-ugc-mode-is-the-heart-of-ea-s-live-service-aspirations-for-the-series" target="_self" data-discover="true">Battlefield 6's Godot-powered UGC mode is the heart of EA's big live service swing for the series</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Good Job Games isn't the only Turkish game studio to receive a millionaire investment to expand its work on mobile in recent times. In January, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Magic Sort</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Car Match</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> developer Grand Games raised $30 million in Series A funding to bolster its team and scale into global markets. Last month, mobile studio Bigger Games raised $25 million in Series A funding to scale flagship title </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Kitchen Masters</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Yet, while these investments are definitely noteworthy, there are significant regional obstacles to consider. "While the hypercasual segment in general has had a tough few years, Turkey has been a rare bright spot thanks to a growing cluster of studios which has helped to build up a lot of specialised hypercasual expertise in a market with relatively low labor costs," Omdia principal analyst Liam Deane told Game Developer. "However, high inflation and the overvaluation of the Turkish lira is starting to threaten this cost advantage."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Game Developer and Omdia are sibling organizations under Informa.</span></span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Contributing Editor, News, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Diego Nicolás Argüello is a freelance journalist and critic from Argentina. Video games helped him to learn English, so now he covers them for places like The New York Times, NPR, Rolling Stone, and more. He also runs Into the Spine, a site dedicated to fostering and supporting new writers, and co-hosted Turnabout Breakdown, a podcast about the Ace Attorney series. He’s most likely playing a rhythm game as you read this.</span></p></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/turkey-based-mobile-dev-good-job-games-raises-60m-series-a-round]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[One Of The Best Parts Of Battlefield 6 Is Dragging Your Buddies To Safety]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/battlefield-6-bf6-dragging-people-multiplayer-reveal-ea-1851787385</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/one-of-the-best-parts-of-battlefield-6-is-dragging-your-buddies-to-safety.1258917/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/bf6-battlefield-6-leak-october-launch-early-access-beta-1851786824?_gl=1*1p9xpb8*_ga*NjgyMDU5NjUzLjE3NTAwODIwMTA.*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*czE3NTM5Njg0NTckbzg4JGcxJHQxNzUzOTczNjEyJGozOCRsMCRoMA..&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/bf6-battlefield-6-leak-october-launch-early-access-beta-1851786824?_gl=1*1p9xpb8*_ga*NjgyMDU5NjUzLjE3NTAwODIwMTA.*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*czE3NTM5Njg0NTckbzg4JGcxJHQxNzUzOTczNjEyJGozOCRsMCRoMA.."><em>Battlefield 6</em> is a massive AAA first-person military shooter</a></span> featuring big maps, lots of guns, plenty of explosions, and some really smart changes to the classic <em>Battlefield</em> formula while staying true to older entries like <em>BF3 </em>and <em>BF4</em>. But the only thing people could talk about after playing EA’s new FPS was dragging people around. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196653" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="The Week In Games: A Star Wars Classic Returns &amp; More New Releases" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="105" data-playlist="196653,196049,196163" data-current="196653"><div><p>The Week In Games: A Star Wars Classic Returns &amp; More New Releases</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196653/196653_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196653/196653_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196653/196653_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196653/196653_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/22209.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>On July 30, I flew out to Los Angeles and, along with a bunch of other journalists and content creators, played a few hours of the upcoming <em>Battlefield 6 </em>as part of a preview event ahead of the game’s multiplayer reveal on Thursday. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/preview/after-4-hours-with-battlefield-6-im-convinced-it-has-th-1851787384?rev=1753940839097&amp;_gl=1*1waadey*_ga*NjgyMDU5NjUzLjE3NTAwODIwMTA.*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*czE3NTM5Njg0NTckbzg4JGcxJHQxNzUzOTczNjUxJGo2MCRsMCRoMA..&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/preview/after-4-hours-with-battlefield-6-im-convinced-it-has-th-1851787384?rev=1753940839097&amp;_gl=1*1waadey*_ga*NjgyMDU5NjUzLjE3NTAwODIwMTA.*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*czE3NTM5Njg0NTckbzg4JGcxJHQxNzUzOTczNjUxJGo2MCRsMCRoMA..">You can read my full thoughts on the game over here</a></span>, but the short version is that EA and Battlefield Studios have created a helluva chaotic and fun shooter, even if it is basically<em> Battlefield 4: Let’s Do It Again Edition.</em> It was one new mechanic though—the ability to drag injured squadmates out of harm’s way—that became one of the most talked-about features among those who played it at the event.</p><p>Like in previous <em>Battlefield </em>games, players in <em>BF6 </em>don’t always “die” when they go down. Instead, they can be revived by other players. One way to do this is to play as a medic, run over to the wounded soldier with some defibrillator paddles, and give them a quick charge. This will instantly bring them back to life. And that’s fine, I guess. But the more enjoyable and exciting way to bring people back is to grab them by their bulletproof vest and drag them to safety. </p><p>On PC, the platform we played on, you simply walk over to the downed player and hold E. Doing so grabs them and slowly fills up a meter that, once filled, signals the player’s revived. While you are holding them, you can move backwards and drag them away from where they fell. You don’t have to do this, but it’s often a smart move, as they were likely in a dangerous spot when they were downed. For example, during one match, my squad was taken down by snipers. I made my way to the closest downed player and dragged them into a nearby building. A moment later, they were up on their feet, and I felt like a big hero from a war movie. </p><figure id="" data-id="0380fe66f678e31f6c329c9f5628dc9c" data-recommend-id="image://0380fe66f678e31f6c329c9f5628dc9c" data-format="png" data-width="1915" data-height="1059" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="First-person gameplay screenshot of a player on a war-torn city street dragging a downed teammate to safety." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="First-person gameplay screenshot of a player on a war-torn city street dragging a downed teammate to safety." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="false" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>A player drags a downed squadmate to safety in footage released by EA.</figcaption><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->EA</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="0380fe66f678e31f6c329c9f5628dc9c" data-recommend-id="image://0380fe66f678e31f6c329c9f5628dc9c" data-format="png" data-width="1915" data-height="1059" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="First-person gameplay screenshot of a player on a war-torn city street dragging a downed teammate to safety." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>I ended up dragging a lot of comrades around <em>Battlefield 6</em>, saving them from danger, bringing them back into the battle, and having a great time in the process. Afterward, when I talked to others who had played during the event, they often would bring up the dragging mechanic and rave about it. Even folks who weren’t as enthused with <em>BF6 </em>as I was were still big fans of heroically grabbing and pulling people to safety.</p><p>Part of what makes this feature so awesome is how easy it is. It’s one button. It’s something anyone can do, but it feels <em>so </em>cool. And it also helps out a teammate, which makes you feel even better. Getting dragged is also nice. You feel so special. </p><p>“Wow, this person really cares about me!” I would think to myself each time a random player dragged me behind some wall and out of gunfire. In reality, they just wanted to feel cool and get some extra XP. But, whatever, everyone is happy in the end. Now that’s a great way to make people work together in an online game. Take note, other shooters: This is an idea worth copying. <br></p><p>I can’t wait to drag more of my buddies and squadmates when <em>Battlefield 6</em> launches on console and PC on October 10. </p><p> .<br></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/battlefield-6-bf6-dragging-people-multiplayer-reveal-ea-1851787385]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battlefield 6 launches October 10, multiplayer revealed]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/07/battlefield-6-launches-october-10-multiplayer-revealed</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/battlefield-6-launches-october-10-multiplayer-revealed.1258905/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Open beta weekends set for August 9 to 10 and August 14 to 17.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><em><a title="Games > Battlefield 6 [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/battlefield-6">Battlefield 6</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [9,990 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [7,596 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [23,768 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2807960/Battlefield_6/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> and <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/p/battlefield-6" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Epic Games Store</a> on October 10, <a title="Companies > Electronic Arts [1,780 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/electronic-arts">Electronic Arts</a> announced during the game’s multiplayer reveal event. Open beta test weekends will run from August 9 to 10 and August 14 to 17. By watching popular streamers, users will have the opportunity to join the first beta weekend two days early on August 7. <span id="more-981267"></span></p><p>The game will be available in the following editions</p><ul><li><strong>Standard Edition</strong> (physical / digital) – $69.99 / £69.99 / €79.99<ul><li>A copy of the game</li><li>Pre-order bonus downloadable content “Tombstone Pack”<ul><li>Gravedigger Soldier Skin</li><li>“Fallen Heroes” Player Card</li><li>“Bandolier” Weapon Charm</li><li>“Express Delivery” Weapon Sticker</li><li>“Hatchet” L110 Weapon Package</li><li>“Doomsayer” Soldier Patch</li><li>Tombstone XP Boost Set</li></ul></li></ul><!-- AD: content -->
        </li><li><strong>Phantom Edition</strong> (digital) – $99.99 / £99.99 / €109.99<ul><li>A copy of the game</li><li>Pre-order bonus downloadable content “Tombstone Pack”</li><li>Battlefield Pro Token</li><li>Downloadable content “Phantom Pack”<ul><li>Phantom Squad: 4 Soldier Skins</li><li>Two Weapon Packages</li><li>Melee Knife Weapon Skin</li><li>Vehicle Skin</li><li>Weapon Sticker</li><li>Weapon Charm</li><li>Dog Tag</li><li>Phantom XP Boost Set</li></ul></li></ul></li></ul><p>“We knew when we set out to create the future of <em>Battlefield</em>, we had to nail the fundamentals of what players have loved about the series for more than 20 years,” said Battlefield senior vice president and general manager Byron Beede in a press release. “We’re back in our all-out warfare playground, with four world-class teams developing the game as a single squad known as <em>Battlefield</em> Studios. Criterion, <a title="Companies > DICE [235 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/electronic-arts/dice">DICE</a>, <a title="Companies > Motive [20 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/motive">Motive</a>, and Ripple Effect have put their heart and soul into this next <em>Battlefield</em> and we’re thrilled to have shared our first look with you today and can’t wait to see you playing next weekend during the Open Beta.”</p><p>Battlefield Studios executive vice president Vince Zampella added, “I’ve worked on a lot of titles over the years and can confidently say that <em>Battlefield 6</em> is something special. We can’t wait to show more of <em>Battlefield 6</em>‘s intense tactical combat and epic warfare in the months to come, leading up to its release on October 10.”</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Electronic Arts:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>The ultimate all-out warfare experience. Fight in high-intensity infantry combat. Rip through the skies in aerial dogfights. Demolish your environment for a strategic advantage. Harness complete control over every <a title="Genres > Action [2,903 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a> and movement using the Kinesthetic Combat System. In a war of tanks, fighter jets, and massive combat arsenals—the deadliest weapon is your squad. This is <em>Battlefield 6</em>.</p><p>The year is 2027. The world is on the edge of chaos. After a high-profile assassination shocks the world, major European countries have left NATO, while the US and its allies grapple with the fallout. A massive private military corporation unafraid to cross lines, with deep pockets and the latest tech, looks to fill the power vacuum. This army is PAX ARMATA. What’s left of NATO is in tatters, wounded and battered. This is the world of <em>Battlefield 6</em>.</p><p><em>Battlefield 6</em> introduces a host of new features, including the all-new Kinesthetic Combat System, which brings enhancements to movement and gunplay. This gives players an unprecedented level of mobility, offering new tactical options such as Drag and Revive to pull teammates out of danger and back from the brink, and mounting weapons on walls to reduce recoil. </p><p><em>Battlefield 6</em> will launch with a robust package of multiplayer modes and maps, taking the fight around the world from Egypt, to Gibraltar and the streets of New York. Each map features multiple combat zones, hand-crafted and tailored to suit specific modes, ensuring each fight is designed to compliment the player experience and provide a variety of play options. Fan favorite multiplayer modes return in <em>Battlefield 6</em>, with classic staples making an appearance, including Conquest, Breakthrough, and Rush. Players will also experience a host of fast-paced and intense <a title="Genres > First-Person Shooter [2,737 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/shooter/fps">first-person shooter</a> staples, including Team Deathmatch, Squad Deathmatch, Domination and King of the Hill. While a brand new mode called Escalation sees two teams fight to capture strategic control points. </p><p><em>Battlefield 6</em> also launches with an all-new and improved iteration of Portal – the creative toolset that lets you redraw the lines of war. Portal is more powerful and streamlined than ever before, giving players brand new tools to create completely unique content called Community <a title="Companies > Experience [212 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/experience">Experience</a>s. Ambitious post-launch support will continue to add more modes, maps, weapons, and other features to the game on a consistent basis.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong><a title="Genres > Multiplayer [562 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer">Multiplayer</a></strong> – Victory, however you envision it. <em>Battlefield 6</em> has more ways to win than ever before. Seize glory in iconic, large-scale modes including Conquest, Breakthrough, and Rush. Jump into fast-paced action with King of the Hill, Domination, and Payload. Change the rules of war with the revamped and refined <em>Battlefield</em> Portal. Fight in iconic locations all over the world including Cairo, Brooklyn, Gibraltar and more.</li><li><strong>Global Scale Campaign</strong> – Campaign is back. Drive tanks across the Sahara. Storm the beaches of Gibraltar. Defend New York from invasion. Join an elite squad of Marine Raiders fighting relentlessly to save a world on the edge of collapse.</li><li><strong>Portal</strong> – Redraw the lines of battle. <em>Battlefield</em> Portal is a massive sandbox where creators and players can push <em>Battlefield</em> to the limit. Take unprecedented control of your environment by moving, scaling, and duplicating objects. Create a completely unique game mode using NPC scripting and a customizable user interface. Your creation can even rise the ranks to become an official <em>Battlefield</em> mode. Show ’em what you’re made of.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new set of trailers below.</p><h2><span>Multiplayer Gameplay Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Battlefield 6 Official Multiplayer Gameplay Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wFGEMfyAQtI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><span>Combat, Classes, and Destruction</span></h2><p><iframe title="Battlefield 6 Combat, Classes &amp; Destruction" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/dW00mXmP0bQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><span>Maps, Modes, and Portal</span></h2><p><iframe title="Battlefield 6 Maps, Modes &amp; Portal" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/92CHDiFW0wA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><span>Multiplayer Gameplay Reveal Event</span></h2><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Battlefield 6 Official Multiplayer Gameplay Reveal Event" width="500" height="375" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/c_BRbvYxgOY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/07/battlefield-6-launches-october-10-multiplayer-revealed]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battlefield Is Getting A New Battle Royale Mode, It Seems]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/battlefield-is-getting-a-new-battle-royale-mode-it-seems/1100-6533613/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/battlefield-is-getting-a-new-battle-royale-mode-it-seems.1258902/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6533613">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>EA is trying its hand again at a Battlefield-themed battle royale mode, it seems. As part of the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/battlefield-6-release-date-trailer-news/1100-6526583/" data-ref-id="1100-6526583">Battlefield 6</a> multiplayer reveal event today, the company strongly teased the revival of the <a href="https://battlefield.fandom.com/wiki/Firestorm_(Gamemode)" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Firestorm mode from Battlefield V. </a></p><p>A teaser video showed soldiers scattering through a tropical location as the camera panned backwards to a massive firestorm spreading down a mountain toward them. The developers never mentioned battle royale or Firestorm by name, but the suggestion is quite obvious. In any event, whatever this is, fans will get to try it first in the Battlefield Labs testing program. </p><p>EA's hosts at the event alluded to the mode being called Firestorm, but stopped short of confirming this.</p><p>Firestorm for Battlefield V was part of that game and was only playable to people who owned a copy. It remains to be seen if the next iteration of the mode, if real, would be a standalone download or only available with a purchase of Battlefield 6.</p><p>At the time of its release in 2018, many remarked that Firestorm felt like a half-baked idea that EA implemented to try to capitalize on the growing popularity of battle royale modes at the time.</p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/battlefield-6-multiplayer-trailer-shows-off-chaos-and-destruction-with-limp-bizkit-too/1100-6533607/" data-ref-id="1100-6533607">Battlefield 6 launches on October 10</a>, and it won't cost $80. Instead, EA is charging $70 for the standard edition or $100 for the Phantom Edition. A <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/battlefield-6-open-beta-release-date-time/1100-6533515/" data-ref-id="1100-6533515">Battlefield 6 open beta begins in August.</a></p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/battlefield-is-getting-a-new-battle-royale-mode-it-seems/1100-6533613/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battlefield 6 Will Be Skipping PS4 And Xbox One, Not Planned For Switch 2]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/battlefield-6-will-be-skipping-ps4-and-xbox-one/1100-6533611/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/battlefield-6-will-be-skipping-ps4-and-xbox-one-not-planned-for-switch-2.1258896/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6533611">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>EA has confirmed that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/battlefield-6/" data-ref-id="5000-687940">Battlefield 6</a> will prioritize current-gen systems and PC, skipping out on PS4 and Xbox One.</p><p>In a press release following the game's multiplayer reveal, the publisher stated definitively that the next entry in its globe-spanning FPS will be arriving on October 10 exclusively on PS5, Xbox Series X|S, and PC. As for a possible Switch 2 appearance, a <a href="https://www.ea.com/games/battlefield/battlefield-6/faq" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">FAQ response</a> reads, "We currently do not have plans to release Battlefield 6 on Switch 2."</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="723356727" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6466222,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Battlefield%206%20-%20Official%20Multiplayer%20Gameplay%20Reveal%20Trailer&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:146,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/battlefield-6-official-multiplayer-gameplay-reveal-trailer\/2300-6466222\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466222\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466222\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466222\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6466222&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6466222,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6533611&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;battlefield-6&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;action,shooter,tactical,third-person&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;playstation-5,xbox-series-x,pc,playstation-4,xbox-one&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;electronic-arts&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;franchise&quot;:&quot;battlefield&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;franchiseRoot&quot;:&quot;battlefield&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6466222},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6466222\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;Publisher Asset&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4541496-11.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/JGBoGwwx.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1753987980,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="JGBoGwwx" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> Battlefield 6 - Official Multiplayer Gameplay Reveal Trailer</p>
      </div>
<p>The move is not entirely unprecedented, seeing as how we're now almost five years into the current generation of consoles, and both Xbox and PlayStation have signaled that they're in production on <a href="https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;source=web&amp;rct=j&amp;opi=89978449&amp;url=https://www.gamespot.com/articles/xbox-president-shares-new-details-on-next-gen-xbox-console/1100-6532502/&amp;ved=2ahUKEwiMyaSj4eeOAxXTmIkEHRt2IosQFnoECBgQAQ&amp;usg=AOvVaw2gh2IQUYeTUf17Tm5VRJR5" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">successors to Xbox Series X|S</a> and <a href="https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;source=web&amp;rct=j&amp;opi=89978449&amp;url=https://www.gamespot.com/articles/for-ps6-sony-is-betting-on-hardware-power-not-the-cloud/1100-6532420/&amp;ved=2ahUKEwiuiPuy4eeOAxUTm4kEHVq-KPcQFnoECCEQAQ&amp;usg=AOvVaw17N4v-2zjvyqY8UUvtpRGV" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PS5</a>.</p><p>Additionally, when preorder and wishlist pages first went live around the reveal of the game's campaign, many spotted the <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/battlefield-6/9p2ff14jzll3" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">absence of dedicated</a> <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/concept/10009568" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">pages</a> for the older generation of systems.</p><p>Typically, developers leave behind previous generation of consoles to better support the newer hardware allowing the team to push the title's tech further than it would if it were hamstrung supporting multiple systems of varying power. Some developers have already struggled to get games running on different systems within the same generation, like Larian Studios did when porting Baldur's Gate 3 to both Xbox Series X and its weaker counterpart, the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/baldurs-gate-3-is-in-development-for-xbox-but-theres-a-series-s-snag/1100-6511819/" data-ref-id="1100-6511819">Series S</a>.</p><p>Battlefield 6 marks the series' return to the modern age after Battlefield 2042's foray into the near future, as well as more typical formula complete with the franchise's iconic classes and a single-player mode. Battlefield 6 will be releasing on October 10 and a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/battlefield-6-open-beta-release-date-time/1100-6533515/" data-ref-id="1100-6533515">series of open betas</a> will take place in August.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/battlefield-6-will-be-skipping-ps4-and-xbox-one/1100-6533611/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battlefield 6 launches 10th October – see the multiplayer trailer & beta reveal here]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/07/31/battlefield-6-launches-10th-october-see-the-multiplayer-trailer-beta-reveal-here/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/battlefield-6-launches-10th-october-%E2%80%93-see-the-multiplayer-trailer-beta-reveal-here.1258887/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>EA has just given us the <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/battlefield-6">Battlefield 6</a> multiplayer reveal, confirming that the game will launch for PS5, Xbox Series X|S and PC on 10th October, as well as beta tests that will take place in August.</p>
<p><iframe title="Battlefield 6 Official Multiplayer Gameplay Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wFGEMfyAQtI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>That’s right, Battlefield 6 is coming out in October, but you’ll be able to play before then with two beta weekends. The first is coming next week, in fact, with a beta running from 7th August, with codes available from Twitch drops from people streaming today or pre-ordering the game. This will morph into an open beta test on 9th August and run through the 10th.</p>
<p>A second Battlefield 6 open beta weekend will take place from 14th-17th August.</p>
<p>Classes are back alongside signature weapons and abilities that fit into the archetypes of games before and 2042</p>

<p>There will be 9 maps at launch including an Operation Firestorm remake, Gibraltar, Egypt<br>
Tajikistan and Brooklyn.</p>
<p>Conquest, Rush and Breakthrough game mode are joined by the likes of TDM, Squad DM, Domination and KOTH.</p>
<p>More maps and modes will arrive in seasonal content, while BF Portal returns as editing tools and modifiers for gameplay.</p>
<p>Officially unveiled last week, Battlefield 6 is a huge production for EA, with the Battlefield Studios comprised of Criterion, DICE, Ripple Effect and Motive Studios, all with different roles to play in its creation. Criterion and Motive have focused on the single player campaign, which will see NATO attacked and going on the counter-offensive against the private military group known as Pax Armata. This announcement trailer brought us plenty of cinematic moments with characters calling in military strikes, angrily slapping tables and more, but there’s also paratroopers jumping from planes, there’s beach landing craft coming out of carriers, there’s rocket artillery, there’s dams blowing up and more. It builds up until parts of New York are getting blown up.</p>
<p>A lot of this was echoed in the multiplayer reveal, which takes players to some rather familiar looking streets for The Division players, over the river from the main city, fighting in the shadow of Brooklyn Bridge. The war extends from the US through to the Middle East with modern combined forces as tanks and soldiers battle through the streets.</p>
<p>We’re going hands on with the game shortly, so keep your eyes peeled for our Battlefield 6 preview very, very soon.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/07/31/battlefield-6-launches-10th-october-see-the-multiplayer-trailer-beta-reveal-here/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Review: Time Flies (Switch) – An Indie Oddity That Makes Every Second Count]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/switch-eshop/time-flies</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/review-time-flies-switch-%E2%80%93-an-indie-oddity-that-makes-every-second-count.1258884/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><section>
<figure><a title="Time Flies Review - Screenshot 1 of 5" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/157651/large.jpg"></a><figcaption>Captured on Nintendo Switch (Docked)</figcaption></figure><p>As I sat down to write this review, I typed ‘What is the lifespan of a housefly?’ into my search bar. It’s not a question I ever really pondered prior to my playthrough of <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/time_flies">Time Flies</a>. Somehow, this minimalist indie puzzler got me curious enough to wonder. I can’t say there’s ever been a piece of media that’s ever piqued my general interest in a pest in quite the same way.</p>
<p>That’s because Time Flies’ protagonist <em>is</em> a fly, and <em>they made him cool.</em> That’s not how I thought I’d be anchoring this review, but it’s the truth. Much like how the goose in <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/untitled_goose_game">Untitled Goose Game</a> wins hearts by being a chaotic menace, the fly is an existentialist rebel worthy of an Albert Camus novella about, say, the absurd search for meaning in a life measured in seconds.</p>
<p>That’s essentially what Time Flies is all about. Developed by Michael Frei and Raphaël Munoz and published by Panic (of Untitled Goose Game fame), the game puts you in control of a tiny housefly with a bucket list of cheeky to-dos to complete. The catch is that, depending on where you live, you’ll only have around a minute and a half or less to tick them all to progress.</p>
<figure><a title="Time Flies Review - Screenshot 2 of 5" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/157655/large.jpg"></a><figcaption>Captured on Nintendo Switch (Docked)</figcaption></figure>
<p>Using data from the World Health Organisation’s life expectancy figures, your in-game lifespan (measured in seconds) is tied to the average life expectancy of the country you're in. In my case, Singapore’s 83.9 years afford me 83.9 seconds of playtime, after which your little fly drops dead and you begin anew. You’re free to set any country as your location ahead of each ‘run’.</p>
<p>There are no button inputs; only the control stick is used to manoeuvre around with buttery smooth flight physics. Exploration is the name of the game. You’re given a vaguely phrased list of objectives like ‘Get Rich’, ‘Start a Revolution’, ‘Go With The Flow’, etc., and it’s up to you to experiment with the world around you through trial-and-error.</p>
<p>For example, if your goal is to ‘Learn an Instrument,’ you could try buzzing around the strings of a guitar. Tasks are never too cryptic and often play out in ironic or unexpected ways with a deadpan delivery that lends the game a distinctive comedic tone. Times Flies never tells you what to do, opting to let you poke around and figure things out on your own.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/switch-eshop/accessibility-report/4221/embed @ 1753988409 -->
<p>Despite the small size of each of the game’s four areas, there’s plenty to discover. The camera zooms in when you’re near certain objects, which is usually your cue that there’s something to interact with. Time pauses during these moments to let you prod, which more often than not leads to the quiet satisfaction of ticking something off your bucket list.</p>
<p>Unlocking a new level requires you to tick off all area-specific objectives within a single life, which is easier said than done. Fortunately, you’re able to buy yourself some additional time when there’s a clock nearby. You literally turn back the clock to gain precious seconds needed to complete your tasks, which adds a layer of strategy to the gameplay.</p>
<p>There’s also a larger achievement list to chip away at as you play, along with 12 hidden puzzle pieces scattered throughout the game. These collectibles are impressively well-hidden, requiring careful observation to sniff out and precise timing to access. Hunting for the last puzzle piece kept me invested and finding it made me feel mighty clever.</p>
<figure><a title="Time Flies Review - Screenshot 3 of 5" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/157653/large.jpg"></a><figcaption>Captured on Nintendo Switch (Docked)</figcaption></figure>
<p>The game’s visual aesthetic won’t be for everyone, but it absolutely lends personality. Settings are imperfectly hand-drawn yet slyly expressive, rendered in black and white with no gradients or shading. It’s unpolished in a deliberate way, landing somewhere between doodles on the margins of a student’s philosophy notebook and early Macintosh aesthetics.</p>
<p>Time Flies similarly uses sound design sparingly but effectively. Throughout the game, two sounds persist: the steady ticking down of the clock and the soft buzz of your wings. Ambient details like dripping water, the crackle of old jazz records, flickering TV channels, and even a tunable radio add charm and ambience to the world.</p>
<p>If Time Flies has a weakness, it’s one the game fully owns: it’s short. The game can be completed within two hours or so, and once you’ve finished it and collected all its secrets, there’s little incentive to return. The developers clearly anticipate criticism of the game’s length and, at one point, even break the fourth wall to gently rib themselves.</p>
<figure><a title="Time Flies Review - Screenshot 4 of 5" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/157656/large.jpg"></a><figcaption>Captured on Nintendo Switch (Docked)</figcaption></figure>
<p>Its creators know exactly what kind of game they’ve made, and they lean into it fully and stay committed to the bit. Time Flies feels like the lovechild of Untitled Goose Game and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/minit">Minit</a>, blending checklist-based mischief with clever time constraints. But where the goose is gleefully anarchic, the fly revels in the shortness of life and is committed to enjoying the ride.</p>
<p>Just a warning, the game does depict nudity and drug/alcohol use, so it’s not one for the kids. Times Flies runs flawlessly on both the Switch and Switch 2 with no discernible difference in performance apart from slightly speedier load times on Nintendo’s newest console. Oh, and if you were wondering, houseflies live between 15 to 30 days. Now you know.</p>
</section><section id="conclusion"><h2>Conclusion</h2>
<p>Time Flies is a clever puzzle-exploration game and a playful meditation on life’s brevity. Its gameplay mechanics don’t evolve dramatically from one level to the next, but that never felt like a hindrance. It’s a tight, focused experience that delivers its core ideas with confidence but doesn’t necessarily push beyond them. That said, Time Flies never feels like a concept stretched too thin, and it bows out before overstaying its welcome.</p></section>

</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/switch-eshop/time-flies]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battlefield 6 Is Out October 10; Pre-Orders Now Open, Two Open Beta Weekends Set in August]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/battlefield-6-october-10-pre-orders-open-two-open-beta-weekends/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/battlefield-6-is-out-october-10-pre-orders-now-open-two-open-beta-weekends-set-in-august.1258881/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Electronic Arts has confirmed the previous Battlefield 6 leaks for both <a href="https://wccftech.com/battlefield-6-release-date-indirectly-confirmed-official-website/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">release date</a> and <a href="https://wccftech.com/battlefield-6-october10-release-date/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">pricing</a>. The game will launch on PC, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series S|X on October 10 with no early access options.</p>



<p>On PC, the pricing is:</p>



<ul>
<li>Standard Edition: $69.99 / €69.99 / GBP 59.99
<ul>
<li>Phantom Edition: $99.99 / €99.99 / GBP 89.99</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>



<p>On consoles, it is slightly higher for Europeans and British players:</p>



<ul>
<li>$69.99 / €79.99 / GBP 69.99
<ul>
<li>$99.99 / €109.99/ GBP 99.99</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>



<p>The Open Beta details are slightly different from the <a href="https://wccftech.com/battlefield-6-open-beta-closed-beta-august/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">leak</a>, though. There will be two beta weekends:</p>



<ul>
<li>Saturday, August 9 - Sunday, August 10</li>



<li>Thursday, August 14 - Sunday, August 17</li>
</ul>



<p>The press release also reveals plenty of details on Battlefield 6. The premise is that in 2027, a high-profile assassination throws the world into chaos. Around the same time, 'major European countries' leave NATO, while the United States and its remaining NATO allies are left to deal with a massive private military corporation called PAX ARMATA.</p>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/BF6-Screen-6-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>



<p>In the single player campaign <a href="https://wccftech.com/battlefield-6-campaign-is-inspired-by-civil-war-film-and-lioness-tv-show/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">made by Motive</a>, players step into the boots of Dagger 1-3, a squad of Marine Raiders fighting private military companies around the world to stop a global collapse. The developers promise 'jaw-dropping set pieces' and 'explosive action on an unparalleled scale'.</p>



<p>The game's combat system is described as 'kinesthetic', enhancing gunplay and character movement. It offers new tactical options, such as:</p>



<ul>
<li>Drag and Revive - Lets you drag a teammate away from danger while reviving them</li>



<li>Peek and Lean - Lets you peek around corners to spy on the enemies while remaining unexposed to their fire</li>



<li>Combat rolls - A new maneuvering ability to limit fall damage and increase the chance to avoid getting hit</li>



<li>Mounting weapons - When behind cover, players can mount weapons to decrease recoil</li>



<li>Hitch ride - This feature expands how many players can be on vehicles beyond just seats</li>
</ul>



<p>The developers also promise that Battlefield 6 will offer 'reliable recoil patterns' and 'well-defined weapon ranges'. </p>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/BF6-Screen-8-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>



<p>The class system returns. That was practically a guarantee - even Battlefield 2042 <a href="https://wccftech.com/battlefield-2042-class-system-breakout-rework-info-blowout-gameplay-ahead-of-next-weeks-debut/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">brought it back eventually</a>, although it was too little and too late. The classes are the same four fans have loved throughout the entire franchise: Assault, Engineer, Recon, and Support.</p>



<ul>
<li>The Assault class, unsurprisingly, uses assault rifles and has a faster transition from sprint to firing and switching to and from the weapons. It also takes less damage and a lower movement speed penalty from a fall. Its signature gadget is an Adrenaline Injector that clears flash and stun effects (and offers resistance against them), boosts sprint speed, reduces damage taken from explosives, and makes the sound of enemy footsteps clearer. Its active ability reveals audible nearby foes, and kills prolong this effect. Assault players can choose from two training options: a Grenadier (quicker reload on grenade launchers, extra grenades, and more resistance against flash effects) or a Frontliner (improved health regeneration, extra adrenaline injector charge, and reduced penalty to shooting on the move).</li>



<li>The Engineer uses submachine guns, has better hip-fire control, and takes reduced damage from explosives. Its gadget is the Repair Tool, which 'fixes friendly assets and armor' but can also damage enemy assets. Its active ability overloads the Repair Tool to improve its efficiency. The Engineer's training options are the Anti-Armor (who focuses on damaging enemy vehicles with faster loads, extra rockets, and its rockets diminish repair efficiency) and the Combat Engineer (who automatically regenerates the health of vehicles they occupy, can use the Repair Tool longer, and automatically spots mines).</li>



<li>The Recon uses sniper rifles, with faster rechambering between shots, decreased scope sway, and improved breath control. It can automatically spot enemies when aiming through an optic sight. Its gadget is the Motion Sensor that tracks any enemy movement in its range. Its active ability calls an UAV to passively spot enemies in a marked position. The Recon's training options are: Sniper (improved auto-spot speed, range, duration, and the sniper shots temporarily prevent healing and headshots make targets unrevivable) and Pathfinder (undetectable by equipment except when sprinting, they also highlight foes for the rest of the squad and can perform quieter takedowns).</li>



<li>Lastly, the Support fights with light machine guns and does not suffer any sprint speed penalty with this weapon. They can drag and revive squadmates faster and also carry a Supply Bag, which heals allies and resupplies both weapon and gadget ammunition. Their active ability is a supply area of effect around them that also temporarily increases their revive speed. The Support's Training Options are: Combat Medic (they function as a health dispensary for squadmates and regenerate health when reviving them) and Fire Support (they have improved weapon control from mounted weapons and can provide ammo to teammates).</li>
</ul>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Battlefield 6 Official Multiplayer Gameplay Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/-9hCyt8yX1g?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>Battlefield 6 also brings tactical destruction back. Players can not only use rockets or tanks to blow things off, as even a sledgehammer or some C4 can take down a wall. The developers say that projectiles now leave a realistic impact based on the round and the wall's material, while explosives blow down walls based on their damage potential.</p>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/BF6-Screen-3-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>



<p>The game will launch with nine maps: Siege of Cairo, Empire State, Iberian Offensive, Liberation Peak, Saints Quarter, Manhattan Bridge, New Sobek City, Kundara Valley, and the remake of Battlefield 3's Operation Firestorm. Multiplayer modes include classics like Conquest, Breakthrough, and Rush, not to mention shooter staples like Team Deathmatch, Squad Deathmatch, Domination, and King of the Hill. The developers also added a brand new mode called Escalation where two teams fight to capture strategic control points.</p>



<p>Portal also returns with a robust toolset that has been improved with a spatial editor powered by Godot. A server browser will be a 'highlighted Community option' that is often available in Featured playlists. Furthermore, Portal-made experiences created in Verified Mode will allow for full progression in Battlefield 6. Lastly, the developers reassured fans that the ambitious post-launch support will deliver more maps, modes, weapons, and features on a regular basis. </p>



<p>For Kai's first impressions with the game after playing it at the reveal event, <a href="https://wccftech.com/battlefield-6-hands-on-impressions/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">head to this article</a>.</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/battlefield-6-october-10-pre-orders-open-two-open-beta-weekends/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mafia: The Old Country PC Specs Reveal That You’ll Need an Extremely Beefy PC for a Smooth Experience]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/mafia-the-old-country-pc-specs/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mafia-the-old-country-pc-specs-reveal-that-you%E2%80%99ll-need-an-extremely-beefy-pc-for-a-smooth-experience.1258875/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p><strong>Update 31/07/2025:</strong> After announcing the PC specs for Mafia: The Old Country, players started to have concerns about what graphical modes on consoles would look like. <a href="https://x.com/mafiagame/status/1951012716409397433">Hangar 13 responded</a> to players' worries, confirming that there will be Performance and Quality graphical modes available on consoles.</p>



<p>On PS5 and Xbox Series X, players can expect the game to run at 60 FPS in Performance mode. However, Hangar 13 does not say the same for the Quality mode. Instead, no target framerate is mentioned for the Quality mode. Cutscenes (and presumably on consoles) are already capped at 30 FPS on PC. It wouldn't be too surprising if Quality mode on consoles is capped at 30 FPS during gameplay. </p>



<p>What Hangar 13 does say on the subject is, "<em>Players who want to prioritize higher resolution and visual fidelity should select Quality Mode, while players who prefer to prioritize framerate should select Performance Mode."</em></p>



<p><strong>Original Story:</strong></p>



<p>Hangar 13 has <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1941540/view/523098355357712525?l=english">announced</a> the PC specs for <a href="https://wccftech.com/roundup/mafia-the-old-country-everything-you-need-to-know-about-the-return-of-the-gangster-franchise/">Mafia: The Old Country,</a> and unfortunately for anyone with a PC on the lower end of the hardware spectrum, you won't be playing this game at launch if you don't upgrade your hardware or buy a console.</p>



<p>Starting with the features PC players can enjoy if they have the hardware for it, Mafia: The Old Country will feature an uncapped framerate during gameplay, though the framerate will be capped to 30 FPS during cutscenes. Unreal Temporal Super Resolution, AMD FidelityFX<em>™</em> Super Resolution 4, NVIDIA Deep Learning Super Sampling 4, and Intel Xe Super Sampling 2 will all be supported at launch, including V-Sync and frame generation for those with the hardware for the features. It'll also have HDR and ultrawide monitor support at launch.</p>



<p>And you'll seemingly need all the upscaling help you can get, as it's an extremely demanding game that seems to require more from your CPU than GPU, given the fact that even the minimum CPU requirements ask that you have an AMD Ryzen 7 2700X or Intel Core i7-9700K in your machine to play the game at 1920x1080p, with graphical settings at 'Medium.' As for the minimum GPU requirement, you'll either need an AMD Radeon RX 5700 XT or NVIDIA RTX 2070 to have a smooth experience.</p>



<figure><figcaption>Mafia: The Old Country PC Specs. Image credit: Hangar 13</figcaption></figure>



<p>If you dared to play the game at the 'High' graphical preset at 2560x1440p, then you'd better have an AMD Ryzen 7 5800X or Intel Core i7-12700K CPU ready to go, paired with an AMD Radeon RX 6950 XT or NVIDIA RTX 3080 Ti GPU.</p>



<p>Finally, playing the game with the graphical settings on 'Epic,' aiming for a 4K resolution, you'll need an AMD Ryzen 7 9700X or Intel Core i7-14700K CPU, paired with an AMD Radeon RX 9070 or NVIDIA RTX 4070 Ti.</p>



<p>With all that said, even those with lower-spec hardware might be able to squeeze out some semblance of a good experience by tweaking the graphical settings to fit their build. Here are all the settings you can tweak at launch: </p>



<ul>
<li>Display Selection: (varies by setup)</li>



<li>Screen Mode: Windowed, Borderless Fullscreen</li>



<li>Window Resolution: (varies by setup)</li>



<li>V-Sync: Off, On (supports VRR via G-Sync / FreeSync)</li>



<li>Gameplay Frame Rate (FPS): 30, 40, 60, 90, 120, 144, Unlimited</li>



<li>Quality Preset: Low, Medium, High, Epic, Custom</li>



<li>Anti-Aliasing &amp; Upscaling: Unreal TSR, NVIDIA DLSS, AMD FSR, Intel XeSS</li>



<li>Upscaling Mode: Performance - High, Performance, Balanced, Quality, Quality - High, Native</li>



<li>Sharpness:&nbsp; 0.1 - 1.0 (in increments of .1)</li>



<li>Frame Generation: Off, On (on supported hardware)</li>



<li>Global Illumination: High, Epic</li>



<li>Shadows: Medium, High, Epic</li>



<li>Reflections: Low, Medium, High, Epic</li>



<li>View Distance: Near, Medium, Far, Epic</li>



<li>Textures: Low, Medium, High, Epic</li>



<li>Foliage: Low, Medium, High, Epic</li>



<li>Effects: Low, Medium, High, Epic</li>



<li>Post Processing: Medium, High, Epic</li>



<li>Motion Blur: Off, On</li>
</ul>



<p>Hopefully, when Mafia: The Old Country launches next week on August 8, 2025, it won't arrive with a slew of other technical issues that impair it from running well on the builds that it should run on without issue. We'll see how things go when it hits PC, PS5, and Xbox Series X/S next week.</p>





			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/mafia-the-old-country-pc-specs/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battlefield 6 Multiplayer Preview - Good Company]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/battlefield-6-multiplayer-preview-good-company</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/battlefield-6-multiplayer-preview-good-company.1258872/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>It’s only been a handful of days since EA raised the curtain on <em>Battlefield 6 </em>and already it’s become abundantly clear: <em>Battlefield</em> is back.</p>

<p>And EA is here to celebrate it with all the exaggerated pomp and circumstance that comes with a homecoming such as this. It’s a return to form in many ways, building upon what worked before, but also trying new things that will help define <em>Battlefield</em>’s identity.</p>

<p>It’s also a chance for a fresh start, and a commitment to fans that branches out from the legacy multiplayer experience using the key pillars of classes, gunplay, vehicles, and destruction.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/battlefield-6-soldiers.jpg?itok=sknvJ_hA 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/battlefield-6-soldiers.jpg?itok=9n46A7n7 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>With that in mind, EA and the developers at Battlefield Studios set fit to put on a dazzling, hard-edge show, inviting us out to see <em>Battlefield 6</em>’s multiplayer mode in action in a studio setting. From the jump it’s just as loud and bombastic as ever, with many facets that are setting the stage for one of this year’s big first-person shooters when it launches on October 10.</p>

<p><em>Battlefield 6</em> is framed by the role of a soldier who finds themself in the midst of a war between NATO and a paramilitary organization known as PAX ARMATA. These fights take place in real-world locations and set the stage for various modes including Conquest, Breakthrough, Squad Deathmatch, and Domination.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/battlefield-6-city.jpg?itok=d1J31W6L 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/battlefield-6-city.jpg?itok=KPULzFKd 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>Core gameplay is important, but especially so when it comes to games that lean on multiplayer for their longevity. <em>Battlefield 6</em> aims to take the stage with one key focus: squads. And with squads comes classes, each with a specific role to play and the capacity to adapt to real-time situations.</p>

<p>These classes include Engineer, which can expertly take down enemy vehicles and boost allies', and can take reduced damage from explosives. The Engineer takes control of submachine guns and has improved hip-fire control.</p>

<p>Then there’s the Recon class, whose role focuses on intelligence and counterintelligence whilst being able to infiltrate and scout at a high degree. As the name suggests, they make use of sniper rifles and can stabilize aim for a longer period of time.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/battlefield-6-single-soldier.jpg?itok=DO3p6aC4 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/battlefield-6-single-soldier.jpg?itok=NBh_hUx2 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>Support is the medic of the squad, offering up support by providing ammo, healing, and revival during combat. They use light machine guns and a supply bag that can heal allies when tossed out onto the field.</p>

<p>At the forefront of the group is the Assault class. They’re the frontline fighter, the leader meant to take the team to the enemy. They wield assault rifles, and can sprint and shift to weapons with a faster transition than is normal.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/battlefield-6-squad.jpg?itok=nF2qmU3K 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/battlefield-6-squad.jpg?itok=p_ppWb2P 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>Each of these four classes are inserted into <em>Battlefield 6</em>’s main combat system, known as the Kinesthetic Combat System. This system is designed to give the player more control, heightening mobility and tactical options in a fight, while also evolving the <em>Battlefield</em> series with all-new features.</p>

<p>For example, players can drag and revive a member of their team, ensuring both are away from danger. Players can get creative and mount weapons, which allows for steadier aim and a decrease in gun recoil. Cover can be further exploited through peeking around corners without being exposed, and you can even roll during combat to limit fall damage and increase the chance of dodging some bullets.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/battlefield-6-vehicle.jpg?itok=s5r7Pdaq 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/battlefield-6-vehicle.jpg?itok=UvDS3Gmj 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>Vehicles in <em>Battlefield 6</em> have been expanded as well, with the ability to hitch a ride and hang on to the back even if all available seats are taken.</p>

<p>The combat system is unique in that it works to give players reliable recoil patterns that will allow players to learn and adjust accordingly. This is something the team really focused on, and getting that feedback ahead of time really helped shaped the state of the game.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/battlefield-6-soldiers-and-helicopters.jpg?itok=JR7jv-uM 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/battlefield-6-soldiers-and-helicopters.jpg?itok=3fhdf3za 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>And it wouldn’t be <em>Battlefield</em> without a big focus on destruction. <em>Battlefield 6</em> offers even bigger transformations to the environment, adding authentic damage that can be wielded to the player’s advantage. There’s some pretty creative solutions here too such as firing on a floor to take out enemies from above.</p>

<p>All of this extends to <em>Battlefield 6</em>’s nine maps, including a remake of <em>Battlefield 3</em>’s Operation Firestorm. Newcomers include Siege of Cairo, Iberian Offensive, Empire State, and Liberation Peak. Several maps that we didn’t see firsthand include Saints Quarter, Manhattan Bridge, New Sobek City, and Kundara Valley.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/battlefield-6-nighttime-fight.jpg?itok=VMvmMffr 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/battlefield-6-nighttime-fight.jpg?itok=Mjlar03R 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>Within the maps themselves, players can expect to spend most of their time in Combat Zones, or special configurations in the map that focus on quality of gameplay that can switch up depending on the mode. More specifically this means that while the maps remain similar, elements within them can change such as how something becomes destroyed or the location of specific objects.</p>

<p>These modes can be broken down rather simply. There’s Conquest, which involves a lot of vehicles like tanks and helicopters, and it’s up to players to control specific locations on the map. When a team’s resources hit zero, they lose the game.</p>

<p>Breakthrough divides the map into sections that players will have to fight for one at a time. These battles will continue until all sections are captured or respawns are depleted.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/battlefield-6-tank.jpg?itok=NQrjdFL- 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/battlefield-6-tank.jpg?itok=iEJCdEED 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>Rush involves defusing and arming explosive systems, and the match will end when all communications systems are destroyed or players run out of respawns. There’s also the classic Team Deathmatch, Squad Deathmatch, King of the Hill, Escalation, and Domination modes available.</p>

<p>The Portal feature returns to <em>Battlefield 6</em> with new tools including a spatial editor. Players will now have the ability to craft their own spaces and their work with the community.</p>

<p>While we didn’t get to experience that particular mode, we did spend some quality time with many of the aforementioned gameplay features, as well as each of the four combat classes. It’s a lot to take in, but so far promises made seem to be promises kept.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/battlefield-6-soldier-charge.jpg?itok=qgHQNM1D 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/battlefield-6-soldier-charge.jpg?itok=0XVKObGK 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p><em>Battlefield 6</em> already feels incredibly polished, and not just in visuals. While yes, the fidelity is there, the explosions are bigger than ever, and the audio tuned along with it, it’s the gunplay that feels familiar yet fresh and tightly tuned.</p>

<p>Things are chaotic, but the assigned roles give you a sense of purpose - you’re not simply running and shooting, there’s the potential for specific tactical actions, and as the developers stressed, a real learning experience.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The Support class in particular feels like a star for the versatility added to a typical healer. Being able to drag and revive people means you’re not going to be stuck out in the open, and playing around with shields, healing items, and zapping enemies with a defibrillator means that there’s a level of creativity involved outside of shooting a gun. When things get tough, hanging out in one of the vehicles isn’t a bad play either.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/battlefield-6-helicopter.jpg?itok=m2fJ6Phd 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/battlefield-6-helicopter.jpg?itok=tuBrdDpA 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>The different game modes are also all unique in their own way. It truly does feel like you’re doing different things on the same map. This is especially true in the close quarters locations like Cairo, which relies a lot on buildings and small spaces.</p>

<p>These few hours were only a taste of what’s to come in <em>Battlefield 6</em>. With promises of post-launch support and an open beta for fans beginning early next month, it’ll be worth seeing if everything we saw holds up on a larger scale. The setup is certainly there, so it's safe to say, at least tentatively, that <em>Battlefield</em> is back.</p>

<hr><p><em><strong>Battlefield 6</strong> was previewed at an event hosted by the publisher - all screenshots were provided by the publisher.</em></p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Erren is a staff writer for TechRaptor whose writing experience stems from years of helming Nova Crystallis – a website dedicated to everything Square Enix… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/erren-van-duine">More about Erren</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/battlefield-6-multiplayer-preview-good-company]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Epic’s Game Store is bringing Fortnite back to Google Play]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/716914/fortnite-epic-games-store-android-google-play</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/epic%E2%80%99s-game-store-is-bringing-fortnite-back-to-google-play.1258869/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span id="follow-author-standard_article_details-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6Mzc1"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span></span><span>Richard Lawler</span></span></span></p> <p><span>is a senior editor following news across tech, culture, policy, and entertainment. He joined The Verge in 2021 after several years covering news at Engadget.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Following <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/716856/epic-v-google-win-in-appeals-court">an appeals court victory on Thursday</a>, Epic CEO Tim Sweeney <a href="https://x.com/TimSweeneyEpic/status/1950968220833423451">tweeted</a> that “the Epic Games Store for Android will be coming to the Google Play Store.” This is despite Google’s plan to appeal the Ninth Circuit panel’s decision, which declined to overturn a 2023 jury verdict that Google’s app store and payment system had become illegal monopolies.</p><div><p>There’s no detail yet on timing, but it would make accessing <em>Fortnite </em>and other Epic-distributed games much simpler on Android devices, without relying on sideloading or <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/12/24319206/epic-games-store-preinstall-telefonica-samsung-uk-europe-latin-america">making deals with phone manufacturers</a> to preload the store. On iPhone and iPad, <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/en-US/mobile">the mobile version of the Epic Games Store</a> is still only available in the European Union, but Android users could sideload it from the web <a href="http://This is despite Google’s plan to appeal today’s ruling, which declined to overturn a 2023 jury verdict that Google’s app store policies and payment system were illegal monopolies.">since the apps launched last fall</a>.</p></div><p>Epic may not be the only company to put a rival app store inside of Google’s Play Store in the near future. The Ninth Circuit appears to have lifted a stay on the entire permanent injunction that Epic won against Google’s app store monopolies, and that injunction would <a href="https://www.theverge.com/policy/2024/10/7/24243316/epic-google-permanent-injunction-ruling-third-party-stores">force Google to crack open Android for other third-party stores</a> as well. “The stay is lifted,” Epic spokesperson Cat McCormack confirms to <em>The Verge</em>.</p><p>The Epic Games Store on Android maintains your persistent status in games across platforms, and earlier this year, the company <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/633579/fr">brought its weekly free games program</a> to the mobile stores, too. It also has other Epic games, like <em>Fall Guys</em> and <em>Rocket League Sideswipe</em>.</p><p>In a statement provided to <em>The Verge</em>, Google’s global head of regulatory affairs Lee-Anne Mulholland said, “This decision will significantly harm user safety, limit choice, and undermine the innovation that has always been central to the Android ecosystem. Our top priority remains protecting our users, developers and partners, and maintaining a secure platform as we continue our appeal.”</p><div><p><span><strong>Follow topics and authors</strong> from this story to see more like this in your personalized homepage feed and to receive email updates.</span></p><ul><li id="follow-author-article_footer-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6Mzc1"><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span><span>Richard Lawler</span></span></span></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li></ul></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/news/716914/fortnite-epic-games-store-android-google-play]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>