<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 14:18:50 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Logitech CEO Hanneke Faber wants your next mouse to last forever]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/24206847/logitech-ceo-hanneke-faber-mouse-keyboard-gaming-decdoer-podcast-interview</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/logitech-ceo-hanneke-faber-wants-your-next-mouse-to-last-forever.939384/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/24206847/logitech-ceo-hanneke-faber-mouse-keyboard-gaming-decdoer-podcast-interview<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="content"><p>Today, I’m talking with Hanneke Faber, the CEO of Logitech. Hanneke’s still pretty new to the role: she joined the company last October, after the former CEO, Bracken Darrell, left. </p><p>You might remember Bracken — he was <a href="https://www.theverge.com/22846681/logitech-ceo-interview-mouse-keyboard-work-from-home-pc-g502-decoder-podcast">on <em>Decoder</em> back in 2021</a>, basically at the height of the covid-19 pandemic-era boom in home office sales, when Logitech was selling mice, keyboards, and webcams <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/9/21199521/webcam-shortage-price-raise-logitech-razer-amazon-best-buy-ebay">as fast as it could make them</a>.&nbsp;</p><p>Obviously, things have changed since then. Logitech, like so many companies that saw huge pandemic booms, very abruptly saw that growth slow down when the world began to normalize. Bracken <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/6/13/23760115/logitech-ceo-bracken-darrell-resigns">left Logitech last June</a> to go to the company that owns Vans and Supreme, and Logitech <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/computer-parts-maker-logitech-appoints-hanneke-faber-ceo-2023-10-30/">brought on Hanneke</a>, a longtime executive with an extensive background in consumer goods at conglomerates like Unilever and Procter &amp; Gamble.</p><div><p>Listen to <em>Decoder</em>, a show hosted by <em>The Verge</em>’s Nilay Patel about big ideas — and other problems.&nbsp;Subscribe&nbsp;<a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/welcome-to-decoder/id1011668648?i=1000496212371&amp;itsct=podcast_box&amp;itscg=30200&amp;ls=1&amp;at=1001l7uV&amp;ct=verge091322">here</a>!</p></div><p>Hanneke and I talked about the structural changes she’s already making at Logitech and the changes she intends to make in the future. It sounds like some Logitech products, like its smart home doorbells and cameras, are not long for this world.</p><p>Hanneke says that people often say “the mouse built this house” inside Logitech, which is a delightful catchphrase I’d never heard before. From there, we talked about how new interface paradigms like voice and AI might upend mice and keyboards and how she’s thinking about the company’s long-term future in a world where traditional PC sales might go down. </p><p>Of course, we talked about whether anyone wants their mouse to be anything more than a mouse — Logitech is adding AI features and <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/4/17/24132468/logitech-ai-prompt-builder-button">even AI buttons</a> to some of its products, and I wanted to know if that’s working.&nbsp;</p><p>You’ll hear Hanneke talk about a concept called the “forever mouse,” or a mouse you buy once and upgrade over time with new software features — features that, of course, might carry a subscription fee.&nbsp;Subscription mice! It’s a lot.</p><p>You’ll also hear Hanneke talk about how she plans to grow the business and hit an <a href="https://logitech.cfzu.net/c/482924/499820/8585?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.logitech.com%2Fen-us%2Fsustainability%2Fclimate-action.html">ambitious carbon footprint reduction milestone</a> by the end of the decade as well as where she thinks the company needs to go next. There’s a lot in this one.</p><p>Okay, Logitech CEO Hanneke Faber. Here we go.</p><p><em>This transcript has been lightly edited for length and clarity.&nbsp;</em></p><p><strong>Hanneke Faber, you are the new-ish CEO of Logitech. Welcome to <em>Decoder</em>.</strong></p><p>Thank you so much.</p><p><strong>I am really excited to talk to you. You have been on the job as CEO for seven months now?</strong></p><p>Seven months. I started on December 1st.</p><p><strong>So you’re in. You’re settled. You know where the bathrooms are, which is step one.</strong></p><p>Yeah, for sure. Although today’s my first day actually in the office in California. I’ve been in Switzerland so far, so you catch me on day one.</p><p><strong>Well, I’m just going to ask you where different things are in that office for the rest of the hour.&nbsp;</strong></p><p>[<em>Laughs</em>]&nbsp;</p><p><strong>Logitech is a fascinating company. It’s one of those companies that I think is undercover. When we started <em>Decoder</em>, one of our first ideas was that we should talk to more than five CEOs, and Logitech is one of those companies that is just ever-present in the world of technology. It is a partner to the big companies. It’s in everyone’s office. It’s in lots of people’s homes. It’s basically a core fixture of gaming. You play in a lot of spaces.</strong></p><p><strong>I </strong><a href="https://www.theverge.com/22846681/logitech-ceo-interview-mouse-keyboard-work-from-home-pc-g502-decoder-podcast"><strong>talked to your predecessor</strong></a><strong>, Bracken Darrell, in the middle of the covid-19 pandemic in 2021, when everything was a lot different. Sales were skyrocketing, and he changed his strategy a little bit. Bracken recently left. He now </strong><a href="https://www.businessoffashion.com/news/retail/vans-owner-vf-corp-appoints-bracken-darrell-as-ceo/"><strong>runs Supreme and Vans</strong></a><strong>, which was a shift. We’ll talk to him about that. You have a background in consumer goods at Procter &amp; Gamble and Unilever. Why jump to Logitech when the job opened up?</strong></p><p>Actually, Bracken came from P&amp;G as well, so that’s not so different. But I’ve been really fortunate throughout my career of working in different industries. I worked mostly in beauty at P&amp;G. I actually worked in tech for four years at Ahold Delhaize. I ran their e-commerce business when it was almost nonexistent. We built a really cool online grocery business. And then, for the last six years, I ran Unilever’s global food business.</p><p>So [despite being] different businesses, I think there are some themes that apply to Logitech: a focus on the user and the consumer first; a focus on innovation and product. And then, finally, really global footprints in every job I’ve worked in and a mix of B2B and B2C. All of those things do translate. Of course, this is a new industry and a new company for me, but it’s great to bring a whole bunch of things that I have experience with and learn a few new things as well.</p><p><strong>One of the things that’s really interesting to me about Logitech is that people tend to think of its core products — mice, keyboards, headsets, webcams — as commodities, but they’re still technology products. There’s a lot of innovation left in those spaces. Logitech has driven some of that innovation, but then you see other weird things blossom into cultures unto themselves — mechanical keyboards, for example. There are webcam startups again, which is really interesting. That was not a thing that was happening pre-covid.&nbsp;</strong></p><p><strong>Do you view the opportunity here as an operational opportunity, as an innovation opportunity, as a “find new categories and make them grow” opportunity? What is your macro view of the situation?</strong></p><p>There are three main tailwinds on our core business. The first one is new ways of working, hybrid working. That’s good for our personal workspace business, the traditional mice and keyboards, because everyone needs multiple setups. And obviously it’s good for our video conferencing business. So the new ways of working post-covid are a real tailwind for us.&nbsp;</p><p>Second is gaming. Gaming, just as a space, continues to grow, and especially with new demographics. Almost half of gamers are now women, which is amazing. And older people game. It’s no longer just teenage boys. We see the market continue to grow. </p><p><strong>Wait, can I ask you one question about older people in that context?&nbsp;</strong></p><p>Yeah. Sorry, older than teenage boys?</p><p><strong>Sure. Is it that a set of teenage boys who were gamers 15 years ago got older, or is it older people are becoming new gamers?</strong></p><p>I think we’re seeing a little bit of both, although it’s probably the first trend that is the biggest one. The teenage boys of 15 years ago are now in their 30s and 40s, so that just extends the demographic. New teenage boys are still coming in, and girls, so that’s good. But we’re also seeing older cohorts coming in mostly through mobile, through <em>Candy Crush</em> but also <em>Wordle</em> and <em>Connections</em>. Those are entry points into gaming that make them more comfortable with gaming and may take them to PC and console gaming as well.</p><p><strong>You said there was a third thing. What was the third thing?</strong></p><p>The third thing… of course you can’t do an interview for three minutes and not say AI, but AI is a real tailwind for us as well.</p><p><strong>How do you think AI is a tailwind for Logitech in particular?</strong></p><p>In three ways. First, like for any other company, is internal productivity. We’re seeing it on the software engineering side, where coding and testing have clearly become more efficient, but we’re also seeing it on the creative and brand-building side, again, where things are getting more efficient but also sometimes more creative.&nbsp;</p><p>More importantly, on the product side, there are two ways in which AI will be a tailwind. First of all, we’ve always been a human-to-technology interface company, and we’re starting to be an interface to the large language models. A couple of months ago, we <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/4/17/24132468/logitech-ai-prompt-builder-button">launched the Logi AI Prompt Builder</a>, which is basically a shortcut in our software to ChatGPT. It has millions of unique users already, and it’s just a simpler way for people to use ChatGPT and not get out of their flow when they use all of our mice and keyboards in English-speaking countries. There will be much more to follow in terms of being that human-technology interface.</p><p>There’s a third area that is big on AI, which is in audio and video. We have a big video conferencing business, a headphones business. That’s really machine learning and large data models, and the company’s been at those for a number of years, but we’re seeing the quality of things like two-way noise cancellation or video conferencing equipment that actually knows when to zoom in on you when you’re speaking and not when you’re opening a packet of crisps. Those kinds of things are really important, and I foresee massive quality improvements thanks to machine learning in the years ahead.</p><p><strong>I want to come back to the AI question because I think there’s a lot to unpack there, and there are a lot of obvious opportunities, like you said, in audio and video. And then there are some opportunities that, I think, deserve a little more time around AI prompt building and that sort of thing.&nbsp;</strong></p><p><strong>But I want to stay focused for a second on you. You’re the new CEO. So covid, work from home, created a massive opportunity for Logitech. I bought a black market webcam at the end of 2020. It was Chinese. It wasn’t even meant for this market.</strong></p><p>I love it.</p><p><strong>The previous administration really ramped production. They saw huge growth. Then there was an enterprise push as more and more companies embraced hybrid and remote and refitted all their conference rooms. That all crashed back to earth, and there were a couple of years when the growth was falling. Logitech’s fourth quarter earnings released back in April marked </strong><a href="https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/earnings/logitech-posts-first-positive-quarter-in-over-two-years-19404532.htm"><strong>your first quarter of sales growth in over two years</strong></a><strong>. You also reported growth in your most recent quarter. What is bringing that growth back?</strong></p><p>Product innovation and markets that are stabilizing a little bit post-covid [are contributing to that growth]. I have to say, this company should be very proud of what it did during covid under Bracken. It did a really great job, but obviously it was a bit of a sugar high. That said, the company is 50 percent bigger today than it was pre-covid, so it hasn’t all come crashing down to earth.&nbsp;</p><p>I think what we’ve done is we’ve really been focusing on great execution and on things that we can control. There are some things that we can’t control: inflation, consumer confidence, corporate IT budgets for our video conferencing business. But within those constraints, we’ve been growing our share. That was one of the drivers of us getting back to growth in Q4. We’ve been delivering really exciting innovation, and we’ll continue to do those things.</p><p><strong>You called it a sugar high. I feel like the broad story of tech in particular is the sugar high of overinvestment during covid, of competing to hire every single person that existed in the world who could write code and then assuming that those trends would be permanent and we would all stay inside and live our lives mediated through screens on the internet forever. Many companies did not survive that sugar high. Is it that simple, that Logitech just weathered the covid highs and the trends and is back to a stable place now?</strong></p><p>We’re not back to where we were in 2019. Again, we’re 50 percent bigger as a company, and the way people work is so different today versus 2019. Virtually every company that I speak to, and I speak to many of them because they’re all our customers, wants to be hybrid. They want their people to come into the office two or three days a week, but they also want to offer the flexibility of working from home or working from anywhere. That is obviously very different from in 2019. We pride ourselves on being a model for ways of working because we sell this stuff, so I think we’re very well positioned to help our corporate customers give people a great experience both in the office and at home.</p><p><strong>You mentioned that you are in the California office today, and it’s your first day there. You moved to Switzerland when you got this job. How are you structuring your time between remote, hybrid, and in person? How’s that working for you?</strong></p><p>Sadly, I live on an airplane, it feels like. Logitech is very special in that it is a super global company. We’re on the ground in more than 100 countries, and we have great capabilities around the world. I spend probably 60 percent of my time in offices that are not my own. When I’m in California, or I spent these first seven months [on the job] in our Swiss office, I try to be in the office. But I might also, if I start early — like today, I started at 6AM — go back home at 1PM and get some exercise and then work more later on. That’s a level of flexibility that I don’t think we necessarily had pre-covid, which is great.</p><p><strong>Do you ever find yourself in that horrible situation of being alone in a conference room on a video call?</strong></p><p>That’s just ridiculous, right?</p><p><strong>That’s my nightmare. If I go to the office and I’m the only one there and everyone else is on a video call, I wonder why we even have an office.</strong></p><p>[<em>Laughs</em>] Yeah, absolutely. Well, we have this concept of gravity days at Logitech. On the gravity days, everyone’s there so you’re not by yourself.</p><p><strong>What are the gravity days?</strong></p><p>It depends on the teams. My gravity days here are Tuesdays and Wednesdays, so I’ll see most of the leadership team. But different teams have different gravity days that they pick themselves.</p><p><strong>And then are you living on a plane just to be in person wherever you need to be?</strong></p><p>Yes, and part of that is because I’m new — and I’m not just new to the company; I’m also new to the industry. I need to meet people, our own people, but very much also suppliers, customers, consumers, investors. There are just a lot of people to meet, and certainly a first meeting, I think, is still best done in person.</p><p><strong>This brings us very neatly to what I think of as the <em>Decoder</em> questions. I was listening to the first fireside chat you had for your investors five days into the job, and I heard you say that your style is to be as close to the customer and as close to the people doing the work as possible because they know best. That’s you on planes. But ultimately, you have to make a lot of decisions. What kind of decisions do you want to be making? What’s your framework for making them?</strong></p><p>I think company strategy is a great way to set that decision framework. I’ve spent a lot of time in the last six months, first listening, then co-creating that strategy, and then setting the strategy and setting the bar high. If I unpack that a little bit, there’s lots of stuff I don’t know and that we all don’t know, so listening was first. Then we sat down with the leadership team first to really make choices. What’s our goal? For 2031, because that’s when Logitech will be 50 years old, we set a goal of doubling the business and reducing our carbon footprint by 50 percent while retaining really attractive margins.&nbsp;</p><p>We set a mission, which <a href="https://news.logitech.com/press-releases/news-details/2024/Logitech-Announces-Q4-and-Full-Fiscal-Year-2024-Results/default.aspx">we’ve said</a> is extending human potential in work and in play. We had a good mission, but it was three pages long, so I really wanted to simplify that. And “extending human potential,” those words are carefully chosen. So “extending” is obviously a riff on the mouse. The mouse built this house. It extends your arm, so we want to extend—</p><p><strong>You say, “The mouse built this house”?</strong></p><p>Yeah, that’s what they say here — and I say it. I like it.</p><p><strong>That should be the whole mission, I got to be honest with you. I think it’s a strong contender.&nbsp;</strong></p><p>That’s right. But we extend human potential in this age of AI, this age of [Zoom CEO] Eric Yuan <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/6/3/24168733/zoom-ceo-ai-clones-digital-twins-videoconferencing-decoder-interview">saying there are digital twins of all of us coming to meetings</a>. It’s really important that we extend human potential because we can make humans better. We can help you win that game. We can help you be more productive. We can help you connect better when you’re in that conference room by yourself. If we can do that in ways that are also healthier for people on the planet, then extending human potential is really worth waking up for every morning.</p><p>And what else is there in life but work and play? We do that in work and play today, but I believe, with my leadership team, that those areas are actually much bigger than where Logitech plays today. Today, we’re mostly focused on work. We focus on office workers. Most people in the world don’t work in an office. They work in retail, healthcare, education, construction, you name it. And we can play there, too. And in gaming, we’re mostly focused on PC gaming. Today, there’s a lot more play out there than just PC gaming. That broadens our TAM, our total addressable market, for the future, which is an opportunity to deliver that growth.</p><p>That’s a long-winded way of saying what we’re doing. That is our framework for decision-making. We’ve then made some pretty clear choices where to play and how to win below that, and now that that is in place, as a leader, I can circle back and say, “Okay, I listened. We co-create it and we set the bar high.” Now, I circle back and I listen again. I go back and I listen to people and say, “What do they need? What obstacles do I need to take away so that they can deliver on doubling the business and reducing the carbon footprint by half?”</p><p><strong>What kind of obstacles have you removed so far?</strong></p><p>Well, we’re in the process [of doing this]. I think some of those obstacles might be the result of that sugar high. We got a little complicated in our organization because we had a lot of people, and that usually makes things a little more complicated. So we’re about to do some simplifications and also invest some more money in areas where we’re maybe not quite as good as we need to be.&nbsp;</p><p>Historically, we’re a fantastic B2C company. We sell our stuff to Amazon, to Best Buy, to MediaMarkt. That’s who we are. B2B is much newer. And again, Bracken and the team did a great job of building a B2B business from scratch with a really disruptive video conferencing product. But we’re like teenagers in that space. I wouldn’t call us babies, but we’re like teenagers. If you compare our capabilities, especially on the go-to-market side, to some of the more legacy players in B2B, we’re just newer. That’s a place where we will be investing, and that’s been an obstacle.</p><p><strong>You have brought up changing the org chart, which is bait for the show. That’s what <em>Decoder</em> is all about. When I talked to Bracken last, I will never forget it, he described one of the most complicated org charts I’ve ever heard. It seemed to be working. He seemed to be happy with it. He told me, and I went and looked it up, he had 23 direct reports. Most of the teams across the company were set up to be almost completely independent, and he was totally fine with duplicated efforts and resources.&nbsp;</strong></p><p><strong>So if two teams were both going to do microphones, that was fine as long as they were both going to market and the teams independently were profitable or successful in their own way. I think he told me there were something like 20 or 30 product teams just running under the various brands. That feels like the thing you’re about to change. Is that what you’re changing?</strong></p><p>Yeah, and again, I don’t want to blame previous setups because they were working for their time. The track record of value creation here at Logitech is fantastic. But I think now what I’m hearing from our people and what we’re seeing in some of the results over the past few years is that we do need to simplify because things have gotten a little bit too complicated.&nbsp;</p><p>Part of that, by the way, is the brand story. Logitech tried to become a multi-brand company, but today, 97 percent of our sales are in the Logitech brand, Logitech and Logitech G, and I consider those one brand, really. So it’s important that we make sure that 97 percent of our resources are focused on that brand and that we don’t get too scattered around the company. That’s one of the other strategic choices that we’ve made: we will build one fantastic iconic Logitech brand, and that’s our focus.</p><p><strong>A lot of the other brands you’re describing are the result of acquisitions. There’s Ultimate Ears, Jaybird, Blue Microphones, Streamlabs — and the list goes on. There have been a lot of acquisitions and there are a lot of new products. Then there are attempts to be more consumer with the Logi brand. Is all of that stuff going to come in under Logitech, or are you going to leave those alone?</strong></p><p>Well, again, it’s the tail wagging the dog, right? It’s very, very small. And some of it has already been folded in successfully under the Logitech brand. If you look at Astro, which was a really good acquisition, it’s now part of Logitech. That makes a lot of sense. And it absolutely doesn’t mean we won’t do acquisitions in the future, but again, when they can be folded in, they probably should.&nbsp;</p><p>There are much, much bigger companies with much bigger brands that don’t rely on a whole stable of brands. So I’m excited about that. And then you also mentioned product development and engineering, which, of course, is the heart of this company. Again, there’s probably room for a little bit more synergy, and this is, by the way, not about cost-cutting. It’s just about getting more out of the resources that we have if we talk to each other a little bit more.</p><p><strong>I’m assuming you’re not going to stick with 23 direct reports and a bunch of basically startup founders everywhere.&nbsp;</strong></p><p>I already haven’t, that I know.</p><p><strong>To your point, it worked.</strong></p><p>Absolutely.</p><p><strong>I remember talking to Bracken. I was like, “That sounds pretty fun,” and he seemed like he was having a good time. But you need to change it now. How are you doing that? What’s the structure now?</strong></p><p>I’m already down to 12 or 13 direct reports, so it’s already streamlined in that way. I think running the company along the lines of three big businesses — personal workspace, gaming, and Logitech for enterprise — is a really important way of going forward, and that’s what we’ll be doing.&nbsp;</p><p>Again, historically, we’re very much a consumer company, so across [personal workspace solutions] and gaming, we’ll be focused on the end user to consumer, the customer, Amazon, Walmart, Gigabyte, MediaMarkt, etc. And B2B is a different kettle of fish where we still have to build significant capability, which is a huge opportunity because, again, we’ve got fabulous products for corporate customers, and our penetration is still very low. So I’m really excited about the growth potential of our B2B business.</p><p><strong>Inside of that structure, which feels like a go-to-market structure, you’ve got the three big consumer segments, and you’ve got products that might move between them. You do still have some brands that people love. Ultimate Ears is a brand that I love. That was my first fancy pair of headphones. You have Blue Microphones, where half or a quarter of the podcasts in the world are on fancy Blue Microphones, and they’re a fixture of all the studios. Are you going to leave some of those to their high-end customers?</strong></p><p>Yeah, absolutely, and we retain a small Ultimate Ears team who are doing great stuff. They just launched the new Wonderboom, which is a super cool product. The same is true for Blue. Absolutely, those little teams, again, we’re super sufficient and scrappy on those, but they’re great products and they’ll stay in place and they’re as loved as the big dogs.</p><p><strong>When you were going through and saying, “Okay, I have to fold some into the three big buckets and I’m going to leave some of these alone,” what was the framework you used? What was the marker for you to say, “Okay, we’re going to set Blue aside, but this one we have to fold into the main consumer Logitech brand”?</strong></p><p>I think the framework is a framework of growth. So if we want to double the business by 2031, then you work back and you say, “Okay, what do we need to do?” Well, we need to grow organically, mid-single digits, and we want to do some M&amp;A. What are the spaces that we’ll play in? It will be work and play and it will be B2B and B2C. Then, when you look at the building blocks, the big chunks will be in B2B video conferencing and personal workspace products, in gaming and in PWS products.&nbsp;</p><p>So then, underneath that, yes, you have to fit in some of these smaller pieces, and that’s totally fine. I’ve always found throughout my career that it’s actually fun to work on some of these smaller pieces because you have a little more freedom. If you do well, people think you’re fantastic. If you don’t do well, it doesn’t really matter. So that’s a nice place to be in.</p><p><strong>One of the other things you said in that investor call, which is also just pure <em>Decoder</em> bait and I thank you for it, is that one of your core beliefs is that companies are perfectly designed to get the results that they are getting. Whatever result you get you can just run right back to the structure of the company. Explain that in more depth.</strong></p><p>The results that we got last quarter, which we’re actually pleased with because we <a href="https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/earnings/logitech-posts-first-positive-quarter-in-over-two-years-19404532.htm">were back to growth</a> and we had really good margins, are the result of the structure that we had then. Now, I’m a big believer that you have to make a few changes if you want to get, in our case, even better results, a little faster growth with the same margins, and not unimportantly, reduce that carbon footprint by 50 percent. If you expect the same results, then it’s fine to stay with that same organization. If you expect results that are a little different, you need to make some tweaks. Again, I don’t think Logitech is a disaster turnaround story at all. This is a good-to-great story. But if we want to be great, then we have to make some tweaks.</p><p><strong>As you think about changing the structure, you talked about your process here tonight. You talked to everybody. You listened. You co-created some ideas. There are some goals here. You’re saying, “I’m designing a structure to get to some very explicit, probably measurable goals.” Do those look mostly like growth? Does it look like product innovation? Does it look like flipping the apple cart over and inventing the next iPhone?</strong></p><p>This is a product and innovation company at its heart. So that’s the way we grow, with great, fantastic products that our users love. But that’s the what and the how. In terms of the outcome, yes, it’s about growth. So we’ve said we want to double the business by 2031 and reduce our carbon footprint because that’s something the company committed to well before I got here, which is not so easy to do when you double your business because each one of those mice and keyboards emits more carbon. Then, of course, we want to create great value for investors. So gross margins and operating income margins are important, and we’ve guided for some really attractive levels.</p><p><strong>You’re the new CEO. You got hired by a board of directors. Some of that board of directors is leaving. You’re going to have some new members that the shareholders can vote for. You’d like them to vote for you to be added to the board of directors.&nbsp;</strong></p><p><strong>When you set that goal and you say, “I’m changing the structure of the company,” or even when you’re interviewing for the job, did you come in and say, “Look, I think we should double the size of the company by 2031”? Was that the pitch? Was it, “I think there’s a new vision”? Now, when you’re actually executing and saying these things out loud, do you feel the pressure to grow from your investors or your board members? Where does that come from?</strong></p><p>I would say, first of all, on the process to get this role, kudos to the board of Logitech. I thought they did a really great job in the interviewing process, where, I’ll spill the beans, but they asked each of the candidates to do a 15- to 20-minute presentation on what they thought the company should be. Now, of course, as an external candidate, you do that not knowing a whole lot.&nbsp;</p><p>So, while some of the themes I talked about have come back in my actual strategy, some of the things have changed because obviously I know a lot more now than I did before I joined. But that was helpful because it allows the board to see where the candidate wants to take the company. But you’d be surprised that not all boards do that.&nbsp;</p><p><strong>So that was the hiring process. You didn’t walk in saying, “I’m going to double the size of the company.” But now is when you’re saying that?&nbsp;</strong></p><p>Yes.</p><p><strong>And is that a decision that is coming from the board in service to its investors?</strong></p><p>No. Again, this is listening, co-creating, and then engaging with the board deeply on “does this make sense — these goals, this vision?” And then these “where to play” and “how to win” choices, do those make sense? The board was a really important stakeholder, obviously, in finalizing that. But so were the people of Logitech. I’m a big believer in co-creation, and that’s not just co-creation with the leadership team.&nbsp;</p><p>We actually invited all 7,000 employees to come to co-creation sessions around the world where we shared with them an MVP of our strategy. But then we said, “Tell us three things you’d like and three things you want to add or change.” We had great feedback on that, and that really shaped the final strategy.</p><p><strong>What was the biggest thing that you added or changed or the biggest thing that people really liked?</strong></p><p>What they really liked is the continued focus on products and innovation. Again, that is our lifeblood, and we have so many fantastic engineers and designers, so that came out very, very clearly. I think what surprised me was actually the passion for sustainability. There’s a huge passion around the world for what we can do to lead in tech on reducing the carbon footprint where there’s a lot of greenwashing and a lot of increasing carbon footprints, unfortunately, in the age of AI. There was more passion for that topic than I had expected. So again, it’s important in our strategy going forward.</p><p><strong>Let’s talk about the products. They are the lifeblood of the company. I’m going to say “the mouse built this house” all the time. It’s very good. I can’t believe I never knew that before. It’s a pretty sprawling product lineup. You’re in a million categories. How did you acquaint yourself with all of it?</strong></p><p>There are three big ones.&nbsp;</p><p><strong>Well, sure, but everything from smart home doorbells to mice to headphones, it’s a lot of things.</strong></p><p>I think those are pretty much gone.</p><p><strong>So wait, you’re going to leave the smart home?</strong></p><p>No, there’s our timing. I need to double-check, but I’m not even sure those are still being sold. It’s really personal workspace, video conferencing, and gaming.</p><p><strong>What about all the customers you sold smart home cameras to who have cloud service dependencies?</strong></p><p>We’ll continue to support, of course, what we’ve sold for some time.</p><p><strong>I’m always curious because every new category now has some sort of ongoing service dependency, which feels very risky. Our audience is constantly telling us that one reason they go back to big companies over and over again and won’t buy products from challengers or startups is that they don’t want their products to disappear. And then big companies like Google have broken that trust anyway. This is a really ongoing conversation with <em>The Verge</em> audience. It must be new for you. When you were at Procter &amp; Gamble, I’m assuming people didn’t buy shampoo and then worry you were going to stop selling shampoo.</strong></p><p>That’s so true, and it’s such an interesting topic. Actually, at Procter &amp; Gamble, we did get lots of people calling when you took their lipstick shade out, but that’s a little different. There’s no software inside.</p><p><strong>Yeah, you weren’t breaking all the existing lipsticks that had been sold.</strong></p><p>Exactly. Again, this is a space that’s somewhat newer for Logitech, but it’s incredibly strategic. We don’t do just pure hardware. We do design-led, software-enabled hardware, and that software component in the age of AI is more important every day. The services that we provide to our corporate customers are actually a nicely growing part of the business that didn’t exist a few years ago because Logitech was new to B2B and wasn’t charging for its services. Now we are.&nbsp;</p><p>I think we deliver great software services to our B2B customers, but we are learning. On the consumer side as well, through Logitech Options Plus, the software, it’s very important to deliver superior products for our users. We now have more software engineers than hardware engineers, which is a big milestone.</p><p><strong>This comes up in surprising ways on <em>Decoder</em>. The CTO of John Deere </strong><a href="https://www.theverge.com/22533735/john-deere-cto-hindman-decoder-interview-right-to-repair-tractors"><strong>once told me</strong></a><strong> that John Deere has more software engineers than hardware engineers because it has to support</strong> <strong>the ongoing service and cloud capabilities of the tractor. This makes a little more sense for Logitech, but really what we’re talking about is an ongoing cost. You sell me the keyboard once. It’s got Options Plus. It has an AI button. I push the button, and someone has to make sure the software still works. Someone probably has to pay ChatGPT for access to the service. Where is that going to come from? Are you baking that into the margin of the keyboard or the mouse?</strong></p><p>Absolutely. We’re baking that in, and I’m not particularly worried about that. What I’m actually hoping is that this will contribute to the longevity of our products, that we’ll have more premium products but products that last longer because they’re superior and because we can continue to update them over time. And again, I talked about doubling the business and reducing the carbon footprint by half. The longevity piece is really important.</p><p>I’m very intrigued. The other day, in Ireland, in our innovation center there, one of our team members showed me a forever mouse with the comparison to a watch. This is a nice watch, not a super expensive watch, but I’m not planning to throw that watch away ever. So why would I be throwing my mouse or my keyboard away if it’s a fantastic-quality, well-designed, software-enabled mouse. The forever mouse is one of the things that we’d like to get to.</p><p><strong>What made the mouse a forever mouse?</strong></p><p>It was a little heavier, it had great software and services that you’d constantly update, and it was beautiful. So I don’t think we’re necessarily super far away from that.</p><p><strong>But, again, I just come back to the cost. You sell me the mouse once. Maybe I’ll pay 200 bucks for it.</strong></p><p>The business model obviously is the challenge there. So then software is even more important when you think about it. Can you come up with a service model? In our video conferencing business, that is now a very important part of the model, the services, and it’s critical for corporate customers.</p><p><strong>Let’s come to that in a second because that makes sense to me. You sell managed services to enterprises. You price support contracts for cameras and whatever. That’s an ongoing need businesses have. I’m still stuck on, “You’re going to sell me a mouse once and it’s going to have ongoing software updates forever.”</strong></p><p>Imagine it’s like your Rolex. You’re going to really love that.</p><p><strong>But Rolex has to employ software engineers to ship me over-the-air updates forever.</strong></p><p>But the artifact is like your Rolex, and then given that we know the technology that we attach to changes, it’s not going to be like your Rolex in that it doesn’t have to ever change. Our stuff will have to change, but does the hardware have to change? I’m not so sure. We’ll have to obviously fix it and figure out what that business model is. We’re not at the forever mouse today, but I’m intrigued by the thought.</p><p><strong>It certainly will help with sustainability. There are two ways people have traditionally proposed monetizing hardware over time. It’s subscription fees and it’s advertising. Is there a third way that I don’t know about that you’re thinking of?</strong></p><p>No. The third way is the traditional model of “we innovate and we have you upgrade.” That’s the current model. And we’re pretty damn good at that model because we have pretty damn good innovators around the company who do come up with fabulous products.&nbsp;</p><p>That is definitely the model today. It’s not a bad model at all, especially since we’re continuing to design for more sustainable products. We’re continuing to recycle and refurbish products. All of that is good. But that said, I am intrigued by a forever mouse or forever video conferencing solution that you just update with software and create a business model around that.</p><p><strong>I’m going to ask this very directly. Can you envision a subscription mouse?</strong></p><p>Possibly.</p><p><strong>And that would be the forever mouse?</strong></p><p>Yeah.</p><p><strong>So you pay a subscription for software updates to your mouse.</strong></p><p>Yeah, and you never have to worry about it again, which is not unlike our video conferencing services today.</p><p><strong>But it’s a mouse.</strong></p><p>But it’s a mouse, yeah.</p><p><strong>I think consumers might perceive those to be very different.&nbsp;</strong></p><p>[<em>Laughs</em>] Yes, but it’s gorgeous. Think about it like a diamond-encrusted mouse.</p><p><strong>You mentioned AI earlier. You have rolled out some of the AI features in the new versions of Options Plus. There is a mouse with an AI button.</strong></p><p>Actually, sorry, Nilay. I am going to give you just a little piece of information. So the mouse built this house. Is that a traditional category? Will it go away? Is it old and tired? We don’t believe so because only about 50 percent of people use a mouse and a keyboard today, a separate keyboard.</p><p>Some only have a mouse or only a keyboard, but many of them have both. But the thing that shocked me was that the average spend on that globally is $26, which is really so low. This is stuff you use every day, that sits on your desk every day, that you look at every day. That’s like the price of four coffees at Starbucks or less than a Nike running shirt. There is so much room to create more value in that space as we make people more productive — to extend human potential.</p><p><strong>Do you think the growth comes from going from 50 to 55 percent, or does it come from selling the 50 percent more expensive products?&nbsp;</strong></p><p>Both. Absolutely both. That’s why this is still an exciting category.</p><p><strong>One of the things about keyboards in particular is that they have become lifestyle items. You see influencers on TikTok talk about their setups. We run photos of people’s setups. People have deep abiding attachments to their key switches in their keyboards. I’m assuming this is new to you, unless you were a diehard mechanical keyboard fan before, which would be amazing. You’re looking at it from a background in consumer products. What’s your view of that, of the keyboard as a lifestyle product?</strong></p><p>I definitely think it’s an important lifestyle product. Obviously, on the gaming side, it’s a really important lifestyle product, and again, it’s a real growth opportunity for us for many years to come. On the work side, what I’m intrigued by is that the needs of different people are very different when it comes to keyboards and mice. So we have done a nice job of growing this business by targeting different groups.&nbsp;</p><p>You have advanced users: a software engineer; a financial analyst who is in Excel all day. They need our MX line where you can do tons of shortcuts. I met someone over the weekend who — I didn’t even know this was possible — had done 120 shortcuts on one of our mice. I’m like, “What? I’m proud I have four.” But anyway, these are super advanced users, and we make MX products for them.</p><p>Then you have people who have some wellness issues because they’re also typing all day, but they’re sitting at the kitchen table or on an airplane like me, and they’re screwing up their arms. So the Ergo line — also very premium, very beautiful — is really made for them. I use an Ergo keyboard. It’s fantastic. It really helps on the shoulder and the arm. Then you have more lifestyle, younger people, especially in China, who want the pink mouse or who want the mouse that goes with the latest game. So these are really different groups, and I think we have opportunities to go even deeper on those consumer needs to build exactly the right products for them.</p><p><strong>That differentiation between gaming and professional and lifestyle, you can pull them apart. I think a lot of companies try to pull them apart. But I think, from my view, they’re getting mashed together. The needs of a gamer and the needs of the Excel macro fanatic, they’re more the same than different in some cases. And then the high-design lifestyle category and gaming as a lifestyle are also the same in very important ways. How do you pull those apart? What’s your approach to that, especially because you have a view from the outside?</strong></p><p>Absolutely. It’s funny. It’s an “and, and.” In some cases, you’re absolutely right, things are blurring. In China, we’re seeing a lot of people working with our gaming stuff, but then there’s also complete bifurcation. Our top-of-the-line gaming mouse is the Pro Light, which is the most simplistic-looking from the outside: a super light, thin thing with a lot of exciting software inside. Whereas our top-of-the-line MX mouse for advanced users is not at all minimalistic because it has 18 buttons and scrollers and whatever. You’ll see the same guy who’s a software engineer by day and a gamer by night use both. So it’s a “yes, and.” And again, it’s really important we understand all of those users and that we build fabulous products for them.</p><p><strong>The really interesting thing about keyboards and mice is that they’re tied to desktop computing as a paradigm, particularly mice. You can plug a mouse into an iPad, but why? You can buy the case, and Apple has a lot of decisions to make about the future of the iPad, but really what we’re talking about is desktop computers: macOS, Windows, Linux, big monitors maybe. </strong></p><p><strong>There’s an endless prediction that this will go away, that mobile will take over everything. That prediction does not appear to have borne out. When you’re thinking about Logitech’s markets, how do you evaluate that? Is it that eventually everyone will just have a phone and the laptop will go away? Even if the evidence doesn’t seem to bear it out, it is a permanent prediction in the tech industry.</strong></p><p>It’s definitely a permanent prediction. As I onboarded at the company, I had a few history lessons. I went through historical documents, and this same thing came up 20–25 years ago: the PC is imminently disappearing. That has not happened, but that doesn’t mean we shouldn’t absolutely be paranoid. One of our innovation streams is called “Beyond the PC,” and we’re dedicating significant resources to innovating beyond the PC.</p><p>Of course, some of what we sell today, quite a good amount of what we sell today, video conferencing, is already beyond the PC. That’s important. If you look at one of our recent innovations, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/6/17/24180060/logitech-mx-ink-stylus-meta-quest-vr-ar">we announced two weeks ago</a> the MX Ink, which is a stylus for the Meta Quest. That’s definitely beyond the PC. So hopefully you get a sense of what we’ll need to do more of in this space, but we know how to do it. I like this example a lot, the MX Ink stylus for Meta, because it’s beyond the PC but also helps us think about work beyond the office. Who’s going to use that stylus? It’s creative people, it’s doctors. It’s not your traditional office worker.</p><p><strong>One thing that’s really difficult about going beyond the PC is that there are vastly more gatekeepers once you leave the realm of Mac and Windows. It’s Apple and Google in particular. There are things that they will simply not allow you to do with their devices. There’s software you can’t ship. There are drivers you can’t load. There are peripherals that won’t attach, all the way down the line. Has that been a bit of a wake-up call?</strong></p><p>Well, it’s been an area where I’m actually very impressed. Logitech, I think, has the best set of partnerships in the industry, and it’s proud of it and it nurtures those partnerships. Whether it’s Microsoft, Alphabet, Meta, Apple, Zoom, we work closely with all of them, and we’re able to develop products with and for them, including Apple, which is fantastic but a little secretive at times, which is their right and they’re amazing.</p><p>We just came out with a <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/5/7/24151465/logitechs-updated-ipad-keyboards-are-the-ones-for-school-lab-carts">Combo Touch for the new iPads</a>, which is a beautiful product, and we work with Apple with Berlin walls around [those products]. So it’s kind of funny. My team in Taiwan who works on that, they were wearing T-shirts when I came that said, “My work is so secretive, I don’t even know what I’m working on.”</p><p><strong>[<em>Laughs</em>] That’s very good.</strong></p><p>But that’s a really close collaboration with a fabulous company, Apple. MX Ink is an example of Meta. And obviously we’re very close in our video conferencing business and beyond to Microsoft, Google, and Zoom. It’s a unique set of partnerships. This company was born as an American and Swiss company. That neutrality of working with all these partners is where the Swissness comes to life best.</p><p><strong>Let me ask you to compare more directly. A lot of times in the tech world when people complain about app store policies or restrictions on what the OS will let you do or the Apple tax, the immediate comparison is, “Well, Walmart controls what goes in its stores,” or, “Target controls what goes in its stores.” You used to work on Head &amp; Shoulders, and if you wanted the end cap at Walmart for Head &amp; Shoulders, you had to pay them some extra money for additional marketing. The analogy is there. It comes up all the time.</strong></p><p><strong>You’re a very unique person to ask this question of, because I have always thought, well, Walmart has competition. If you’re not getting a favorable rate to put the shampoo in Walmart, you can go to Target or the grocery store or Walgreens or wherever else. The platforms do not have that in that way. Have you felt that yet in your seven months?</strong></p><p>You’re right that they don’t in that way. If I use video conferencing as an example, there is competition. Microsoft is obviously very large, but there is Google and there is Zoom. We do work really well with all three of them and we value all three of them and we put significant resources against all three of them, and they do the same with us. It’s not like there’s only one. And that’s true when it comes to virtual reality as well as beyond the PC. It’s a real competitive advantage for Logitech to have this range of partnerships and not just be in bed with any one of them.</p><p><strong>Are there things you’d like to build or ideas you’ve heard that are being blocked by the various rules that the mobile platforms have in place?</strong></p><p>No. Again, it’s been seven months so this may change, but from what I’ve seen, we can talk about everything, including with the very big boys. I love that and I think that will lead to some really great innovation going forward.</p><p><strong>But if you wanted to have the AI button on a keyboard connected to an iPad that brought up your overlay and Options Plus to create a prompt, Apple would simply not let you do that on iPadOS in the way that you can on Windows and macOS. </strong></p><p>Yeah, and again, I’m not sure that’s something we would die on our sword for.</p><p><strong>Makes sense. The other piece of the puzzle here is basically everybody at some point tells me that they won’t die on their sword to continue connecting to Apple, but it just seems very obvious to me that comparison to retail falls apart because there are so many more retailers.</strong></p><p>Yeah, although Walmart, don’t underestimate the size of Walmart, certainly in the US.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><p><strong>Fair enough. The other world Logitech lives in is the world of standards. There’s USB for however much you’re going to play in the smart home. There’s Matter. There’s Bluetooth. Every time we do an episode on standards, we discover it’s intensely political and almost not technical in a very specific way. Has that come up for you — “Boy, we need to make sure that the next version of the USB standard can do all the things we want it to do”? Or are you saying, “We’re going to let the platforms figure that out”?</strong></p><p>We’re really active in all of the industry forums and associations that talk about standards because it is really important for us, not just for the platforms. I would say the most important thing is that there is a standard because, when there isn’t, that just creates complexity and cost for everyone. We’re active and always trying to go for a standard.</p><p>I think we’ll have to go to some new standards as well. One of the things I’m quite proud of at Logitech is that we carbon-label our products with a really solid methodology. It shows that your mouse is 1.5 in terms of emissions and your keyboard is 15 and your video conference, I don’t know by heart, but it’s a lot more. What would be super interesting is if we could get to an industry standard for carbon labeling so that consumers and corporate consumers can make a choice on a product that has lower emissions. That’s one of the things we’re trying to work with some industry associations and groups on. But in general, standardization is important for the industry, and we’ll push that as hard as we can.</p><p><strong>Did you open a door in some office at Logitech and find the people who have to work with the standards board and it’s just a group of sad lawyers?</strong></p><p>They’re really exciting. They’re great.</p><p><strong>I’m dying to know.</strong></p><p>There’s not a lot of them. There’s like one, but they’re super active.</p><p><strong>You’ve talked about climate and sustainability several times now. Let’s talk about it in the context of AI. A bunch of the big companies, in particular companies investing in data centers and foundation models, they’re </strong><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/7/2/24190874/google-ai-climate-change-carbon-emissions-rise"><strong>blowing their climate goals out of the water</strong></a><strong> because they’re spending so much more in energy to power these AI systems. Those things are obviously in tension. You’re in on AI. You have Options Plus. You have the buttons on the mice. Then you’re also talking about being sustainable. How are you managing that tension?</strong></p><p>Clearly we’re not building LLMs ourselves, so the impact of our stuff is very modest. It’s on the edge. In the context of our total footprint, we don’t expect that to have a significant impact. Our impact sits in materials and components, in PCBs and plastics, and it sits in the circularity, or the lack thereof. Because we sell stuff, hardware, and that’s a huge part of our footprint.&nbsp;</p><p>So that is not where I’m concerned, but clearly, as an industry, we should be super concerned about the fact that pretty much every player has goals to be carbon neutral by 2040 or 2050, but right now the numbers are only going up and up and up. That is very concerning. We’re a relatively small player, but I hope we can be a pioneer and show the way on taking real climate action rather than just buying offsets.</p><p><strong>Some of your goals are using more than 70 percent recycled plastic in manufacturing. Can you get to 100 percent? Is that feasible?</strong></p><p>We should be able to get very close. The first priority for us on our glide path to a 50 percent emissions reduction by 2030 is to expand what we already know how to do. I’m really proud that Logitech is already at 75 percent of products using recycled plastic. That is huge. Unilever, Nestlé, Procter &amp; Gamble, they’re like 20 percent. This is huge on a large number of products every year. We also know what to do in terms of low-carbon aluminum, low-carbon some other things. We’ve got to scale what we already know how to do, and I think we can get very close to 100 percent.</p><p>Then we have to use renewable energy wherever we can because that is a big part of our footprint. And then third and fourth, we have to innovate and we have to drive circularity. The last one is probably the hardest innovation to come. PCBs are a big focus for innovation. They’re a big part of our footprint as well, and they’re very carbon-intensive. We know what the four pillars are: We have to scale. We have to use renewable energy. We have to innovate, and we have to go for circularity. And then I think we have a fighting chance to actually be minus 50 percent and again grow the business because that’s the tricky thing here and that’s what Google and Microsoft are really struggling with right now.</p><p><strong>Can you quickly define circularity?</strong></p><p>The forever mouse, and the forever mouse could be the mouse that you keep and we just send you software updates, but it could also be the mouse that you turn in at Best Buy and we get it back or Best Buy takes it back and refurbs and resells it, which is another business model. We’re starting to do that but not yet at the scale that we need to.</p><p><strong>Let’s end on the forever mouse because I’m fascinated by this concept: the idea that you would have a mouse and you’d buy it once and then you’d maybe pay some fees for software upgrades or you’d trade it in and get a newer one, and that would be a recurring revenue source for you. That all depends on a vision of what the mouse software should do besides just move the cursor around. But whenever we do episodes with anything to do with AI, our audience is like, “We don’t want this.” In a very direct way, sometimes they’re like, “We don’t want this and we especially don’t want it here.”</strong></p><p><strong>We might want it when we want it. I might want to use generative fill in Photoshop on my terms, but I don’t need it to follow me around the computer. And even if you’re saying the climate impact is minimal, I certainly don’t want to feel like there’s any climate impact of using my mouse and expanding the range of places where you might go ask OpenAI for inference. That’s one problem. The second problem is you’re still competing with OpenAI and Google and Apple to be the primary interface for their backend services, right? You’re not training your own model.</strong></p><p><strong>The question for me is really twofold. It’s one:&nbsp; is there a vision beyond “the software will do more for you” than just drive your mouse around? And the second part is: even if it can do more, can you realistically compete against the giants that have every incentive to make sure that you never look anywhere else?</strong></p><p>On the second piece, this company has been a human-technology interface for its entire existence. And while the mouse built this house and maybe there won’t be mice forever — although I think there’ll be mice for a long time to come — we’ve always been that human-technology interface. There were always people who said, “Well, Google and Microsoft won’t want you to be.” In fact, they often come to us and say, “We want an interface.” So, that MX Ink, it’s not that we were pushing Meta really hard. It was Meta saying, “Oh, we’d love for you to do something like this,” and us saying, “Well, we think we can.” </p><p>I think the big players will continue to want to work with players like us who have the luxury of focus. For us, a $40 million idea is 1 percent growth. Whereas, for Microsoft or Google, that’s nothing. That luxury of focus is important, and I think we’ll continue to be a human-technology interface in that way. Should the mouse do more than just move the cursor? Absolutely. And it does that today, and I think similarly about being more productive with shortcuts to the large language models and all kinds of other things. The guy that I met at a barbecue over the weekend who has programmed 120 shortcuts on his mouse, that’s the kind of stuff that can extend human potential in ways that are healthier.</p><p><strong>This idea — that Logitech sits at a machine-human interface — right now, it’s expressed in Options Plus. Your software that has AI in it is essentially prompt engineering, right? You’re guiding people through the process of making a prompt, which is, for better or worse, how we are all talking to AI right now.</strong></p><p>Yeah, totally.</p><p><strong>Is that it? Is that the vision? Is there a different vision? Is that just the stopping point right now?</strong></p><p>No, I think we’re at the beginning of AI, and [with time], it will become multimodal and we won’t even need to build prompts because it will know what prompts we need. Things will evolve exactly how that will evolve. Who knows? But I think the human is going to be a limiting factor. Human hands, the human brain. I suspect we’ll still need human-technology interfaces. They may not look exactly like what Logitech sells today, but I think the future for human-technology interfaces is really, really bright.</p><p><strong>The danger there is that’s also what Apple and Microsoft and Google see. I talked to </strong><a href="https://www.theverge.com/24158374/google-ceo-sundar-pichai-ai-search-gemini-future-of-the-internet-web-openai-decoder-interview"><strong>Sundar Pichai</strong></a><strong> and </strong><a href="https://www.theverge.com/23589994/microsoft-ceo-satya-nadella-bing-chatgpt-google-search-ai"><strong>Satya Nadella</strong></a><strong>, and they happily tell me that AI is a platform shift. And what they mean is that it’s an interface shift, that we’re going to get the phone out of your hand or you’re going to deal with something else that is not Apple’s phone. That’s very much what they mean.</strong></p><p><strong>What they’re talking about is, “Okay, you’re going to talk to the computer. It’s going to do stuff for you.” Or, “You’re going to issue a set of commands, and the computer will figure out how to do whatever task you want it to.” You can already see they’re getting there. You can see some of the demos of the concepts. Do you worry about that disintermediating Logitech?</strong></p><p>Yeah, but again, there’s still going to be technology, whether that’s an AI button or something else. I think Logitech did a really fine job surviving the shift from PC to phone and still being a fabulous interface. I’m pretty sure that with the fabulous engineers and designers we have, we’ll also be an interface to whatever’s next.</p><p><strong>Well, that’s a great place to end it. Hanneke, tell the people what you think is next for Logitech. You’ve been there for seven months. What’s the stuff you’re looking forward to now that you’ve figured it out?</strong></p><p>We’ve got a great bunch of innovations coming up. I could tell you, but I’d have to kill you. [<em>Laughs</em>.] As we go toward the end of your holidays, I think we have a really bright fiscal year ahead, and then we’ll continue to extend human potential in work and play.</p><p><strong>I love it. Well, the mouse built this house. This is amazing. Thank you so much for joining <em>Decoder</em>.</strong></p><p>Alright, it is so nice to see you, Nilay.</p><div><div><h2>Decoder with Nilay Patel<!-- --> <!-- --> / </h2><p>A podcast from The Verge about big ideas and other problems.</p></div><p><a href="https://pod.link/decoder">SUBSCRIBE NOW!</a></p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Watch YouTubers Use Mario Kart's Green Shells To Destroy A Car In Real Life]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/mario-kart-no-bitrate-green-shell-real-life-1851607447</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/watch-youtubers-use-mario-karts-green-shells-to-destroy-a-car-in-real-life.939378/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/mario-kart-no-bitrate-green-shell-real-life-1851607447<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>There are many who lament the effects of YouTube on our children’s minds, as unvetted dross-like entertainment is churned out separately from the eyes of regulatory bodies, inevitably crammed with product placement and woeful thought of child safety. But <em>then</em>, there are people who spend three months figuring out how to fire <em>Mario Kart</em>-style green shells from the roof of their car.<br></p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196923" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Kotaku’s Hopes For Spyro The Dragon’s (Reported) Comeback" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="355" data-playlist="196923,196922,196918" data-current="196923"><div><p>Kotaku’s Hopes For Spyro The Dragon’s (Reported) Comeback</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196923/196923_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196923/196923_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196923/196923_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196923/196923_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/22494.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>This is thanks to Alex Corea, known on YouTube as <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.youtube.com/@NoBitrate&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.youtube.com/@NoBitrate" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">No Bitrate</a></span>, a sort of baby <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.youtube.com/@MarkRober&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.youtube.com/@MarkRober" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Mark Rober</a></span>, with swearing. The channel’s ethos is to build “some of the dumbest, most dangerous things online (that are allowed on YouTube).” But that does rather sell it short, given the Rober-like efforts to include a hefty amount of educational-adjacent information on the physics, math, and experimentation involved. But yes, it’s also far dumber in the best way.</p><p>On the pretence that other similar channels are too scared to try, Corea set out to be the first to recreate a real-life version of <em>Mario Kart</em>’s green shells, attempting to base as much as possible on what’s modelled in the games, and then throwing aside the bits that make it impossible.</p><p>A lot of guesstimation takes place, because of course this is about translating a cartoon concept to the real world, but there are nods toward attempting to make the shells the correct size, and indeed to work out the speed they would need to travel in order to cause the sorts of damage they see in the games. (Which also meant throwing out how fast they move in the games, because it turns out Nintendo does <em>not</em> respect physics.)</p><p>Then, once rockets become involved, comes the added challenge of figuring out how to launch the shells from the roof of a moving car, and be able to have them hit another car, all without breaking the law. Ironically, it turns out that using a remote-controlled car to ensure human safety <em>would</em> make this illegal<em>, </em>but sitting in the car themselves is juuuust fine.</p><p>Having spent years watching <em>Mythbusters</em>, it’s rather hard to cope with the absolute lack of the safety standards that came with going out on FTC-regulated cable, as Corea and chums fire dubiously legal rockets in the desert with no more protection than a pair of shades. (Although, eventually, a tank-like windshield, thank god.)</p><p>The results, however, are glorious. If...slightly dissimilar to <em>Mario Kart</em>’s own shelling.</p><p>Nonsense like this always offers me hope. These are smart people doing a dumb thing in a smart way, the sort of thing that can point a lot of young minds toward STEM subjects. It’s also superbly edited, if a little frenetic, and funny.</p><p>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fortnite Leak Claims Creative Mode Could Add Collab Items]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-leak-claims-creative-mode-could-add-collab-items/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fortnite-leak-claims-creative-mode-could-add-collab-items.939375/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-leak-claims-creative-mode-could-add-collab-items/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>In a recent <a href="https://x.com/HYPEX/status/1817260295460643148" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">post on X</a>, reliable longtime leaker HYPEX teased that Fortnite Creative Mode could potentially let players create maps with IP collaboration items.</p>



<p>HYPEX did not have a concrete release window to accompany the leak. However, today’s post suggested the Fortnite teams is already “working on a way” to implement the feature.</p>



<p>The leaker also claims that collaboration items involving Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles are currently supported so far. </p>



<p>However, the new feature may come at the cost of revenue sharing. HYPEX claimed that more IP content could “likely” require maps with collab items to share a percentage of its revenue “with the IP owners.”</p>



<figure><div>
<blockquote data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>FORTNITE CREATIVE x COLLABS 🔥</p><p>Fortnite are working on a way to let you create Maps with Collab Items in them, but so far the only supported items are TMNT.. They'll likely add more &amp; share a % of your map's revenue with the IP owners.. <a href="https://t.co/miJSHTXxlS">pic.twitter.com/miJSHTXxlS</a></p></div>— HYPEX (@HYPEX) <a href="https://twitter.com/HYPEX/status/1817260295460643148?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 27, 2024</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>







<p>Fans consistently request collab items for Creative Mode, and it could open a lot of inventive opportunities. Fortnite frequently collaborates with popular IP, such as the recent <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-will-introduce-a-deadpool-wolverine-bundle-its-claimed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">tie-in with Deadpool &amp; Wolverine.</a></p>



<p>Besides the Creative leak, HYPEX also recently leaked an extensive <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-leaks-tease-release-dates-for-deadpool-wolverine-content-and-more/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">list of release dates</a> for new additions coming to the Fortnite Item Shop. </p>



<p>That includes more IP crossovers with Lethal Company, My Hero Academia, and Jujutsu Kaisen. HYPEX claims these items will release through the first week of August 2024.</p>



<p>Other new Fortnite leaks include the desert biome from chapter one <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-leaks-tease-desert-biome-possibly-coming-to-reload/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">possibly coming to Reload</a>. It’s one of many leaks that followed the major v30.30 update in Fortnite, which introduced a Fall Guys crossover and more.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more of the latest gaming industry news, you can read about Landfall announcing its plans for new <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/content-warning-gets-last-patch-for-a-while-devs-planning-new-ports/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Content Warning patches and ports</a>, and sign up to receive the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/newsletter/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming newsletter</a>.</p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Suicide Squad: Kill the Justice League Cutscene Suggests We're Now Saving the Justice League]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/suicide-squad-kill-the-justice-league-cutscene-suggests-were-now-saving-the-justice-league</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/suicide-squad-kill-the-justice-league-cutscene-suggests-were-now-saving-the-justice-league.939372/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/suicide-squad-kill-the-justice-league-cutscene-suggests-were-now-saving-the-justice-league<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>A new <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/suicide-squad-kill-the-justice-league">Suicide Squad: Kill The Justice League</a> cutscene has sparked a debate about the direction the story is going in, as the latest season teases the next playable character.</p><p>Mrs. Freeze was added to Rocksteady’s controversial live service shooter last week as part of the launch of Season 2, and with it came a cutscene that’s set tongues wagging within the game’s small but loyal community.</p><p><em><strong>Warning! Suicide Squad Kill The Justice League Season 2 spoilers follow:</strong></em></p><p>The new <a href="https://youtu.be/04ZpedLMA_U?feature=shared" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">cutscene</a> shows the return of The Flash after the Suicide Squad save him from captivity by killing yet another post-launch Brainiac as part of Season 2. The Suicide Squad had killed The Flash alongside other corrupted members of the Justice League in a bid to save Metropolis from destruction at the hands of Brainiac in the base game's main story.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3>Suicide Squad: Kill the Justice League Season 2 Images</h3></div></output><p>Some have called the story development a surprise, while others have said a post-launch plot twist that saw the return of “good” Justice League members was always on the cards. Either way, players are wondering about the exact nature of the Flash’s return, what it means for Brainiac’s masterplan, and raising the possibility that other characters apparently killed by the Suicide Squad, including Batman, Green Lantern, and Superman, could also be set to return.</p><p>One of the most controversial story beats in the Suicide Squad base game is <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/fans-are-pretty-mad-about-one-batman-scene-in-suicide-squad-kill-the-justice-league">the death of corrupted Arkham trilogy Batman</a>, who is unceremoniously executed by Harley Quinn. Some criticized the death, saying it failed to give the character, voiced by the late Kevin Conroy, the sendoff he deserved.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>But could Batman now be set to return alongside more voice work from Kevin Conroy? This new cutscene suggests the Suicide Squad killed clones of the original Justice League members during the main story, with Brainiac holding the real deals hostage. However, some suggest the Suicide Squad did in fact kill the original Justice League members, but Brainiac has since revived them, and it is now the task of Captain Boomerang, Deadshot, Harley Quinn, and King Shark, to save them.</p><p>Whatever the case, in the cutscene The Flash sees the Suicide Squad and wonders why they’re not in jail, before collapsing. The character’s return is not mentioned further.</p><p>Perhaps more revelations, and real Justice League members, will show up in Season 3, which looks set to add Lawless as a playable character. While the list of post-launch DLC characters was already leaked via a datamine, Rocksteady has teased their inclusion with changes to Metropolis that clearly indicate who’s up next. Season 1, for example, teased the arrival of Mrs. Freeze with a chilly change to Metropolis, and now players have spotted another change that suggests Lawless is coming soon. After Lawless, Deathstroke is expected to round out the year one list of playable characters.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/07/29/screenshot-2024-07-29-123841-1722253130592.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption>Image credit: <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/SuicideSquadGaming/comments/1eei22j/found_new_rift_bubble/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button">r/JacobLikesToastWI</a></figcaption></figure></output><p><a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/suicide-squad-kill-the-justice-league-review"><u>Suicide Squad: Kill the Justice League was of course panned by critics upon launch</u></a> and has extremely low player numbers on Steam. Some of the frustration stems from Suicide Squad: Kill the Justice League <em>not</em> being another Batman game from Rocksteady, despite being set within the Arkhamverse. The developer’s single-player Arkham series is much-loved by fans, with 2011’s <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/batman-arkham-city"><u>Batman: Arkham City</u></a> in particular held up as one of the greatest, if not <em>the</em> greatest, superhero video games of all time.</p><p>Suicide Squad: Kill the Justice League, on the other hand, is a live service third-person shooter in which Batman is a villain. Soon after the game's February 2024 release, publisher Warner Bros. admitted <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/suicide-squad-kill-the-justice-league-flop-leads-to-200-million-impairment-charge-warner-bros-confirms"><u>the failure of Suicide Squad: Kill the Justice League contributed to a $200 million hit to revenue</u></a>.</p><p>Last month, Warner Bros, told IGN that <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/suicide-squad-kill-the-justice-league-will-complete-its-currently-announced-roadmap-but-warner-bros-quiet-on-what-happens-after"><u>Suicide Squad: Kill the Justice League will see out its first year of support</u></a>, but declined to comment on what happens afterwards. The question is, will Rocksteady’s apparent post-launch plan to have the Suicide Squad pivot to saving the Justice League after killing them be fully realized?</p><p><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hatsune Miku: COLORFUL STAGE! anime movie Project SEKAI the Movie: Kowareta SEKAI to Utaenai MIKU announced]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/07/hatsune-miku-colorful-stage-anime-movie-project-sekai-the-movie-kowareta-sekai-to-utaenai-miku-announced</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hatsune-miku-colorful-stage-anime-movie-project-sekai-the-movie-kowareta-sekai-to-utaenai-miku-announced.939366/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/07/hatsune-miku-colorful-stage-anime-movie-project-sekai-the-movie-kowareta-sekai-to-utaenai-miku-announced<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/anime">Anime</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Premieres on January 17, 2025.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > CyberAgent [212 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/cyberagent">CyberAgent</a>, <a title="Companies > Colorful Palette [6 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/colorful-palette">Colorful Palette</a>, <a title="Companies > SEGA [2,600 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sega">SEGA</a>, and animation studio PAWORKS have <a href="https://prtimes.jp/main/html/rd/p/000000171.000085936.html" rel="noopener" target="_blank">announced</a> <em><a title="Games > Islands of Insight [5 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/islands-of-insight">Project S</a>EKAI the Movie: Kowareta SEKAI to Utaenai MIKU</em>, the first anime movie based on the rhythm and <a title="Genres > Adventure [1,641 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure game</a> <em><a title="Games > Hatsune Miku: COLORFUL STAGE! [6 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/hatsune-miku-colorful-stage">Hatsune Miku: COLORFUL STAGE!</a></em> (known as <em>Project SEKAI: COLORFUL STAGE! feat. Hatsune Miku</em> in Japan). It will premiere in theaters on January 17, 2025 in Japan. <span id="more-901795"></span></p><p>The movie will feature a completely original story, featuring a new Hatsune Miku not depicted in the game. The main visual displays a lonely-looking Hatsune Miku covered in noise on the busy streets of Shibuya, ignored by most of the people passing by, and without a reflection in the puddle beneath her.</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/Project-SEKAI-the-Movie_-Kowareta-SEKAI-to-Utaenai-MIKU_2024_07-29-24_012.jpg"></a></figure><p>Here is the story synopsis:</p><blockquote><p>“Tell me about yourself. Maybe then I’ll understand the song.”</p><p>Ichika Hoshino heard a Miku song she never heard before at a CD shop. On the monitor, she saw a Miku she had never seen, and unintentionally blurted “Miku!?” out loud. Surprised by her voice, Miku’s eyes meet with Ichika’s, but she disappeared soon after.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/Project-SEKAI-the-Movie_-Kowareta-SEKAI-to-Utaenai-MIKU_2024_07-29-24_001.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/Project-SEKAI-the-Movie_-Kowareta-SEKAI-to-Utaenai-MIKU_2024_07-29-24_002.jpg"></a></figure><p>Several days later, the Miku she had previously encountered appears on Ichika’s smartphone after a music performance on the street. Miku sadly hung her head, and when Ichika gently asked her about it, Miku told her that she wants to reach people with her song, but no matter how much she sings, her songs never reach anyone.</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/Project-SEKAI-the-Movie_-Kowareta-SEKAI-to-Utaenai-MIKU_2024_07-29-24_003.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/Project-SEKAI-the-Movie_-Kowareta-SEKAI-to-Utaenai-MIKU_2024_07-29-24_004.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/Project-SEKAI-the-Movie_-Kowareta-SEKAI-to-Utaenai-MIKU_2024_07-29-24_005.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/Project-SEKAI-the-Movie_-Kowareta-SEKAI-to-Utaenai-MIKU_2024_07-29-24_006.jpg"></a></figure><p>Seeing Ichika sing and reach the hearts of many during her own performances, Miku thought that she could do the same if she got to know her, and so she came to Ichika. Ichika smiles and responds to Miku’s wish with, “If you think I’m good enough,” and thus begins a new Hatsune Miku story with the youth.</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/Project-SEKAI-the-Movie_-Kowareta-SEKAI-to-Utaenai-MIKU_2024_07-29-24_007.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/Project-SEKAI-the-Movie_-Kowareta-SEKAI-to-Utaenai-MIKU_2024_07-29-24_008.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/Project-SEKAI-the-Movie_-Kowareta-SEKAI-to-Utaenai-MIKU_2024_07-29-24_009.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/Project-SEKAI-the-Movie_-Kowareta-SEKAI-to-Utaenai-MIKU_2024_07-29-24_010.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/Project-SEKAI-the-Movie_-Kowareta-SEKAI-to-Utaenai-MIKU_2024_07-29-24_011.jpg"></a></figure></blockquote><p>Watch the announcement trailer below. Visit the official website <a href="https://sh-anime.shochiku.co.jp/pjsekai-movie/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">here</a>.</p><h2><span>Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="『劇場版プロジェクトセカイ　壊れたセカイと歌えないミク』特報映像" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/e1TrAhX3qnY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Modern Warfare 3 See’s Influx in Cheaters Following Xbox Game Pass Debut]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/modern-warfare-3-cheaters-game-pass/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/modern-warfare-3-see%E2%80%99s-influx-in-cheaters-following-xbox-game-pass-debut.939354/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/modern-warfare-3-cheaters-game-pass/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>Call of Duty: Modern Warfare 3 has seen an influx of cheaters since it was released on Xbox Game Pass.</p>



<p>That’s according to Call of Duty X handle (formerly Twitter) <a href="https://x.com/charlieINTEL/status/1817575928312263085" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">CharlieINTEL</a>, who has reported that an influx of cheaters has been spotted following the game’s debut in Game Pass. As CharlieINTEL points out, most cheaters appear with an Xbox logo in the game lobby. </p>



<p>Activision is yet to comment on the increase in cheaters, but given the game’s debut on Game Pass, which would offer the game to potentially 10’s of millions more players (34 million users as of February 2024), it isn’t difficult to see why there could be an influx of cheaters. The task now, though, is banning and preventing them from returning.</p>



<p>Before the release of Modern Warfare 3, Activision announced that its Richochet anti-cheat system was using machine learning and client—and server-side systems that continue to evolve and grow to combat cheating. In the lead-up to Modern Warfare 3, Richchet banned over 80,000 accounts during Monder Warfare 2 (80,000 accounts banned in 12 months).</p>



<p>We wouldn’t be surprised to see a blog post from Activision in the coming weeks about the issue, what they are doing to combat cheating, and how many more players have since been banned.</p>



<p>For now, though, players of Modern Warfare 3 will have to endure the influx of new cheaters.</p>



<p>Have you seen any cheaters in Modern Warfare 3? Let us know in the comments below!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more of the latest Insider Gaming news, you can read about new claims suggesting that Mafia: Definitive edition is coming to Xbox Game Pass&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-game-pass-will-receive-mafia-definitive-edition-on-august-13-its-claimed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">in August 2024</a>, and sign up for&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/newsletter/">our official newsletter</a>.</p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A small games manifesto]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/production/a-small-games-manifesto</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/a-small-games-manifesto.939342/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/production/a-small-games-manifesto<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Hi, I am Brandon Dillon, co-founder of 2weeks, a new independent development studio building experimental games on the open web. As many of you know, games cost too much to make.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">I’m speaking less about the current economics of game development, though certainly much has been written about the difficulties faced by the industry during the current period of contraction.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">I’m speaking about the personal costs to us as developers. As a game’s team size expands, your relative contribution to the work shrinks. As development timelines rise, you get fewer opportunities to make new games. The risks increase as well: delays and cancellations can further dilute and erase your contributions.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">AAA games now often take 5-7 years to make. According to the 2023 </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="http://gameworkers.org/">gameworkers.org</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> survey, more than half of all developers (57.3%) worked on AAA games, and less than half (45%) had tenures longer than seven years. Many game developers are lucky to ship a single game.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">We find ourselves in a unique time - the pandemic led to a gaming bubble that has since burst, and rising interest rates have cut off the easy access to capital that could help studios weather the reversal, but these dynamics have only amplified a trend that has been steadily progressing.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Raph Koster has been talking about the central cause for a long time: development budgets correlate with technology advancement, and both have been growing exponentially. Almost two decades ago, Koster gave a talk where he referred to this phenomenon as </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.raphkoster.com/games/presentations/moores-wall-technology-advances-and-online-game-design/">Moore’s Wall</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a data-discover="true" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/why-is-it-so-expensive-to-make-games-in-the-united-states-" target="_self">Why is it so expensive to make games in the United States?</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Moore’s Law is a famous observation in computing that the number of transistors in computer chips has doubled roughly every two years. After decades of consistent doubling, the phenomenon has led to astounding growth in the capabilities of our computing devices and will continue to.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Moore’s Wall represents the realization that the increase in content production needed to keep up with this growth will eventually hit an economic limit. Koster </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.raphkoster.com/2018/01/17/the-cost-of-games/">updated his analysis in 2018</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and concluded that development costs for AAA games were increasing roughly 10x every 10 years.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Audience growth has let us keep up with rising costs for a long time. Good news: gaming is now pervasive! NewZoo’s latest global gamer study shows that 94% of Gen Alpha play games. Bad news: this means audience growth is now just population growth.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Development costs continue to grow exponentially, but audience growth no longer does. There’s still opportunity for growth in emerging markets, but it is not exponential. There’s an intercept point where our current approach to game development ceases to be economically feasible.</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a data-discover="true" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/production/illusion-of-skill-how-to-make-a-better-game-in-less-time" target="_self">The illusion of skill: how to make a better game in less time</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">There’s a good chance we’ve hit that point.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">So, what do we do?</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Some folks believe that AI tools will drive more efficiency, but as Koster notes that we’ve actually been getting more efficient at producing content the whole time; just not fast enough to keep up with the pace of technology. AI tools are not likely to close the gap. Koster has </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.raphkoster.com/2012/01/04/making-games-more-cheaply/">a number of useful suggestions</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> to manage rising costs including embracing tools, but mitigations are not enough. The thing we need to do is clear:</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">We need to make smaller games.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Of course, indie developers have been building on a smaller scale the whole time, and they’ve become an increasingly important part of our ecosystem. Thanks to the Wall, that trend will continue. According to Konvoy, indie games accounted for 31% of all Steam revenue, and is up significantly so far in 2024.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Many AAA studios have their roots in this kind of small-scale development. Even the greatest epics of our medium trace back to smaller, more experimental games. GTA III, perhaps the strongest influence for the modern AAA open world formula, was developed in two years by a couple dozen people. Elden Ring traces its lineage back to King’s Field, developed in six months by ten people.</span></p><p>King’s Field for the PlayStation&nbsp;</p><p>Elden Ring</p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">But as traditional studios have grown to larger and larger scales, they’ve lost their connection to this style of development. The work becomes more about building an efficient content production organization and less about finding new kinds of compelling gameplay.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">That’s not to say that traditional studios don’t try. It’s hard not to - every studio is full of tons of talented and creative developers with compelling ideas for new games. Most large studios have some kind of internal incubation or prototyping process to try and harness that energy. Too often, though, projects from these incubation efforts fail to make it past the greenlighting process.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Often, this has little to do with the potential market viability of the new game concept, and much more to do with the internal pressures at the studio. This isn’t just because of studio politics and risk aversion. As people have built massive organizations that have become heavily specialized in making a particular kind of game, it’s often simply too much risk to change that organization to build a different kind.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">And yet, something must change. Games that require massive teams are unsustainable and will hit an economic limit that will force studios to scale back, hurting teams and failing to meet player expectations. This will lead to stagnation and decline or has already.</span></p><p>Source: Video Game Business Management Economics, Eric Bailey</p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">If you’re part of leadership at a traditional studio, it’s time to greenlight the risky new ideas - especially the ones that can scale without a huge content investment. Build smaller teams, take new, leaner approaches to production, to bring new games to market. Your future depends on it.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">If you’re a developer at a traditional studio, and you have ideas for newer, smaller concepts the studio can pursue, pitch them! Your studio needs to find new paths. If new paths don’t seem possible, keep an eye on the growth potential for the studio’s existing projects and make your own evaluation of the long-term sustainability of the studio’s approach.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">If you’re at a smaller indie studio, congratulations: you’re already part of the future of the industry. Be wary of ambitions to build the next big AAA studio. Most great franchises were born from small games and incremental investment. This is far from easy in a crowded market, but it’s the path to sustainable success.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Brandon Dillon</span></span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Co-founder, 2weeks, a new independent game development studio building experimental games on the open web for you and your friends.</span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[More Than Movements: Animation in Mobile Game Dev]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/mobile/more-than-movements-animation-in-mobile-game-dev</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/more-than-movements-animation-in-mobile-game-dev.939339/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/mobile/more-than-movements-animation-in-mobile-game-dev<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">My name is Mikhail, and I have been working in the animation and game development industry for over 8 years. I live in London and specialize in creating 2D/3D animations, providing feedback, and improving workflows for mobile games. Throughout my career, I have participated in numerous projects and collaborated with colleagues from different countries. However, I've noticed that many problems in the industry remain relevant year after year, despite technological advancements and the availability of knowledge.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">In this article, I want to share my thoughts, examine common problems in 2D/3D character animation and UI, and share my experience in solving them. If you are interested in game development or animation, this article is for you.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="IS IT ALIVE? PROBLEMS OF GAME ANIMATIONS">IS IT ALIVE? PROBLEMS OF GAME ANIMATIONS</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Before delving into the issues of animation in games, I want to highlight the difference between two key concepts: </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>"animation"</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>"motion."</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">Although at first glance they may seem synonymous, there is a significant distinction between them. </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Motion</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> is merely the foundation of animation, the physical movement of an object from point A to point B. It is an important component but does not encompass the essence of the process.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Animation</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> is the art of bringing these movements to life, adding depth through the conveyance of characters' moods and emotions. It involves the use of principles such as timing, weight, expressiveness, and many others,</span><span data-testid="content-text"><span> to make the movements of characters or objects meaningful and emotionally rich</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">. In the context of games, animation plays a crucial role in enhancing the emotional impact of events and actions, as well as directing the player's attention where necessary.In the example below, I want to visually demonstrate how the perception of these two concepts affects the attractiveness of the result. </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Please note that the character can be any inanimate object, even a UI button.</span></span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">In the first case (the white circle), the object moves linearly, conveying no mood, and as a result, the goal of animation is not fulfilled. It is merely boring mechanical movement, nothing more. In the second case (the yellow circle), character, weight, and awareness of the object begin to emerge, and we sense a playful mood.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="LIMITED ANIMATION vs. PRIMITIVE MOTIONS">LIMITED ANIMATION vs. PRIMITIVE MOTIONS</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>An animation software should not do the animation for us</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">. Although this may seem paradoxical, a software merely speeds up the work process by creating in-between frames. One common mistake is using basic program interpolation (splines), which kills the illusion of life in characters or objects, creating a sense of boredom.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Splines </span></span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>in animation are mathematical curves used to create smooth transitions between keyframes. Automatic splines allow the software to interpolate motion, providing smoother animation.</span></span></p><p>In animation, the idea is extremely important. If the character's motivation is immediately clear to the viewer, then the effect of emotional engagement will work (the animation courtesy of Playrix)</p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">It's important to distinguish between</span><span data-testid="content-text"><span> limited animation</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, which adheres to animation principles under limited resources, and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>primitive linear movements</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> that do not incorporate these principles (as in the example with the circles above). </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Limited animation</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> involves creative choices to achieve high quality with limited means, whereas primitive movements often look unnatural and unattractive.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Limited animation</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> is a technique where the minimum possible number of frames is used to save time and resources. This implies the reuse of some elements and less detail in movements.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Every movement in animation must be justified and stem from the character's traits, emotional state, physical weight, and the laws of physics. Issues such as unnatural movement of characters caused by the automatic application of splines, or their collision with "invisible walls," indicate the need for a deeper understanding and application of animation principles.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="THE ART OF ANIMATION">THE ART OF ANIMATION</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>The primary goal of an animator</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> is not just to create the illusion of movement but to breathe life into it, making it part of a larger story. This requires not only technical skills but also </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>creative vision</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">. Understanding and applying animation principles is key to creating compelling and memorable animation that will make players return to the game again and again.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The main problem is that some colleagues in the industry </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>perceive animation as something simple and unsophisticated</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">. After all, one can always achieve quick results by setting a few keyframes, enabling frame interpolation, and the result immediately appears on the screen. But, as I've mentioned before, this only creates thoughtless movements, not animation. There's neither idea nor emotion in it. It's like a black-and-white sketch, a quick draft, but not a complete work.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">For example, in high-budget games, the main approach to creating animations is motion capture. However, it's not possible to just use data from actors and insert it into the game. The team of animators needs to do a lot of work adapting the motion capture to make the visuals brighter and more expressive. All animation principles, although based on real life, cannot exist outside animation software. A person cannot move only in arcs, make exclusively attractive movements, control spacing, and so on. In a game, we need to create a kind of theater, exaggerating our life, even for photorealistic genres.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Motion Capture</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"><span> is the process of recording the movements of real people or objects for their subsequent use in animation. The motion data is applied to 3D models of characters in video games or films, allowing for realistic animation.</span></span></p><p>Apex Legends is one of the examples of games where motion capture was used</p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="CREATIVE CONTROL">CREATIVE CONTROL</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Relying solely on program-generated movements, an animator deprives themselves of control over the animation process. Players might not be able to explain why the animation looks bad, but </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>they subconsciously feel it</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">. This is especially noticeable when it comes to the poor execution of character performance. Unclear poses and mechanical, abrupt movements create a sense of repulsion, prompting the user to close the game and find something less irritating. In a highly competitive environment, this becomes a significant problem for developers, considering that users can now install triple-A games even on mobile devices, where the level of detail is much higher. Undoubtedly, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>a big budget is not a guarantee of success</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, but the visual quality of such products often surpasses that of competitors.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Coming from the world of animated series into game development, I immediately realized the extent of </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>restrictions present in games</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">. Due to the strict technical requirements of game engines, the freedom of creativity is greatly reduced. For example, when creating visual effects, it's necessary to strictly adhere to particle count limits, which can restrain the realization of ambitious ideas.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">In the realm of mobile development, Spine is often used for 2D animations. However, game projects typically have limitations </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>on the number of bones and mesh points,</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> questioning the ability to create complex animations. Beginner animators sometimes get carried away by </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>adding an excessive number of elements</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, thinking that this will directly improve the animation. In reality, the quality and effectiveness of animated content are determined not by the number of elements but by the ability to use them wisely and appropriately to achieve the desired effect within the task at hand. </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Minimalism is the key to success!</span></span></p><p>An example of a character from Spine 2D</p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Project organization must also be impeccable; otherwise, even minor errors can lead to serious problems. For instance, in games, it's not uncommon to see characters' bones turning inside out or characters suddenly falling through objects. Nevertheless, the entire work process can be fascinating. Sometimes, the art lies in how elegantly a situation is played out, turning disadvantages into advantages. All these restrictions do not hinder the creation of smooth and harmonious movements.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="THE ROOT OF POOR QUALITY">THE ROOT OF POOR QUALITY</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>One of the primary goals of animation</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> is to convince the player of the realism of the character or situation. On mobile phones, the limited screen size does not allow for the same depth of involvement compared to a television or monitor screen. Therefore, the character's emotions </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>must be clear and expressive</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> so that the player can instantly understand the mood of the situation, whether it's the joy of victory or the disappointment of defeat.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">We create smooth and energetic movements of game elements, but definitely not abrupt ones. It's important that the character and visual effects </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>enhance the emotional impact</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> of the game situation, without confusing the user with their ambiguity. For example, when an important dramatic scene occurs. If the poses and movements in such a situation are abrupt, the player simply will not understand what happened.</span></p><p>Example of great animation: the drama of a scene is achieved through precise timing and clear poses (example from Ori and The Blind Forest)</p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Animation is an art</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> that combines visual creativity, acting skills, and complex technical approaches. An animator must simultaneously consider dozens of aspects, investing their personal emotions into the work, as well as playing a role, even if it's a living chair or a beetle. We have to control a multitude of bones and character controllers, all the while keeping an eye on the principles of animation. Therefore, I constantly repeat the importance of </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>a comprehensive approach to the workflow</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Animation is often studied in a chaotic order, leading to systematic errors. People can work in the game industry for many years, but continue to make fundamental mistakes. I understand that this problem is widespread in many fields, but in the case of animation, it can lead to the need for hours of work to correct them due to a lack of fundamental knowledge.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="MAKING MISTAKES IS NORMAL">MAKING MISTAKES IS NORMAL</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The animator's path is impossible without constant challenges and mistakes, which deserves great respect. Creating new animation is a new trial every time. However, in this article, I'm not expressing a subjective opinion.</span><span data-testid="content-text"><span> I cannot simply tell a colleague, "I don't like your work. Redo it."</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">Instead, I analyze any animations frame by frame and demonstrate through specific examples how the animation can be improved.</span><span data-testid="content-text"><span> I explain</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> in detail the principles of tracking body parts, showing exactly where sharp spacing (the distance between frames) occurs, at what moments there is a lack of body part lag, where the pose can be strengthened, balance added, and so on. Holding all this information in mind is extremely difficult, so making mistakes is normal. </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>The main thing is not to be overconfident and to be open to help from others.</span></span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">One of the most pleasant moments in game animation, when it's easy to achieve a good and fast result, is the basic idle animation of a character. If you want to successfully complete a task and lift your spirits, animate idle! Adding offsets creates a pleasant effect of motion delay (overlapping), and the calm state does not raise questions. Although keyframe offsetting provides a pleasant visual effect, it is still not full-fledged animation.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">What I most often observe is the application of the same principles to more active animations, such as lifting an object. As a result, the character either starts moving as if in zero gravity or, conversely, jerks like an old mechanical toy, violating all the laws of physics. And in my opinion, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>the root of evil lies precisely in the superficial approach to animation.</span></span></p><p>Animators often have to balance speed and quality of work (Image courtesy of Playrix)</p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="MISTAKES BRING EXPERIENCE">MISTAKES BRING EXPERIENCE</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">I have made all the mentioned mistakes repeatedly, and it is only through experience that I can speak openly about them. Even now, I make mistakes because</span><span data-testid="content-text"><span> we cannot achieve perfection in everything</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">. The most important thing is to constantly work on oneself, strive for self-improvement, continuously study new approaches, and openly accept feedback. I strongly recommend playing various game genres, watching cartoons, and maintaining communication with industry colleagues. We cannot afford to ignore market trends and new technologies.</span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Level Design Postmortem: Sixth Street (Zenless Zone Zero)]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/level-design-postmortem-sixth-street-zenless-zone-zero-</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/level-design-postmortem-sixth-street-zenless-zone-zero.939336/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/level-design-postmortem-sixth-street-zenless-zone-zero-<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">I worked for the Hoyoverse project&nbsp;</span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Zenless Zone Zero</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">&nbsp;several years ago from the first playable demo to the start of β. One of the part I made is Sixth Street, a hub world that plays a role as a start menu in the game.</span></p><p>The welcome card on my desk. Picture taken on the first day I joined the team.</p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">It is important to note that the level changed a lot for multiple reasons, making it completely different from my design. Therefore, there is no need to refer to the game; reading this article is enough. And in this article, I will focus on the methods and processes. Also, I did this about three years ago when I was less experienced and faced many challenges with frequent revisions. In this article, I will simplify and highlight only the aspects proved effective.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Determine What It Is">Determine What It Is</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">In the game world, it is a silent street where the main characters live and work, while in the game, it’s the start menu. Therefore, it should provide access to most of the game’s functions. A menu should be user-friendly, so the map should be easy to navigate, allowing players to reach functions without having to search extensively. Additionally, moving between these functions should be engaging, meaning the time spent traveling between points should be controlled.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">To compare, it’s similar to levels like the village in&nbsp;</span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Monster Hunter: Rise</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">&nbsp;and Dedsec’s den of&nbsp;</span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Watch Dogs</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">&nbsp;series. These areas are the most stylized place in their respective games. So I believe Sixth Street should also be highly stylized, both in terms of shape and structure.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Functions">Functions</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">As mentioned above, this is essentially a menu, so the first step is to gather information about the functions that should be included. This involves identifying entrances to all gameplay elements and peripherals. For example, the start of main story and where players gacha. I obtained this information from the system design team and prioritized these elements accordingly.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">There are also functions that go beyond the basic gameplay elements, such as the inherent features of the location itself. For example, characters encountered in the story may visit, so there should be natural spawn points that are easy to encounter. Additionally, maybe later, the main character holds a concert, a gathering place is necessary.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Once I had all the functions, I mapped out their relationships, considering spatial, temporal, and visibility factors. Each function was represented with a bubble diagram. Some functions have similar settings, such as a store and a bookshop, which might be placed adjacent to each other and grouped into a district.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="World building">World building</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">To create a virtual place that make sense, world building is essential. “Make sense” means not only ensuring that the functions work well within the place, but also the place fits and showcases the game’s world setting.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Reference Gathering">Reference Gathering</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The first step is reference gathering, which involves two types of references: prototypes and art references.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Prototypes</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">&nbsp;are places with similar functions to the place you want to create. These can be real world location or settings from other works of art. For Sixth Street, a prototype could be a street with single-family detached houses and stores, an old but cozy residential area near the city center, or a street with a well-known video shop.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Using prototype references is valuable even if the map is not based on a real-world location because they provide information that has been tested by time and people. Instead of copying these places, I analyzed their features and the reason behind them. For example, I considered the percentage and allocation of businesses facilities, the influence of modern urban planning theories, and the context or relationship with other parts of the city. This analysis helps ensure that the virtual place feels authentic and well-integrated into the game’s world.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">To use a reference, the first step is to identify the specific reason for using it. For example, if the reference pertains to the percentage of businesses in an area, I might need to compare it with places that have different business percentages.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">One of the most memorable features I found in the prototypes was influenced by a policy: in Japan, if someone wants to build a house, they must purchase the land. Due to Japan’s mountainous terrain, the shapes of the land parcels vary greatly, leading to diverse architectural shapes. This unique characteristic is the flavor I need for the place, so it becomes a guiding principle for the design.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Art references</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">&nbsp;are used for visualization. They include places that fit or provide inspiration for the artistic style. These references can be at various scales — props, stores, buildings, or entire districts. All are valuable for creating a cohesive and visually appealing environment.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Image Analysis">Image Analysis</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">After gathering references, the next step is image analysis, which involves examining both the overall site and its individual components.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>The image of the whole site</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">&nbsp;pertains to how the location functions within the game world. In this project, characters gather on Sixth Street for various reasons, so it serves as a node within the game world.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Next, I analyzed the&nbsp;</span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>image of each part of the site</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">. For example, characters might visit the street because of the video shop, making the video shop a node within Sixth Street.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">During the&nbsp;</span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>block-out process</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, the focus is on emphasizing these images through structure, roads, and decoration. For instance, I created a curved road around the video shop’s front facade, using the echo effect to emphasize its importance. From a decoration perspective, I used numerous lines to symbolize the televisions, connecting the video shop with other parts of the street and implying its relative position. This approach ensures that each node is distinct and effectively integrated into the overall design.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">During the design process, I encountered several problems. Here are two notable issues:</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="The Metrics Issue"><span>The Metrics Issue</span></h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Creating a seamless experience was challenging due to the game’s ultra-fast ACT mechanics, which made determining metrics a significant hurdle. (My previous work on combat metrics provided valuable experience, which I plan to discuss in future articles.)</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Initially, I used the combat 3Cs for Sixth Street, which led to problems: the spaces were large, making a corner store appear as large as a stadium. The high ceilings made it nearly impossible to create variations in elevation. Additionally, the movement cadence in Sixth Street differed from combat areas; players might stop anywhere, making it easy to notice unrealistic building sizes, breaking immersion. After discussing with team members, I decided to develop new metrics and create a dedicated 3Cs for this area.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="The Art Accident"><span>The Art Accident</span></h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The design process went smoothly, and the grey box worked perfectly in the engine for several weeks. However, when the art phase began, an unexpected issue arose: the headquarters wanted the artists to determine the map structure. This meant discarding my work and using a map designed solely by the artists.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">This was frustrating and nonsensical, but I understood that Hoyoverse values art highly, which has contributed to their success in previous projects. To move forward, compromise was necessary. This situation made me reconsider the level designer’s highest priority, which should never be compromised. Ultimately, I found ways to adapt certain areas of the map to fit my spatial relationships, ensuring the most basic functions were preserved.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://medium.com/@liuxinyan0227/level-design-postmortem-sixth-street-zenless-zone-zero-56cfde7b497e">This blog first appeared on Medium and has been published with the author's permission.</a></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Content Warning Gets Last Patch ‘For a While,’ Devs Planning New Ports]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/content-warning-gets-last-patch-for-a-while-devs-planning-new-ports/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/content-warning-gets-last-patch-%E2%80%98for-a-while-%E2%80%99-devs-planning-new-ports.939330/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/content-warning-gets-last-patch-for-a-while-devs-planning-new-ports/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>In a new <a href="https://x.com/LandfallGames/status/1817893663994794092" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">post on X</a> today, Landfall broke down the new Content Warning patch, and confirmed plans for future updates and ports for new platforms.</p>



<p>The latest patch for Content Warning is now live, introducing a range of bug fixes and quality-of-life changes. However, the devs say it will be “the last patch for a while.”</p>



<p>Landfall explains that Content Warning creatives have “prior commitments to another project they’ve been working on with another team since 2021.” The nature of that project is currently unclear, but mentioning 2021 does give fans an idea of the development timeline.</p>



<figure><div>
<blockquote data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>The new Content Warning patch is live! 🎉</p><p>It's mostly bug fixes but we've also added a sketch pad and language options for matchmaking so you can choose to play with others speaking your language 🗣️ <a href="https://t.co/eOKfHtkoqW">pic.twitter.com/eOKfHtkoqW</a></p></div>— Landfall (@LandfallGames) <a href="https://twitter.com/LandfallGames/status/1817893663994794092?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 29, 2024</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>







<p>Today’s post also finally confirms Landfall’s interest in pursuing new Content Warning ports. The devs stated they are already “looking into getting the game onto other platforms.” There is no mention of exactly which platforms players should expect.</p>



<p>Landfall added that it will update fans about those ports, as well as the future of the game, “before the end of the year.” </p>



<p>Content Warning first launched in April 2024 and quickly became an indie darling. It still maintains ‘Very Positive’ Steam reviews. </p>



<p>Just a couple of months later in June 2024, Landfall revealed that Content Warning reached <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/content-warning-sells-2-2-million-copies-console-release-possibly-coming/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">2.2 million copies sold</a>. In that same announcement, Landfall also teased the potential of console ports for Content Warning. However, it did not confirm it was actively looking into them just yet.</p>



<p>The latest Content Warning patch adds a new sketch pad, language options, additional LODs for performance, and more.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more of the latest Insider Gaming news, you can read about new claims suggesting that Mafia: Definitive edition is coming to Xbox Game Pass <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-game-pass-will-receive-mafia-definitive-edition-on-august-13-its-claimed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">in August 2024</a>, and sign up for <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/newsletter/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">our official newsletter</a>.</p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Visions of Mana ‘Battle and Elemental Vessels’ trailer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/07/visions-of-mana-battle-and-elemental-vessels-trailer</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/visions-of-mana-%E2%80%98battle-and-elemental-vessels%E2%80%99-trailer.939327/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/07/visions-of-mana-battle-and-elemental-vessels-trailer<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>Publisher and developer <a title="Companies > Square Enix [5,274 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/square-enix">Square Enix</a>, and developer <a title="Companies > Ouka Studios [8 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/netease-games/ouka-studios">Ouka Studios</a> have released a new deep dive trailer featuring the game’s <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2024/07/visions-of-mana-details-aesh-more-elemental-vessels-elemental-plots-and-lil-cactus">recently introduced</a> Elemental Vessels—“Vessel of Earth: Gnome Shovel,” “Vessel of Light: Lumina Lantern,” and “Vessel of Darkness: <a title="Companies > Shade [69 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/shade">Shade</a> Sight.” <span id="more-901785"></span></p><p>Additionally, <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2024/07/29/visions-of-mana-new-details-on-three-elemental-vessels-plus-deep-dive-video/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">PlayStation Blog</a> has published commentary from <em><a title="Games > Visions of Mana [7 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/visions-of-mana">Visions of Mana</a></em> producer Masaru Oyamada and director Ryosuke Yoshida on how the Elemental Vessels were created.</p><p>Get the full commentary below.</p><div><p><strong>■ Capturing the (Elemental) Spirit of the <em><a title="Series > Mana [10 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/series/mana">Mana</a></em> Series</strong></p><p>While Visions of Mana is intended to be a fresh start for the series, with no prior experience needed, the team still wanted to capture the series’ very distinct identity through the combat. But what defines the combat of a Mana game?</p><p><strong>Masaru Oyamada, Producer:</strong> “From the start of the series, the <em>Mana</em> games have featured multiple weapons and magic spells for the player to wield—as well as enjoyable <a title="Genres > RPG [16,451 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg">RPG</a> character growth systems. So, it was important that people feel those elements strongly in <em>Visions of Mana</em> too!”</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong>Ryosuke Yoshida, Director:</strong> “One of the most important elements of <em>Mana</em> games is that feeling that you’re interacting with the elementals (spirits that control elements like wind, fire or darkness).</p><p>“That’s at the core of the design of <em>Visions of Mana</em> and something that was really important to me. It’s such a vital part of that distinctive Mana series identity, and if the battles didn’t capture it, there would be no point to the game at all!</p><p>“In <em>Visions of Mana</em>, we focus the flow of battle around the use of the Elemental Vessels—potent weapons infused with elemental magic. These artifacts use the Elemental’s powers to manifest mysterious primal forces, such as trapping the foe in water bubbles or pinning them in the air with wind blasts. </p><p>“The effects they create can also be changed in various ways through the player’s <a title="Genres > Action [2,041 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a>s, which creates a fun dynamic where it feels like you are interacting with the Elementals as you fight.”</p><p><strong>■ Getting to the Core of Combat</strong></p><p>The combat in <em>Visions of Mana</em> is very fast and fluid. You’ll have consider lots of different aspects, from positioning to the abilities you unleash, but you’ll soon be able to take down foes in spectacular style. </p><p>There’s a lot of amazing powers to use in combat, especially when you start using Elemental Vessels, but before they could get into that, the developers had to make sure the basics of battle were rock solid.</p><p><strong>Yoshida:</strong> “When we were thinking about how to design the battle system, we didn’t just look at the combat in isolation. Instead we tried to make it something that tied closely into the overall concept that was decided for the game.</p><p>“Central mechanics like switching between three party members in battle, using ring menu and shortcut bindings are inspired by elements from past Mana games. However, I had a strong desire to put more weight on switching between different characters during combat. </p><p>“One way we did this, for example, was through the Elemental Vessels and the gameplay options they offer. You have a party of three characters and can equip each one with a different Elemental Vessel that manifests different effects. It’s possible to follow up after you use one of these effects by switching and using a different elemental power to create an even more potent compound ability. </p><p>“In this way we create motivation and benefits for the player to switch between different characters in battle.</p><p>“That said, we took care not to make it so important that switching became compulsory. To that end, we avoided creating enemies that can’t be defeated unless you jump between characters.”</p><p><strong>■ Elemental Vessels</strong></p><p>As mentioned, the Elemental Vessels are central to both combat and traversal in the game. These artifacts, bestowed on the player by the eight elementals over the course of the game, offer you new ways to get around the world, and special powers to use during battles.</p><p>This was a core focus for the game and sits at the heart of the experience. Naturally, that meant it was something the team were very careful to make as satisfying and exciting to use as possible.</p><p><strong>Yoshida:</strong> “I felt it was very important to have a consistent feel across the whole game, with a design that tied both the battles and the exploration to the core concept of interacting with the elementals as sentient beings.</p><p>“The tools that let us realize this concept practically are the Elemental Vessels.”</p><p><strong>Oyamada:</strong> “The <em>Mana</em> series has always featured eight distinct elementals with each embodying one of the core forces that shape the world. Naturally then, there would be eight vessels that house each of their powers. We came up with lots of interesting ideas for different objects to use, but ultimately aimed to create designs that would best capture the interesting aspects of each elemental.”</p><p><strong>■ Vessel of Earth: Gnome Shovel</strong></p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/Visions-of-Mana-PV_07-29-24_002.jpg"></a></figure><p>In the video, we show three Elemental Vessels: Earth, Light, and Darkness. Producer Oyamada and director Yoshida offered some insight into the creation of these vessels—and the associated abilities.</p><p><strong>Oyamada:</strong> “The concept for the Vessel of Earth was ‘defense.’ When used, it surrounds the player in a solid, rocky shield that protects against attacks.”</p><p><strong>Yoshida:</strong> “It took a little trial and error to get right though! Originally, it created a gigantic wall of earth which would protect the player from attacks. Unfortunately, we found that summoning a huge barrier into the battle area obstructed the player’s vision. Plus, enemies attack from multiple angles anyway, so it didn’t really protect them at all. So, we switched the current idea, where the vessel creates a dome-like shield out of semi-transparent rocks!”</p><p><strong>■ Vessel of Light: Lumina Lantern</strong></p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/Visions-of-Mana-PV_07-29-24_003.jpg"></a></figure><p><strong>Oyamada:</strong> “The concept behind this one was ‘reflection.’ Using the Lumina Lantern, the player can link enemies together with rays of light, reflecting the damage from one enemy to another!”</p><p><strong>■ Vessel of Darkness: Shade Sight</strong></p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/Visions-of-Mana-PV_07-29-24_004.jpg"></a></figure><p><strong>Oyamada:</strong> “The idea behind this vessel was ‘gravitation’. When the elemental is unleashed, it creates a black hole, which draws in enemies.”</p><p><strong>Yoshida:</strong> “Our battle director innocently brought up that he was curious about what would happen if there was a lake or river close by and suggested the water should be sucked up along with the enemies. However, there aren’t many battle areas which are next to lakes in the first place, and if we were going to do this, it would have created a heap of problems, such as when would the water come back!</p><p>“So, understandably, we soon abandoned that particular idea (laughs).”</p><p><strong>■ Class Acts</strong></p><p>Equipping an Elemental Vessel to a character changes their class, giving them new abilities, weapons, and even costumes. Every vessel can be equipped to every character, which makes for a lot of variety regarding how you customize your party.</p><p><strong>Yoshida:</strong> “We came up with the specifications for the different weapons and classes alongside those of the Elemental Vessels. </p><p>“We did so because we knew from the start that future balancing would be needed to ensure that none of weapons and actions paired with the vessels would break the system.</p><p>“This meant that by the time we reached the prototyping stage, all the vessel’s basic effects were already decided and we could focus on the final balancing between the classes. Not only that, but we could also make up for any areas where a class was less distinct by adding unique abilities and altering their parameters.”</p><p><strong>Oyamada:</strong> “Once we decided that there would be eight different elements, we designed ideas for each character’s classes based on combinations of the different Elemental Vessel effects and weapon types.</p><p>“Of course, these still went through changes over development. For example, we originally went with more of a succubus-style appearance for Careena’s darkness-based class, but our character designer Haccan proposed a great idea which swayed us in a different direction. I think this turned out great and captures her cheery personality too!”</p></div><p>Watch the trailer below.</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SAG-AFTRA Strike Won’t Impact GTA 6 or Any Other Game That Started Development Before September 2023]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/sag-aftra-strike-wont-impact-gta-6-or-any-other-game-that-started-development-before-september-2023/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sag-aftra-strike-won%E2%80%99t-impact-gta-6-or-any-other-game-that-started-development-before-september-2023.939324/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/sag-aftra-strike-wont-impact-gta-6-or-any-other-game-that-started-development-before-september-2023/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The newly announced <a href="https://wccftech.com/sag-aftra-videogame-strike-now-in-effect-due-to-ai-concerns-potentially-leading-to-game-delays/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SAG-AFTRA</a> strike won't impact GTA 6, or indeed any other game that started development before September 2023. That's due to a prior stipulation, although SAG-AFTRA isn't happy about this, as Chief Contracts Officer Ray Rodriguez <a href="https://aftermath.site/sag-aftra-video-game-voice-actor-strike-grand-theft-auto-6" target="_blank" rel="noopener">explained</a> to Aftermath:</p>
<p><em>We're obviously not happy about that. That language was bargained into one of the legacy Interactive Media Agreements before the merger of SAG and AFTRA. It's language that the merged union basically inherited, that I think is insane. But it’s there.</em></p>
<p><em>We do believe that there are certain titles that we can challenge, and we are preparing ourselves to bring a challenge with respect to the application of this language with respect to some of the titles. So we are doing our best to wage the strike as effectively and as strongly as we can – even in spite of that language being there.</em></p>
<p>In theory, the exemption also applies to live service games since all those have obviously started development way before September 2023. However, SAG-AFTRA isn't too keen on letting this slide. Rodriguez added:</p>
<p><em>If you apply this language that we're talking about to live-service games, they become contracts of unlimited duration, and there is a law that a contract of unlimited duration can be terminated on reasonable notice. So that's what we've done: We have provided reasonable notice that we are terminating our contract with respect to those live-service games.</em></p>
<p>SAG-AFTRA voted on the strike mainly because it couldn't reach an agreement to protect its workers from the dangers of AI utilization in the industry. We'll keep you updated if there's any news on the ongoing strike.</p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Dark Pictures Anthology Curator Tony Pankhurst Has Died]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-dark-pictures-anthology-curator-tony-pankhurst-has-died/1100-6525365/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-dark-pictures-anthology-curator-tony-pankhurst-has-died.939321/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-dark-pictures-anthology-curator-tony-pankhurst-has-died/1100-6525365/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6525365">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Supermassive Games has revealed that Tony Pankhurst has passed away recently at the age of 67. He was the face of the Curator in The Dark Pictures Anthology.</p><p>In a post on Twitter, Supermassive Games said, "We are all saddened to hear of Tony Pankhurst's passing. He was the face of The Curator, and we loved working with him." On a <a href="https://tonypankhurst.muchloved.com/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">tribute page</a>, his family stated that he passed away on May 9, and shared that he was an avid Briton Hove Albion FC football fan. The family is also open to donations to "Hospice in the Weald," to which Supermassive Games itself donated £200.</p><div data-embed-type="tweet" data-src="https://x.com/SuperMGames/status/1817871260073841096" data-has-image="true"><blockquote data-conversation="none" data-mce-disable-toolbar="true"><p dir="ltr">We are all saddened to hear of Tony Pankhurst's passing. He was the face of The Curator, and we loved working with him. 🤍 <a href="https://t.co/ZZQbeViE8S" rel="nofollow ">pic.twitter.com/ZZQbeViE8S</a></p>  — Supermassive Games (@SuperMGames) <a href="https://twitter.com/SuperMGames/status/1817871260073841096?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 29, 2024</a></blockquote>              </div><p>In The Dark Pictures Anthology, The Curator is the omniscient narrator in each of the games, often speaking to players about and reacting to what choices they made during their playthroughs. While Pankhurst's likeness was used for The Curator, the character's voice and motion-capture credits belong to actor Pip Torrens. Pankhurst portrayed The Curator in the live-action trailer for the series' <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/the-dark-pictures-anthology-house-of-ashes/" data-ref-id="5000-521489">House of Ashes</a> entry.</p><p>The Dark Pictures Anthology is a series of horror-adventure games developed by Supermassive Games and published by Bandai Namco. The series has had four games so far, making up its first season. The second season starts with <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-next-dark-pictures-anthology-directive-8020-is-sci-fi-horror/1100-6509242/" data-ref-id="1100-6509242">Directive 8020</a>, which was revealed back in 2022, but no release date has been announced for it yet.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/115776530127739146123?rel=author">George Yang</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Zula Hendricks revealed as the protagonist for Alien: Rogue Incursion]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/07/29/zula-hendricks-revealed-as-the-protagonist-for-alien-rogue-incursion/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/zula-hendricks-revealed-as-the-protagonist-for-alien-rogue-incursion.939306/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/07/29/zula-hendricks-revealed-as-the-protagonist-for-alien-rogue-incursion/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>We now know who we will be playing as in <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/alien-rogue-incursion/">Alien: Rogue Incursion,</a>&nbsp; Zula Hendricks. She is described as “an unbreakable ex-Colonial Marine, on a dangerous mission that brings her to the uncharted planet Purdan.”</p>
<p>”&nbsp;With her sentient AI companion, Davis-01, Zula must fight her way to the heart of the infested Gemini Exoplanet Solutions black-site facility.&nbsp;There she will need to survive deadly attacks from the most cunning Xenomorphs ever encountered and discover new horrors and threats that once unleashed could spell the end for humankind.”</p>
<p><iframe title="Alien: Rogue Incursion | Zula Hendricks Reveal Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/49WAFl7u6gA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>The Alien game project has been in development for the last two years at VR specialists Survios. The company burst on the scene with the dawn of VR with <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2017/11/30/raw-data-review/">Raw Data</a> in 2016, before bringing the rapid releases of <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2018/02/22/sprint-vector-review/">Sprint Vector</a>, Electonauts and <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2023/02/21/creed-rise-to-glory-psvr-2-release-date-april/">Creed: Rise to Glory</a> through 2018.</p>
<p>There’s a rich pedigree for Survios and VR, in other words, but really the main reason why people will be excited for Alien: Rogue Incursion is because of 2014 game Alien: Isolation. The celebrated horror game was once shown as being playable in VR prior to release, and fans have long wanted to see a VR version of the game released – hopes that will sadly never be realised at this point. Hopefully Rogue Incursion can be the VR horror surrogate that we need.</p>

<p>“Our team at Survios are huge fans of Alien and have been building Alien: Rogue Incursion for a long time, honing our ability to pair the most technically advanced, immersive, and engaging VR experiences with best-in-class franchises,” says TQ Jefferson, Chief Product Officer at Survios. “This fully original story embraces all our favorite elements from 45 years of Alien, from kinetic action and heart-pounding exploration to our terrifyingly resourceful Xenomorphs that will truly make your skin crawl. We can’t wait for fans to get their hands on it this holiday season.”</p>
<p>Alien: Rogue Incursion will launch on&nbsp; PSVR 2, Meta Quest 3 and Steam VR this&nbsp;Holiday 2024.</p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=49WAFl7u6gA">YouTube</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Overwatch 2 may get 6v6 again as Blizzard try to bring back the "chaotic, over-the-top" variety of the first game]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/overwatch-2-may-get-6v6-again-as-blizzard-try-to-bring-back-the-chaotic-over-the-top-variety-of-the-first-game</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/overwatch-2-may-get-6v6-again-as-blizzard-try-to-bring-back-the-chaotic-over-the-top-variety-of-the-first-game.939303/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/overwatch-2-may-get-6v6-again-as-blizzard-try-to-bring-back-the-chaotic-over-the-top-variety-of-the-first-game<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
  

        <p>But headcounts are only part of the picture</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/overwatch6v6_m7fNr8A.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Microsoft / esportsedition</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p><a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/overwatch-2">Overwatch 2</a> director Aaron Keller has posted a lengthy blog on Steam about the transition from 6v6 player matches in the first Overwatch to 5v5 in the poorly received free-to-play sequel. It's a juicy read for armchair designers and lapsed Overwatchers like myself, packing in analysis of class roles and the shift from the free choice of heroes to single hero picks and enforced team compositions.</p>
<p>In broad strokes, Keller summarises how the Overwatch experience has drifted away from "player freedom and creativity in order to create a more balanced, consistent and competitive experience for players". It's possible, however, that Overwatch 2 will swing back in the other direction, as Blizzard are now "exploring how we can test different forms of 6v6 in the game to gauge the results", with a view to restoring some of the joyful chaos that saw entire teams of Reinhardts charging the objective in formation.</p><!--more-->
<p>"The community has, juuuust once or twice, suggested a test," Keller <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/2357570/view/4352250327659121671?l=english">writes in the post</a>. "Why not put various forms of 6v6 in the game in order to gauge the results? We agree, and based on your feedback, we're exploring how we can test different forms of 6v6 in the game to gauge the results."</p>
<p>Don't expect those tests to begin anytime soon, however, as there are a number of obstacles. "The first, and honestly largest, reason is the need to do this in a way that allows the game to have optimized technical performance (I'm referring to framerate and memory constraints) with 12 players in a match," Keller goes on.</p>
<p>He notes that Overwatch 2 has seen several upgrades and additions that impact performance, such as HUD outlines for allied heroes and fancier map fixtures. "In a 6v6 setting, these upgrades can have significant impacts for our players, causing the game to underperform on older systems. Overwatch is a fast-paced game, and maintaining a game that runs smoothly across all our platforms is important for the player's experience."</p>
<p>As such, "while a limited time test could arrive sooner, the team is still investigating exactly how long it would take to permanently increase performance across the game," Keller writes. "This would be a large effort that would most likely take at least several seasons to accomplish."</p>
<p>The bigger issue, however, may be the effect of a return to 6v6 on the game's multiplayer queue times. A fair chunk of Keller's blog is devoted to explaining how the combination of role queues and the original 12-a-side format led to delays finding a match. Blizzard were not able to really address this problem in the first game, Keller comments, hence shrinking the headcount in Overwatch 2. He's not 100% confident they'll fare better second time around.</p>
<p>"Another issue, and one that still gives me anxiety about opening this Pandora's Box, is what to do with queue times if enough players prefer 6v6 to keep some form of it around," the post goes on. "The team was not able to solve this issue previously. While we have some ideas now, there's no guarantee that they will work. </p>
<p>"Is there a world where people are willing to live with long queue times to play this format? Maybe, but that's a pretty risky move to make. We also have tens of millions of new players that have only played 5v5. We want to be openly mindful not to frustrate those who like the game as it is today."</p>
<p>In the event that Blizzard do host some 6v6 tests, these would likely run for a few weeks, with the results being compared against regular Overwatch 2 modes. "We would reflect carefully on the learnings from whatever test we run and explore how to best give players what's being asked for," Keller says. "Whether that's a world of 5v5, 6v6 or even both, is for future us to figure out."</p>
<p>Keller is upfront about the fact that the evolution of Overwatch into Overwatch 2 was a trade-off that has alienated much of the first game's audience. "The game started its life with six players on each team," he writes. "I discussed why we moved away from 6v6, but that doesn't mean it's without any merit. There were moments and madness that could happen with twelve players in a match that just don't quite coalesce when there are ten."</p>
<p>The occasional feeling of overwhelm was "part of the charm", Keller adds. "There are big moments in Overwatch 2, but they don't quite have that same chaotic, over-the-top feeling to them." More specifically, having two tanks in the mix per side "had a stabilizing effect on gameplay" whereby "teams would fold a bit slower than they do now".</p>
<p>The sequel is a more focussed competitive experience and perhaps, the superior esport, but it doesn't have the same sense of abandon, Keller acknowledges. "When you look at the changes to Overwatch since its inception, it's clear that many of those have reduced some of the variety within an Overwatch match," the post concedes. "We get feedback from some players that Overwatch can feel "the same" from game to game."</p>
<p>"While much of this gets attributed to 5v5, we feel that there is more at play here. Besides running experiments with 6v6, we'd like to run some that re-examine the ways we tried solving previous problems, specifically with the goal of bringing some of the freedom back to an Overwatch match without the severity of issues that accompanied it."</p>
<p>The on-going dislike for Overwatch 2 (it still has a Mostly Negative user review consensus on Steam) is about more than 5v5, of course. <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/overwatch-2s-overwhelmingly-negative-steam-launch-brings-years-of-frustration-to-the-boil">Take your pick</a>: the first game no longer being available, making the sequel a forced replacement; the retiring of certain grand plans for story modes; nickel-and-diming players with the battle pass. Still, there's a great hero sandbox in there somewhere, and the prospect of a tentative move back toward the first game's looser, wildcard ethos is encouraging.</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bethesda trademark points to future Starfield expansion, fans believe]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/bethesda-trademark-points-to-future-starfield-expansion-fans-believe</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/bethesda-trademark-points-to-future-starfield-expansion-fans-believe.939297/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/bethesda-trademark-points-to-future-starfield-expansion-fans-believe<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>



            <p><a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/starfield-main-story-walkthrough-9352">Starfield</a> fans believe a trademark for "Starborn" registered by Bethesda parent company Zenimax earlier this month points to the game's currently unrevealed second expansion, likely due in 2025.</p>
<p>Bethesda's space RPG released last year, and is set to launch its first expansion Shattered Space in the coming months. In conversation with YouTuber MrMattyPlays back in June, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/bethesdas-todd-howard-confirms-at-least-one-more-starfield-expansion-after-shattered-space">Bethesda's Todd Howard confirmed there would be at least one more expansion to come after Shattered Space</a>, stating the studio was already "planning for the one after this".</p>
<p>It now appears that this 'planning' has made further progress, thanks to that aforementioned trademark. As spotted by <a href="https://x.com/bogorad222">Timur222</a> on social media platform X, Bethesda has filed a trademark for something known as <a href="https://trademarks.justia.com/986/45/starborn-98645285.html">Starborn</a>. What is a Starborn? We'll explain below - so <strong>beware of small Starfield spoilers</strong>.</p>
<figure>
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<figcaption>Starfield: Shattered Space - Official Trailer - Xbox Games Showcase 2024<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=93dtPInrIMg" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>A mysterious group known as Starborn feature in the base game. They have passed through a portal known as the Unity and travelled between universes. Starborn only reveal themselves to the heroic Constellation group after enough of the game's Artefacts have been collected.</p>
<p>Purely speculatively for now, this trademark suggests that Starfield's next DLC after Shattered Space could focus on this group, perhaps expanding on the group's origins and their abilities to visit different universes.</p>
<p>We shall have to wait and see.</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/image-(251).png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>JUSTIA trademarks/Eurogamer</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>As for more imminent DLC, we got our <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/first-look-at-starfields-shattered-space-expansion-but-still-no-release-date">first proper look at Starfield's Shattered Space expansion</a> earlier this year, when Bethesda released a space-horror flavoured trailer during Xbox's summer showcase. You can check it out in the video above.</p>
<p>Shattered Space will offer a fresh mystery involving the snake-loving House Va'ruun, at some point later in 2024.</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Assassin’s Creed Reddit Says Ubisoft Statement ‘Exacerbated’ the ‘Tedious Discussion’ About Shadows, Warns Users Against Disputing Yasuke's Status as ]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/assassins-creed-reddit-says-ubisoft-statement-exacerbated-the-tedious-discussion-about-shadows-warns-users-against-disputing-yasukes-status-as-samurai</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/assassin%E2%80%99s-creed-reddit-says-ubisoft-statement-%E2%80%98exacerbated%E2%80%99-the-%E2%80%98tedious-discussion%E2%80%99-about-shadows-warns-users-against-disputing-yasukes-status-as.939291/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/assassins-creed-reddit-says-ubisoft-statement-exacerbated-the-tedious-discussion-about-shadows-warns-users-against-disputing-yasukes-status-as-samurai<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>The main Assassin’s Creed subreddit has warned users against debating the historical accuracy of the upcoming video game <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/assassins-creed-shadows">Assassin’s Creed Shadows</a>, specifically protagonist Yasuke's status as a samurai.</p><p>Moderators of r/assassinscreed, which has over 700,000 members, locked down a <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/assassinscreed/comments/1ee83ow/there_is_no_debate_yasuke_was_a_samurai_if_you/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">post</a> titled “There is no ‘debate’ - Yasuke was a Samurai. If you disagree, you can do that somewhere else,” due to “brigading” in the comments.</p><p>The post followed a <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/assassins-creed-shadows-team-issues-apology-to-japanese-fans-for-marketing-that-has-caused-concern">controversial statement</a> issued by Ubisoft to Japanese fans in which the company apologized for <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ubisoft-apology-for-using-historical-re-enactment-group-flag-in-assassins-creed-shadows-not-enough-group-says">promotion materials</a> it said “have caused concern” among the community.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3>Assassin's Creed Shadows Concept Art With Historical Re-Enactment Group's Flag</h3></div></output><p>The four-page message, posted in both English and Japanese, explained that Assassin’s Creed Shadows is not intended to be a factual representation of history. Instead, it is described as “a compelling, historical fiction set in Feudal Japan. Ubisoft added that it hoped Shadows would “spark curiosity” in players who then research the historical period the game is inspired by.</p><p>In addition to the apology regarding the marketing materials, the message also discussed Yasuke, one of Shadows’ two protagonists: “While Yasuke is depicted as a samurai in Assassin’s Creed Shadows, we acknowledge that this is a matter of debate and discussion. We have woven this carefully into our narrative and with our other lead character, the Japanese shinobi Naoe, who is equally important in the game, our dual protagonists provide players with different gameplay styles.”</p><p>While Yasuke has often been presented as a samurai in popular media, both in Japan and beyond, his depiction in Shadows has given rise to debate regarding the historical truth. The argument has lived side-by-side with criticism over Ubisoft’s decision to feature a Black man as a lead protagonist in a Japan-set Assassin’s Creed game – <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ubisoft-ceo-condemns-hateful-acts-against-developers-following-ac-shadows-backlash"><u>a backlash Ubisoft CEO Yves Guillemot alluded to while condemning “malicious and personal online attacks.”</u></a></p><p>The statement noted that the Assassin’s Creed series has always taken “creative license and incorporated fantasy elements” into its historically-inspired settings. “The representation of Yasuke in our game is an illustration of this. His unique and mysterious life made him an ideal candidate to tell an Assassin’s Creed story with the setting of Feudal Japan as a backdrop.”</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3>Assassin's Creed Shadows - Art and Concept Art</h3></div></output><p>The mod team behind r/assassinscreed said Ubisoft’s statement “exacerbated” what it called “this tedious discussion that has been endlessly talked to death,” and gave users of the subreddit a “final reminder” of what the Assassin’s Creed franchise entails.</p><p>Here’s the r/assassinscreed mod team’s statement in full:</p><blockquote>With the reveal of Assassin's Creed Shadows, there has been an influx of certain individuals spilling into various communities online such as this subreddit and raising arguments about "historical accuracy". As we are all exhausted of this tedious discussion that has been endlessly talked to death, not to mention exacerbated by a recent official statement from Ubisoft, we would like to give a final reminder to those participating in these debates as to what exactly this franchise entails, and why there was never any point to these discussions to begin with outside of thinly veiling bad faith intent.</blockquote><blockquote>Assassin's Creed is historical fiction. This means that while certain locations, events and figures may be based on reality, and can even have a slight focus on accuracy, their depictions are largely exaggerated for the sake of a more enjoyable video game. While all of our player protagonists have been fictional to date, the introduction of Yasuke has given some people the false impression that the above rule does not apply. It still does. Yasuke, who is a samurai as confirmed by multiple reputable historians around the world including from Japan, may not have held as large as a role in the real world as he does in Shadows. This is okay. It is a video game. You are not meant to use Assassin's Creed as a sourcebook for actual historical knowledge - it is meant to compel you to do your own external research after immersing you in a glimpse of authenticity.</blockquote><blockquote>We are not here in this community to debate on historical record. Most of us understand as fans that while these games provide us a great look into what historical settings could have felt like and have fun comparing them to actual record, we do not chase accuracy within this franchise and primarily play for other reasons. So if you are specifically here to leave comments about your displeasure about Yasuke's inclusion or various other inaccurate details that have been pointed out in Ubisoft's depiction of Feudal Japan, it is time to understand that this is not the place for this discussion and it never will be. Feel free to take your displeasures elsewhere, away from this franchise and its communities.</blockquote><blockquote>Any further comments attempting to dispute Yasuke's societal status, disparage his inclusion in game or containing statements bordering on concern trolling for historical accuracy will be swiftly removed and met with a ban.</blockquote><p>The mod team also provided a list of links to reddit posts explaining how the Assassin’s Creed series has handled historical accuracy in previous games.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>The post outlines the subreddit’s firm stance on Shadows, and is a clear attempt to draw a line under what has become one of the big talking points around the game. As <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/assassins-creed-reddit-takes-firm-stance-on-yasuke-debate-says-ubisoft-exacerbated-issue-with-statement" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Eurogamer</a> pointed out, this debate has spilled over into the real-world, with a fringe Japanese politician requesting the Japanese government comment on the matter. But so far there has been no meaningful result.</p><p>Assassin’s Creed Shadows launches November 12, 2024 for those buying the <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/assassins-creed-shadows-release-date-collectors-edition"><u>Gold, Ultimate, Deluxe Editions</u></a>, or Collector's Editions, while the Standard Edition is available on November 15, 2024. You can learn more about its goals in <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/assassins-creed-shadows-inside-ubisofts-ambitious-open-world-japan"><u>our extensive interview with the development team</u></a>, as well as our list of <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/assassins-creed-shadows-50-details-you-need-to-know"><u>50 key details</u></a>.</p><p><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Yes, you can run Doom in Balatro]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/yes-you-can-run-doom-in-balatro</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/yes-you-can-run-doom-in-balatro.939282/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/yes-you-can-run-doom-in-balatro<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>"Literally nobody asked for it, but here it is."</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Screenshot-2024-07-29-at-12.23.44-(2).png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>u/UwUDev / localthunk</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>Balatro is the latest thing that can seemingly run the seminal 90s shooter Doom.</p>
<p>"Literally nobody asked for it, but here it is: Doom on Balatro," announced u/UwUDev on reddit, appending a video that proves they've somehow embedded Zoom into the poker game's Joker collection screen.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="6 Things We Liked About DOOM Eternal And 2 Things We Didn’t - Easter Eggs, Glory Kills and More!" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/76_0aUOr1B8?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>6 Things We Liked About DOOM Eternal And 2 Things We Didn’t - Easter Eggs, Glory Kills and More!</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/76_0aUOr1B8?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/76_0aUOr1B8?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Eurogamer plays Doom Eternal - at slightly better resolution.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=76_0aUOr1B8" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>"Honestly, I didn't think anyone would care. I'd just done it for fun/challenge, but since the community seems to like it, I'm planning something even more impressive and stupid," UwuDev said.</p>
<p>"It's super laggy and I often have big lag spikes but it works. I'll see later if I can optimise it because it's really unplayable," they acknowledged later in the thread.</p>
<blockquote data-embed-height="546"><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/balatro/comments/1eby5y7/literally_nobody_asked_for_it_but_here_it_is_doom/">Literally nobody asked for it, but here it is, Doom on balatro</a><br> by<a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/UwUDev/">u/UwUDev</a> in<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/balatro/">balatro</a></blockquote><p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span></p><p>Even Balatro creator localthunk seems impressed by the feat:</p> <div>

<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>It's a long-running joke that iconic 90s shooter Doom is playable on almost anything, including Fortrnite, Team Fortress 2, a pregnancy test, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/doom-is-now-playable-on-a-tractor">a tractor</a>, and a piece of <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/a-piece-of-lego-can-now-play-doom">Lego</a>.</p>
<p>ICYMI, Balatro is getting a physical edition. Localthunk confirmed last month that fans will soon be able to <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/balatro-is-getting-a-physical-edition-on-playstation-switch-and-xbox-consoles">pick up a physical copy of the game on PS5, Switch, Xbox Series X/S, and last-gen consoles</a>.</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Doctor Who, Star Trek crossover officially revealed]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/star-trek-doctor-who-crossover-officially-revealed</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/doctor-who-star-trek-crossover-officially-revealed.939279/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/star-trek-doctor-who-crossover-officially-revealed<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/ZqUaoB5LeNNTxinG_XLOB_GAMES_DWXST-BAGEY-DIRECTIVE_KEY.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>BBC / Paramount</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
Doctor Who and Star Trek are officially crossing over, with David Tennant's iconic Tenth Doctor and his future wife River Song meeting characters from the animated Star Trek: Lower Decks series. 
</p>
<p>
The crossover will take place as a limited-time event beginning 1st August in two mobile games: <a href="https://bit.ly/STLD">Star Trek: Lower Decks - The Badgey Directive</a> and <a href="https://bit.ly/46OOf53">Doctor Who: Lost in Time</a>.
</p>
<p>
Events in both games will show different perspectives of the same wibbly-wobbly space-time macguffin, with Ten onboard Lower Deck's USS Cerritos and River Song joined by crewmembers Lieutenant Brad Boimler and Ensign Beckett Mariner.
</p>
<p>
Both mobile games are developed by the same studio, Eastside Games, which specialises in making licensed spin-offs for major TV series brands. Each offers their own selection of new stories for their respective franchises, unlocked via collecting a large cast of characters.
</p>
<p>
This is, as far as I can recall, the first time Star Trek and Doctor Who have joined forces in the world of video games - though the two long-running sci-fi series have nodded to each other multiple times over the years. 
</p>
<p>
The latest season of Doctor Who included Ncuti Gatwa's Fifteenth Doctor making reference to visiting Star Trek, the latest of various references in each show to the other. Most notably, Matt Smith's Eleventh Doctor teamed up with the legendary Jean-Luc Picard in an eight-issue comic book series back in 2012, which saw the pair fighting a combined threat of the Cybermen and the Borg. 
</p>
<p>
Behind the scenes, showrunner Russell T Davies has said he's attempted to get an actual TV crossover episode made where the Doctor visits the Enterprise - though, so far, it's yet to happen. Perhaps this could be used to gauge interest?
</p>





        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NVIDIA DLSS 3.7 New Comparison Highlights How 4K Performance Mode is Superior to Native 1440p, Quality Mode]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/nvidia-dlss-3-7-new-comparison-highlights-how-4k-performance-mode-is-superior-to-native-1440p-quality-mode/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nvidia-dlss-3-7-new-comparison-highlights-how-4k-performance-mode-is-superior-to-native-1440p-quality-mode.939276/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/nvidia-dlss-3-7-new-comparison-highlights-how-4k-performance-mode-is-superior-to-native-1440p-quality-mode/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The NVIDIA DLSS upscaler continues to be the best upscaler on the market, achieving impressive results that look considerably better than native resolutions.</p>
<p>A new comparison video based on the 3.7 version of the upscaler put together by <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@MxBenchmarkPC">MxBenchmarkPC</a> puts native 1440p, 1440p in Quality mode and 4K in Performance mode side by side in five games - Cyberpunk 2077, Horizon Forbidden West, The Witcher 3 Next-Gen, Senua's Saga: Hellblade 2 and Ghost of Tsushima, highlighting how, in terms of visual quality, 4K with DLSS Performance mode is clearly better than native 1440p and 1440p in Quality Mode in every game. The performance hit, in some cases, such as in Cyberpunk 2077, may not make 4K with Performance mode worth it for some, but generally, it is always the better choice, especially if the game also supports Frame Generation.</p>
<p><iframe title="1440p DLSS 3.7 Quality vs 4K DLSS 3.7 Performance - Which is Better? | Test in 5 Games | RTX 4080" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/WSIg89lQZ04?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>As time passes, NVIDIA DLSS continues to be adopted by a variety of different games. Among the <a href="https://wccftech.com/nvidia-dlss-supported-latest-games-include-kunitsu-gami-path-of-the-goddess-marvel-rivals-beta-final-fantasy-xiv-online/">new games</a> supporting the upscaler are <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/kunitsu-gami-path-of-the-goddess-night-full-terrors/">Kunitsu-Gami: Path of the Goddess</a>, which also supports Frame Generation, the Bladekisser DLC for Trepang 2, and Final Fantasy XIV Online, which received NVIDIA DLSS 2 support with the update that introduced support for the latest expansion, <a href="https://wccftech.com/final-fantasy-xiv-dawntrail-benchmark-test-previews-nvidia-dlss-amd-fsr-additions-and-graphics-improvements/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Dawntrail</a>.</p>
<p>You can learn more about NVIDIA DLSS and supported games by going <a href="https://www.nvidia.com/en-us/geforce/news/nvidia-rtx-games-engines-apps/">here.</a></p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sonic x Shadow Generations Price and Game Size Disclosed]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/sonic-x-shadow-generations-price-and-game-size-disclosed/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sonic-x-shadow-generations-price-and-game-size-disclosed.939273/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/sonic-x-shadow-generations-price-and-game-size-disclosed/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>Nintendo’s Sonic X Shadow Generations store page has just gone live, and we now know the price, game size, and other details about the upcoming title. Additionally, pre-orders are live, allowing you to pre-load the game and play it as soon as it is released. Sonic X Shadow Generation arrives for Nintendo Switch on October 25, 2024. &nbsp;</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>Sonic x Shadow Generations prices vary according to the edition you purchase. The Standard Digital edition has been priced at $49.99, and the Digital Deluxe edition will cost the player $59.99. If you scroll down to the very end of the <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/us/store/products/sonic-x-shadow-generations-digital-deluxe-edition-switch/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">store listing</a>, you will find the game file size, ESRB rating and other details for the game. The file size also varies according to the edition, with the standard edition at 13.1GB and the Digital Deluxe edition at 14.1 GB. The ESRB rating is Everyone10+, and players can play the title on TV, tabletop, and handheld modes.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Sonic x Shadow Standard Edition consists of only the base game, whereas the Digital Deluxe edition brings players some bonus content. In addition to the base game, players will receive additional iconic music tracks from previous Sonic and Shadow games, a Terios skin based on Shadow’s original concept, behind-the-scenes art, an extra level, Shadow Skin, which is releasing Holiday 2024, Skill points for Sonic Generations, an extra BGM pack, and a Digital Deluxe Season Pass.&nbsp;</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="SONIC X SHADOW GENERATIONS - Summer Game Fest Trailer" width="1200" height="675" src="about:blank" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6E36fOpk-Yg?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>In other news, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/sega-teasing-another-character-for-sonic-x-shadow-generations/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">SEGA teased</a> another character introduction for Sonic X Shadow Generations earlier this month. Also, the Sonic Jam Legacy skin was<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/sonic-jam-legacy-skin-revealed-for-sonic-x-shadow-generations/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> recently revealed </a>for the upcoming game. What are your views on Sonic X Shadow Generations’ price and game size? Let us know in the comments. &nbsp;</p>



<hr>



<p>For more of the latest Insider Gaming news, read about <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-game-pass-will-receive-mafia-definitive-edition-on-august-13-its-claimed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Xbox Game Pass receiving Mafia: Definitive Edition on August 13,</a> and sign up for&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/newsletter/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">our official newsletter</a>.</p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Castle Crashers is getting new DLC 16 years after it first released]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/castle-crashers-is-getting-new-dlc-16-years-after-it-first-released</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/castle-crashers-is-getting-new-dlc-16-years-after-it-first-released.939264/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/castle-crashers-is-getting-new-dlc-16-years-after-it-first-released<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>"Didn't have a Castle Crashers DLC in my 2024 bingo card."</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Screenshot-2024-07-29-at-11.34.36-(2).png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>The Behemoth</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>12 years after it first arrived on Steam, and 16 years after it debuted on Xbox Live Arcade, Castle Crashers is getting new DLC.</p>
<p>Premium DLC Painter Boss Paradise not only includes new player and weapon artwork for all official characters and new character Paint Junior, but it also adds Steam workshop functionality, so players can create and share their own skins "with the world".</p>
<p>Although Castle Crashers debuted on Xbox and is still available on Sony consoles and Nintendo Switch, the DLC is only coming to Steam.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Castle Crashers DLC Announcement: Painter Boss Paradise" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/LjS40-isk0s?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Castle Crashers DLC Announcement: Painter Boss Paradise</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/LjS40-isk0s?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/LjS40-isk0s?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>  Castle Crashers DLC Announcement: Painter Boss Paradise.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LjS40-isk0s" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>"We used to be enemies. We used to destroy the world around us. Now, we create! Introducing… the Castle Crashers Painter Boss Paradise DLC, coming soon to Steam!" the team at The Bethemoth announced, <a href="https://x.com/thebehemoth/status/1816937250703433989">confirming</a> players can toggle the new lick of paint "on or off".</p> <div>

<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>"Didn't have a Castle Crashers DLC in my 2024 bingo card," said one happy fan in the YouTube comments.</p>
<p>There's no price tag or firm release date yet – "coming soon" is all Behemoth will commit to for now – but, as always, we'll keep you posted.</p>
<p>"Much like The Behemoth's last Live Arcade effort, Alien Hominid HD, this is a resolutely old-fashioned side-scroller," Dan Whitehead wrote in <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/castle-crashers-review">Eurogamer's Castle Crashers review</a>, waaaaay back in 2008.</p>
<p>"Where it differs is in a much less brutal learning curve, a vastly increased amount of peripheral stuff to play with and a generally more rounded gaming experience."</p>
<p>If you're a fan of Xbox 360 games, don't forget that Microsoft is set to <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/xbox-360-digital-store-will-close-next-july">close its Xbox 360 digital store later today (29th July)</a>. That means you have <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/psa-this-weekend-is-your-last-chance-to-buy-from-the-xbox-360-online-marketplace">just a few hours left</a> to make the most of the final discounts on some of the best Xbox 360 games of the generation.</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mortal Kombat 1: Khaos Reigns DLC announced; Animalities, T-1000, Conan, and Scream's Ghostface all on the way]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/mortal-kombat-1-khaos-reigns-dlc-announced-animalities-t-1000-conan-and-screams-ghostface-all-on-the-way</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mortal-kombat-1-khaos-reigns-dlc-announced-animalities-t-1000-conan-and-screams-ghostface-all-on-the-way.939261/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/mortal-kombat-1-khaos-reigns-dlc-announced-animalities-t-1000-conan-and-screams-ghostface-all-on-the-way<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Mortal-Kombat-1-animality.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>NetherRealm</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>NetherRealm has announced Mortal Kombat 1 DLC Khaos Reigns, which will expand the game's story campaign with an all-new cinematic narrative.</p>
<p>"When a perilous threat arrives from an alternate timeline, led by the ruthless Titan Havik whose sole mission is to throw the realms into khaos, Liu Kang must rally his champions and put faith in his enemies to defeat this grave danger," reads the <a href="https://uk.finance.yahoo.com/news/warner-bros-games-announces-mortal-223900046.html">official blurb</a>. "If they fail, the New Era will be reduced to anarchy."</p>
<figure>
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<figcaption>Mortal Kombat 1 Official Banished Trailer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=W2L6v8-7Ru4" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>In addition, the Mortal Kombat 1 team has revealed its next Kombat Pack, which will provide players with more fighters to add to their roster. Upcoming fighters include returning kombatants Noob Saibot, voiced by Kaiji Tang; Cyrax, voiced by Enuka Okuma; and Sektor, voiced by Erika Ishii. These three all have "unique backstories as part of the reimagined Mortal Kombat 1 Universe". For example, Sektor and Cyrax are both women in this universe.</p>
<p>As well as the fighters mentioned above, Kombat Pack 2 will also bring three guest fighters into the fray: Scream's Ghostface,  T-1000 (the liquid metal-based Terminator and cybernetic assassin from Terminator 2: Judgment Day) and Conan the Barbarian. T-1000 will not only feature the likeness of Robert Patrick. The actor will also be providing the voice as well. Conan, meanwhile, only features the likeness of Arnold Schwarzenegger.</p>
<p>Kombat Pack 2 is not available as a standalone character bundle.</p>
<p>Rounding out the most recent batch of Mortal Kombat 1 news, the team also announced Animalities will be returning as a free content update for all owners. This upcoming feature will allow characters to "morph into their spirit animal". Then, once in their animalistic forms, they can "annihilate" their defeated opponents.</p>
<p>You can see a suitably bloody trailer for it all below.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Mortal Kombat 1: Khaos Reigns Official Announcement Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/PF7nFD80g3M?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Mortal Kombat 1: Khaos Reigns Official Announcement Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/PF7nFD80g3M?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/PF7nFD80g3M?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Mortal Kombat 1: Khaos Reigns Official Announcement Trailer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PF7nFD80g3M" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>Mortal Kombat 1: Khaos Reigns will launch digitally on 24th September across PC (Steam and Epic Games Store), PlayStation 5, Nintendo Switch and Xbox Series X/S, with <a href="https://www.mortalkombat.com/en-gb/purchase">pre-orders available now</a>. Noob Saibot, Cyrax, and Sektor will be available from that date. </p>
<p>Ghostface, T-1000, and Conan the Barbarian will then be released post-launch, with one-week early access provided to Mortal Kombat 1: Khaos Reigns owners. A more specific date for these three fighters was not provided at this time.</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/image-(248).png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>NetherRealm</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>We awarded the game three out of five stars on its release last year. "Death, Taxes, and Mortal Kombat. The name is established, the lore is beloved, the roster is compelling, and the community is extremely passionate," reads <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/mortal-kombat-1-review">Eurogamer's Mortal Kombat 1 review</a> from September.</p>
<p>"It will be a part of the fighting game scene, both competitively and casually, now and forever. But serious evolution is needed if this franchise is to keep up with the pace of its modern competition, and galvanise itself for the coming decades."</p>
<p>Elsewhere in franchise news, earlier this year it was announced New Line Cinema's <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/mortal-kombat-2-film-ties-down-release-date-but-its-not-out-until-next-year">Mortal Kombat 2 will arrive in cinemas on 24th October, 2025</a>. Mortal Kombat 2 serves as a sequel to 2021's Mortal Kombat, and is again directed by Simon McQuoid.</p>
<p>Joining the cast for the upcoming release is <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/karl-urban-reportedly-in-line-to-play-johnny-cage-in-mortal-kombat-2">The Boys and Lord of the Rings star Karl Urban</a>, who will play Johnny Cage.</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ShadPS4 PlayStation 4 Continues To Make Impressive Progress, Getting In-Game In Red Dead Redemption]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/shadps4-playstation-4-progress-red-dead-redemption/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/shadps4-playstation-4-continues-to-make-impressive-progress-getting-in-game-in-red-dead-redemption.939258/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/shadps4-playstation-4-progress-red-dead-redemption/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The ShadPS4 PlayStation 4 emulator continues to make impressive progress, and its latest version is now capable of getting in-game in yet another title.</p>
<p>As showcased in a new video shared by <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@BRUTALSAMM" target="_blank" rel="noopener">BrutalSam</a>, the emulator can now get in-game in Red Dead Redemption Remastered. The game is evidently not in a playable state, but considering the emulator was only capable of booting the game up<a href="https://wccftech.com/shadps4-red-dead-redemption-remastered/"> two weeks ago</a>, this is impressive progress that bodes very well for the future.</p>
<p>In the video, BrutalSam also tests a few other games, including One Piece Unlimited World Red, Tomb Raider I-III Remastered, Steamworld Dig 2, Persona 5 Royal, and others. You can check out how these games run below.</p>
<p><iframe title="ShadPS4 Emulator Progress, Red Dead Redemption in-game | 16 Games Tested" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/mHmBY1zjolU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>The ShadPS4 isn't the only PlayStation 4 emulator in the works, but it has quickly become the most promising thanks to the amazing progress it has been making in a short amount of time. The emulator's progress is also getting followed closely by a lot of players as it could become the only way to finally play <a href="https://wccftech.com/shadps4-emulator-improves-bloodborne-pc/">Bloodborne</a> on PC in the future. The emulator can currently boot the game up, but the day PC players will finally be able to participate in the hunt may not be too far off in the future.</p>
<p>More information on the ShadPS4 PlayStation 4 emulator can be found <a href="https://github.com/shadps4-emu/shadPS4" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here.</a></p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trademarks Suggest ‘Starborn’ is Starfield’s Second Expansion]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/starfield-starborn-dlc/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/trademarks-suggest-%E2%80%98starborn%E2%80%99-is-starfield%E2%80%99s-second-expansion.939255/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/starfield-starborn-dlc/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>A new trademark filing suggests that Starfield’s second expansion may be called ‘Starborn’.</p>



<p>First spotted by Twitter user <a href="https://x.com/bogorad222/status/1817853485028725009" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Timur222</a>, the new trademark was filed on July 12, 2024, and is registered by ZeniMax Media Inc.</p>



<p>For context, Starborn refers to the group of humans who have passed through Unity, which allows them to travel between universes. In the game’s story, they reveal themselves to&nbsp;Constellation&nbsp;after the&nbsp;Spacefarer&nbsp;collects enough&nbsp;Artifacts. </p>



<p>There’s no indication of when Starfield Starborn will release, as players are still eagerly waiting for a definite release date of Starfield’s first DLC, Shattered Space. Shattered Space was initially revealed before the release of Starfield and included in the game’s Premium Edition.</p>



<p>At the very least, it seems Starfield’s Starborn DLC is at least a 2025 release.</p>



<p>Starfield achieved an 83 on Metacritic for the Xbox Series X version of Starfield, whereas PC gained 85. </p>



<p>What do you think of Starfield having a second DLC? Let us know in the comments below.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more of the latest Insider Gaming news, check out Insider Gaming’s&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fallout-london-review-first-impressions/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">early impressions of the Fallout: London Mod</a>, and sign up for&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/newsletter/">our official newsletter</a>.</p>













									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox Fans Wave Goodbye to 360 Marketplace as Microsoft Shuts Down 19-Year-Old Storefront]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/xbox-fans-wave-goodbye-to-360-marketplace-as-microsoft-shuts-down-19-year-old-storefront</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/xbox-fans-wave-goodbye-to-360-marketplace-as-microsoft-shuts-down-19-year-old-storefront.939252/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/xbox-fans-wave-goodbye-to-360-marketplace-as-microsoft-shuts-down-19-year-old-storefront<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">"Alas, digital preservation evangelists are again proven correct."</h2></div><section><p>Xbox fans are waving goodbye to the Xbox 360 Marketplace, which shuts down today nearly 19 years after it launched.</p><p>The Xbox 360 Marketplace hit the internet alongside the Xbox 360 in November 2005, and brought with it a storefront that would become familiar to a generation of gamers.</p><p>Microsoft shuts down the Xbox 360 Marketplace today, July 29, not only marking the end of an era and the true end of the Xbox 360, but making a long list of video games and add-ons that were exclusive to the digital storefront impossible to buy. That list includes the likes of Aegis Wing, Meteos Wars, and Crimson Alliance.</p><p>Fans have taken to social media to reminisce about the Xbox 360 Marketplace, including former Microsoft employee Larry ‘Major Nelson’ Hryb, who for years would write posts about sales and updates for the Xbox 360 Marketplace and became the face of Xbox for so many fans.</p><p>“Almost 19 years on, all good things must come to an end,” Hryb <a href="https://x.com/majornelson/status/1817696501558317267" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">tweeted</a>. “It was my pleasure sharing all the thousands of marketplace sales and updates I’ve given over the years. Thank for having fun, playing fair and filing feedback.”</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/07/29/gettyimages-971159730-1722242201673.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption>Major Nelson at E3 2018. Photographer: Patrick T. Fallon/Bloomberg via Getty Images.</figcaption></figure></output><blockquote data-theme="light"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>This is the final weekend for the Xbox 360 Marketplace.</p><p>If you don't purchase in these last 2 days, you'll lose your chance forever. End of an era to my favourite system of the 7th Generation. <a href="https://t.co/tqZo06NFXx" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/tqZo06NFXx</a></p></div>— Clement (@ClementJ64) <a href="https://twitter.com/ClementJ64/status/1817252037748285580?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">July 27, 2024</a></blockquote> <blockquote data-theme="light"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Xbox 360 Marketplace <a href="https://t.co/ereYEXaLCs" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/ereYEXaLCs</a></p>— no context nostalgia (@nostalgiaooc) <a href="https://twitter.com/nostalgiaooc/status/1817654520886759518?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">July 28, 2024</a></blockquote> <blockquote data-theme="light"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Before the marketplace closes on Monday, here's a showcase of my final Xbox 360 digital library. I'll still be collecting physical games, but it's sad to see my childhood console have it's support finally dropped. <a href="https://t.co/J9or5CPrcX" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/J9or5CPrcX</a></p>— Batty (@battybuh) <a href="https://twitter.com/battybuh/status/1817047324020945141?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">July 27, 2024</a></blockquote> <blockquote data-theme="light"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Xbox 360 marketplace closed forever today <a href="https://t.co/0P6ADFDjCs" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/0P6ADFDjCs</a></p>— Buster (@bustershii) <a href="https://twitter.com/bustershii/status/1817817944534950288?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">July 29, 2024</a></blockquote> <p>Others have gone on one last spending spree, buying games and DLC set to disappear from sale forever.</p><blockquote data-theme="light">— Eric Hewitt / Ghost (@GH057ayame) <a href="https://twitter.com/GH057ayame/status/1817653445710745620?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">July 28, 2024</a></blockquote> <blockquote data-theme="light"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">WARNING: TONIGHT IS THE FINAL NIGHT YOU CAN GET THE $1 SOUR BILL AVATAR SHIRT FROM THE XBOX 360 MARKETPLACE, THIS IS NOT A JOKE <a href="https://t.co/qRdsg4SKZr" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/qRdsg4SKZr</a></p>— TheRayReviewer (@RayReviewer) <a href="https://twitter.com/RayReviewer/status/1817581102523089152?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">July 28, 2024</a></blockquote> <blockquote data-theme="light">— GNARFIELD (@Nintendont_64) <a href="https://twitter.com/Nintendont_64/status/1817580058615394705?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">July 28, 2024</a></blockquote> <p>It’s worth noting that despite this shutdown, you <em>can</em> redownload previously owned titles and DLCs, buy backwards compatible games on the Xbox One and Series storefront, and still play online on Xbox 360. So, only games unavailable via backwards compatibility on Xbox One / Series and Xbox 360-era content such as avatars, icons, and themes are gone forever.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>Alas, digital preservation evangelists are again proven correct.</p></div><p>Ahead of the shutdown, Microsoft-owned video game developer Double Fine offered Xbox 360 owners free digital codes for Kinect Party, the sequel to Happy Action Theater. The Psychonauts and Brütal Legend developer warned Xbox 360 players that they should download any games ahead of the closure. Because Xbox 360 Kinect is not supported by subsequent Xbox hardware, Kinect Party is one of the games lost forever amid this shutdown.</p><p>And in a nod to concern from some quarters that Microsoft's closure of the Xbox 360 Marketplace would have a significant impact on video game preservation, Double Fine <a href="https://x.com/DoubleFine/status/1815872631842955421" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">tweeted</a>: “Alas, digital preservation evangelists are again proven correct.”</p><p>X/Twitter user <a href="https://x.com/Kalyoshika" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@Kalyoshika</a> provided a helpful list of video games that haven’t survived the shutdown. It includes the likes of The Dishwasher: Dead Samurai, Death Tank, and Diabolical Pitch.</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Alright alright people want it so here it is. The Xbox 360 store is being obliterated from orbit on July 29, 2024 so I've written a non-exhaustive thread here of a few interesting games/DLC that will not survive*. Some are on sale others...not on sale.🧵 <a href="https://t.co/a8Mn2pIX09" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/a8Mn2pIX09</a></p>— KaL (@Kalyoshika) <a href="https://twitter.com/Kalyoshika/status/1816024266162487375?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">July 24, 2024</a></blockquote> <p>Do you have any fond memories of the Xbox 360 Marketplace? Did you buy anything last minute before it was lost forever? Let us know in the comments.</p><p><em>Photo by Tomohiro Ohsumi/Bloomberg via Getty Images.</em></p><p><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mortal Kombat 1 will get the T-1000, Conan, and the Scream guy alongside a new story expansion]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/mortal-kombat-1-will-get-the-t-1000-conan-and-the-scream-guy-alongside-a-new-story-expansion</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mortal-kombat-1-will-get-the-t-1000-conan-and-the-scream-guy-alongside-a-new-story-expansion.939243/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/mortal-kombat-1-will-get-the-t-1000-conan-and-the-scream-guy-alongside-a-new-story-expansion<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/mortal-kombat-1-t-1000.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Warner Bros</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>The story of Mortal Kombat games in recent years has been a mish-mash of double-crosses, weird friendships, and alternate dimension wobbles. They often feel like a casualty of Marvel movie bloat. <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/mortal-kombat-1">Mortal Kombat 1</a> was marketed as a "reboot", for example, but is really just a continuation of previous nonsense, with developers NetherRealm saying "I don't know, stick a multiverse in it." Yet from that multiverse now arrives another bad guy, bringing new story chapters for the fighting game's first big expansion, as well as extra characters like the liquid metal murderer from Terminator 2, a Conan of the barbarian persuasion, and the masked killer of the Scream movies.</p>
<!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Mortal Kombat 1: Khaos Reigns Official Announcement Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/PF7nFD80g3M?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Mortal Kombat 1: Khaos Reigns Official Announcement Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/PF7nFD80g3M?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/PF7nFD80g3M?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PF7nFD80g3M" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>The new story chapters will see the various realms of reality threatened by an alternate world version of Havik, the gravelly voiced, zombie-faced C-lister of the Mortal Kombat franchise. Some other characters will appear alongside him, including a bizarro-land Noob Saibot and a gender-flipped Sektor and Cyrax. Heavens knows how they're going to make any of this sensible. Then again, the most fun part of the base game's storyline came from ascending a pyramid swarming with mash-up characters, and pulverizing said hybrids into pulp. So maybe, just maybe, the storyline doesn't matter a damn?</p>
<p>The "Khaos Reigns" DLC will come out September 24 and also include a bunch of guest characters. Like I say, the T-1000, Conan, and Ghostface will all make an appearance. A free update releasing along with the expansion will also add "animalities" to the biff 'em up. These are a zoological spin on the series' traditionally violent finishing moves, and <a href="https://mortalkombat.fandom.com/wiki/Animality">first appeared way back in Mortal Kombat 3</a>. When you perform one, your character will transform into a gorilla, hippo, or other charismatic megafauna, and then tear your opponent asunder. The trailer shows Mileena transmogrifying into a giant preying mantis and nibbling on her foe's head, for instance. It remains unknown if Johnny Cage's kangaroo kill will reappear, but one can dream.</p>
<p>Like I said in our <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/mortal-kombat-1-review">Mortal Kombat 1 review</a>, I was not keen on the Marvel-esque kliché of its storytelling. But the fighting was solid, with a fun "kameo" system that allowed for other characters to appear on screen and briefly throw a spanner into the brawl, by saving you from a hit or extending a combo. It's not my go-to <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-fighting-games">fighting game</a> if I'm in the mood for getting pummeled by strangers online (that's still <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/tekken-8">Tekken</a>), but put the comic book bloat aside and you'll find MK1 isn't too shabby.</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Assassin's Creed reddit takes firm stance on Yasuke "debate", says Ubisoft "exacerbated" issue with statement]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/assassins-creed-reddit-takes-firm-stance-on-yasuke-debate-says-ubisoft-exacerbated-issue-with-statement</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/assassins-creed-reddit-takes-firm-stance-on-yasuke-debate-says-ubisoft-exacerbated-issue-with-statement.939240/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/assassins-creed-reddit-takes-firm-stance-on-yasuke-debate-says-ubisoft-exacerbated-issue-with-statement<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>"There was never any point to these discussions outside of thinly veiling bad faith intent."</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/0x0_lEXCPGR.webp?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Ubisoft</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
The main Assassin's Creed reddit, subscribed to by more than 717,000 users, has taken a firm stance on the continuing backlash to Black samurai Yasuke protagonist in <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/assassins-creed-codename-red">Assassin's Creed Shadows</a>.
</p>
<p>
A <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/assassinscreed/comments/1ee83ow/there_is_no_debate_yasuke_was_a_samurai_if_you/">post</a> from the popular reddit's moderation team has drawn a line under the ongoing "'debate'" over whether the real-life figure of Yasuke was a samurai or not, and to what extent his depiction in Assassin's Creed Shadows will be historically accurate. 
</p>
<p>
It's a matter Ubisoft appeared to wade into last week via a vaguely-worded statement that raised eyebrows after it <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/assassins-creed-shadows-team-acknowledges-elements-that-have-caused-concern-among-japanese-fans">apologised for "some elements" in the game's promotional materials it said had "caused concern" among some Japanese fans</a>. Now, in a lengthy statement, the moderation team says Ubisoft's statement had "exacerbated" the matter further.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Assassin's Creed Shadows Official Gameplay - Combat and Stealth Evolved | Ubisoft Forward" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/eG9JKgcRJHw?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Assassin's Creed Shadows Official Gameplay - Combat and Stealth Evolved | Ubisoft Forward</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/eG9JKgcRJHw?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/eG9JKgcRJHw?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Assassin's Creed Shadows gameplay trailer showing dual protagonists Yasuke and Naoe.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eG9JKgcRJHw" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
"With the reveal of Assassin's Creed Shadows, there has been an influx of certain individuals spilling into various communities online such as this subreddit and raising arguments about 'historical accuracy'," the Assassin's Creed reddit moderation team wrote. 
</p>
<p>
"As we are all exhausted of this tedious discussion that has been endlessly talked to death, not to mention exacerbated by a recent official statement from Ubisoft, we would like to give a final reminder to those participating in these debates as to what exactly this franchise entails, and why there was never any point to these discussions to begin with outside of thinly veiling bad faith intent.
</p>
<p>
"Assassin's Creed is historical fiction. This means that while certain locations, events and figures may be based on reality, and can even have a slight focus on accuracy, their depictions are largely exaggerated for the sake of a more enjoyable video game. While all of our player protagonists have been fictional to date, the introduction of Yasuke has given some people the false impression that the above rule does not apply. It still does. 
</p>
<p>
"Yasuke, who is a samurai as confirmed by multiple reputable historians around the world including from Japan, may not have held as large as a role in the real world as he does in Shadows. This is okay. It is a video game. You are not meant to use Assassin's Creed as a sourcebook for actual historical knowledge - it is meant to compel you to do your own external research after immersing you in a glimpse of authenticity."
</p>
<p>
The moderation team goes on to provide an extensive series of links to a "helpful list" of historical inaccuracies in every Assassin's Creed game so far, collated by fans.
</p>
<p>
"We are not here in this community to debate on historical record," the statement continues. "Most of us understand as fans that while these games provide us a great look into what historical settings could have felt like and have fun comparing them to actual record, we do not chase accuracy within this franchise and primarily play for other reasons. 
</p>
<p>
"So if you are specifically here to leave comments about your displeasure about Yasuke's inclusion or various other inaccurate details that have been pointed out in Ubisoft's depiction of Feudal Japan, it is time to understand that this is not the place for this discussion and it never will be. Feel free to take your displeasures elsewhere, away from this franchise and its communities.
</p>
<p>
"Any further comments attempting to dispute Yasuke's societal status, disparage his inclusion in game or containing statements bordering on concern trolling for historical accuracy will be swiftly removed and met with a ban."
</p>
<p>
The post itself has now been locked due to "brigading", an update from the moderation team states.
</p>
<p>
Online discussion around Yasuke, stoked up by outraged YouTube and social media channels, has centred on the Black character's prominence in the fedual Japan-set game alongside shinobi co-star Naoe, and criticism of a particular historian Ubisoft consulted with over Yasuke's real-life background.
</p>
<p>
The debate has spilled over into the real-world, too, enough that a fringe Japanese politician requested the Japanese government comment on the matter - to seemingly no meaningful result. 
</p>
<p>
In a <a href="https://x.com/mrjeffu/status/1815993456579461156">thread</a> on X by Jeffrey J Hall, a university lecturer on Japanese politics, the outcome was described thus: "Foreign Ministry: it's not our concern. Education Ministry: canned answer saying games shouldn't violate 'public order and morals'. METI [Ministry of Economy, Trade and Industry] declined to answer because it doesn't concern them."
</p>
<p>
"Internet culture warriors hyped up the NHK Party's questions like they were a huge thing, not understanding that Japanese government ministries aren't in the business of censoring works of historical fiction," Hall concluded. "This kind of questioning is common in Japanese politics and is often just performative. Many of these content creators did not inform their audiences that the NHK Party is a tiny party with almost zero practical political influence in Japan."
</p>
<p>
Last month, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/ubisoft-boss-condemns-malicious-developer-abuse-after-assassins-creed-shadows-reveal">Ubisoft boss Yves Guillemot spoke out to condemn "malicious and personal online attacks" directed at Assassin's Creed Shadows' development team</a> in the wake of the game's reveal.
</p>
<p>
Assassin's Creed boss Marc-Alexis Coté has also addressed the matter, and discussed <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/assassins-creed-shadows-boss-explains-why-he-ignored-elon-musk-after-backlash-over-african-samurai-yasuke">how he reacted to a tweet from billionaire X and Tesla owner Elon Musk criticising diversity in game design</a>.
</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>