<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 21:03:47 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EA partners with Stability AI for ‘transformative’ AI game-making tools]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/805777/ea-stability-ai-transformative-game-development-tools</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ea-partners-with-stability-ai-for-%E2%80%98transformative%E2%80%99-ai-game-making-tools.1333480/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span id="follow-author-standard_article_details-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTIz"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span></span><span>Jay Peters</span></span></span></p> <p><span>is a senior reporter covering technology, gaming, and more. He joined The Verge in 2019 after nearly two years at Techmeme.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>EA is partnering with Stability AI, the company that develops the Stable Diffusion AI image model, to help infuse AI into its development processes. The two companies will “co-develop transformative AI models, tools, and workflows that empower our artists, designers, and developers to reimagine how content is built,” <a href="https://www.ea.com/news/ea-partners-with-stability-ai">EA says</a>.</p><p>The company says that humans will still be “at the center of storytelling,” but “we’re evolving how we work so that AI becomes a trusted ally: supporting faster iteration, expanding creative possibilities, accelerating workflows, and allowing more time to focus on what matters most – building world-class games and experiences that entertain massive online communities.” EA adds that AI “can draft, generate, and analyze, but it can’t imagine, empathize, or dream. That’s the work of EA’s extraordinary artists, designers, developers, storytellers, and innovators.”</p><p>EA CEO Andrew Wilson has spoken highly of AI in the past, saying last year that the technology is at <a href="https://www.pocketgamer.biz/ea-the-future-of-entertainment-is-interactive-as-dev-looks-to-become-launchpad-for-new-businesses/">“very core”</a> of the company’s business. AI could be embedded in EA’s operations even more in the future: the investor group that is <a href="https://www.theverge.com/games/787723/ea-private-deal-buyout-future-games-layoffs">looking to take EA private</a> has its eyes on using AI at the company, with the <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/be980240-13ec-498c-ba79-71eada30d133"><em>Financial Times</em> reporting that</a> “the investors are betting that AI-based cost cuts will significantly boost EA’s profits in the coming years.” And EA isn’t the only major gaming company looking to increase its use of AI; <em>PUBG: Battlegrounds</em> maker Krafton <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/805509/krafton-pubg-ai-first-developer-agentic-gpu-cluster">just announced</a> that it’s investing heavily into AI as part of an “AI First” strategy.</p><p>One of the first initiatives EA and Stability will work on together is “to accelerate the creation of Physically Based Rendering (PBR) materials through the development of new artist-driven workflows – for example, tools that generate 2D textures that maintain exact color and light accuracy across any environment,” according to EA. Stability AI <a href="https://stability.ai/news/stability-ai-and-ea-partner-to-reimagine-game-development">notes that</a> the two companies will “also pursue developing AI systems capable of pre-visualizing entire 3D environments from a series of intentional prompts, allowing artists to creatively direct the generation of game content with unmatched speed and precision.”</p><div><p><span><strong>Follow topics and authors</strong> from this story to see more like this in your personalized homepage feed and to receive email updates.</span></p><ul><li id="follow-author-article_footer-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTIz"><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span><span>Jay Peters</span></span></span></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li></ul></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/news/805777/ea-stability-ai-transformative-game-development-tools]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[DEFECT gameplay reveal trailers, screenshots]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/10/defect-gameplay-reveal-trailers-screenshots</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/defect-gameplay-reveal-trailers-screenshots.1333477/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>First in-game look at the cyberpunk first-person shooter.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > emptyvessel [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/emptyvessel">emptyvessel</a> has released a pair of gameplay reveal trailers and new screenshots for cyberpunk <a title="Genres > First-Person Shooter [2,809 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/shooter/fps">first-person shooter</a> <em><a title="Games > DEFECT [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/defect">DEFECT</a></em>. <span id="more-1002175"></span></p><p>“Our entire emptyvessel team is incredibly excited to show off this first look at gameplay in <em>DEFECT</em> as we’ve poured a ton of passion and time into <a title="Genres > Crafting [46 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/crafting">crafting</a> the game’s tone, atmosphere, and underlying systems,” said emptyvessel founder and game director Emanuel Palalic in a press release. “<em>DEFECT</em> is a HUD-less immersive <a title="Genres > Shooter [4,306 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/shooter">shooter</a> where any wall can be destroyed, gadgets and tools completely redefine how you approach combat, and every weapon or ammo type affects the world, interactables, and enemies in unique ways. The world is filled with emergent moments and dynamic branching narratives that react to player <a title="Genres > Action [3,138 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a>s in real time.”</p><p>Get the latest details below.</p><blockquote><p>The <em>DEFECT</em> gameplay trailer kicked off [Galaxies Autumn 2025] and to further delight the audience, emptyvessel surprised fans with a second gameplay trailer post-show. The extended five-minute cut was introduced by studio founder Emanuel Palalic, and offered more gameplay by showing off a squad of THE SYSTEM’S heavily armed police forces storming the grimy halls of a massive apartment complex to terminate a rogue artificial intelligence. They’re quickly given a warm welcome by the ruthless gang lording over the complex, drawing each faction into an explosive firefight that tears the environment to shreds. A quick-thinking officer is able to hijack the consciousness of an unfortunate gang member which allows him to revive a downed teammate by placing them into the mind of this gang member thereby making them part of the friendly team until the end of the match. The squad of police descend further into the guts of the building in order to reboot the entire block, taking their final stand while soaking in the neon lights and lasers of an underground dancefloor. The two-minute short-form version of the gameplay trailer condenses the action down to the highlights in all their destructive glory.</p><p>Initially announced in 2024, <em>DEFECT</em> is a new squad-based cyberpunk shooter, from the creative minds of emptyvessel. <em>DEFECT</em> delivers a new kind of experience through its immersive and highly tactical combat for fans of the action shooter genre. The game is set in a futuristic, divided city ruled by an enigmatic AI known as “THE SYSTEM” all while ruthless gangs and rogue law enforcement vie for supremacy. <em>DEFECT</em> is being created by industry-leading developers behind iconic franchises including <em>DOOM</em>, <em>Call of Duty</em>, and <em>The Last of Us</em>; and features music from legendary composer Mick Gordon.</p></blockquote><div id="carousel_1002177"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div><!-- AD: content -->
        <blockquote><p>The world of <em>DEFECT</em> is like none other and dominated by one rule: Chaos Above All. Players will revel in the anarchy of a city on the brink. Set in the last city of mankind, where THE SYSTEM, an authoritarian AI, rules with inhuman logic. Choose from a collection of dangerous factions—THE SYSTEM’S own policing force, Rogue Police Elements, or a host of gangs vying for power. Players will compete to achieve objectives like smuggling guns, assassinating targets, or arresting suspects. Suit up with state-of-the-art weaponry and technology to give yourself the edge you need to live another day. </p><p>Every mission is different, whether you’re acting as the law, the lawless, or those caught in between. Choice will determine how the game is played with friends in single player, PvP or <a title="Genres > Co-Op [343 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer/co-op">co-op multiplayer</a>. Squads of 4v4 players vie to complete multiple open-ended objectives, valuable items and enhancements that can change the tide of a battle, and the inevitable chaos means no firefight ends the exact same way.</p><p>With a passion for creating games that deliver immersive experiences, <em>DEFECT</em> serves as the inaugural title for emptyvessel. The game is being built using Unreal Engine 5, and utilizes the latest technology alongside the team’s vision for delivering unique and exciting gameplay experiences. </p></blockquote><p><em>DEFECT</em> will be available for <a title="Platforms > PC [24,599 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2470010/DEFECT/" target="_blank">Steam</a>, <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/p/defect-dde0e6" target="_blank">Epic Games Store</a>, and <a href="https://www.gog.com/en/game/defect" target="_blank">GOG</a>. A release date has yet to be announced.</p><p>Watch the trailers below. View the screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/defect/october-23-2025/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>Gameplay Reveal Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="DEFECT | Gameplay Reveal Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/5xrVTBvS7o0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><span>Extended Gameplay Reveal Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="DEFECT | Extended Gameplay Reveal Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/O0d9sqm5LX0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/10/defect-gameplay-reveal-trailers-screenshots]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nivalis has been delayed to 2026]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/10/23/nivalis-has-been-delayed-to-2026/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nivalis-has-been-delayed-to-2026.1333453/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Ion Lands has announced that its cyberpunk slice of life RPG Nivalis, set in the same world as Cloudpunk, will not be making a 2025 release date. Last year, the development team was aiming for a Spring 2025 release but that passed. However, the team did want to get the game out this year. However, there is still work to be done, so Ion Lands has made the decision to delay Nivalis to 2026.</p>
<p><iframe title="Nivalis | Official Summer 2024 Trailer [PEGI]" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/VYykZ9RBo3w?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>In a blog post, Ion Lands said, <em>“As you know, our goal over the past year has been to launch the game within 2025. The progress we’ve made in recent months has been both steady and substantial, allowing us to refine every aspect of Nivalis – our unique take on the slice-of-life genre – including all the intertwined, dystopian, and mysterious stories unfolding throughout its streets. However, there’s still one final piece of the puzzle missing.</em></p>
<p><em>Right now, we’re deeply focused on the voice over: we’ve just completed the casting process for over 100 new voice roles after our first casting of 32 roles for our demo 2 years ago. We have received more than 8,000 auditions this time. In Nivalis, there will be around 135 primary and secondary fully voiced characters, for a total of about 200,000 words. They will bring to life the multitude of complex personalities you’ll meet in the game. It’s a massive undertaking that we’re carefully overseeing, because for us this is a key element: as we’ve said many times before, we want the Nivalis experience to be as immersive as possible. So – as some of you correctly guessed after last month’s devlog – between casting, recording, and implementing the voiceover, releasing the game in 2025 would risk compromising its quality.</em></p>
<p><em>For that reason, we’ve made the decision to officially move Nivalis’ release a few months ahead into 2026. This will also allow us to dedicate all the time needed for additional testing, optimization, polishing, and balancing, to ensure the smoothest experience possible. We’re currently working closely with our publisher to determine a specific launch date – which we hope to share before the end of the year. Soon, we’ll let you know when we’ll be able to celebrate ‘Nivalis Day’. Thank you all for your patience, understanding, and incredible support – it’s what gives us the strength and motivation to push through this final stretch.”</em></p>

<p>In Nivalis, you begin with a small business, such as a noodle stand or a small nightclub. Your goal is to grow from these modest origins into a huge enterprise that Nivalis’ citizens will rave about and want to spend their time and money at. However, there’s more to Nivalis than just building up a business. You can get to know some of the city’s inhabitants, go fishing, or just dedicate time to home decoration. Delving into the underworld of Nivalis is also an option, if you want to go that route.</p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1488490/view/536616765394782627">Steam</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/10/23/nivalis-has-been-delayed-to-2026/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mouse: P.I. For Hire gets a March 2026 release date]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/10/23/mouse-p-i-for-hire-gets-a-march-2026-release-date/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mouse-p-i-for-hire-gets-a-march-2026-release-date.1333450/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Yesterday, PlaySide Studios and Fumi Games announced <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/10/22/mouse-p-i-for-hire-has-been-pushed-back-to-early-2026/">Mouse: P.I. For Hire had been pushed back to early 2026.</a> Today, the teams have confirmed a concrete release date for the cartoony first person shooter, and players will be able to get their hands on it from March 19th, 2026. The game is coming PC, PS5, and Xbox Series XS.</p>
<p><iframe title="MOUSE: P.I. For Hire | Official Release Date Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/IlwZMgDK-kQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p><i>“We are very excited to share our game,&nbsp;<b>MOUSE: P.I. For Hire</b>, with fans across the world on 19 March 2026”</i>, says Mateusz Michalak, CEO &amp; Founder, Fumi Games.&nbsp;<i>“Set in the cartoon-noir city of Mouseburg, MOUSE: P.I. For Hire offers a unique mix of explosive FPS action and hand-drawn rubber hose animation. Stepping into the shoes of Private Investigator Jack Pepper – played by the inimitable Troy Baker – will be an experience that players will not forget!”</i></p>
<p><wbr>In Mouse: P.I. For Hire you play private investigator Jack Pepper, who is being voiced by Troy Baker, in a noir inspired first person shooter drawing on 1930’s animation. The setting is the city of Mouseburg and Jack is initially hired to help a “damsel in distress”. However, things take a turn as the case dives deep into the criminal and corrupt world that lays beneath the surface of the city. There will be numerous areas to explore including the city streets, the sewers, a casino, a film studio, and the docks. All of these locations will have loot and collectibles to gather, along with clues to help Jack solve the case.</p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/2416450/view/499462068471072756">Steam</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/10/23/mouse-p-i-for-hire-gets-a-march-2026-release-date/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NYT Connections Hints Today (#866)—Clues and Answers for Friday, October 24]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/nyt-connections-hints-solutions-october-24-866/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nyt-connections-hints-today-866-%E2%80%94clues-and-answers-for-friday-october-24.1333444/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>It’s Friday, and as the week comes to a close, I’ve got another round of NYT Connections hints and solutions to help you usher in the weekend. Today’s puzzle was tricky, but I persevered to bring you the hints you need to wrap this NYT Connections puzzle up much faster.</p>



<p>It’s time for the weekend! Let’s get into the NYT Connections hints.</p>



<h2 id="h-what-is-nyt-connections">What is NYT Connections?</h2>



<p>It would be remiss of me not to give a little foundational backstory before leaping into today’s NYT Connections clues and hints.</p>



<p>In June 2023, NYT Connections emerged as yet another game in the ever-growing New York Times lineup. This title soared immediately, and it’s easy to see why. As a free-to-play, accessible <em>New York Times </em>game, NYT Connections is available to users <span><strong>worldwide</strong>&nbsp;and can be played on either desktop devices</span> or via a mobile app.</p>



<p>Playing NYT Connections on your commute or while waiting for a coffee is a fantastic way to kill a few minutes.</p>



<p>But how do you play NYT Connections?</p>



<figure></figure>







<p>It’s relatively simple, and that’s why it’s the best New York Times game, in my opinion.</p>



<p>The NYT team will provide you with a grid of 16 words once a day. The only task left up to you is to sort those words into four groups of four by finding their commonalities. Every NYT Connections puzzle has just one solution, and some words might have a double meaning, so it can sometimes be tricky to figure out the answers.</p>



<p>It’s also important to stress that the words are color-coded: yellow, blue, green, and purple. That’s in order of difficulty from least to most difficult, too.</p>



<p>What’s critical here is that you get <strong>four guesses </strong>every day, and if you use those, your NYT Connections answers for today will be out of reach, as it’ll be <strong>game over</strong>.</p>



<h2 id="h-today-s-nyt-connections-hints-october-24">Today’s NYT Connections Hints (October 24)</h2>



<p>If you want to figure out today’s NYT Connections clues without getting the answers outright, I’ll start with the words themselves. Perhaps just seeing the words here will spur your brain into action, and you’ll spot the trends immediately.</p>



<p>Here are the NYT Connections words from today’s puzzle, #866:</p>



<ul>
<li>BAYWATCH</li>



<li>HIGHLIGHT</li>



<li>RAINBOW</li>



<li>HERRING</li>



<li>PRIME</li>



<li>SUNSET</li>



<li>BOLD</li>



<li>PEACOCK</li>



<li>COOTIE</li>



<li>HEYDAY</li>



<li>KALEIDOSCOPE</li>



<li>UNDERLINE</li>



<li>ZENITH</li>



<li>KINGPIN</li>



<li>STRIKETHROUGH</li>



<li>PINNACLE</li>
</ul>



<h3>And here are the hints I can offer for today’s NYT Connections:</h3>



<ul>
<li><strong>Yellow </strong>– <em>These words mark the peak of something — think career highs, golden eras, or when someone was “in their prime.”</em></li>



<li><strong>Green</strong> – <em>These are all formatting options — the kind you’d find in a word processor or messaging app.</em></li>



<li><strong>Blue</strong> – <em>These are vibrant by nature — often used metaphorically to describe something dazzling or full of variety.</em></li>



<li><strong>Purple</strong> – <em>Each word ends with something you might wear or carry — but the full word itself isn’t necessarily about fashion.</em></li>
</ul>



<p>Here’s the final warning before we get to the NYT Connections answers for today, October 24.</p>



<p>Are you sure you want to scroll further?</p>



<p>Very well!</p>



<h2 id="h-nyt-connections-answers-for-today-october-24-866">NYT Connections Answers for Today, October 24 (#866)</h2>



<p>If you want to jump straight to the answers for today’s NYT Connections puzzle, I’ve got you covered:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Yellow </strong>– HEYDAY, PINNACLE, PRIME, ZENITH</li>



<li><strong>Green</strong> – BOLD, HIGHLIGHT, STRIKETHROUGH, UNDERLINE</li>



<li><strong>Blue</strong> – KALEIDOSCOPE, PEACOCK, RAINBOW, SUNSET</li>



<li><strong>Purple</strong> – BAYWATCH, COOTIE, HERRING, KINGPIN</li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-when-does-nyt-connections-reset">When Does NYT Connections Reset?</h3>



<p>That’s today’s puzzle, but if you want the next one, the game resets daily at midnight local time (that’s <strong>your </strong>local time). You’ll have 24 hours to complete the puzzle when midnight ticks over in your timezone.</p>



<p>How did you do? Did you get a perfect run? Let me know what your streak looks like on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/Bhv3AMa5a9">Insider Gaming Discord server</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/nyt-connections-hints-solutions-october-24-866/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Open-world survival crafting game Unhinged announced for PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/10/open-world-survival-crafting-game-unhinged-announced-for-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/open-world-survival-crafting-game-unhinged-announced-for-pc.1333441/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Playtest sign-ups now available.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Unifiq Games" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/unifiq-games">Unifiq Games</a> has announced <em><a title="Games > Unhinged" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/unhinged">Unhinged</a></em>, an <a title="Genres > Open-World [759 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/open-world">open-world</a> survival craft game where you are trapped in a bizarre corporate experiment. It will be available for <a title="Platforms > PC [24,599 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3664200/Unhinged/" target="_blank">Steam</a>. Private playtest sign-ups are <a href="https://subscribepage.io/PNYVwI" target="_blank">available now</a>. <span id="more-1002137"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3664200/Unhinged/" target="_blank">Steam page</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>Unhinged</em> is an open-world survival craft game where you find yourself trapped in a bizarre corporate experiment. Explore a brutal open world, build modular machines and survive mind-bending trials to uncover the terrifying truth that brought you here.</p><p><strong>Explore</strong></p><p>Explore a retro-futuristic island controlled by a high-tech corporate giant. Scavenge the island for resources and craft tools that help you survive.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong>Build</strong></p><p>Construct modular machines, build bases, harvest electricity, automate processes, and expand your footprints on the island.</p><p><strong>Survive</strong></p><p>Maintain a balanced diet, forge your path through dangerous biomes, overcome the corporate trials, confront unsettling entities, and fight to maintain your sanity… or risk becoming UNHINGED.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Sanity System</strong> – More than hunger or thirst, your mind is your foremost need. <a title="Series > Mana [17 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/series/mana">Mana</a>ge your brain chemical imbalances in one of the most complex sanity systems ever seen in <a title="Genres > Survival [473 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/survival">survival games</a>.</li><li><strong>Systemic <a title="Genres > Crafting [46 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/crafting">Crafting</a></strong> – Experiment freely with ingredients to cook food, brew tea and synthesise drugs. From lethal failures to superhuman breakthroughs, every craft expands your mastery.</li><li><strong>Contraption Building</strong> – Build machines, vehicles, and inventions from modular blocks. Your creativity determines your survival.</li><li><strong>Trials</strong> – Scattered across the island, these corporate games test your resourcefulness. Conquer them using every tool at your disposal.</li><li><strong>Automation</strong> – Set up bases connected with pipes and conveyors to automate tasks, leaving you free to focus on exploration and survival.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch the announcement trailer below.</p><h2><span>Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Unhinged - Announcement Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/SPLztzuwiE0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/10/open-world-survival-crafting-game-unhinged-announced-for-pc]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Edge of Memories ‘Story’ trailer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/10/edge-of-memories-story-trailer</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/edge-of-memories-%E2%80%98story%E2%80%99-trailer.1333435/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Introducing the universe, characters, and themes.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Nacon [260 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/nacon">Nacon</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Midgar Studio [16 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/midgar-studio">Midgar Studio</a> have released the official story trailer for <a title="Genres > Action RPG [1,828 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg/action-rpg">action RPG</a> <em><a title="Games > Edge of Memories [4 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/edge-of-memories">Edge of Memories</a></em>. <span id="more-1001463"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Nacon:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>The Corrosion, a plague of unparalleled proportions, has already ravaged the Astryan continent. On the other side of the world, the continent of Avaris and its nomadic peoples—so far spared from the <a title="Genres > Horror [736 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/horror">horror</a>s spawned by this abomination—now stand on the brink of extinction. <a title="Games > Elin [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/elin">Elin</a>e, an itinerant Soul Whisperer, relentlessly battles the force that turns the once-thriving fauna, flora and humans of this lush land into grotesque abominations. Following a mysterious encounter, a dark power awakens within her, one that may hold the key to ending this apocalypse: the ability to control the Corrosion within her own body.</p><p>But saving a world already doomed is no easy task. With the help of Ysoris, her unlikely mentor, and Kanta, shaman prince of a lost tribe, Eline must overcome the formidable adversaries standing in her way.</p><p><strong>Intense Real-Time Combat</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Engage in fierce battles against relentless enemies alongside your allies, and unleash your devastating powers to wipe them out!</p><ul><li>String together spectacular combos by alternating between rapid strikes and devastating techniques to dominate your opponents.</li><li>Your allies are the key to victory. Customize your companions, and use their skills wisely to inflict more damage at crucial moments.</li><li>Let rage consume you and transform into a Berserker to deliver earth-shattering blows, which turn into a series of merciless executions.</li></ul><p><strong>A Stunning and Corrupted World</strong></p><p>Avaris, a land of many faces, is as scarred as the rest of Heryon. From the idyllic sandy shores of the port city of Sarlah-Durah to the snow-capped peaks of the Kezal Mountains, every landscape bears the marks of the Corrosion’s abominations.</p><ul><li><strong>Explore the Continent of Avaris in the Grip of the Corrosion</strong> – Discover rich environments with vibrant colors, and observe the scourge ravaging these enchanting landscapes. As you progress through the story, the game transforms places you have previously travelled through and creates strange new paths to take.</li><li><strong>Ride a Nekaroo</strong> – Traverse the vast lands of Avaris atop this loyal feline companion and take advantage of its agility to access unreachable areas.</li><li><strong>Enjoy Stunning Visuals Inspired by Japanese Animation</strong> – Discover or rediscover the breathtaking world of Heryon through Avaris, a colorful and radiant continent brought to life with Unreal Engine 5.</li></ul><p><strong>An Intense Story With No Dull Moments</strong></p><ul><li><strong>A Gripping Epic With No Fillers</strong> – <a title="Companies > Experience [212 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/experience">Experience</a> an original narrative where every quest matters, adding new depth to the story, the characters or their relationships.</li><li><strong>Dive Into an Emotional Journey</strong> – Travel across a continent inhabited by nomadic civilizations forced to migrate to escape the Corrosion, and connect with those who have chosen to await death while celebrating life.</li></ul><p><strong>A Poetic Soundtrack</strong></p><p>Whether you are exploring the vast expanses of the continent of Avaris or battling relentless Corroded foes, enjoy a dynamic and adaptive soundtrack composed by Cedric Menendez. Carried by the enchanting voice of Emi Evans, known for her work on <em><a title="Games > NieR: Automata [117 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/nier-automata">NieR: Automata</a></em>, your journey culminates with a final theme composed by Yasunori Mitsuda, famed for his work on games such as <em><a title="Games > Chrono Trigger [12 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/chrono-trigger">Chrono Trigger</a></em>, <em>Xenoblade Chronicles</em>, and <em><a title="Games > Sea of Stars [21 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/sea-of-stars">Sea of Stars</a></em>.</p></blockquote><p><em>Edge of Memories</em> is due out for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [10,657 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [8,134 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [24,599 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2738170/Edge_of_Memories/" target="_blank">Steam</a> in 2026.</p><p>Watch the trailer below.</p><h2><span>Story Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Edge of Memories | Story Trailer (UK)" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/vWXmv3y6yp4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/10/edge-of-memories-story-trailer]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pacific Drive Whispers In The Woods Expansion Is Out Now, And It's Coming To Xbox Too]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/pacific-drive-whispers-in-the-woods-expansion-is-out-now-and-its-coming-to-xbox-too/1100-6535659/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pacific-drive-whispers-in-the-woods-expansion-is-out-now-and-its-coming-to-xbox-too.1333432/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6535659">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Anyone looking to return to the Olympic Exclusion Zone in the first <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/pacific-drive/">Pacific Drive</a> story DLC, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/one-of-2024s-best-games-is-getting-a-huge-horror-expansion/1100-6534553/">Whispers in the Woods</a>, are in for a surprise, as the expansion is out right now. In a surprise announcement, developer Ironwood Studios and publisher Kepler Interactive revealed that Whispers in the Woods is now available, and the game has also been ported over to Xbox Series X|S consoles.</p><p>The expansion features a brand-new story and content that Ironwood Studios says is roughly a third of the size of the base game, and it includes new anomalies and horrors to discover.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cXRk1pFRgOc" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/cXRk1pFRgOc" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>Players can also experiment with several new gameplay systems, such as the Whispering Tide. This is described as a "mysterious force that grows more perilous" the longer you linger in the Whispering Woods, and to survive, you'll need to equip specially attuned parts to your station wagon that can keep it at bay. Artifacts from Altars will also be found in the expansion, and these offer reality-warping powers that affect both the environment and you.</p><p>Pacific Drive made a lasting impression when it debuted last year, as the Indie survival game blended a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/how-pacific-drive-pulls-off-being-unnervingly-spooky-and-relaxingly-chill-all-at-once/1100-6523113/">well-crafted layer of suspense with a surprisingly chill vibe</a> as you explored a creepy patch of the Pacific Northwest from the relative safety of your station wagon.</p><p>"With its wonderful depth in both story and gameplay, Pacific Drive is an early hit in 2024," Mark Delaney wrote in GameSpot's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/pacific-drive-review-road-trippy/1900-6418183/">Pacific Drive review</a>. "It sets out to create a world that fits comfortably in the New Weird genre but brings its own style and substance to it. Though the game can be especially hard to decipher, difficulty options help to counter some of its more overwhelming aspects. I'll stick to bikes in my day-to-day life through the actual northwest, but in Pacific Drive, I'm up for another joy ride through one hell of a winding road."</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/pacific-drive-whispers-in-the-woods-expansion-is-out-now-and-its-coming-to-xbox-too/1100-6535659/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Take-Two CEO predicts genAI will create jobs, not kill them]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/take-two-ceo-predicts-genai-will-create-jobs-not-kill-them</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/take-two-ceo-predicts-genai-will-create-jobs-not-kill-them.1333429/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="captioned-content" data-testid="featured-image"><p><span>Image via Rockstar Games/Take-Two Interactive.</span></p></div><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">During a talk at The Paley Center for Media in the San Francisco Bay Area on changing consumer trends in media, Take-Two Interactive CEO Strauss Zelnick spoke about the current state of AI technologies in game development and how they will influence games in the future.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Along with expanding on his views on the nascent technology, its limitations compared to human creativity, and how he believes it will lead to more employment opportunities, a theory that runs counter to </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.yahoo.com/news/articles/sam-altman-says-jobs-gets-143000252.html?guccounter=1&amp;guce_referrer=aHR0cHM6Ly9kdWNrZHVja2dvLmNvbS8&amp;guce_referrer_sig=AQAAALQZ_5M-WFV-TgyFq1sUcZkvlm8FQH3BHYzcKQIp4Pv_z9sBJ5Snry3g6nsp4tBx_JaGnuCPC_mtwnvTCR0Wh42B_MM-Rd7gxXjeyMcpG_8L3WhlzJbHcdof-gq8MwNcg3mlWG7eUToGa8lg4_a92kI-o3-_z2nth4avl-SVfGHp">predictions of job losses</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> made by other executives. He said this while responding to a question from fellow panelist Bob Pittman, CEO of iHeartMedia about the future of employment in a world with generative AI. "It will not reduce employment, it will increase employment," he said. "Technology always increases productivity, which in turn increases GDP, which in turn increases employment. And you know, in 1865, 65% of the US workforce was involved in agriculture."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Today, we produce food for America and the rest of the world, and 2% of the workforce is involved in agriculture. And I defy you to find anyone who recently said to you, 'It's so horrible I can't get a job as a farmer,' and employment is way up. AI is a great thing. It's a great thing for every industry. Will it create a genius? No. Will it create hits? No. It's a bunch of data with a bunch of computers with a language model attached."</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/gdc-lowers-ticket-prices-streamlines-pass-types-in-festival-of-gaming-reimagination-" target="_self" data-discover="true">GDC lowers ticket prices, streamlines pass types in Festival of Gaming 'reimagination'</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">These followed other comments where he described generative AI as a "backward-looking" technology, unable to excel in a "forward-looking" creative field.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"You have to look at it as a tool set. Our business has been involved with digital tools since its inception," said the CEO of the company soon to release </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Grand Theft Auto VI</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">. "I think we'll probably be able to create a bunch of efficiency, and we're already trying to do that. We're reviewing 200 different opportunities at any given time, but what AI is not going to do—because remember, what AI is, is the combination of big data sets with a bunch of computers within a natural LLM, a large language model. And by definition, a data set is backward-looking, while creativity is forward-looking. To the extent that AI appears to be forward-looking, it is what a predictive model is."&nbsp;</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="&quot;We have a combination of metadata with a parlor trick.&quot;">"We have a combination of metadata with a parlor trick."</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The growing impact and potential of AI technologies have been a topic of </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/devs-are-more-worried-than-ever-that-generative-ai-will-lower-the-quality-of-games">increasing interest and concern for developers</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> in the video game industry. With industry layoffs becoming a recurring occurrence in recent years, some developers are looking to pivot by bringing more AI technologies into the workflow to expand productivity.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/south-australian-game-devs-can-apply-to-new-grants-of-up-to-100-000-aud" target="_self" data-discover="true">South Australian game devs can apply to new grants of up to 100,000 AUD</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The Take-Two CEO made a point of clarifying that AI is a tool for human workers and that it is, in effect, a "parlor trick" that leverages predictive data.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"The reason [AI] is so extraordinary right now is because what we have is a combination of metadata with a parlor trick; we're all going to get used to it," he said. "We're getting really used to it in the same way that if this were 25 years ago and I handed you today's version of Google, you would have been blown away by what it could do for you. But now it's like, 'yeah, I searched again'—this is all very standard, and [AI] will be standard, this is the future of technology."&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Currently, multiple industries across tech, media, and other fields are enduring </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ubisoft-redlynx-says-up-to-60-positions-could-be-cut-in-restructuring-proposal">waves of layoffs</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> (some at </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/2k-confirms-layoffs-at-civilization-developer-firaxis">Zelnick's own company</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">) that have disrupted careers and projects. However, Strauss remained optimistic that the technology would ultimately be helpful and that it would eventually expand employment further.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Contributor</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Alessandro Fillari is a writer/editor who has covered the games, tech, and entertainment industries for more than 12 years. He is based in the San Francisco Bay Area.</span></p></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/take-two-ceo-predicts-genai-will-create-jobs-not-kill-them]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battlefield 6’s Battle Royale Mode Rumored to Shadow-Drop Next Week with Season 1]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/battlefield-6-battle-royale-mode-shadow-drop-next-week-rumour/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/battlefield-6%E2%80%99s-battle-royale-mode-rumored-to-shadow-drop-next-week-with-season-1.1333405/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			<div data-nosnippet="">
		
		<ul>
			<li>0-20%: Unlikely - Lacks credible sources</li>
			<li>21-40%: Questionable - Some concerns remain</li>
			<li>41-60%: Plausible - Reasonable evidence</li>
			<li>61-80%: Probable - Strong evidence</li>
			<li>81-100%: Highly Likely - Multiple reliable sources</li>
		</ul>
	</div>


			
			
			
			<p>A new datamine points from <a href="https://x.com/ModernWarzone/status/1981402959180427611">X (formerly Twitter) user ModernWarzone</a> points to <a href="https://wccftech.com/battlefield-6-battle-royale-mode-details-testing-starts-this-week/">the battle royale mode</a> for Battlefield 6 shadow-dropping next week when the game's Season 1 update arrives on October 28, 2025.</p>



<p>According to ModernWarzone, the new mode which is codenamed "<em>Granite</em>" will be fully revealed first on October 27 with a trailer before it goes live the next day on October 28. It's worth noting that we've heard nothing concrete from EA and Battlefield Studios about when the battle royale mode will arrive, and that it has not been included in any promotional materials for the game's Season 1 roadmap.</p>



<figure><div>
<blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>BREAKING: A new content drop for Battlefield 6 that is NOT Season 1 codenamed “Granite” with release date of October 28th has been datamined from the EA App. 🗓️</p><p>Think it’s safe to say this is the BF6 Battle Royale. 🪂</p><p>Thanks to <a href="https://twitter.com/onebattlefield?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@onebattlefield</a> for sending the info over to me 🫡 <a href="https://t.co/H3xaZpWmne">pic.twitter.com/H3xaZpWmne</a></p></div>— ModernWarzone (@ModernWarzone) <a href="https://twitter.com/ModernWarzone/status/1981402959180427611?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 23, 2025</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>



<p>According to ModernWarzone, this is partly due to EA not wanting to immediately pull focus away from Battlefield 6's core offering, its multiplayer modes. If that's true, then that's likely because the coming battle royale will be free-to-play and likely a separate offering compared to the core Battlefield 6 game. Essentially, it'll be just like how you can play Call of Duty: Warzone for free, but to jump into the multiplayer for the new annual Call of Duty release, you'll have to buy the latest entry.</p>



<p>Just yesterday from the time of this writing, Wccftech and several other media outlets <a href="https://wccftech.com/battlefield-6-season-1-hands-on-preview/">shared hands-on impressions with the Season 1 content set to arrive next week</a>, including the new maps and game modes, the first batch of which arrives on October 28, the second on November 18, and the third on December 9.</p>



<p>The new maps both look stunning and like they'll be solid additions to Battlefield 6, but the new game modes, both the permanent one arriving next week and the limited-time mode coming in November failed to impress, and at least in their current state, are rather stale and boring.</p>



<p>If this battle royale mode does arrive next week, then that certainly gives Season 1 a huge boost compared to what it already has available. </p>



<p>For more on Battlefield 6, <a href="https://wccftech.com/tag/battlefield-6/">check out our dedicated page for the game</a> to catch up on all our coverage so far. There, you'll find our <a href="https://wccftech.com/battlefield-6-pc-performance-benchmarks-wreck-havoc-break-stuff-with-solid-performance-on-all-gpus/">PC benchmarks and optimized settings guide</a>, our guide on <a href="https://wccftech.com/best/the-best-graphics-cards-for-battlefield-6/">which graphics cards are the best for Battlefield 6 at different resolutions</a>, a <a href="https://wccftech.com/how-to/battlefield-6-guide-tips-to-rule-the-battlefield/">general tips guide to help you be a better player</a>, a guide for <a href="https://wccftech.com/how-to/battlefield-6-guide-best-early-weapons-and-loadouts-for-each-class/">the best early weapons and loadouts</a> when for when you've just started playing multiplayer, and if you've been unfortunate enough to have issues with the game on PC, <a href="https://wccftech.com/how-to/battlefield-6-troubleshooting-guide-how-to-fix-common-pc-errors/">our guide on how to solve several common issues for PC users</a>. You can also <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/battlefield-6-battlefield-is-mostly-back/">check out my full review of the game when it launched earlier this month</a>.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> or <a href="https://google.com/preferences/source?q=wccftech.com">add us as a preferred source</a>, to get our news coverage and reviews in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/battlefield-6-battle-royale-mode-shadow-drop-next-week-rumour/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Twin Peaks-inspired spooky private eye puzzler Silver Pines is set to deliver missing musician mystery next year]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/twin-peaks-inspired-spooky-private-eye-puzzler-silver-pines-is-set-to-deliver-missing-musician-mystery-next-year</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/twin-peaks-inspired-spooky-private-eye-puzzler-silver-pines-is-set-to-deliver-missing-musician-mystery-next-year.1333402/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>As well as the chance to shoot some pesky birds</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/silver-pines-lynchian-detective-horror-puzzler-announced-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/silver-pines-lynchian-detective-horror-puzzler-announced-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/silver-pines-lynchian-detective-horror-puzzler-announced-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/silver-pines-lynchian-detective-horror-puzzler-announced-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/silver-pines-lynchian-detective-horror-puzzler-announced-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/silver-pines-lynchian-detective-horror-puzzler-announced-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/silver-pines-lynchian-detective-horror-puzzler-announced-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/silver-pines-lynchian-detective-horror-puzzler-announced-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/silver-pines-lynchian-detective-horror-puzzler-announced-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Team 17</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Watch out. There's a musician mystery afoot. They've gone missing, mysteriously. So says Silver Pines, a Twin Peaks-inspired survival horror puzzler that's set to arrive next year, according to an announcement trailer that's just <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/galaxies-autumn-25-showcase-how-to-watch">barged into my house</a> in a trench coat, waving a gun about and demanding to know whether I did it.</p>
<p>No, I respond calmly, there are no missing musicians around here. For a moment, I fear he might notice the outline of a guitar's headstock buried under the carpet. Hmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmm, he says, as all detective-ish types do. Hmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmm...</p>
<!--more-->

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Silver Pines | Announce Trailer" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/y_PVwrQivKE?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Silver Pines | Announce Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/y_PVwrQivKE?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/y_PVwrQivKE?autoplay=1" title="Silver Pines | Announce Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=y_PVwrQivKE" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>


<p>I try to distract him by asking for more information about Silver Pines. It's by developers Wych Elm, he says. You must roam the small town filled with horrors to survive, doing puzzles to unlock different areas and managing your resources. Arrrrrrggghhhhhh, I scream, resource management! Shhhhh, he replies, let me read you the plot synopsis to calm you down:</p>
<blockquote>Private investigator Red Walker finds himself in Silver Pines, a place half-abandoned, half-forgotten, in the middle of nowhere on a job to track down vanished musician Eddie Velvet. As the case begins to reveal a dark past, Walker soon slips into a strange and nightmarish descent beyond his control.</blockquote>
<p>The exploration's a bit Metroidvaniay, he claims, and you'll need to find better tools and weapons to open up more bits. Ok, I reply, the roaming around a small town as a moody investigator clearly going through some shit intrigues me, even if this certainly isn't pitching itself to be as <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/disco-elysium">Disco Elysium</a>y in an RPG sense as my brain sort of wishes it was.</p><p>It's set to arrive at some point in 2026, he says, and you can wishlist it on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2333000/Silver_Pines/">Steam</a>. Nice, I respond, hoping the ensuing awkward silence will drive him away. He turns towards the door, takes a few steps, and brutally stubs his toe on the telltale head. Watch out, I whisper as he writhes on the floor.</p>

        </div>

      </article>




        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/twin-peaks-inspired-spooky-private-eye-puzzler-silver-pines-is-set-to-deliver-missing-musician-mystery-next-year]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bojack-style band management sim Rockbeasts gets a fresh trailer which asks existential questions I was afraid to]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/bojack-style-band-management-sim-rockbeasts-gets-a-fresh-trailer-which-asks-existential-questions-i-was-afraid-to</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/bojack-style-band-management-sim-rockbeasts-gets-a-fresh-trailer-which-asks-existential-questions-i-was-afraid-to.1333399/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Oh, and a cat guy sings his hairball-filled lungs out</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/rockbeasts-preview-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/rockbeasts-preview-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/rockbeasts-preview-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/rockbeasts-preview-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/rockbeasts-preview-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/rockbeasts-preview-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/rockbeasts-preview-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/rockbeasts-preview-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/rockbeasts-preview-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Lichthund</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Looking back on it, when I <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/rockbeasts-is-about-managing-an-animal-band-in-a-bojack-style-world-but-itll-need-to-do-more-than-horse-around">played a preview build</a> of zoological band management game <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/rockbeasts">Rockbeasts</a> earlier this year, I think I went along with it a bit too easily. I didn't question why people were now animals, how those animals had acquired the opposable thumbs necessary to play Black Sabbath riffs, or whether the bulldog version of Simon Cowell I signed up with at the end might have any ulterior motives.</p>
<p>Luckily, the clearly Bojack Horseman-inspired game about trying to get some musicians you've dubbed Pearl Spam to their gig on time, so they can jam out in their silly hats, has a gotten a fresh trailer at today's <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/galaxies-autumn-25-showcase-how-to-watch">Galaxies showcase</a> that asks some of those questions for me.</p>
<!--more-->

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="ROCKBEASTS | Gameplay Trailer 2" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/DV4ULIZ6qyw?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>ROCKBEASTS | Gameplay Trailer 2</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/DV4ULIZ6qyw?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/DV4ULIZ6qyw?autoplay=1" title="ROCKBEASTS | Gameplay Trailer 2">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DV4ULIZ6qyw" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>


<p>I'll admit, I didn't think too hard about the whole furry angle. Mainly because I was afraid of potential retaliation from the unaccountable security services they operate in order to support their efforts to bend the will of the world to their own greedy purposes. Actually, wait, maybe I'm getting them mixed up with the billionaires.</p><p>Either way, this trailer offers a few quick peeks at stuff and scenes that weren't in the opening chapter of developers Lichthund's game that I've played. I, regretfully, am yet to pick a colour for a guitar or meet the llama version of Lemmy from Motorhead. I did, however, meet the cat guy who sings towards the end. He was cool. Here's an excerpt from my musings:</p>
<blockquote>All in all, there’s potential here, and some indication in the intro - which scored big GTA 4 nostalgia points with me by having Iggy Pop host a rock radio station - that the events of you guiding the band to superstardom in the 90s will echo into what they’re up to nearer the present day. If Rockbeasts is to properly sell out stadiums, though, it’ll have to prove it’s more than just a tribute band.</blockquote>
<p>Rockbeasts remains release dateless for now, but you can wishlist it on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1445880/ROCKBEASTS/">Steam</a> if you're so inclined.</p>

        </div>

      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/bojack-style-band-management-sim-rockbeasts-gets-a-fresh-trailer-which-asks-existential-questions-i-was-afraid-to]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[All Video Game Controllers Need Back Paddles, Damn It]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/god-of-war-20th-anniversary-dualsense-edge-controller-2000638652</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/all-video-game-controllers-need-back-paddles-damn-it.1333396/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><span>When I </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/dualsense-edge-controller-playstation-5-review-kotaku-1850018508"><span>agreed to review the DualSense Edge</span></a><span> for this here </span><i><span>Kotaku </span></i><span>period com, I didn’t know I was getting ready to break my brain from decades of video game muscle memory habits. I hadn’t used a modular controller before, and I wanted to approach the PS5 premium controller from the perspective of someone who maybe didn’t see what all the fuss was about. Every video game I play already has button assignments for any action I could do. What was the point of putting two extras on the back? But once I saw the light, it became nearly impossible for me to go back to a standard DualSense, and when I do hold one of the default controllers, I feel my fingers scratching at the back for back paddles that are no longer there.</span></p> <p><span>This came up today because Sony is selling a </span><a href="https://direct.playstation.com/en-us/buy-accessories/dualsense-wireless-controller-god-of-war-20th-anniversary-limited-edition"><i><span>God of War </span></i><span>20th anniversary DualSense controller</span></a><span> stylized to look like the titular god Kratos’ ash-white skin and blood-red tattoos. I like the design of the controller a lot, and even if I didn’t love </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/god-of-war-ragnarok-review-release-date-ps4-ps5-spear-1849734382"><i><span>Ragnarök</span></i></a> <span>(the excellent </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/god-of-war-ragnarok-valhalla-dlc-review-1851097244"><i><span>Valhalla </span></i><span>DLC</span></a><span> really brought me around on it, though), Kratos still occupies a cozy little place in my heart. In another life, I would have scooped it up, even at the whopping $85 price point. But that hefty chunk of change gave me pause. That’s grocery money for a controller that, in all likelihood, I wasn’t going to use. I’ve become so accustomed to having back paddles after two years of playing games with my DualSense Edge that the standard PS5 controller feels almost like a toy in my hands. So if I did buy this Kratos-themed controller, it would probably just be a display item. And that’s a pretty expensive thing to stick on shelf space I don’t have here in the Big Apple.</span></p>

 <p><span>I’ve bought controllers I don’t use before. I own an Xbox Pride controller that sits on my shelf next to all my </span><i><span>Mass Effect </span></i><span>stuff because </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/lgbtq-games-mass-effect-romance-options-overwatch-pride-1850586480"><span>Kaidan Alenko made me gay as a teenager</span></a><span>. But that was a special case where I saw something covered in rainbows and reacted accordingly. Nowadays, I default to my DualSense Edge whenever I can, so I’m not just picky with my money, I’m picky with my controllers. The Edge isn’t even the best version of a modular controller, as it’s pretty limited compared to its contemporaries like the Xbox Elite, but it has rewired my brain to reach for back paddles in shooters and action games.</span></p>

 <p><span>The moment it all changed for me was when I was testing the Edge for our review while playing </span><i><span>Overwatch 2</span></i><span>. As I described in my review, a Pharah was flying behind my team’s backline and shooting rockets down upon my helpless supports. As Soldier: 76, I reloaded while turning around to shoot down my airborne foe. I had mapped the square button to the right paddle and could turn the right analog stick with my thumb to change where I was facing, rather than having to pick between the two actions. That split-second difference saved me from getting blown up, and it was all thanks to this bougie-ass controller. It’s such a small change, but I’ve gotten so used to having the option that my brain defaults to it now. I usually have jump mapped to the left paddle and either reload or dodge on the right. For the longest time, I would have to remap buttons in action games to the default </span><i><span>Devil May Cry </span></i><span>control scheme because I spent so much time playing the old PS2 games that the layout had hardwired itself into my brain. The circle button is the dodge button, right? It’s supposed to be! Now, my hands naturally search for a back paddle to move out of the way. Even when I’m playing games on my Switch 2 like </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-legends-za-review-switch-2-bugs-performance-2000637719"><i><span>Pokémon Legends: Z-A</span></i></a><span>, I’m wishing I had an easy dodge button on the back of my Joy-Cons.</span></p> <p><span>I know it’s an unreasonable ask, but I would be so much more inclined to buy these special controllers if Sony made Edge variants, so I didn’t feel like I was sacrificing function for the sake of the aesthetic. And now it’s hard for me to justify buying collector’s items when my tiny apartment only has so much room. You think I didn’t want that </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/new-ps5-controller-last-of-us-dualsense-ugly-price-sony-1851768135"><span>kinda dumb-looking </span><i><span>Last of Us </span></i><span>controller</span></a><span>? Although now that I’m looking at it, I probably could have fit it on my </span><i><span>TLOU </span></i><span>shelf next to the Joel statue. Actually, never mind, I looked at the price again. Maybe I should look into modding these controllers myself. There’s gotta be some sicko out there who’s willing to mess with all the circuitry and put these back paddles on the Kratos controller.</span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/god-of-war-20th-anniversary-dualsense-edge-controller-2000638652]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kingdom Come Deliverance 2’s Third Story DLC Arrives Next Month]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/kingdom-come-deliverance-2s-third-story-dlc-arrives-next-month/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/kingdom-come-deliverance-2%E2%80%99s-third-story-dlc-arrives-next-month.1333393/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Deep Silver has announced that Kingdom Come Deliverance 2’s third story DLC, Mysteria Ecclesiae, will arrive on November 11, 2025, for PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X/S, and PC. The new expansion will take players to Sedletz Monastery, where they will “investigate a deadly mystery”. The DLC will introduce a brand-new storyline to the game, featuring fresh quests, interesting characters, and endings you will not see coming. </p>



<h2 id="h-henry-plays-a-detective-in-kingdom-come-deliverance-2-s-mysteria-ecclesiae-dlc">Henry Plays a Detective in Kingdom Come Deliverance 2’s Mysteria Ecclesiae DLC</h2>



<figure></figure>



<p>In Kingdom Come Deliverance 2’s Mysteria Ecclesiae DLC, players will see Henry play a detective as he unravels the secrets of a quarantined monastery. Henry is trying to figure out the cause behind the sudden disease outbreak, which will be told through a new cinematic quest. </p>



<p>The new area, Sedletz Monastery, will be unlocked with the expansion and will remain accessible even after completing the DLC. The “new level features a historically accurate new location that’s rich in detail and life.” The DLC will also include a new outfit, weapons, potions, and books that will help expand Henry’s knowledge and abilities. Interested readers can check out the latest <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oRdzdd8rX-8" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">trailer</a> below: </p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Kingdom Come Deliverance II - Mysteria Ecclesiae DLC Announce Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/oRdzdd8rX-8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>Talking about DLCs, KCD 2’s Legacy of the Forge expansion arrived <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/kingdom-come-deliverance-2s-legacy-of-the-forge-expansion-release/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">last month</a>, where players got to learn more about their father’s legacy as a blacksmith. While reliving these memories, the players complete an ambitious masterpiece their father once worked on. Moreover, the expansion also introduced a home customisation system with over 100 million combinations to personalise your forge, private quarters, and its surroundings.</p>



<p>In other news, Kingdom Come Deliverance could reportedly receive an upgrade ‘<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/kingdom-come-deliverance-upgrade-could-come/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">early next year</a>‘. Additionally, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/today-tom-mckay-last-day-kingdom-come/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Tom McKay’s last day </a>in the Kingdom Come booth has come and gone. Are you going to play Kingdom Come Deliverance 2’s third DLC, Mysteria Ecclesiae? Let us know through the official&nbsp;Insider Gaming&nbsp;<a href="https://t.co/dLOFaEGOMl" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Discord</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-battle-royale-datamine/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> a new Battlefield 6 datamine revealing that battle royale is arriving on October 28</a>.&nbsp;Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/kingdom-come-deliverance-2s-third-story-dlc-arrives-next-month/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tormented Souls 2 Review]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/tormented-souls-2-review</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/tormented-souls-2-review.1333390/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">With its unsettling backdrops and detailed worldbuilding, Tormented Souls 2 may <em>look </em>like a contemporary horror game, but don't let that modern dressing fool you. At its core beats the blackened heart of stone-cold classics like Resident Evil and Silent Hill, with all the treats — and tricks — that both endeared me to and enraged me about these formulaic survival horror games when they first gained popularity. Fixed camera angles? Check. Tank controls? Check. Insanely complex puzzles and an even more bizarre story, complete with cheesy dialogue and a manual save system? Check, check, check, and check. It makes Tormented Souls 2 a surprisingly faithful homage, bringing back all the stuff I loved about old survival horror games… as well as many of the things I loved to hate.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Tormented Souls 2 picks up right after the events of its 2021 predecessor, but you don't have to have met the Walker sisters before to make sense of this sequel. That’s partly because it tells a standalone story, and partly because it's so fantastical that nothing makes sense anyway. Sure, you may have questions about Caroline's fetching eyepatch, but all you really need to know is she’s searching for answers about her little sister Anna's terrifying visions and reality-bending drawings. For reasons that seem to exist exclusively in schlocky horror tales, that answer apparently sits somewhere in the depths of a creepy convent nestled in a far-flung location. </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Before Caroline even gets the chance to shrug off her (exceedingly 90s) leather jacket, though, Anna goes missing, and it's up to the older sibling to both find her sister and figure out what the hell is going on before it's too late… with an emphasis on the “hell” bit, naturally. As stories go, it's not unique, no, but the twists and turns of Tormented Souls 2's roughly 20-hour campaign are delightfully over-the-top in the same way the original Resident Evil games are. It’s packed with cheesy dialogue, curious flavor text, and some truly bizarre encounters I couldn’t help but smile at. Caroline's stay in the remote town of Villa Hess will take you to a number of wonderfully grim places, including a processing plant, spooky school, abandoned mall, bunker, and the sprawling convent you start off in, keeping the creepy environments feeling fresh.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">And those environments are so detailed! Stuffed with interest and plenty of lore, Villa Hess and its surroundings are such fascinating, atmospheric places to explore. You never know when a key item or a helpful tool may be secreted away in a hidden room somewhere, so it's always best to keep your curiosity piqued. While your investigation is sometimes interrupted by a bladed demon or shambling zombie, you'll find that enemies have a tendency to stay dead in Tormented Souls 2 — once you've cleared out an area, you're usually left to explore at your leisure. With little more than a flickering candle to guide the way, though, it's a little too easy to miss things; I've been caught out a couple of times by overlooking a key clue or item, even in areas I <em>thought</em> I'd examined pretty closely.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As is seemingly the law for old-school survival horror, the more you play, the more you'll find yourself opening up new routes to old places, providing access to rooms and entire areas that were previously blocked off. I suspect the backtracking will irk some — there's a lot of it, particularly early on — but as the levels and fetch-quests are well-designed and usually rewarding, I couldn't begrudge it. That said, there's a reason fixed camera angles and tank controls are considered relics of the past. I grew up playing the games Tormented Souls 2 pays homage to (Resident Evil, Silent Hill 3, Parasite Eve, Alone in the Dark), but moving around Villa Hess is frustrating even when there isn't a demon on your tail, with tight corridors and dead ends that make getting from one side of a building to the other unduly long-winded. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Add in Caroline's fear of the dark: she'll freeze and start to hyperventilate if plunged into darkness for even a split second, dying completely if you leave her there too long. You can’t even put away your lighter to shatter a porcelain pot or smash open a wooden crate unless there's an ambient light source nearby… which there very often isn't. The lighter sure does add to the atmosphere, though, which is almost continually tense and unnerving. As the primary source of light quite often, you'll have to proactively step into a room to illuminate what, if anything, is hiding in the shadows, which inevitably means unwittingly getting up close and personal with the denizens skulking around the place. </p><div data-cy="playlist-view-trigger"><p><h3 data-cy="title3">Vikki's List of Classic Horror Games That Deserve a Remake</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">It all falls apart a bit when there <em>is</em> something hiding in the dark, though. Tormented Souls 2's combat isn't clumsy as much as it is enraging. The reliance on Caroline's lighter means you're often unarmed when something lunges at you, and the fixed camera angles and stiff character movement make it harder than it should be to retreat or create a little distance. Caroline protects herself with a range of acquired and improvised weapons, from a shotgun to a nail gun. Some of them can be upgraded to improve their rate of fire or reload speed, but they're still slow to use and difficult to wield accurately in a panic. I know it's kind of a genre convention to ensure we feel weak and underpowered, but this could've been achieved through scarcer ammo or by throwing more enemies at us; inefficient weapons and fixed cameras don't ramp up the tension as much as snap the immersion entirely. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Perhaps unsurprisingly, that jankiness follows you into boss fights. One of the first you'll encounter, a giant nun, stomps around the room trying to batter you with a gigantic steel cross. But in that one single room, there are at least <em>three</em> different fixed camera angles, which means you may find yourself inadvertently sprinting <em>towards</em> your foe if the camera shifts while trying to put distance between you. This wouldn't be so bad if your shotgun held more than two shots at a time or if the nun flinched with each hit, but she'll keep galloping like an aggravated rhino, which made the camera feel like the real boss I was fighting. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Thankfully, for every underwhelming boss fight you're forced to endure, you'll happen across a good half-dozen puzzles which confuse and delight in equal measure. I never felt closer to an old Resident Evil or Silent Hill game than trying to figure out how to open a door, or decode a cipher, or prise open the jaws of a dead shark for reasons I still don't quite understand. Often deeply cryptic, maddeningly illogical, or completely unsolvable because I stupidly missed a clue somewhere, these puzzles were exactly what I want from a game like this, all the way down to the mini-puzzles that ask you to combine specific items in your inventory. Yes, I'll admit one or two (or five) brain teasers truly stumped me for an embarrassing amount of time, but if that isn't old-school survival horror, then what is?</p></section><div data-cy="verdict"><h3 data-cy="title3">Verdict</h3><p data-cy="article-verdict-paragraph">If you're nostalgic for the survival horror games of old, Tormented Souls 2 can provide a modern-looking trip down memory lane, with all the good and bad that brings. It has a tense atmosphere to soak up and some gorgeously spooky locations to explore, but you’ll need to push through janky combat and a bit of backtracking to enjoy them. Its esoteric puzzles really test your brainpower in a way that could sometimes frustrate, but also delighted the part of me that missed smashing key items together to see what would happen. There's a lot to enjoy here, as well as plenty that perhaps should have remained in the past, but Tormented Souls 2 still manages to stand as an entertaining callback to the adventures that made contemporary horror gaming what it is.&nbsp;</p></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/tormented-souls-2-review]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fallout: New Vegas 15th Anniversary Bundle Announced on Fallout Day — Here Are the Contents]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/fallout-new-vegas-15th-anniversary-bundle-announced-on-fallout-day-here-are-the-contents</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fallout-new-vegas-15th-anniversary-bundle-announced-on-fallout-day-%E2%80%94-here-are-the-contents.1333387/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Bethesda has used Fallout Day to announce the Fallout: New Vegas 15th Anniversary Bundle, which celebrates Obsidian’s much-loved post-apocalyptic role-playing game turning 15 years old.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">This edition will be available for pre-order on October 23 via the Bethesda Gear Store, and includes:</p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Fallout: New Vegas: Ultimate Edition PC Code</li><li>Victor Statue (8" PVC): The friendly Securitron stands tall and is ready to roll</li><li>Doc Mitchell’s Evaluation Cards (8x8 cardstock set): Straight from your first moments in Goodsprings, a true piece of New Vegas history</li><li>Vault Boy Enamel Pin (1.5"): Vault Boy stacks the odds with poker chips in hand</li><li>Mojave Express Patch (3.5" × 1.9"): Woven, iron-on, and full of wasteland charm</li><li>NCR Recon Patch (3.25" × 3.5"): Woven, iron-on insignia of the New California Republic’s finest</li><li>Collector’s Big Box: A throwback-style display box created exclusively for the anniversary</li></ul><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/10/23/screenshot-2025-10-23-133610-1761223381918.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">The Fallout: New Vegas 15th Anniversary Bundle.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">There was no mention made during the Fallout Day broadcast of a Fallout: New Vegas remaster, which some (<a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/remaster-new-vegas-boss-danny-trejo-calls-on-bethesda-to-give-fallout-fans-what-they-really-want">including Danny Trejo!</a>) have called on Bethesda to develop. Indeed, there were no new Fallout games announced at all. Find out <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/fallout-day-2025-everything-announced-live">everything announced during the Fallout Day broadcast here</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">2010’s Fallout: New Vegas still lives long in the memory, and interest in it is surging as a result of Fallout Season 2, which will head to New Vegas for Season 2 in December. Indeed, there are all sorts of rumors floating around about potential Fallout remakes now that The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion Remastered is out the door (<a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/oblivion-remaster-fallout-3-remaster-and-more-leaked-from-microsoft-document"><u>Fallout 3 Remastered was leaked back in 2023</u></a>, but those plans may have changed). And we know Bethesda wants to eventually get to <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/fallout-5"><u>Fallout 5</u></a>, albeit after <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/the-elder-scrolls-vi"><u>The Elder Scrolls 6</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The last we heard on Fallout 5, by the way, was back in June 2024, when <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/bethesda-doesnt-feel-the-need-to-rush-fallout-5-in-the-wake-of-tv-shows-success"><u>Bethesda Softworks head Todd Howard said he wasn’t interested in rushing it out the door</u></a>. Howard opened up about the future of the hit post-apocalyptic RPG series during <a href="https://youtu.be/2ew8LQFGNWU?si=Ua6SywsuPtdIr0yv" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>an interview with YouTube content creator MrMattyPlays</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"For other Fallout games in the future, you know, obviously I can’t talk about those right now, but I would say, sort of rushing through them, or we kind of need to get stuff out that is different than the work we’re doing in 76… we don’t feel like we need to rush any of that," he said. "The Fallout TV show fills a certain niche in terms of the franchise and storytelling."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The last mainline Fallout game was Fallout 4, which was released in 2015. DLC content for the entry was steadily released for PC and consoles over the next year, and in 2018, Bethesda launched its multiplayer-centered offshoot, Fallout 76. While fans slowly flocked to the West Virginia-set open-world RPG, it wasn’t until the premiere of Prime Video’s Fallout TV show that the Bethesda series leveled up in terms of attention.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Still, Howard wouldn't budge when it came to desires for a substantial video game release. For him, it comes down to wanting to treat Bethesda's franchises with care.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"Totally get the desire for a new kind of mainline single-player game," he said. "And look, those things take time. I don’t think it’s bad for people to miss things. We just want to get it right and make sure that everything we’re doing in a franchise, whether it’s Elder Scrolls, Fallout, or now Starfield, that those become meaningful moments for everybody who loved these franchises as much as we do."</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is Director, News at IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/fallout-new-vegas-15th-anniversary-bundle-announced-on-fallout-day-here-are-the-contents]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fallout 76 Is Finally Getting Native Versions for Xbox Series X and S and PS5 Early 2026]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/fallout-76-is-finally-getting-native-versions-for-xbox-series-x-and-s-and-ps5-early-2026</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fallout-76-is-finally-getting-native-versions-for-xbox-series-x-and-s-and-ps5-early-2026.1333381/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">"Optimizations” coming for PS4 and Xbox One players, too.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Bethesda has announced native versions of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/fallout-76">Fallout 76</a> are coming to Xbox Series X and S and PlayStation 5 early 2026.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The announcement came as part of Bethesda's Fallout Day broadcast, which also brought news that “optimizations” are coming for PlayStation 4 and Xbox One players, too. Bethesda didn't reveal any more info on what these new versions of Fallout 76 actually do.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">However, Bethesda did use Fallout Day to show more of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/walton-goggins-is-set-to-play-the-ghoul-from-the-fallout-tv-show-in-fallout-76-but-how-does-the-character-fit-in-the-fallout-76-timeline">Fallout 76’s Burning Springs update</a>, which is due out December 2, 2025. This is the big update that expands the map to include a brand-new arid region in Ohio, where players will encounter the raider-like supermutant Rust King, battle desert Deathclaws, and join up with friends in two new public events.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">But the headline here is the new bounty hunting system, which is led by The Ghoul from the Fallout TV show. Actor Walton Goggins has reprised his role for Fallout 76 with new voice work. It’s a well-timed update, given Season 2 of the Fallout TV show is set to him Prime Video in December.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Timeline wise (both Fallout 76 and the Fallout TV show are canon), it turns out The Ghoul set up shop in Ohio to run a bounty hunting operation before the post-apocalyptic events of the Fallout TV series, which takes place after all the Fallout games.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s worth remembering where we are in the overall Fallout timeline: the TV show is set in the year 2296, Fallout 4 takes place in the year 2287, while Fallout: New Vegas is set in the year 2281, a full 15 years prior to the events of the show.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The Fallout 76 timeline, meanwhile, begins in 2102, on October 23, known as Reclamation Day. It is the earliest game in the Fallout franchise, set 25 years after the Great War of 2077, when nuclear bombs devastated the Earth. We know from Season 1 of the Fallout TV show that The Ghoul has survived for over 200 years out in the wasteland. Now we know some of what he was up to.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">For more, check out <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/fallout-day-2025-everything-announced-updating-live">everything announced during the Fallout Day broadcast</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is Director, News at IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/fallout-76-is-finally-getting-native-versions-for-xbox-series-x-and-s-and-ps5-early-2026]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Todd Howard Reassures Fallout Fans as Fallout Day 2025 Ends Without a Brand New Game Reveal: 'Just Know We Are Working on Even More']]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/todd-howard-reassures-fallout-fans-as-fallout-day-2025-ends-without-a-brand-new-game-reveal-just-know-we-are-working-on-even-more</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/todd-howard-reassures-fallout-fans-as-fallout-day-2025-ends-without-a-brand-new-game-reveal-just-know-we-are-working-on-even-more.1333378/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Bombshells are coming.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Fallout Day 2025 has come to an end without the announcement of any new Fallout video games. Yes, there’s <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/bethesda-announces-fallout-4-anniversary-edition-confirms-nintendo-switch-2-version-for-2026">a new version of Fallout 4</a>, a <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/fallout-new-vegas-15th-anniversary-bundle-announced-on-fallout-day-here-are-the-contents">new Fallout: New Vegas bundle</a>, and new content for Fallout Shelter and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/fallout-76-is-finally-getting-native-versions-for-xbox-series-x-and-s-and-ps5-early-2026">Fallout 76</a>. But there was no word on any Fallout remasters, which some had hoped for, or — less likely — Fallout 5.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">At the end of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/fallout-day-2025-everything-announced-updating-live">the Fallout Day broadcast</a>, Bethesda design chief Todd Howard acknowledged that Fallout fans were probably left a little disappointed by this, and promised that the developer is working on “even more” Fallout. What that means exactly is anyone’s guess, but Howard did say Bethesda is looking forward to showing fans what it’s cooking.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/10/23/gettyimages-971146114-1761227333315.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Todd Howard introduces Fallout 76 during the Microsoft Xbox E3 briefing in 2018. Photo by Christian Petersen/Getty Images.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Here’s the quote from Todd Howard:</p><blockquote>Even though I am recording this — it’s not live — and I’m probably watching myself right now from my desk and I’m reading your chat and these… that thing you want and this other thing you want… Hey, we read it all. Just know we are working on even more. We are looking forward to the day when we can share that with everybody.</blockquote><p data-cy="paragraph">Ahead of Fallout Day, Hollywood star Danny Trejo, who played <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/fallout-new-vegas/Raul_Tejada"><u>Raul Alfonso Tejada</u></a>, a Ghoul companion, in the much-loved Fallout: New Vegas, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/remaster-new-vegas-boss-danny-trejo-calls-on-bethesda-to-give-fallout-fans-what-they-really-want">called on Bethesda to remaster the game</a>. It’s a sentiment shared by many Fallout fans, especially given the surge in interest following the breakout Fallout TV show, which heads to New Vegas for Season 2 in December.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Indeed, there are all sorts of rumors floating around about potential Fallout remakes now that The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion Remastered is out the door (<a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/oblivion-remaster-fallout-3-remaster-and-more-leaked-from-microsoft-document"><u>Fallout 3 Remastered was leaked back in 2023</u></a>, but those plans may have changed). And we know Bethesda wants to eventually get to<a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/fallout-5"> <u>Fallout 5</u></a>, albeit after<a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/the-elder-scrolls-vi"> <u>The Elder Scrolls 6</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The last we heard on Fallout 5, by the way, was back in June 2024, when<a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/bethesda-doesnt-feel-the-need-to-rush-fallout-5-in-the-wake-of-tv-shows-success"> <u>Todd Howard said he wasn’t interested in rushing it out the door</u></a>. Howard opened up about the future of the hit post-apocalyptic RPG series during<a href="https://youtu.be/2ew8LQFGNWU?si=Ua6SywsuPtdIr0yv" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"> <u>an interview with YouTube content creator MrMattyPlays</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"For other Fallout games in the future, you know, obviously I can’t talk about those right now, but I would say, sort of rushing through them, or we kind of need to get stuff out that is different than the work we’re doing in 76… we don’t feel like we need to rush any of that," he said. "The Fallout TV show fills a certain niche in terms of the franchise and storytelling."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The last mainline Fallout game was Fallout 4, which was released in 2015. DLC content for the entry was steadily released for PC and consoles over the next year, and in 2018, Bethesda launched its multiplayer-centered offshoot, Fallout 76. While fans slowly flocked to the West Virginia-set open-world RPG, it wasn’t until the premiere of Prime Video’s Fallout TV show that the Bethesda series leveled up in terms of attention.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Still, Howard wouldn't budge when it came to desires for a substantial video game release. For him, it comes down to wanting to treat Bethesda's franchises with care.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"Totally get the desire for a new kind of mainline single-player game," he said. "And look, those things take time. I don’t think it’s bad for people to miss things. We just want to get it right and make sure that everything we’re doing in a franchise, whether it’s Elder Scrolls, Fallout, or now Starfield, that those become meaningful moments for everybody who loved these franchises as much as we do."</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is Director, News at IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/todd-howard-reassures-fallout-fans-as-fallout-day-2025-ends-without-a-brand-new-game-reveal-just-know-we-are-working-on-even-more]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MOUSE: P.I. for Hire launches March 19, 2026]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/10/mouse-pi-for-hire-launches-march-19-2026</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mouse-p-i-for-hire-launches-march-19-2026.1333375/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>1930s noir cartoon-inspired first-person shooter dated.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>1930s noir cartoon-inspired first-person <a title="Genres > Shooter [4,306 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/shooter">shooter</a> <em><a title="Games > MOUSE: P.I. for Hire [6 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/mouse-pi-for-hire">MOUSE: P.I. for Hire</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [10,657 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [8,134 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [28,463 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox One [14,271 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch [17,857 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [24,599 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2416450/MOUSE_PI_For_Hire/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> on March 19, 2026, <a title="Companies > PlaySide Publishing [5 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/playside-studios/playside-publishing">PlaySide Publishing</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Fumi Games [5 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/fumi-games">Fumi Games</a> announced. <span id="more-1001530"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via PlaySide Publishing:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>MOUSE: P.I. for Hire</em> is a gritty, noir-fueled first-person shooter that draws inspiration from the classic cartoons of the 1930s. The monochromatic visual style of hand-drawn rubber hose animation and retro jazz soundtrack are created with the same techniques of the era. As Private Investigator Jack Pepper, you will discover that a corrupt city full of crooks and danger is just a taste of things to come; explore the noir-inspired city teeming with heavily armed gangs, mobs, and characters from the darkside to uncover the secrets within Mouseburg.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Solve the <a title="Games > Myst (2020) [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/myst-2020">Myst</a>ery</strong> – Meet Private Investigator Jack Pepper, once a war hero, now a detective in a world where danger lurks in the smallest mouse hole. His journey starts with a seemingly cliche damsel in distress, but as P.I. Pepper begins to scratch the surface of Mouseburg’s seedy underbelly, his journey for justice quickly spirals into a complex web of intrigue, involving murder, corruption, and the unlikeliest of enemies.</li><li><strong>Power-ups for Any Playstyle</strong> – Discover and combine powerful upgrades with comical weapons to knock-down, slash, stomp and blow apart enemies in creative and violent ways, as Pepper ventures through non-linear maps trying to thwart the takeover by corrupt politicians. <a title="Companies > Enhance [33 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/enhance">Enhance</a> melee combat with a can of Spike-D Spinach, extend aerial traversal with a Helicopter, or even attach your mouse tail to a Grappling Hook to rapidly ascend across platforms and more!</li><li><strong>Lock, Load, and Loot</strong> – From crackling tommy guns to explosive firepower, each tool in Pepper’s arsenal is designed to bring out the noir grit and cartoon chaos using an array of classic yet creatively twisted weaponry in epic fights and boss battles with comical demises. Encounter a mischievous and disturbed cast of big bads as Pepper takes the gritty journey to the dark side of town. Playful weaponry and a distinctive health display, coupled with enemies behaving like cartoon characters, add a lighthearted twist to traditional <a title="Genres > First-Person Shooter [2,809 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/shooter/fps">first-person shooter game</a>play.</li><li><strong>A City of Danger</strong> – Explore a diverse city playground, from the dark city streets of Mouseburg, to a noir film studio and casinos, to the Marina port and dock district, vast underground sewers and swamp marshlands. Beware what lurks beneath the surface! Loot collectibles and clues, play mini-games and fight through the city’s towns, alleyways, and more.</li></ul><!-- AD: content -->
        </blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="MOUSE: P.I. For Hire | Official Release Date Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/IlwZMgDK-kQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/10/mouse-pi-for-hire-launches-march-19-2026]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rockbeasts ‘Gameplay’ trailer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/10/rockbeasts-gameplay-trailer</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/rockbeasts-%E2%80%98gameplay%E2%80%99-trailer.1333369/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>New look at the story-driven band management RPG.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Team17 [202 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/team17">Team17</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Lichthund [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/lichthund">Lichthund</a> have released a new gameplay trailer for story-driven band management RPG <em><a title="Games > Rockbeasts [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/rockbeasts">Rockbeasts</a></em>. <span id="more-1001528"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Team17:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Lead a band of misfits on a roller-coaster ride to stardom in the age of MTV, rock anthems, and bad haircuts. <em>Rockbeasts</em> is a story-driven, <a title="Genres > RPG [17,722 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg">role-playing</a> <a title="Genres > Management [34 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/management">management game</a> that puts you in the shoes of a manager of an up-and-coming rock band. Your job—take them to the top.</p><p>A dark comedy story, crafted by the writer of <em>The Witcher 3: Wild Hunt</em>, <em><a title="Games > Cyberpunk 2077 [73 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/cyberpunk-2077">Cyberpunk 2077</a></em>, and <em><a title="Games > The Blood of Dawnwalker [6 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/the-blood-of-dawnwalker">The Blood of Dawnwalker</a></em>. <em>Rockbeasts</em> is a role-playing management game that puts you in the shoes of a manager in the age of MTV, rock anthems, and bad haircuts</p><p><strong>Rock and Roll Band <a title="Series > Mana [17 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/series/mana">Mana</a>ger</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>You’re changing the world of music. Your band’s tracks are the kind of art that redefines genres. That’s why you signed with a label that cares about creative freedom, right? You didn’t become sellouts, did you?</p><p>The road to success is a tricky one, and being a manager is a complex task. Will you help your band become rock rebels or sellouts? The choice is not always easy. <em>Rockbeasts</em> is set in the 90s United States, a time of grunge rock, raging capitalism, and music television.</p><p><strong>Coffee and Cigarettes for Breakfast</strong></p><p>“A kid once said to me ‘do you get hangovers?’ I said, ‘to get hangovers you have to stop drinking.” – Lemmy Kilmister</p><p>Somebody’s gotta make sure this bunch of misfits get ready for the gig. That’s where you come in. Make sure they get it together. There’s real potential here, but you’re gonna have to be the one that makes sure they make it through each week with a half-decent meal and a working amp.</p><p>strong&gt;Don’t Stop Me Now</p><p>“I won’t be a rock star. I will be a legend.” – Freddie Mercury</p><p>Pick the venue, prep the set and make sure it all goes according to plan. Pull it off and the band might just finally take those first steps to fame and glory. Sure, this one was in a grimy basement, but even the rock legends had to start somewhere, right?</p><p><strong>Encore</strong></p><p>We drew over 100 characters and 90 locations just for you! <em>Rockbeasts</em> is no EP, it’s a full double LP.</p><p>Every one of those characters is real, the choices you make will impact them. Your band members will change in time and so will your relationship with them.</p><p>In <em>Rockbeasts</em>, the tough choices as manager will be yours. Write your own rockstar legend where your decisions will shape the story.</p><p>Featuring voice actors from games including <em><a title="Games > Baldur's Gate III [27 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/baldurs-gate-iii">Baldur’s Gate III</a></em>, <em>Cyberpunk 2077</em>, <em>Horizon Zero Dawn</em>, <em><a title="Platforms > Meta [159 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/meta">Meta</a>phor ReFantazio</em>, <em><a title="Games > Alan Wake II [20 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/alan-wake-ii">Alan Wake II</a></em>, and more.</p></blockquote><p><em>Rockbeasts</em> is due out for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [10,657 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [8,134 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch [17,857 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [24,599 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1445880/Rockbeasts/" target="_blank">Steam</a> in 2025.</p><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Gameplay Trailer #2</span></h2><p><iframe title="ROCKBEASTS | Gameplay Trailer 2" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/DV4ULIZ6qyw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/10/rockbeasts-gameplay-trailer]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SLEEP AWAKE launches December 2]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/10/sleep-awake-launches-december-2</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sleep-awake-launches-december-2.1333366/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Psychedelic first-person horror game dated.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Psychedelic first-person <a title="Genres > Horror [736 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/horror">horror game</a> <em><a title="Games > SLEEP AWAKE [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/sleep-awake">SLEEP AWAKE</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [10,657 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [8,134 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [24,599 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2446540/SLEEP_AWAKE/" target="_blank">Steam</a> on December 2, publisher <a title="Companies > Blumhouse Games [6 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/blumhouse-games">Blumhouse Games</a> and developer <a title="Companies > EYES OUT [5 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/eyes-out">EYES OUT</a> announced. <span id="more-1001453"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Blumhouse Games:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>SLEEP AWAKE</em> is an immersive first-person psychedelic horror narrative experience that explores the realm between sleep and death.</p><p>Submitted to perpetual insomnia, the denizens of the last known city on Earth are reaching a panic crisis of reckless experiments in an effort to avoid The HUSH, the inexplicable disappearance of those who sleep.</p><p>Playing as Katja, you must survive the devotees of various depraved death cults and desperately try to stay awake. Solve the puzzles of this mysterious world while avoiding the grasp of the death cults in an attempt to shatter the horrors of the past.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Led by Cory Davis (<em>Spec Ops: The Line</em>) and Robin Finck (Nine Inch Nails), <em>SLEEP AWAKE</em> combines full-motion video sequences with psychedelic visuals, blurring boundaries between reality and imagination.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>A Psychedelic Trip of the Senses</strong> – Immersive and vibrant. A gorgeous visualization of a terrifying reality caught between the crumbling physical world and a symbolic otherworldly realm.</li><li><strong>Struggle Between Oblivion and the Waking World</strong> – Katja confronts the grief of having lost her family to The Swell in the disaster-ravaged city of The Crush where the only fate worse than death… is sleep.</li><li><strong>Unique and Deeply Unsettling Horror Gameplay</strong> – Explore and solve the puzzles of a distorted reality. Survive harrowing enemy encounters through challenging <a title="Genres > Stealth [101 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/stealth">stealth</a>, <a title="Genres > Survival [473 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/survival">survival</a>, and chase sequences.</li><li><strong>Arresting Audio <a title="Companies > Experience [212 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/experience">Experience</a></strong> – Hypnotic evil from Robin Finck of Nine Inch Nails.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Sleep Awake Release Date Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/vpjEyOWcInw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/10/sleep-awake-launches-december-2]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Solasta II launches in Early Access in early 2026]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/10/solasta-ii-launches-in-early-access-in-early-2026</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/solasta-ii-launches-in-early-access-in-early-2026.1333360/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Embark on a new adventure.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Tabletop-inspired <a title="Genres > Strategy RPG [461 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg/strategy-rpg">strategy RPG</a> <em><a title="Games > Solasta II [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/solasta-ii">Solasta II</a></em> will launch in Early Access for <a title="Platforms > PC [24,599 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2975950/Solasta_II/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> in early 2026, developer <a title="Companies > Tactical Adventures [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/tactical-adventures">Tactical Adventures</a> announced. <span id="more-1001457"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2975950/Solasta_II/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam page</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>From the creators of <em><a title="Games > Solasta: Crown of the Magister [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/solasta-crown-of-the-magister">Solasta: Crown of the Magister</a></em> comes another intriguing tactical <a title="Genres > RPG [17,722 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg">RPG</a> faithful to the world’s most popular tabletop RPG’s ruleset.</p><p><strong>Uncover the Lands of Neokos</strong></p><p>Create and guide your party of four <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,642 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a>rs as they head to the faraway continent of Neokos in a quest driven by their family legacy. In the face of the threat by the ancient and enigmatic Shadwyn, what choices will you make to push back the impending tide of corruption?</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><em>Solasta II</em> is a grand sequel to <em>Solasta: Crown of the Magister</em>, a much beloved tactical RPG known for its faithfulness to the Tabletop experience. Decades after defeating the Sorak menace, a new flegdling party of heroes travels to distant lands in search for redemption. </p><p><strong>Just Like on Tabletop</strong></p><p><em>Solasta II</em> remains true to its promise to deliver gameplay based on the world’s most popular tabletop RPG. Prepare your spells, land that sneak attack, smite this monster—bathe in the familiarity of your Tabletop experience.</p><p>But that’s not all <em>Solasta II</em> will have to offer. This new opus will also allow you to freely roam the lands of Neokos, to explore and uncover the map as you will. Whether you stick to familiar roads, or head off into the wilderness… The choice is yours. Just be careful—because as we’ve always said…</p><p>You make the choices, dice decide your destiny.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Complete <a title="Genres > Party [109 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/party">Party</a> <a title="Genres > Management [34 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/management">Management</a> and Customization</strong> – Create and develop your own party of four adventurers, all fully voiced and each fully customizable with unique skills and abilities.</li><li><strong>Up to Four Players Online Cooperative Play</strong> – Team up with others online to strategize and share tactical triumphs.</li><li><strong>Turn-Based Tactical Combat</strong> – <a title="Companies > Mas [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/mas">Mas</a>ter tactical combat, utilizing the full depth of the <em>Dungeons &amp; Dragons</em>5E ruleset for immersive, strategic battles.</li><li><strong>Unreal Engine 5</strong> – <a title="Companies > Experience [212 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/experience">Experience</a> cutting-edge visuals and immersive environments.</li><li><strong>Console Optimization</strong> – Designed for seamless play with console pads delivering an experience on par with mouse and keyboard.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>“Welcome to Neokos” Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Solasta II - Welcome To Neokos [Official Trailer]" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ecp8AtdDdSg?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/10/solasta-ii-launches-in-early-access-in-early-2026]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cthulhu: The Cosmic Abyss launches April 16, 2026]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/10/cthulhu-the-cosmic-abyss-launches-april-16-2026</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cthulhu-the-cosmic-abyss-launches-april-16-2026.1333354/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>First gameplay trailer released.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Genres > Adventure [2,642 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">Adventure game</a> <em><a title="Games > Cthulhu: The Cosmic Abyss [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/cthulhu-the-cosmic-abyss">Cthulhu: The Cosmic Abyss</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [10,657 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [8,134 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [24,599 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2760560/Cthulhu_The_Cosmic_Abyss/" target="_blank">Steam</a> on April 16, 2026, publisher <a title="Companies > Nacon [260 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/nacon">Nacon</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Big Bad Wolf Studio [17 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/big-bad-wolf-studio">Big Bad Wolf Studio</a> announced. The next playtest will run from October 28 to November 4. <span id="more-1001461"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Nacon:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>2053. Across the globe, the occult threat grows ever more blatant, and strange, incomprehensible events multiply. As the Earth’s surface resources dwindle, powerful corporations turn to the uncharted depths of the oceans, unaware of the ancient <a title="Genres > Horror [736 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/horror">horror</a> they are about to awaken.</p><p>In this tense Lovecraftian thriller, you play Noah, tasked with investigating the mysterious disappearance of miners in the depths of the Pacific Ocean. With the help of your AI companion, Key, explore the vast, labyrinthine prison of R’lyeh—an ancient, sunken city of cyclopean proportions—and resist the creeping madness caused by Cthulhu’s influence. At its core lies a secret that could shatter your understanding of reality.</p><p>Powered by Unreal Engine 5, <em>Cthulhu: The Cosmic Abyss</em> features mind-bending environments that defy the laws of physics, pushing the boundaries of immersive storytelling to new heights.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Reveal the Unspeakable</strong> – Face nightmares and cosmic abominations that will push your sanity to its limits. Journey through a futuristic reinterpretation of Lovecraft’s mythos and uncover the legendary sunken city of R’lyeh. But beware: the deeper you descend, the more your mind succumbs to Cthulhu’s relentless influence.</li><li><strong>Challenge the Boundaries of Your Mind</strong> – Dive into the darkness with Key, your AI companion. Follow leads, gather scattered clues, and sharpen your detective skills to solve immersive and complex puzzles. Uncover hidden truths and look beyond appearances to choose your path to resolving the case. Every mystery offers branching routes and secret passages waiting to be discovered.</li><li><strong>An Unforgettable Narrative <a title="Companies > Experience [212 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/experience">Experience</a></strong> – As an agent of Ancile, a secret division of Interpol specializing in occult affairs, you are thrust into a gripping story with complex characters, brought to life through cinematic storytelling. Immerse yourself in a first-person investigative horror adventure with a rich, branching narrative, where your choices and understanding will shape Noah’s fate in this nightmarish world.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Cthulhu: The Cosmic Abyss | Release Date Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6UYr8qWhLL4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/10/cthulhu-the-cosmic-abyss-launches-april-16-2026]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Eating Poop Is No Longer A Solid Strategy In Viral Steam Game Duckov]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/eating-poop-is-no-longer-a-solid-strategy-in-viral-steam-game-duckov/1100-6535668/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/eating-poop-is-no-longer-a-solid-strategy-in-viral-steam-game-duckov.1333351/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6535668">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>The newest update for the viral Steam game Escape from Duckov is out now, and it discourages players from eating poop.</p><p>Up until now, players of the game <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/escape-from-duckov-a-parody-of-tarkov-featuring-ducks-is-putting-up-huge-numbers-on-steam/1100-6535556/" data-ref-id="1100-6535556">made by five people that has sold more than 1 million copies</a> could eat poop to restore energy and hydration values. Players can still do that after the new update, but it's less effective to do so. The patch notes state:</p><p>"Reduced the Energy and Hydration values provided by Poop."</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ewmV79zP5XQ" data-width="854" data-height="480">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/ewmV79zP5XQ" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/third-person-shooter/after-making-1-million-sales-escape-from-duckov-makes-eating-s-worse/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">As PC Gamer points out</a>, some players resorted to downing dookie to revitalize their character. The fecal matter is found on the map and can be eaten to restore some energy and hydration levels, at the cost of somewhat poisoning yourself. Apparently this proved to be too successful a tactic, and developer Team Soda made some changes. Players can still craft poop to create a throwable weapon called, wait for it, a Poop Ball.</p><p>You can see the full patch notes for the Duckov October 23 update below, <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/3167020/view/503965668093200561?l=english" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">as Team Soda shared on Steam. </a></p><h2><strong>Escape from Duckov October 23 patch notes</strong></h2><p><b>Updates</b></p><ul><li>Orange Headphones can now be dismantled.</li><li>Added indicator display when the player is injured.</li><li>Removed the footstep sound of dogs.</li><li>Reduced the Energy and Hydration values provided by Poop.</li><li>Added another construction site in the base to prevent players from getting stuck inside rooms.</li><li>Slightly reduced the damage of Storm Creatures.</li><li>In Motion Sickness-Friendly Mode, removed the camera movement when leaving the base.</li><li>Mad Bombers now have a chance to drop other cellar keys.</li><li>Reduced the durability consumption of Small Energy Bullets, Enhanced Small Energy Bullets, and Large Energy Bullets.</li><li>Monster: Storm? now inflicts a “Shatter” effect.</li></ul><p><b>Fixes</b></p><ul><li>Fixed lag issues caused by mining machines.</li><li>Fixed an issue where the Sniper Trial quest requirements do not match its description after the last update.</li><li>Fixed a bug where the MCXspear blueprint incorrectly appeared in the Recipe Collection even when it was locked.</li><li>Fixed an issue where the Standard Bullet (MAG) crafting recipe used a deprecated item.</li><li>Fixed an abnormal amount of ornaments appearing in the sewers.</li><li>Fixed an issue where weapon attachments were lost when disassembling guns.</li><li>Guns with Armor Penetration will now display their Penetration Level.</li><li>We're trying to fix the issue where reloading caused ammo to become “-1.”</li></ul><p><a href="https://x.com/ZhugeEX/status/1979966966447177783" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Analyst Daniel Ahmad reminded people</a> that Duckov was made by a team of five people, which makes the game's success even more impressive. The game is a parody of Escape from Tarkov and published by BiliBili, a Chinese giant also behind titles like Magicraft, Core Keeper, and Warm Snow.</p><p>Duckov is available now for $15.83 USD, but the price will go up 12% to $18 USD on October 30. It's putting up massive numbers on Steam, where it's reached <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/charts/mostplayed" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">more than 250,000 concurrent players.</a> The game is also available on the Epic Games Store, but not console.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/eating-poop-is-no-longer-a-solid-strategy-in-viral-steam-game-duckov/1100-6535668/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fallout 4: Anniversary Edition Brings The Apocalypse To Switch 2 In 2026]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/10/fallout-4-anniversary-edition-brings-the-apocalypse-to-switch-2-in-2026</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fallout-4-anniversary-edition-brings-the-apocalypse-to-switch-2-in-2026.1333333/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Save those caps</p>
</section></header><section>

<p>Today's <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-IZm-Hws334">Fallout Day Broadcast</a> delivered a very nice surprise to Switch 2 owners: Bethesda is bringing <a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/games/ps5/fallout_4">Fallout 4</a> to the hybrid console in <strong>2026</strong> in the form of <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/fallout-4-anniversary-edition">Fallout 4: Anniversary Edition</a>.</p>
<p>The Anniversary Edition includes the base game and all six official add-ons — Automatron, Far Harbor, Nuka-World, and the three Workshop expansions. Plus there's over 150 pieces of Creation Club content to discover. New weapons, different breeds of Dogmeat (that's your dog companion in-game, in case you've never heard of this good boy), new quests... it's a big ol' package, let's just say.</p>
<p>The teaser above doesn't really tell us much about this port, so we'll likely have to wait until next year for some more info on how it looks and runs. We've popped some screens from the Steam version of the game below just so you get an idea of what the game looks like.</p>
<p>For now, here's a brief rundown of the plot — taking place a decade after Fallout 3, you are the sole survivor of Vault 111. After your spouse is murdered and your son is kidnapped, you step out into the world of the Commonwealth, a huge post-apocalyptic wasteland region which encompasses Boston and other parts of Massachusetts. Your goal? To save your kid, of course.</p>

<p>The fourth numbered <strong>Fallout</strong> game was praised for its world, customisation, and amount of freedom available, but many thought it wasn't much of a step forward compared to Fallout 3, and many of the game's RPG elements were toned down slightly. Still, it garnered a fair amount of acclaim and has grown in many people's estimation in the 10 years since.</p>
<p>We're now suddenly realising that Fallout 4 is a decade old on 10th November. How did that happen?</p>
<hr>
<p><em>Fallout 4 comes to Switch 2 next year! Will you be stepping out into the Commonwealth? Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section></article><div><p>Alana has been with Nintendo Life since 2022, and while RPGs are her first love, Nintendo is a close second. She enjoys nothing more than overthinking battle strategies, characters, and stories. She also wishes she was a Sega air pirate.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/AlanaHagues"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/alanahagues.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('AlanaHagues');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/10/fallout-4-anniversary-edition-brings-the-apocalypse-to-switch-2-in-2026]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ICARUS Q&A – DayZ Creator Dean Hall Talks Console Edition, Ongoing Support and Survival Genre Evolution]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/icarus-qa-dayz-creator-talks-console-edition-support-survival-genre-evolution/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/icarus-q-a-%E2%80%93-dayz-creator-dean-hall-talks-console-edition-ongoing-support-and-survival-genre-evolution.1333330/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>RocketWerkz and GRIP Studios have just announced that ICARUS, the sci-fi co-op survival game created by former DayZ lead Dean 'Rocket' Hall, is coming to <a href="https://store.playstation.com/concept/10013354" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">PlayStation 5</a> and <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/store/productid/9p3h2pvzzpsd" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Xbox Series S|X</a> in Q1 2026. </p>



<p>ICARUS <a href="https://wccftech.com/icarus-the-co-op-survival-game-from-dean-hall-just-got-delayed-to-november/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">launched on Steam in late 2021</a>. It was initially quite rough, but over time, it secured a very dedicated fanbase, partly due to the continued support of the development team.</p>



<p>Console gamers can look forward to a much-improved version of the game that also includes the New Frontiers expansion, which added the alien region of Prometheus for an additional 64 square kilometers of terrain to explore (on top of the base game's 64 square kilometers). Prometheus also introduced three deadly biomes, a host of mutated apex predators, over 30 additional workshop items, the ability to craft over a hundred new items, and six narrative-driven missions across a single story arc.</p>



<p>As part of this announcement, I had the pleasure of interviewing Dean Hall about ICARUS: Console Edition, but we also discussed the game's four-year journey on PC, the evolution of the survival genre since DayZ, and more.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="ICARUS: Console Edition – Official Announce Trailer | Coming to Xbox &amp; PlayStation in 2026" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/luKC7WUOKOg?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p><strong>First of all, Dean, it's a pleasure to have you on Wccftech for the first time. Can you walk us through today's news?</strong></p>



<p>Sure. ICARUS is coming to consoles. It's something that people have asked me about a lot on social media. In fact, there's people who still contact me every few months on the ICARUS subreddit, which is kind of awesome. A lot of work has gone into getting the game ready for that, and we had to actually partner with another studio because we just didn't really have the experience with even just basic stuff like a controller. That's something that's actually been missing from ICARUS, controller support, and there's a lot of specialty knowledge in there. </p>



<p><strong>As far as I understand, it will be developed by GRIP Studios for console, right?</strong></p>



<p>Yes, we partnered with them. A number of their staff I actually worked with on DayZ, and I ran into them a couple of years ago at the 10th anniversary of DayZ and they had set up their own studio and were doing a bunch of good work. I was familiar with their work and obviously knew them. So, we hung out and just kind of hit it off from there. It felt like they were a team that we could partner with, a team that understood survival games and could help us in all the areas we weren't experienced with.</p>



<p><strong>Can you tell me if there are any major differences between the PC and console versions, or will they be largely the same?</strong></p>



<p>Certainly, if you're coming from the PC, it's very different in terms of the controller versus the mouse. There's been a lot of work that had to be done in terms of how you navigate around. But broadly speaking, it plays the same as on the PC, except you can sit down and play on the couch. That's really I think the miracle of it: the experience has been able to be ported very nicely to consoles. The biggest difference for me at least is the controller and just learning to jump around the different menus, because ICARUS has a lot of menus. It has a talent tree, it has inventory, it has all the interactions with deployables and placing things and all that kind of stuff. How the game gets put together is a little different as well. We packaged stuff a bit more to make it easier for console gamers to get into it. That's in terms of some of the content.</p>



<p><strong>Will you also port this controller-based UI to PC for those who may want to play ICARUS with the controller?</strong></p>



<p>That's something that we'd really love to do. There's also a number of optimizations, fixes, and other things like that that the GRIP team has done. We're very interested in pulling those things off. In a way, I'm a little jealous of console gamers because their first experience of ICARUS is going to be the product of over 200 weeks' worth of updates. They're coming in with this refined experience, so we're hopeful that some of the changes that GRIP have made will actually be able to make it back to the PC game as well. There's certainly a lot of PC gamers who contact me about having really good controller support.</p>



<figure><figcaption><em>We'd really love to port controller support to PC. There's also a number of optimizations, fixes, and other things like that that the GRIP team has done. We're very interested in pulling those things off. In a way, I'm a little jealous of console gamers because their first experience of ICARUS is going to be the product of over 200 weeks' worth of updates to ICARUS.</em></figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Yeah. It's even my preferred way to play on PC nowadays because I have my PC connected to a big OLED TV. So it's much more relaxing to play with the controller. A lot of PC gamers have this kind of setup.</strong></p>



<p>True. It's very frustrating that we haven't been able to put the controller support in before. It's something we've long wanted to do, but we just haven't had a lot of experience with that. And I think too often a PC game implementing controller support poorly leads to a very bad result and vice versa, where a console game is ported to PC. I think it's very important that the teams doing that have experience with it. Being able to partner with GRIP, get their advice about how we approach controller support and integrate it with the menus. Now that work's done, it is much easier for us to look at that on the PC.</p>



<p><strong>The press release says ICARUS is launching on Xbox Series S|X and PlayStation 5, but several Unreal Engine games are also being ported to the Switch 2. Do you think that's potentially feasible, and if so, would you like that to happen?</strong></p>



<div><p>I know the Switch 2 is something that's been talked about. I think it's already a minor miracle that GRIP has been able to do the fantastic work getting ICARUS to run as it does on consoles, just because the game is very RAM hungry. It's very memory hungry, very resource hungry in general, and this is largely just because of the scale of the worlds and the content in them. I think sometimes it is lost on people just how big it is as a survival game. That all adds up to a lot. So GRIP has done a pretty fantastic job at being able to port to that. I certainly know they're very keen to get it to as many platforms as possible, but I guess we'll have to see how it goes on PlayStation and Xbox first. One thing I should add is that we've really tried to focus on improving the performance of the game over the last 200 weeks.</p><p><strong>Sometimes, with other games that were first released on PC and later on consoles, the optimization that had to be made for the console ports was eventually backported to the PC version. Do you think that might happen here, too?</strong></p></div>



<p>Definitely, I think there is stuff like that. We were very particular, though, to make sure that both the console and the PC version run sort of branched. That's very important to me, because I don't like it when a game comes from PC to console and it just feels like a PC game on console, or vice versa. We really wanted each version to live sort of free and able to best utilize what each platform gave it. So that means that when we want to port something between them, we actually really sit down and say, "Hey, is this appropriate? Does this work? Does this best utilize the hardware?" Obviously, with a PC, you get a massive breadth of hardware available to the consumer. You have some people with insanely good graphics cards who want to turn everything up to a million. With consoles, you're getting a much more standardized experience. So, we wanted to make sure that each of those was able to go in its direction. We're definitely hopeful that we'll be able to pull across some really good stuff on the PC, but we also want to make sure that on the PC, people can utilize the latest and greatest hardware they have. That does limit some of those things we pull across from consoles.</p>



<p><strong>Will there be crossplay between PC and consoles in ICARUS?</strong></p>



<p>Crossplay was something we really wanted to do, but because there are those two separate versions, it's just not something we can deliver at the moment. The biggest challenge is simply that we've been updating the game every week on PC, which would just make that absolute hell for GRIP to try and deal with. Either we would have had to stop those weekly updates or figure out a way to try and do weekly updates on the consoles. which just isn't possible at the moment.</p>



<figure><figcaption><em>Crossplay was something we really wanted to do, but because there are those two separate versions, it's just not something we can deliver at the moment. The biggest challenge is simply that we've been updating the game every week on PC, which would just make that absolute hell for GRIP to try and deal with. Either we would have had to stop those weekly updates or figure out a way to try and do weekly updates on the consoles. which just isn't possible at the moment.</em></figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Is there crossplay between consoles?</strong></p>



<p>No, not even then. Multiplayer sessions are hosted natively on each console platform, which prevents cross-platform connectivity between PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series S and X.</p>



<p><strong>ICARUS has been live for nearly four years on PC. It's been quite a long journey for you. Can you walk us through it and all the expansions that you've made? How important has the community's feedback been to get these updates right?</strong></p>



<p>When we launched, it was a little rough. We went straight to Mixed reviews on Steam. We had broken localization. That was one of the biggest issues. We actually released to Mostly Positive reviews in the United States, but there was a simple bug with a drop-down combo box for the language settings that meant the language settings didn't get applied. So, a whole bunch of people weren't able to play the game in their language, which was super frustrating. We did get that fixed within hours, but there was that and there were a bunch of other bugs, not to mention a lot of optimization concerns. That's where we really committed to that idea of doing an update every single week just to build trust with the community and turn that around a bit. And we did an update every single week. We didn't miss one. We did it through the floods of Auckland, the city we live in, which got flooded twice. There was basically a cyclone, too. We went through many different natural disasters and still managed to deliver an update every week. That community feedback was intensely important through both Steam as well as Discord and Reddit. There's actually two ICARUS subreddits, so we hang out in both of them. They really helped us head the game in the right direction.</p>



<p>Probably the biggest example would be bringing in the open world. We still really love the idea of the session-based survival, but I think for that to really hit it off, we would have needed to have put a lot more work into the orbital side of it, which we just weren't able to do and deliver to the level of quality we wanted. However, we were able to bring in a full open world, which means that people could do the missions in one session. That came from a lot of discussion and a lot of working with our community veterans, who got early builds and gave us a lot of feedback. It has been a really long journey, very difficult, especially the first two years, and also when we removed our backend. Some people don't realize this: when we launched, we had this huge backend and we were spending like $100K a month running it. It had some good features, but it meant people couldn't run their dedicated servers. Eventually, we were like, look, this is really bad. If we get into financial trouble, the game will stop working. What we did was sit down and look at it. It was an enormous amount of work, but we changed it so it didn't have that backend. So if the company stopped running, it would still be totally playable as it is today, and that lets people run their own dedicated servers.</p>



<p>Again, we worked really heavily with the community on that one as well, so it was a long journey. But the last two years have been just a lot of fun as we've added a lot of content and things we really wanted the game to have.</p>



<p><strong>Now that ICARUS has been out for a while, are you happy with how it's done commercially on PC?</strong></p>



<p>Yes. By all rights, a game that is this old should have tailed off. Actually, all the games we released with have disappeared off the radar, which is sad in its own way. But we actually had a resurgence, particularly in Europe and Germany, after Gamescom. For a while there, Germany was our top-selling region. In fact, one out of every two copies of the game was being sold in Germany. We just had a sale recently on Steam that really reinvigorated things as well. It's always been a little bit of a surprise in a good way. I like to think a lot of that is just because of the work we've put in to really turn things around, try to address some of the community's concerns, and sort of almost meet in the middle. We obviously have our vision for what the game should be and also what the game is capable of doing, but the players are the ones who actually play the game. We also really like to try and play the game a lot ourselves and try and experience it as a customer and then see where we can take it from there. I would say ICARUS has been commercially successful in terms of us being able to keep developing it for all this time and we hope to keep on developing it as well.</p>



<figure><figcaption><em>By all rights, a game that is this old should have tailed off. Actually, all the games we released with have disappeared off the radar, which is sad in its own way. But we actually had a resurgence, particularly in Europe and Germany, after Gamescom. For a while there, Germany was our top-selling region. In fact, one out of every two copies of the game was being sold in Germany. We just had a sale recently on Steam that really reinvigorated things as well. It's always been a little bit of a surprise in a good way.</em></figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Regarding future content additions, I know you have been working on a map called Elysium, right? Can you share the status of this map? How far is it in development?</strong></p>



<p>The first thing I'd say is that there's a lot of DLC for ICARUS, and that's a good thing and a bad thing. Some people get pretty nervous, quite rightly, when they see so much DLC. We kind of identified when ICARUS launched that we didn't want to just leave the game where it was. We wanted to keep making stuff, and also, I get a bit frustrated with sequels. We tried to divide the content into three parts: expansions, which are almost like another whole game and they're priced accordingly. Those are for someone who plays ICARUS and goes, "Man, this is just the game for me." That is definitely not going to be everybody, but that's how we tried to position that. And then the content packs and outposts, they're more for people if they want to support the studio. The outposts are kind of a fun little thing that some people really like, and a chance for our map designers to show off some of their skills. With that in mind, we treat our next big expansion really as approaching almost like another version of ICARUS. We actually do a map review session every week, and the last two weeks have been fantastic as it's really been coming together. I won't give out any spoilers. But I think you will see the progression that we've had in the team with our technology around worldbuilding.</p>



<p>This new area just brings in a lot of those map design lessons that you started to see in Null. There are also a lot of art improvements in terms of how we design and approach areas, and a heck of a lot of new creatures, a few new mechanics, and quite a few surprises. The narrative chain I'm very happy with as well. I think it builds on the experience of New Frontiers and tries to give you this fun, interesting mission chain that you can play with your friends in the open world.</p>



<p><strong>Do you think it will be available in the first half of next year?</strong></p>



<p>It's definitely going to be the first half of next year. We'd really love to get it out this year, but it could end up being pretty tight. The internal target for the studio is to finish it this year, but people in the community who follow us a lot will remember that with Null and with Prometheus we did hold them back just to get the quality and stability we wanted. Actually, I think the real turnaround of ICARUS was when we released the New Frontiers expansion, which was the Prometheus map, because I think people saw, hey, that's what they wanted the studio to do. We were able to finally hit our stride, and then we went back and reworked the base game content as well. So yeah, the target would be the end of this year, but it will be pushed if we need to get that performance and quality we want. For example, very recently while we've been playing through it, we just realized we wanted more missions, so we are actually going back and adding more side missions.</p>



<p>Anyone who follows a lot on Discord will know that we push stuff if we have to. I'm so glad that now the studio has a bit of financial security that we can do that. It was looking very grim with the ICARUS launch as to whether we would be able to continually push it. The fact that people have bought those DLCs has meant that we could take our time with a lot of this content and updates.</p>



<figure><figcaption><em>The expansion is definitely going to be released in the first half of next year. We'd really love to get it out this year, but it could end up being pretty tight. The internal target for the studio is to finish it this year, but people in the community who follow us a lot will remember that with Null and with Prometheus we did hold them back just to get the quality and stability we wanted.</em></figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>People want to know if they can get a power switch in the game!</strong></p>



<p>It's something that we've talked about a lot. I'll bring it up at the steering group and we'll see what the team says. A lot of our decisions around what we do with ICARUS are really made just by talking with the team from a technical perspective. I'm hopeful we can. I'd recommend that people post about this on Feature Upvote, where people can actually upvote different features they want to have. It doesn't mean we necessarily deliver it. But yeah, I will go back and check out and see if we can do that one.</p>



<p><strong>Did you ever consider adding vehicles to the game? Was that something you discussed internally?</strong></p>



<p>Yeah. When we were developing ICARUS, we went all the way and we actually made a whole vehicle system. You could drive around in vehicles. You could actually assemble the vehicles from parts. But we noticed it just destroyed performance, particularly back then. The traversal of the terrain just got that stutter that many people have seen in Unreal Engine games and we worked extremely hard, to the point we nearly ran out of money at the studio, to try and bring that one and make that one work, and it just didn't. Additionally, it really affected how we were designing the maps. The speed at which you wanted to move around when you were in the vehicle just didn't really work, and we had a lot of technical problems, physics problems, etc. We'd even developed our building system so that you could build bridges to support this. If you have a mount and you stand on a structure, you actually add extra weight to it, and that was actually intended to be for a vehicle system. What we ended up doing instead of that was focusing on the mounts, and that seemed to work well, so we've just leaned into that. It also means we can deliver those talent trees per mount, which has worked out very nicely. So, what you're going to see particularly with uh you know the new expansion and in fact, there's a new mount coming to the game, the Ibis.</p>



<p>Vehicles are something we've thought about and we keep looking at again, but our maps are handcrafted and a lot of effort goes into them. As we found with our other game, Stationeers, if you have vehicles and the terrain doesn't handle them, it gets intensely frustrating for players. You get your vehicle jammed up in a corner every ten seconds or so.</p>



<p><strong>Will there be any updates to the pathing/pet AI?</strong></p>



<p>If people haven't checked the game out in, say, six months or so, it's definitely worth checking it out now because we've already done some updates to this all the time. If people do encounter problems or issues with the pathing, if they've managed to get a video of that, throw it on Feature Upvote. We have some really good programmers who then just look at those edge cases, particularly if people can report where they have pathing issues on the map. There are some spots that are just difficult for even the player to path, which is deliberate, particularly some of the areas in Null are designed to be quite tricky to navigate. We do a lot of work on the AI stuff, but it can be a sort of work that can take three to four months, and then we test it and we're like, okay, it's actually causing problems, so we have to go back and do some more work. It's the kind of thing that people might be like, why are they not working on pathing? It's just because it's not linear from how much work you put in to what you get out. It's almost a bit like prospecting, really. You're exploring to see if something is going to help and work. </p>



<p><strong>You've been making survival games for a long time, since the days of DayZ. What do you think about this genre and where it is today compared to when you started? How has it evolved in your opinion?</strong></p>



<p>It's evolved awesomely. You can tell there's features in ICARUS that are a result of playing Valheim. Valheim came out in our development and I remember that I went like, oh man, we made some bad decisions. We tried to change some of the things we could. There were just some fantastic things in Valheim. It can be such a cozy game sometimes, and I really love that push and pull and the feeling of the biomes is just so consistent. Our food system and that stacked buff system came as a direct result of us putting about 400 hours into Valheim. We were playing Valheim to the point that it almost delayed the project. I wish we could have gotten more in-world interaction. It's something we've done an enormous amount on with Stationeers and we had intended to do with Icarus. You know that idea, like in Minecraft when you walk up to a door and you just whack the door and it opens, or you walk up to a switch and you whack it and it moves.</p>



<p>Stationeers does a fantastic job of all that in-world stuff, but we never quite got into Icarus. But yes, there has been a lot of new survival stuff. There's <a href="https://wccftech.com/popular-survival-game-enshrouded-launch-update-november-10/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Enshrouded</a>. I'm actually pretty keen to get back into playing Project Zomboid's new build. I mostly play multiplayer, so I like multiplayer survival games, but with Project Zomboid, there's just so much good new innovation in terms of its experience. Some people would say that there are probably too many survival games out there. Players do have a difficult time finding the time to try them.</p>



<p><strong>True, even though the new kind of hotness is PvPvE games, right? With some extraction and survival elements thrown in.</strong></p>



<p>It is. Many people asked me, "Why did you make a PVE game after making Day Z?" The thing is, I'd love to look at another PvP game. But with Icarus, I didn't want to look at a PVP game until we had learned to deal with performance stability, quality, and particularly antisocial-type issues like hacking and stuff like that. I really feel that the survival genre hasn't dealt with this enough: how do we deliver these consistent experiences that aren't getting destroyed by other people?</p>



<p>I actually think I made a mistake with DayZ where I tried to solve it all just in terms of everything on the server. If you look at Minecraft communities, I think a lot of it can actually be solved by the communities themselves if you give them the tools to do so. So, giving people a lot of support for how they run and control dedicated servers, logging, and stuff like that. That's super important. I'm still extremely interested in PvP. I just think it's really important that we deal with the ability for the games to scale. Even Icarus suffers from this a lot. I saw people posting on Reddit about performance. We have done an enormous amount of work to try and improve the performance with large bases. In fact, in the last month or so, we actually released an update, well, two updates focused entirely on performance, particularly for large bases and stuff like that.</p>



<p>That's a very long-winded answer to your question. I'd say I'm very interested in survival and PvP, but I think it has to be done right, and it is something that we're not doing a very good job at, including myself, which is why I kind of needed to get back to basics and develop technology and approaches that would deliver those experiences.</p>



<figure><figcaption><em>We really love all the effort we put into it. There's still heaps of people playing it. I think there's like 8,000 people playing Icarus right now at this at this very second. We really want that to continue and we want to keep paying our staff, and pay them well. We don't have any plans to stop.</em></figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Do you plan to support ICARUS for years to come?</strong></p>



<p>Absolutely. This is probably a good segue to another controversial topic: DLC. Broadly speaking, I think the community is very positive towards the DLC in Stationeers but also in Icarus, because we kind of said to the community, hey, we want to keep developing this game as long as we can. We really love all the effort we put into it. There's still heaps of people playing it. I think there's like 8,000 people playing Icarus right now at this at this very second. We really want that to continue, and we want to keep paying our staff and pay them well. The content approach we came up with delivered on that and I think we managed to find a really nice sweet spot instead of doing a whole bunch of bad stuff. We split it into those three parts, and that actually allowed us to keep the base game cheaper and also allows us to put it on discount while still being able to fund the studio. We don't have any plans to stop. We've done an update every week and they're pretty meaty updates. Last week, it was the farming backpack, and this week, it's a new, combat-focused mount too.</p>



<p><strong>Just a final question about AI and its impact on game development. What's the opinion within RocketWerkz? Did you discuss the possibility of using it in some way or are you just against it? What are your feelings?</strong></p>



<p>I'm part of that micro-generation that first had the Internet at school. It just sort of came in, and all the adults lost their minds over Wikipedia coming out and Google and it's going to be the end of information. It feels a little bit like that. I think that regardless of what we do, AI is here. So really then it's about a matter of how do we deal with what the impact of that is. We handcraft our maps and a lot of stuff. We like to say games are played, not made. For us, there's not really a lot of stuff that we use AI on for ICARUS because the whole idea of it is we want to sit down and handcraft an experience. That's not a judgment against AI. It's more, that's what we really wanted to do. We wanted to sit down and sketch a big map out on a whiteboard and then see it come to life. Our lead world builder actually worked at Bethesda for a while and just loves worldbuilding. We do utilize AI for some of our other projects as a coding support tool. We get an AI model, expose it to our codebase, and that means you can ask it questions, which is really helpful because one person can't easily have the whole codebase in their head so that we can expose the codebase to it and then ask it questions. As to getting it actually to do work, I don't think we are necessarily quite there yet.</p>



<p><strong>Thank you for your time.</strong></p>

			
			<p>Follow <a href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> or <a href="https://google.com/preferences/source?q=wccftech.com">add us as a preferred source</a>, to get our news coverage and reviews in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/icarus-qa-dayz-creator-talks-console-edition-support-survival-genre-evolution/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fallout 4 is getting a new edition just in time for the TV show]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/805612/fallout-4-anniversary-edition-release-date-trailer</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fallout-4-is-getting-a-new-edition-just-in-time-for-the-tv-show.1333327/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span id="follow-author-standard_article_details-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTIz"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span></span><span>Jay Peters</span></span></span></p> <p><span>is a senior reporter covering technology, gaming, and more. He joined The Verge in 2019 after nearly two years at Techmeme.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p><em>Fallout 4</em> will turn 10 on November 10th, and to celebrate the milestone, Bethesda is releasing a new anniversary edition of the game that same day on PC, PS4, PS5, Xbox One, and Xbox Series X / S. With <em>Fallout 4 Anniversary Edition</em>, you’ll get the base game, six official expansions, more than 150 pieces of Creation Club content (including new options to switch what breed of dog Dogmeat is), and a Creations hub to access mods.</p><p>The release is happening about a month before the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7TsP09cZA7o">December 17th release</a> of the second season of Prime Video’s <em>Fallout</em>, so you’ll have some time to dig into everything if you want to play <em>Fallout 4</em> ahead of watching the show. And sometime next year, the <em>Fallout 4 Anniversary Edition</em> will come to the Nintendo Switch 2, too. (It’s been a big day for news about <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/805404/switch-into-the-shadows">Switch 2</a> <a href="https://www.theverge.com/games/805381/elden-ring-tarnished-edition-nintendo-switch-2-delay">third-party releases</a>.)</p><p>As part of its Fallout Day broadcast today, Bethesda <a href="https://bethesda.net/en/article/5S63EJI5hmThAU6I8jaiQj/fallout-day-broadcast-2025-news">also announced updates</a> coming to <em>Fallout Shelter</em> and <em>Fallout 76</em>. At the end, Bethesda’s Todd Howard gave an extremely vague hint on what’s potentially next for <em>Fallout</em>: “Just know, we are working on even more. We’re looking forward to the day where we can share that with everybody.”</p><div><p><span><strong>Follow topics and authors</strong> from this story to see more like this in your personalized homepage feed and to receive email updates.</span></p><ul><li id="follow-author-article_footer-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTIz"><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span><span>Jay Peters</span></span></span></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li></ul></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/news/805612/fallout-4-anniversary-edition-release-date-trailer]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Two More Black Ops 2 Remastered Maps Are Coming to Black Ops 7 Season 1]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-standoff-meltdown-maps-season-one/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/two-more-black-ops-2-remastered-maps-are-coming-to-black-ops-7-season-1.1333324/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 is bringing back some fan-favorite Black Ops 2 maps for Season One of the game.</p>



<p>Releasing on November 14th, Black Ops 7 continues the Black Ops series name, as well as its story. Players will finally reunite with the Mason family from <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-2-call-of-duty-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Black Ops 2</a> and witness another mind-bending narrative, now with friends. However, it seems the story isn’t the only thing coming back, as two remastered maps from Black Ops 2 are returning for the new entry, as said by Activision.</p>



<h2 id="h-call-of-duty-black-ops-2-s-standoff-and-meltdown-return-as-season-one-maps-in-black-ops-7">Call of Duty: Black Ops 2’s Standoff and Meltdown Return as Season One Maps in Black Ops 7</h2>



<figure><div><blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>Season 01 of <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/BlackOps7?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#BlackOps7</a> will be the biggest post-launch content drop in our history, and we're just getting started. Get your first look in our new Dev Talk:</p><p>✅ 7 signature 6v6 maps<br>✅ 7 new &amp; fan-favorite weapons (Maddox! 😍)<br>✅ 3 Zombies maps<br>✅ S01 remasters confirmed<br>✅ MP… <a href="https://t.co/VoKWLqycLW">pic.twitter.com/VoKWLqycLW</a></p></div>— Treyarch (@Treyarch) <a href="https://twitter.com/Treyarch/status/1981421047376465996?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 23, 2025</a></blockquote></div></figure>



<p>In <a href="https://x.com/Treyarch/status/1981421047376465996" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">a Dev Talk</a> with the team at Treyarch, the team revealed two Black Ops 2 maps returning for Black Ops 7 as part of Season One: Meltdown and Standoff. Each map will be remastered and available as part of the next batch of maps, though a release date was not given. Standoff did join Black Ops: Cold War’s roster of maps during Season Three, acting as both a Multiplayer map and Zombies map. However, Meltdown has not been in the series since Black Ops 2 back in 2012, so fans will be excited to return to the nuclear powerplant.</p>



<p>The Season One roadmap for Black Ops 7 <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-season-one-roadmap/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">was revealed today</a> as part of the Dev Talk. Seven maps, including Meltdown and Standoff, will will release during the season, with more to come later. Three other Zombies maps, two being Survival, are also coming in Season One. The team is calling the new season its biggest yet and based on what we can tell, it sure seems to be. Either way, both new and returning players are in for a treat when it releases on November 14th.</p>



<p>Are you excited to return to Standoff and Meltdown? Any maps you hope make a return for Black Ops 7? Will you be getting the game at launch? Let us know in the comments and on&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.gg/Bhv3AMa5a9" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">the official Insider Gaming Discord</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Call of Duty, check out our articles on the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-7-will-have-non-disbanding-lobbies-at-launch/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">lack of skill-based matchmaking</a>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-7-release-date-remains-unchanged/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">debunked early release rumors</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">subscribe to our weekly newsletter</a>!</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-standoff-meltdown-maps-season-one/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pacific Drive now available for Xbox Series alongside DLC expansion ‘Whispers in the Woods’]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/10/pacific-drive-now-available-for-xbox-series-alongside-dlc-expansion-whispers-in-the-woods</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pacific-drive-now-available-for-xbox-series-alongside-dlc-expansion-%E2%80%98whispers-in-the-woods%E2%80%99.1333321/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>A surprise release.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><em><a title="Games > Pacific Drive [14 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/pacific-drive">Pacific Drive</a></em> is now available for <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [8,134 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a> alongside the launch downloadable content expansion “Whispers in the Woods,” publisher <a title="Companies > Kepler Interactive [55 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/kepler-interactive">Kepler Interactive</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Ironwood Studios [14 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/ironwood-studios">Ironwood Studios</a> announced. <span id="more-1002080"></span></p><p><em>Pacific Drive</em> first launched for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [10,657 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a> and <a title="Platforms > PC [24,599 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1458140/Pacific_Drive/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> and <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/p/pacific-drive" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Epic Games Store</a> on February 22, 2024.</p><p>Here is an overview of the content, via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3594760/Pacific_Drive_Whispers_in_the_Woods/" target="_blank">Steam page</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Return to the Zone and witness the rise of a group of Anomaly-obsessed fanatics in this terrifying new expansion to <em>Pacific Drive</em>.</p><p>“Whispers in the Woods” is a brand new story for you and your trusty station wagon. Available at any point after the first few hours of the game, this expansion takes you deep within a new and mysterious part of the Olympic Exclusion Zone’s forests. Marked with strange symbols and effigies, these woods are filled with new dangers and mysteries to uncover. Find and experience the power of Artifacts, each adding bizarre and inexplicable new effects.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong><a title="Companies > Experience [212 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/experience">Experience</a> Their Story</strong><ul><li>Dig into a eight to 12 hour story for you and your station wagon, playable from within a new or existing save.</li><li>Embark on a fully voiced journey filled with a new cast of characters and additional side narrative to discover.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Learn Their Ways, Uncover Their Secrets</strong><ul><li>They have come to the Zone and left their mark. Travel into the whispering woods of the OEZ – a disturbing vision of the once familiar forests.</li><li>Explore new maps and junction types filled with strange altars and unique resources.</li><li>Adorn your car with their designs of new parts and cosmetics.</li><li>Encounter new anomalies and anomaly behaviors hidden beneath the dark canopy.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Find Their Artifacts, Embrace the Unknown</strong><ul><li>Unlock the power—and peril—of Artifacts, a new gameplay system featuring objects that create mysterious changes and effects to you and the world around you.</li><li>Carrying Artifacts increases the challenge you and your car will face, but they’re instrumental to your <a title="Genres > Survival [473 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/survival">survival</a>. How much risk are you willing to take?</li></ul></li><li><strong>And More</strong><ul><li>New Garage Stations to aid on your journey.</li><li>New Route Modifiers that change how you play.</li><li>New Garage Cosmetics to find and collect.</li><li>New Original Score from composer Wilbert Roget II.</li></ul></li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>DLC “Whispers in the Woods” Launch Trailer</span></h2><p>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GMFYPDRnuyo</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/10/pacific-drive-now-available-for-xbox-series-alongside-dlc-expansion-whispers-in-the-woods]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>