<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 12:30:23 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater Hits New Levels of Realism With Complete RT Shader and Enhanced Visuals]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater-complete-rt/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater-hits-new-levels-of-realism-with-complete-rt-shader-and-enhanced-visuals.1301292/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The Complete RT shader and a selection of other visual improvements make Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater look stunning, making its visual more realistic and its lighting closer to path tracing quality.</p>



<p>In a new video shared today on YouTube, known modder <a href="https://www.patreon.com/MassiHancer">MassiHancer</a> showcased the remake of the third entry in the series by KONAMI released last month on PC and consoles running with the Complete RT shader and ReSTIR G.I., which deliver path tracing quality with enhanced global illumination, ambient occlusion, tessellation, color grading and depth of field. The video also includes a few comparisons that highlight the significant improvements introduced to the game by the shader over the game's native Lumen.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Metal Gear Solid Δ Snake Eater: POV Real Life 4K Graphics | RAYTRACING Mod on RTX 5090 | Complete RT" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/c-qduZ_FQ98?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>Although the game suffers from performance and stability issues that are being addressed with <a href="https://wccftech.com/metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater-patch-gameplay-issues-crashes/">post-launch updates</a>, Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater is a solid remake of one of the best entries in the series created by Hideo Kojima. The faithful recreation of what is, still today, one of the finest stealth games ever released, and the addition of Legacy Style for purists and New Style for newcomers makes this remake a solid purchase for all sorts of players, as highlighted by Kai in his<a href="https://wccftech.com/review/metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater-ps5-review-based-on-a-hideo-kojima-game/"> review.</a></p>



<p>Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater is now available on PC, PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X and Xbox Series S.</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater-complete-rt/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Seven indie games that will upgrade your downtime this fall]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/games/774447/upgrade-downtime-indie-games-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/seven-indie-games-that-will-upgrade-your-downtime-this-fall.1301289/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>We all know there’s a lot of tech to potentially upgrade in your life, but for those who want to upgrade their downtime with inexpensive, relatively short video games, I have good news. 2025 has already featured a wealth of excellent titles to spend your time with, including ones from smaller and independent developers that you can complete in a few sessions. If you’re looking for a good new game to play (and aren’t already deep into <em><a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/769489/hollow-knight-silksong-news-updates">Hollow Knight: Silksong</a></em>), here are some great options from this year.</p><p>This new take on the classic side-scrolling versions of <em>Ninja Gaiden</em> from Dotemu and The Game Kitchen has gorgeous pixel art, tight platforming, thrilling combat, and a soundtrack that feels ripped straight from a cheesy action movie. The game can be pretty tough, which is fitting given its lineage, but there are Assist Mode features for those who want to make things a bit easier. It hits all the right notes for a great retro action game, yet it still feels very modern.</p><div><p><cite>Image: Poti Poti Studio / Wholesome Games Presents</cite></p></div><p>If a chill puzzle game is more of what you’re hankering for, <em>Is This Seat Taken?</em> should fit the bill. In the game, you’re tasked with finding the right seats for adorable little shape people while taking into account their various needs. Some may request to sit near a window, or to be far away from a stinky person. It’s all very relaxing and charming, and there’s no time limit or major penalty for not seating everyone exactly as they want. When you do find the right seats for everyone, it’s extremely satisfying.</p><p><em>The Drifter</em> has all the hallmarks of an old-school point-and-click adventure game, like beautiful pixel art, many interesting people to talk to, and lots of items to experiment with. But unlike goofier stalwarts, such as the <em>Monkey Island</em> series, <em>The Drifter</em> uses the genre to tell a gripping thriller story. It’s a refreshing take on a classic genre, and like a great novel, I couldn’t put it down.</p><p><em>Rift of the NecroDancer</em> is a <em>Guitar Hero</em>-like music game that’s <em>packed</em> with excellent original music, including some catchy remixes of tunes from the hit roguelike <em>Crypt of the NecroDancer</em>. I was a huge fan of <em>Rift</em>’s story mode, which uses a lightweight narrative to introduce you to the more than 30 songs in the game. There are also silly rhythm-based minigames and epic bosses. It’s foot-tapping fun, and if you’re like me, you’ll be humming the songs long after you put the game down.</p><p>Toby Fox’s parallel story to the indie classic <em>Undertale</em> has been in development for years and still isn’t finished. But even with four of seven planned chapters available to play right now, it feels like a complete experience. <em>Deltarune</em> is packed with just as much humor and oddities as <em>Undertale</em>, and the battles that blend RPG and bullet hell mechanics are just as entertaining to figure out in the in-development game. <em>Deltarune</em> is the longest game on this list — it took me about 15 hours to get through all four chapters that are out now — but every minute is worth your time.</p><p><em>Despelote</em>, set in Ecuador in 2001, puts you in the shoes of a soccer-obsessed kid who’s swept up in the excitement of Ecuador competing to qualify for the World Cup. It features a stunning art style that puts black-and-white characters in an oversaturated world, and according to my colleague Andrew Webster, you can finish the game in about two hours. He called it a “picture-perfect portrait of childhood obsession,” so if you’re looking for a game that might make you feel a bit nostalgic — even if you didn’t grow up being into soccer — this might be one to check out.</p><p>Sometimes, you just want a game that encourages you to turn off part of your brain, and <em>A Game About Digging a Hole</em> can do just that. The game gives you basic tools that you can level up to dig, dig, dig your way down. There isn’t some late-game twist that breaks the fourth wall. You dig a hole, monitor your remaining health and power levels, mine valuable treasures, and reemerge to upgrade your gear so you can go even deeper. It’s mesmerizingly simple, and a good game to check out if you’re exhausted by games with upgrade trees and endless quests.</p><p><span><a href="https://www.theverge.com/games/774447/upgrade-downtime-indie-games-2025#comments"><span>0<!-- --> <!-- -->Comments</span></a></span></p><div><p><span><strong>Follow topics and authors</strong> from this story to see more like this in your personalized homepage feed and to receive email updates.</span></p><ul><li id="follow-author-article_footer-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTIz"><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span><span>Jay Peters</span></span></span></li><li></li><li></li></ul></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/games/774447/upgrade-downtime-indie-games-2025]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mark Zuckererg Demos New Facebook AI And It Couldn’t Have Gone Worse]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/meta-ai-mark-zuckerberg-korean-steak-sauce-facebook-2000626808</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mark-zuckererg-demos-new-facebook-ai-and-it-couldn%E2%80%99t-have-gone-worse.1301283/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p id="featured-image">
                              <figure id="attachment_featured" aria-describedby="featured-caption">
                                                                          <figcaption id="featured-caption">
                    <span>Zuckerberg introduces Chef Cuso on stage.</span> © Meta / Kotaku
                  </figcaption>
                </figure>
                                                      </p><div>
              
              <p>Mark Zuckerberg took the stage at Meta Connect 2025 to show off the corporation’s latest non-AI. The tool, designed to spy on the objects in your home and send that data back to Facebook for advertising reasons…wait, sorry, I mean to answer questions while responding to your current environment, was asked to help Mark’s pretend-friend Jack Mancuso create a new sauce for his sandwich. Even in the heavily rehearsed and pre-scripted demonstration, the AI immediately shit the bed, leaving Mancuso and Zuckerberg to spuriously blame the wifi for the obvious technological fail.</p> <p>The AI being hyped right now is not AI at all. It’s really important that we all acknowledge this, that the world is selling itself a multi-billion dollar lemon, predictive text engines that have nothing intelligent about them. They’re giant sorting machines, which is why they’re so good at identifying patterns in scientific research, and could genuinely advance medicine in wonderful ways. But what they cannot do is&nbsp;<em>think</em>, and as such, it’s a collective mass-delusion that these systems have any use in our day-to-day lives beyond plagiarism.</p> <p>Here’s the set-up. Jack “Chef Cuso” Mancuso (the not-chef YouTuber and seller of knives and seasonings) is stood on camera in a kitchen set, before a table of ingredients capable of being put together for pretty much one purpose. Zuckerberg fake-ass pretends to think up an idea on the spot for what could be cooked up, “Maybe a steak sauce, maybe a Korean-inspired thing?”</p>

 <p>“Yeah, let’s try it. It’s not something I’ve made before,” says Mancuso, remembering his script, “so I could definitely use the help.”</p> <p>In the best case scenario for this Meta Connect demo, the Meta “AI” would scan the table of ingredients in front of Mancuso, and suggest a sauce he could make from the items it recognizes. The hilariously clearly-labeled bottles of “Sesame Oil” and “Soy Sauce,” with the words squarely facing the camera, sit next to—oh my goodness, would you look at that—a jar of Cuso-branded seasoning! There’s also some spring onions, a couple of lemons, two garlic cloves, salt and pepper and maybe a potato and a bottle of honey? It’s all next to a very sad-looking steak sandwich. So, Meta AI, what can we&nbsp;<em>possibly</em> do?</p>

 <p>“Hey Meta, start Live AI,” says Mancuso, just like in rehearsal, before a very long and awkward pause. “Starting Live AI” the robot voice eventually intones, before adding the unimprovable words, “I love this set-up you have here, with soy sauce and other ingredients.” Thanks! It loves it! That’s so thoughtful and demonstrative that it was able to scan the words in the image. “How can I help?”</p> <p>“Hey, could you help me make a Korean-inspired steak sauce for my steak sandwich here?” asks Mancuso, stood in front of the exact ingredients used to make Korean steak sauce <a href="https://www.thekitchn.com/recipe-korean-bbq-marinade-recipes-from-the-kitchn-172750">according to this online recipe</a>. Oh, except for a pear. That recipe I just found wants a pear. He doesn’t have a pear. Interesting.</p>

 <p>“You can make a Korean-inspired steak sauce using soy sauce, sesame oil…” beings Meta AI, before Mancuso interrupts to stop the voice listing everything that happens to be there. “What do I do first?” he demands. Meta AI, clearly unimpressed by being cut off, falls silent. “What do I do first?” Mancuso asks again, fear entering his voice. And then the magic happens.</p>   <p>“You’ve already combined the base ingredients, so now grate a pear to add to the sauce.”</p>

 <p>Mancuso looks like a rabbit looking into the lights of an oncoming juggernaut. He now only has panic. There’s nothing else for it, there’s only one option left. He repeats his line from the script for the third time.</p> <p>“What do I do first?”</p> <p>There’s then audience laughter.</p> <p>“You’ve already combined the base ingredients, so now grate the pear and gently combine it with the base sauce.”</p>

 <p>Mancuso seems to snap out of his stupor and makes the hilariously silly claim, “Alright, I think the wifi might be messed up. Sorry, back to you Mark.”</p> <p>There’s louder audience laughter.</p> <p>“It’s all good!” says Zuck, as he hears billions of dollars flushing down a toilet. “It’s a…the irony of the whole thing is you spend years making technology and then the wifi at the, er, day kinda…catches you.”</p>

 <p>Yeah, the wifi. You know how a bad wifi connection causes an AI to skip steps in a recipe. We’ve all been there. Same reason I lost that game of pool—the damn wifi in the bar.</p> <p>Rather than because of wifi, the reason this happened is because these so-called AIs are just regurgitating information that has been parsed from scanning the internet. It will have been trained on recipes written by professional chefs, home cooks and cookery sites, then combined this information to create something that sounds a lot like a recipe for a Korean sauce. But it, not being an intelligence, doesn’t know what Korean sauce is, nor what recipes are, because it doesn’t&nbsp;<em>know</em> anything. So it is that it can only make noises that sound like the way real humans have described things. Hence it having no way of knowing that ingredients haven’t already been mixed—just the ability to mimic recipe-like noises. The recipes it will have been trained on will say “after you’ve combined the ingredients…” so it does too.</p>

 <p>What’s so joyous about this particular incident isn’t just that it happened live on stage with one of the world’s richest men made to look a complete fool in front of the mocking laughter of the most non-hostile audience imaginable… Oh wait, it largely is that. That’s very joyous. But it’s also that it was so ludicrously over-prepared, faked to such a degree to try to eliminate all possibilities for error, and even so it&nbsp;<em>still</em> went so spectacularly badly.</p> <p>From Zuckers pretending to make up, “Oh, I dunno, picking from every possible foodstuff in the entire universe, what about a…ooh! Korean-inspired steak sauce!” for a man stood in front of the base ingredients of a Korean-inspired steak sauce, to the hilarious fake labels with their bold Arial font facing the camera, it was all clearly intended to force things to go as smoothly as possible. We were all supposed to be wowed that this AI could recognize the ingredients (it imagined a pear) and combine them into the exact sauce they wanted! But it couldn’t. And if it had, it wouldn’t have known the correct proportions, because it would have scanned dozens and dozens of recipes designed to make different volumes of sauce, with contradictory ingredients (the lack of both gochujang&nbsp;<em>and</em> rice wine vinegar, presumably to try to make it even simpler, seems likely to not have helped), and just approximated based on averages. Plagiarism on this scale leads to a soupy slop.</p> <p>You know what <del>Chef</del> Cuso could have done? He could have Googled a recipe, and visited a trusted site. Or, and sorry to be quite so old-fashioned, looked in a recipe book! Hell, he could have looked up instructions on Facebook.</p> <p>Oh, and here’s Jack Mancuso making a Korean-inspired steak sauce in 2023.</p>   
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/meta-ai-mark-zuckerberg-korean-steak-sauce-facebook-2000626808]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fortnite creators will soon be able to sell in-game items to make more money, but are Creative Mode offerings like Steal A Brainrot what players want?]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/fortnite-creators-will-soon-be-able-to-sell-in-game-items-to-make-more-money-but-are-creative-mode-offerings-like-steal-a-brainrot-what-players-want</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fortnite-creators-will-soon-be-able-to-sell-in-game-items-to-make-more-money-but-are-creative-mode-offerings-like-steal-a-brainrot-what-players-want.1301274/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>"They are promoting AI slop."</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
      <picture data-src-full="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/The-Power-of-Megazord-_-Fortnite-Battle-Royale-Gameplay-Trailer-0-17-screenshot.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" src="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/The-Power-of-Megazord-_-Fortnite-Battle-Royale-Gameplay-Trailer-0-17-screenshot.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/The-Power-of-Megazord-_-Fortnite-Battle-Royale-Gameplay-Trailer-0-17-screenshot.png?width=570&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 570px) and (min-resolution: 2x)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/The-Power-of-Megazord-_-Fortnite-Battle-Royale-Gameplay-Trailer-0-17-screenshot.png?width=570&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 570px)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/The-Power-of-Megazord-_-Fortnite-Battle-Royale-Gameplay-Trailer-0-17-screenshot.png?width=414&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-resolution: 2x)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Epic</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Epic will soon allow <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/fortnite">Fortnite</a> developers to sell in-game items from their Fortnite islands, allowing creators to make more money.</p>
<p>This will begin in December 2025, and for the first year developers will earn 100 percent of the V-Bucks value from sales - usually this is at 50 percent.</p>
<p>The <a href="https://www.fortnite.com/news/fortnite-developers-will-soon-be-able-to-sell-in-game-items?lang=en-US">news</a> comes as Fortnite's Creative Mode of fan-made content is proving exceptionally popular - recently, the Fortnite version of Roblox meme game Steal A Brainrot had <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/FortNiteBR/comments/1mtklb7/oh_wow/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button">more concurrent players</a> than Epic's official maps.</p>

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="The Power of Megazord | Fortnite Battle Royale Gameplay Trailer" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Xu3WYDFhB_Y?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>The Power of Megazord | Fortnite Battle Royale Gameplay Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Xu3WYDFhB_Y?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/Xu3WYDFhB_Y?autoplay=1" title="The Power of Megazord | Fortnite Battle Royale Gameplay Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>The Power of Megazord | Fortnite Battle Royale Gameplay Trailer<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Xu3WYDFhB_Y" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>


<p><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/fortnite-is-getting-a-major-new-sandbox-mode-separate-from-battle-royale">Fortnite's Creative Mode first launched back in 2018</a>, and allows players to create their own maps and modes. Epic then offers a payout based on engagement - <a href="https://www.fortnite.com/news/fortnite-ecosystem-2024-year-in-review-celebrating-creators-and-looking-ahead?team=personal">last year</a> it paid out $325m to creators, with seven receiving over $10m.</p>
<p>Since Creative Mode's release, Epic has revealed, players have spent over 11.2bn hours across 260,000 creator-made islands, resulting in $722,000,000 paid to creators.</p>
<p>The amount of money creators will make in Fortnite is only going to increase when they're able to sell in-game items directly from their islands, in addition to receiving an engagement payout from Fortnite's item shop sales.</p>
<p>Epic has a formula for calculating the V-Bucks value in US dollars each month, which takes all real-money spending towards V-Bucks (in dollars), subtracting platform and store fees, and dividing by total V-Bucks spent. With creators usually earning 50 percent of V-Bucks value from sales, this equates to 37 percent of retail spending. Roblox offers 25 percent, by way of comparison.</p>
<p>In addition, Epic will add a Sponsored Row to Fortnite's Discover, meaning creators can pay for increased visibility by bidding for placement in the row. That's a further investment in generating more in-game sales.</p>
<p>Epic has also announced Fortnite Creator Communities, to allow creators to share updates directly with players on the web and within Fortnite. Creator posts will be text and image-based and allow for sharing information and gathering feedback - much like on Steam.</p>
<figure>

<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Epic</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>But despite the huge success of creator islands, is this really what Fortnite players want?</p>
<p>Take Steal A Brainrot. It's proven to be a phenomenal success - as <a href="https://www.dexerto.com/gaming/steal-a-brainrot-smashes-records-with-nearly-24-million-players-across-roblox-and-fortnite-3250973/">Dexerto</a> reported, it had 24 million players in a single day across both Roblox and Fortnite versions. While the Roblox version peaked at 23.4 million players in a day, Fortnite's version contributed 542,000. That vastly outweighs Fortnite's primary Battle Royale modes that generate around 100,000 players during peak weekend play.</p><p>"They are promoting AI slop, copy and paste creative maps more than their own BR season," wrote one player on <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/FortNiteBR/comments/1n4fbrt/this_is_very_much_so_alarming_and_needs_to_be/">reddit</a>. "This is going to prove to be extremely unhealthy for the game in general I believe, and with the already low player counts this season Epic needs to do something to steer back to the basics, this metaverse stuff has RUINED Fortnite. This game has become a corporate shell of what it once was and I believe the remainder of this year will very much so make or break Fortnite as a whole."</p>
<p>"Stuff like this cluttering the overview makes me disinterested in random creative maps. Those who put genuine effort into their maps often get hardly any attention," wrote a user on a <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/FortNiteBR/comments/1mtklb7/oh_wow/">separate reddit post</a>. Others point to the casual nature of user-made maps, as well as the high XP offered, as reasons for players to flock over.</p>
<p>Still, this new update for Fortnite creators is further shifting the game away from its Battle Royale roots into a Roblox-rivalling metaverse.</p>



        </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/fortnite-creators-will-soon-be-able-to-sell-in-game-items-to-make-more-money-but-are-creative-mode-offerings-like-steal-a-brainrot-what-players-want]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nvidia invests $5 billion into Intel to jointly develop PC and data center chips]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/780792/nvidia-intel-investment-pc-chips-data-center</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nvidia-invests-5-billion-into-intel-to-jointly-develop-pc-and-data-center-chips.1301256/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span id="follow-author-standard_article_details-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTY0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span></span><span>Tom Warren</span></span></span></p> <p><span>is a senior editor and author of <a href="https://www.theverge.com/notepad-microsoft-newsletter"><i>Notepad</i></a>, who has been covering all things Microsoft, PC, and tech for over 20 years.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Nvidia is throwing Intel a $5 billion life raft, just weeks after similar stakes from the US government and SoftBank. <a href="https://nvidianews.nvidia.com/news/nvidia-and-intel-to-develop-ai-infrastructure-and-personal-computing-products">Nvidia is investing</a> $5 billion in Intel common stock in a collaboration that will see the pair “jointly develop multiple generations of custom data center and PC products.”</p><p>Nvidia says Intel will help build “x86 system-on-chips (SoCs) that integrate Nvidia RTX GPU chiplets.” These chips will power a “wide range” of PCs, by closely integrating Intel’s CPUs with Nvidia’s GPUs. Intel and Nvidia already have a close partnership on many gaming laptops, but combining both on a single SoC is a big step further.</p><div><p>It will help Intel and Nvidia better compete with AMD, which has been gaining ground on Intel with its <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/6/24288948/amd-ryzen-7-9800x3d-review-cpu-processor-benchmark-test?showComments=1">impressive gaming desktop CPUs</a> and a wide variety of <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/6/2/24168951/amd-ryzen-ai-9-300-series-hx-laptop-processors">AI laptop processors</a>. It also raises further questions about the future of <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/6/24337345/intel-discrete-gpu-ces-2025">Intel’s Arc graphics card business</a>, especially if the company is now relying on Nvidia’s GPU expertise.</p></div><p>Nvidia’s investment in Intel comes after the chipmaker has reportedly been working with MediaTek to develop an accelerated processing unit (APU) that combines an Arm-powered CPU with Nvidia’s Blackwell GPU architecture. Nvidia has been <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/10/23/23929240/nvidia-amd-cpu-arm-pc-chips-2025-release-rumors">rumored to be working</a> on Arm-based laptop chips for years, and a <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/678000/nvidia-arm-gaming-laptop-mediatek-alienware">recent report suggested</a> Nvidia’s Arm-powered gaming laptop could launch later this year with Alienware.</p><p>Nvidia and Intel will also work together on connecting both their architectures via Nvidia’s NVLink communications link system that’s used in data centers to link GPUs together. “Intel will build Nvidia-custom x86 CPUs that Nvidia will integrate into its AI infrastructure platforms and offer to the market,” says Nvidia.</p><p>“This collaboration tightly couples Nvidia’s AI and accelerated computing stack with Intel’s CPUs and the vast x86 ecosystem — a fusion of two world-class platforms,” says Nvidia CEO Jensen Huang. “Together, we will expand our ecosystems and lay the foundation for the next era of computing.”</p><p>The US government agreed to take an around <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/764480/intel-donald-trump-lip-bu-tan-deal">10 percent stake in Intel last month</a>, valued at $8.9 billion. SoftBank is also investing $2 billion into Intel, as the struggling chipmaker has been pulling back on spending and <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/713388/intel-q2-2025-leave-germany-poland-costa-rica">laying off thousands</a> of workers.</p><p>Intel’s stock price jumped 28 percent in pre-market trading after Nvidia’s announcement.</p><p><span><a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/780792/nvidia-intel-investment-pc-chips-data-center#comments"><span>0<!-- --> <!-- -->Comments</span></a></span></p><div><p><span><strong>Follow topics and authors</strong> from this story to see more like this in your personalized homepage feed and to receive email updates.</span></p><ul><li id="follow-author-article_footer-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTY0"><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span><span>Tom Warren</span></span></span></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li></ul></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/news/780792/nvidia-intel-investment-pc-chips-data-center]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Sony seeks an impermissible monopoly on genre conventions:' Tencent moves to dismiss Horizon cloning lawsuit]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/-sony-seeks-an-impermissible-monopoly-on-genre-conventions-tencent-moves-to-dismiss-horizon-cloning-lawsuit</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sony-seeks-an-impermissible-monopoly-on-genre-conventions-tencent-moves-to-dismiss-horizon-cloning-lawsuit.1301253/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-testid="article-base-contributors"><div data-component="contributors"><p><a data-testid="contributor-name" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/author/chris-kerr" data-discover="true">Chris Kerr</a><span data-testid="contributor-title">, <!-- -->Senior Editor, News</span><span data-testid="contributor-title">, <!-- -->GameDeveloper.com</span></p><p data-testid="contributors-date">September 18, 2025</p></div><p><span data-component="icon" data-name="Clock"></span><span>3 Min<!-- --> <!-- -->Read</span></p></div><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Tencent is fighting back after </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/sony-files-lawsuit-against-tencent-for-allegedly-cloning-horizon-series">being sued by Sony</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> for allegedly cloning the PlayStation maker's popular Horizon series.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The Chinese conglomerate has filed a motion to dismiss the lawsuit, in which Sony described </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Light of Motiram</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">—an upcoming survival title developed by Tencent subsidiary Polaris Quest—as a "blatant" and "unlawful" copy of Horizon.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">As a result, Sony claims Tencent has committed copyright and trademark infringement. Perhaps unsurprisingly, Tencent disagrees.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">In a motion to dismiss filed in the United States District Court Northern District of California on September 17, 2025 (</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://storage.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.cand.453426/gov.uscourts.cand.453426.48.0.pdf">via Court Listener</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">), Tencent said Sony's lawsuit contains "undifferentiated, vague allegations" and claimed the Japanese firm has failed to "identify with specificity the trademark that allegedly was infringed."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">In addition, Tencent said Sony's lawsuit is "based almost entirely on speculation regarding future conduct." As such, Tencent claimed Sony has failed to allege facts that would justify exercising personal jurisdiction over Tencent Holdings, which is a foreign company incorporated in the Cayman Islands and headquartered in China. It suggested that alone is sufficient grounds to dismiss all of Sony's claims.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Plaintiff Sony has sued a grab-bag of Tencent companies—and ten unnamed defendants— about the unreleased video game </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Light of Motiram</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, alleging that the game copies elements from Sony's game </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Horizon Zero Dawn</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and its spinoffs," reads the filing.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/new-elder-scrolls-online-co-lead-says-studio-really-doesn-t-use-generative-ai" target="_self" data-discover="true">New Elder Scrolls Online co-lead says studio 'really doesn't use' generative AI</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"At bottom, Sony’s effort is not aimed at fighting off piracy, plagiarism, or any genuine threat to intellectual property. It is an improper attempt to fence off a well-trodden corner of popular culture and declare it Sony’s exclusive domain."&nbsp;</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Tencent claims Sony is attempting to &nbsp;transform 'ubiquitous genre ingredients into proprietary assets'">Tencent claims Sony is attempting to &nbsp;transform 'ubiquitous genre ingredients into proprietary assets'</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Tencent described Sony's attempt to brand Horizon as being unlike any "fictional world created before [or] since" as a "startling" bid to monopolize popular video game elements.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Long before this lawsuit was filed, the developers of </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Horizon Zero Dawn</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> publicly acknowledged that the very same game elements that, today, Sony claims to own exclusively, were in fact borrowed from an earlier game," added Tencent.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"In a behind-the-scenes documentary, the art director for </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Horizon Zero Dawn</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, Jan-Bart Van Beek, explained that the game's core conceit—an intrepid, red- haired woman navigating the ruins of a shattered civilization overrun by robotic beasts—had already been executed by a different video game studio in the 2013 title Enslaved</span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>: Odyssey to the West</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">."&nbsp;</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/sony-fires-ghost-of-yotei-artist-after-posts-joking-about-charlie-kirk-killing" target="_self" data-discover="true">Sony fires Ghost of Yotei artist after posts joking about Charlie Kirk killing</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Tencent said Sony has "tellingly" ignored the above facts in an effort to transform "ubiquitous genre ingredients into proprietary assets."&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"By suing over an unreleased project that merely employs the same time-honored tropes embraced by scores of other games released both before and after Horizon—like </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Enslaved</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">Wild, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Far Cry: Primal</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Far Cry: New Dawn</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Outer Wilds</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Biomutant</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, and many more—Sony seeks an impermissible monopoly on genre conventions," adds Tencent.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">&nbsp;In conclusion, Tencent asserts the lawsuit filed by Sony consists "almost entirely of speculative allegations" related to possible future conduct and should be dismissed as a result.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"These allegations of hypothetical future involvement in preparations for a forthcoming beta test and eventual game release—and vague allegations of unspecified 'current' involvement in the same—are insufficient to support the exercise of subject matter jurisdiction."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"The Court therefore lacks jurisdiction to decide the claims against the Served Defendants(even if they were adequately pled, which they are not, see supra III.B.) and should dismiss them on this independent basis."&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://storage.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.cand.453426/gov.uscourts.cand.453426.48.0.pdf">You can read the full document on Court Listener</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/devs-are-more-worried-than-ever-that-generative-ai-will-lower-the-quality-of-games" target="_self" data-discover="true">Devs are more worried than ever that generative AI will lower the quality of games</a></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Senior Editor, News, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer news editor Chris Kerr is an award-winning journalist and reporter with over a decade of experience in the game industry. His byline has appeared in notable print and digital publications including Edge, Stuff, Wireframe, International Business Times, and&nbsp;</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="http://pocketgamer.biz/">PocketGamer.biz</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. Throughout his career, Chris has covered major industry events including GDC, PAX Australia, Gamescom, Paris Games Week, and Develop Brighton. He has featured on the judging panel at The Develop Star Awards on multiple occasions and appeared on BBC Radio 5 Live to discuss breaking news.</span></p></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/-sony-seeks-an-impermissible-monopoly-on-genre-conventions-tencent-moves-to-dismiss-horizon-cloning-lawsuit]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Genre-Bending 'Baroque YA' Collection Headed To Switch In Japan]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/genre-bending-baroque-ya-collection-headed-to-switch-in-japan</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/genre-bending-baroque-ya-collection-headed-to-switch-in-japan.1301244/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Multiple genres in one easy-to-store package</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure><a title="baroque YA collection announcement" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/85f54e2137f79/baroque-ya-collection-announcement.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Sting</em></figcaption></figure><p>Japanese dev outfit Sting has just announced <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/baroque_ya">Baroque YA</a>, a collection of four games from the genre-spanning series, will release on Switch (in Japan only, for now) on <strong>18th December</strong>.</p>
<p>Originally released for the Sega Saturn all the way back in the Spice Girls-heady days of 1998, the first <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/wii/baroque">Baroque</a> is a post-apocalyptic RPG in the roguelike vein that was eventually ported to Wii in 2008.</p>
<p>The game was then followed by a smattering of further entries, all of which are included in this new release, jumping genres from visual novel to platformer and shoot 'em up.</p>
<p>Here's the complete list of what's made the cut:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>BAROQUE: Original Version</strong></li>
<li><strong>BAROQUE Syndrome</strong></li>
<li><strong>BAROQUE Shooting: Reversed</strong></li>
<li><strong>BAROQUE ~Become a Meta-Being~ Revive</strong></li>
</ul>
<figure><a title="baroque YA collection announcement" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/11ca8aa7c7bdc/baroque-ya-collection-announcement.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Sting</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>Hopefully, at some point we'll see this collection make it over to the West. But for now the old tried and tested means of grabbing this from the Japan eShop (or importing from your purveyor of choice) will have to suffice for big fans who just can't hold out. We'll keep you posted with any further news.</p>
<hr>
<p><em>Looking forward to Baroque YA? Played any games in the series, or <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/wii/baroque">the Wii version</a> or the original? Check out the trailer for that 2008 version below if you need a reminder.</em><em><br></em></p>
</section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://www.gematsu.com/2025/09/sting-announces-baroque-ya-for-switch" rel="noopener" href="https://www.gematsu.com/2025/09/sting-announces-baroque-ya-for-switch">gematsu.com</a>, via <a title="External Link: https://www.resetera.com/threads/sting-announces-baroque-collection-for-switch-in-japan-original-game-syndrome-shooting-and-become-a-meta-being.1301103/" rel="noopener" href="https://www.resetera.com/threads/sting-announces-baroque-collection-for-switch-in-japan-original-game-syndrome-shooting-and-become-a-meta-being.1301103/">resetera.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-info/32dcf523bad44e91e76da24f280d1578 @ 1758197706 --></div></article><div><p>PJ is a staff writer across Hookshot Media. He's been playing video games pretty much nonstop since the early 1980s, which is ages ago. Favourite genres include RPGs, puzzle games and lovely big single player adventures of all kinds. The weirder the better.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/PJOReilly"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('PJOReilly');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/genre-bending-baroque-ya-collection-headed-to-switch-in-japan]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 To Launch on PlayStation 5 In November – Rumor]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/microsoft-flight-simulator-2024-playstation-5-november/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/microsoft-flight-simulator-2024-to-launch-on-playstation-5-in-november-%E2%80%93-rumor.1301241/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 is reportedly the next Xbox exclusive to launch on PlayStation 5.</p>



<p>In a new report shared today, Polish publication <a href="https://www.ppe.pl/news/383315/wiemy-jaki-kolejny-ex-microsoftu-trafi-na-ps5-co-z-pudelkami-oblivion-remastered.html">PPE</a> revealed that the latest entry in the Microsoft series will make its debut on PlayStation 5 sometime this November. No other information about this new edition of the game has been revealed besides the fact that it will receive a retail release alongside the digital release on the PlayStation Network.</p>



<p>Although its PlayStation 5 release has yet to be confirmed, there's a good chance that PPE's report is correct, as Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 has been repeatedly mentioned by <a href="https://wccftech.com/halo-the-master-chief-collection-playstation-5-switch-2/">reliable leakers</a> as one of the Xbox exclusives that will launch on other platforms before the end of the year, alongside other titles such as Halo: The Master Chief Collection and Starfield, whose PS5 debut is rumored to have<a href="https://wccftech.com/starfield-playstation-5-2026-poor-sales/"> moved to 2026</a>. With the Tokyo Game Show right around the corner, there's a very good chance we won't have to wait too long to learn if the game is indeed launching on PlayStation 5 before the end of the year.</p>



<p>If Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 launches on PlayStation 5 this year, it will be only the latest among many other former Xbox exclusives that have made the jump to the Sony current-generation system. Among them are Sea of Thieves, Grounded, and Forza Horizon 5. The multiplatform strategy seems to be working out, as some of these former Xbox exclusives are doing great on Sony's consoles, so much so that<a href="https://wccftech.com/forza-horizon-5-best-selling-game-playstation-5/"> Forza Horizon 5 is currently the best-selling 2025 PS5 game to </a>, an impressive feat to accomplish for a game already available on other platforms.</p>





			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/microsoft-flight-simulator-2024-playstation-5-november/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Would-be Disco Elysium successor XXX Nightshift morphs from an isometric RPG into a third-person ski resort murder mystery]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/would-be-disco-elysium-successor-xxx-nightshift-morphs-from-an-isometric-rpg-into-a-third-person-ski-resort-murder-mystery</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/would-be-disco-elysium-successor-xxx-nightshift-morphs-from-an-isometric-rpg-into-a-third-person-ski-resort-murder-mystery.1301238/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture data-src-full="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/xxx-nightshift-name-change-tangerine-antarctic-01.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" src="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/xxx-nightshift-name-change-tangerine-antarctic-01.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/xxx-nightshift-name-change-tangerine-antarctic-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 690px) and (min-resolution: 2x)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/xxx-nightshift-name-change-tangerine-antarctic-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 690px)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/xxx-nightshift-name-change-tangerine-antarctic-01.jpg?width=414&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-resolution: 2x)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Dark Math Games</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Dark Math Games, one of the multiple studios staffed by former <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/disco-elysium">Disco Elysium</a> developers to pop up and announce a very Disco Elysiumy RPG last year, have given their game a revamp. <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/xxx-nightshift">XXX Nightshift</a> is now called Tangerine Antarctic, with the switch also bringing a shift from isometric perspective to third-person.</p>
<p>If you missed the recent flourishing of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/theres-a-playable-disco-elysium-2-prototype-in-the-wilds-according-to-a-report-on-clashes-between-the-spiritual-successors">Disco spiritual successors</a> created by ex-ZA/UMers, the others include Longdue's RPG <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/first-look-at-disco-elysium-spiritual-successor-hopetown-shows-a-painterly-gorgeous-and-utterly-unconvincing-rpg">Hopetown</a> and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/sure-why-not-third-group-of-former-disco-elysium-devs-announce-revolutionary-new-rpg-studio">Summer Eternal</a>'s mystery project. Meanwhile, Disco writer Robert Kurvitz and artist Aleksander Rostov are making something for a studio called Red Info, and ZA/UM themselves are <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/zero-parades-looks-to-be-the-new-name-of-zaums-post-disco-elysium-spy-crpg-not-that-its-reveal-paraded-that-aroundre">working on a new CRPG called Zero Parades</a>. It's all very easy to keep track of.</p>
<!--more-->

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Tangerine Antarctic - A true detective RPG. Dialogue Gameplay Trailer" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/bXQRS5L_aWo?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Tangerine Antarctic - A true detective RPG. Dialogue Gameplay Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/bXQRS5L_aWo?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/bXQRS5L_aWo?autoplay=1" title="Tangerine Antarctic - A true detective RPG. Dialogue Gameplay Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bXQRS5L_aWo" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>


<p>According to Dark Math Games founder Timo Albert, the pitch for Tangerine Antarctic is as follows: "Set at the World’s End ski village at Mount Hope, British Antartica, Tangerine Antarctic is the name of the in-game hotel, designed by renown Estonian architect Kaur Stőőr, where most of the games’ action takes place. This is where you are stuck because of the blizzard and must solve the mysterious murders. And Tangerine Antarctic is one of the important characters of this true detective's RPG."</p><p>The switch from isometric to third person could be construed as an effort to distance the game from the 'Disco Elysium successor' label that's been applied with various degrees of cynicism to all of the projects I mentioned earlier. However, as you can see from the freshly posted peek at a bit of Tangerine Antarctic's dialogue above, it still very much looks like someone's reinterpreted Disco's homework.</p>
<p>Dark Math's revamped Steam page for the game promises "deep single-player role-playing with seismic choices" and a "unique companion dynamic" that helps you solve those murders. The devs write that your "choices, substances, and experiences" will all "affect how you hear and feel the world". It also boasts a "Dopamine Buffet", which is described thusly: "Rehearse your moves. Dance through crime scenes. Drift through parties. Or find pleasure in completing the simplest chores. Get better with every action you take."</p>
<p>So, you're like Hercule Poirot with the ability to do the macarena whenever someone snuffs it, and also the power to do some "Marafet calculations to alter your time and space". Sounds like it could be fun, but who knows with any of these games at this point.</p>
<p>Tangerine Antarctic doesn't have a release date, but you can <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3261450/Tangerine_Antarctic/">wishlist it on Steam</a>.</p>

        </div>
      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/would-be-disco-elysium-successor-xxx-nightshift-morphs-from-an-isometric-rpg-into-a-third-person-ski-resort-murder-mystery]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tencent responds to Sony lawsuit against "slavish" Horizon clone, stating its claims of originality are "startling"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/tencent-responds-to-sony-lawsuit-against-slavish-horizon-clone-stating-its-claims-of-originality-are-startling</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/tencent-responds-to-sony-lawsuit-against-slavish-horizon-clone-stating-its-claims-of-originality-are-startling.1301232/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>"Sony seeks an impermissible monopoly on genre conventions."</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
      <picture data-src-full="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/horizon-motiram.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" src="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/horizon-motiram.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/horizon-motiram.png?width=570&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 570px) and (min-resolution: 2x)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/horizon-motiram.png?width=570&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 570px)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/horizon-motiram.png?width=414&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-resolution: 2x)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Sony / Tencent / Eurogamer</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/companies/tencent">Tencent</a> has responded to Sony's Horizon lawsuit, claiming its action adventure game Light of Motiram uses "time-honoured" genre tropes.</p>
<p>Back in July, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/sony-sues-tencent-over-slavish-horizon-knock-off-light-of-motiram">Sony filed a lawsuit against Tencent</a> claiming its newly-revealed game was a "slavish clone" of the Horizon games, owing to its red-headed heroine, post-apocalyptic world, and robotic enemies.</p>
<p>Tencent has now filed its response in a motion to dismiss, stating Sony "seeks an impermissible monopoly on genre conventions" (thanks <a href="https://thegamepost.com/sony-monopoly-genre-tencent-horizon-lawsuit-light-of-motiram/">The GamePost</a>). It reads as something of an attack against Guerrilla's games, stating Sony's claims of Horizon's originality are "startling".</p>

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="21 Horizon Forbidden West Advanced Tips - HORIZON FORBIDDEN WEST NEW PS5 GAMEPLAY" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/xN4UOHwx6ow?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>21 Horizon Forbidden West Advanced Tips - HORIZON FORBIDDEN WEST NEW PS5 GAMEPLAY</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/xN4UOHwx6ow?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/xN4UOHwx6ow?autoplay=1" title="21 Horizon Forbidden West Advanced Tips - HORIZON FORBIDDEN WEST NEW PS5 GAMEPLAY">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>21 Horizon Forbidden West Advanced Tips - HORIZON FORBIDDEN WEST NEW PS5 GAMEPLAY<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xN4UOHwx6ow" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>


<p>"Plaintiff Sony has sued a grab-bag of Tencent companies - and ten unnamed defendants - about the unreleased video game Light of Motiram, alleging that the game copies elements from Sony's game <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/horizon-zero-dawn">Horizon Zero Dawn</a> and its spinoffs," said Tencent.</p>
<p>"At bottom, Sony's effort is not aimed at fighting off piracy, plagiarism, or any genuine threat to intellectual property. It is an improper attempt to fence off a well-trodden corner of popular culture and declare it Sony's exclusive domain."</p>
<p>Sony previously claimed Horizon Zero Dawn was "like no fictional world created before [or] since". In response, Tencent claimed this is "flatly contradicted" by Guerrilla itself, pointing to a behind-the-scenes documentary where art director Jan-Bart Van Beek admitted the game's central premise has been done before - specifically in 2013 game Enslaved: Odyssey to the West.</p>
<p>"That claim is startling, because it is flatly contradicted by Sony’s own developers, not to mention the long history of video games featuring the same elements that Sony seeks to monopolise through this lawsuit," said Tencent.</p>
<p>"Sony's Complaint tellingly ignores these facts. Instead, it tries to transform ubiquitous genre ingredients into proprietary assets."</p>
<p>It continued: "By suing over an unreleased project that merely employs the same time-honoured tropes embraced by scores of other games released both before and after Horizon - like Enslaved, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/zelda-breath-of-the-wild-walkthrough-guide-tips-4857">The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild</a>, Far Cry: Primal, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/far-cry-new-dawn">Far Cry: New Dawn</a>, Outer Wilds, Biomutant, and many more - Sony seeks an impermissible monopoly on genre conventions."</p>
<figure>

<figcaption>Comparison of characters from Sony's initial Complaint | <span>Image credit: <cite>Sony</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Tencent's response also addressed a meeting at GDC in March 2024 where Tencent representatives pitched a licensed Horizon mobile game that Sony ultimately turned down. The Chinese company stated no executives or employees were at the meeting, so nothing at the meeting "is alleged to be an act of copyright or trademark infringement".</p>
<p>What's more, Tencent has claimed Sony is attempting to sue the wrong company, so wants the case thrown out on legal grounds.</p>
<p>While Sony's lawsuit is against Tencent America, Proxima Beta U.S., and Tencent Holdings, Light of Motiram - according to Tencent's response - is being developed and published by Polaris Quest / Aurora Studios, a developer operating under Tencent Technology (Shanghai) Co. Ltd, and Proxima Beta PTE Ltd, a company in Singapore "doing business as '<a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/companies/tencent-games">Tencent Games</a>' and/or 'Level Infinite'".</p><p>"None of the served defendants develop and market the Light of Motiram video game that Sony alleges infringes its intellectual property in the Horizon franchise," said Tencent. It stated Tencent Holdings Ltd. is simply a parent company and has no involvement in Light of Motiram.</p>
<p>"Sony's threadbare, conclusory allegations improperly lump these Defendants together with the foreign companies alleged to be responsible for the core conduct at issue. Sony's vague allegations against 'Tencent' or 'Defendants' generally cannot substantiate the claims it brings against Tencent America, Proxima Beta U.S., or Tencent Holdings specifically."</p>
<p>Lastly, Light of Motiram won't release until the end of 2027, meaning Sony's lawsuit is built on what the game "might" look like before it's even out, said Tencent.</p>
<p>Still, shortly after Sony began suing Tencent, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/tencent-quietly-updates-slavish-horizon-clone-light-of-motirams-steam-page">Light of Motiram's Steam page was quietly altered</a> to remove, edit, and/or replace key art, as well as rewrite the description.</p>



        </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/tencent-responds-to-sony-lawsuit-against-slavish-horizon-clone-stating-its-claims-of-originality-are-startling]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Random: Wait, Is Donkey Kong Bananza's DLC Hiding A Neat Namco Easter Egg?]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/random-wait-is-donkey-kong-bananzas-dlc-hiding-a-neat-namco-easter-egg</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/random-wait-is-donkey-kong-bananzas-dlc-hiding-a-neat-namco-easter-egg.1301220/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
<figure><a title="Donkey Kong Bananza DLC" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/a6184125b5da8/donkey-kong-bananza-dlc.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Nintendo</em></figcaption></figure><p>There is a lot to be distracted by in the <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/donkey-kong-bananza-dk-island-and-emerald-rush">Donkey Kong Bananza DLC</a>. It might be the beautifully reimagined DK Island, the fast and frantic Emerald Rush mode or... actually, that's about it. But those are two pretty distracting things! Distracting enough, we'd say, for a sneaky Easter Egg to slip under the radar.</p>
<p>If you had asked us yesterday whether we spotted the Namco reference in the DKB DLC, then all you would have got in return is a blank stare — and that's with near enough 10 hours of Emerald Rush roguelike runs under our belts. But modding extraordinaire <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/ohpoorpup.bsky.social">Christa Lee</a> has opened our eyes. What's been seen cannot be unseen.</p><div><figure data-videoid="fMx2XNyAq4E" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fMx2XNyAq4E?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><iframe title="YouTube Video" src="javascript:''" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/fMx2XNyAq4E?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fMx2XNyAq4E?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" type="text/html" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed5d98e4tsxwny&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><figcaption><p><a title="Watch This Video on YouTube" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fMx2XNyAq4E" rel="noopener">Watch on <strong><span></span> YouTube</strong> <span></span></a></p>
<p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>834k</span></a></p>
</figcaption></figure></div>
<p>Okay, let's cut to the chase. When you finish an Emerald Rush run, DK's VoidCo employee card pops up on screen so you can see all the rewards you've pulled in. But if you take a closer look at the platforming primate's employee number, you'll see a pretty recognisable series of digits (if you're a Pac-Man fan, that is): 7650.</p>

<p>For those <em>not</em> in the know, 7,650 is the maximum number of points you can pick up in a Pac-Man game. It's a recurring figure that cropped up in a bunch of Namco-developed titles, apparently due to the numbers' <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Numeric_substitution_in_Japanese">gorowase</a> substitutions sounding like the company name (7='Na', 6='Mu', 5='Ko', 0='O').</p>
<p>Now, sure, its appearance in the Bananza DLC <em>could</em> be a complete coincidence, but we doubt it. Nintendo clearly has knowledge of it — remember the Wii U Smash Bros. '<a href="https://www.ssbwiki.com/The_Big_7650!">The Big 7650!</a>' event? Yep, we forgot it too — so we think the employee number is a nice nod to the high-score-achievers and arcade originators of the past.</p>
<p>We have smashed our way through the DLC's interactive credits, and we saw no sign of Bandai Namco having done any work on it. Then again, the studio has paired up with Nintendo on various things in the past, so this isn't to say that the team had <em>no</em> sway over the roguelike add-on.</p>
<p>It's a neat little nod, and one that definitely would have passed us by had it not been pointed out to us (so that's for the heads up, Christa!). We had a good time with the DK Island &amp; Emerald Rush DLC, praising the fast and fun roguelike mode, but feeling a little short-changed by the rest of the experience. You can find our full thoughts in the <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/nintendo-switch-2/donkey-kong-bananza-dk-island-and-emerald-rush">review</a> below.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:187829 @ 1758197825 -->
<p><em>Did you notice this Namco nod in the DKB DLC? Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/random-wait-is-donkey-kong-bananzas-dlc-hiding-a-neat-namco-easter-egg]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Two Namco classics join Nintendo Switch Online's Game Boy Advance library]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/two-namco-classics-join-nintendo-switch-onlines-game-boy-advance-library</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/two-namco-classics-join-nintendo-switch-onlines-game-boy-advance-library.1301217/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>

  <figure>
      <picture data-src-full="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/klonoa-gba.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" src="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/klonoa-gba.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/klonoa-gba.png?width=570&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 570px) and (min-resolution: 2x)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/klonoa-gba.png?width=570&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 570px)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/klonoa-gba.png?width=414&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-resolution: 2x)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Nintendo</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
    <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Two Namco classic Game Boy Advance games are joining the Nintendo Switch Online catalogue.
</p>
<p>
First up is Mr. Driller 2, the iconic puzzle game that started life as an arcade game before being ported to the GBA for the Japanese launch. It was later released worldwide, and was previously re-released for the Wii U Virtual Console.
</p>
<p>
The second is Klonoa: Empire of Dreams, a 2D platformer spin-off of the console games that began on the PS1. By comparison, it has more puzzle-like gameplay and introduced a new realm to the ongoing series.
</p>

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Game Boy Advance – September 2025 Games Update" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/vX3DG9XMG4s?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Game Boy Advance – September 2025 Games Update</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/vX3DG9XMG4s?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/vX3DG9XMG4s?autoplay=1" title="Game Boy Advance – September 2025 Games Update">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Game Boy Advance – September 2025 Games Update<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vX3DG9XMG4s" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>


<p>
Both games will be available from 25th September for Nintendo Switch Online subscribers with the Expansion Pack.
</p>
<p>
Earlier this month, Nintendo added an <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-switch-nintendo-classics-app-just-got-a-cool-hidden-game-boy-advance-easter-egg">Easter egg to the Game Boy Advance app</a>, which adds the classic bootup sequence if you twiddle the analogue stick.
</p>
<p>
And at <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/heres-everything-announced-in-nintendos-latest-direct">last week's Nintendo Direct</a>, the company announced Virtual Boy games will be coming to Switch Online too, along with a dedicated accessory to play them in 3D - it comes in both plastic and cardboard varieties.
</p>
<p>
For more on Nintendo Switch Online, check out our list of <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/all-nintendo-switch-online-games-available-to-play-right-now">all the games available to subscribers</a>.
</p>

        </div>


      </article>



  
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/two-namco-classics-join-nintendo-switch-onlines-game-boy-advance-library]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[AI Animal Crossing Hack Turns The Villagers Against Tom Nook]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ai-animal-crossing-hack-turns-the-villagers-against-tom-nook/1100-6534847/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ai-animal-crossing-hack-turns-the-villagers-against-tom-nook.1301208/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6534847">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Nintendo's original <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/animal-crossing/" data-ref-id="5000-3602">Animal Crossing</a> on GameCube helped pave the way for many of the cozy games players have today. The cute animal villagers largely enjoy a blissful experience, but a new AI hack has the town feeling that Tom Nook--the raccoon who basically controls the local economy based on bells as currency--is a tyrant who needs to go down.</p><p>Software engineer <a href="https://joshfonseca.com/blogs/animal-crossing-llm" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Josh Fonseca</a> created this Animal Crossing hack (via <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/09/animal-crossing-mod-uses-ai-to-orchestrate-anti-tom-nook-villager-revolt/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Ars Technica</a>), and he explained at length how he pulled it off in the accompanying YouTube video. The GameCube software wasn't really designed to hacked like this, but Fonseca was eventually able to find his way in and give Animal Crossing some commands that could be understood by the game's code.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7AyEzA5ziE0" data-width="100%" data-height="100%" data-video-start="1115">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/7AyEzA5ziE0?start=1115" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>Fonseca initially tried to use a single live language model AI to write new dialogue for the characters, while also drawing their character traits from online wikis. According to Fonseca, that approach failed because he was asking the AI to do too much. In the end, he set aside one AI program to handle the dialogue, while another program essentially directed its in-game presentation.</p><p>Once this was done, Fonseca introduced some modern elements to the game including news about current events. He also cheekily instructed the AI to depict resentment towards Tom Nook, which grows into unrest among the villagers over time. There's no endgame conclusion where the villagers confront Tom, but it is a very funny turn for these gentle creatures.</p><p>Former Nintendo of America localization manager Leslie Swan recently shared that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/animal-crossing-almost-had-a-better-title-in-the-west-but-nintendo-rejected-it/1100-6534576/" data-ref-id="1100-6534576">Animal Crossing almost had another name</a> that was ultimately rejected. The most recent game in the franchise, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/animal-crossing-new-horizons/" data-ref-id="5000-487113">Animal Crossing: New Horizons</a>, was released in 2020. That game <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ahead-of-switch-2s-launch-animal-crossing-new-horizons-gets-first-update-in-years/1100-6531857/">received a Switch 2 update</a> earlier this year. Although there aren't any new titles in the franchise at the moment, there are <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/animal-crossing-crocs-let-you-bring-your-favourite-villagers-everywhere-now-available-to-order/1100-6534311/">Animal Crossing Crocs</a> that are available for order.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ai-animal-crossing-hack-turns-the-villagers-against-tom-nook/1100-6534847/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hyrule Warriors: Age Of Imprisonment Gets New Trailer Revealing Some Save Data Surprises]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/hyrule-warriors-age-of-imprisonment-gets-new-trailer-revealing-some-save-data-surprises</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hyrule-warriors-age-of-imprisonment-gets-new-trailer-revealing-some-save-data-surprises.1301199/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Free blades if you've played TOTK or AoC</p>
</section></header><div><section>

<p>It's not too long now until we finally get our hands on <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/hyrule-warriors-age-of-imprisonment">Hyrule Warriors: Age of Imprisonment</a> on Switch 2, with that <strong>2nd November</strong> release date rapidly approaching.</p>
<p>To sate our appetites in the interim, Nintendo has dropped a new teaser trailer showing off Koei Tecmo's very slick-looking Musou action featuring all of your favourite lunatics from the Zelda series. Oh, and Zelda herself, who is shown kicking seven shades out of huge armies in gameplay footage that, as a big Warriors franchise fan, this writer is incredibly excited about. It's all so smooth, so 60fps, so crystal clear and beautiful. Hold me, Tingle!</p>
<p>Now, beyond the excitement of finally getting a 60fps Musou game in the palm of our hands (and one that happens to look incredible, to boot), the trailer above also unveils some goodies to be nabbed for players who have a <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/legend-of-zelda-tears-of-the-kingdom-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom</a> and/or <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/hyrule_warriors_age_of_calamity">Hyrule Warriors: Age of Calamity</a> save on their system.</p>
<p>Tears of the Kingdom data nets you a <strong>High Guard's Sword</strong> to be used in the game, whereas Age of Calamity nets you a <strong>High Guard's Claymore</strong>. Nothing groundbreaking, but welcome nonetheless.</p>

<p>If November is too far away, remember that the previous entry in the Hyrule Warriors series is playable on Switch 2 with a much improved, now-stable frame rate - one of various games to get <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/features/33-games-with-secret-performance-bumps-you-should-revisit-on-switch-2">unnannounced, 'secret' updates</a> thanks to the newer hardware's grunt. If the frequent dips put you off on your Switch 1, now's a good time to catch up.</p>
<p>And if that's not enough Musou for you, remember that Koei Tecmo is bringing Omega Force's <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/dynasty-warriors-origins">Dynasty Warriors: Origins</a> to Switch 2 in January, too. Plenty of hacking and/or slashing to be getting on with, then!</p>
<hr>
<p><em>Looking forward to Hyrule Warriors: Age of Imprisonment? Prefer your Warriors without the Zelda trappings? Let us know in the comments.</em></p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:188006,187851,131556 @ 1758195068 --></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1JRRdphP_q8&amp;amp;t=1s" rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1JRRdphP_q8&amp;t=1s">youtube.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-info/feee303afe3e65e9800f83c403e11ddb @ 1758198021 --></div></article><div><p>PJ is a staff writer across Hookshot Media. He's been playing video games pretty much nonstop since the early 1980s, which is ages ago. Favourite genres include RPGs, puzzle games and lovely big single player adventures of all kinds. The weirder the better.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/PJOReilly"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('PJOReilly');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/hyrule-warriors-age-of-imprisonment-gets-new-trailer-revealing-some-save-data-surprises]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vampire: The Masquerade – Bloodlines 2 DLC Clans added to the base game, with new DLC stories revealed]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/09/18/vampire-the-masquerade-bloodlines-2-dlc-clans-added-to-the-base-game-with-new-dlc-stories-revealed/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/vampire-the-masquerade-%E2%80%93-bloodlines-2-dlc-clans-added-to-the-base-game-with-new-dlc-stories-revealed.1301190/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Paradox Interactive and The Chinese Room have announced that the Lasombra and Toreador clans will now be included as part of the Vampire: The Masquerade – Bloodlines 2 base game, following strong criticism of the previous plans to have them be premium DLC and for pricier editions of the game. In their place two Story Packs will be created and launched in 2026 as part of an Expansion Pass available separately or with the Premium Edition.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/vampire-the-masquerade-bloodlines-2">Vampire: The Masquerade – Bloodlines 2</a> has a release date confirmed for 21st October 2025 across PS5, Xbox Series X|S and PC.</p>


<p>“Thanks to our community for the frank feedback on Bloodlines 2 and the Premium Edition. That feedback made it clear: Lasombra and Toreador belong in the base game, so that is what we are doing,” said Marco Behrmann, White Wolf Executive Vice President and Bloodlines 2 Executive Producer. “We’d also like to thank The Chinese Room for their quick turnaround on the concepts for the post-launch Story Packs. We’re constantly impressed by their creativity and skill in weaving enticing narrative threads that expand on the main story in Bloodlines 2.”</p>
<p>This change now means that there will be six clans available to all players – the Banu Haqim, Brujah, Lasombra, Toreador, Tremere and Ventrue – which are equivalent to character classes in other RPGs.</p>
<p>The two new stories are Loose Cannon, which will give players Brujah Sheriff Benny’s perspective and let them experience his story of relentless pursuit, set for Q2 2026, and <b><i>The Flower &amp; the Flame, which follows</i></b> Toreador Primogen Ysabella’s path to creating her dark magnum opus in Q3 2026.</p>

<p>Both story packs can be purchased separately for $14.99/£12.99/€14.99, and there’s also Santa Monica Memories cosmetic pack with decor items inspired by the original cult classic Vampire: The Masquerade – Bloodlines to feature in Phyre’s in-game apartment for $11.99/£9.99/€11.99. They’re bundled into the $34.99/£28.99/€34.99 Expansion Pass or as part of the Premium Edition $89.99/£74.99/€89.99. Deluxe Edition ($69.99/£58.50/€69.99) is now worse value, as they get the Santa Monica Memories included, but there doesn’t seem to be a cheaper Expansion Pass option for them.</p>
<p>Physical Day One and limited Premium Editions are to be released in collaboration with PLAION, including character cards, a journal, and a steelbook case.</p>
<p>Bloodlines 2 is a game that’s evoked plenty of strong opinions amongst fans of the 2004 original, and the Vampire: The Masquerade setting in general. First announced back in March 2019 with Seattle-based developer Hardsuit Labs, the game’s development struggled to the extent that <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2021/02/23/vampire-the-masquerade-bloodlines-2-delay-release-date-2021-hardsuit-labs-cancelled-developer/">Paradox made the decision to pull the project from Hardsuit Labs</a> and, <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2021/10/14/vampire-the-masquerade-bloodlines-2-was-nearly-cancelled-instead-of-getting-a-new-developer/">after considering cancelling it outright</a>, brought in The Chinese Room to reboot the game.&nbsp;<a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2023/09/04/vampire-the-masquerade-bloodlines-2-new-developer-is-the-chinese-room-coming-in-2024/">Bloodlines 2 was re-revealed</a> in September 2023, the pitch and overarching story for Bloodlines 2 shifting compared to the originally revealed version of the game.</p>
<p>Still set in Seattle, the narrative has shifted away from casting you as a freshly fledged vamp and you are instead Phyre, an Elder Vampire who is known for being a harbinger of tumult and sudden change. That, for some, detracts from the fantasy of the setting, even if you are still able to tap into the abilities of a clan of your choosing and role play through the world. At the same time, it could be more accessible as an entry point for those unfamiliar with the TTRPG or original game.</p>
<p>We’ve been hands on with the opening couple hours of the game in the run up to Gamescom, and there’s an intriguing blend of characters, dire situations and powerful vampire types. <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/08/19/fangs-on-vampire-the-masquerade-bloodlines-2s-opening-hours-and-the-lasombra-clan/">Check out our preview here</a>.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/09/18/vampire-the-masquerade-bloodlines-2-dlc-clans-added-to-the-base-game-with-new-dlc-stories-revealed/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Alleged Marvel 1943: Rise of Hydra fight video shows Black Panther having an Angry Cat moment in a bar]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/alleged-marvel-1943-rise-of-hydra-fight-video-shows-black-panther-having-an-angry-cat-moment-in-a-bar</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/alleged-marvel-1943-rise-of-hydra-fight-video-shows-black-panther-having-an-angry-cat-moment-in-a-bar.1301184/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Rumoured screens and footage from Hennig-penned action game appear online</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture data-src-full="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/1_9q10UPP.jpeg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" src="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/1_9q10UPP.jpeg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/1_9q10UPP.jpeg?width=690&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 690px) and (min-resolution: 2x)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/1_9q10UPP.jpeg?width=690&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 690px)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/1_9q10UPP.jpeg?width=414&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-resolution: 2x)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>MP1st / Rock Paper Shotgun</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Development footage of what appears to be upcoming superhero action game <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/marvel-1943-rise-of-hydra">Marvel 1943: Rise Of Hydra</a> has exploded upon the internet like <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/black-panther">Black Panther</a> clawing his way into a seedy Parisian bar and flinging himself at alt-fascist soldiers in a whirlwind of kicked chairs and bursting bottles. This also being the content of said video. 
</p>
<p>
Assuming the leaked goods are the Real McCoy, they suggest that the game will be a fast and furious brawler with a fair amount of environment destruction, which is probably what you're expecting from a game with Azzuri and Steve Rogers on the poster. 
</p><!--more-->
<p>
The <a href="https://streamable.com/ka4jm7">footage</a> comes to us via <a href="https://mp1st.com/news/first-look-gameplay-marvel-1943-rise-of-hydra-surfaces">MP1st</a>, who attribute it to "a developer who worked on the game", and say it was created between 2022 and 2023, but do not link to the portfolio that originally contained it. 
</p>
<p>
They've also found <a href="https://imgur.com/a/jF1GGSk#oHzWJeF">a selection of images</a> that show various possible Marvel 1943 environments, including a plush lamp-lit hallway, a vast cavern entrance with dangling stalactites, a bunch of building-top areas with glass conservatory roofs, and a hazy nocturnal view of searchlights over what is presumably Paris.
</p><p>
Assuming it's the Genuine MacGyver, the leaked Black Panther video is very clearly WIP. The fixed camera perspective suggests that it's an internal test, knocked together to illustrate the flow of a typical Marvel 1943 fight scene. As such, we should be careful about reading too much into it. But I have to say, I do enjoy the 5am cat energy here. 
</p>
<p>
If you live with a younger feline, you'll be familiar with that time of day when they Catch The Crazy and start zipping about, striking amateur ninjitsu poses and climbing every nearby human bodypart/piece of furniture. I'd love it if Black Panther had a Zoomies mode that caused him to spontaneously sit on Captain America's face. I'd love it if he had a special terrain execution that consisted of hiding under the sofa and slashing people's feet off. "D'awww," the abbreviated sturmtruppen of Hydra would coo, clutching their bloody stumps. "What on Earth is going through his ickle head."
</p>
<p>
Developed by Skydance New Media and published by Plaion, with former Naughty Dog scribe Amy Hennig on-board to produce and co-write, Marvel 1943: Rise of Hydra is the story of Captain America and the Panther fighting Hydra in occupied France, though part of it is set in Wakanda. It's inspired by the comicbook series Captain America/Black Panther: Flags of Our Fathers.
</p>
<p>
<a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/uncharted-directors-black-panther-and-captain-america-game-revealed-as-marvel-1943-rise-of-hydra-out-2025">Announced in 2024</a>, the game is <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/marvel-1943-rise-of-hydra-release-date-pushed-to-early-2026-for-polishing">slated to land in early 2026</a>. Which is not that far away, and Plaion have shown us little of the game beyond a couple of 'cinematic' trailers. I'll ask them if they have any comment on this footage, and when we can see more of the game.
</p>

        </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/alleged-marvel-1943-rise-of-hydra-fight-video-shows-black-panther-having-an-angry-cat-moment-in-a-bar]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Studio of former Disco Elysium staff rename forthcoming detective RPG and shift from familiar isometric perspective as rivalry continues]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/studio-of-former-disco-elysium-staff-rename-forthcoming-detective-rpg-and-shift-from-familiar-isometric-perspective-as-rivalry-continues</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/studio-of-former-disco-elysium-staff-rename-forthcoming-detective-rpg-and-shift-from-familiar-isometric-perspective-as-rivalry-continues.1301172/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>Now called Tangerine Antarctic.</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
      <picture data-src-full="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/dbc643931248c99c08d9bdc0c3f85d7f-(1).png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" src="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/dbc643931248c99c08d9bdc0c3f85d7f-(1).png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/dbc643931248c99c08d9bdc0c3f85d7f-(1).png?width=570&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 570px) and (min-resolution: 2x)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/dbc643931248c99c08d9bdc0c3f85d7f-(1).png?width=570&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 570px)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/dbc643931248c99c08d9bdc0c3f85d7f-(1).png?width=414&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-resolution: 2x)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Dark Math Games</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
    <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Dark Math Games, a new studio of former <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/disco-elysium">Disco Elysium</a> developers, have announced a change to their forthcoming debut project, which will now be a third-person RPG.</p>
<p>The studio is one of many that have risen from the shattering of Disco Elysium studio ZA/UM, following <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/disco-elysium-studio-says-lawsuits-from-former-members-have-been-resolved">years of legal threats</a>, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/report-details-allegations-of-toxic-behaviour-ip-theft-at-disco-elysium-developer">accusations of toxic behaviour</a>, and <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/disco-elysium-standalone-expansion-reportedly-cancelled-and-quarter-of-staff-facing-redundancy-at-zaum">layoffs</a>.</p>
<p>While ZA/UM still exists and is <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/zero-parades-is-the-next-game-by-disco-elysium-dev-zaum-revealed-at-gamescom-opening-night-live">working on a new project</a>, other rival studios have formed to create their own spiritual successor to the isometric detective RPG.</p>

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Tangerine Antarctic - A true detective RPG. Dialogue Gameplay Trailer" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/bXQRS5L_aWo?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Tangerine Antarctic - A true detective RPG. Dialogue Gameplay Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/bXQRS5L_aWo?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/bXQRS5L_aWo?autoplay=1" title="Tangerine Antarctic - A true detective RPG. Dialogue Gameplay Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Tangerine Antarctic - A true detective RPG. Dialogue Gameplay Trailer<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bXQRS5L_aWo" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>


<p>Perhaps that's why Dark Math Games has now shifted perspective. Formerly XXXNightshift, the studio's forthcoming project is now known as Tangerine Antarctic and will be a third-person RPG instead of isometric.</p>
<p>"Set at the World's End ski village at Mount Hope, British Antarctica, Tangerine Antarctic is the name of the in-game hotel, designed by renowned Estonian architect Kaur Stőőr, where most of the games' action takes place," explained Timo Albert, founder and art director of Dark Math Games (formerly at ZA/UM).</p>
<p>"This is where you are stuck because of the blizzard and must solve the mysterious murders. And Tangerine Antarctic is one of the important characters of this true detective's RPG."</p>
<figure>

<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Dark Math Games</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/detective-rpg-in-the-works-from-breakaway-group-of-former-disco-elysium-developers">Dark Math Games first revealed its formation and project in October</a> last year. Simultaneously, other former developers announced the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/disco-elysium-spiritual-successor-in-development-from-leads-of-cancelled-sequel">formation of their studio Longdue</a>, while others still <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/more-former-zaum-devs-have-set-up-another-studio-but-they-are-definitely-not-working-on-a-disco-elysium-sequel">announced Summer Eternal</a>.</p>
<p>There's plenty of rivalry going on, then, but <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/disco-elysium-staff-say-rival-projects-from-former-colleagues-are-friendly-competition">ZA/UM told Eurogamer earlier this year it's all "friendly competition"</a>.</p>
<p>"For us, always we think it's friendly competition," said principal writer Siim (Kosmos) Sinamäe. "We're not going to really think about what the other writers are doing, or the studios... how can I be better at my own craft? We're competing essentially against ourselves in this way of can we take it further? Do we have to make any compromises? I think it absolutely sets us apart."</p>



        </div>


      </article>



  
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/studio-of-former-disco-elysium-staff-rename-forthcoming-detective-rpg-and-shift-from-familiar-isometric-perspective-as-rivalry-continues]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Split Fiction Just Received An Award From The Prince Of Sweden]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/split-fiction-just-received-an-award-from-the-prince-of-sweden/1100-6534843/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/split-fiction-just-received-an-award-from-the-prince-of-sweden.1301166/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6534843">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>One of this year's biggest hits is Hazelight Studios' <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/split-fiction/" data-ref-id="5000-654965">Split Fiction</a>, the two-player co-op sci-fi/fantasy adventure that has sold over 4 million copies since its release in March 2025. Now, Hazelight Studios has shared the news of a rare honor in its home country of Sweden, as Split Fiction has become the first video game to ever receive the Excellent Swedish Design award.</p><p>On Hazelight Studios' social media accounts, the company posted a picture of studio founder and Split Fiction director Josef Fares alongside Sweden's Prince Carl Philip, who presented the award.</p><div data-embed-type="tweet" data-src="https://twitter.com/HazelightGames/status/1968341212399820878" data-has-image="true"><blockquote data-conversation="none" data-mce-disable-toolbar="true"><p dir="ltr">Swedish royalty (left) and his buddy (right) 😏<br>But seriously - the prince of Sweden, his majesty Carl Philip, just awarded Split Fiction the prestigious Excellent Swedish Design award. <br>We’re thankful to be the first videogame to ever receive it! 👑🇸🇪 <a href="https://t.co/9xT5KvOJDj" rel="nofollow ">pic.twitter.com/9xT5KvOJDj</a></p>  — Hazelight Studios (@HazelightGames) <a href="https://twitter.com/HazelightGames/status/1968341212399820878?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 17, 2025</a></blockquote>              </div><p>The <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/best-co-op-games/2900-5361/" data-ref-id="2900-5361">co-op game</a> follows two young writers, Mio Hudson (Kaja Chan) and Zoe Foster (Elsie Bennett), who find themselves trapped in a simulation of their stories. Mio and Zoe are forced to work together as their fictional worlds bleed into each other. Split Fiction was the follow up to Hazelight Studios' other successful co-op title, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/it-takes-two/" data-ref-id="5000-514264">It Takes Two</a>, which sold 23 million copies.</p><p>There's already <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/split-fiction-is-getting-a-movie-adaptation-just-like-it-takes-two/1100-6530270/" data-ref-id="1100-6530270">a Split Fiction movie</a> in development, with Wicked director John M. Chu potentially helming the film. Sydney Sweeney is also attached to star in the project. Deadpool writers Paul Wernick and Rhett Reese <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/sydney-sweeney-starring-split-fiction-movie-from-deadpool-writers-gets-a-key-update/1100-6531988/" data-ref-id="1100-6531988">signed on to handle the script </a>in June. Fares has <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/split-fiction-creator-is-unsure-if-movie-will-actually-happen-teases-next-game/1100-6530492/">expressed some doubt </a>about whether Split Fiction will actually make it to the big screen, but it does appear to have momentum behind it.</p><p>Split Fiction is available on PS5, Xbox Series X|S, Nintendo Switch 2, and PC.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/split-fiction-just-received-an-award-from-the-prince-of-sweden/1100-6534843/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Touryst: Deluxe Hits Switch 2 Next Week At 4K / 60fps]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/the-touryst-deluxe-hits-switch-2-next-week-at-4k-60fps</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-touryst-deluxe-hits-switch-2-next-week-at-4k-60fps.1301154/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>With a heavy discount for current owners</p>
</section></header><section>

<p><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/touryst">The Touryst</a> was a delightful little game from developer Shin'en Multimedia, and the company has now revealed that its official re-release, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/touryst-deluxe">The Touryst: Deluxe</a>, will launch on the Switch 2 next week on <strong>25th September 2025</strong>.</p>
<p>Pre-orders are available now at <strong>19.99€ / $19.99</strong>, though current owners who purchased The Touryst from the Switch eShop can bag the re-release at a heavily discounted price of <strong>4.99€ / $4.99</strong>.</p>
<p>The game will run at 4K resolution with frame rate set at 60fps; it's worth mentioning here that the game already ran at 60fps on Switch, albeit at a max resolution of 1080p. 120fps won't be supported at launch, but this might be something Shin'en could explore at a later date.</p>
<p>Several other graphical enhancements have been applied, but players can also look forward to brand new content, including new locations and quests, and even a playable arcade spin-off of the <strong>FAST</strong> racing series.</p>
<p>Let's take a peek at everything new:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>- Resolution is now 4k (from 1080p) at 60fps<br>
- Added new locations, new items, new quest<br>
- Added new Arcade Cabinet (featuring FAST ZERO racing game)<br>
- Added Global Illumination for many locations<br>
- Added Voxel waves on the beach shores<br>
- Added dynamic Ambient Occlusion<br>
- Added Anti-Aliasing<br>
- Much improved Rain effect<br>
- Much improved Depth of Field effect<br>
- Improved controls<br>
- Import your save game from the Nintendo Switch 1 version</p>
</blockquote>
<p>And now let's see how The Touryst: Deluxe is shaping up, along with a couple of comparison shots with the Switch original:</p>


<p>Shin'en Multimedia also launched <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/fast-fusion">Fast Fusion</a> as a launch title for the Switch 2 to critical acclaim, earning a well-deserved score of 9/10 from us. It's since received a free update to add more performance options and content.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:186691,183389,185004 @ 1758196907 -->
<p><em>Will you be picking up The Touryst: Deluxe when it launches next week? Let us know your thoughts with a comment.</em></p></section></article><div><p>Nintendo Life’s resident horror fanatic, when he’s not knee-deep in Resident Evil and Silent Hill lore, Ollie likes to dive into a good horror book while nursing a lovely cup of tea. He also enjoys long walks and listens to everything from TOOL to Chuck Berry.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Olliemar28"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/ollie-nl.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Olliemar28');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/the-touryst-deluxe-hits-switch-2-next-week-at-4k-60fps]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tencent Fights Back on Light of Motiram Lawsuit, Says Horizon Devs Acknowledged It Wasn’t Original in the First Place]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/tencent-fights-back-light-of-motiram-lawsuit-horizon-wasnt-original/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/tencent-fights-back-on-light-of-motiram-lawsuit-says-horizon-devs-acknowledged-it-wasn%E2%80%99t-original-in-the-first-place.1301139/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Ever since Light of Motiram was <a href="https://wccftech.com/horizon-zero-dawn-clone-light-of-motiram-announced-for-pc/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">unveiled</a> in November 2024, it was immediately obvious to everyone (us included) that it looked very, very similar to Guerrilla Games' Horizon Zero Dawn/Forbidden West, from the animal-like machines down to the red-haired protagonist dressed in tribal gear.</p>



<p>In July 2025, Guerrilla Games' owner Sony Interactive Entertainment <span><a href="https://wccftech.com/sony-sues-tencent-over-horizon-copy-light-of-motiram/" target="_blank">sued Tencent</a>&nbsp;(the parent company of Light of Motiram developer Polaris Quest) in the state of California, alleging copyright and trademark infringement and adding that Tencent reps had reached out to Sony in 2024 about the possibility of making</span> a mobile Horizon game. Sony assumes that when talks failed, Tencent went ahead and made its own Horizon-inspired title anyway.</p>



<p>Yesterday, Tencent officially fought back with a motion to dismiss on a 'myriad of flaws', including but not limited to:</p>



<ul>
<li>Lack of actual jurisdiction over Tencent Holdings, which is incorporated in the Cayman Islands and headquartered in China and merely the parent company of the actual entities developing the game, which the motion says haven't been served yet in the case: '<em>Sony’s threadbare, conclusory allegations improperly lump these Defendants together with the foreign companies alleged to be responsible for the core conduct at issue. Sony’s vague allegations against ‘Tencent’ or ‘Defendants’ generally cannot substantiate the claims it brings against Tencent America, Proxima Beta U.S., or Tencent Holdings specifically</em>.</li>



<li>For the time being, the claims amount to speculation as the game's release date (which has conveniently been set just now to Q4 2027 <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3319630/LIGHT_OF_MOTIRAM/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">on Steam</a>) is far away and the alleged infringements haven't happened and may never happen.</li>



<li>Lastly and perhaps more interestingly, the motion to dismiss labels Sony's lawsuit as a clumsy attempt to secure a corner of popular culture for themselves. </li>
</ul>



<p>In this regard, Tencent's motion goes as far as including actual quotes from Guerrilla Games, specifically from Lead Artist Jan-Bart van Beek, who mentioned <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=h9tLcD1r-6w&amp;t=859s" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">in a NoClip documentary</a> that when pitching Horizon, the developers initially shelved it because of its similarities to Ninja Theory's 2013 game Enslaved: Odyssey to the West:</p>



<p><em>Enslaved basically featured a post-apocalyptic world, a female protagonist, machines that were slumbering that would be awakened. So I myself went to Hermen and I said like, I don't think we should do this, it touches too much of these other points. And Hermen, he sort of was very reluctant. He said like okay, well, I think it's a bad idea to do this, but you know, we'll can it for now and maybe we'll look at it later.</em></p>



<p>That's exactly what happened. For some time, Guerrilla worked on another pitch, a shooter set in an alternate history steampunk setting loosely in the vein of The League of Extraordinary Gentlemen. Unbeknownst to the Dutch studio, though, Ready at Dawn was already doing something not too far from that with The Order: 1886. Eventually, Studio Technical Director Michiel van der Leeuw asked Studio Head Hermen Hulst to reconsider the Horizon pitch, and Guerrilla switched back to that.</p>



<p>Tencent's point is clear-cut: </p>



<p><em>By suing over an unreleased project that merely employs the same time-honored tropes embraced by scores of other games released both before and after Horizon—like Enslaved, The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild, Far Cry: Primal, Far Cry: New Dawn, Outer Wilds, Biomutant, and many more—Sony seeks an impermissible monopoly on genre conventions.</em></p>



<p>However, it should be noted that Tencent, or at least its developers who are actually making the game, have made several changes in the description and the screenshots of Light of Motiram to distance themselves from the Horizon IP. The red-headed protagonist who looked a lot like Aloy is nowhere to be seen, for instance. </p>



<p>To be fair, the actual game is probably going to play quite a bit differently. It will have survival mechanics such as base building. It also supports online cooperative play, which is missing from the Horizon games (although Guerrilla is now working <a href="https://wccftech.com/horizon-online-is-guerrillas-next-big-game-with-horizon-3-a-ways-off/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">on Horizon Online</a>).</p>



<p>As to the lawsuit, we'll see how Sony responds to this motion to dismiss. We'll report any noteworthy updates on the lawsuit, so stay tuned.</p>





			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/tencent-fights-back-light-of-motiram-lawsuit-horizon-wasnt-original/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[R-Type Tactics I • II Cosmos Confirms Switch 2 Version Alongside 2026 Launch]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/r-type-tactics-i-b-ii-cosmos-confirms-switch-2-version-alongside-2026-launch</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/r-type-tactics-i-%E2%80%A2-ii-cosmos-confirms-switch-2-version-alongside-2026-launch.1301130/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Local release date TBA</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure><a title="R-TYPE" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/87def262aa60b/r-type.large.jpg"></a></figure><p><strong>Update [<time datetime="2025-09-17T23:30:00+00:00" data-format="D jS M Y, g:ia">Thu 18th Sep 2025, 12:30am</time>]:</strong> We've finally got an update about the development status of <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/r-type_tactics_i_b_ii_cosmos"><strong>R-Type Tactics I • II Cosmos</strong></a>, with Granzella this week <a href="https://rtypetactics.com/ja/news/2025/update-2025091801.html">announcing it will now be arriving next year</a> in Japan on 12th March 2026 for 6,380 yen (<a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2025/09/r-type-tactics-i-ii-cosmos-adds-switch-2-version-launches-march-12-2026-in-japan">thanks again, Gematsu</a>).</p>
<p>The local release will be published by NIS America, but we don't have a release date just yet. On a more positive note, a Switch 2 version (and Game-Key Card physical release) has also been confirmed. It's arriving in Japan alongside the Switch, PlayStation and PC release.</p><div><figure data-videoid="C1rrCdi_XjA" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><iframe title="YouTube Video" src="javascript:''" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" type="text/html" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed3be067qvwtnk&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><figcaption><p><a title="Watch This Video on YouTube" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=C1rrCdi_XjA" rel="noopener">Watch on <strong><span></span> YouTube</strong> <span></span></a></p>
<p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>834k</span></a></p>
</figcaption></figure></div>
<p>The Japanese release will include standard and premium physical options (with the fancier one including a copy of the game, a scale plastic kit and an acrylic stand set):</p>
<figure><a title="R-TYPE" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/3c2b06b5f47ca/r-type.large.jpg"></a></figure>
<p>This title was previously targeting a 2025 launch, after it was delayed in September 2024. So hopefully the wait will finally be over early next year. If we hear any updates about the local release date or window, we'll let you know.</p><hr><p><strong>Original Story:</strong> Remember how <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/r-type_tactics_i_b_ii_cosmos"><strong>R-Type Tactics I • II Cosmos</strong></a> by Granzilla was meant to be coming to the Switch this year? Well, it's now been delayed (again).</p>
<p>In an update during a live stream, the developer announced the title would be arriving on Nintendo's hybrid system in <strong>2025</strong> instead of Fall 2024. No reason was attached to this delay, but the developer has apologised once again.</p>

<p>As previously mentioned, this package will contain the turn-based strategy tactical RPG's <strong>R-Type Tactics</strong> (Command in the West) and <strong>R-Type Tactics II: Operation Bitter Chocolate</strong>. You can find out more about these releases in our existing coverage.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-articles:130823 @ 1758195183 -->
<p><em>When a new release date is shared, we'll let you know.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://www.gematsu.com/2024/09/r-type-tactics-i-ii-cosmos-delayed-to-2025" rel="noopener" href="https://www.gematsu.com/2024/09/r-type-tactics-i-ii-cosmos-delayed-to-2025">gematsu.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-info/f9e0a13ec8767567850df909cb59fab0 @ 1758197115 --></div></article><div><p>Liam is a news writer and reviewer across Hookshot Media. He's been writing about games for more than 15 years and is a lifelong fan of many iconic video game characters.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Liam_Doolan"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/liamdoolan.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Liam_Doolan');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/r-type-tactics-i-b-ii-cosmos-confirms-switch-2-version-alongside-2026-launch]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Time-leap survival horror adventure game’ Kigetsu no Yoru announced for Switch]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/09/time-leap-survival-horror-adventure-game-kigetsu-no-yoru-announced-for-switch</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/%E2%80%98time-leap-survival-horror-adventure-game%E2%80%99-kigetsu-no-yoru-announced-for-switch.1301124/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Due out on January 29, 2026 in Japan.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Edia [37 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/edia">Edia</a> has <a href="https://prtimes.jp/main/html/rd/p/000000977.000021592.html" target="_blank">announced</a> “time-leap <a title="Genres > Survival [460 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/survival">survival</a> <a title="Genres > Horror [711 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/horror">horror</a> <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,563 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure game</a>” <em><a title="Games > Kigetsu no Yoru" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/kigetsu-no-yoru">Kigetsu no Yoru</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > Switch [17,698 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>. It will launch on January 29, 2026 in Japan for 4,800 yen (5,280 yen with tax). <span id="more-993479"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Edia:</p><blockquote><p>A modern-day high school student is reincarnated as someone caught up in a mass murder case in a gloomy rural village of the early Showa era. This is a “time-leap survival horror” in which the protagonist gets dragged into the incident and dies, repeating the same time over and over while striving to make the right choices to survive. With each time leap, relationships become more entangled, and murderous intent becomes inescapable. Through repetition, the village’s customs, hidden secrets, and the true culprit’s motives gradually come to light.</p><p>When the waning moon fades, will you be greeted by hope… or despair?</p></blockquote><p>Watch the opening movie below. Visit the official website <a href="https://kigetsunoyoru.com/" target="_blank">here</a>.</p><h2><span>Opening Movie</span></h2><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><iframe title="「虧月の夜」OPムービー" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/GU0ITWyAYSI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/09/time-leap-survival-horror-adventure-game-kigetsu-no-yoru-announced-for-switch]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Super Mario Galaxy + Super Mario Galaxy 2 Switch Online Icons Revealed]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/super-mario-galaxy-plus-super-mario-galaxy-2-switch-online-icons-revealed</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/super-mario-galaxy-super-mario-galaxy-2-switch-online-icons-revealed.1301118/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Three waves starting next week</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure><a title="Super Mario Galaxy icons" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/7b6d26f13aee7/super-mario-galaxy-icons.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Nintendo</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>Super Mario's 40th anniversary is now underway and Nintendo's been promoting it with all sorts of announcements and reveals.</p>
<p>As part of the ongoing celebrations, next month <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/super_mario_galaxy_plus_super_mario_galaxy_2">Super Mario Galaxy + Super Mario Galaxy 2</a> is returning for Switch. Ahead of this, Nintendo has also announced a new wave of themed Switch Online icons. It features a bunch of characters from this particular universe such as Mario and Rosalina.</p>
<p>The first wave gets underway next week on 25th September, with the second wave following on 1st October and the final wave scheduled for 8th October. Each of these icons will set you back 10 Platinum Points, with borders and backgrounds priced at 5 Platinum Points each.</p>
<figure><a title="Super Mario Galaxy icons" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/65ea2fe64dc62/super-mario-galaxy-icons.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Nintendo</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>This week also marks the final wave of Kirby and the Forgotten Land Nintendo Switch 2 Edition + Star-Crossed World icons (<a href="https://gonintendo.com/contents/52976-final-wave-of-kirby-and-the-forgotten-land-icons-now-available-for-switch-online">thanks, GoNintendo</a>).</p>
<p>Apart from these icons, Nintendo has also released a new seven-minute overview trailer for Galaxy + Galaxy 2, showcasing the gameplay and extra content in this title. Earlier this week the <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/mobile/nintendo_music">Nintendo Music</a> app got a Galaxy 2 update as well, adding 70 tracks (with a run time of 2 hours and 9 minutes).</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-articles:188030,187914 @ 1758197380 --></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://www.nintendo.com/jp/topics/article/066246e8-3429-49e5-bbd7-39cfaf7e3ca2" rel="noopener" href="https://www.nintendo.com/jp/topics/article/066246e8-3429-49e5-bbd7-39cfaf7e3ca2">nintendo.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-info/566af3473f9d7fdfbf390f54b6ac66d4 @ 1758196544 --></div></article><div><p>Liam is a news writer and reviewer across Hookshot Media. He's been writing about games for more than 15 years and is a lifelong fan of many iconic video game characters.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Liam_Doolan"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/liamdoolan.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Liam_Doolan');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/super-mario-galaxy-plus-super-mario-galaxy-2-switch-online-icons-revealed]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>