<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 13:44:37 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2 Release Date and Delay Revealed]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-release-date-delay</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-release-date-and-delay-revealed.953808/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-release-date-delay<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Warhorse Studios has announced the&nbsp;<em>Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2&nbsp;</em>release date, but it's landing a little later than you might have expected.</p>
<p>Per <a href="https://x.com/WarhorseStudios/status/1823949533128036374" rel="noopener" target="_blank">a post on X (formerly Twitter)</a>,&nbsp;<em>Deliverance 2&nbsp;</em>officially launches across PC and consoles on February 11th, which the studio admits is a "long wait". The game was previously slated to arrive sometime this year.</p>
<p>Despite the extra wait time, Warhorse says there's plenty of stuff on the way to whet your appetite for&nbsp;<em>Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2</em>, including gameplay footage, a collector's edition, and more.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-release-date-delay-party.jpg?itok=tXb-ZZM2 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-release-date-delay-party.jpg?itok=Y_X5LJzQ 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Fear not, revellers, for&nbsp;<em>Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2&nbsp;</em>has a release date.</figcaption></figure><p>Warhorse PR manager&nbsp;Tobias Stolz-Zwilling <a href="https://x.com/T0_8I/status/1823951710206722306" rel="noopener" target="_blank">says</a>&nbsp;the dev team was "this close" to releasing in 2024, but eventually made the decision that it needed "a tiny bit more time". He also echoes the studio's excitement with regards to what's coming up for&nbsp;<em>Deliverance 2</em>.</p>
<p>First up, a showcase demonstrating over 20 minutes of gameplay will air at this year's Gamescom, which is due to start later this month. Following that, the collector's edition of the game will be revealed at some point, and previews from various content creators and press outlets will also begin to appear.</p>
<p>In short, even though<i>&nbsp;Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2&nbsp;</i>has technically been delayed, there should still be plenty to keep you busy between now and its February release date, however far off that date currently seems.</p>

<p>If you're not familiar with&nbsp;<em>Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2</em>, it's the sequel to 2017's <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/kingdom-come-deliverance-sales-six-million">hugely popular medieval RPG</a>&nbsp;<em>Kingdom Come: Deliverance</em>.</p>
<p>Like its predecessor, the sequel will also revolve around protagonist Henry of Skalitz, and this time he's "caught in a gripping tale of revenge, betrayal, and discovery". Sounds like an average day in 15th-century Bohemia to me.</p>
<p><em>Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2&nbsp;</em>launches on PC, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series X|S on February 11th. Stay tuned for more on this one.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Persona 3 Reload's The Answer DLC Shows How The Series Should Do Epilogues]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/persona-3-reload-answer-preview-aigis-price-dlc-1851622486</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/persona-3-reloads-the-answer-dlc-shows-how-the-series-should-do-epilogues.953802/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/persona-3-reload-answer-preview-aigis-price-dlc-1851622486<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>I have complicated feelings on how the <em>Persona </em>series (and the <em>Shin Megami Tensei </em>series at large) handles its updated “definitive editions.” <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/persona-4-golden-pc-is-the-definitive-edition-of-a-damn-1844024943&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/persona-4-golden-pc-is-the-definitive-edition-of-a-damn-1844024943"><em>Persona 4 Golden</em></a></span><em> </em>and <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/oh-no-im-playing-all-of-persona-5-again-1842377082&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/oh-no-im-playing-all-of-persona-5-again-1842377082"><em>Persona 5 Royal</em></a></span><em> </em>are undoubtedly the best versions of their respective games, adding dozens of hours of new story, characters, relationships, and bangin’ songs. However, Atlus has opted to include all that delicious new shit <em>woven throughout</em> the original game, meaning that to see some of <em>Royal</em>’s best stuff, you have to play through the entirety of <em>Persona 5 </em>again. This means little to those who wait until the definitive editions are out before playing a <em>Persona game</em>—but for people like me who jump on a new one the second it’s out, playing the entire game all over again has always been a big ask.<br></p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196411" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="A Typical Day On Persona 3 Reload’s Tatsumi Port Island" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="378" data-playlist="196411,196394,196055" data-current="196411"><div><p>A Typical Day On Persona 3 Reload’s Tatsumi Port Island</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196411/196411_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196411/196411_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196411/196411_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196411/196411_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21958.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>That’s why <em>Persona 3</em>’s <em>The Answer</em> feels like the ideal scenario, looking back on the original PS2 game. Instead of weaving a new story into the main game that can only be discovered at the tail end, <em>The Answer </em>offers an entirely separate campaign set after the events of the main game, and <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/persona-3-reload-remake-review-ps5-steam-pc-xbox-1851201927&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/persona-3-reload-remake-review-ps5-steam-pc-xbox-1851201927"><em>Persona 3 Reload</em></a></span>, the from-the-ground-up remake of the RPG that launched earlier this year, is finally getting the epilogue on September 10. Though Atlus’ implementation has been controversial. The original PS2 game’s “definitive edition” included <em>The Answer</em> as a pack-in, while the remake is getting it as <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/persona-3-reload-dlc-the-answer-expansion-pass-1851313160&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/persona-3-reload-dlc-the-answer-expansion-pass-1851313160">a $35 paid DLC as part of an expansion pass</a></span>. it is, at least, a better version of the business model Atlus has adopted in the years since we first ascended the stairs of Tartarus. Rather than asking someone to buy and play the full game again, it’s nice to have a playable epilogue available separately, and for cheaper than buying an updated version would theoretically cost.</p><p>When I played an hour of <em>The Answer</em>, I effortlessly put <em>Persona 3 Reload </em>back on like a glove without all the pressure of replaying a 70-hour RPG to get there.</p><figure id="" data-id="afpvuwnfoibrncd6upmy" data-recommend-id="image://afpvuwnfoibrncd6upmy" data-format="png" data-width="800" data-height="88" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><span data-id="afpvuwnfoibrncd6upmy" data-recommend-id="image://afpvuwnfoibrncd6upmy" data-format="png" data-width="800" data-height="88" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p><em>The Answer </em>begins weeks after the events of <em>Persona 3 </em>proper. The demon-fighting high school team S.E.E.S. is mourning the loss of their leader following his sacrifice during the final battle, and it seems like they are ready to go their separate ways. That is, until Aigis, the shadow-killing android of the team, meets another android named Metis claiming to be her sister. She attacks the group, and Aigis awakens to the trademarked <em>Persona </em>protagonist power of swapping between different summonable creatures at will to face any foe they might encounter.<br></p><p>Aigis becomes the hero of the story when a portal to a new, shadow-infested world opens below the dormitory, and S.E.E.S. is forced to once again take up arms against the monsters. As the group descends, hoping they can find answers for why they’re being dragged back into the fight, they find a series of procedurally generated floors overrun with shadows. It’s back to <em>Persona 3</em>’s usual dungeon crawling, but there are a few tweaks that make Aigis feel different than the original protagonist.</p><p>The main change is that Aigis, being an android who uses firearms, is able to preemptively attack enemies from a distance, which Makoto from the base game can’t do as a swordsman. However, it does feel a little imprecise and finicky compared to a simple sword strike in the base game. You don’t aim down sights when playing as Aigis, you just wait for her reticle to appear on an enemy when you’re at a close-enough distance. It’s not a foolproof system, and perhaps it will become more manageable with practice, but it definitely sticks out as an early complication.</p><p>Besides that, however, a lot of <em>The Answer </em>seems like more of what made <em>Persona 3 Reload</em> a successful remake earlier this year. It still feels as effortlessly stylish as the main game, its characters are still lovable (even if they’re maybe not as happy to see each other as they once were), and the chain-centric turn-based combat is still full of challenges that it feels like more recent <em>Persona </em>games have gotten away from. I haven’t played the original <em>Answer </em>in over a decade, and I’m excited to revisit it with fresh eyes. <em>Persona 3 Reload </em>brilliantly captured the hopeful melancholy of living for the ones you love, even against terrible hardship. I’m eager to revisit <em>The Answer</em> and see if S.E.E.S. learned that lesson once more when the DLC launches on September 10.</p><p>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2 Delayed to February 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-delayed-to-february-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-delayed-to-february-2025.953799/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-delayed-to-february-2025<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Gameplay coming this month.</h2></div><section><p>Warhorse Studios has delayed medieval open world role-playing game <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/kingdom-come-deliverance-ii">Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2</a> from 2024 to February 11, 2025, though will release 25 minutes of gameplay later in August.</p><p>No explicit reason for the delay was given, with Warhorse public relations manager Tobias Stolz-Zwilling merely saying on X/Twitter that "we slipped to 2025." A three minute video was shared to announce the delay, release date, and Warhorese's plans for the coming months.</p><p>“We aimed for the end of the year and almost made it," Stolz-Zwilling said. "Almost is not good enough though, so unfortunately we slipped to 2025."</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">A message from Warhorse Studios! The official release date for <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/KCD2?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">#KCD2</a> is 11 February 2025.<br>It's a long wait, but we have a lot to show you between now and release, starting with:<br>⚔️ 20+ min gameplay showcase at <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Gamescom2024?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">#Gamescom2024</a><br>⚔️ Collectors Edition Reveal<br>⚔️ Previews from Press and… <a href="https://t.co/YSJrxdZZZT" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/YSJrxdZZZT</a></p>— Warhorse Studios (@WarhorseStudios) <a href="https://twitter.com/WarhorseStudios/status/1823949533128036374?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">August 15, 2024</a></blockquote> <p>He then said a Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2 trailer will be released during <a href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/gamescom/Gamescom_2024">Gamescom 2024</a>'s Opening Night Live showcase on August 20, the 25 minute gameplay video will be released on August 21, and that a Collector's Edition will also be revealed during the event. Those attending Gamescom in Cologne, Germany can play a demo too.</p><p>Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2 is promised to be a "behemoth" of a game featuring a map twice the size of the 2018 original, new weapons, a "much more epic" story," reputation system, and more.</p><p>“What we are making now is what it was supposed to be in the beginning, but we weren’t able to do it because we didn’t have enough resources and experiences and all that stuff,” <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-xbox-ps5-pc-warhorse-studios?">Warhorse creative director Daniel Vavra said in April</a>. “We’ve proven the concept works, so now we can take it to another level, which is what we always wanted.”</p><p><a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2018/02/17/kingdom-come-deliverance-review">In IGN's 8/10 review of the original</a>, we said: "Kingdom Come: Deliverance is an RPG that does the medieval era right with a refreshingly small-scale story and strong realistic combat."</p><p>Anthony is a freelance contributor covering science and video gaming news for IGN. He has over eight years experience of covering breaking developments in multiple scientific fields and absolutely no time for your shenanigans. Follow him on Twitter @BeardConGamer</p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Persona 3 Reload Will 'Likely Never' Get the Female Protagonist, Producer Says]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/persona-3-reload-will-likely-never-get-the-female-protagonist-producer-says</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/persona-3-reload-will-likely-never-get-the-female-protagonist-producer-says.953796/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/persona-3-reload-will-likely-never-get-the-female-protagonist-producer-says<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">She was added in Persona 3 Portable.</h2></div><section><p>The Persona 3 Reload remake released in February 2024 will "likely never" get female protagonist Kotone Shiomi, who was introduced in a previous iteration of the game, its producer has said.</p><p>As reported by <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/rpg/persona-3-reload-producer-dashes-any-remaining-hopes-for-the-return-of-portables-female-protagonist-it-is-likely-never-going-to-happen/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">PC Gamer</a>, Persona series producer Kazuhisa Wada told <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/magazine" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Game Informer Magazine</a> that he was "really sorry" but fan pleas for Shiomi's inclusion will probably never be answered.</p><p>"The more we discussed it, the more unlikely it became," Wada said. "The development time and costs would not have been manageable.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>I'm really sorry to all of the fans who were holding out hope.</p></div><p>"Persona 3 Reload has just released, and there is currently a lot of player interest, so if we are to do an additional release, it has to be now. But since it is not possible for us to release Persona 3 Reload with the female protagonist in this window, we just can't do it. I'm really sorry to all of the fans who were holding out hope, but it is likely never going to happen."</p><p>Persona 3 Reload is the fourth iteration of Persona 3 (<a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/persona-4-golden-and-persona-3-portable-will-be-released-on-modern-consoles-in-january-2023">or the fifth if the port to modern consoles is included</a>). The <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2007/07/25/shin-megami-tensei-persona-3-review">base game</a> launched in 2006, followed by an enhanced edition called <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2008/04/22/shin-megami-tensei-persona-3-fes-review">Persona 3 FES</a> in 2007, and a PlayStation Portable version aptly called <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2010/07/06/shin-megami-tensei-persona-3-portable-review">Persona 3 Portable</a> in 2009.</p><p>It was in this latter version the female protagonist was released, so when Atlus announced a full remake promised to be a "complete experience," many fans were disappointed to learn <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/persona-3-reload-wont-include-content-from-fes-or-portable-including-the-female-protagonist">it wasn't planning to include FES or Portable content</a>.</p><p>The release model of Atlus, particularly of the Shin Megami Tensei (of which Persona originated) and Persona franchises, <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/persona-3-reload-fans-slam-expansion-pass-as-a-cash-grab">is starting to frustrate some fans</a>. It's common practice for the developer to release the base game and then, a year or two later, released essentially a better version with extra content at full cost. Persona 4 received Persona 4 Golden, and Persona 5 received Persona 5 Royal.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3>Persona 3 Reload Screenshots</h3></div></output><p>Fans therefore took issue with Persona 3 Reload releasing without this content, not just because it was missing, but because they expected Atlus to release an enhanced edition soon after that would include it.</p><p>Looking to quell those concerns, <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/persona-3-reload-wont-get-an-expanded-golden-or-royal-edition-anytime-soon-dev-says">Wada promised fans in March 2024 that Persona 3 Reload was a "complete experience,"</a> but just one month later Atlus announced an expansion pass. This would add a handful of cosmetics alongside Episode Aegis — a 30 hour epilogue added to Persona 3 FES — but no female protagonist.</p><p>Further frustration came as <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/persona-3-reload-episode-aigis-dlc-wont-be-sold-outside-the-expansion-pass">Atlus confirmed Episode Aegis wouldn't be available as a standalone</a> but only as part of the $34.99 expansion pass. The "complete experience" promise therefore fell through, with fans actually having to pay a total of $104.98 to play every part of Persona 3 Reload. This still won't include all the Persona 3 content ever released, of course, and seemingly never will, as the female protagonist and other additional content remains locked in Persona 3 Portable.</p><p><em>Ryan Dinsdale is an IGN freelance reporter. He'll talk about The Witcher all day.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Plucky Squire launches September 17]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/the-plucky-squire-launches-september-17</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-plucky-squire-launches-september-17.953793/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/the-plucky-squire-launches-september-17<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>A magical adventure of storybook characters who discover a 3D world.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Genres > Action [2,082 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">Action</a> <a title="Genres > Adventure [1,665 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a> <a title="Genres > Platformer [508 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/platformer">platformer</a> <em><a title="Games > The Plucky Squire [6 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/the-plucky-squire">The Plucky Squire</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [7,661 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [5,834 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch [15,781 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [20,896 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1627570/The_Plucky_Squire/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> on September 17, publisher <a title="Companies > Devolver Digital [376 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/devolver-digital">Devolver Digital</a> and developer <a title="Companies > All Possible Futures [5 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/all-possible-futures">All Possible Futures</a> announced. <span id="more-887849"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1627570/The_Plucky_Squire/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam page</a>:</p><blockquote><p><em>The Plucky Squire</em> follows the magical adventures of Jot and his friends—storybook characters who discover a three-dimensional world outside the pages of their book.</p><p>When the malevolent Humgrump realizes he’s the villain of the book—destined to lose his battle against the forces of good for all eternity – he kicks the heroic Jot out of its pages and changes the story forever.</p><p>Jot must face challenges, unlike anything he’s ever seen if he is to save his friends from Humgrump’s dark forces and restore the book’s happy ending.</p><p>Jump between 2D and 3D worlds in this charming action adventure—solving puzzles, boxing badgers, flying with a jetpack, and enjoying many more delightful and surprising mini-challenges as you become the hero of a living storybook.<!-- AD: content -->
        </p></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="The Plucky Squire | Release Date Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/4DpvZWrts_M?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Open universe’ sandbox survival game For the Stars announced for PS5, Xbox Series, and PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/open-universe-sandbox-survival-game-for-the-stars-announced-for-ps5-xbox-series-and-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/%E2%80%98open-universe%E2%80%99-sandbox-survival-game-for-the-stars-announced-for-ps5-xbox-series-and-pc.953787/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/open-universe-sandbox-survival-game-for-the-stars-announced-for-ps5-xbox-series-and-pc<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>From ARK series publisher Snail.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><em>ARK</em> series publisher <a title="Companies > Snail [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/snail">Snail</a> has <a href="https://projecth.snail.com/news/item2.html" rel="noopener" target="_blank">announced</a> <em><a title="Games > For the Stars" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/for-the-stars">For the Stars</a></em>, an internally developed space-themed “open universe” sandbox survival game coming to <a title="Platforms > PS5 [7,661 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [5,834 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [20,896 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1415230/For_The_Stars/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a>. A release date was not announced. <span id="more-904318"></span></p><p>In <em>For the Stars</em>, players will be able to explore diverse worlds, research new technology, customize their spacecraft, battle space pirates, and much more.</p><p>“We’re thrilled to finally officially announce <em>For the Stars</em> after three years of development,” said game director Primus Majda in a press release. “We are gamers first and foremost. We love <a title="Genres > Survival [302 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/survival">survival games</a> and Snail has a lot of experience with them. We have an ambitious game in mind, and we are taking what we’ve learned from other projects to make it happen. Our goal is to create a game that’s played like a sandbox survival game, but has the impact of a 4X galaxy civilization game.”</p><div id="carousel_905294"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Snail:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><em>For the Stars</em> invites you to explore and settle a vast universe of diverse planets, each with its own unique wonders and mysteries to uncover. As an intrepid explorer and scientist, your mission is to travel from world to world, uncovering secrets of alien civilizations, seeking out rare and exotic creatures and resources, and using them to tame the deadly biomes you encounter.</p><p>Your mission is to establish thriving outposts on alien worlds, harness their unique traits, and unlock advanced technologies. Conquer the challenges of hostile biomes, forge alliances, and build a legacy that spans the galaxy.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Diverse Worlds</strong> – Each planet you visit offers new challenges and rewards, with distinct ecosystems, creatures and resources. From lush, verdant worlds to barren, rocky landscapes, the variety ensures no two explorations are the same.</li><li><strong>Strange Alien Ruins</strong> – Discover remnants of lost civilizations, ancient ruins, and hidden treasures that tell the stories of the cosmos.</li><li><strong>Unique Resources</strong> – Collect and harness strange resources found on different planets. Build advanced outposts, craft powerful tools, and develop cutting-edge technology needed to overcome each world’s challenges.</li><li><strong>Advanced Construction</strong> – Establish and expand outposts on various planets. Balance your needs with laboratories, factories, and living quarters. Your ingenuity and strategy will determine the success of your colonies and determine if they can withstand the trials of space.</li><li><strong>Extensive Research</strong> – Start with advanced technologies that you can innovate on. Unlock new technologies by studying alien artifacts and natural phenomena. Research to help you overcome specific challenges, build more efficient outposts, create advanced equipment, and explore further into the unknown.</li><li><strong>Customizable Spacecraft</strong> – Design and build your own spacecraft to travel between planets. Each ship can be tailored to your specific needs using resources and technology you have found, whether it’s for combat, exploration, or resource gathering.</li><li><strong>Dynamic Combat</strong> – Engage in fast-paced combat using both futuristic weapons and special abilities with alien origins. Customize your arsenal for counterplay against hostile alien creatures, enemy players, and other threats.</li><li><strong><a title="Genres > Multiplayer [362 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer">Multiplayer</a> Exploration</strong> – Team up with friends or make new allies as you explore the galaxy together in a persistent multiplayer universe. Collaborate on building projects, share discoveries, and tackle challenges as a united front. Choose to enter contested regions to fight other players for control of the galaxy.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch the announcement trailer below. View the first screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/for-the-stars/august-15-2024/">at the gallery</a>. Visit the official website <a href="https://forthestars.game/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">here</a>.</p><h2><span>Developer Vision Video</span></h2><p><iframe title="For the Stars - Developer Vision Video" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/vUdIxsrBVx4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Lord Of The Rings Games Being Prototyped Right Now]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/new-lord-of-the-rings-games-being-prototyped-right-now/1100-6525818/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-lord-of-the-rings-games-being-prototyped-right-now.953784/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/new-lord-of-the-rings-games-being-prototyped-right-now/1100-6525818/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6525818">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Multiple new Lord of the Rings games are in the early stages of development, Embracer Group--the company that owns Middle-earth Enterprises--has confirmed. As part of Embracer's <a href="https://embracer.com/releases/embracer-group-publishes-interim-report-q1-april-june-2024-adjusted-ebit-amounted-to-sek-828-million/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">latest earnings briefing</a>, the company said it is "actively testing and prototyping multiple new game concepts."</p><p>Embracer said its efforts in this area include "exploring a wide range of immersive and authentic gameplay within the Middle-earth world."</p><p>The publisher went on to say it will take an "honest and tactical approach" to making these games with an aim of creating "authentic storytelling."</p><p>"We believe that engaging deeply and early with the community is essential to creating experiences that truly resonate," Embracer said. "We have been diligently working with our own creative teams, other world-class creators, and our passionate fanbase in laying the foundation and strategic long-term planning for [The Lord of the Rings and The Hobbit]."</p><p>Before this, Embracer's Lord of the Rings boss, Lee Guinchard, spoke about how <a href="https://venturebeat.com/games/a-new-generation-of-j-r-r-tolkien-games-is-coming-lee-guinchard-exclusive-interview/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">he wants there to be a renaissance for Lord of the Rings games.</a></p><p>Embracer is working with Amazon Games currently on a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/all-the-lord-of-the-rings-games-on-the-way/1100-6514561/" data-ref-id="1100-6514561">new MMO in the Middle-earth universe</a>. Another upcoming Lord of the Rings game is the cozy-looking <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/tales-of-the-shire-a-lord-of-the-rings-game/" data-ref-id="5000-604117">Tales of the Shire</a>, which releases later this year. As Guinchard said in the interview mentioned above, there are multiple other new Lord of the Rings games in the works that have yet to be announced.</p><p>There have been many iconic Lord of the Rings games over the years. In particular, some of the early movie tie-ins were well-received, while the more recent Shadow of Mordor and Shadow of War were enjoyable as well. On the less-serious side, there are also Lego Lord of the Rings and Lego The Hobbit titles that are fondly remembered. Check out the gallery below to see some of the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-best-lord-of-the-rings-games-ranked/1100-6503738/" data-ref-id="1100-6503738">best Lord of the Rings games ever.</a></p><p>One not-so-fondly-remembered Lord of the Rings game was The Lord of the Rings: Gollum, which came out in 2023 to very low review scores. Following the game's release, developer Daedalic <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gollum-studios-next-lotr-game-canceled-dev-no-longer-making-games-at-all/1100-6515620/" data-ref-id="1100-6515620">canceled the next Lord of the Rings game it had in the works and announced it would no longer make any games at all.</a></p><p>Beyond video games, Embracer is working with Warner Bros. Pictures and New Line Cinema on multiple upcoming films, including The Hunt for Gollum. Andy Serkis, who played Gollum in Peter Jackson's original The Lord of the Rings series, is coming back to direct this film.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dragon Age: The Veilguard Release Date Seemingly Leaked Ahead of Trailer]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/dragon-age-veilguard-release-date-leaked-trailer</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dragon-age-the-veilguard-release-date-seemingly-leaked-ahead-of-trailer.953766/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/dragon-age-veilguard-release-date-leaked-trailer<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>EA is set to announce the&nbsp;<em>Dragon Age: The Veilguard&nbsp;</em>release date later today, but it looks like the release date may already have leaked, along with the associated trailer.</p>
<p>As <a href="https://x.com/Wario64/status/1823957103859396777" rel="noopener" target="_blank">spotted by Wario64 on X</a> (formerly Twitter), the trailer was uploaded to Streamable in its entirety earlier today. It's not a long trailer, clocking in at around 21 seconds, but it states the release date clear as day at its conclusion: October 31st.</p>
<p>The trailer isn't actually set to air until around 12pm Eastern, so it's possible that someone at EA accidentally set the video to go live at 12AM instead. Hey, mistakes happen.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/dragon-age-the-veilguard-release-date-leaked-combat.jpg?itok=etsmhprc 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/dragon-age-the-veilguard-release-date-leaked-combat.jpg?itok=2atjFux7 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Dragon Age: The Veilguard&nbsp;</em>is apparently set to release in late October.</figcaption></figure><p>Since&nbsp;<em>Dragon Age: The Veilguard&nbsp;</em>(formerly known as&nbsp;<em>Dragon Age: Dreadwolf</em>) was <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/dragon-age-dreadwolf-the-veilguard">formally unveiled in June</a>, speculation has swirled regarding its 2024 release date, but it now looks like that speculation can be put to rest.</p>
<p>It's been a strange journey for <i>Veilguard</i>. The latest entry in the&nbsp;<em>Dragon Age&nbsp;</em>series was originally <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/dragon-age-dreadwolf-named-as-next-dragon-age-game">revealed as&nbsp;<em>Dreadwolf&nbsp;</em>back in 2022</a>, and the game <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/bioware-reaches-dragon-age-dreadwolf-alpha-milestone">completed its alpha development milestone</a> in October that same year.</p>
<p>Following that, however, BioWare fell relatively silent with regards to&nbsp;<em>Dreadwolf</em>, until it <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/dragon-age-dreadwolf-will-be-fully-revealed-in-summer-2024">announced in December last year</a> that the game would be fully revealed this summer.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The studio held to that promise, and the game, along with its new name, got its first gameplay reveal in June. If you're a long-time&nbsp;<em>Dragon Age&nbsp;</em>fan, you might notice some changes around the place.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/dragon-age-the-veilguard-release-date-leaked-monuments.jpg?itok=Mz8N7OSd 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/dragon-age-the-veilguard-release-date-leaked-monuments.jpg?itok=Vd09Vu-X 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Dragon Age: The Veilguard&nbsp;</em>has had a long and strange journey.</figcaption></figure><p>The game will <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/dragon-age-veilguard-gameplay-trailer">lean further towards action</a> than even its predecessor&nbsp;<em>Inquisition&nbsp;</em>did, so if you were hoping for a return to the classic real-time-with-pause CRPG combat for which the first game became known, you're out of luck, sadly.</p>
<p>However, if you're just hoping to start up a loving relationship with one of your companions, you'll be pleased to know they're all romanceable, a move about which&nbsp;<em>Dragon Age&nbsp;</em>creator David Gaider <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/dragon-age-creator-veilguard-romance">has expressed reservations</a>.</p>
<p><em>Dragon Age: The Veilguard&nbsp;</em>launches on October 31st, if the above leak is anything to go by. You can <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/dragon-age-veilguard-preview-epic-fantasy-action">check out our preview of the game here</a> to find out how it plays.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Homeworld 3's latest free update and paid DLC probably won't fix its Overwhelmingly Negative Steam reception]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/homeworld-3s-latest-free-update-and-paid-dlc-probably-wont-fix-its-overwhelmingly-negative-reception</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/homeworld-3s-latest-free-update-and-paid-dlc-probably-wont-fix-its-overwhelmingly-negative-steam-reception.953763/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/homeworld-3s-latest-free-update-and-paid-dlc-probably-wont-fix-its-overwhelmingly-negative-reception<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
  

        <p>It's tough in space right now</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/kalanfleetpack.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Gearbox Publishing</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>I was all set to plunge into Blackbird and Gearbox's <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/homeworld-3">Homeworld 3</a> this spring when I received <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/homeworld-3-review">a slightly underwhelmed intergalactic transmission from Nic</a>, praising the game's atmosphere and story while ruminating over fussy controls and a want of tactical depth. Like a herd of frigates scenting a pride of destroyers lurking behind a nearby asteroid, I rerouted hastily and took up a holding position approximately one astronomical unit from the Buy button, hoping that the developers might iron out a few of the wrinkles. </p><!--more-->
<p>I'm not sure if <a href="https://steamcommunity.com/app/1840080/eventcomments/4513255804484823645?snr=1_5_9_">today's free Homeworld 3 update</a> is the one I'm waiting for, but it does encompass "a host of gameplay improvements, bug fixes, [and] free Skirmish maps". It will launch alongside the Kalan Fleet pack DLC, which adds two new fleets to the space <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-best-strategy-games-on-pc">strategy</a> sim's roguelike War Games mode, including the Kalan Raiders from the story, along with three new ships.</p>
<p>The Kalan Raider fleet are a mix of Kalan and repurposed Hiigaran ships. The other new fleet is the Capture Fleet, who blend Incarnate with Kalan vessels - guess what they're good at. If you guessed "stealing other people's frigates", then go away and sulk, for I have no medals to give out. The DLC also includes 11 new challenges and 40 Artifacts. I don't get the sense that all of this will address the complaints I'm reading on the Steam forums about the single player campaign and - oh wow, the current Steam user review consensus is Overwhelmingly Negative. Is it <em>really</em> that bad?</p>
<p>Revealed to much rejoicing in 2019, Homeworld 3 has had a troubled gestation. It was repeatedly <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/homeworld-3-delayed-till-may-to-incorporate-player-feedback-to-war-games-demo">delayed to address player feedback</a>, with <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/heres-how-the-homeworld-3-devs-are-improving-the-game-after-delaying-release-over-demo-feedback">the controls proving a particular bugbear</a>. Creators Blackbird <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/homeworld-3-studio-blackbird-interactive-hit-with-layoffs">laid off staff in February this year</a> following some unannounced project cancellations.</p>
<p>According to Blackbird's <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/homeworld-3-dlc-plans-revealed-alongside-collectors-edition-with-model-spaceships">season pass roadmap from April</a>, we can expect another paid Homeworld 3 DLC in October which adds a new playable faction, starting fleets, faction artifacts and challenges. There's also a further free update in the works with maps and challenges for around the end of the year. A third paid DLC pack and free update combo are planned for 2025, with a similar balance of goodies.</p>
<p>It's hard to imagine all that moving the needle of player reaction, but still - best of luck, Blackbird. This is deep space survey ship USG Evans-Thirlwell, signing off until further notice.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2 Delayed to February 2025, Gamescom Plans Revealed]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-delayed-to-february-2025-gamescom-plans-revealed/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-delayed-to-february-2025-gamescom-plans-revealed.953760/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-delayed-to-february-2025-gamescom-plans-revealed/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>In a new <a href="https://x.com/WarhorseStudios/status/1823949533128036374" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">post on X</a> today, developer Warhorse Studios announced that its anticipated sequel Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2 will launch on February 11, 2025. </p>



<p>Fans originally expected the game to release sometime in late 2024, following a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-is-releasing-in-2024/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">leak on IGN</a> in April 2024. </p>



<p>However, today’s post also included details on future reveals, including the developer’s plans for Gamescom.</p>



<p>Warhorse Studios confirmed it will reveal a new gameplay showcase for Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2 with over 20 minutes of footage. This will release on August 21, along with a playable version, first impressions, and a Collector’s Edition reveal. </p>



<p>Fans got a small glimpse of the Collector’s Edition box during the video accompanying today’s release date announcement post.</p>



<figure><div>
<blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">A message from Warhorse Studios! The official release date for <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/KCD2?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#KCD2</a> is 11 February 2025.<br>It's a long wait, but we have a lot to show you between now and release, starting with:<br>⚔️ 20+ min gameplay showcase at <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Gamescom2024?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Gamescom2024</a><br>⚔️ Collectors Edition Reveal<br>⚔️ Previews from Press and… <a href="https://t.co/YSJrxdZZZT">pic.twitter.com/YSJrxdZZZT</a></p>— Warhorse Studios (@WarhorseStudios) <a href="https://twitter.com/WarhorseStudios/status/1823949533128036374?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 15, 2024</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>







<p>Warhorse Studios revealed the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/kingdom-come-2-gameplay-trailer/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">first gameplay trailer</a> for Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2 during Summer Game Fest 2024. </p>



<p>Although the devs acknowledged that February is “a long wait,” they also pointed out that it lines up with the release week of the first Kingdom Come. Fans remain patient and supported plans for a smooth launch.</p>



<p>Last month, Martin Ziegler of Warhorse Studios offered <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/warhorse-kingdom-come-deliverance-2-immersive/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">some in-depth details</a> on the making of the game during a new interview. They revealed behind-the-scenes efforts to create something as authentic and immersive as possible.</p>



<p>Ziegler added that “we’re introducing many iterative changes to the combat,” aiming to add more depth and make it more accessible too.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more of the latest Insider Gaming news, you can read about Sega announcing that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/sega-announces-two-point-museum-with-new-trailer/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Two Point Museum is coming soon</a> with its first trailer, and sign up to receive <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/newsletter/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">our official newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>
    
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ocean Drive Studio titles Lost Eidolons: Veil of the Witch and Section 13 to be published by Kakao Games]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/ocean-drive-studio-titles-lost-eidolons-veil-of-the-witch-and-section-13-to-be-published-by-kakao-games</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ocean-drive-studio-titles-lost-eidolons-veil-of-the-witch-and-section-13-to-be-published-by-kakao-games.953757/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/ocean-drive-studio-titles-lost-eidolons-veil-of-the-witch-and-section-13-to-be-published-by-kakao-games<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Both games featured at Gamescom 2024.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Kakao Games [4 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/kakao-games">Kakao Games</a> Europe has signed an agreement with <a title="Companies > Ocean Drive Studio [12 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/ocean-drive-studio">Ocean Drive Studio</a> to globally publish upcoming titles <em><a title="Games > Lost Eidolons: Veil of the Witch [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/lost-eidolons-veil-of-the-witch">Lost Eidolons: Veil of the Witch</a></em> and <em>Section 13</em>, the companies announced. <span id="more-906079"></span></p><p><em>Lost Eidolons: Veil of the Witch</em> is a <a title="Genres > Turn-Based RPG [955 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg/turn-based-rpg">turn-based RPG</a> follow-up to the original <em><a title="Games > Lost Eidolons [8 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/lost-eidolons">Lost Eidolons</a></em>. <em>Section 13</em> is a tactical <a title="Genres > Co-Op [189 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer/co-op">cooperative</a> <a title="Genres > Shooter [3,843 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/shooter">shooter</a> formerly titled <em><a title="Games > Section 13 [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/section-13">Blackout Protocol</a></em>.</p><p>Here is a brief overview of each game, via Kakao Games:</p><ul><li><em>Lost Eidolons: Veil of the Witch</em> builds upon the highly praised combat system of its predecessor, <em>Lost Eidolons</em>, while introducing a more immersive and enriched storyline. Unlike the original, this new title is being crafted as a turn-based RPG infused with <a title="Genres > Roguelite [183 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/roguelite">roguelite</a> elements, offering a fresh and dynamic gameplay experience.</li><li>On the other hand, <em>Section 13</em> is a reinterpretation of the tactical cooperative shooter <em>Blackout Protocol</em> as an <a title="Genres > Action [2,082 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a>-packed roguelite shooter. Ocean Drive Studio has invested heavily in enhancing both the story and gameplay, dedicating substantial resources to develop this game under its new title.</li></ul><p>Both games will be featured at Gamescom 2024, which will run from August 21 to 25 at Koelnmesse in Cologne, Germany.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[LEGO Horizon Adventures for Switch to be distributed by Solutions 2 GO]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/lego-horizon-adventures-for-switch-to-be-distributed-by-solutions-2-go</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/lego-horizon-adventures-for-switch-to-be-distributed-by-solutions-2-go.953733/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/lego-horizon-adventures-for-switch-to-be-distributed-by-solutions-2-go<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Sony Interactive Entertainment to handle other versions.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>The Switch version of <em><a title="Games > LEGO Horizon Adventures [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/lego-horizon-adventures">LEGO Horizon Adventures</a></em> will be distributed by <a title="Companies > Solutions 2 GO" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/solutions-2-go">Solutions 2 GO</a>, a video game publisher and global distributor based in the Greater Toronto area, the company announced. <span id="more-906073"></span></p><p><em>LEGO Horizon Adventures</em> is published by <a title="Companies > Sony Interactive Entertainment [4,872 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sony-interactive-entertainment">Sony Interactive Entertainment</a> and developed by <a title="Companies > Studio Gobo [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/studio-gobo">Studio Gobo</a> and <a title="Companies > Guerrilla Games [197 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sony-interactive-entertainment/guerrilla-games">Guerrilla Games</a>. The PlayStation 5 and PC versions of the game will be distributed by Sony Interactive Entertainment.</p><p>“We are incredibly excited to partner with Sony Interactive Entertainment to bring <em>LEGO Horizon Adventures</em> to a global audience on the <a title="Platforms > Switch [15,781 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Nintendo Switch</a> family of systems,” said Solutions 2 GO vice president of global publishing Rob Cleva in a press release. “This partnership underscores our commitment to delivering high-quality entertainment experiences to retail consumers around the world.”</p><p><em>LEGO Horizon Adventures</em> is due out for PlayStation 5, Switch, and PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2428810/LEGO_Horizon_Adventures?snr=1_7_15__13" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> and <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/p/lego-horizon-adventures" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Epic Games Store</a> this holiday season.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Multiplayer squad-based cyberpunk first-person shooter DEFECT announced for PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/multiplayer-squad-based-cyberpunk-first-person-shooter-defect-announced-for-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/multiplayer-squad-based-cyberpunk-first-person-shooter-defect-announced-for-pc.953730/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/multiplayer-squad-based-cyberpunk-first-person-shooter-defect-announced-for-pc<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>An "immersive and highly tactical" action shooter.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > emptyvessel [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/emptyvessel">emptyvessel</a>, an independent studio made up of former <em>DOOM</em>, <em>Call of Duty</em>, and <em>The Last of Us</em> developers, has announced <a title="Genres > Multiplayer [362 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer">multiplayer</a> squad-based cyberpunk <a title="Genres > First-Person Shooter [2,513 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/shooter/fps">first-person shooter</a> <em><a title="Games > DEFECT" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/defect">DEFECT</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > PC [20,896 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> (<a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2470010/DEFECT/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a>). A release date was not announced. <span id="more-905649"></span></p><p>“Our goal with <em>DEFECT</em> is to deliver a new approach for both gamers and for developers,” said emptyvessel CEO and game director Emanuel Palalic in a press release. “We’re exploring an authoritarian take on the game world, and leaning hard into the ‘punk’ in cyberpunk, fully immersing players into the carnage of a society where technology isn’t just a tool, but a burden. For the industry, we want to inspire other game makers to work in smaller teams, as we are, to have the ability to take more creative risks and work more independently. We’re really excited about making <em>DEFECT</em> and hope that everyone follows our story!”</p><div id="carousel_905652"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div><p>Here is an overview of the game, via emptyvessel:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>DEFECT</em> is a multiplayer, squad-based cyberpunk <a title="Genres > Shooter [3,843 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/shooter">shooter</a>. It will deliver a new kind of experience through its immersive and highly tactical combat for fans of the action shooter genre.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>From the creative minds of emptyvessel comes an original intellectual property set in a futuristic, divided city ruled by an enigmatic artificial intelligence system, all while ruthless gangs and rogue law enforcement vie for supremacy. <em>DEFECT</em> is being created by industry-leading developers behind iconic franchises including <em>DOOM</em>, <em>Call of Duty</em>, and <em>The Last of Us</em>.</p><p>DEFECT is emptyvessel’s first title, and is built using the groundbreaking Unreal Engine 5. Utilizing the latest technology and the team’s vision for delivering unique and exciting gameplay experiences, players will be immersed into a war between anarchy and authority that can only be found in <em>DEFECT</em>.</p><p>Revel in the anarchy of a city on the brink. <em>DEFECT</em> is an immersive objective shooter set in the last city of mankind, where THE SYSTEM, an authoritarian artificial intelligence, rules with inhuman logic. Players will choose from a collection of dangerous factions–The System’s own policing force, Rogue Police Elements, or a host of gangs vying for power to play with friends in player-versus-player or <a title="Genres > Co-Op [189 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer/co-op">cooperative multiplayer</a>. Compete to achieve objectives like smuggling guns, assassinating targets, or arresting suspects. Suit up with state-of-the-art weaponry and technology to give you the edge you need to live another day.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Control vs. Chaos</strong> – Fight as the totalitarian forces crushing humanity beneath the boot of the law or the gang factions killing anyone between them and full control of the city.</li><li><strong>Dynamic <a title="Genres > Action [2,082 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">Action</a></strong> – Fight in tense and tactical matches as a member of a four-person squad, as you attempt to fend off other teams eager to claim every credit and reward for their own. Every match has multiple objectives with different finales.</li><li><strong>Prepare for Anarchy</strong> – Come together with your squad to gear up and collect what you need in your squad car or gang hangout to be ready for anything the battle throws at you. While in the fight, keep an keen eye out for pickups that can change the course of the match. You never know what you’ll find.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch the announcement trailer below. View the first screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/defect/august-15-2024/">at the gallery</a>. Visit the official website <a href="https://www.playdefect.com/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">here</a>.</p><h2><span>Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="DEFECT - Announce Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/hqMC6K9Iq8o?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Forza Horizon 5 Is Coming to PlayStation 5 Soon; There Are No Active Plans for Starfield Yet]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/forza-horizon-5-starfield-playstation-5/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/forza-horizon-5-is-coming-to-playstation-5-soon-there-are-no-active-plans-for-starfield-yet.953712/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/forza-horizon-5-starfield-playstation-5/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Forza Horizon 5 will be the next former Xbox console exclusive from Microsoft to release on PlayStation 5, according to rumors circulating online.</p>
<p>As revealed by the reliable <a href="https://x.com/eXtas1stv/status/1823894370040373519?t=brqrJCUvYX180NOKKmjyzg&amp;s=19" target="_blank" rel="noopener">eXtas1s</a>, the latest entry in the series is coming to PlayStation 5 soon, within the next few months. The timing of the announcement is not clear, but the leaker has no doubt the game is coming to Sony's current generation console.</p>
<p>Besides revealing the Forza Horizon 5 PS5 port, eXstas1s also commented on the highly anticipated port of Starfield, saying that there are no active plans for it yet. This is hardly surprising, considering Bethesda's RPG launched not even<a href="https://wccftech.com/review/starfield-the-elder-space-scrolls/"> a year ago.</a></p>
<p>Forza Horizon 5 may not be the Xbox exclusive PlayStation 5 owners have been waiting for the most, but it's still great news that more players will be able to enjoy Playground Games' excellent racing game. You can learn more about it by checking out Chris' <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/forza-horizon-5-review/">review.</a></p>
<p><em>Forza Horizon 5 is yet another step up for the series and arguably the best racing game ever made. Offering a host of content across a fantastic representation of Mexico, its varied terrain and scenery, there's so much to explore and race. A massive roster of cars will perform all of these, each feeling different from the others, with a variety of upgrade and tuning options almost matching those of simulation titles. While there are a few minor niggles here and there, they are nearly so small as to be hardly worth mentioning. All in all, it's impossible not to recommend this for anybody, regardless of them being a fan of racing games or not, as this is that good.</em></p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indiana Jones And The Great Circle is Still Launching in 2024]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/indiana-jones-2024-release-date/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-is-still-launching-in-2024.953709/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/indiana-jones-2024-release-date/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Indiana Jones The Great Circle is still launching in 2024 and will be given a release date at Opening Night Live on August 20.</p>



<p>Earlier in August, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/avowed-delay-confirmed-2025/">Xbox delayed Avowed to February 18, 2025</a>, which was said to be because Xbox Game Pass had a plethora of games launching in late 2024. Shortly after the announcement, speculation online turned to Indiana Jones and its lack of release date. However, according to a preview event that took place this week, Xbox has said that the game is on track to launch in 2024 and that its release date will be announced at Opening Night Live at Gamescom.</p>



<p>Unfortunately, the exact date wasn’t announced during the preview event.</p>



<p>Officially, we know that Indiana Jones and the Great Circle will be getting a “new look” during Opening Night Live.</p>



<p>Earlier today, rumours began circulating that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/next-xbox-game-coming-to-playstation-next-week-its-claimed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">another Xbox game would be coming to PlayStation</a>, with an announcement coming sometime next week. So far, the rumors seem to indicate that the game will be Forza Horizon 5. eXtas1s, a leaker who has gained a reputation for Xbox Game Pass leaks simply tweeted a GIF saying “Feliz Cinco de Mayo”, implying Forza Horizon, however, <a href="https://www.windowscentral.com/gaming/xbox/rumor-another-big-xbox-game-is-heading-to-ps5-to-be-announced-next-week" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Jez Corden of Windows Central</a>&nbsp;claims that a port is going to be announced next week, but it’s not expected to be Forza Horizon 5 at this time.</p>



<p>Are you excited tog et your hands on Indiana Jones later this year? Let us know down in the comments below!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more of the latest gaming industry news, read about&nbsp;the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dragon-age-the-veilguards-release-date-has-surfaced-online/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Dragon Age: The Veilguard’s release date leaking online</a>&nbsp;and sign up for the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/newsletter/">Insider Gaming&nbsp;newsletter</a></p>




















    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>
    
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Monster Hunter Wilds weapon trailer – ‘Switch Axe’]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/monster-hunter-wilds-weapon-trailer-switch-axe</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/monster-hunter-wilds-weapon-trailer-%E2%80%93-%E2%80%98switch-axe%E2%80%99.953706/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/monster-hunter-wilds-weapon-trailer-switch-axe<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Morph between Axe and Sword modes depending on the situation.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Capcom [2,516 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/capcom">Capcom</a> has released a new weapon trailer for <em><a title="Games > Monster Hunter Wilds [13 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/monster-hunter-wilds">Monster Hunter Wilds</a></em> introducing the Switch Axe. <span id="more-906036"></span></p><p><em>Monster Hunter Wilds</em> is due out for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [7,661 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [5,834 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [20,896 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2246340/Monster_Hunter_Wilds/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> in 2025.</p><p>Watch the trailer below.</p><h2><span>Weapon Overview: Switch Axe</span></h2><p>“The versatile Switch Axe can morph between it’s powerful Axe Mode and the swift Sword Mode on the fly to fit the situation. With Focus Mode, accurately target the enemy’s weak point and discharge your weapon’s phials!”</p><p><strong>English</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><iframe title="Monster Hunter Wilds: Switch Axe | Weapon Overview" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/toi52e8Lf0U?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe title="『モンスターハンターワイルズ』武器紹介動画：スラッシュアックス" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/lbTgUFI7YNY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Final Fantasy XVI on Xbox Is “Going to Happen”, Known Leaker Says]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/final-fantasy-xvi-xbox-happen/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/final-fantasy-xvi-on-xbox-is-%E2%80%9Cgoing-to-happen%E2%80%9D-known-leaker-says.953700/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/final-fantasy-xvi-xbox-happen/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Final Fantasy XVI has yet to be released on platforms other than the PlayStation 5, but according to rumors circulating online, Square Enix has more in the works than the announced PC port.</p>
<p>Speaking on the <a href="https://www.resetera.com/threads/xbox-game-studios-bethesda-abk-ot31-perfect-doom.894510/post-127183653">ResetERA forums,</a> well-known leaker NateDrake talked about the latest main entry in the series coming to Xbox consoles, saying that it is going to happen without adding much more. While next week's Gamescom would be perfect for an announcement, the fact that the PC port has yet to receive an official release date suggests that Square Enix may wait a little longer to make an announcement.</p>
<p>Final Fantasy XVI coming to Xbox Series X and Xbox Series S wouldn't exactly be surprising, considering Square Enix and Microsoft collaborated for Final Fantasy XIV release on the consoles. Naoki Yoshida himself<a href="https://wccftech.com/final-fantasy-xvi-director-wants-as-many-as-possible-to-play-the-game-possibly-hinting-at-xbox-launch-after-pc/"> confirmed</a> that they would like to make the game available for as many people as possible, heavily hinting at the unannounced Xbox version of the game.</p>
<p>Final Fantasy XVI is now out on PlayStation 5 and should be released on PC <a href="https://wccftech.com/final-fantasy-xvi-pc-driver-profile/">before long</a>. You can learn more about the latest entry in the series by checking out Kai's <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/final-fantasy-xvi-the-planets-dyin-clive/">review.</a></p>
<p><em>Final Fantasy XVI heralds in a new standard for Japanese role-playing games and while the RPG components themselves are limited by Square-Enix standards, it's the narrative and gameplay that exceed all expectations. What begins with kingdom-wide subterfuge and destruction ends with a world forever changed and the player, as Clive Rosfield and Ifrit together, are the driving force to see it all through until the end.</em></p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Skyblivion Oblivion Remaster Mod New Video Provides New Look at Gameplay]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/skyblivion-oblivion-remaster-gameplay/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/skyblivion-oblivion-remaster-mod-new-video-provides-new-look-at-gameplay.953697/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/skyblivion-oblivion-remaster-gameplay/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>New <a href="https://wccftech.com/skyblivion-looks-gorgeous-in-the-latest-developer-diary/">Skyblivion</a> gameplay footage was shared online, providing a new look at the mod, which will attempt to remake the fourth entry in The Elder Scrolls series using Skyrim's engine.</p>
<p>The new footage, which can be watched below, showcases a big part of the map and multiple quests set in the shown areas that seem to have been recreated quite faithfully from the original. Hopefully, the rest of the project will feature the same level of quality as the sequences shown in the new footage.</p>
<p><iframe title="Oblivion Remastered Gameplay First Look | SKYBLIVION Quest Showcase 2" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/hQohYRzybBg?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Skyblivion has been in development for quite some time, but thankfully the wait won't be much longer as the total conversion mod is still targeting a 2025 release. Once it launches, players will be able to experience the entirety of Oblivion like they never did before with both Skyrim Legacy Edition and Skyrim Special Edition, with reimagined and improved cities, homes, caves, dungeons, and forts across Cyrodiil with new and improved layouts and encounters, new creatures and monsters featuring lore-friendly additions from the rest of the series, new loading screens, class cards, attribute art and much more.</p>
<p>More information on Skyblivion can be found on its <a href="https://skyblivion.com/">official website</a>. As mentioned above, the mod is scheduled for a 2025 release.</p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2 delays its medieval RPG hustling until early next year]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-delays-its-medieval-rpg-hustling-until-early-next-year</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-delays-its-medieval-rpg-hustling-until-early-next-year.953691/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-delays-its-medieval-rpg-hustling-until-early-next-year<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-delayed-release-date.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Deep Silver</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>Put your mortar and pestle down, my herb-smooshing friend. The peasant-quelling <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-rpgs">RPG</a> antics of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/kingdom-come-deliverance-2">Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2</a> won't be releasing this year after all, say developers Warhorse <a href="https://x.com/WarhorseStudios/status/1823949533128036374"> in a video message to fans</a>. "We aimed for the end of the year, and almost made it," said PR man Tobi Stolz-Zwilling. "Almost is not good enough though, so unfortunately we slipped to 2025."  Never mind, it's easy to slip in the medieval era. There was mud everywhere.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>They do now have a firmer release date for the game though, as opposed to a vague "2024". It'll be out on February 11th, they say. There's also talk of upcoming previews and a presence at Gamescom. Oh, hey! We'll be at Gamescom! James? JAMES. Is Kingdom Come Deliverance 2 on your itinerary for Gamescom?</p>
<p><strong>James:</strong> It is not, apologies.</p>
<p>Ah, jeez. How are we going to know what this sequel will be like? Well, the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/boys-will-once-again-be-boys-in-kingdom-come-deliverance-2-revealed-today-for-2024-release">lengthy reveal trailer</a> shown earlier this year gives us some clues. It'll continue the story of peasant-born adventurer Henry, and be set mostly in the Czech city of Kuttenberg. Developers Warhorse seem to feel their story as a business matches that of its rags-to-rapiers hero, citing their growth from a small studio of 11 people to a big company of 250 employees. It other words, the game will probably be shinier.</p>
<p>We can also consider the first game. It was <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/kingdom-come-deliverance-delayed-2017">also delayed</a>, just so you know. And it turned out to be a mostly okay mix of interesting features and grounded questing. Reading was a skill you had to learn. You could save your game by getting mildly drunk. And NPC guards would stop you to check your pockets if you were consistently misbehaving. </p>
<p>"Warhorse's debut RPG shines brightest when the quest design really digs into the peculiarities of its era, not quite cutting you adrift, but certainly not holding your hand," said Edwin in <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/kingdom-come-deliverance-review">our review</a>. But he also pointed out some "tedious macho elements" and a loose bugginess that plagued the game. Concerning the emphasis on historical accuracy which the game strove for, lead developer Daniel Vávra was criticised for fuelling gamergate with <a href="https://x.com/danielvavra/status/569686445344079872?lang=en">some questionable remarks</a>, and later <a href="https://www.resetera.com/threads/statement-by-daniel-v%C3%A1vra-and-martin-kl%C3%ADma-regarding-racism-nazism-accusations-gamestar-de.17259/">apologised for that</a>. This somewhat soured the game's reception in many quarters.</p>
<p>We'll know more about the sequel as the days pass until its release, whether it's on James' itinerary or not.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Final Fantasy 16 is Coming to Xbox, It’s Claimed]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/final-fantasy-16-is-coming-to-xbox-its-claimed/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/final-fantasy-16-is-coming-to-xbox-it%E2%80%99s-claimed.953685/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/final-fantasy-16-is-coming-to-xbox-its-claimed/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Reliable leaker NateDrake has claimed that Final Fantasy 16 is arriving for Xbox soon.&nbsp;</p>



<p>NateDrake was asked on ResetEra (via <a href="https://xboxera.com/2024/08/15/rumor-final-fantasy-16-coming-to-xbox/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">XboxEra</a>) whether any more games were coming to Xbox and if a Final Fantasy 16 release is possible. NateDrake replied that Final Fantasy 16 on Xbox “is going to happen. Just waiting for Square to announce it”. &nbsp;</p>



<p>It’s worth noting that this claim about Final Fantasy 16 being released on Xbox comes just a week after rumours about the game coming to PC surfaced. Last week, keen-eyed Reddit users spotted a Game Ready profile for Final Fantasy 16 in <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nvidias-latest-driver-includes-a-game-ready-profile-for-final-fantasy-16/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Nvidia’s latest driver</a>, suggesting an announcement for a potential PC release could be on the horizon. We might receive more clarity on this at Gamescom 2024. </p>



<h2 id="h-about-final-fantasy-16">About Final Fantasy 16</h2>



<p>Final Fantasy 16 is the newest standalone entry in the long-standing Square Enix series, exclusive to PlayStation 5. The game is set in Valisthea, a world filled with Mothercrystals that provide aether fuel to help the population survive. However, the light from the Mothercrystals is slowly fading, and the Blight is gradually destroying everything in its path.</p>



<p>You play Clive Rosfield, First Shield of Rosaria, in the game. Your mission is to free humankind from their fate and use Eikonic powers as the Dominant to defeat all enemies that come your way. Eikons are the most powerful and deadly creatures in Valisthea, and you have to harness their power to overcome them.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Final Fantasy XVI - 'Salvation' Launch Trailer | PS5 Games" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/aPT26Dd3OzE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>In other news, the director of Final Fantasy 7 Rebirth <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/final-fantasy-7-rebirth-director-is-considering-unreal-engine-5-for-the-next-instalment/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">is considering switching to Unreal Engine 5</a> for the final instalment. Also, the director of Final Fantasy 14 <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/final-fantasy-14-director-denies-ff9-remake-involvement/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">denied involvement</a> in the FF 9 remake. What are your thoughts on Final Fantasy 16 seemingly coming to Xbox? Let us know in the comments.&nbsp;</p>



<hr>



<p>For more of the latest gaming industry news, read about&nbsp;the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dragon-age-the-veilguards-release-date-has-surfaced-online/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Dragon Age: The Veilguard’s release date leaking online</a>&nbsp;and sign up for the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/newsletter/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming&nbsp;newsletter</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>
    
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Embracer prioritizing 'controlled key IPs' to improve profitability of PC and console releases]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/embracer-prioritizing-controlled-key-ips-to-improve-profitability-of-pc-and-console-releases</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/embracer-prioritizing-controlled-key-ips-to-improve-profitability-of-pc-and-console-releases.953679/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/embracer-prioritizing-controlled-key-ips-to-improve-profitability-of-pc-and-console-releases<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Perennial spender turned layoff merchant Embracer Group says its plan to </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/embracer-splitting-into-three-standalone-companies-to-search-for-winning-formulas-">transform into three standalone businesses</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> is on track, but feels there's room for improvement in some areas.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">In its </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://embracer.com/releases/embracer-group-publishes-interim-report-q1-april-june-2024-adjusted-ebit-amounted-to-sek-828-million/">fiscal report for the first quarter ended June 30, 2024</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, the Swedish conglomerate indicated it must improve profitability within its PC / Console Games segment by focusing on its "own and controlled key IPs, which typically have better unit economics." That comes with net sales in the unit decreasing by 34 percent year-over-year to SEK 2.65 billion ($253.2 million).</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Elsewhere, Mobile Games net sales decreased by 3 percent to SEK 1.39 billion. Tabletop Games net sales fell by 5 percent to SEK 3.04 billion, and Entertainment &amp; Services net sales tumbled by 54 percent to SEK 848 million.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Combined, those downturns resulted in consolidated net sales falling by 24 percent to SEK 7.9 billion ($754.8 million) across Q1. Adjusted EBIT totalled SEK 0.8 billion ($76.4 million). Pro forma net debt stands at SEK 14.3 billion ($1.36 billion).</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Embracer CEO Lars Wingefors said performance is "in line with management expectations," and highlighted "growing profitability year-on-year in both the Mobile and Tabletop segments." He claimed performance was "softer" in PC / Console and Entertainment &amp; Services due to "lower release activity."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Due to a lack of notable new releases and a tough comparison from the successful release of </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Dead Island 2 </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">in the corresponding quarter last year, the organic growth in the PC/Console Games segment was -30 percent in the quarter," he added.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Excluding the release of </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Dead Island 2 </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">in the comparison quarter, the organic growth was 15 percent in Q1. The 5 percent adjusted EBIT margin is impacted by amortization of releases with low ROI from the past 24 months. The new content that came out for </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Deep Rock Galactic</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Remnant II </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Dead Island 2 </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">performed well in line with management expectations."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Embracer is still attempting to steady the ship after </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/embracer-s-m-a-era-is-ending-with-job-cuts-and-game-cancellations">enacting a colossal restructuring program</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> that resulted in </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/gearbox-is-officially-out-from-under-embracer-group">studio closures and divestments</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, project cancellations, and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/embracer-says-it-s-looking-out-for-shareholders-after-cutting-almost-1-400-jobs">mass layoffs</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. Highlighting the scale of that upheaval, the number of game projects in development has dropped to 127 from 215 in the space of 12 months. The company's total headcount has also fallen to 10,844 employees from 16,605 employees over the past year.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Looking ahead, Wingefors said he remains "confident" in Embracer's release pipeline for the financial year, and indicated the company will be able to deliver higher quality titles thanks to an "updated capital allocation process" that will enable "new and continued investment."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"We are confident in our pipeline for the financial year, and still expect the value of completed game development for the year to be around SEK 3.9 billion. Our teams are committed to making and delivering better games," continued Wingefors.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Our highly anticipated game </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Kingdom Come: Deliverance II</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, is now confirmed for global release on February 11, 2025, which we believe enables some final polish and a better release window. We look very much forward to Gamescom next week to share more details about this game and other titles."</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">News Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer news editor Chris Kerr is an award-winning journalist and reporter with over a decade of experience in the game industry. His byline has appeared in notable print and digital publications including Edge, Stuff, Wireframe, International Business Times, and&nbsp;</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="http://pocketgamer.biz/">PocketGamer.biz</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. Throughout his career, Chris has covered major industry events including GDC, PAX Australia, Gamescom, Paris Games Week, and Develop Brighton. He has featured on the judging panel at The Develop Star Awards on multiple occasions and appeared on BBC Radio 5 Live to discuss breaking news.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Oops... the release date for Dragon Age: The Veilguard leaks a few hours early]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/oops-the-release-date-for-dragon-age-the-veilguard-gets-leaks-a-few-hours-early</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/oops-the-release-date-for-dragon-age-the-veilguard-leaks-a-few-hours-early.953661/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/oops-the-release-date-for-dragon-age-the-veilguard-gets-leaks-a-few-hours-early<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/dragon-age-the-veilguard-headline3.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Electronic Arts</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>The release date for <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/dragon-age-dreadwolf">Dragon Age: The Veilguard</a> has been revealed in a last-minute leak thanks to a naughty video advertisement. Electronic Arts had planned to share the game's debut-day in about... *checks watchless wrist* ... 7 hours, as part of a special <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=g8DkDQhPx2A">release date trailer</a>. But the internet will ever internet, and thanks to some slip-up or other, we have the knowledge just a smidge early. Will I tell you what the actual release date is? Sure. I guess so.</p>
<!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Dragon Age: The Veilguard | Release Date Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/g8DkDQhPx2A?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Dragon Age: The Veilguard | Release Date Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/g8DkDQhPx2A?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/g8DkDQhPx2A?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=g8DkDQhPx2A" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>The very purple <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-rpgs">RPG</a> is coming out October 31, according to the wayward ad, which was <a href="https://x.com/Wario64/status/1823957103859396777">caught by Xitter leak-enjoyer Wario64</a>, among others. I've embedded the upcoming release trailer anyway, so you can enjoy that when it finally does land. I haven't seen it yet, so let's see if I can accurately predict what will happen in it.</p>
<ul>
<li>A creature squeals and is upset</li>
<li>A mage crosses their arms haughtily</li>
<li>VFX blasts a bunch of wooden crates to pieces</li>
<li>Varric looks suggestively at the camera</li>
</ul>
<p>Did any of that come true? As you can see, I'm struggling. I lept from the Dragon Age tour bus after the city of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/dragon-age-ii">Dragon Age 2</a> pulled the series away from being a world-crossing jaunt and focused on one (I think) fairly uninteresting city. The opening area of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/dragon-age-inquisition">Dragon Age: Inquisition</a> didn't reinvigorate me. But I know lots of folks follow the trials of these warlocky weirdoes with relish. "Dragon Age II, unfairly maligned in my opinion, is about one city facing external and internal conflict over a long period of time," said Alice B <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/have-you-played-dragon-age-inquisition-2">once upon a time</a>. "Inquisition is about a world at war with itself, literally and metaphorically." It also has a fun bit where you <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-joy-of-being-the-belle-of-the-ball-in-dragon-age-inquisition">gatecrash a fancy masked ball</a>. </p>
<p>It's been a while since Inquisition came out, so you can be forgiven if you have no idea why elf mage Solas is suddenly doing some dubious portal opening. Luckily, Veilguard will bring you through the story so far, and even <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dragon-age-the-veilguard-will-let-you-bring-over-your-choices-from-inquisition-whether-you-still-have-your-save-or-not">let you stick to your old choices</a>, if you can remember them.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dragon Age: The Veilguard’s Release Date Has Surfaced Online]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/dragon-age-the-veilguards-release-date-has-surfaced-online/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dragon-age-the-veilguard%E2%80%99s-release-date-has-surfaced-online.953658/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/dragon-age-the-veilguards-release-date-has-surfaced-online/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-52978">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>Dragon Age: The Veilguard’s developer announced yesterday that the title’s release date should arrive today, August 15. However, before the official announcement, a video revealing the game’s release date surfaced online.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Spotted on the popular subreddit r/<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GamingLeaksAndRumours/comments/1esmb92/dragon_age_the_veilguard_release_date/?utm_source=ifttt" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">GamingLeaksAndRumours</a>, a small clip for Dragon Age: The Veilguard has surprisingly popped up ahead of the official announcement. This 20-second clip showcases some cinematics and gameplay before providing a release date for the upcoming title. According to the video, Dragon Age: The Veilguard will be released on October 31, 2024.</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>Bioware had announced an ‘Upcoming Reveals’ schedule on X (formerly Twitter) yesterday. The schedule stated that a release date trailer and announcement would arrive on August 15, followed by a ‘High-Level Combat and PC Spotlight’ trailer in the week of August 19. Then, in the week of August 26, Dragon Age: The Veilguard’s Companions will be highlighted with a Developer Discord Q&amp;A scheduled for August 30. More reveals were planned for September and beyond.&nbsp;</p>



<figure><div>
<blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>The release date for <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/DragonAge?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#DragonAge</a>: The Veilguard will be revealed TOMORROW!   </p><p>We're excited to share this moment with our fans with a release date trailer, and in the coming weeks we'll also have high-level warrior combat gameplay, Companions Week, and more. 💜  </p><p>Tune in to our… <a href="https://t.co/Djft37NIh5">pic.twitter.com/Djft37NIh5</a></p></div>— Dragon Age (@dragonage) <a href="https://twitter.com/dragonage/status/1823751789453435295?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 14, 2024</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>



<p>In other news, you can check out 20 minutes of Dragon Age: The Veilguard gameplay <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/watch-20-minutes-of-dragon-age-the-veilguard-gameplay/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">here</a>. Also, check out why Dragon Age Dreadwolf was <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dragon-age-the-veilguard/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">renamed</a>. What are your thoughts on Dragon Age: The Veilguard’s leaked release date? Let us know in the comments.&nbsp;</p>



<hr>



<p>For more of the latest gaming industry news, read about&nbsp;the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/next-xbox-game-coming-to-playstation-next-week-its-claimed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">next Xbox title coming to PlayStation next week</a>&nbsp;and sign up for the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/newsletter/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming&nbsp;newsletter</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>
    
	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/next-xbox-game-coming-to-playstation-next-week-its-claimed/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/next-xbox-game-coming-to-playstation-next-week-its-claimed/">Next Xbox Game Announced For PlayStation Next Week, It’s Claimed</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>According to multiple teases, the next Xbox console-exclusive game could be making its way to PlayStation as early as next week.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/alien-rogue-incursion-vr-release-date-pre-order-details-and-more-revealed/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/alien-rogue-incursion-vr-release-date-pre-order-details-and-more-revealed/">Alien: Rogue Incursion VR Release Date, Pre-Order Details and More Revealed&nbsp;</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Survios has announced the release date, pre-order details, and more for Alien: Rogue Incursion VR, along with a new trailer.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dr-disrespect-deleted-confession-post/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dr-disrespect-deleted-confession-post/">Dr Disrespect Deleted His Confession Post From X</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Dr Disrespect has deleted the post he published on social media in which he confessed to inappropriately messaging a minor in 2017.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/grid-esports-tracker-network-partnership/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/grid-esports-tracker-network-partnership/">GRID Esports Links With Tracker Network To Provide Valorant Esports Data</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>GRID Esports has linked up with Tracker Network to provide key esports data for Valorant, presenting a new competitive edge for the platform.</p>
                    </div>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cataclismo Early Access Review – the most innovative indie of the year?]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/08/15/cataclismo-early-access-review-the-most-innovative-indie-of-the-year/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cataclismo-early-access-review-%E2%80%93-the-most-innovative-indie-of-the-year.953652/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/08/15/cataclismo-early-access-review-the-most-innovative-indie-of-the-year/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>How do you make a game stand out in the modern age? Innovative ideas and designs might be the path to longevity, but, if we’re all being honest, a game’s visuals are the initial hook. Cataclismo manages both feats though, with a beautiful, distinctive aesthetic married to an inventive take on tower defence and RTS mechanics. Launched into Early Access last month, Cataclismo is an enigmatic, atmospheric, and even at this point, borderline essential title from the team behind <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2018/05/28/moonlighter-review/">Moonlighter</a> and The Mageseeker: A League of Legends Story.</p>
<p><iframe title="Cataclismo - Sandbox Mode Trailer | Base Building RTS/Siege Defense" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9nacsUxzSLQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>You take on the role of the Lady Iris, leader of the last remnants of humanity. This was once a vibrant world, and remained so when the perlas appeared, giant glowing orbs that carried immense power. Humanity accepted their gifts, but, as with most things, this power came with a price. The world became covered in Mist, its enveloping cloak hiding a malignance that transformed people into foul, thoughtless creatures known as horrors. These grim remnants are attracted to the remaining humans, and so, you must defend against this ongoing threat.</p>


<p>The remaining people reside in Hogar, the last city yet to fall to the Mist. As their leader, Lady Iris commands the steadily growing troops, oversees building, and assists in the city’s defence as well. Unusually, Lady Iris was born with a perla within her, an oddity that allows her to perform Artes. These special actions form the cornerstone of your defense against the monstrous hordes. These abilities can be discovered, upgraded and strengthened as you progress, and likewise you’ll unlock new buildings and structures to help you guard against the horrors as they grow ever more dangerous and greater in number.</p>


<p>Cataclismo is dark. Its landscape leers out of the gloom, black edges teetering against stone and tree alike. It marries well with the bold lines and simple shapes of the people that dwell there, and there’s a comic-like design to each of the different units and the Lady Iris herself. That ties into the cutscenes, which in turn remind you of the more thoughtful artstyle of books like Y: The Last Man or Mike Mignola’s Hellboy. Whichever comparisons or influences are apparent, Art Director David Aguado has absolutely nailed it.</p>
<p>Controlling your army is reassuringly familiar. Selecting units and deploying them is as simple as it’s ever been, though at the outset they might just be the chattiest group I’ve come across since Warcraft III, acknowledging your every request with a selection of dialogue. While actions are played out in real-time, you can pause the action whenever you like, issuing commands or simply gathering your breath for the next assault. It’s especially important when you’re about to indulge in Cataclimso’s most rewarding aspect: building.</p>
<p>Each settlement you build must be designed to protect the people within. You have to build up your defenses, make them accessible for your troops, and think about the most effective way to fight off your attackers. This means chunky stone walls and parapets thrusting into the air behind your ground troops, as well as walkways and stairs for your ranged units to clamber up.</p>

<p>Hogar’s impressive Solas Gate forms the initial defensive structure, and it stands as the last line of defense against the swarms that come every night, attracted to the people within. Your first major task in the campaign is to build further walls, and you immediately get a sense of the straightforward but powerful building tools that let you quickly create new structures.</p>
<p>The higher your walls, the more strength they have. There’s then a variety of bonuses that can be bestowed on your troops by adding Tactical Pieces to your structure. The team have previously likened the building tools to Lego, and there is a glorious simplicity to the way it all locks together, telling you when something isn’t correctly supported, or making you rethink your approach so that you create a structure using the finite resources at your disposal.</p>
<p>As you try to push back against the horrors, you build new settlements, or reinforce those that have fallen. To do so, you have to build up a working economy, with wood, stone and oxygen forming the central points within it. A Sawmill is the first building you must put down, but you then have to make sure there’s a clear route to your Citadel for it to function. The city-building tools are as well thought out as you’d hope, and the modularity of the walls carries over to each of the buildings, with flat roofs allowing you to continue building further structures on top of them.</p>

<p>The music here is the final, and perhaps most important, layer to Cataclismo’s atmosphere. Synth-led tones grow and pulsate, rising out of the gloom in the same way the visuals do, while plaintive acoustic guitar tells its own story in the quieter moments. These are then juxtaposed with bombastic moments of drama, the two key instruments joining together to create something powerful and moving.</p>
<p>Cataclismo is tough. You have to get used to the rhythm of pausing the game to build, organise your troops and prepare, before letting the timer wind down to the evening and a fresh wave of horrors. It’s well worth persevering though, and with Iris’ ability to rewind time, you can return to several set points through each level, allowing you to correct where you’ve gone wrong.</p>
<p>This is all in the stellar campaign, with hours of gameplay to be found here alone. The addition of skirmish mode, where you can play across hand-crafted maps, including your own, and an endless mode that gives you a steady stream of procedurally generated maps means that Cataclismo is capable of taking all your gaming time, and then probably a bit more. I didn’t go to sleep until 1AM last night, and it is definitely Cataclismo’s fault.</p>
<p>If you’re looking for this year’s most innovative, genre-splicing indie, then Cataclismo has set a standard that looks unlikely to be beaten.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dragon Age: The Veilguard October release date leaks]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/08/15/dragon-age-the-veilguard-october-release-date-leaks/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dragon-age-the-veilguard-october-release-date-leaks.953649/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/08/15/dragon-age-the-veilguard-october-release-date-leaks/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>EA and BioWare will reveal the <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/dragon-age-the-veilguard">Dragon Age: The Veilguard</a> release date later today, with an announcement trailer set to go live at 5PM BST, but the game’s 31st October 2024 launch has already leaked by way of a video advertisement – picked up by the ever-watchful <a href="https://x.com/Wario64/status/1823957103859396777">Wario64</a>.</p>
<p>So…. Dragon Age: The Veilguard is coming to <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/playstation-5">PS5</a>, <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/xbox-series-x">Xbox Series X|S</a> and PC on 31st October.</p>
<p><iframe title="Dragon Age: The Veilguard | Release Date Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/g8DkDQhPx2A?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>Dragon Age: The Veilguard – <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/06/06/dragon-age-the-veilguard-dreadwolf-single-player/">previously known as Dragon Age 4 and then as Dragon Age: Dreadwolf</a> – is the long-awaited return of one of BioWare’s most popular RPG series.</p>
<p>The studio has ramped up the reveals and announcements in the last few months, starting with <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/06/11/the-dragon-age-the-veilguard-gameplay-reveal-is-here/">a big gameplay trailer</a> during Summer Game Fest, which showcased the earliest part of the game with our player character, Rook, and series mainstay Varric delving into the very pretty, but seedy city of Minrathous on the hunt for Solas. This also introduced a few other companions, as they raced against time to stop&nbsp;Solas from conducting a ritual that’s breaking the barrier between world, the Veil, which is allowing demons to enter this world.</p>

<p>At the end of July, BioWare then revealed the full cast list of voice actors for all the companions:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Rook </strong>voiced be&nbsp;Erika Ishii&nbsp;(Apex Legends, Destiny 2),&nbsp;Jeff Berg&nbsp;(Battlefield 1, NCIS),&nbsp;Bryony Corrigan&nbsp;(Baldur’s Gate 3, Good Omens) and&nbsp;Alex Jordan&nbsp;(Cyberpunk 2077, The Amazing World of Gumball).</li>
<li><strong>Harding the Dwarven Scout</strong> voiced by Ali Hillis (Mass Effect 3, Naruto)</li>
<li><strong>Davrin the Grey Warden&nbsp;</strong>voiced by Ike Amadi (Mass Effect 3, Halo 5: Guardians, Insomniac’s Spider-Man)</li>
<li><strong>Bellara the Veil Jumper </strong>voiced by Jee Young Han (Perry Mason, Unprisoned)</li>
<li><strong>Neve the Shadow Dragons rebel </strong>voiced by Jessica Clark (True Blood, Pocket Listing)</li>
<li><strong>Taash the Dragon Hunter </strong>voiced by Jin Maley (Star Trek: Picard, Silicon Valley)</li>
<li><strong>Emmrich the Necromancer </strong>voiced by Nick Boraine (Call of Duty: Modern Warfare, Black Sails)</li>
<li><strong>Manfred, Emmrich’s skeletal assistant</strong>, voiced by Matthew Mercer&nbsp;(Critical Role, Fallout 4).</li>
<li><strong>Lucanis the Assassin </strong>voiced by&nbsp;Zach Mendez (Horizon Forbidden West, Married Alive)</li>
</ul>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://x.com/Wario64/status/1823957103859396777">Wario64</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>