<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 23:56:59 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sea of Thieves is finally letting private server players earn full rewards starting in December]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/sea-of-thieves-is-finally-letting-private-server-players-earn-full-rewards-starting-in-december</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sea-of-thieves-is-finally-letting-private-server-players-earn-full-rewards-starting-in-december.1035321/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/sea-of-thieves-is-finally-letting-private-server-players-earn-full-rewards-starting-in-december<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>But it's lowering the level cap.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/sea-of-thieves-gold-crop.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Rare/Xbox</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
We're coming up to a year since <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/sea-of-thieves">Sea of Thieves</a> <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/sea-of-thieves-long-awaited-private-servers-arrive-next-week">launched its long-requested private servers</a>, and with that first anniversary looming, Rare has announced it's making some welcome changes, finally allowing players to earn full rewards while sailing in Safer Seas mode.
</p>
<p>
Safer Seas, if you're unfamiliar, provides a means for a single crew of up to four pirates to sail Sea of Thieves' entire open-world map without the ever-looming PvP threat of High Seas mode. While the absence of other crews means a good chunk of PvP focussed content is unavailable in Safer Seas, players <em>can</em> still tackle emergent PvE events, complete Trading Company voyages, and embark on narrative-driven Tall Tales.
</p>
<p>
Crucially too, it's possible to earn gold to spend on cosmetics and to increase Trading Company standing by earning reputation in Safer Seas - but both of these have been capped at 30 percent of the amount you'd ordinarily earn in High Seas until now, making things a bit of a drag for pirates who just want to, say, have a chill time raising funds for a shiny new figurehead away from the hubbub of Sea of Thieves' main mode.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="The Mimic Dart, Legends Week and the Voyage of Luck: Sea of Thieves News November 7th 2024" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/TvbLyq-ZO0w?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>The Mimic Dart, Legends Week and the Voyage of Luck: Sea of Thieves News November 7th 2024</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/TvbLyq-ZO0w?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/TvbLyq-ZO0w?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Sea of Thieves News, November 7th 2024.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TvbLyq-ZO0w" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
In a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-pzdHh1ALXc">new developer update</a>, however, Rare has acknowledged Safer Seas' "punishingly restrictive rewards", admitting they're working against its intention of providing an "onboarding ramp for new players". As such, it'll be increasing the current gold and reputation payout rate all the way up to 100 percent, matching the rewards earned in High Seas. There's a trade-off, though; the studio is dropping Safer Seas' level cap down from 40 to 25.
</p><p>
Essentially, that means players wanting to work their way up to Pirate Legend status and gain access to the various Trading Company cosmetics unlocked along the way will now need to hop over to High Seas much sooner. On the flip side, players looking for a safe environment to learn the ropes, or for a more relaxed space to amass gold or Seasonal Renown (which continues to be awarded at a 100 percent rate in Safer Seas) can now do so completely unhindered. It is, admittedly, a shame the Hunter's Call faction has been slapped with a lower level cap given how perfect Safer Seas mode is for a evening of quietly contemplative fishing (and given the Trading Company's already glacial reward payouts), but perhaps that'll be something - alongside the use of Captaincy ships, pretty please Rare - revisted as a Christmas treat <em>next</em> year.
</p>
<p>
In other Sea of Thieves news, players will soon get their hands on a number of features originally promised for the start of the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/sea-of-thieves-stealthy-season-14-grapple-guns-toward-an-october-release-date">current stealth-focused Season 14</a>, but which were <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/sea-of-thieves-temporarily-yanks-nearly-all-its-big-new-stealth-features-following-significant-issues">pulled en masse</a> as part of "drastic steps" following a disastrous launch in October. Once Rare releases its next patch this Thursday, 14th November, players can finally lay traps, hang from ledges while sneaking, and wear disguises. Rare is also promising a number of "high impact" fixes, putting a stop to players using crouch to gain a firing speed advantage, and preventing pirates grabbing supplies from barrels after moving out of range. Additionally, measures have been introduced to stop players swiping treasure from the Fort of the Damned's vault by swimming underneath.
</p>
<p>
The studio notes this week's update has gained "additional [testing] time internally and with insiders", and that the team has also been trialling a new process enabling it to address critical experience issues as it locks down each build. "There's been a concerted effort across the team to improve on quality control", says Rare, and plans are also now in motion for "broader improvements for quality at the studio", with more details to come.
</p>
<p>
And finally, players sailing the Sea of Thieves within the first week of tomorrow's update will earn bonus gold and doubloons, alongside a Lucrative Voyage of Luck or Legendary Voyage of Luck for Pirate Legends. These bonuses will now be offered with every monthly update.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Best Christmas Gifts for Gamers]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/best-christmas-gifts-for-gamers/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/best-christmas-gifts-for-gamers.1035300/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/best-christmas-gifts-for-gamers/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>That time of year is just around the corner and many people are looking for the best gift to get their gamer kids or spouse. So, what are the best Christmas gifts for gamers?</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-best-christmas-gifts-for-those-who-love-gaming">Best Christmas Gifts for Those Who Love Gaming</h2>



<p>When making a list of items to get people who love to game, many different thoughts come to mind. However, some may end up being a bit pricier, like a new PC or console. Assuming that every one this list is for already has something to play video games on, we are going to make this list dedicated more towards accessories and more.</p>



<p>Here are the best Christmas gifts for gamers. </p>



<hr>



<h3 id="h-gift-cards">Gift Cards</h3>



<p>Starting the list of easy with gift cards. Everyone loves a good gift card for Christmas, as it lets gamers purchase exactly what they want.</p>



<p>Below is a list of different gift card options you could get for your favorite gamer:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Xbox Gift Card</strong></li>



<li><strong>PlayStation Gift Card</strong></li>



<li><strong>Gamestop Gift Card</strong></li>



<li><strong>Walmart Gift Card</strong></li>



<li><strong>Target Gift Card</strong></li>



<li><strong>Best Buy Gift Card</strong></li>



<li><strong>Nintendo eShop Gift Card</strong></li>
</ul>



<p>Looking for something a bit more detailed than just a plain ole’ gift card? Luckily, there are quite a few other options when purchasing gifts for a gamer.</p>



<hr>



<h3 id="h-gaming-headset">Gaming Headset</h3>



<figure></figure>







<p>Is your favorite gamer in need of a new headset? Luckily, there are quite a few on the market that work for both PC and console. Brands such as HyperX, Logitech and Turtle Beach all make extremely affordable headsets that come equipped with decent mics.</p>



<p>Not only do headsets look great as an accessory, but they can really make or break a gamer’s gaming experience. Having a good headset is essential for all gamers.</p>



<p>Headsets can be found online at Amazon, Best Buy and any other major retailer.</p>



<hr>



<h3 id="h-controller-charger">Controller Charger</h3>



<figure></figure>







<p>Is your favorite gaming enthusiast a controller gamer? Well, no one enjoys having to plug in their wireless controller or change the batteries frequently. That is why having a controller charger is a must for a gamer.</p>



<p>In fact, many of these chargers can work as a dock station, charging multiple controllers at once. This allows people to never worry about their battery running out.</p>



<p>Controller chargers can be found on almost any major retailer’s website or in-store.</p>







<hr>



<h3 id="h-gaming-chair">Gaming Chair</h3>



<figure></figure>







<p>Having a good gaming chair is essential. The truth is, many of those who game up close to a monitor have already begun to develop terrible posture and back issues. Having the right chair to prevent this could really help with any future health issues.</p>



<p>However, good gaming chairs can be quite expensive. While Amazon and Walmart do have some decent ones for cheap, if you are willing to spend a lot of money, then <a href="https://secretlab.co/collections/promotions?utm_source=google&amp;utm_medium=cpc&amp;utm_content=secretlab&amp;utm_campaign=us-s-brand-exact&amp;stop_redirect=true&amp;gad_source=1&amp;gclid=CjwKCAiAudG5BhAREiwAWMlSjISSPn-XXGekcKL3Za2Bhr-sR7kap-eGnI8V7m8FztnoYEfcHDvISxoCAgUQAvD_BwE">Secretlabs</a> would be a great purchase.</p>



<hr>



<h3 id="h-mouse-pad">Mouse Pad</h3>



<figure></figure>







<p>We have already discussed controller accessories, but what about mouse and keyboard accessories? While having a full-desk mouse pad is great for gaming on a PC, it is also fun to have one with a unique design.</p>



<p>Whether it’s anime or other fantasy worlds, shops like <a href="https://higround.co/?tw_source=google&amp;tw_adid=645614658202&amp;tw_campaign=20950847950&amp;gad_source=1&amp;gclid=CjwKCAiAudG5BhAREiwAWMlSjPiGrbC5QxGYaDGGAZm4CDm-ZRYFwE-xc3PgODY-c5phDlKumWeBlxoCaWEQAvD_BwE">Higround</a> have some of the most unique and impressive mouse pad designs on the market. </p>



<p>Help deck your gamer’s setup by getting him one of these top-of-the-market mouse pads. </p>



<hr>



<h3 id="h-lighting">Lighting</h3>



<figure></figure>







<p>RGB lighting is huge within the gaming world. Whether you are getting strips to put around your favorite gamer’s desk or buying Philips Hue lights to put behind their TV, lighting helps really immerse a gamer into the gaming experience.</p>



<p>Every major retailer sells lighting and you can even find special smart lights at stores like Home Depot and Lowes.</p>



<p>What will you be buying your favorite gamer for Christmas this year?</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming guides, check out the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/best-black-friday-deals-for-xbox-series-xs/">best Black Friday deals for Xbox X|S.</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Blizzard, What Are You Doing? Signed: Nathan Grayson, Eight Years Old]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/blizzard-warcraft-remaster-graphics-bad</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/blizzard-what-are-you-doing-signed-nathan-grayson-eight-years-old.1035297/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://aftermath.site/blizzard-warcraft-remaster-graphics-bad<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Today Blizzard <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ryZ2jiW95qo" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">announced remasters</a> of its classic fantasy real-time strategy hits <em>Warcraft I </em>and <em>II</em>, the games that put it on the map in the distant, functional past of the ‘90s. I should be celebrating; the second <em>Warcraft </em>was unequivocally my favorite game as a young child. I spent God only knows how many hundreds of hours playing it, and even He eventually got bored of watching me make my own horrible little maps and walked away. These remasters, though? They ain’t it.</p><p>I’ll preface this by saying that I’m very glad these classics remain playable. I’m sure Blizzard’s making a pretty penny off doing so, but at least it’s keeping its history alive. That said, I will be playing these re-releases with the new graphics turned off, because just look at them:</p><div><figure><p><iframe title="Warcraft Remastered Battle Chest Launch Trailer" width="710" height="399" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ryZ2jiW95qo?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></figure></div><p>The art looks basic and generic where the original pixels inspired imagination, letting your mind fill in the gaps of these units’ physical features. Some, like Ogres and Ogre Magi, appeared almost photorealistic to young me, who sought to recreate them (over and over and over) in drawings and other, larger-scale art projects. In trying to more fully inhabit this universe whose collection of <a href="https://aftermath.site/strategy-game-turn-based-tactics-movement" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Little Guys</a> inspired me to dare to dream, I constructed life-sized (relative to an eight-year-old) paper dolls of nearly every unit in the game. It was my Everest, entirely because – again – the original game left room for interpretation.</p><p>Now admittedly, I’m no longer a small child fueled entirely by starry-eyed wonder, and that’s definitely part of the problem. But <em>Warcraft</em>’s original look was a product of its limitations, and trying to pave over that with plastic-y sheen is a mistake. I don’t know who the new graphics are for – I doubt these old games are going to lure in many new players, especially with art that looks like it belongs in a vastly less-intricate game than <em>Warcraft </em>– but it’s certainly not me.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Watch Hugh Grant Do The Worst Jar Jar Binks Impression I've Ever Heard]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/star-wars-jar-jar-hugh-grant-heretic-impression-clip-1851698047</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/watch-hugh-grant-do-the-worst-jar-jar-binks-impression-ive-ever-heard.1035291/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/star-wars-jar-jar-hugh-grant-heretic-impression-clip-1851698047<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Hugh Grant stars as a strange and dangerous villain in <em>Heretic</em>, A24's new horror flick that debuted with <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.boxofficemojo.com/weekend/2024W45/?ref_=bo_wey_table_3&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.boxofficemojo.com/weekend/2024W45/?ref_=bo_wey_table_3" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">$11 million last weekend</a></span>. And at one point in the film he does an impression of <em>Star Wars</em> character Jar-Jar Binks and folks, it’s the worst impression of the hated alien I’ve ever heard. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="193897" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="10 Creatures We Wanna Ride In Star Wars Jedi: Survivor" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="418" data-playlist="193897,197298,197284" data-current="193897"><div><p>10 Creatures We Wanna Ride In Star Wars Jedi: Survivor</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/193897/193897_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/193897/193897_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/193897/193897_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/193897/193897_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/19360.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p><em>Heretic</em>, a movie about two young women who quickly regret entering the home of Grant’s character, landed in theaters on November 8 and has already become one of <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://collider.com/heretic-domestic-box-office-11-million-a24/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://collider.com/heretic-domestic-box-office-11-million-a24/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">A24's highest-grossing pictures</a></span>, beating out movies like <em>I Saw the TV Glow </em>and <em>Love Lies Bleeding </em>in just a few days. Impressive stuff! What’s not so impressive is a moment in the movie in which Hugh Grant’s character does a brief impersonation of Jar-Jar Binks. </p><p>On November 12, <em>IGN </em>posted a clip from Heretic showing Grant’s character talking about how, in the future, people will worship Jar-Jar Binks as a religious figure. The clip was later “borrowed” and <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/discussingfilm/status/1856757930714173477?s=46&amp;t=ELmQU9gVKk7kgACkfTFs1Q&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/discussingfilm/status/1856757930714173477?s=46&amp;t=ELmQU9gVKk7kgACkfTFs1Q" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">reposted by DiscussingFilm</a></span> on Twitter, where it blew up.</p><p>Jar-Jar first appeared in <em>Star Wars Episode I: The Phantom Menace</em> in 1999 and people hated him. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/mandalorian-star-wars-jedi-beq-jarjar-actor-ahmed-best-1850257681?_gl=1*1n90v1m*_ga*MzQzNjkwNDM2LjE2NDY2NjQ1NzQ.*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczMTUzMTQ0Ni4xMTIuMC4xNzMxNTMxNDQ4LjU4LjAuMA..&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/mandalorian-star-wars-jedi-beq-jarjar-actor-ahmed-best-1850257681?_gl=1*1n90v1m*_ga*MzQzNjkwNDM2LjE2NDY2NjQ1NzQ.*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczMTUzMTQ0Ni4xMTIuMC4xNzMxNTMxNDQ4LjU4LjAuMA..">The negative reaction and abuse pushed Jar-Jar’s actor, Ahmed Best, to nearly kill himself</a></span>. But since then, he’s bounced back, has a great family, and has returned to <em>Star Wars</em> as <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/themandalorian/status/1638937426357010432&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/themandalorian/status/1638937426357010432" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">a badass Jedi who saved Grogu</a></span>. </p><p>Anyway, I have to imagine that Hugh Grant is aware of who Jar-Jar Binks is and at least looked up one video of the character talking. So I’m going to assume that the horrible impersonation is on purpose and is an example of how the character doesn’t know much about who Jar-Jar is, which might be a clue toward how much you can trust him. </p><p>Or maybe Grant did it, everyone on set was silent, he took that as a sign of success and moved on, and nobody had the heart to say it was bad. Either way, I’d pay money to see Grant impersonate more <em>Star Wars </em>characters. Give me your best Jabba or Yoda, my dude. </p><p><em>Heretic</em> is out now in theaters. Don’t boo the screen when his Jar-Jar impersonation happens. Okay? </p><p> .<br></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 and Warzone Season 1 Patch Notes Details Complete Update List and How It's Handling Bots]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-and-warzone-season-1-patch-notes-details-complete-update-list-and-how-its-handling-bots</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-and-warzone-season-1-patch-notes-details-complete-update-list-and-how-its-handling-bots.1035288/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-and-warzone-season-1-patch-notes-details-complete-update-list-and-how-its-handling-bots<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Treyarch has published patch notes for Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 and Warzone Season 1 ahead of its launch on PC and consoles tomorrow.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Following <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-november-8-patch-further-nerfs-recon-as-10v10-goes-live">a string of smaller updates</a> delivered throughout the last few weeks, today’s <a href="https://www.callofduty.com/patchnotes/2024/11/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-season-01-patch-notes" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>patch notes</u></a> tease an update that is (unsurprisingly) the biggest yet. It’s got everything from weapon balance adjustments to details on Warzone, and while most of the news focuses on changes to Multiplayer and Zombies, the team made sure to iron out some Campaign wrinkles, too. There’s a laundry list of fixes for players of every shape and size, including those worried about players who want to cheat their way to the top.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/11/13/bo6-s1-sevhero-01-1731530923478.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 and Warzone get Season 1 patch notes targeting cheaters and weapon balancing.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">One specific area Treyarch took aim at with its Black Ops 6 Season 1 update revolves around what it calls “disruptive behavior.” The team has adjusted ping thresholds to tackle VPN abuse and enhanced AFK detection in hopes of extinguishing boosting in lobbies. These are changes that should help ward off the use of popular exploits like bot lobbies, with additional tweaks to the anti-cheat measures sure to come as more updates arrive. Players will also be required to win 50 match-made Multiplayer matches before they’re allowed to dive into Ranked mode.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It's all about making every aspect of the Black Ops 6 experience authentic, so it’s not shocking to see a bevy of weapon tweaks coming to Multiplayer in Season 1, too. While assault rifles like the XM4, GPR 91, and AMES 85 received general damage buffs across the board, their headshot multipliers have also been reduced. Shotguns users were handed some changes, too, including increased damage multipliers and even more general damage improvements for the Marine SP and ASG-89.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Omnimovement comes to Warzone</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Black Ops 6 Season 1 alone comes with a long list of additions that will surely only change more as more content rolls out. Warzone, meanwhile, is an entirely different beast, but the team as Raven Software made sure to go over all of the details in <a href="https://www.callofduty.com/patchnotes/2024/11/call-of-duty-bo6-warzone-season-01-patch-notes" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">its own post on the Call of Duty website</a>. While things like Area 99 and omnimovement are sure to give fans of the long-running battle royale mode an entirely new hill to climb, there are plenty of other smaller changes here to help iron out the mode, too.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Those same Ricochet anti-cheat measures from Multiplayer will be carried into Warzone, for example. Warzone UI is also getting a massive facelift, which includes a legacy tab for previously unlocked Modern Warfare 2 and 3 customization options, an option to change your mini-map type, and a legacy content filtering system. Treyarch says it also brough back some original Warzone elements, such as equipment icons and armor plate shape.</p><div id="black-ops-6-tier-list-best-guns-ranked" data-cy="tierlist-view-trigger"><p><h3 data-cy="title3">Black Ops 6 Tier List: Best Guns Ranked</h3><h3>Black Ops 6 Tier List: Best Guns Ranked</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">More Multiplayer maps, modes, skins, and much, much more are coming with Season 1 when it arrives tomorrow. For a breakdown of the highlights, you can check out <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-and-warzone-season-1-roadmap-revealed-details-on-maps-weapons-and-more">Treyarch’s roadmap here</a>. You can also learn about some of the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/new-call-of-duty-black-ops-6-skins-revealed-including-a-shark-a-raccoon-and-a-parasite-warrior">wacky Operator bundles</a>, which include shark and racoon cosmetics, that will be available to purchase in the coming weeks.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Finally, you can see the full Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 and Warzone Season 1 patch notes below.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 Season 1 Patch Notes</h2><h3 data-cy="title3"><strong>WELCOME TO SEASON 01</strong></h3><p data-cy="paragraph">Season 01 of Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 is imminent! Tomorrow you’ll get your chance to wreak some havoc when Sevati “Sev” Dumas brings home a deal to take down the remaining Pantheon rats.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Until then, check out our Patch Notes for details on New Season 01 Content and the latest balance adjustments, gameplay improvements, bug fixes, and more.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Looking for Warzone Patch Notes? The team at Raven Software has you covered right here.</p><strong>New Multiplayer Maps </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Season Launch </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Hideout (6v6) <ul data-cy="list"><li>Sharpen your combat skills in this mid-sized Multiplayer map featuring an extensive training site including target practice, an obstacle course, and a lifelike recreation of a vault and security room to help plan for the next mission to hit the Luttazzi crime family. </li></ul></li><li>Heirloom (6v6, 2v2) <ul data-cy="list"><li>Crash a private showing of Luttazzi family art to create a diversion for the other Rogue Black Ops team as they execute the real job. </li></ul></li><li>Extraction (6v6) <ul data-cy="list"><li>All hell has broken loose in the aftermath of a Crimson One ambush when the attack on the Luttazzis goes sideways.</li></ul></li></ul></li></ul><strong>New Multiplayer Modes </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Season Launch </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Ransack <ul data-cy="list"><li>Ransack sees you looting gold bars from crates dotted around the area of operations on 6v6 maps. Once gathered, secure your loot by bringing it back to your team’s stash. </li></ul></li></ul></li><li><strong>In-Season </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Prop Hunt <ul data-cy="list"><li>Prepare for an infamous game of hide-and-seek, as the fan-favorite Black Ops party mode is back! Drop into a Multiplayer map as a Prop or Hunter.</li></ul></li></ul></li></ul><strong>New Weapons (Multiplayer &amp; Zombies) </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Season Launch </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Krig C – Assault Rifle (Battle Pass) <ul data-cy="list"><li>For a hard-hitting, versatile Assault Rifle that performs well across multiple ranges, look no further than the Krig C. </li></ul></li><li>Saug – SMG - Battle Pass (Battle Pass)<ul data-cy="list"><li>Pepper your enemies with a hailstorm of lead using this rapid-fire SMG that’s perfect for breaching and clearing small spaces. </li></ul></li></ul></li><li><strong>In-Season </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Sirin 9mm – Special Weapon (Special Event Reward)<ul data-cy="list"><li>Take your game to the next level with this foldable Special category weapon offering full-auto fire with a slow and steady fire rate to help you stay on target up to the mid-range.</li></ul></li><li>Power Drill – Melee Weapon (Event Reward)<ul data-cy="list"><li>There’s no better tool for the job than the Power Drill, offering a rapid attack speed for quick follow-up hits to get the job done. </li></ul></li></ul></li></ul><strong>New Attachments (Multiplayer &amp; Zombies) </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Season Launch </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>12 Gauge Dragon’s Breath (Battle Pass)<ul data-cy="list"><li>Add some heat to your Shotgun blasts with incendiary rounds comprised of magnesium sparks that stick to and burn enemies over time. </li></ul></li></ul></li><li><strong>In-Season </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Buffer Weight Stock (Event Reward)<ul data-cy="list"><li>The heavier Buffer Weight Stock provides significantly smoother action through the additional resistance met by the bolt carrier group for the XM4 Assault Rifle, XMG LMG, and DM-10 Marksman Rifle. </li></ul></li><li>XM4 Burst Fire Conversion (Event Reward)<ul data-cy="list"><li>Convert the XM4 Assault Rifle’s primary firing mode into a three-round burst to help conserve ammo and stay on target. </li></ul></li><li>Kompakt 92 Burst Fire Conversion (Event Reward)<ul data-cy="list"><li>Convert the Kompakt 92 SMG’s primary firing mode into an exceptionally rapid three-round burst. </li></ul></li></ul></li></ul><strong>New Multiplayer Perks </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Season Launch Window </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Shadow – Strategist <ul data-cy="list"><li>Undetectable to enemy traps and mines. </li></ul></li></ul></li></ul><strong>New Scorestreak (Multiplayer &amp; Zombies) </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Hand Cannon </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Available as an Event Reward in the Season Launch Window, this mid-level Scorestreak allows players to equip a massively powerful handgun for a finite amount of time. </li><li>The Hand Cannon can also be accessed in Zombies at the Crafting Table under Support. </li></ul></li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>New Operators (Multiplayer &amp; Zombies) </strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Goliath (BlackCell, Rogue Black Ops, Launch) </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Solidify your fiery combat mastery as the molten man of fire himself, Goliath! All biographical information for this Operator has been redacted. </li></ul></li><li><strong>Sevati “Sev” Dumas (Battle Pass, Rogue Black Ops, Launch) </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>A main player in the Rogue Team after the conclusion of the Campaign, Sev is ready to make a deal with the untrustworthy French Syndicate and is gearing up to take down the rival Luttazzi family to prove it. </li></ul></li><li><strong>The Replacer (Bundle, Rogue Black Ops, In-Season) </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>There’s no substitute for greatness. The Replacer has concluded his whirlwind Black Ops 6 takeover tour and has freed up some time to appear in-game, available as a Store Bundle shortly after Launch. </li></ul></li><li><strong>Competitor CDL Home and Away Operators </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Two new Operators arrive just in time for the 2025 Call of Duty League® season, and both are available (along with a host of other content including a Weapon Camo) in the CDL Store Bundle. The first available Bundle includes the “2025 CDL Home” “Competitor” Operator (Rogue Black Ops), and the “2025 CDL Away” “Competitor” Operator (Crimson One). </li><li>Access either of the Competitor Operators to find the location where a variety of incoming Operator Skins will become available, once earned. Expect the following as Season 01 progresses:  <ul data-cy="list"><li>CDL Team Packs for the Atlanta Faze, Boston Breach, Carolina Royal Ravens, Los Angeles Guerrillas, Los Angeles Thieves, Miami Heretics, Minnesota Rokkr, Cloud9 New York, Vancouver Surge, Optic Texas, Toronto Ultra, and Vegas Falcons. </li><li>Skins unlocked during Multiplayer Ranked Play for Challenge Wins, Gold, Platinum, Diamond, Crimson, Iridescent, Top 250, and Seasonal World Champion. </li><li>Skins unlocked during Warzone Ranked Play for Challenge Wins, Gold, Platinum, Diamond, Crimson, Iridescent, Top 250, and Seasonal World Champion. </li></ul></li></ul></li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>New Events </strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>The Hit List (In-Season) </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Who’s next? Keep up your luxurious – but slightly corrupt – lifestyle during the Hit List Event. You’re offered up a take-no-prisoners mission: kill or be killed. The Hit List Limited Event gives players a board of contracts with one goal – take them all out. Cross off the entire list and earn some exclusive loot for hire.</li></ul></li></ul><strong>New Zombies Directed Mode </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Liberty Falls and Terminus </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>For those players looking to witness the Zombies story with a guided experience to complete the objectives of the Main Quests in Liberty Falls and Terminus, Directed Mode is available at launch.<ul data-cy="list"><li>Directed Mode offers direct assistance in completing the Main Quest with objectives listed on-screen.</li><li>All Side Quests, S.A.M. Trials, and the Rampage Inducer are disabled in this mode.</li><li>Rounds are capped based on certain steps in the Main Quest progression, with a maximum of Round 15.</li><li>The chance to earn unique Calling Card rewards for completing the Main Quests for Liberty Falls or Terminus before Directed Mode goes live will expire when Season 01 launches.</li></ul></li></ul></li></ul><h3 data-cy="title3"><strong>GLOBAL </strong></h3><strong>Ricochet Anti-Cheat </strong><p data-cy="paragraph">Here is a message from our partners at Team Ricochet:Treyarch has delivered several updates to combat disruptive behavior, including: </p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Enhanced AFK detections to battle against account boosting </li><li>Adjusting ping thresholds to require players play matches in their region to cut down on VPN abuse </li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph">To unlock Ranked Play in Black Ops 6, players will need to win 50 match-made multiplayer matches: </p><ul data-cy="list"><li>This ensures that players are experienced with multiplayer before they enter the mode and gives #TeamRICOCHET a historical match history to examine before an account enters Ranked Play </li><li>#TeamRICOCHET also utilizes its Replay Investigation Tool to monitor replays of top players as part of the investigation process </li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph">Detection systems initially deployed at launch from #TeamRICOCHET to collect data to test for effectiveness will be activated to help flag accounts for action beginning with Season 01. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The security system updates listed above will also be active for Ranked Play in Call of Duty®: Warzone™, which launches at mid-season. </p><strong>Armory</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>The Armory will go live in Black Ops 6 in S01 Reloaded when post-Event content is available to unlock.</li><li>In Warzone, the Armory will be available to unlock at Player Level 24 at Season 01 launch. For more details, check out the Warzone Season 01 patch notes here.</li></ul><h3 data-cy="title3"><strong>CAMPAIGN</strong></h3><strong>Performance</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Made improvements to mission intro sequence animations. </li></ul><strong>Bug Fixes</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Updated text for a number of languages localizations. </li><li>Addressed various issues that resulted in infrequent game crashes. </li><li>Addressed a memory error that was forcing players to restart their game. </li><li>Addressed visual fidelity issues with water effects. </li><li>Addressed an issue causing the High Contrast setting to be on by default. </li><li>Addressed an issue where players would be mistakenly shown an out-of-bounds warning while navigating a mission. </li><li>Addressed an issue that would prevent players from completing a mission due to the untimely passing of Gladney. </li></ul><h3 data-cy="title3"><strong>MULTIPLAYER</strong></h3><strong>Maps  </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Lowtown <ul data-cy="list"><li>Addressed an issue where the water would flicker for some players. </li></ul></li><li>Protocol <ul data-cy="list"><li>Adressed an issue where the water would flicker for some players.</li><li>Adjusted the A S&amp;D bombsite to prevent line of sight from artillery above.</li></ul></li><li>Red Card <ul data-cy="list"><li>Addressed an issue where players could get outside of the intended playspace.</li></ul></li><li>Vault<ul data-cy="list"><li>Adjusted the A S&amp;D bombsite to reduce line of sights from start spawn area.</li></ul></li></ul><strong>Spawns</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Spawn logic updates across several maps to reduce the chances of spawning near enemies.</li><li>Adjusted start spawns in Subsonic to prevent damaging opposing enemy team at match start. </li></ul><strong>Modes</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Addressed an issue across several maps where Hardpoint zones could be captured outside of the intended boundaries. </li><li>Addressed an issue where incorrect icons could display on the Next Hardpoint lock icon. </li><li>Addressed an issue where the bomb in Search &amp; Destroy could not be retrieved if dropped on a destroyed vehicle. </li><li>Addressed an issue where the “Time is almost up” line would play too frequently in Gunfight. </li></ul><strong>Game Chat </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Addressed an issue where some players were unable to hear each other during Intermission (between rounds) and in Post-Game voice chat.  </li></ul><strong>Weapons</strong><p data-cy="paragraph">Throughout the pre-season we have seen a steady and healthy variety of weapon usage. Most weapons sit quite closely in both performance and pick rate, with no weapons dominating in both areas. As such our first round of Season 01 tuning changes will not be introducing any major shifts to the current state of weapon balance, and instead focus on elevating some of the weapons at the bottom of the pack. We are also addressing feedback regarding Assault Rifle damage in Hardcore and completing our adjustments to the shotgun slug attachment.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Reminder: We're using a new Weapon Damage Adjustments tables to identify post-patch damage changes when possible. Need an explainer? <a href="https://www.callofduty.com/patchnotes/2024/11/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-season-01-patch-notes#explainweapondamagetables" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Click here!</u></a></p><strong>All Weapons</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Adjusted weapon motion while moving and changing stances to improve aiming feel and centering (especially with optics). </li><li>Hold Breath focus state will now be maintained while firing if applicable.</li><li>Improved Weapon depth of field settings when performing a Weapon Inspect.</li></ul><strong>Assault Rifles </strong><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>We are increasing the damage values for some of our Assault Rifles to ensure that they kill in just one bullet in Hardcore modes. The headshot multiplier changes have either kept the bullets to kill with headshots the same or even improved them at some Min Damage Ranges. </em></p><strong>Shotguns</strong><p data-cy="paragraph">Strelok Laser Attachment Adjustments</p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Increased the time it takes to reach ADS spread from 20% of Aim Down Sight Speed to 70% of Aim Down Sight Speed </li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph">Slug Attachment Adjustments</p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Slugs allow players to run shotguns as mid-range precision weapons. As a tradeoff, they have limited short range effectiveness if you are not carefully hitting headshots</li></ul><strong>Marksman Rifles</strong><p data-cy="paragraph"> <em>We are adjusting handling stats on the burst rifles so that they fit more squarely into their intended roles. The Swat 5.56 has a slower fire rate within each burst and more recoil, making it better suited for mid-range engagements. Meanwhile the AEK-973 has better stability and precision, but a longer burst delay makes it a riskier pick when playing aggressively. We are also significantly reducing the power of the AEK-973 Rapid Fire, which was too strong not to take. </em></p><strong>Sniper Rifles</strong><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>We have been monitoring feedback on Sniper Rifles and are making some changes to promote more build diversity and improve the sniping experience before gaining access to a complete attachment set. We are lowering the baseline flinch on all Snipers and reducing the Flinch Resistance given by stock attachments. The resulting received flinch values are much lower up front and just a bit lower overall after equipping the stocks. We are also increasing Aim Walking Movement Speed bonuses on stock attachments to make those choices more valuable.</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Lastly, we are improving the ADS Idle Sway delay by default on all Snipers, meaning that on average there will be less deviation from your point of aim when entering ADS. Our goal is to support the various sniping playstyles you all enjoy through several viable weapon builds. We will continue to monitor weapon and attachment data as well as your feedback to ensure that all sniping playstyles are fun and rewarding in Black Ops 6. </em></p><p data-cy="paragraph">Sniper Rifle Class Adjustments</p><ul data-cy="list"><li>All snipers now have 1 second of 50% Idle Sway scaling at the beginning of Aim Down Sight </li><li>All snipers have had base Flinch Resistance improved by 17% </li></ul><strong>Gunsmith  </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Various updates to weapon descriptions. </li><li>Addressed an issue where stickers would appear in the Decal slot. </li></ul><strong>Perks</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li> Slight reduction to Ninja footstep volume.<ul data-cy="list"><li>Additionally we’ve made a slight reduction to default footstep volume.</li></ul></li><li>Addressed an issue that prevented Gearhead from being able to booby-trap enemy Care Packages.</li><li>Addressed an issue that prevented Equipment from replenishing with the Scavenger Perk.</li></ul><strong>Scorestreaks </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Archangel </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Addressed an issue where the rocket would sometimes explode immediately when firing near a wall. </li></ul></li></ul><strong>Challenges </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Addressed an issue where some Daily Challenges were not tracking properly. </li></ul><strong>Movement Updates </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Addressed a bug causing player to be slowed when shot while mantling. </li></ul><strong>Theater </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Added Nuketown and Private Match recordings. </li><li>Addressed various stability issues when viewing matches. </li></ul><strong>UI </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Closed an exploit that allowed players to equip Operators they had not unlocked. </li><li>Addressed an issue where the AAR could close when entering the Scoreboard tab. </li><li>Addressed an issue earned and unearned medals would not display correctly in Collections. </li><li>Addressed an issue where the option to select an attachment skin would not be visible for some players. </li></ul><strong>Graphics </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Addressed an issue where some weapon effects would persist on the character after changing weapons. </li></ul><strong>Stability </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Added numerous stability fixes. </li></ul><h3 data-cy="title3"><strong>ZOMBIES</strong></h3><strong>Maps </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Terminus </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Addressed an issue where defuse progress was sometimes not saved if the player stopped defusing during the Apocalypse Protocol Main Quest step. </li><li>Addressed an issue where entering a Kazimir after completing the Main Quest would teleport the player to the boss arena and down them. </li><li>Addressed an issue where loading into a saved game after unlocking the Pack-A-Punch machine could cause some doors to have inconsistent collision. </li><li>Addressed an issue during the Main Quest where connecting both Node Connectors at the same time would cause overlapping voice lines. </li><li>Changed the location of the Ammo Cache on the Seaside Path. </li></ul></li><li><strong>Liberty Falls </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Updated the first Mangler whose arm is blown off to always drop a Mangler Cannon instead of only the first Mangler that spawns. </li><li>Resolved an issue where Blanchard would not be present during some dialogue. </li></ul></li></ul><strong>Weapon Adjustments </strong><p data-cy="paragraph">The recent changes to Assault Rifles in Zombies were an unintended carryover from a global weapon tuning pass. We do not intend to inherit all MP weapon tuning without looking at how it affects Zombies tuning as well. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">We have corrected this in this update, while also making a pass on increasing the damage performance of ARs in Zombies. All ARs have had their Pack-a-Punched base damage and overall critical damage increased. While you may see the word "decreased" in a few places, the performance for these weapons is still increased overall! </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Additionally, the HE-1 Launcher has gotten a buff to become more useful at stopping hordes of zombies. When Pack-a-Punched, it will now have more stock ammo and a larger explosion with more overall damage. </p><strong>Bug Fixes </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Addressed an issue where camos were not being applied to Zombie Builds. </li><li>Closed an exploit that allowed players to have 3 weapons. </li><li>Addressed an issue where Wallbuy rarity would reset when loading into a save. </li><li>Addressed an issue where yellow damage numbers would appear when hitting a critical spot with the Ray Gun. </li></ul><strong>Perks</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Quick Revive</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Dying Wish Augment <ul data-cy="list"><li>Addressed an issue where Dying Wish could activate when diving from large heights while protected from fall damage. </li></ul></li></ul></li><li><strong>Elemental Pop </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Addressed an issue where Elemental Pop would prevent normal Ammo Mod activations. </li></ul></li><li><strong>Jugger-nog </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Turtle Shell Augment <ul data-cy="list"><li>Turtle Shell will now apply damage mitigation when being grabbed by an Amalgam.  </li></ul></li></ul></li><li><strong>PHD Flopper </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Addressed an issue where diving onto an elevated or inclined surface, such as stairs or up a hill, would not activate the perk. </li></ul></li></ul><strong>GobbleGums </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Addressed an issue that prevented players revived by Near Death Experience from keeping all their Perks. </li></ul><strong>Field Upgrades </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Adjusted the description for the Energy Mine to no longer say it deals Electrical damage to accurately reflect the damage type. </li><li>Increased Dark Flare damage from 25% to 40% of the base zombie max health per tick. </li><li>Addressed an issue where an extra charge on Field Upgrades would be lost when loading a save. </li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Support</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Addressed an issue that could cause the Mutant Injection to end early when near water. </li><li>Addressed an issue that allowed the player to pick up a Sentry Turret while using Mutant Injection. </li><li>Reduced self-damage from the LDBR. </li></ul><strong>Save &amp; Load </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Closed an exploit that allowed keeping a save file after it had already been loaded. </li></ul><strong>Enemies </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Addressed an issue where zombies charmed by Brain Rot could prevent the player from completing an exfil. </li><li>Addressed an issue where loading a save would disable the rampage inducer if it was active. </li><li>Addressed an issue where zombies would throw guts at the end camera if the player leaves the match to end the game. </li><li>Terminus <ul data-cy="list"><li>Addressed an issue where rarely the round would not end after killing all zombies. </li><li>Addressed an issue where the Amalgam could grab the player while slowed. </li><li>Addressed an issue where the Amalgam could pull players into walls causing them to get stuck. </li><li>Addressed an issue where diving while being hit by knockback from Patient 13 could push the player further than intended. </li></ul></li><li>Liberty Falls <ul data-cy="list"><li>Addressed an issue that prevented the Abomination from spawning inside Fuller’s Liberty Lanes. </li><li>Addressed an issue where the Abomination could fire off a beam attack before leaving a spawn closet. </li></ul></li></ul><strong>Activities </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Addressed an issue that would prevent one elite from spawning consistently during exfil from rounds 16 onward </li><li>Updated S.A.M. Trials that required the player to not take damage to display a progress bar instead of a timer. </li><li>Terminus.<ul data-cy="list"><li>Addressed an issue where players would be able to use Equipment, Scorestreaks, and fire weapons during the Boat Race awards sequence. </li></ul></li></ul><strong>XP Earn Rates </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Addressed an issue where XP was being awarded to all weapons being used in an assist instead of just the last one. <ul data-cy="list"><li>If two weapons were used in an assist only the last one used by the players getting the assist will be awarded XP. </li></ul></li></ul><strong>Challenges </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Addressed an issue where Wall Buys would not progress the Prestige 8 Challenge Value Town. </li><li>Addressed an issue where Legendary GobbleGums would progress the Ultra Prestige 8 Challenge Full Power instead of Ultra GobbleGums. </li><li>Addressed an issue where the Liberated Challenge could be completed by saving and quitting before starting the final encounter. </li><li>Addressed an issue that would complete the Social Distancing and Invincible Challenges by joining a game in progress. </li><li>Addressed an issue that would complete the Harbinger of Doom Challenge when loading into a saved game and using a Scorestreak. </li><li>Addressed an issue where the Prestige 5 Challenge Fire &amp; Forget would mention needing a Bombing Run medal instead a Lethality medal. </li><li>Addressed an issue where the player would not complete Outrageous Challenge until Round 16 instead of Round 15. </li><li>Addressed an issue where loading a save past Round 25 would complete the Sticks N’ Stones Challenge. </li><li>Addressed an issue where the Dark Journey Challenge could show as not complete when unlocking Nebula on 33 weapons and being awarded the Calling Card. </li></ul><strong>AFK Detection  </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>We have updated the detection logic to determine if a player is AFK during an active match. <ul data-cy="list"><li>This should reduce the amount of false positive AFK kicks in Zombies. </li></ul></li><li>Added AFK Kick warning UI to ZM </li></ul><strong>UI </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Updated visuals on all GobbleGums to improve readability. </li><li>Addressed an issue where the Boat UI would overlap with the Map with the Central Command HUD preset. </li><li>Addressed an issue where the Drop Node Connecter prompt during the Terminus Main Quest would overlap with the Map with the Central Command HUD preset. </li><li>Addressed an issue where the Round number would initially be displayed incorrectly when loading a save. </li><li>Addressed an issue where the Weapon Stats on the AAR would show the loadout players started with instead of the loadout they ended with.</li><li>Addressed an issue where some items would show the wrong text on the Tac Map when pinged. </li><li>Removed Multiplayer information from Melee Weapon descriptions. </li><li>Added a Highest Round icon to the AAR when reaching a new personal highest round. </li><li>Added a timer to the scoreboard. </li><li>Added a notification when picking up Intel. </li></ul><strong>Graphics </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Addressed an issue on PS4 where some effects would stop rendering at higher rounds. </li><li>Addressed an issue where some effects for the Mutant Injection were not working when Sprinting. </li><li>Addressed an issue where the character effects from Brutus would be present during Mutant Injection. </li><li>Liberty Falls <ul data-cy="list"><li>Addressed an issue where some damaged vehicles would not have smoke effects. </li></ul></li></ul><strong>Stability </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Addressed an issue where the game could crash when attempting to start a solo match after playing in splitscreen. </li><li>Addressed an issue where sometimes the player would be unable to Save &amp; Quit with the error "The game failed to save for an unknown reason. Try again later." </li><li>Added numerous stability fixes.</li></ul><h2 data-cy="title2">Call of Duty: Warzone Patch Notes</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Season 01 of Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 is imminent! Tomorrow, you’ll get your chance to wreak some havoc when Sevati “Sev” Dumas brings home a deal to take down the remaining Pantheon rats. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Until then, check out our Patch Notes for details on New Season 01 Content and the latest balance adjustments, gameplay improvements, bug fixes, and more. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Looking for Multiplayer or Zombies Patch Notes? The team at Treyarch has you covered <a href="https://www.callofduty.com/patchnotes/2024/11/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-season-01-patch-notes" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>right here</u></a>. </p><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>RICOCHET ANTI-CHEAT</strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Treyarch has delivered several updates to combat disruptive behavior, including:</p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Enhanced AFK detections to battle against account boosting </li><li>Adjusting ping thresholds to require players play matches in their region to cut down on VPN abuse</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph">To unlock Ranked Play in Black Ops 6, players will need to win 50 match-made multiplayer matches: </p><ul data-cy="list"><li>This ensures that players are experienced with multiplayer before they enter the mode and gives #TeamRICOCHET a historical match history to examine before an account enters Ranked Play </li><li>#TeamRICOCHET also utilizes its Replay Investigation Tool to monitor replays of top players as part of the investigation process </li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph">Detection systems initially deployed at launch from #TeamRICOCHET to collect data to test for effectiveness will be activated to help flag accounts for action beginning with Season 01. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The security system updates listed above will also be active for Ranked Play in Call of Duty®: Warzone™, which launches at mid-season. </p><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>EVENTS</strong></h2><strong>The Hit List (Launch Window)</strong><p data-cy="paragraph">Who’s next? Keep up your luxurious – but slightly corrupt – lifestyle during the Hit List Event. You’re offered up a take-no-prisoners mission: kill or be killed. The Hit List Limited Event gives players a board of contracts with one goal – take them all out. Cross off the entire list and earn some exclusive loot for hire.</p><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>BATTLE PASS</strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">An all-new Battle Pass System grants you the opportunity to earn 100+ rewards, including free base weapons, numerous Weapon Blueprints, Equipment Skins, Operator Skins, and much more. There are three ways to obtain some or all of this content:</p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Earn 20+ free rewards, including cosmetic content and base weapons.</li><li>Purchase the premium Battle Pass and earn up to 1,100 COD Points as you progress through the Battle Pass Pages.</li><li>Or purchase BlackCell for the ultimate seasonal experience, including a variety of molten hot Operator Skins, Weapon Blueprints, COD points, and other rewards.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph">For a full breakdown of the Season 01 Battle Pass and the breadth of content that it has to offer, check out the <a href="https://www.callofduty.com/blog/2024/11/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-season-one-blackcell-bp-bundles-zombies-announcement" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>official blog here</u></a>.</p><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>WARZONE</strong></h2><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>MAPS</strong></h2><h3 data-cy="title3"><u><strong>New Map</strong></u></h3><strong>Area 99</strong><p data-cy="paragraph">Season 01 introduces Area 99, a new Warzone map designed by Treyarch and inspired by Nuketown's high-paced gameplay. This map is set in the Nevada desert at the Echo Ridge Weapons Station — a hidden 1950s government site abandoned after a reactor leak. The map offers intense, tactical combat through desert roadways, open trenches, and pipework around a central Reactor “bullseye,” anticipated as the hottest drop zone. Another key point of interest is a massive crane suspending a Nuketown house in the Loading Bay, adding to the map's unique and dynamic environment.</p><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Points of Interest</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Reactor</li><li>Bunker</li><li>Test Site</li><li>Mannequin Assembly</li><li>Cooling Towers</li><li>Nuketown Shipping</li><li>Loading Bay</li><li>Warehouse</li><li>Manufacturing</li><li>Pods</li></ul></li></ul><h3 data-cy="title3"><u><strong>Returning Maps</strong></u></h3><strong>Urzikstan </strong><p data-cy="paragraph">The "big map" returns to its early days featuring familiar landmarks from before the destruction of Popov Power Plant and the arrival of the Atlas Superstore.  </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Enhanced with Black Ops 6 innovations, Urzikstan is the staging ground for a fierce Ranked Play Battle Royale later when Season 01's Mid-Season launches. </p><strong>Rebirth Island</strong><p data-cy="paragraph">The infamous prison island returns during Season 01's playlist with Resurgence Modes, enhanced by Omnimovement, Black Ops 6 weaponry, and Killstreaks for added tactical intensity.</p><h3 data-cy="title3"><u><strong>Map Adjustments</strong></u></h3><strong>Urzikstan, Rebirth Island</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Vehicles </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>All new vehicles with improved handling, detailed further below. </li><li>Brand new dirtbike for quick rotation. </li></ul></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Loot  </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>All new Black Ops 6 ground loot including weapons and equipment. </li></ul></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Visuals </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Lighting and visual improvements to the map with Black Ops 6 technology. </li></ul></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Sound  </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Audio improvements to in-game sound effects including footsteps balance tuning. </li></ul></li></ul><strong>Rebirth Island</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Submarine </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>The Submarine POI introduced earlier this year now appears 100% of the time. </li></ul></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Redeploy Drones </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Increased Redeploy Drone count and spawn rate for balancing later circles. </li></ul></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Biometric Scanner &amp; Weapon Trade Station </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Rewards for the Biometric Scanner and Weapon Trade Station have been rebalanced and updated to Black Ops 6 loot. </li></ul></li></ul><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>MODES</strong></h2><h3 data-cy="title3"><u><strong>Returning Modes</strong></u></h3><strong>Battle Royale</strong><p data-cy="paragraph">This mode offers the classic Warzone experience, centered around high-risk, high-reward gameplay. You and your squad have only but a few attempts to survive - and the match concludes with one ultimate winner.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>•    Player Count:</strong> 120 (Solos, Duos, Trios, Quads) </p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>•    Map: </strong>Urzikstan</p><strong>Resurgence</strong><p data-cy="paragraph">This mode offers a bit more forgiveness and a whole lot more action. As long as one squad member remains alive, others can redeploy after a countdown. However, once the resurgence window expires, free redeployment is no longer possible for the remainder of the game.  </p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>•    Player Count:</strong> 44 (Solos, Duos, Quads), 45 (Trios) </p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>•    Map: </strong>Area 99, Rebirth Island</p><strong>Plunder</strong><p data-cy="paragraph">This mode is a squad-based mode where accumulating Cash is the main objective. The squad that gathers the most Cash by the end of a timed period - extended into overtime once a squad reaches $2 million - claims victory. Cash can be earned by eliminating players and collecting their valuables, searching ground loot and Supply Boxes, and completing Contracts and in-game events. Operators can start with a custom Loadout and redeploy after each elimination throughout the entire match. </p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>•    Player Count:</strong> 120</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>•    Map: </strong>Urzikstan</p><strong>Bootcamp</strong><p data-cy="paragraph">This mode is a Quads-only training mode, allowing players to experience Warzone with up to 20 players and 24 bots. XP progression is limited, and the mode does not contribute to Daily/Weekly Challenges or include public events or advanced contracts. </p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>•    Player Count:</strong> 44 </p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>•    Map: </strong>Urzikstan</p><h3 data-cy="title3"><u><strong>Mode Adjustments</strong></u></h3><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Resurgence </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Players will receive an additional 25% discount in the Buy Station on "Redeploy Squadmate" while the Resurgence timer is still active.</li></ul></li></ul><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>PLAYLIST</strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Additional Note: To celebrate the new Area 99 map, it is the exclusive Resurgence map during the first weekend of launch, with Rebirth Island then returning to the playlist.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">For information about upcoming Playlists, please check out the dedicated <a href="https://trello.com/b/1eSBEowr/warzone-raven-software" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Warzone Trello Board</u></a>.</p><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>RANKED PLAY</strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">An all-new Ranked Play experience will come to Battle Royale on Urzikstan for the first time with Season 01 Reloaded. Keep an eye open for more intel later this year.</p><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>GENERAL</strong></h2><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Carry-Forward </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Weapons, blueprints, operators and skins, and vast majority of the cosmetics from Modern Warfare II and III will be available to players in the Black Ops 6 era of Warzone. </li></ul></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>AFK Detection </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>We have updated the detection logic to determine if a player is AFK during an active match.</li></ul></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Leaderboards </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>To accommodate and track the new statistics coming with the Black Ops 6 integration, the Warzone Leaderboard stats will be reset at launch.</li></ul></li></ul><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>ARMORY</strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">The Black Ops 6 Armory (BETA) is a repository that provides access to previously missed Loadout content from prior titles including Modern Warfare II and III. Players can look for and activate an item in the Armory to start earning XP toward unlocking it.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The Armory is unlocked at Player Level 24 and is added to the Level Unlock Menu. This menu serves as a platform to browse items that otherwise cannot be earned through normal weapon progression.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Please note that certain legacy attachments will be missing from the armory at the launch of Season 01. New players seeking to unlock these items can do so by playing the respective legacy title until they are implemented in Black Ops 6 in a future update. Players that have already unlocked this content in previous games are not impacted.</p><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>PROGRESSION</strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Season 01 introduces an extensive progression and Prestige system, with 55 levels of unlocks, 10 Prestige levels, and a final Prestige Mastery tier with 1,000 additional levels. Players unlock weapons, equipment, killstreaks, and perks through progression, with exclusive Calling Cards, animated "Dark Ops" cards, and 10 reticle unlocks per optic. Weapon camos include 9 Military Camos per weapon, 2 Special Camos sharable across modes, and 4 Mastery Camos, including animated designs like Gold Tiger and Abyss. Some rewards are exclusive to Black Ops 6 but can be earned retroactively.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">For a deep dive on Progression in Call of Duty Black Ops 6, check out the <a href="https://www.callofduty.com/blog/2024/10/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-launch-progression-leveling-prestiging-challenges-intel" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>dedicated blog here</u></a>.</p><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>CAMOS</strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Weapon Mastery Camos</strong> <em>NEW </em></p><p data-cy="paragraph">The Weapon Camo grind has been overhauled in Black Ops 6 and is bigger than ever. You’ll be progressing through Camos on the quest to earn the first ever Call of Duty: Warzone Mastery Camo: Abyss (Season 01).</p><p data-cy="paragraph">For a more detailed look at Progression in Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 and Warzone, check out the Launch Comms: Progression Systems blog <a href="https://www.callofduty.com/blog/2024/10/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-launch-progression-leveling-prestiging-challenges-intel" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>here</u></a>. </p><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>COMBAT</strong></h2><h3 data-cy="title3"><u><strong>New Combat</strong></u></h3><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Body Shield </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Sneak up behind an unsuspecting enemy and double-tap the melee button to pull them close as your personal shield against incoming fire.  </li><li>Once they’ve served their purpose, gracefully deliver the coup de grâce. </li><li>Body Shield is the spiritual successor to the previous Interrogation mechanic. </li></ul></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Dedicated Melee Weapon </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>All player loadouts will have a dedicated melee weapon by default, in addition to their primary and secondary weapon slots.  </li><li>Players can swap to their dedicated melee weapon by holding down the melee button. </li><li>Players holding a melee weapon will benefit from unlimited tac sprint. </li></ul></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Shootable Doors </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Doors can now be shot open allowing for new tactics and strategy. </li></ul></li></ul><h3 data-cy="title3"><u><strong>Combat Adjustments</strong></u></h3><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Primary Weapon </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>The Loadout inventory is returning to the classic Warzone experience where players can only equip one Primary weapon. </li><li>There is a Wildcard detailed further below that allows for two Primary weapons to be equipped. </li></ul></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Self-Revive Auto Pickup </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>While downed, players will now be able to automatically loot Self-Revive kits that are within close proximity. </li></ul></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Live Ping Duration </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>The duration of live pings has been reduced from 3 seconds to 2 in order to bring more balance to a combat engagement. </li></ul></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Armor Plate Replacement Speed </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>The speed at which players can replace broken or missing armor plates has been increased by 8% to match the fluidity of Black Ops 6 Omnimovement. </li></ul></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Abandon Timer </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>The time players must wait to give up has been reduced from 5 seconds to 4 seconds due to the previous Interrogation mechanic being replaced. </li></ul></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Deaths Door </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>The health at which players will enter the death’s door state has been reduced from 50% to 35%. </li><li>The health at which the death’s door state will end has been reduced from 70% to 55%. </li><li>This change is due to us wanting to enable Players to better hear and see their surroundings when under threat by an enemy. </li></ul></li></ul><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>MOVEMENT</strong></h2><h3 data-cy="title3"><u><strong>New Movement</strong></u></h3><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Omnimovement </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>The movement and combat innovations from Black Ops 6 are fully integrated into Warzone. This allows players to Sprint, Slide, and Dive in any direction, perform 180-degree Combat Dives, and execute advanced moves like the Combat Supine and Omni-Sprint for dynamic tactical play. </li></ul></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Combat Supine</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Drop to a prone position, then rotate your Operator for a complete 360-degree view of your surroundings. Then fire to eliminate the enemy quickly as they appear, all the while staying in the supine position.</li></ul></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Intelligent Movement </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Players can now customize elements of how they traverse landscape and navigate combat. </li><li>Available in the Keyboard &amp; Mouse or Controller Options under “Movement,” players will find the following features: <ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Sprint Assist: </strong>Choose whether to manually or automatically sprint, tactically sprint, how much of a delay before sprinting begins, and if the assist occurs while sprinting sideways or backwards. </li><li><strong>Mantle Assist: </strong>Customize how and when to automatically mantle over obstacles. </li><li><strong>Crouch Assist: </strong>This enables crouching and sliding when the intent is to move through a valid opening. </li><li><strong>Corner Slice: </strong>Allows the act of inclining weapons (and camera) when adjacent to or moving around a corner. This doesn’t affect aim. Default is “on.” </li></ul></li></ul></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Unlimited Tac Sprint  </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Players will have access to unlimited tac sprint via the Sprinter Perk or by holding their dedicated melee weapon. </li></ul></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Mantle Protection </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Players will now climb onto thin or high ledges rather than over them to prevent untimely deaths.</li></ul></li></ul><h3 data-cy="title3"><u><strong>Movement Adjustments</strong></u></h3><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Tac Sprint Duration </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>We heard feedback around default tac sprint duration, so it has been increased from 2 seconds to 4 seconds. </li></ul></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Landing Tuning </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>The duration of the shock effect when falling from a near-death height has been reduced to 2.1 seconds from 3 seconds. </li><li>The minimum fall damage required before the shock effect from landing is now 55%, up from 50% allowing for slightly higher jumps with less punishment. </li><li>This change is made to better enable the movement opportunities that the Black Ops 6 integration allows. </li></ul></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Vertical Ascenders &amp; Horizontal Zipline Improvements </strong><em>Quality of Life</em><em><strong> </strong></em><ul data-cy="list"><li>Interacting with the Ascenders and Ziplines lines has been improved, making it easier to attach to the line from an angle or while free falling to increase fluidity. </li></ul></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Redeploy Drones </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Redeploy Drones are fixed in place for the duration of a match. </li><li>Once a Redeploy Drone has been consumed by the gas, it will leave the map rather than relocating to give a more consistent experience.</li></ul></li></ul><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>INVENTORY</strong></h2><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Streamlined Inventory </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>At the start of Season 01, we're streamlining the inventory system by removing the “Backpack” and returning to a classic inventory layout, organized by sections for cash, gas mask, armor plates, killstreaks, field upgrades, weapons, ammo and perks.  </li></ul></li></ul><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>PERKS</strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Perks in Warzone are now streamlined, allowing players to choose three Perks (one from each color-coded slot) in the Loadouts Menu. Most Pick-3 Perks unlock as you level up but re-lock upon Prestiging. Black Ops 6 player levels carry over to Warzone, unlocking corresponding Perks. </p><h3 data-cy="title3"><u><strong>General</strong></u></h3><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Lootable Perks </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Lootable Perks return! Each season, players will encounter a number of perks via Ground Loot and Supply Boxes. These perk effects stack on top of the original Pick-3 Perks players have selected in their loadout. </li><li>When a player is eliminated, their Pick-3 Perks will drop on the ground as a “Custom Perk Pack” to be recovered or stolen by another player, while any looted perks will disappear. </li><li>The Lootable Perks players can find include a mix of perks from the 18 possible Pick-3 Perks, in addition to two perks that are unique to ground loot; <ul data-cy="list"><li>Shrouded </li><li>Irradiated </li></ul></li><li>Players will recognize their Pick-3 Perks when they are equipped in the bottom right of the HUD, while lootable perks can be viewed in the Inventory. </li></ul></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Specialist Perk Package </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Found as a rare loot drop or Care Package reward, Specialist grants every Perk including all 18 Pick-3 Perks, as well as both Ground Loot exclusive Perks - Irradiated and Shrouded.  </li><li>If you're eliminated, the Specialist Perk package will disappear. </li><li>Can be acquired in Buy Stations in limited quantities for $30,000. </li></ul></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Pre-Match Perks</strong><em> Quality of Life </em><ul data-cy="list"><li>Perks can now be edited in the pre-match lobby. </li></ul></li></ul><h3 data-cy="title3"><u><strong>Available Perks</strong></u></h3><strong>Slot 1</strong><strong>Veteran</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Reduce the negative effects of some enemy equipment.  <ul data-cy="list"><li>Immunity to Grenadier. </li><li>Immunity to Snapshots. </li><li>Resistant to Flash, Gas, Movement, and Shock negative effects. </li></ul></li><li>While aiming down sights reduce flinching and extend Hold Breath duration.  </li><li>Unlocked via Season 01 - The Hit List Event Reward </li></ul><strong>Grenadier</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Explosive damage slows enemy health regeneration and movement speed.  </li><li>Throw equipment farther and see a previous of the trajectory.  </li><li>Throw distance reduced to 15% from 25%. </li><li>Increased the delay for enemy health to regen to 10 seconds from 5 seconds. </li><li>Unlocked at player level 1</li></ul><strong>Dexterity</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Reduced weapon motion while jumping, sliding, and diving.  </li><li>Take less fall damage.  </li><li>Unlocked at player level 20</li></ul><strong>Scavenger</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Start equipped with maximum reserve ammo for your primary weapon.  <ul data-cy="list"><li>Extra ammunition from Loadout acquisition only. </li></ul></li><li>Resupply ammo, equipment, plates, and extra cash from dead enemies. </li><li>Unlocked at player level 26</li></ul><strong>Survivor</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Start regenerating health more quickly. <ul data-cy="list"><li>Health regen begins after 3 seconds. </li></ul></li><li>Your allies revive you faster when you’re downed. </li><li>The passive ability to ping enemies that down you has been moved to Tracker. </li><li>Removed reviving allies faster. </li><li>Removed the death tax reduction. </li><li>Unlocked at player level 47 </li></ul><strong>Slot 2</strong><strong>Quartermaster</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Recharge equipment over time (50 seconds).  </li><li>Unlocked at player level 1</li></ul><strong>Bomb Squad</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Reduces incoming explosive and fire damage.  <ul data-cy="list"><li>Does not reduce Killstreaks damage. </li></ul></li><li>Spot enemy equipment and Killstreaks through walls. <ul data-cy="list"><li>Can hack enemy equipment. </li><li>ADS to highlight equipment for your squad. </li></ul></li><li>Unlocked at player level 8</li></ul><strong>Tracker</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Track enemy footsteps, bullets you fire briefly mark an enemy on contact for you and your squad. <ul data-cy="list"><li>Hitting the enemy from farther away increases the time they are marked. </li></ul></li><li>Enemies that down you are automatically pinged.  </li><li>Unlocked at player level 29</li></ul><strong>Sprinter</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Can Tactical Sprint indefinitely. </li><li>Unlocked at player level 32</li></ul><strong>Cold-Blooded</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Undetectable by AI targeting and thermal optics.  </li><li>Prevents some enemy recon Perks and effects. <ul data-cy="list"><li>Immunity to EMP and Scrambling. </li><li>Immunity to Tracker. </li><li>Will not trigger Alertness. </li></ul></li><li>Unlocked at player level 41</li></ul><strong>Quick Fix</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Killing enemies or inserting armor plates immediately starts health regeneration.  <ul data-cy="list"><li>Health regeneration triggers on gun, melee, and throwing knife kills. </li></ul></li><li>Players can now insert amor plates one-handed enabling them to still hold onto a weapon and hip fire. </li><li>Unlocked at player level 50 </li></ul><strong>Slot 3</strong><strong>Gung-Ho</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Reduced movement penalties when reloading or using equipment. </li><li>Reload while Tac Sprinting. </li><li>Unlocked at player level 1</li></ul><strong>Resolute</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Taking damage from gunfire provides a boost to movement speed for a short duration. <ul data-cy="list"><li>15% movement speed bonus, an increase from 5%. </li></ul></li><li>Unlocked at player level 5</li></ul><strong>Ghost</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Undetectable by enemy Radar Pings while moving.  </li><li>Cannot be detected by some devices.  <ul data-cy="list"><li>Immunity to Heartbeat Sensor and Proxy Alarm. </li></ul></li><li>Unlocked at player level 17</li></ul><strong>Birdseye</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>UAVs you call in are 25% larger and show the heading of the enemy for your squad.  <ul data-cy="list"><li>Increase applies to UAV Killstreaks, UAV Towers, and Portable Radar. </li></ul></li><li>Detects players who have the Ghost effect.  <ul data-cy="list"><li>Players with Ghost do not show a heading. </li></ul></li><li>Will no longer increase sweep speed or duration of UAVs. </li><li>Unlocked at player level 23</li></ul><strong>Tempered</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Refill armor plates to full with two plates instead of three. </li><li>Unlocked at player level 35</li></ul><strong>Alertness</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Sense when enemies are nearby with on-screen information. <ul data-cy="list"><li>Sense at a 30m radius. </li></ul></li><li>Your vision pulses when you are being aimed at by the enemy. </li><li>Unlocked at player level 44 </li></ul><strong>Lootable Perks</strong><strong>Shrouded</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Drop a Smoke Grenade when entering the downed state.  </li><li>Available via ground loot</li></ul><strong>Irradiated</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>While under the effects of the gas circle or equipment you will move faster, take reduced gas damage, and can insert armor plates. </li><li>Available via ground loot </li></ul><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>WILDCARDS</strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">First introduced in Black Ops Cold War, Wildcards come to Warzone with 4 options that act as special, single-use perks for each loadout. These loadout modifiers allow players to equip more gear, weapons, or attachments, adding unique customization and variety to gameplay.</p><h3 data-cy="title3"><u><strong>Available Wildcards</strong></u></h3><h3 data-cy="title3"><strong>Bandolier</strong></h3><p data-cy="paragraph">- Your loadout provides a Munitions Satchel.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">- This Wildcard is only available in Warzone.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">- Unlocked at player level 15</p><h3 data-cy="title3"><strong>Overkill</strong></h3><p data-cy="paragraph">- Equip two Primary or Secondary weapons. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">- Unlocked at player level 24</p><h3 data-cy="title3"><strong>Gunfighter</strong></h3><p data-cy="paragraph">- Get 3 extra attachment points for your Primary weapon. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">- This only applies to Black Ops 6 weapons. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">- Unlocked at player level 33</p><h3 data-cy="title3"><strong>Battle Ready</strong></h3><p data-cy="paragraph">- Your loadout provides a UAV and Utility Box. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">- This Wildcard is only available in Warzone. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">- Unlocked at player level 38</p><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>SATCHELS</strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Satchels are new loot items that expand storage for inventory slots, allowing players to carry more of an item type and improve efficiency. Each Satchel type can be equipped simultaneously and are dropped upon elimination. </p><h3 data-cy="title3"><u><strong>Available Satchels</strong></u></h3><h3 data-cy="title3"><strong>Armor Satchel</strong></h3><p data-cy="paragraph">- This substantially increases your Armor Plate carrying capacity from 6 to 12.</p><h3 data-cy="title3"><strong>Munitions Satchel</strong></h3><p data-cy="paragraph">- This increases the Ammunition capacity for all weapon types. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">- Increases Equipment capacity by 2 to 4. </p><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>EQUIPMENT</strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Warzone continues to provide an extensive selection of lethal and tactical equipment, allowing players a range of options to suit their combat style. With the release of Black Ops 6, players can explore new additions to the equipment lineup, some of which we suspect may become fan favorites. We’ve also made several visual and balance adjustments to classic equipment, ensuring a diverse arsenal to choose from.</p><h3 data-cy="title3"><u><strong>Available Equipment</strong></u></h3><strong>Lethal Equipment</strong><strong>Frag Grenade</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Cookable fragmentation grenade. </li><li>Unlocked at player level 1</li></ul><em><strong>NEW</strong></em><strong>Spring Mine</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Proximity-triggered explosive that launches in the air and deals heavy damage to the surrounding area. </li><li>Unlocked at player level 1</li></ul><strong>Semtex</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Reliable sticky grenade with a timed fuse. </li><li>Unlocked at player level 9</li></ul><strong>C4</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Sticky explosive with large damage radius. </li><li>Unlocked at player level 14</li></ul><strong>Thermo Grenade </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Creates a large fuel-air cloud that explodes after a duration. </li><li>Updated to the Black Ops 6 version of the Thermobaric. </li><li>Unlocked at player level 21</li></ul><em><strong>NEW</strong></em><strong>Impact Grenade</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Precision grenade that explodes on impact. </li><li>Unlocked at player level 26 </li></ul><strong>Molotov Cocktail</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Thrown incendiary weapon that creates a patch of flames. </li><li>Unlocked at player level 32</li></ul><strong>Throwing Knife</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Retrievable knife that is lethal on impact to unarmored targets or the head. </li><li>Unlocked at player level 36 </li></ul><em><strong>NEW</strong></em><strong>Blast Trap</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Planted explosive device that detonates when enemies come near. </li><li>Unlocked at player level 41</li></ul><strong>Drill Charge</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Explosive charge that burrows into a surface and explodes, damaging enemies on the other side. </li><li>Unlocked at player level 50</li></ul><em><strong>NEW</strong></em><strong>Combat Axe</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Retrievable axe that is lethal on impact to unarmored targets and bounces off surfaces. </li><li>Unlocked at player level 53 </li></ul><strong>Tactical Equipment</strong><em><strong>NEW</strong></em><strong>Prox Alarm</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Thrown sticky alarm that rings and flashes when an enemy is nearby. Tripped alarms show on allied minimaps. </li><li>The alarm will outline enemies within the tripped area. This cannot be seen through walls. </li><li>Available via ground loot</li></ul><strong>Concussion</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Grenade that slows enemy movement and aiming. </li><li>Unlocked at player level 1 </li></ul><strong>Flashbang</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Grenade that blinds enemies for a duration. </li><li>Unlocked at player level 6 </li></ul><strong>Snapshot Grenade</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Provides a momentary glimpse of enemies within the blast radius for your squad. </li><li>Unlocked at player level 11 </li></ul><em><strong>NEW</strong></em><strong>Spy Camera</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Quickly mark enemies and hostile Equipment for your team. </li><li>Unlocked at player level 12 </li></ul><strong>Smoke Grenade</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Deploys a smoke screen that blocks vision and automated targeting systems. </li><li>Unlocked at player level 17</li></ul><strong>Experimental Gas</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Grenade that releases a lingering cloud of gas that causes slowed movement, blurred vision, coughing, and light damage. </li><li>Unlocked at player level 27 </li></ul><strong>Stim Shot</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Combat stim that heals wounds, provides an immediate burst of movement speed, and refreshes tac sprint. </li><li>Unlocked at player level 30 </li></ul><strong>Decoy Grenade</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Grenade that simulates footsteps and gunfire to confuse enemies. Sticks to surfaces. </li><li>Unlocked at player level 35 </li></ul><strong>Shock Charge</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Electrical trap that sticks to surfaces and electrocutes enemies, stunning them. </li><li>Unlocked at player level 42 </li></ul><em><strong>NEW</strong></em><strong>Neurogas Mine</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Deployed trap which emits a neurotoxic gas cloud, causing severe hallucinations, disorienting, and damaging enemies. </li><li>Unlocked at player level 48</li></ul><h3 data-cy="title3"><u><strong>Equipment Adjustments</strong></u></h3><p data-cy="paragraph">With the Black Ops 6 integration, we have adjusted a number of the Lethal and Tactical equipment to offer a new and fresh arsenal of choices.</p><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Maximum Deployed Equipment </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>The maximum number of lethal and tactical equipment that can be planted at the same time has been increased to 3 up from 2. </li><li>We aligned Warzone with the changes to Multiplayer. This enables some of the new traps to be better utilized and function better with other adjustments like the Munitions Vest and Bomb Squad. </li></ul></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Frag </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Outer damage decreased to 65 from 110. </li><li>Middle damage increased to 170 from 155. </li><li>Inner damage decreased to 260 from 275.</li><li><strong>Frag Cooking Indicator</strong> <em>Quality of Life </em><ul data-cy="list"><li>Players will now notice a UI indicator to better determine the time remaining until a frag detonates.</li></ul></li></ul></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Semtex </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Explosion radius decreased to 5m from 6.5m. </li><li>Outer damage decreased to 45 from 110. </li><li>Inner damage decreased to 180 from 200. </li></ul></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Throwing Knife </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Damage decreased to 180 from 200. </li></ul></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Drill Charge </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Outer damage decreased to 39 from 110. </li></ul></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Molotov </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Burn stage damage was reduced to 10,15,25 from 15, 25, 30. </li></ul></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Smoke </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>VFX updated to be at parity with Black Ops 6. </li></ul></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Experimental Gas </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Will now deal 10 damage per tick. </li></ul></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Snapshot Grenade </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Radius increased to 15m from 10m. </li><li>Will now put a mark over a successfully “snapped” target which lasts for 5 seconds. </li></ul></li></ul><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>KILLSTREAKS</strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Killstreaks in Warzone, much like Multiplayer’s Scorestreaks, are game-changing tools that players can find via ground loot, Supply Boxes, or as rewards from contracts and events. Many of these Killstreaks are lethal, unleashing devastating airstrikes and explosions that can decimate enemy squads from above. Others are tactical, offering valuable intel on enemy positions or on ideal positioning for upcoming fights. With Black Ops 6, a few new Killstreaks have been introduced designed to give players a real advantage in the heat of battle. </p><h3 data-cy="title3"><u><strong>Available Killstreaks</strong></u></h3><strong>Killstreaks</strong><em><strong>NEW</strong></em><strong>Care Package</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Call in a care package that will provide several random items including killstreaks, legendary or greater weapons, lootable perks, and field upgrades. </li></ul><em><strong>NEW</strong></em><strong>Napalm Strike</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Launch a targeted carpet bomb strike of explosive napalm. </li></ul><em><strong>NEW</strong></em><strong>SAM Turret</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>An automated turret that scans for and attacks enemy aerial vehicles within range.</li></ul><em><strong>NEW</strong></em><strong>Sentry Turret</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Automated turret that scans for and attacks nearby enemies in a forward-facing cone.</li></ul><strong>UAV</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>UAV recon that reveals enemy locations in a large area. </li></ul><strong>Advanced UAV</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>An advanced version of the UAV that reveals the enemies across the entire map.</li></ul><strong>Bunker Buster</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Designate a missile strike that pierces a building, detonating on impact and deploying gas several stories downward.</li></ul><strong>Cluster Strike</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Launch a missile bombardment in a targeted area for a duration.</li></ul><strong>Counter UAV</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Launch a drone that scrambles enemy mini maps.</li></ul><strong>Foresight</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Shows all future Gas circles on the map. </li></ul><strong>Precision Airstrike</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Call in twin jets for a precision strike along the best available path. </li></ul><strong>Supply UAV</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Radar sweeps that show Supply Box locations on the map.</li></ul><h3 data-cy="title3"><u><strong>Killstreak Adjustments</strong></u></h3><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Bunker Buster </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>The trophy system will now counter the bunker buster. </li></ul></li></ul><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>FIELD UPGRADES</strong></h2><h3 data-cy="title3"><u><strong>Available Field Upgrades</strong></u></h3><strong>Field Upgrades</strong><em><strong>NEW</strong></em><strong>Scrambler</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Creates an area that disrupts enemy equipment, field upgrades, killstreaks, and minimaps.</li></ul><em><strong>NEW</strong></em><strong>War Cry</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Rally your team, improving nearby allies' movement speed and health regen speed for a duration.</li></ul><em><strong>NEW</strong></em><strong>Armor Box</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Drop a box of armor for you and your squad.</li></ul><em><strong>NEW</strong></em><strong>Munitions Box</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Drop a box of ammo and equipment for you and your teammates.</li></ul><strong>Decontamination Station</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Deployable autonomous neutralizing agent that disperses the toxic gas cloud to enable breathing in it. Lasts for a limited time and is very fragile. </li></ul><strong>Deployable Buy Station</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Marks a location and calls in a Deployable Buy Station by drone. </li><li>The drone can be shot down as it flies in, enabling you to change the drop location. </li></ul><strong>Deployable Cover</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Portable, rapidly deployable ballistic cover. </li></ul><strong>Heartbeat Sensor</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>A limited use tablet that displays rough information about nearby enemies. </li></ul><strong>Loadout Drop</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Marks a location and deploys a Loadout Drop Crate, allowing your team to pick-up their loadout, including weapons, perks, lethals and tacticals.</li></ul><strong>Portable Radar</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Emits a periodic radar ping to detect nearby enemies. </li></ul><strong>Portable Redeploy Drone</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>A portable drone used for fast repositioning.</li></ul><strong>Recon Drone</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Player controlled drone that can be parked. Targets in the reticle of the drone for a time will be marked for the squad. </li></ul><strong>Redeploy Drone Beacon</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>A compact redeployment system for fast team repositioning. </li></ul><strong>Reinforcement Flare</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Flare gun that brings a squad mate back. </li></ul><strong>Trophy System</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Deployable autonomous defense system that destroys up to three nearby pieces of equipment and projectiles.</li></ul><strong>Utility Box</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Deploy a box of ammo, equipment, and armor plates for you and your teammates. </li></ul><h3 data-cy="title3"><u><strong>Field Upgrade Adjustments</strong></u></h3><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Heartbeat Sensor </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>The warning display now highlights in red when enemies are within 15 meters, up from 7. </li><li>The time between pings has been reduced to 1.5 seconds, down from 2.5 seconds. </li></ul></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Munitions Box </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>The munitions crate now grants 3 clips of every ammo type, rather than only refilling your primary and secondary weapon ammo types. </li><li>With this change players are enabled to make pivots in their weapon choices. A focus on breadth rather than depth of ammo. </li></ul></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Portable Radar </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>The duration of the portable radar pulse has been increased from 25 seconds to 30. </li></ul></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Personal Redeploy Drone </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Deploys 50% faster.  </li><li>No longer prohibits firing while in use. </li><li>Standardized height across the different maps. </li></ul></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Reinforcement Flare </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>30% faster to use. </li></ul></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Trophy System </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Counter charges increased from 3 to 5. </li></ul></li></ul><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>WEAPONS</strong></h2><h3 data-cy="title3"><u><strong>Introduction</strong></u></h3><p data-cy="paragraph">We've expanded the Warzone arsenal to include weapons from the launch of Black Ops 6 in October 2024, giving players even more options to customize their loadouts. Dive into Warzone with these powerful additions, now available alongside fan favorites from previous titles.  </p><p data-cy="paragraph">At launch, Black Ops 6 weapons in Warzone will share similar values to their Multiplayer counterparts such as ADS speed, sprint to fire, and recoil. However, damage profiles for a number of weapons have been modified to establish a baseline for Warzone. We encourage new and returning players to study their favorite weapon’s details in the Gunsmith. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">With the integration of Black Ops 6, we also now have new tuning options for weapons that weren’t previously available, allowing us to adjust aspects like handling (ADS speed and sprint to fire), magazine sizes, recoil, and more. For instance, while the AS VAL has a default magazine size of 20 in Multiplayer, we’ve set it to 30 for Warzone. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Our goal is to make weapon adjustments faster to keep the available selection dynamic and engaging, without making any weapons feel obsolete. With these new tuning options, we aim to refine each weapon’s identity and role specific to their use in Warzone, such as emphasizing Assault Rifles as strong long-range options. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Additionally, all bolt-action snipers and pump-action shotguns (while aiming down sights) from Modern Warfare II, Modern Warfare III, and Black Ops 6 will have a one-shot headshot potential within their respective max damage ranges. Additionally, in order to incentivize intentional aim, all shotguns will fire 5 pellets while ADSing versus 4 when fired from the hip. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">We want players to feel that weapons from Modern Warfare II and Modern Warfare III continue to remain solid, viable choices in Warzone. Our goal is to create a unified combat system that makes each gun enjoyable to use, regardless of its origin. We’ll continue to improve legacy weapons and attachments throughout the coming year to further support this vision. </p><h3 data-cy="title3"><u><strong>Black Ops 6 Weapons</strong></u></h3><p data-cy="paragraph">Black Ops 6 weapons have a unique Warzone damage profile, which includes specific base damage, range, and location-based modifiers. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">We’ve adjusted several Black Ops 6 attachments to function differently in Warzone: </p><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>CHF Barrel </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>For Assault Rifles, LMGs, DMRs, SMGs, and Pistols: This now grants an increased neck multiplier rather than a head multiplier. </li><li>For Sniper Rifles and Shotguns: This now provides increased leg modifiers instead of arm modifiers. </li></ul></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Flip Magazine </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>The magazine capacity penalty from Multiplayer has been removed. In Warzone, flip mags match the base weapon's ammo capacity. </li></ul></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Rapid Fire </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>This attachment now applies a base damage penalty in Warzone, along with greater penalties to bullet velocity and range. </li></ul></li></ul><h3 data-cy="title3"><u><strong>Modern Warfare II &amp; III Weapons</strong></u></h3><p data-cy="paragraph">A visual recoil reduction pass has been applied to Modern Warfare II weapons, enhancing their feel and control while shooting. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Barrel and stock attachments from Modern Warfare II have also had their penalties reduced. Additionally, a significant balancing pass has been completed for underbarrel and muzzle attachments from both Modern Warfare II and III. All cons have been removed from these attachments, meaning they now only provide stat boosts, with each subcategory of underbarrels and muzzles functioning identically except for cosmetic differences. AMP attachments in these slots, however, retain their unique functionality and balancing. </p><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Muzzle Enhancements </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Suppressors:</strong> Boost velocity and damage range. </li><li><strong>Comps:</strong> Improve recoil control. </li><li><strong>Flash Hiders:</strong> Increase damage range and firing aim stability. </li><li><strong>Breacher: </strong>Enhance melee damage and recoil control. </li></ul></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Underbarrel Enhancements </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Angled Grip:</strong> Increases hipfire and tacstance accuracy and aim walking steadiness. </li><li><strong>Handstop:</strong> Improves sprint-to-fire and ADS speed. </li><li><strong>Vert Grip:</strong> Enhances recoil control and firing aim stability. </li></ul></li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph">Furthermore, Modern Warfare II and III weapons now have corner-slicing functionality, adding an extra tactical edge.</p><h3 data-cy="title3"><u><strong>Global Weapon Builds</strong></u></h3><p data-cy="paragraph">Seamlessly access a custom weapon build you've created across Black Ops 6 Multiplayer, Zombies, and Warzone. This time-saving feature lets you adjust any Build or Blueprint in one game, with changes automatically applied wherever that weapon is equipped. To create a build, select a base weapon or Blueprint, add attachments and cosmetics in the Gunsmith, and return to the Custom Loadout screen to save it. The build, with all selected customizations, will then appear in other modes under the same weapon type.</p><h3 data-cy="title3"><u><strong>New Weapons</strong></u></h3><p data-cy="paragraph">These weapons are new to Season 01 and were not part of the original launch of Black Ops 6 Multiplayer in October 2024. </p><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Krig C </strong><em>Assault Rifle </em><ul data-cy="list"><li>Full-auto assault rifle. High damage and average handling. Recoil pattern starts very controllable before ramping up. </li><li>Unlockable via Battle Pass Page 3 HVT Tier Reward OR Page 14 Battle Pass Blueprint </li></ul></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>SAUG </strong><em>Submachine Gun </em><ul data-cy="list"><li>Fully automatic submachine gun. Excellent mobility and good handling. Great rate of fire. High recoil. </li><li>Unlockable via Battle Pass Page 3 HVT Tier Reward OR Page 11 Battle Pass Blueprint </li></ul></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Sirin 9mm </strong><em>Special Weapon</em> (In-Season) <ul data-cy="list"><li>Fully automatic specialty weapon. Offers SMG characteristics as a secondary weapon. Slow rate of fire. </li><li>Unlockable via Event Reward </li></ul></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Power Drill </strong><em>Melee Weapon</em> (In-Season) <ul data-cy="list"><li>Two-hit kill. Very short range. Very fast attack speed. </li><li>Unlockable via Event Reward </li></ul></li></ul><h3 data-cy="title3"><u><strong>New Attachments</strong></u></h3><p data-cy="paragraph">These attachments are new to Season 01 and were not part of the original launch of Black Ops 6 in October 2024. </p><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>12 Gauge Dragon’s Breath </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Add some heat to your Shotgun blasts with incendiary rounds comprised of magnesium sparks that stick to and burn enemies over time. Equipping the 12 Gauge Dragon’s Breath Fire Mod prevents using Barrel Attachments, but the tradeoff is well worth it when seeking a fiery finish. </li><li>Compatible with Shotguns </li><li>Acquired via Battle Pass Page 7 Reward </li></ul></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Buffer Weight Stock</strong> (In-Season) <ul data-cy="list"><li>The heavier Buffer Weight Stock provides significantly smoother action through the additional resistance met by the bolt carrier group. The improvement results in more manageable recoil through sustained fire, ideal for staying on target though at the expense of ADS Speed and Aim Walk Movement Speed. </li><li>Compatible with XM4 Assault Rifle, XMG LMG, DM-10 Marksman Rifle </li><li>Acquired via Event Reward </li></ul></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Burst Fire Conversion </strong>(In-Season) <ul data-cy="list"><li>Convert the XM4 Assault Rifle’s primary firing mode into a three-round burst to help conserve ammo and stay on target. There’s an impressive lack of recoil too, so it’s still possible to pump out consistent damage when facing heavy threats. </li><li>Compatible with XM4 Assault Rifle </li><li>Acquired via Event Reward </li></ul></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Burst Fire Conversion</strong> (In-Season) <ul data-cy="list"><li>Convert the Kompakt 92 SMG’s primary firing mode into an exceptionally rapid three-round burst. Equipping the Burst Fire Conversion Fire Mod locks the Underbarrel and Barrel Attachment slots. When you need to fire quickly in close quarters, hold down the trigger to automatically cycle through burst shots. </li><li>Compatible with Kompakt 92 SMG </li><li>Acquired via Event Reward </li></ul></li></ul><h3 data-cy="title3"><u><strong>Weapon Adjustments</strong></u></h3><p data-cy="paragraph">The following weapon adjustments are strictly limited to Modern Warfare II and III weapons. It's a lot.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Future patch notes for Black Ops 6 weapons will follow the table format introduced with the launch of Black Ops 6.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>CLICK HERE TO SHOW/HIDE INFO</strong></p><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>LOOT</strong></h2><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Ground &amp; Supply Box Loot </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Added Black Ops 6 items including: <ul data-cy="list"><li>Weapons </li><li>Field Equipment: War Cry, Scrambler </li><li>Killstreaks: Napalm Strike, Sentry Gun, SAM Turret, Care Package </li><li>Lethals: Throwing Axe, Blast Trap, Impact Grenade, Spring Mine </li><li>Tacticals: Neurogas Mine, Prox Alarm, Spy Camera </li><li>Perks: Grenadier, Combat Tracker, Dexterity, Cold-Blooded, Irradiated, Shrouded </li><li>Satchels: Armor Satchel, Munitions Satchel </li></ul></li><li>Removal of the following: <ul data-cy="list"><li>Killstreaks: Cluster Mine, Mosquito Drone, Guardian, Bomb Drone</li><li>Lethals: Proxy Mine, Claymore, Thermite, Breacher Drone </li><li>Tacticals: Tracker Grenade, Scatter Mine </li><li>Redeploy tokens </li></ul></li></ul></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Loot Distribution </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>The loot distribution system will now create further space for larger items as they are dropped to the ground to avoid overlapping loot. </li><li>The loot distribution system will now purposely avoid dropping items near objects in close proximity such as Buy Stations. </li></ul></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Medical Cabinets</strong> <em>Quality of Life </em><ul data-cy="list"><li>Loot that drops out of medical cabinets now drops within closer proximity of its origin. </li></ul></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Buy Stations</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Buy Station inventory and prices have had slight adjustments with the Black Ops 6 integration. </li></ul></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Weapon Outlines</strong><em> Quality of Life</em><ul data-cy="list"><li>Weapons now have rarity outlines to help players better evaluate the options at their disposal throughout a match.</li></ul></li></ul><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>CONTRACTS</strong></h2><h3 data-cy="title3"><u><strong>Available Contracts</strong></u></h3><p data-cy="paragraph">Below is a summary of each contract type to help both new and returning players quickly grasp how each one functions with the integration of Black Ops 6. These summaries cover key objectives, mechanics, and rewards, making it easier for players to jump in and engage with contracts confidently.</p><strong>Bounty </strong><strong> </strong><p data-cy="paragraph">When you pick up a Bounty contract, a nearby player will be selected as your target. A circle will appear on your tac map, periodically updating to show the target’s location. The target will be somewhere within this circle each time it updates, and the circle gradually shrinks as you move closer. The target can also see an indicator on their HUD showing how close the closest player from your hunting team is; this is displayed as a three-level "threat indicator." Completing the contract by killing the target rewards cash, XP, and a singular ping from the bounty target’s body. If another team kills the target, your contract ends with a "poached" outcome, offering a lesser reward. Allowing the timer to run out or losing your team will fail the contract. </p><strong>Big Game Bounty </strong><strong> </strong><p data-cy="paragraph">This contract works similarly to the base Bounty but with a few twists. It only spawns after Circle 2 closes and prioritizes teams with the highest cumulative kills, provided they’re not already bounty targets. If you complete this contract by eliminating the target, you’ll earn an immediate advanced UAV ping along with extra cash and XP, offering greater rewards than a standard Bounty. </p><strong>Scavenger</strong><p data-cy="paragraph">Upon picking up a Scavenger contract, three scavenger caches will spawn near the pickup spot. You’ll be directed to each cache one at a time, with the next cache revealed only after you open the previous one. Opening a cache adds 45 seconds to the contract timer. These caches contain slightly better loot than usual, and each will drop a lootable perk. Opening the third and final cache completes the contract, rewarding your team with cash, XP, and an armor satchel from the last cache. Failing to open all caches before time runs out, or having your team wiped, will fail the contract. </p><strong>Intel</strong><p data-cy="paragraph">When you accept an Intel contract, a nearby upload station will be marked for your team to upload sensitive intel. Reaching the station and interacting with it initiates an "upload" phase where one team member must remain near the station until the upload is complete. If multiple players are in this radius, the upload speed can increase by up to 200%. Completing the upload rewards cash, XP, and a peek at the next circle’s location. Failure occurs if the timer expires or if your team is wiped. </p><strong>Most Wanted </strong><strong> </strong><p data-cy="paragraph">By picking up the Most Wanted contract, you or the team member who picked it up becomes visible on the map for all players. Opponents who kill the Most Wanted target receive cash and XP, while the Most Wanted team can reduce their contract time by obtaining kills and opening loot caches (10-second reduction per cache, 25-second reduction per kill). If the Most Wanted target survives the full contract duration, the contract is completed, and the team earns cash, XP, and revives any dead squad members. Whether the contract ends in success or failure, a "VIP reward crate" appears near the VIP’s location, containing ammo, plates, a killstreak, a weapon, a Gulag token, and cash. </p><strong>Signals Intelligence</strong><p data-cy="paragraph">This contract directs your team to hack nearby contracts for rewards. The nearest contract will be marked for hacking, although you can hack any contract. The number of contracts required depends on team size: solos and duos hack one, while trios and quads hack two. Hacking all required contracts completes the mission, rewarding your team with XP and ten periodic cash payments. Letting time run out or losing your team results in failure.</p><strong>Spy Drone</strong><p data-cy="paragraph">This contract spawns multiple drones in a circle formation near your team. The number of drones varies with team size—solos face five, duos six, trios seven, and quads eight. Destroy all drones to complete the contract and earn cash, XP, a UAV, and redeploy drone beacon from the last drone. Failure results if time expires or your team is wiped out. </p><strong>Elite Contracts</strong><strong> </strong><p data-cy="paragraph">These are tougher versions of existing contracts, offering higher rewards. Elite Contracts reduce the contract time by 45% and reward an additional 1,500 cash on completion. Completing an Elite Contract also drops a reward crate with items, including an ammo pile, armor plate, ultra-rare weapon, and one of several rare items such as a UAV, redeploy drone beacon, deployable kiosk, or, with low probability, a Specialist or Foresight. Note that Most Wanted contracts cannot become Elite, although other contracts might turn Elite as the match progresses. </p><h3 data-cy="title3"><u><strong>Contract Adjustments</strong></u></h3><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Bounty </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Completing the contract now includes finishing downed targets you didn’t down yourself. </li><li>Bounty contracts should no longer start without a valid target. </li><li>"Poached" end state now counts as a contract failure for challenge tracking. </li></ul></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Most Wanted </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Removed the redeploy token from the Most Wanted reward crate in solos. </li></ul></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Scavenger </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>The primary reward in Battle Royale and Resurgence is now an armor plate carrier. </li></ul></li></ul><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>PUBLIC EVENTS</strong></h2><strong>Battle Royale &amp; Resurgence </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Firesale </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>All items in the buy station are discounted at 50% for a limited time. </li></ul></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Restock  </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>All Supply Boxes close and are refilled with items. </li></ul></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Jailbreak  </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>All operators in gulag and eliminated operators are redeployed at the end of a timer. </li></ul></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Fly Buy  </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>A series of drones drop a number of deployable buy stations across the warzone. </li></ul></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Recon Flyover  </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Avoid the detection of overhead drones to prevent your location from being broadcast. </li></ul></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Squad Loadout Drop  </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Loadout drops that are only accessible by their assigned team.</li></ul></li></ul><strong>Battle Royale </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Contested Loadout Drop  </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Limited number of loadout drops that are accessible by any team. </li></ul></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Cash Drop  </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>A number of crates are dropped across the field that, when captured, drop a bounty of cash. </li></ul></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Contractor  </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>All contracts pay out more when completed within a timer. </li></ul></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Rogue Signal  </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>All teams compete on a random task -- the top teams get access to a reward with exclusive loot. </li></ul></li></ul><strong>Resurgence </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Bounty Royale </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>All teams are automatically assigned a Bounty contract. </li></ul></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>High Stakes </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>A number of crates are dropped across the warzone that, when captured, double the XP earn in the current match for the team while also drop high tier loot.</li></ul></li></ul><strong>Plunder </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Blood Money </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>For the duration of the event, operators that are eliminated drop significantly more money.</li></ul></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Attack Choppers </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Once the match enters overtime, attack choppers enter the warzone. Take them down for a large payout.</li></ul></li></ul><strong>Gulag </strong><strong> </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Locked &amp; Loaded </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Start the match with full armor and upgraded guns. </li></ul></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Go Again </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Get another chance at gulag if you lose your fight. </li></ul></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Cash Drop </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>The ground loot is replaced with all cash. </li></ul></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Climb &amp; Punishment </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Ladder's drop in the center of the Gulag. Choose to leave together or perhaps betrayal? </li></ul></li></ul><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>OPERATORS</strong></h2><h3 data-cy="title3"><u><strong>New Operators</strong></u></h3><p data-cy="paragraph">Warzone is now home to all of the operators that were introduced with the launch of Black Ops 6 in addition to a few newcomers introduced in Season 01.</p><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Goliath</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Solidify your fiery combat mastery as the molten man of fire himself, Goliath! All biographical information for this Operator has been redacted. </li><li>Acquirable via BlackCell Bundle </li></ul></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Sevati “Sev” Dumas</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>A main player in the Rogue Team after the conclusion of the Campaign, Sev is ready to make a deal with the untrustworthy French Syndicate and is gearing up to take down the rival Luttazzi family to prove it.  </li><li>Acquirable via BlackCell Bundle </li></ul></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>The Replacer</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>There’s no substitute for greatness. The Replacer has concluded his whirlwind Black Ops 6 takeover tour and has freed up some time to appear in-game, available as a Store Bundle shortly after Launch.  </li><li>Acquirable via Store Bundle </li></ul></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Competitor CDL Home and Away Operators  </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Two new Operators arrive just in time for the 2025 Call of Duty League® season. </li><li>Acquirable via CDL Store Bundle </li></ul></li></ul><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>VEHICLES</strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">All new vehicle physics tech leveraged from the Treyarch engine and Infinity Ward engine.  Our goal is to bring more fun to driving with enhanced maneuverability and natural physics that is easy to use but can also be mastered. Towards this goal, we have removed flat tires, vehicle repairing and fuel.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In addition to the aforementioned changes, we’ve included a number of additional improvements listed below:</p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Updated models</li><li>Improved Natural Physics </li><li>Improved Camera </li><li>Procedural Character Leaning </li><li>Improved VFX - Vehicle lights, exhaust </li><li>Dynamic vehicle death and explosion reactions </li><li>New helicopter simulation and audio </li><li>Support for Aim-Based controls </li></ul><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>FIRING RANGE</strong></h2><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Damage Summary</strong><em> Quality of Life </em><ul data-cy="list"><li>The Firing Range now provides the total amount of damage done with the currently equipped gun. </li></ul></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Default Armor Plates</strong> <em>Quality of Life </em><ul data-cy="list"><li>The firing range will default to 3 armor plates per target dummy. </li></ul></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Default Health</strong> <em>Quality of Life </em><ul data-cy="list"><li>The firing range will default to 150 health per target dummy. </li></ul></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Default Perks </strong><em>Quality of Life </em><ul data-cy="list"><li>The firing range will now default to Warzone perk settings. </li></ul></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Reset Speed </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>The target dummies will now “respawn” or reset to their active position faster than before. </li><li>Removed the delay that prevented target dummies from receiving damage as soon as they reset.  </li></ul></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Hit Locations</strong> <em>Quality of Life </em><ul data-cy="list"><li>Target dummies will now have the same hit location modifiers as actual players to more accurately reflect damage dealt to opponents in a match. </li></ul></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Movable Target Dummy</strong><em><strong> </strong></em><em>Quality of Life </em><ul data-cy="list"><li>A new target dummy is now available that can be moved to various damage ranges based on the currently equipped weapon. </li><li>The moveable dummy cycles between damage ranges as soon as it’s eliminated. </li></ul></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Target Collision </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Target dummy collision has been improved so that bullets register more precisely. </li></ul></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Line-of-Sight</strong> <em>Quality of Life </em><ul data-cy="list"><li>Removed vertical walls that previously broke aim assist when testing weapon strafing. </li></ul></li></ul><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>EMOTES &amp; SPRAYS</strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Adding to the personalization of your Operators are the return of Emotes  and Sprays (iconography you primarily daub on walls, either to tag them or to tactically flag a location for your teammates). Emotes are accessible anywhere you have control over your character. </p><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>EXFIL</strong></h2><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Winner's Circle</strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>The winning squad in a match receives their own Winners’ Circle showcase, with some of their statistical competence on display for all to see. This is also a location where you can celebrate your prowess more individually by employing a favorite Emote, too!</li></ul></li></ul><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>End-of-Game Flow </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>The exfil sequence duration has been reduced with a larger focus on the winning squad. </li><li>Players can now swap between their own squad and the winning squad showing off accolades &amp; player stats.  </li><li>There is a new progression overview screen, focused on player choice experience. </li></ul></li></ul><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>UI/UX</strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">The upcoming Season 01 update for Call of Duty: Warzone introduces a revamped, fully integrated user interface. The primary game tiles on the Home tab will feature Black Ops 6 and Warzone, allowing for instant access to gameplay. The Store and Battle Pass tabs will direct players to their respective sections in either Black Ops 6 or Warzone, depending on what is installed. Warzone will also get its own unique UI with enhancements similar to Black Ops 6. </p><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Customize Menu </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>The customize menu now includes a legacy tab to equip your unlocked MWII and MWIII Calling Cards, Emblems, and Loading Screens. </li></ul></li><li><strong>Legacy Content Filtering </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Similarly, brand new quick filtering for Black Ops 6 and other legacy titles helps filter content organized by game in the gunsmith, operator select, and barracks. </li></ul></li><li><strong>Tac Map Icon Layout </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Cleaner Interface: We've streamlined the interface by hiding the icon prompts on the right side of the screen. </li><li>Reorganized Contracts: Contracts have been moved to the left side of the map for easier access and a more intuitive layout. </li></ul></li><li><strong>Minimap Type</strong> <em>Quality of Life </em><ul data-cy="list"><li>Added the ability to change minimap type and compass type without impacting your Multiplayer settings. </li></ul></li><li><strong>Munitions Satchel Ammo Count</strong> <em>Quality of Life </em><ul data-cy="list"><li>Added an icon next to your ammo count when a munitions satchel is equipped to indicate if your weapon has room to carry more ammo. </li></ul></li><li><strong>Classic Squad Widget </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>We brought back many elements from Warzone's original release including equipment icons, the shape of armor plate icons and more. </li></ul></li><li><strong>Loot Cards </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Loot cards have been updated with overall layout treatment for improved visuals. </li></ul></li><li><strong>Squad Wipe Kill Feed </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>The messaging that appears in the kill feed when a squad is wiped has been updated as follows: <ul data-cy="list"><li>Battle Royale: the message will now display “Sent to Gulag” if the defeated team has one or more members going to the Gulag.  </li><li>Plunder: the message has now been reworded to “Squad Repositioning”. </li></ul></li></ul></li><li><strong>Kill Feed Calling Cards </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Eliminating an enemy player now displays their calling card in the bottom center of the UI. </li></ul></li><li><strong>Aim Assist Settings </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Numerous aim assist settings have been changed including but not limited to the addition of: <ul data-cy="list"><li>Minimum aim assist distance </li><li>Max turn clamp speed </li></ul></li></ul></li><li><strong>Loot Ping Distance </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Loot can no longer be pinged from more than 40 meters away for improved legibility during combat. </li></ul></li><li><strong>Live Ping Visibility</strong><em> Quality of Life </em><ul data-cy="list"><li>Live Pings and Danger Pings have received position and scaling adjustments to prevent blocking or covering enemies upper bodies. </li></ul></li><li><strong>In-Game Splash Frequency</strong><em> Quality of Life </em><ul data-cy="list"><li>We have reduced the overall clutter of in-game splashes by reducing frequency and associated noise. </li></ul></li><li><strong>Weapon Attachment HUD</strong><em><strong> </strong></em><em>Quality of Life </em><ul data-cy="list"><li>The weapon attachments show on the HUD with a blue color for better visibility and clarity on which part of the weapon has an attachment attached. </li></ul></li><li><strong>Playlist Navigation </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>The menu for playlists have been improved – it now includes a vertical list with sub menus for each squad size and a map preview window for a complimentary view of maps offered for each game mode. </li></ul></li><li><strong>Buy Station Redeploy Ping</strong><em> Quality of Life</em><ul data-cy="list"><li>An eliminated Player who pings a Buy Station for a Redeploy, will show a unique Redeploy icon on the Buy Station to better inform their Squad of the buy-back request.</li></ul></li></ul><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>AUDIO</strong></h2><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Enhanced Headphone Mode </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>We’re excited to introduce our best-in-class audio experience to Warzone with the introduction of HRTF (Head-Related Transfer Function) via Universal Profile in Enhanced Headphone Mode, which is available to all players for free. </li></ul></li><li><strong>Armor Plate Break Audio </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>New audio has been added to indicate that armor plates have been destroyed.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Proximity Chat </strong><ul data-cy="list"><li>Proximity chat radius has been reduced from 55 meters to 45. </li></ul></li><li><strong>Stacking Hit Markers &amp; Sound Effects</strong><em> Quality of Life  </em> <ul data-cy="list"><li>Enables displaying both a wall bang, hitting a player in water and pairing of new audio per marker. </li></ul></li><li><strong>Bounty Contract Sound Cues</strong> <em>Quality of Life </em><ul data-cy="list"><li>Added sound cues for when the bounty threat level increases or decreases. </li></ul></li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Michael Cripe is a freelance contributor with IGN. He started writing in the industry in 2017 and is best known for his work at outlets such as The Pitch, The Escapist, OnlySP, and Gameranx.</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Be sure to give him a follow on Twitter @MikeCripe.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Resident Evil 2 remake for iPhone, iPad, and Mac launches December 10]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/11/resident-evil-2-remake-for-iphone-ipad-and-mac-launches-december-10</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/resident-evil-2-remake-for-iphone-ipad-and-mac-launches-december-10.1035267/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/11/resident-evil-2-remake-for-iphone-ipad-and-mac-launches-december-10<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/mobile/smartphone">Smartphone</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Free to try, with an in-app purchase to unlock the full game.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>The iPhone, iPad, and Mac versions of the <em><a title="Games > Resident Evil 2 (2019) [55 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/resident-evil-2-2019">Resident Evil 2</a></em> remake will launch via <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/resident-evil-2/id1640632432" rel="noopener" target="_blank">App Store</a> on December 10, <a title="Companies > Capcom [2,544 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/capcom">Capcom</a> announced. It will be compatible with all iPhone 16 models, iPhone 15 Pro models, and every iPad and Mac with the M1 chip or later. <span id="more-927482"></span></p><p>Get the latest details below.</p><blockquote><p>Players are invited to try a portion of the gripping story with a free download before purchasing the full experience. <em>Resident Evil 2</em> includes support for Universal Purchase and cross-progression, enabling players to enjoy Leon and Claire’s journey through Raccoon City across iPhone, iPad, and Mac and transfer save data between devices.</p><p><em>Resident Evil 2</em> on iPhone and iPad includes enhanced controls along with a new Auto Fire feature, giving players the option to automatically fire weapons after aiming at enemies for a short time. The title also supports a range of compatible controllers on iPhone, iPad, and Mac.</p></blockquote><p>The <em>Resident Evil 2</em> remake is currently available for PlayStation 5, Xbox Series, PlayStation 4, Xbox One, and PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/883710/Resident_Evil_2/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a>, as well as for Switch via cloud streaming.</p><p>View a new set of screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/resident-evil-2-2019/november-13-2024/">at the gallery</a>.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <h2><span>Screenshots</span></h2><div id="carousel_927484"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Modiphius Announces Star Trek Adventures Second Edition Starter Sets Now Available For Pre-Order]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/modiphius-announces-star-trek-adventures-second-edition-starter-sets-now-available</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/modiphius-announces-star-trek-adventures-second-edition-starter-sets-now-available-for-pre-order.1035258/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/modiphius-announces-star-trek-adventures-second-edition-starter-sets-now-available<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Star Trek Adventures Second Edition</em> Starter sets are now available for pre-order. Modiphius Entertainment has announced special box sets to help lower the bar to entry for the newest edition of its licensed Star Trek TTRPG, letting players live out their Starfleet fantasies.</p>



<p>According to an official press release, the <em>Star Trek Adventures Second Edition</em> starter sets contain everything players need to begin their journey in the sci-fi universe created by Gene Roddenberry.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/star-trek-adventures-second-edition-starter-sets-set-up.jpg?itok=hLXPEPT8 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/star-trek-adventures-second-edition-starter-sets-set-up.jpg?itok=eQ41gbxe 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>The starter set includes a major campaign comprised of three linked missions. These missions are designed to challenge a crew of 3-7 player characters. Those missions may involve sending aid to colonies in need, navigating complex issues on the borders of galactic powers, or exploring strange new worlds.</p>

<p>A single S<em>tar Trek Adventures Second Edition</em> starter set contains the following:</p>

<ul><li>A 48-page rules booklet providing an overview of Modiphius' 2d20 system.</li>
	<li>A 60-page campaign booklet containing the adventure "Infinite Combinations"</li>
	<li>A stat sheet for the Constitution-class U.S.S. Challenger and seven player character sheets. Each one has rules references on the back</li>
	<li>Four double-sided rules reference sheets.</li>
	<li>Five uniquely colored d20s.</li>
	<li>A series of tokens. 36 Momenum tokens, 36 Threat tokens, and 9 Determination tokens</li>
</ul><p><em>Star Trek Adventures Second Edition</em> was announced <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/star-trek-adventures-second-edition-sets-course-for-strange-new-worlds" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">in February</a>. Alongside streamlined rules, the latest edition will include rules and resources for Klingon and Romulan player characters, expanding potential stories beyond Starfleet.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/star-trek-adventures-second-edition-starter-sets-box-art.jpg?itok=4rdohmy7 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/star-trek-adventures-second-edition-starter-sets-box-art.jpg?itok=t6oz4DCl 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>Modiphius' Project Manager Jim Johnson said the following about the <em>Star Trek Adventures Second Edition</em> starter sets:</p>

<blockquote>
<p>“One of our key goals for second edition was to make the game accessible to new players, not just of <em>Star Trek Adventures</em> but of RPGs in general. I challenged the Starter Set campaign writers to think about what new gamemasters and new players might need to know as they play the game, and we wrote as much of that advice as possible into the campaign booklet. I hope you’ll be able to pick up the box, open it up, hand out characters, and then jump right into the first adventure and cooperatively tell a fun, evocative Star Trek story together. This one’s got it all–a dramatic rescue of citizens in peril, alien life-forms to investigate, and a science-fiction mystery to dig into and solve."</p>
</blockquote>

<p>The starter sets are available for pre-order right now on Modiphius' store page. Pre-ordered sets are expected to ship in December. The sets will appear at retail stories in January.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Ever since he was small, Tyler Chancey has had a deep, abiding love for video games and a tendency to think and overanalyze everything he enjoyed. This… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/tyler-chancey">More about Tyler</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What Pokémon TCG Pocket Needs More Than Anything Is A Dark Mode]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/pokemon-tcg-pocket-dark-mode-bright-phone-battery-life-1851697973</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/what-pok%C3%A9mon-tcg-pocket-needs-more-than-anything-is-a-dark-mode.1035252/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/pokemon-tcg-pocket-dark-mode-bright-phone-battery-life-1851697973<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="1ca125f1f33ec893045af47d9cea0428" data-recommend-id="image://1ca125f1f33ec893045af47d9cea0428" data-format="jpg" data-width="1066" data-height="600" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Pikachu in sunglasses and a straw-hat hides from the sun. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Pikachu in sunglasses and a straw-hat hides from the sun. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->The Pokemon Company</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="1ca125f1f33ec893045af47d9cea0428" data-recommend-id="image://1ca125f1f33ec893045af47d9cea0428" data-format="jpg" data-width="1066" data-height="600" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Pikachu in sunglasses and a straw-hat hides from the sun. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>It’s midnight. The room is pitch black. I gingerly creep into bed so as not to disturb the amorphous blob of children that may be residing somewhere near its center. I’m sleep-deprived but unable to turn my brain off. I pull out my phone and see a tiny notification out of the corner of my eye that my booster pack stamina has recharged. My finger taps the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/pokemon-tcg-pocket-set-expansion-event-schedule-leak-1851694729&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-tcg-pocket-set-expansion-event-schedule-leak-1851694729"><em>Pokémon TCG Pocket</em></a></span> icon to open the game and collect my rewards. The light of a hundred dying suns immediately fills the room. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="192873" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="The Week In Games: Pocket Monsters And Simulated Goats" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="133" data-playlist="192873,196165,195752" data-current="192873"><div><p>The Week In Games: Pocket Monsters And Simulated Goats</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/192873/192873_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/192873/192873_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/192873/192873_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/192873/192873_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/18337.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>Even on my phone’s darkest setting, <em>Pokémon TCG Pocket </em>is bright as hell. In the morning, when I’m opening my packs and battling for Laprases while my coffee cools, it helps the mobile card game’s beautiful creature art pop amid the window glare. When I’m trying to sneak a session in while mixing formula or rocking a baby back to sleep, however, having <em>Pokémon TCG Pocket</em> open is like shooting a phosphorus flare directly into my eyeballs. At one point or another, probably every one of the game’s over 30 million <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/PTCGP/comments/1gh4nb5/me_opening_tcgp_first_thing_in_the_morning_they/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/PTCGP/comments/1gh4nb5/me_opening_tcgp_first_thing_in_the_morning_they/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">players have realized</a></span> <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/PTCGP/comments/1gbpki3/me_every_time_i_play_midnight_even_when_on_low/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/PTCGP/comments/1gbpki3/me_every_time_i_play_midnight_even_when_on_low/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">how completely absurd this is</a></span>.<br></p><p>“I really hope they add a dark mode,” one player wrote <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/PTCGP/search/?q=dark+mode&amp;cId=2995cc3e-333e-4194-809a-c97dc7a28e47&amp;iId=05c2fd01-59e6-4d7d-818d-7c9e68629125&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/PTCGP/search/?q=dark+mode&amp;cId=2995cc3e-333e-4194-809a-c97dc7a28e47&amp;iId=05c2fd01-59e6-4d7d-818d-7c9e68629125" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">on Reddit</a></span> during early access. “Will they ever put a ‘Dark mode?’” another player wrote when the game came out. “Dark Mode PLEASE,” continued a plea on Halloween. “Hot take: Can we have a Dark mode ui?” someone chimed in a few days ago. “I’m a designer and wanted to save everyone from blindness with…dark mode!” a fan wrote today alongside their mockup. It looks like every other dark mode app on my phone. I need it now. </p><p>There are a couple of reasons the status quo in <em>Pokémon TCG Pocket</em> is particularly bad. First, there is just a ton of white space in this game. Loading animations and default backgrounds all look like they’re made out of pearl. The result is like facing an oncoming car with nauseatingly bright LED high beams that never actually drives past. Second, because of all this light being output, <em>Pokémon TCG Pocket</em> absolutely destroys my phone’s battery life. A five-minute match ticks multiple percentage points off my meter. Before I know it, the whole thing is shutting down just as <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/pokemon-tcg-pocket-best-decks-mewtwo-charizard-1851696181?_gl=1*6cqpk0*_ga*MzQzNjkwNDM2LjE2NDY2NjQ1NzQ.*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczMTUyMTM4Ni4xMTEuMS4xNzMxNTI2MjM5LjQxLjAuMA..&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-tcg-pocket-best-decks-mewtwo-charizard-1851696181?_gl=1*6cqpk0*_ga*MzQzNjkwNDM2LjE2NDY2NjQ1NzQ.*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczMTUyMTM4Ni4xMTEuMS4xNzMxNTI2MjM5LjQxLjAuMA..">my Charizard</a></span> has hit four energy. </p><p>  <em>Pokémon TCG Pocket</em> needs a lot of things at the moment. Card trading for one, a feature that is missing but listed as coming soon. Also emotes, or any other way of communicating with opponents during matches. How else can I troll people when they make a mistake or their turn-one Misty immediately flips a tails? But more than any of those things, <em>Pokémon TCG Pocket </em>needs a dark mode. I let my premium pass free trial lapse today. If it came with a dark mode, I can promise you I would have re-upped. My family’s uninterrupted sleep and my corneas depend on it. </p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What’s Inside the Stalker 2 Ultimate Edition?]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/whats-inside-the-stalker-2-ultimate-edition/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/what%E2%80%99s-inside-the-stalker-2-ultimate-edition.1035231/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/whats-inside-the-stalker-2-ultimate-edition/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-68528">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>I’m as much of a sucker for a physical collector’s edition of my favorite video games as anyone else, and you can bet I have my eye on the Stalker 2 Ultimate Edition. It’s expensive, though. It’s a little too expensive for my blood, and I’m pretty sure my wife would have something to say about one showing up in the mail, too. In any case, it’s still nice to dream and live vicariously through others. So, here’s what’s inside the Stalker 2: Heart of Chornobyl Ultimate Edition!</p>



<h2 id="h-everything-in-the-stalker-2-heart-of-chornobyl-ultimate-edition">Everything In The Stalker 2: Heart of Chornobyl Ultimate Edition</h2>



<figure></figure>







<ul>
<li>S.T.A.L.K.E.R. 2: Heart of Chornobyl (Digital Copy)</li>



<li>Ultimate Edition Digital Content
<ul>
<li>Season Pass</li>



<li>Story-Based Side Quest</li>



<li>Single Player: 1 Costume Skin &amp; 3 Weapon Skins</li>



<li>Multiplayer: 3 Costume Skins &amp; 7 Weapon Skins</li>



<li>Digital Artbook</li>



<li>Digital Soundtrack</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li>Pre-Order Bonus
<ul>
<li>Extended Campfire Content</li>



<li>Early Bird Weapon Skin</li>



<li>Early Bird Costume Skin</li>



<li>Early Bird Multiplayer Badge</li>



<li>Steam Pack</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li>Letter From the Developers</li>



<li>Souvenir Zone Permit</li>



<li>Sticker Pack</li>



<li>Zone Map</li>



<li>Poster</li>



<li>Faction Patches</li>



<li>Military Token</li>



<li>Multi-Tool Keychain w/Fire Starter</li>



<li>Art Book</li>



<li>Stalker Figurine</li>



<li>Artefact Container Lamp</li>



<li>S.T.A.L.K.E.R. Backpack</li>
</ul>







<p>It’s a whole lot of incredibly awesome physical goods and plenty of in-game content, like skins and additional quests to keep you busy across the zone!</p>



<p>Of course, there’s also the Ultimate Edition available on Steam, and that one is completely digital with no physical items. It includes:</p>



<ul>
<li>S.T.A.L.K.E.R. 2: Heart of Chornobyl (Digital Copy)</li>



<li>Ultimate Edition Digital Content
<ul>
<li>Season Pass</li>



<li>Story-Based Side Quest</li>



<li>Single Player: 1 Costume Skin &amp; 3 Weapon Skins</li>



<li>Multiplayer: 3 Costume Skins &amp; 7 Weapon Skins</li>



<li>Digital Artbook</li>



<li>Digital Soundtrack</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li>Pre-Order Bonus</li>
</ul>



<p>Will you delve into the zone on day one in Stalker 2: Heart of Chornobyl? Let us know down in the comments or throw up a post on our <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a> to find other scavengers brave enough to venture into Chornobyl!</p>



<hr>



<p>On the topic of the game, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/stalker-2-gone-gold-november/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Stalker 2 has gone gold ahead of its November 20 release date!</a> Prepare yourself for launch day by learning more about <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/what-are-the-final-stalker-2-pc-specs-needed-to-play-the-game/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the game’s PC specifications</a> to ensure you can run it smoothly!</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/this-zombie-survival-game-is-on-sale-through-the-end-of-november/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/this-zombie-survival-game-is-on-sale-through-the-end-of-november/">This Zombie Survival Game is on Sale Through the End of November</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>If you’re constantly on the lookout for a zombie survival game on sale, then look no further than Dread Dawn at its reduced price through November 26!</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/best-black-friday-deals-for-xbox-series-xs/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/best-black-friday-deals-for-xbox-series-xs/">Best Black Friday Deals for Xbox Series X|S</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Ready for Black Friday this year? Here is a list of Xbox Series X|S deals to look out for.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/arc-raiders-still-free-to-play/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/arc-raiders-still-free-to-play/">Is Arc Raiders Still Free to Play? Pricing Guide</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>When it was initially announced, Arc Raiders was a free-to-play PvE shooter, but what about all these years later?</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/best-black-friday-deals-for-ps5/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/best-black-friday-deals-for-ps5/">Best Black Friday Deals for PS5</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Ready for Black Friday this year? Check out some of the upcoming and current deals on PS5s and PlayStation games.</p>
                    </div>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Activision Cracking Down on Call of Duty VPN Users]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/activision-cracking-down-on-call-of-duty-vpn-users/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/activision-cracking-down-on-call-of-duty-vpn-users.1035228/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/activision-cracking-down-on-call-of-duty-vpn-users/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Activision’s Team RICOCHET has published changes on Black Ops 6 and Warzone to combat account boosting and VPN users. For the longest time, gamers worldwide have accused streamers of abusing ‘VPN lobbies’ to get better clips while playing in regions with a less talented pool of players.</p>



<p>In the latest round of changes, RICOCHET has confirmed how it’s tackling that practice, and while it’s not eradicating the use of VPNs, it’s ‘cutting down’ VPN abuse.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-wherever-you-will-go">Wherever You Will Go</h2>



<p>Using a VPN in Call of Duty has been a thing for several years. Typically, players will use a VPN to get away from highly competitive regions like the United Kingdom, North America, and some European countries. It reached a point where some VPN providers were marketing their products directly at Call of Duty players trying to circumvent ‘tougher lobbies’.</p>



<p>In a recent update, it was confirmed that Team RICOCHET (and Treyarch) has deployed two new changes:</p>



<ul>
<li>Enhanced AFK detections to battle against account boosting</li>



<li>Adjusting ping thresholds to require players to play matches in their region to cut down on VPN abuse</li>
</ul>



<p>If you’ve got awful internet, then the latter change might impact you regardless of whether you have a VPN active or not. One thing that users insist Activision needs to address is the number of players taking part in the practice of ‘2 boxing’.</p>



<p>Black Ops 6 is yet to have a serious issue with cheaters, so something is being done right at Team RICOCHET. In the latter months of its lifecycle, Modern Warfare III was plagued by cheaters, particularly the Ranked Play platform. In the coming days, Ranked Play will hit Black Ops 6, so it could just be a matter of time before this game also suffers.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/after-20-years-world-of-warcraft-is-getting-player-housing/">World of Warcraft is getting player housing</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[World of Warcraft getting customisable cars, player housing, and Classic Classic's launching soon]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/world-of-warcraft-getting-customisable-cars-player-housing-and-classic-classics-launching-soon</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/world-of-warcraft-getting-customisable-cars-player-housing-and-classic-classics-launching-soon.1035225/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/world-of-warcraft-getting-customisable-cars-player-housing-and-classic-classics-launching-soon<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/wow-home-tease.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Blizzard Entertainment</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
Warcraft, you might have noticed, is 30 this year (this <em>week</em> in fact, if you want to be more specific), and Blizzard is celebrating the occasion with a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=efhAa3zYZLw">bit of a news splurge</a> covering its various games set in the Warcraft universe. And that, of course, includes <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/world-of-warcraft">World of Warcraft</a>, with today bringing word the long-running MMO will soon see customisable cars, the launch of <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/world-of-warcraft-classic">World of Warcraft Classic</a> <em>Classic</em>, plus player houses sometime next year.
</p>
<p>
On the World of Warcraft Classic front, Blizzard has announced it'll be launching <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/world-of-warcraft-mists-of-pandaria">Mists of Pandaria</a> Classic in 2025, with a <a href="https://worldofwarcraft.blizzard.com/en-gb/news/24148499/catch-up-on-the-future-of-warcraft-with-the-warcraft-30th-anniversary-direct">roadmap accompanying the news</a> pointing to a pre-patch drop early next summer, before the full release a little later on. Additionally, it's confirmed the impending arrival of World of Warcraft Classic Classic (not <em>strictly</em> an official title), which introduces new fresh realms as part of a <a href="https://worldofwarcraft.blizzard.com/en-gb/news/24156594/relive-your-adventure-with-the-wow-classic-20th-anniversary-edition">WoW Classic 20th Anniversary Edition</a> launching on 21st November this year. These will be available in PvP, PvE, and Hardcore flavours, all progressing through to Burning Crusade Classic (Classic?) next year.
</p>
<p>
Over in World of Warcraft regular, meanwhile, patch 11.0.7 is on the horizon, introducing the Siren Isle as this year's The War Within expansion continues to unfold. That's alongside a revamped Winter Veil event for the festive season, and the previously announced return of WoW's battle royale-style Plunderstorm mode, which is making a comeback next year.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Mists of Pandaria Classic Announce Trailer | World of Warcraft Classic" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/uYGvtbrDiiw?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Mists of Pandaria Classic Announce Trailer | World of Warcraft Classic</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/uYGvtbrDiiw?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/uYGvtbrDiiw?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Mists of Pandaria Classic  launches next year.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uYGvtbrDiiw" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
And as for what's next, that'll be WoW's 11.1 update, officially known as Undermined, releasing this winter. Undermined takes players to the capital city of the goblin's trade empire - called, yes, Undermine - where they'll learn more about goblin culture as The War Within's story continues, aligning themselves with one of the four warring goblins cartels: Steamwheedle, Blackwater, Bilgewater, and the Venture Company.
</p><p>
There's a lot going on in update 11.1, including a new dungeon, Operation: Floodgate, which'll see players racing to stop a group of goblins from blowing up a dam that would bring ruin to the Ringing Deeps. This'll be immediately available as part of Season 2's dungeon pool, alongside four other launch dungeons and three returning legacy dungeons - including Motherlode from Battle for Azeroth. There's also a new arena PvP map set in the heart of the city, plus an eight-boss raid zone - The Liberation of Undermine - taking players through the city's streets and into the colourful but deadly Gallagio, where its owner, Gallywix, awaits.
</p>
<figure>

</figure>
<p>
Undermined's most notable addition, however, is the introduction of cars, which players will earn early on in their quest, enabling them to barrel through Undermine's streets "much, much faster" than a regular ground mount would allow. Better yet, car characteristics - grip, drift, acceleration, top speed, and so on - can all be customised to suit players' tastes.
</p>
<p>
Blizzard has plenty more planned for World of Warcraft in 2025, of course, with its roadmap outlining various new content drops as the year continues. That includes the MMO's next expansion, World of Warcraft: Midnight, which continues the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/world-of-warcrafts-the-war-within-expansion-kickstarts-worldsoul-saga-next-year">Worldsoul Saga</a> started in The War Within. And while Blizzard is mostly keeping tightlipped about Midnight for now, it <em>has</em> teased - via its favoured medium of <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fQXHFrLX6A4">cinematic reveal trailer</a> - the introduction of player houses. It'll likely be some time, however, before it's ready to share more.
</p><p>
In other Warcraft news, Blizzard has <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/blizzards-warcraft-1-2-remasters-are-official-and-out-now-on-pc">announced remasters of Warcraft 1 and 2</a>, which real-time strategy fans can purchase via - either on their own or as part of a new $39.99 USD Battle Chest bundle containing <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/warcraft-iii-reforged">Warcraft 3: Reforged</a> - starting today.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Blizzard Shadow Drops Warcraft 1 and 2 Remasters for 30th Anniversary]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/blizzard-shadow-drops-warcraft-1-and-2-remasters-for-30th-anniversary/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/blizzard-shadow-drops-warcraft-1-and-2-remasters-for-30th-anniversary.1035210/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/blizzard-shadow-drops-warcraft-1-and-2-remasters-for-30th-anniversary/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>In a rather surprising turn of events, in celebration of Warcraft’s 30th anniversary, Blizzard unveiled and surprise launched remasters of Warcraft 1 and Warcraft 2, which are available on Battle.net at this very moment. If you want to purchase the entire collection, you can score Warcraft Remastered, Warcraft 2 Remastered, and Warcraft 3 Reforged for $39.99 in a unique Battle Chest. Oh, and if you buy now, you’ll also receive Warcraft Orcs &amp; Humans, Warcraft 3 Reforged multiplayer hero skins, and the World of Warcraft Meat Wagon mount, akin to a siege weapon with massive, bloody spikes on its front, rear, and wheels.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Warcraft Remastered Battle Chest Launch Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ryZ2jiW95qo?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>The surprise shadow drop of both Warcraft remasters occurs alongside the announcement that, after two decades, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/after-20-years-world-of-warcraft-is-getting-player-housing/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">World of Warcraft is finally getting player housing</a> in its upcoming expansion, Midnight. However, it’s still a year or two away from launch. But for now, if you pick up the Warcraft Battle Chest, you’ll find yourself with plenty of real-time strategy goodness to sift through before then.</p>



<p>For now, let’s focus on Warcraft Remastered and Warcraft 2 Remastered. For starters, Brad Chan, senior manager of Warcraft RTS, said:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>These remasters have brand new hand drawn visuals that capture the original art style from each game, and you’ll be able to swap between the original graphics and the remastered versions in real time.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>The remasters feature UI and UX improvements, making both real-time strategy games more accessible to modern audiences. Alongside the remasters, Warcraft 3: Reforged Patch 2.0 is on its way, featuring an environment and lighting overhaul, and improvements to the user interface. Oh, and there are uprezzed HD assets.</p>



<p>Is Warcraft a little too old for your tastes? Let us know if you’re hopping into the remastered RTS trilogy this week with the Battle Chest by visiting us on the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>It wasn’t long ago that Blizzard took the stage at BlizzCon 2023 to announce <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-worldsoul-saga-warcraft/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">20 more years of World of Warcraft with the Worldsoul Saga</a>!</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GOG’s new preservation program intends to  keep classic games playable ‘forever’]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/13/24295683/gog-preservation-program-pc-game-drm</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gog%E2%80%99s-new-preservation-program-intends-to-keep-classic-games-playable-%E2%80%98forever%E2%80%99.1035198/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/13/24295683/gog-preservation-program-pc-game-drm<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>PC game platform GOG has launched a new preservation program dedicated to keeping beloved older games playable, “now and in the future.”</p><p>“If a game is part of the Preservation Program, it means that we commit our own resources to maintaining its compatibility with modern and future systems,” <a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=1025X1701640&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.gog.com%2Fblog%2Fthe-gog-preservation-program%2F">the announcement blog reads.</a></p><p>The program is launching with 100 games including <em>Diablo</em>, <em>System Shock 2</em>, and <em>Resident Evil 1-3</em>, with GOG planning to add emore titles in the coming months. Games featured in the program will come with a number of perks. GOG says that when you buy a game from the program, you can:</p><div><ul><li>“expect it to work on current and&nbsp;future&nbsp;popular PC configurations”</li><li>“be sure that this version is the best and most complete available anywhere, including compatibility, manuals, and other bonus content, but also DLCs and even features that are missing in other editions”</li><li>“access GOG’s Tech Support if you encounter technical issues with running the game”</li><li>“as with all titles in our catalog, always keep access to their offline installers, granting you the power to safeguard them how you want”</li></ul></div><p>GOG says that its goal is to acquire “all games no longer updated or maintained by their original publisher,” no matter their age. A recent study from the Video Game History Foundation found that 87 percent of games released before 2010 <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/7/14/23792586/classic-game-preservation-video-game-history-foundation-esa">are no longer able to played</a>. These figures are exacerbated by the trend of <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/7/24290671/sega-classic-games-delisted">delisting classic games from storefronts</a> or <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/3/26/23657431/wii-u-nintendo-3ds-eshops-shut-down">shutting</a> <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/7/29/24208627/the-xbox-360-store-shuts-down-today">down</a> entire storefronts altogether. Even new games are subject to inaccessibility with Sony’s <em>Concord</em> <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/29/24282900/sony-shutting-down-concord-firewalk-studios">going permanently offline</a> mere weeks after its launch earlier this year.</p><p>With the launch of this preservation program, GOG is one of the only major game platforms to directly acknowledge the grim reality of video game preservation while taking significant action to keep older games accessible. </p><p>“Games shaped us,” reads the announcement. “Being able to play them is an essential part of reconnecting with ourselves. They must stay accessible, playable, and alive.”</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Overwatch Players, Y’all Lived Like This In 2016?]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-classic-6v6-event-dates-no-limits-tank-1851697905</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/overwatch-players-y%E2%80%99all-lived-like-this-in-2016.1035159/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-classic-6v6-event-dates-no-limits-tank-1851697905<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>I started playing <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-anniversary-pve-story-events-skins-shop-1851665897&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-anniversary-pve-story-events-skins-shop-1851665897"><em>Overwatch</em></a></span><em> </em>in 2019. By the time I was pushing payloads and getting Play of the Game with a well-placed Tactical Visor, a lot of the old hero kits and team compositions that were infamous when the hero shooter launched in 2016 were more like cautionary tales for relative newbies. But since I never experienced things like Mercy being able to revive her entire team with a press of the triangle button, I was excited to see what I missed thanks to the current <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-classic-blizzard-6v6-tanks-event-dates-1851694954&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-classic-blizzard-6v6-tanks-event-dates-1851694954"><em>Overwatch Classic </em>mode</a></span>, which lets you play as the original versions of the 21-hero roster from 2016. However, even though there are still a few weeks left before the event ends on December 3, I played it for one night and…I think I’m done. I cannot believe y’all had the patience to play this game for thousands of hours eight years ago.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196880" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Ranking Overwatch 2 Season 10's Biggest Changes" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="218" data-playlist="196880,195460,196049" data-current="196880"><div><p>Ranking Overwatch 2 Season 10's Biggest Changes</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196880/196880_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196880/196880_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196880/196880_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196880/196880_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/22434.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>To be clear, a lot of my immediate aversion to <em>Overwatch Classic </em>likely comes from jumping into the shooter after Blizzard had spent years balancing and fine-tuning it. Some of the problems I have with the game would have been less damning if I’d jumped in when it was an exciting, brand-new thing that was fresh and hadn’t yet been sanded down by patches and ruleset changes. There’s something endearing about how unpolished <em>Overwatch Classic </em>feels. I imagine that back in 2016, it felt like there was so much potential for this universe and these heroes. If I’d been playing the game since launch, I think that feeling of potential is what I’d feel more nostalgic for, rather than the actual nuts and bolts of how <em>Overwatch </em>used to play.</p><p>The first match I played was against a team of three Roadhogs. I didn’t realize the “No Limits” setting that lets you and your team all pick the same character was in effect, meaning you could have teams made up of bulky tanks that would basically be immovable bullet sponges. These days, <em>Overwatch 2 </em>has limits that require you to play as different heroes, and in some modes your composition has to include an allotted number of characters per role. But it was the wild west in 2016 and people could create teams of all one hero if they wanted. And reader, that’s what my friends and I were up against. I thought I was gonna bust a blood vessel when I, as Soldier: 76, ran up the hill of the Hollywood map only to be greeted by a team of six Meis.</p><p>Mei, for those unfamiliar with her original kit, was able to freeze an enemy in their tracks with her primary fire. Her icy beam starts with a slowing effect that keeps you in place until the frozen status takes hold, giving the hero an easy opening to pop a headshot. That’s manageable when you’re facing one of her, but when it’s six? I effectively wasn’t playing for swaths of the match thanks to their icy assault, and even as we slowly but surely made progress on the objective, the opposing team didn’t change things up. It was just a constant barrage of ice keeping all of us in place.</p><p>I’m sure this was a funny bit for the opposing team, but I can’t imagine putting in the 1000+ hours I have in the game now if that’s what the game was like. What drew me to <em>Overwatch </em>in the first place was how heroes synergize, and facing opponents who have free reign to make a team of unkillable, self-healing tanks or the <em>Overwatch </em>equivalent of an Elsa snowstorm is the kind of thing that would have killed my enthusiasm for the game early on.</p><p>I’ve seen comments from the <em>Overwatch </em>community joking that the <em>Overwatch Classic </em>event is just reverse psychology to make people realize how good we’ve got it with <em>Overwatch 2</em>, and after playing the throwback mode for a night, I think I could be convinced of that. So much of <em>Overwatch </em>discourse is “make it like it used to be,” whether that be bringing back loot boxes instead of the battle pass it uses now, reverting to the 6v6 format instead of the current-day 5v5 structure, or going back to a previous rework for a character who doesn’t play like they once did. The original <em>Overwatch </em>was slower-paced, and playing it again after years of <em>Overwatch 2 </em>making the game feel more frantic is like suddenly getting caught in a fly trap. It’s a fun gimmick that’s brought back lapsed fans jonesing for the old days. But by and large, it’s been a reminder that sometimes parts of a game do get mechanically better over time and that maybe we’re not nostalgic for the game as it was, but the feeling we had when playing it.</p><p>I played a night of <em>Overwatch Classic </em>and I think I’ve had my fill. I missed all the characters I main that have been added since 2016 and all the balance and ruleset tweaks that have made matches feel less like chaotic shitposts. I don’t have much opinion on whether or not 6v6 should come back, but I do know that I’m more intrigued by <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-6v6-test-season-14-open-role-queue-date-1851680742&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-6v6-test-season-14-open-role-queue-date-1851680742">the plans Blizzard has laid out</a></span> for reintegrating that original ruleset than the free-for-all we once had. </p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Warcraft 30th Anniversary Direct: Everything Announced]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/warcraft-30th-anniversary-direct-everything-announced</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/warcraft-30th-anniversary-direct-everything-announced.1035150/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/warcraft-30th-anniversary-direct-everything-announced<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Blizzard just wrapped up its Warcraft 30th Anniversary Direct, a nearly hour-long presentation featuring numerous updates from across the Warcraft franchise - almost like a miniature BlizzCon. We heard about World of Warcraft’s next major update, a tease for its next expansion, new updates for World of Warcraft Classic, some long-awaited remasters, and planned updates for both Hearthstone and Warcraft Rumble.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">If you missed the Direct, don’t worry, we’ve got you covered. Here’s everything Blizzard showed at its Warcraft 30th Anniversary Direct today:</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><h3 data-cy="title3">World of Warcraft: The War Within next major update unveiled</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">First up, retail World of Warcraft, which is currently near the end of the first major story beat of the expansion The War Within. Today, we got a look at the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/world-of-warcrafts-next-major-patch-will-finally-visit-the-legendary-goblin-capital-undermine">first major patch of the expansion</a>, entitled “Undermine(d)”, which will take players into the underground goblin capital of Undermine for the first time ever. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The patch, which is planned for early next year, will include a new customizable vehicle, new story, a new arena map, a new dungeon, two new delves, a new raid, and a number of other updates. You can read more about everything planned for 11.1, Undermine(d), right here.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><h3 data-cy="title3">World of Warcraft: Midnight will feature player housing at last</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">At the very end of the presentation, Blizzard gave us a surprising “one more thing” tease of its next planned expansion: Midnight. Though Midnight is still a long ways away, today we <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/world-of-warcrafts-next-expansion-finally-adding-player-housing-after-years-of-requests-by-fans">learned that it will include a long-requested feature: player housing</a>. No details were provided on this in today’s presentation, but we’re expecting to hear more late next summer when Blizzard fully unveils Midnight to the world.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><h3 data-cy="title3">World of Warcraft: Classic is headed to Pandaria</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">As expected, World of Warcraft Classic continues apace through the expansions, with Blizzard announcing that it will be <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/world-of-warcraft-classic-heads-to-mists-of-pandaria-next-year">moving to Mists of Pandaria in 2025</a>. But for those who might be frustrated with Classic seemingly racing to catch up with retail through World of Warcraft’s expansion history, Blizzard is also dropping new “vanilla” Classic realms on November 21. The realms will include fresh PvE, PvP, and Hardcore servers, all of which will slowly progress through Classic’s cadence of updates, with the Molten Core raid opening a few weeks after their launch. In addition, the PvE and PvP realms (sorry, Hardcore) will eventually move into The Burning Crusade Classic, starting the expansion progression all over again.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><h3 data-cy="title3">Warcraft I and II are being remastered</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">To kick off today’s presentation, Blizzard <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/warcraft-1-and-2-remasters-shadow-dropped-with-improved-graphics-quality-of-life-improvements-and-other-new-features">announced it would be shadow-dropping remasters of both Warcraft I and II today</a>. They’re remasters, not remakes, and will include fully remastered graphics as well as a number of quality of life features. Warcraft II specifically will include multiplayer, and all legacy custom maps will be compatible and playable.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In addition, Blizzard is releasing a new patch for Warcraft III: Reforged that includes a graphics overhaul and various other quality of life changes that will hopefully improve the experience. And all three games will be available as part of a Battle Chest, with flexible pricing based on which games you already have in your library.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><h3 data-cy="title3">Hearthstone is getting a crossover with…Starcraft?!</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">Over in the tavern, we got a look at Hearthstone’s upcoming roadmap for 2025. And Hearthstone is starting the new year with a crossover with another Blizzard property: Starcraft.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">2025 will start with a mini set themed around StarCraft, featuring themes and powers unique to all three StarCraft factions: Protoss, Zerg, and Terran. This will be followed by the first 2025 expansion, themed around the Emerald Dream, followed by a return to Un’Goro Crater for The Shrouded City expansion. Hearthstone will wrap up the year in a time-themed expansion called The Heroes of Time, featuring everyone’s favorite time traveler, Chromie.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><h3 data-cy="title3">Warcraft Rumble is coming to PC</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">Warcraft Rumble will soon introduce new split faction leaders in a new update. These leaders belong to two families simultaneously, instead of just one. Newly-added split faction leaders will include Orgrim Doomhammer, Malfurion Stormrage, and Anub’arak, while other characters such as Sylvanas will gain a second faction in addition to their current one.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">But most importantly, mobile game Warcraft Rumble is celebrating its first birthday by breaking free of the confines of our phones. Blizzard announced today that it’s coming to PC soon, with a beta launching on December 10th.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Rebekah Valentine is a senior reporter for IGN. You can find her posting on BlueSky @duckvalentine.bsky.social. Got a story tip? Send it to rvalentine@ign.com.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>