<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 13:44:21 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Samsung added AI upscaling to its new OLED gaming monitor]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2024/6/4/24171076/samsung-odyssey-oled-g8-gaming-monitor-ai-upscaling-price</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/samsung-added-ai-upscaling-to-its-new-oled-gaming-monitor.889062/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/2024/6/4/24171076/samsung-odyssey-oled-g8-gaming-monitor-ai-upscaling-price<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Samsung has added some additional features to the new OLED G8 gaming monitor it <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/1/3/24023513/samsung-ces-2024-gaming-monitors-odyssey-oled-g6-g8-g9">announced back in January</a>, including safeguards against OLED burn-in and AI-powered resolution upscaling for content and games.</p><p>Preorders for the display are already available in regions like Australia and Singapore, suggesting that a US launch isn’t far behind. Best Buy lists the 32-inch Odyssey OLED G8 <a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/samsung-32-odyssey-oled-g8-g80sd-4k-uhd-240hz-0-03ms-smart-gaming-monitor-with-hdr-silver/6573686.p?skuId=6573686&amp;intl=nosplash">(model G80SD) for $1,299.99</a> — making it a smidge cheaper than the first <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/2/6/23586882/samsung-odyssey-oled-g8-display-price-preorder-specs">$1,499.99 OLED gaming monitor Samsung released last year</a> — and Samsung currently has a countdown timer teasing its “<a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/monitors/2024-monitors-lineup/">new 2024 monitors</a>,” which expires today at 9:59AM ET. We’ve asked Samsung to clarify the release dates for the Odyssey OLED G8 but haven’t yet heard back.</p><p>Samsung says the G80SD model is its first AI-powered gaming monitor, featuring the same NQ8 AI Gen3 processor as its recently released <a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/tvs/neoqled-tv/">2024 Neo QLED 8K TV</a>. That chip is behind the monitor’s AI-upscaling capabilities, according to Samsung, which enables content and games to be upscaled to almost 4K when run through the monitor’s built-in smart TV apps and Gaming Hub, respectively.</p><div><div><figcaption><em>The slim metal design is, to my eye, unchanged since it was first announced in January.</em></figcaption> <p><cite>Image: Samsung</cite></p></div><div><figcaption><em>Here’s the view from the back, showing the monitor’s ports and RGB lighting.</em></figcaption> <p><cite>Image: Samsung</cite></p></div></div><p>The company has also updated the G80SD’s cooling system to mitigate OLED burn-in, adding a proprietary “pulsating heat pipe” to the monitor, which Samsung says is five times more effective at diffusing heat than the graphite sheet method it was previously using. The monitor also detects and automatically reduces the brightness of static images like taskbars or heads-up displays in games.</p><p>The G8’s remaining specifications — such as its flat display, 3840 x 2160 resolution, 240Hz refresh rate, and 16:9 aspect ratio — are otherwise identical to what was <a href="https://news.samsung.com/us/samsung-expands-odyssey-gaming-monitor-lineup-new-oled-models-ces-2024/">already announced ahead of CES 2024</a>. Samsung says the monitor can deliver 250 nits of peak brightness and supports FreeSync Premium Pro to help reduce screen lag and screen tearing.</p><p>Resolution upscaling has been available in TVs and <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/26/21402819/nvidia-shield-tv-update-4k-upscaling-remote-customize">streaming devices</a> for some time now, but I'm still curious to see how well it performs built into a gaming-focused monitor. As <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/1/7/23543021/oled-monitors-tvs-gaming-office-desk-ces-2023">OLED gaming displays especially</a> keep growing in popularity, the feature could help Samsung’s latest offering stand out against the competition — provided people actually want to use it.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[They have been racing for a month]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/they-have-been-racing-for-a-month</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/they-have-been-racing-for-a-month.889056/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/they-have-been-racing-for-a-month<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/trackmania-deep-dip-2-tower-wirtual-5.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Rock Paper Shotgun / Ubisoft</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>It's been one month since the sound of engines began. The <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/these-racing-game-players-are-11-days-into-an-exhausting-race-to-climb-a-deadly-tower">hardest track ever created in Trackmania</a> was published by a team of mappers on May 4th, bringing an intimidating 16-floor tower called Deep Dip 2 into the racing game. It became a magnet for competitive drivers after a prize pool of over $30,000 was offered to the first three players to conquer its hellish heights. The prize has yet to be claimed. Even today, determined racers continue to bang their heads against the brutally designed course, featuring icy surfaces, curving rails, and perilous loop-the-loops that hang kilometres about the ground. Some players have parked their hopes and given up. But others persevere. The top three players have reached the final floor and currently stand shoulder to shoulder, eyes focused on the prize.

<!--more-->
</p><p>At the time of writing, the remaining competitors are warring it out at a particular spot on floor 16, tantalisingly close to the finish line. To proceed, they have to perform a nigh-impossible trick that involves <a href="https://www.twitch.tv/videos/2163059065?t=03h44m26s">crawling along a vertical surface on two wheels</a>. It is disgusting. The three players currently in the running are "Larstm", "Hazardu", and "BrenTM" - whose <a href="https://deepdip2.com/leaderboard">personal bests</a> now all stand within a couple of metres of each other.</p>
<p>One racer who has bowed out of the contest is  Øyvind "Wirtual" Iversen, a prominent Trackmania speedster who got as far as floor 14, a hefty achievement in itself. </p>
<p>"It sorta gets to the point where the way we're playing the map now, we just have to drive for half an hour," says Iversen in <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CxCzLV1pyUs&amp;t=1s">a video</a> where he explains the reasons he is throwing in the towel. "Half an hour of perfect driving without falling just to explore the hardest floor. And it feels very unrewarding in that sense.</p>
<p>"The map I think is too difficult. The difficult floors should be earlier in the map because this way of exploring is so taxing... This is the type of map that you need the determination and iron will of, like, a god. Seriously."</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/trackmania-deep-dip-2-tower-wirtual-1.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Rock Paper Shotgun / Ubisoft</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>He also admits that, as a YouTuber, he can't do the same thing over and over again and expect viewers to keep tuning in. That, and normal life must go on. "If I keep playing Deep Dip now," he says, "it'll be destructive to the rest of my life."</p>
<p>But Iversen also encourages people to support the remaining drivers.

</p><p>"I am so incredibly impressed with their progress," said Iversen, "and you only get such a huge respect for this the more you play the map... It's completely bewildering to me."</p>
<p>Iversen once <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oVzsVE60uqU&amp;t=3s">beat Trackmania blindfolded</a>. When someone like that nopes out of a challenge, you know it's a tortuously difficult task. Yet the end is in sight and, barring some Sisyphean nightmare trap metres before the finish line, one of the remaining contestants is sure to take the prize money any day. </p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Like a Dragon: Yakuza is Amazon’s Fallout follow-up — and it drops in October]]></title>
            <link>https://www.polygon.com/24171051/like-a-dragon-yakuza-show-amazon-prime-video-release-date</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/like-a-dragon-yakuza-is-amazon%E2%80%99s-fallout-follow-up-%E2%80%94-and-it-drops-in-october.889053/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.polygon.com/24171051/like-a-dragon-yakuza-show-amazon-prime-video-release-date<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  <p id="CHhuIK">After the huge success of its <a href="https://www.polygon.com/24122477/fallout-tv-series-review-prime-video-show"><em>Fallout </em>series</a>, Amazon has moved quickly to follow it up with another video game adaptation. <em>Like a Dragon: Yakuza</em>, a live-action Japanese production based on Sega’s long-running series of gangster soaps, drops on Prime Video worldwide on Oct. 25, 2024.</p>
<p id="WcxrEy">Well, half of it does, anyway. It’s a six-episode series, to be released in two chunks: the first three episodes on Oct. 25 and the next three on Nov. 1.</p>
<p id="q4ZMwj">The show follows series protagonist Kazuma Kiryu and his friends across two time periods, in 1995 and 2005 — suggesting an adaptation of the first game, which came out in 2005 and followed Kazuma after he was released from a 10-year prison sentence. Kazuma is played by Ryoma Takeuchi, star of the <em>Kamen Rider Drive </em>series. The series is directed by Masaharu Take, with a story by Sean Crouch and Nakamura Yugo, and a Japanese screenplay by Yoshida Yasuhiro and Yamada Kana.</p>
<p id="WWlgej">Amazon describes the show as “an original crime-suspense-action series” that “follows the life, childhood friends, and repercussions of the decisions of Kazuma Kiryu, a fearsome and peerless Yakuza warrior with a strong sense of justice, duty, and humanity.”</p>
<p id="EsdZPD">“Audience will enjoy the show’s human drama and conflict that unfolds around Kazuma Kiryu,” Takeuchi said in a statement. “Moreover, please take a look Kiryu’s intense fighting scenes with the Dragon tattoo on his back.” </p>
<p id="rmbOkf">Reading between the lines, it seems like Amazon has swooped in to acquire an already-filmed independent Japanese production, which explains why the show’s release is only a few months away. Amazon’s streaming muscle and deep pockets mean the show gets a simultaneous worldwide release, supported by subtitling and/or dubbing in 30 languages.</p>
<p id="k7Wafr">Given not just the success of <em>Fallout</em> and HBO’s <em>The Last of Us </em>but the acclaim and ratings bestowed on FX’s mostly Japanese-language <a href="https://www.polygon.com/24138469/shogun-finale-review-war-toranaga-explained-episode"><em>Shōgun</em></a>, this seems like a clever, opportunistic move from Amazon. To the point: “The unfettered appeal for Japanese content from within Japan and other parts of the world has been growing exponentially,” said James Farrell, head of international originals at Amazon MGM studios.</p>
<p id="OWPSPq">It’s not the first adaptation the Yakuza series has had, though — the first game was adapted into <a href="https://www.polygon.com/what-to-watch/23196727/best-video-game-movies-adaptations-tv-watch-streaming">a typically anarchic movie by Takashi Miike</a> in 2007.</p>
  
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Star Wars Hotel Failure Was Just A Real-Life Bad Video Game Launch]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/jenny-nicholson-star-wars-hotel-youtube-review-1851517079</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-star-wars-hotel-failure-was-just-a-real-life-bad-video-game-launch.889050/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/jenny-nicholson-star-wars-hotel-youtube-review-1851517079<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Unless you’ve been living under a rock on Exegol for the last month, you’ve probably heard of YouTuber <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=T0CpOYZZZW4&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=T0CpOYZZZW4" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Jenny Nicholson’s viral, four-hour-long video</a></span> reviewing the <em>Star Wars</em> hotel, officially known as <em>Star Wars</em>: Galactic Starcruiser. Titled “The Spectacular Failure of the <em>Star Wars </em>Hotel,” it goes into excruciating detail about why the immersive (and expensive) experience went off like a Wookie fart in the Jedi Temple. Throughout the video, there are obvious parallels to recent, spectacularly bad video game launches centered around popular IP, like <em>Suicide Squad: Kill the Justice League</em> and <em>Marvel’s Avengers</em>. It’s almost as if no amount of lucrative lore can save something when it’s rushed or half-assed, am I right?<br></p><p><em>Star Wars</em>: Galactic Starcruiser opened on March 1, 2022 and permanently closed a year and a half later in September, 2023. The “immersive” experience required guests to stay there for two nights—no more, no less. (Nicholson’s stay cost just over $3,000 per person, though the lowest possible option was $1,209 per person.) During your stay, you spend almost the entire time “on” the Starcruiser, which promised wild views of space you could glimpse through its fake windows, and an excursion to Disney’s <em>Star Wars</em> world, aka Galaxy’s Edge. “Immersion” was the big promise here—you’d get pulled into your own unique storyline that was meant to seamlessly weave into other guests’ storylines as well as those of the cast members working at the hotel, like a real-world RPG. If you wanted to turn it into a proper LARPing (live action role playing) experience, you could even wear full <em>Star Wars</em> attire while staying there. </p><div data-video-id="196653" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="The Week In Games: A Star Wars Classic Returns &amp; More New Releases" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="105" data-playlist="196653,195840,196049" data-current="196653"><div><p>The Week In Games: A Star Wars Classic Returns &amp; More New Releases</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196653/196653_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196653/196653_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196653/196653_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196653/196653_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/22209.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><p>The experience proved lackluster for the price point, and thus the Galactic Starcruiser closed last year. Jenny Nicholson exhumed its corpse in her May 18 video, opening the floodgates for derision from fans, a litany of memes, and even a weird, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://screenrant.com/star-wars-galactic-starcruiser-hotel-what-everyone-gets-wrong/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://screenrant.com/star-wars-galactic-starcruiser-hotel-what-everyone-gets-wrong/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">PR-heavy <em>ScreenRant</em> article from a former Starcruiser employee</a></span>.<br></p><p>There are so many details packed into this YouTube video (which is roughly the length of <em>A New Hope</em> and <em>Empire Strikes Back</em> combined), that I couldn’t even approach properly covering it, but there are some really stark parallels to poorly received video games that stand out, from the bugged quest lines to the bevy of microtransactions that serve as a reminder of the perils of putting all your eggs in one IP basket. </p><figure id="" data-id="91ebc643fee28507b410fba8dc4dc50b" data-recommend-id="image://91ebc643fee28507b410fba8dc4dc50b" data-format="jpg" data-width="800" data-height="450" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Galactic Starcruiser concept art shows a busy lobby full of aliens, robots, Stormtroopers, and more. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Galactic Starcruiser concept art shows a busy lobby full of aliens, robots, Stormtroopers, and more. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Disney / Lucasfilm</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="91ebc643fee28507b410fba8dc4dc50b" data-recommend-id="image://91ebc643fee28507b410fba8dc4dc50b" data-format="jpg" data-width="800" data-height="450" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Galactic Starcruiser concept art shows a busy lobby full of aliens, robots, Stormtroopers, and more. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><h2 id="h40056"><a id=""></a><strong>The <em>Star Wars</em> hotel: expectations vs reality</strong></h2><p>First, there’s the stark contrast between concept art and reality. Concept art is just that—a concept, so while there’s some expectation that the final product will at least resemble the concept art, it’s not something that can make or break a video game or a real-world experience. Except, that is, when the wonder and promise of the concept art dwarfs the reality of the final product, or when things from that concept art are excised from the final product entirely. Both of those things happened at the <em>Star Wars</em> hotel.<br></p><p>All of the concept art for the Galactic Starcruiser showed that the common areas would be bustling hives filled with space citizens and droids, while giant windows offered a breathtaking look out into space. As Nicholson shows in her video, the lobby of the hotel has a few tiny windows that are <em>way </em>up high on the walls, far enough away to avoid close inspection, and nowhere near eye-level. Meanwhile, the space station-themed restaurant in Epcot has a ton of gigantic fake windows looking out into virtual space.<br></p><p>Things were clearly rushed or cut here. There was one droid roaming around amongst hotel guests, not several skittering around the space. There were a few actors in alien makeup, not a ton. Many times the actors and droids appeared in balcony in the lobby that was inaccessible to guests. </p><p> Nicholson even points out the rooms were needlessly small—as this isn’t a real cruise ship of the sea or the stars, there’s no similar size restrictions Disney had to stay within—likely to cut costs so that the company could maximize its profits.</p><figure id="" data-id="6a181ec2b8f2ced5a20128dc20889b33" data-recommend-id="image://6a181ec2b8f2ced5a20128dc20889b33" data-format="jpg" data-width="800" data-height="450" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="More concept art of the Star Wars hotel. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="More concept art of the Star Wars hotel. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Disney / Lucasfilm</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="6a181ec2b8f2ced5a20128dc20889b33" data-recommend-id="image://6a181ec2b8f2ced5a20128dc20889b33" data-format="jpg" data-width="800" data-height="450" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="More concept art of the Star Wars hotel. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><h2 id="h40057"><a id=""></a><strong>The <em>Star Wars</em> hotel’s microtransactions</strong></h2><p>The astronomical cost of staying at the <em>Star Wars</em> hotel was already a problem, but when you add on the lack of transparency around pricing (as Nicholson explained, folks had to call a number to book their stay, and could only get a sense of the range of possible prices by comparing notes) and the tons of other, pay-walled experiences the hotel offered, I am violently reminded of the gaming industry’s <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/live-service-games-95-studios-destiny-suicide-squad-1851221959&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/live-service-games-95-studios-destiny-suicide-squad-1851221959">love affair with live-service games and microtransactions</a></span>.<br></p><p>At the <em>Star Wars</em> hotel, you could upgrade your seat during dinner time to the “Captain’s Table,” for $30 per person. You could pay $169 for the Memory Maker package, which ensured that the roaming photographers would snap pictures of you living this immersive experience and that you had access to unlimited downloads of those photos. You could also pay $399 for a half-hour private photo shoot, but this package was added at a later date, and appears to have negatively affected those who bought the original, $169 Memory Maker tier, as Nicholson claims she saw no roaming photographers during her stay—apparently now too busy covering the private photo shoots.<br></p><p>And, as Nicholson points out, though your stay at the hotel would get you seven hours of time in the Disney parks, there were tons of paid add-ons that were <em>not </em>included: lightsaber building ($220), droid building ($100), or a table at Oga’s Cantina (food and drink not included). The Galactic Starcruiser staff also suggested people arrive the night before their stay so that they wouldn’t miss out on any of the activities—another hidden cost.<br></p><p>All of this is reminiscent of the recent, worrying trend: full-priced video games being released that are littered with microtransactions. This is different from free-to-play titles like <em>Fortnite</em> or <em>Overwatch</em>, which are also littered with microtransactions but at least allow you to get your foot in the door for free. The exorbitant pricing of the <em>Star Wars</em> hotel and its equally pricy add-ons is a direct parallel to AAA games charging the new $70 norm just to offer you even more crap to spend your hard-earned money on.<br></p><p>Like <em>Suicide Squad: Kill the Justice League</em>. Though it was developed by <em>Batman Arkham </em>studio Rocksteady, it adopted the microtransaction trend: You’d have to spend $70 to buy the game (<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/suicide-squad-kill-justice-server-offline-major-bug-1851205221&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/suicide-squad-kill-justice-server-offline-major-bug-1851205221">which launched in a fairly broken state</a></span>), and if you wanted to unlock its new characters you have to grind its battle pass—or pay up.<br></p><p>Or what about <em>Diablo 4</em>, another full-priced game that <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/diablo-4-shop-cosmetic-armor-mounts-microtransactions-1850498188&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/diablo-4-shop-cosmetic-armor-mounts-microtransactions-1850498188">offered $25 armor sets</a></span>, a <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/diablo-4-iv-season-malignant-battle-pass-platinum-1850671621&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/diablo-4-iv-season-malignant-battle-pass-platinum-1850671621">battle pass that many considered at one point to be “stingy</a></span>,” and a <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/diablo-4-dlc-30-portal-colors-bundle-blizzard-1851252883&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/diablo-4-dlc-30-portal-colors-bundle-blizzard-1851252883">fast-travel portal that cost you $30</a></span>?<br></p><p>Or how about the <em>NBA 2K</em> games, which are also not free-to-play and which, at one point, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/nba-2k23-durag-microtransaction-vc-finders-keepers-1849640528&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/nba-2k23-durag-microtransaction-vc-finders-keepers-1849640528">charged $5 for virtual durag</a></span>s (when IRL ones cost you about $3). The <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/surprise-nba-2k20-is-still-full-of-bullshit-microtrans-1838000636&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/surprise-nba-2k20-is-still-full-of-bullshit-microtrans-1838000636"><em>NBA 2K </em>games have historically relied heavily on players buying its VC</a></span> (virtual currency) to unlock animations, buy virtual cards to flesh out their fantasy teams, or increase their players’ stats.<br></p><p>Ultimately, these secondary costs feel like highway robbery when you’re already shelling out for the base experience—just like the <em>Star Wars</em> hotel. Nicholson makes a parallel with the notoriously cheap, paid-option-heavy Spirit Airlines, which is still usually a pretty economical way to fly, but can feel more grating because it explicitly charges you for amenities that other airlines bake into the cost of your ticket. Nicholson asks you to imagine Disney’s “immersive” hotel experience is like if Spirit Airlines “actually cost more…and all those amenities still cost extra.”</p><figure id="" data-id="ecb48e871e842a4180bbbea90095e36c" data-recommend-id="image://ecb48e871e842a4180bbbea90095e36c" data-format="jpg" data-width="800" data-height="450" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Concept art shows parents and their kids standing in a Star Wars hotel room." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Concept art shows parents and their kids standing in a Star Wars hotel room." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Disney / Lucasfilm</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="ecb48e871e842a4180bbbea90095e36c" data-recommend-id="image://ecb48e871e842a4180bbbea90095e36c" data-format="jpg" data-width="800" data-height="450" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Concept art shows parents and their kids standing in a Star Wars hotel room." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><h2 id="h40058"><a id=""></a><strong>The <em>Star Wars</em> hotel’s bugged quests</strong></h2><p>For the marketing push leading up to the opening of the Galactic Starcruiser, Disney released a few Imagineer roundtables that delved deeper into what guests could expect. As Nicholson points out, one of those roundtables suggested you’d be able to “help someone stow away” or break someone out of the brig, or run into a “galactic superstar” during your stay. One video even suggested that there was a “love story” on board.<br></p><p>Nicholson’s video lays out how the RPG elements of the Starcruiser worked: the cast (which included a Togrutan, a Twi-Lek, and a Rodian) were the NPCs of this world, and an app that you had to use on your phone let you “communicate” with these characters and others. Those characters would “text” you via the app, and you could reply by choosing a few pre-written options.<br></p><p>There were rumors swirling that the Radio Frequency Identification (RFID) bracelets all the guests had to wear were somehow transmitting info to the actors, including things like whether you’d responded to a specific character positively in the app, which would, in turn, increase (or decrease) your trust score with them. Yes, this is all exactly like how an RPG works.</p><p>Except it didn’t work.<br></p><p>“The gameplay did not work for us at all,” Nicholson says in her video. “At some point there was some sort of critical logistical failure which broke every aspect of it. I was continually frustrated the entire time I was there and I left extremely disappointed. In our particular experience, none of the actions we took at any point directed the course of our story in any way.”<br></p><p>Oh, and the item collection mechanic (yay, fetch quests!) that the Starcruiser had for guests? “It was bad,” Nicholson says. “It isn’t any fun.” Her video shows several, unsatisfying examples of the Starcruiser’s item collection feature. “The ordinary gameplay is just earning you imaginary currency to spend on nothing,” she says. Hmm...sound familiar?</p><p>Like video games and the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/starfield-beta-test-quest-fix-patch-bugs-1851180926&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/starfield-beta-test-quest-fix-patch-bugs-1851180926">bevy of bugged quests that plagued <em>Starfield</em></a></span> after its launch, or that <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/ff7-ffvii-rebirth-impossible-trophy-side-quest-bug-fix-1851404624&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/ff7-ffvii-rebirth-impossible-trophy-side-quest-bug-fix-1851404624">impossible-to-finish side quest in <em>FF7 Rebirth </em>that necessitated a patch,</a></span> or players getting <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/cyberpunk-2077-new-person-same-old-mistakes-bug-door-1850894905&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/cyberpunk-2077-new-person-same-old-mistakes-bug-door-1850894905">locked out of random side quests in one version of <em>Cyberpunk 2077</em></a></span>, the <em>Star Wars</em> hotel’s quests were fundamentally broken for Nicholson and others. But instead of it just being a few bugged side quests in <em>Fallout 4</em>, the <em>Star Wars</em> hotel’s entire immersive story was broken. Nicholson’s experience was like if you tried to go Renegade in <em>Mass Effect 3 </em>and nothing you did mattered. The story goes on as if you weren’t even there, the Reapers win, Khalisah Bint Sinan al-Jilani never gets punched in the face. Does that sound immersive to you?<br></p><p>Or even remotely fun? They can’t patch this, either. This is a game you spent literal thousands of dollars to play, <em>once</em>.</p><figure id="" data-id="7fea4117daea92cdf546909683dec2a7" data-recommend-id="image://7fea4117daea92cdf546909683dec2a7" data-format="png" data-width="1280" data-height="720" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Star Wars concept art where a person points to a porthole, but Lillith from Diablo 4's face has been Photoshopped in. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Star Wars concept art where a person points to a porthole, but Lillith from Diablo 4's face has been Photoshopped in. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Disney / Lucasfilm</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="7fea4117daea92cdf546909683dec2a7" data-recommend-id="image://7fea4117daea92cdf546909683dec2a7" data-format="png" data-width="1280" data-height="720" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Star Wars concept art where a person points to a porthole, but Lillith from Diablo 4's face has been Photoshopped in. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><h2 id="h40059"><a id=""></a><strong>What have we learned from the failure of the <em>Star Wars</em> hotel?</strong></h2><p>Nicholson’s scathing video is yet another stark example of IP-driven capitalism gone wrong. It’s the heat death of the Marvel Cinematic Universe, the bevy of schlocky, subpar games tied to hugely expensive franchises like <em>Suicide Squad: Kill the Justice League</em> or <em>Gotham Knights—</em>the late-game excisions to rush out a product, the crunch to release something quickly to capitalize on fans’ shifting interests. Corners get cut, original ideas get sanded down until they are barely reminiscent echoes of a much more palpable promise—and you have to pay a premium to experience this smoothness.</p><p>The failure of the <em>Star Wars</em> hotel reminds me of the lead-up to the launch of <em>Starfield</em>: the hype, the deep-dive videos, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/starfield-rpg-planets-xbox-pc-gaming-todd-howard-1850565329&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/starfield-rpg-planets-xbox-pc-gaming-todd-howard-1850565329">the 1,000 planets</a></span> promise, the assurance from Microsoft that this would be <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/starfield-xbox-microsoft-bethesda-rpg-game-pass-1850531802&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/starfield-xbox-microsoft-bethesda-rpg-game-pass-1850531802">“one of the most important RPGs ever made,</a></span>” just for us to get an unsurprising, thoroughly Bethesda experience. Was <em>Starfield</em> an abject failure? No it wasn’t, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/starfield-game-bethesda-xbox-pc-metacritic-reddit-hype-1850819494&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/starfield-game-bethesda-xbox-pc-metacritic-reddit-hype-1850819494">even if it was just <em>Skyrim </em>in space</a></span>—because you weren’t charged $3K to experience it. The <em>Star Wars </em>hotel was an abject failure, because it did not deliver what was promised after you forked over a massive sum of cash.<br></p><p>The rabid <em>Star Wars</em> fan base will pay just about anything for something that feels unique, different, or exclusive, and the Galactic Starcruiser promised just that. But even the types of people who would pay a grand to go on a vacation where they have to pack very little luggage and cram into a small room with four other folks can tell bad value when they see it.<br></p><p>It’s why gamers, despite their affinity for rallying behind all the wrong causes, can at least point to a game that’s riddled with microtransactions, or that launched in a broken state, or that was made on the backs of crunched employees and go, “That’s bad.” And the <em>Star Wars</em> hotel was bad. </p><p>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Following Fallout, Amazon Prime Announces Yakuza TV Series]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/like-a-dragon-yakuza-tv-show-amazon-prime-1851517847</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/following-fallout-amazon-prime-announces-yakuza-tv-series.889047/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/like-a-dragon-yakuza-tv-show-amazon-prime-1851517847<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Amazon Prime clearly knows it’s onto a good thing as it mines the seams of video games for new TV series. <em>Fallout</em>&nbsp;<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/fallout-tv-show-ratings-nielsen-amazon-bluey-netflix-1851470341&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/fallout-tv-show-ratings-nielsen-amazon-bluey-netflix-1851470341">was an astonishing success</a></span> for the streamer, and you can only imagine how many meetings must have been held with every imaginable publisher for the last few months. One winner is Sega, with the announcement of a <em>Yakuza Like a Dragon</em> series due to appear this October.<br></p><div data-video-id="196578" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Total Recall: Why Yakuza Is So Much More Than A Japanese GTA" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="387" data-playlist="196578,194088,196805" data-current="196578"><div><p>Total Recall: Why Yakuza Is So Much More Than A Japanese GTA</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196578/196578_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196578/196578_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196578/196578_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196578/196578_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/22135.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><p>If you’ve ever tried to piece together the history and chronology of Sega’s <em>Yakuza</em> games, you likely still have a headache. Going since 2005's original <em>Yakuza</em>, and most recently releasing its ninth mainline entry, <em>Like A Dragon: Infinite Wealth</em> in January, 2024, the franchise also sports multiple spin-off games, Japanese-only releases, and the inevitable remakes of older games to confuse anyone who isn’t paying close attention. Oh, and yeah, it switched English-language names over the last five years, ditching the <em>Yakuza</em> moniker for <em>Like a Dragon</em> as its official title.</p><p>Amazon Prime’s show is to compromise on that,  titled <em>Like a Dragon: Yakuza</em>, flipping around the ordering of 2019's game name to ensure maximum confusion. However, it’s not the first live-action TV show based on the game, that honor going to 2010's <em>Kurohyō: Ryū ga Gotoku Shinshō </em>based on the PSP spin-off game, airing only in Japan. It then had a sequel based on the following PSP release, <em>Kurohyō 2: Ryū ga Gotoku Ashura hen</em>. You can find it all on YouTube if you look, and it has some powerful soap opera vibes. It’s safe to say Prime’s version will sport a somewhat larger budget.</p><p>Filmed in Japan, and in Japanese, Amazon plans to subtitle <em>and</em> dub the show for international audiences. It will star Ryoma Takeuchi (<em>Kamen Rider: Drive</em>) as lead character Kazuma Kiryu, with direction by Masaharu Take (<em>We Make Antiques</em>) and Kengo Takimoto (<em>Kamen Teacher</em>), in a six-episode show taking place in both 1995 and 2005.</p><p>The storyline, as described by <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://variety.com/2024/tv/news/like-a-dragon-yakuza-live-action-series-sega-game-prime-video-1236024275/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://variety.com/2024/tv/news/like-a-dragon-yakuza-live-action-series-sega-game-prime-video-1236024275/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Variety</em></a></span>, will be “the life, childhood friends and the repercussions of the decisions of a fearsome and peerless Yakuza warrior with a strong sense of justice, duty, and humanity.”</p><p>It appears to have the official seal of approval by the video games’ writer and producer Masayoshi Yokoyama, who has an executive producer credit on the program. While making it clear that he had no desire to rewrite events based on games he’d previously made, he seems very happy with the job done by others. “If I were ever sent to the past through some kind of cosmic joke, this is the experience I’d want to create. If I had to go through the wringer anyhow, I’d want to make the most engaging versions of Kamurochō and Kazuma Kiryu I could —and this show has it all.”</p><p><em>Like A Dragon: Yakuza</em> will be dropped in two three-episode batches, one on October 25, the next on November 1, although there’s no information yet on how long each episode will be.</p><p>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[XDefiant Y1S0.2 Patch Notes]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/xdefiant-patch-y1s02/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/xdefiant-y1s0-2-patch-notes.889041/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/xdefiant-patch-y1s02/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>Here are the XDefiant Y1S0.2 Patch Notes, released on June 4, 2024.</p>



<h2 id="U29jaWFs">Social</h2>



<ul>
<li>While in a party, we now display the most restrictive Crossplay setting among the party members, as it applies to the whole party. Also fixed an issue where party members with differing Crossplay settings couldn’t matchmake.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue with displaying incorrect player names on some Social screens.</li>



<li>Fixed a crash caused by spamming open/close View Party Invites, but who would even do that, calm down.</li>



<li>On consoles, Ubisoft Connect party invites could display as if they were coming from Xbox or PlayStation Network friends. Fixed that, along with some other weird invite-related things.</li>
</ul>



<h2 id="TWlzY2VsbGFuZW91cw==">Miscellaneous</h2>



<ul>
<li>Fixed some missing terrain textures when players joined matches in progress on some maps.</li>



<li>Input-Based Matchmaking setting status now updates correctly after changing it on Xbox.</li>



<li>Fixed a thing on PS5 where people could sneak into places they shouldn’t via PS5 Activities.</li>



<li>Security improvements, various.</li>
</ul>



<p>You can see the official patch notes on the <a href="https://www.ubisoft.com/en-gb/game/xdefiant/news/7uPCH1ds2CjmwkdpRnbqVU" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Ubisoft Blog</a>.</p>



<p>What do you think of XDefiant Patch Notes Y1S0.2? Let us know in the comments below!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more of the latest gaming industry news, you can read about Prime Video announcing a new live action&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/like-a-dragon-yakuza-series-amazon/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Like a Dragon: Yakuza adaptation</a>, and sign up to receive the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/newsletter/">Insider Gaming newsletter</a>.</p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[When is the XDefiant Ranked Play Release Date?]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/xdefiant-ranked-play-release-date/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/when-is-the-xdefiant-ranked-play-release-date.889038/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/xdefiant-ranked-play-release-date/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>It’s been confirmed for a while that XDefiant will eventually get a Ranked Play, but when exactly will the release date be?</p>



<p>According to the developers, Ranked Play is expected to launch in a “future season”, which admittingly does not give us a lot of information on when it’s coming. XDefiant’s first season, which is set to add three new maps and three new weapons, is set to launch on July 2nd, 2024, with each following season launching three months later.</p>



<p>However, there is a glimpse of hope for those waiting to play XDefiant Ranked Play. The game already has a Ranked Trial Run available, suggesting that the mode will be released sooner rather than later.</p>



<p>The Ranked Trial Run currently sees players battling it out in a 4v4; however, XDefiant lead Mark Rubin has previously suggested that it could be increased to 5v5 later based on feedback.</p>



<p>As the name suggests, Ranked Play is a matchmaking system in which teams of similar skill are matched against each other. This is unlike the randomness in XDefiant’s public matchmaking. It’s currently unclear on what gamesmodes and maps will be available for the mode, but as the game does have some Call of Duty esports professionals on its development team, it’s likely to be somewhat similar to Call of Duty. Domination and Occupy are the most likely candidates for gamemodes, whereas maps will ultimately depend on what the studio deems best.</p>



<p>Are you excited for XDefiant’s Ranked Play? Let us know in the comments below!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more of the latest gaming industry news, you can read about Prime Video announcing a new live action&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/like-a-dragon-yakuza-series-amazon/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Like a Dragon: Yakuza adaptation</a>, and sign up to receive the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/newsletter/">Insider Gaming newsletter</a>.</p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[IKEA Will Pay People £13.15 an Hour to Serve Meatballs at Its Virtual Roblox Store]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/ikea-will-pay-people-1315-an-hour-to-serve-meatballs-at-its-virtual-roblox-store</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ikea-will-pay-people-%C2%A313-15-an-hour-to-serve-meatballs-at-its-virtual-roblox-store.889035/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/ikea-will-pay-people-1315-an-hour-to-serve-meatballs-at-its-virtual-roblox-store<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>Furniture store IKEA will pay people £13.15 / €14.80 per hour to work in a virtual store it’s opening inside Roblox.</p><p>The Co-Worker Game, as it’s called, will let players “experience working in IKEA’s virtual universe”, the company said. “Fans will be able to live their home furnishing dreams and get paid for it, with a limited number of paid roles available,” IKEA continued. Applications run to June 16, with the game itself launching June 24.</p><p>“The immersive experience gives players the opportunity to experience IKEA's unique approach to careers where non-linear career journeys are the norm and lateral moves across departments are commonplace,” IKEA said. It is IKEA’s first foray into mainstream gaming.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/06/04/screenshot-2024-06-04-132544-1717503962760.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption>Image credit: IKEA.</figcaption></figure></output><p>There are paid shifts on offer for 10 successful applicants. They’ll help customers and get promoted to move departments, working in different sections of the store like the Showroom and Bistro, helping people choose their furniture, and even serving meatballs.</p><p>“We’re excited to be the first brand to launch paid work on Roblox to showcase how we do careers differently, bringing our unique careers philosophy to life,” commented IKEA’s Country People and Culture Manager, Darren Taylor. “At IKEA, there is no set route to career progression. Our co-workers are able to change roles, switch departments, and grow in any direction they choose, both in the game or in the real world. There are many ways to learn and grow at IKEA, and that's what IKEA on Roblox is all about.”</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/06/04/screenshot2-csxy-wuk-1717504041109.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption>Image credit: IKEA.</figcaption></figure></output><p>Digging into the detail, virtual interviews for shortlisted applicants take place for the fully remote virtual role between Thursday, June 14 and Tuesday, June 18. Each successful applicant will be paid an hourly IKEA Co-Worker rate for their time on the game. You have to be 18+ and in the UK or Republic of Ireland to apply. Successful applicants will be paid £13.15 (approx $16.78) per hour, the IKEA hourly rate of pay for a London member of staff. The wage matches the London Living Wage set in the UK, rather than the lower National Living Wage.</p><p>Roblox, which has an incredible 77.7 million daily active users, is used by a number of companies to promote their brands with virtual experiences. But the platform and the company behind it has been accused of “exploiting” children who develop many of the experiences available to play. <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/roblox-ceo-pay-to-earn-isnt-child-labor-its-a-gift">Roblox has denied this</a>.</p><p><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[It’s Time for Sony to Bring Back Killzone and Resistance]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/sony-playstation-bring-back-killzone-and-resistance</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/it%E2%80%99s-time-for-sony-to-bring-back-killzone-and-resistance.889032/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/sony-playstation-bring-back-killzone-and-resistance<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>Following on from <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/sony-state-of-play-may-2024-everything-announced"><u>PlayStation’s State of Play</u></a>, we now have a solid look at many of the PS5’s upcoming titles. Your mileage may vary on how the lineup looks but the recurring question of <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/where-are-all-the-ps5-games"><u>where all the PS5 games are</u></a> hasn’t quite been answered. Some of the biggest games at the showcase were remakes or remasters of older games such as <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/until-dawn-remaster-will-arrive-in-fall-2024-state-of-play-2024"><u>Until Dawn</u></a> or the <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/silent-hill-2-remake-gets-brand-new-trailer-and-release-date-ahead-of-transmission-stream-state-of-play-2024"><u>Silent Hill 2</u></a> remake, or PC ports of already released titles like <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/god-of-war-ragnarok-pc-release-officially-confirmed-state-of-play-2024"><u>God of War: Ragnarok</u></a>. That’s not to say there weren’t some big new PS5 games shown, but one in particular has me scratching my head at what we’re supposed to take away from it.</p><p>That would be <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/concord-gets-new-cinematic-and-gameplay-trailer-and-a-release-date-state-of-play-2024"><u>Concord</u></a>, the debut game from first-party PlayStation developer Firewalk Studios. A 5v5 endless multiplayer shooter, the game didn’t exactly give me the best first impression. The writing and characters in the cinematic trailer feel like microwaved Guardians of the Galaxy leftovers, and knowing that this is an Overwatch-like hero shooter where the pretty cutscenes and lore won’t actually be reflected in the gameplay doesn’t help. Of course, Concord could very well surprise once we get our hands on it, but Sony putting such heavy focus on a game that looks so bland just brings to mind that they have two solid first-party shooter IPs that have been languishing in their back-catalog for far too long: Killzone and Resistance. Why should Sony bring these forgotten franchises back to the spotlight? Let me explain.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><h2>Sony’s FPS Crisis</h2><p>Concord being the first game shown during the State of Play isn’t something that happened in a vacuum. Ever since Microsoft announced its intention to purchase Activision, there has been a question mark hovering above the PlayStation brand, that being what’s going to happen to the Call of Duty franchise now that its direct competitor owns it. A big part of <a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/sony-claims-microsofts-true-strategy-is-to-make-playstation-like-nintendo/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Sony’s argument</u></a> in the regulation case that tried and failed to block the Activision purchase hinged on Call of Duty, with Sony stating during the case that “Microsoft claims that Nintendo’s differentiated model demonstrates that PlayStation doesn’t need Call of Duty to compete effectively. But this reveals Microsoft’s true strategy… Post-Transaction, Xbox would become the one-stop-shop for all the best-selling shooter franchises on console.”</p><p>To address the concern, Microsoft and Sony <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/xbox-has-signed-a-binding-agreement-to-keep-call-of-duty-on-playstation-after-its-acquisition-of-activision-blizzard"><u>signed an agreement</u></a> to keep the long-running series multiplatform, but such agreements aren’t bulletproof. Microsoft has full control over the Call of Duty IP, meaning Sony is effectively at its mercy when it comes to that franchise. However, Sony’s argument that PlayStation needs Call of Duty to stay competitive is a defeatist mindset. Call of Duty being the number one shooter franchise is not preordained by the gods. Franchises trend up and down all the time; look at Halo going from the top of the universe in the mid-2000s to simply “one among many” shooters in the modern era, or Overwatch being the biggest thing in the world on launch to now becoming a laughing stock as Blizzard tries and fails to deliver on the many promises of what Overwatch 2 was supposed to be.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>Right now, Sony doesn’t have a prominent FPS to call its own.</p></div><p>However, none of that changes the fact that right now, Sony doesn’t have a prominent FPS to call its own. Helldivers 2 was certainly a surprise smash hit, but it’s a third-person shooter with no campaign. There’s also the recent snafu about the PSN login requirement that, <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/playstation-reverses-course-on-helldivers-2-psn-account-requirement"><u>although it was walked back</u></a>, still caused much chaos in the game’s community and led the game to be <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/helldivers-2-pulled-from-sale-in-177-countries-due-to-psn-linking-requirement"><u>delisted in 177 countries</u></a>. Sony needs a big win in the FPS space to counteract Microsoft gobbling up the likes of Activision, Blizzard, and Id Software. Luckily, Sony has two old franchises waiting in the wings that could help it out of this bind.</p><h2>Helghan Forever</h2><p>At a time when a big part of Sony’s brand is its focus on AAA first-party games like The Last of Us, God of War, Horizon, or Insomniac’s Spider-Man games, Killzone being left out to dry is a serious missed opportunity. More so than most other franchises, Killzone was synonymous with the PlayStation brand in the PS3 era, with Killzone 2’s release in February of 2009 being something of a landmark moment for a console that seriously struggled with quality exclusives in its first couple of years. Alongside the likes of Metal Gear Solid 4 and Uncharted 2, Killzone 2 helped change the PS3’s reputation and finally made it a worthy competitor to the Xbox 360. That it was a sequel to a game that was <em>not </em>that well-received in the first place only made Killzone 2 all the more remarkable.</p><p>The first Killzone was released in 2004 on the PS2, and despite much pre-release hype as Sony’s potential answer to Halo, the game received <a href="https://www.metacritic.com/game/killzone/critic-reviews/?platform=playstation-2" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>mixed reviews</u></a>. It’s not a bad game by any means, but it’s a disappointing beginning for the franchise given how compelling the world and visual design is. It often felt like a decent game with excellent presentation, including Brian Cox’s stellar vocal performance as Scolar Visari and Joris de Man’s iconic original score. But Killzone 2 showed that it’s sometimes worth taking a second chance on an idea that didn’t work out perfectly the first time, launching to <a href="https://www.metacritic.com/game/killzone-2/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>spectacular reviews</u></a> (<a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2009/01/29/killzone-2-review"><u>including IGN’s</u></a>), and selling <a href="https://kotaku.com/killzone-2-sells-1-million-worldwide-5215424" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>more than a million units</u></a> worldwide in less than two months. The Killzone series would become one of Sony’s marquee franchises in the years that followed, with a PS3 sequel Killzone 3 launching in 2011, and one of the PS4’s launch titles in 2013 being Killzone: Shadow Fall.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>Now, we know Guerrilla Games is busy with Horizon these days, but certainly Sony has enough studios under its umbrella to let someone else take up Killzone’s flag. Its unique blend of hard sci-fi space opera, weighty FPS combat, and ‘WWII in space’ aesthetic, coupled with the iconic designs of the Helghast troopers, hasn’t really been borrowed by other shooters on the market. A new game in the series could also finally pull the trigger on a story campaign from the Helghast perspective, something fans have wanted for a long time because of their sympathetic backstory. Given Killzone’s importance to the history of PlayStation consoles, leaving it off the PS5 seems like a massive unforced error. Killzone 2 in particular is close to a masterpiece of sci-fi shooter design and not only deserves a modern facelift, but also a proper new entry to continue the saga. But it’s not the only Sony shooter series that warrants a resurrection.</p><h2>Vive la Résistance</h2><p>As mentioned previously, the PS3 struggled out of the gate given how few quality games were made for the console in its opening year. But out of all the launch titles, the one that stood out the most was Resistance: Fall of Man, an original FPS from Insomniac Games, more well known for Ratchet &amp; Clank and its recent Spider-Man series. Although its multiplayer was bland, the single-player campaign was surprisingly meaty and could also be played in split-screen co-op (remember that?). More so, its story was fascinating – set in an alternate history where aliens called the Chimera invaded Earth in the 1950s  – and Insomniac’s trademark for off-the-wall weapon design made for a great game that kind of got lost in the cultural conversation as more anticipated games launched on the system.</p><p>Despite this, Resistance was a regular player in the PS3’s catalog of franchises, with two direct sequels in Resistance 2 and 3 also released during the console’s lifecycle. Sadly, the series suffered a downturn with the second game, which tried too hard to match the conventions of other shooters in the marketplace at the expense of its own personality. Not only did the collection of creative weapons from the first game get shortchanged by forcing players to carry only two at a time instead of the whole arsenal, but the meager campaign was also dotted with an array of disappointing boss fights that tended to be more scripted sequences than dynamic battles. The multiplayer was improved, but the story was weak compared to the previous entry.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>Insomniac righted the ship with Resistance 3, which went back to a lot of what both fans and the developers enjoyed about the series. In an interview with <a href="https://kotaku.com/why-did-resistance-never-get-as-big-as-halo-maybe-it-c-5942309" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Kotaku</u></a>, Insomniac CEO Ted Price said that all the changes in Resistance 2 “may have not been a good thing,” and that “on Resistance 3, we went back to some of our more traditional core mechanics that players did love, and then built a story that was more personal… we're really proud of Resistance 3.” But that improvement didn’t translate to sales and the series flamed out with the third entry and the <a href="https://www.metacritic.com/game/resistance-burning-skies/critic-reviews/?platform=playstation-vita" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>poorly received</u></a> PlayStation Vita spin-off, Resistance: Burning Skies. Yet if Killzone taught us anything, it’s that one misstep shouldn’t mean giving up on a good series, and the alternate history world presented in Resistance is still rife with creative possibilities. The unconventional arsenal of weapons could be a great way to spice up a multiplayer suite, and there are many unseen eras or locations in the Resistance world that could be the focus of a new campaign should Insomniac or one of Sony’s other developers take another crack at it.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>If Killzone taught us anything, it’s that one misstep shouldn’t mean giving up on a good series.</p></div><p>Sony has the resources to put up a fight in the shooter space, such as long-dormant franchises like Killzone or Resistance, or developers known for shooters like Bungie. There are many avenues to build first-person shooters on PlayStation, and games like Concord come from that need. We’ll see how Firewalk’s debut fares, but chasing the highs of other games that are already starting to age past their sell-by date is rarely a winning strategy. Not that Sony shouldn’t try to cultivate new IPs, it absolutely should, but if it needs a competitive edge, it would be worthwhile to highlight the values of the PlayStation brand that are, in fact, specific to PlayStation. And reviving two big franchises in the genre you’re currently struggling with that have pre-established fanbases and are already associated with your console? That would be one way to have that competitive edge a hell of a lot sooner.</p><p><em>Carlos Morales writes novels, articles and Mass Effect essays. You can follow his fixations on </em><u><em>Twitter</em></u><em>.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Magical Delicacy adds Switch version, launches July 16]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/06/magical-delicacy-adds-switch-version-launches-july-16</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/magical-delicacy-adds-switch-version-launches-july-16.889029/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/06/magical-delicacy-adds-switch-version-launches-july-16<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Metroidvania-lite-meets-cooking game dated.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Genres > Metroidvania [145 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/metroidvania">Metroidvania</a>-lite-meets-<a title="Genres > Cooking [10 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/cooking">cooking game</a> <em><a title="Games > Magical Delicacy [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/magical-delicacy">Magical Delicacy</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [5,413 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox One [13,192 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch [15,397 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [20,231 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via Steam on July 16, publisher <a title="Companies > Whitethorn Games [24 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/whitethorn-games">Whitethorn Games</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Skaule [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/skaule">Skaule</a> announced. The Switch version is newly announced. It will also be available via <a title="Platforms > Xbox [24,115 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox">Xbox</a> Game Pass. <span id="more-887048"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Whitethorn Games:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>A wholesome <a title="Genres > Adventure [1,508 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a> set in an enchanting world, <em>Magical Delicacy</em> invites you to play as the young witch Flora, who travels to the adventurer’s town of Grat to grow her magical skills and fulfill her dream of becoming a fully-fledged witch. Upon arriving, she takes up shop to cook meals and potions for the diverse cast of characters, from the charming townsfolk and mysterious travelers to forgotten figures of legend and masters of their craft. As she traverses the cozy harbor town, she’ll discover the stories of the townsfolk and learn that there is more to Grat than meets the eye.</p><p>Collect an assortment of inspiring ingredients from shops, foraging through the town, and by growing them in your garden, cook up a storm in your upgradeable kitchen using a variety of tools and deliver your meals to fulfill the orders from hungry townsfolk. Explore the unfamiliar town of Grat, learn new ways to traverse, discover secrets, and experience a unique and witchy world one dish at a time.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <ul><li>Collect new recipes and ingredients through trade, questing, growing vegetables in your garden, and exploring throughout the town of Grat.</li><li>Learn an extensive cooking system, allowing for flexible, creative choices to fulfill even the oddest orders.</li><li>Build the kitchen of your dreams by commissioning new equipment to help you create even more delicious dishes.</li><li><a title="Companies > Experience [210 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/experience">Experience</a> a wholesome linear story filled with witchy wonder and intrigue, with many optional encounters and free play opportunities.</li><li>Traverse a 2D <a title="Genres > Platformer [444 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/platformer">platformer</a> inspired by Metroidvanias, gain new abilities, reach new areas, and unlock shortcuts.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Magical Delicacy - Release Date Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/08QeSO2gw7U?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Final Fantasy VII Rebirth update 1.040 slashes more bugs]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/06/04/final-fantasy-vii-rebirth-update-1-040-slashes-more-bugs/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/final-fantasy-vii-rebirth-update-1-040-slashes-more-bugs.889020/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/06/04/final-fantasy-vii-rebirth-update-1-040-slashes-more-bugs/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p><a href="http://thesixthaxis.com/tag/square-enix">Square Enix</a> has released a new <a href="http://thesixthaxis.com/tag/final-fantasy-vii-rebirth">Final Fantasy VII Rebirth</a> update which is now available to download on PS5. It’s important to note that this patch doesn’t deliver any new content to the JRPG sequel and is mainly aimed at bug fixes.</p>
<p><iframe title="FINAL FANTASY VII REBIRTH Final Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Q56cRDseTGQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>According to Square, Final Fantasy VII Rebirth update 1.040 “will apply fixes to several bugs, as well as improving the stability and functionality of the overall game.”</p>
<p>You can find a quick rundown of what’s included in the latest patch below. In the meantime, check out <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/02/22/final-fantasy-7-rebirth-review/">Nic’s glowing review</a> in which he scored the game a resounding 9/10, saying: “Final Fantasy VII Rebirth is a beautifully crafted experience that fans old and new will absolutely love. It almost goes too far in correcting the first game’s linearity with broad open areas stuffed with things to do, but there’s also key additions to the combat, and the story running through this middle chapter is masterfully retold. Really the biggest problem you’ll have once the credits roll is knowing that it will be far too many years before we can finish the trilogy.”</p>
<p>Anyway, onto those patch notes!</p>

<h3>Final Fantasy VII Rebirth Update 1.040 Patch Notes</h3>
<ul>
<li>Fixes to bugs that would very occasionally prevent game progress under specific conditions.</li>
<li>Fixes that allow the player to acquire photo frames if a bug occurs that would prevent their acquisition after fulfilling the relevant unlock conditions.</li>
<li>Fixes to bugs that are triggered under specific circumstances in battle.</li>
<li>Fixes to a bug where information was not shown on screen when selecting to play Stage 2 of the Gambit Gears mini game on Hard Mode.</li>
<li>Fixes to several display-related bugs.</li>
<li>Improvements to the overall game stability.</li>
</ul>
<p>These aren’t the only improvements that have been made to the game since its launch earlier this year.&nbsp;Gamers who choose to play in Performance Mode will now have the choice of ‘Sharp’ or ‘Soft’ visuals. At launch, there were complaints that the image quality in Performance Mode was too soft, thanks to the significant drop in the dynamic resolution bracket compared to the Quality Mode. It seems that Square Enix has now added an optional sharpening filter or upscaling technique to help.</p>
<p>Publisher Square Enix is said to be making major changes to the way its creates blockbuster hits. This comes after a recent financial report which showed huge losses for the company after its abandonment of cancelled projects to the tune of $140,000,000. As a result, Square will be more selective in which games its chooses to greenlight.</p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://www.square-enix-games.com/en_US/documents/notice-regarding-updates-final-fantasy-vii-rebirth">Square Enix</a></em></p>


<!-- AI CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pax Dei Early Access Q&A – Mainframe Talks Improvements from the Wilderness Alpha, Monetization and Much More]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/pax-dei-early-access-qa-mainframe-talks-improvements-from-the-wilderness-alpha-monetization-and-much-more/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pax-dei-early-access-q-a-%E2%80%93-mainframe-talks-improvements-from-the-wilderness-alpha-monetization-and-much-more.889017/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/pax-dei-early-access-qa-mainframe-talks-improvements-from-the-wilderness-alpha-monetization-and-much-more/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p><a href="https://wccftech.com/mainframe-industries-reveals-pax-dei-a-sandbox-mmo-coming-to-pc-and-cloud-gaming-platforms/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Pax Dei</a>, the sandbox MMORPG in development at Iceland-based studio Mainframe Industries, has found a publishing partner in New Tales, the French team that helped publish the free-to-play collectible card game Waven.</p>
<p>Together, Mainframe and New Tales announced that Pax Dei will debut in early access in exactly two weeks, on Tuesday, June 18. Pre-purchase is available starting today on the <a href="https://playpaxdei.com/en-us" target="_blank" rel="noopener">official website</a>, with various Founder's Packs options, and the game will be playable via Steam or the dedicated Pax Dei launcher.</p>
<p>Mainframe doesn't shy away from the fact that the game is still very much in Alpha and, as such, in 'heavy' development. It will stay in early access for at least a year, during which major changes will be introduced. At times, full wipes of character progress may even take place. The first big post-launch update will introduce markets and a gold economy to Pax Dei.</p>
<p>I recently had the opportunity to interview Sulka Haro, co-founder and Chief Product Officer at Mainframe, to discuss the game's current state and its future throughout early access.</p>

<p><iframe title="Pax Dei | Early Access Announcement" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/m9kbu7qtYR4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p><strong>When I <a href="https://wccftech.com/mainframe-ex-ccp-remedy-ceo-the-industry-is-headed-towards-cloud-native-games/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">talked</a> to Thor four years ago, he told me the original goal was to make a cloud-native game Cloud native. It was meant to run directly on cloud servers, but that seems to be gone now. Can you speak to this fundamental change?</strong></p>
<p>We still very much want to publish the game across all platforms, including mobile devices, and see streaming as a critical part of that rollout. 5 years ago, it looked like the game streaming platforms were on a steep rise, and we were assuming there would be a widely available ecosystem for distributing games using streaming available by the time we ship the game. This ended up not happening due to a variety of things and we still have a game we’d like to grant access to, so we’re launching on PC first. But as said before, there are plans to expand the available platforms later.</p>
<p><strong>Will Pax Dei be available to play on GeForce NOW and/or other cloud services? If so, when?</strong></p>
<p>We fully intend to bring the game out to a much wider selection of distribution platforms. As a matter of fact, we’ve announced back in January that we’re working on making Pax Dei available on GeForce Now. Not in June, though! Let’s get this PC launch out of the way first.</p>
<p><strong>Will there be support for Steam Deck?</strong></p>
<p>There’s no official support at this time.</p>
<p><strong>During the Wilderness Alpha, I noticed the lack of proper controller support. Is it coming at the early access launch or later?</strong></p>
<p>We’re actively working on improving the controller access. We don’t have a locked-down ETA for it at this point, but we do want to have this available before too long.</p>
<p><strong>The combat felt quite barebones, especially due to the stiff animations. Are you looking to improve that?</strong></p>
<p>Absolutely. The combat system in the Early Access build has already been improved quite a bit in terms of responsiveness, but we can see how we still have to work a lot to get the combat to the level we aspire. We just did a planning session with the whole team and did agree that combat improvements is one of the focus areas for the rest of the year.</p>
<p><strong>Is there a set amount of active combat abilities that players will have at their disposal?</strong></p>
<p>Each one of the weapons (and shields) has a special ability, which we’re improving all the time. Additionally, we’re adding more spells to a larger selection of gear. If you only played the game for a short period of time in the Alpha, you may never get your hands on the spell gear - as you play in PvE, you can find Relics, which unlock recipes for wearables and wieldables that grant you spells, most of which are in form of active combat abilities.</p>
<p><strong>Other MMOs have class-specific special resources (rage/energy/mana, etc.). Will you add something like that to Pax Dei? What about Ultimate abilities?</strong></p>
<p>Our game doesn’t have classes - we use the gear you’re using to effectively create the classes. So when you go raiding, you’ll want to choose gear that matches the role you want to play (which in turn grants you spells once you’ve found some Relics). This system eliminates the need for class-specific resources - we use stamina to gate the spells and abilities you get from the gear. Not related, we are planning to introduce a second resource by the end of the year that will, to some degree, have a similar role in the game.</p>
<p><strong>Previously, you said that magic would be rather rare in the game. Is that still the case? Do you have to work hard to find magic spells?</strong></p>
<p>When you start the game, you have no access to magic. As you progress in the game, you can find Relic, which unlock recipes that allow manufacturing gear that grants you spells and abilities when worn or wielded. The relics for more powerful spells are quite challenging to find, and as the Relics are consumed as part of the crafting process, magic items indeed are not common, and the powerful spells will be quite rare.</p>
<p><strong>Is all gear going to be tradeable? Could you conceivably lend high-end gear to a newbie to make them competitive right away?</strong></p>
<p>Yes, we don’t gate trading and/or using items with character progression. Having said that, new characters will not have progressed in the skills and will not be able to effectively use advanced gear, and of course, a new player is unlikely to have the player skills needed to maximize the use potential of the gear. What this means in practice is that a twinked new player will be immediately useful to you but will not be as powerful as an experienced player with a character that’s in the skill cap in the progression.</p>
<p><strong>In terms of PvE, you talked about the dungeon. Is there a limit to player numbers in dungeons? How does instancing work for dungeons? Could you find other groups there?</strong></p>
<p>Each dungeon has a maximum capacity of players that can be in the same instance at a time. The number is based on the dungeon size &amp; performance requirements to ensure the gameplay experience in the dungeon is pleasant. The instances are not made specifically for a party, so you can find other groups in the dungeons, and new instances are created as needed if the dungeon is full. There’s a system related to the instances in Pax Dei that looks at which instance your party &amp; clan members are and automatically picks the instance with your friends if multiple instances are active. The system also has a different “soft” and “hard” caps for the player routing to give it room to do this social matching to maximize the probability you always end up in the correct instance. This same system also applies to the open world areas of the game, where if a Heartland or Wildland reaches the soft cap, it gets instanced, after which we prioritize the instance for you based on where your friends are.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/PvP-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>

<p><strong>Will PvP work in dungeons, allowing fights between different groups?</strong></p>
<p>Currently, no - we do not want to create significant PvE content in the game that’d be locked behind PvP flags, so players who do not want to participate in PvP don’t feel like we’re forcing them to PvP. Having said that, we are working on an expansion to the PvP system, which will allow players to flag themselves for PvP in a manner that will also work in dungeons. We’ll tell more about this later.</p>
<p><strong>You spoke about potential rewards for PvP, so what are people getting from PvP activities except for loot from the defeated foes?</strong></p>
<p>Currently, PvP is enabled in Lyonesse, a central area in the world accessible from the four Provinces that feature the buildable areas. Entering the area flags you for PvP. The risk/reward related to entering Lyonesse is about the resources you can find in the area - for example, Pure Iron, which is very good for advanced gear manufacturing, is relatively common in Lyonesse (and very rare outside of the area).</p>
<p><strong>I believe Clan Wars were also mentioned somewhere in the presentation slides. Is that feature coming during the early access phase?</strong></p>
<p>We are indeed working on an expansion to the PvP system, and yes, this will launch during the Early Access. The system is not tied directly to the Clans - the PvP organizations are independent of the Clan memberships of the players. We’re assuming some Clans might choose to go all in on PvP and have the PvP organization and the clan memberships match 1:1, but this is up to the players, and we’re sure there will be interesting mixing of clans across the different organizations.</p>
<p><strong>How would those work? Will there be sieges and stuff like that?</strong></p>
<p>We do want to pull off sieges eventually, but in the short term the PvP will be skirmish based. We’ll tell everyone more once we have a better idea of when the features are going to ship to players!</p>
<p><strong>Will there be some bigger PvP-enabled area than Lyonesse at some point?</strong></p>
<p>The entire world will eventually be PvP-enabled. Having said that, the players who do not want to PvP will not be forced to do so and the plots you’re building are sacrosanct and protected by the Divine Peace, so no destruction will come to the villages players are building currently.</p>
<p><strong>You've listed Churches and Feudal System as upcoming Pax Dei features. How do those systems work? What about Altars and Miracles?</strong></p>
<p>The altars will enable new gameplay through Grace, a new resource attainable from the altars used for Miracles and churches are built… around the altars. Grace will also allow anointing Knights, who are PvP flagged across the entire world, which forms the basis of the Feudal System. We’ll tell more about this when we’re a bit closer to shipping these features.</p>
<p><strong>You said transitions to other provinces will require load times. Is there no way to make it seamless at some point?</strong></p>
<p>Currently, when you play the game, it’s pretty rare to get to a loading screen during a typical play session as the 100 square kilometer provinces already provide a huge area for exploration. At this moment, there are practical limits to level sizes, and 100 square kilometers is already pushing it when it comes to seamless travel in the world. We’ll probably look into this at some point, but at the moment we think our time is better spent on other things like improving the combat feel and adding the new game systems discussed earlier.</p>
<p><strong>Can you move between different instances, perhaps to find friends?</strong></p>
<p>At the moment we don’t have a feature for the players to move between instances. We’ll probably add this eventually, but at the moment this is not critical as the way we’ve implemented the instancing areas means players very rarely experience areas that need instancing and when they do, we have the matchmaking system that places layers into the instance with their friends, so it’s extremely unlikely that you’ll ever experience a moment where you’d need to hop between instances.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/Village-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>

<p><strong>What options will there be to reach distant players with fast travel?</strong></p>
<p>At the moment, the only fast travel option is the ability to return home. We’re likely to keep the fast travel in the world very, very restricted, as we want distance to matter in the game. There will be features to make travel more pleasant (mounts will definitely appear in the game eventually).</p>
<p><strong>Regarding character customization, will you add more faces and cosmetic options?</strong></p>
<p>Absolutely.</p>
<p><strong>In the Pax Dei Wilderness Alpha, even with <a href="https://wccftech.com/dlss-3-is-coming-to-horizon-forbidden-west-dragons-dogma-2-like-a-dragon-infinite-wealth-pax-dei-and-more/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DLSS 3</a> enabled on a PC equipped with an RTX 4090 GPU, the game stuttered every few hundred meters. Will you solve that problem in time for the early access launch?</strong></p>
<p>We’ve made several improvements to the content loading, and you should see significant improvement in reducing those stutters in the Early Access build. The stutters were caused by a multitude of issues not related to the GPU, and the work on these, with the help of some of the profiling data we gathered during the Alpha, has paid off very well. We have a few remaining issues, which we’ll address as part of upgrading to a newer version of the Unreal Engine later this year.</p>
<p><strong>What other improvements have you made to Pax Dei since the last Alpha test?</strong></p>
<p>We’ve made a ton of changes that improve the combat responsiveness. Almost everything that can be touched regarding balancing (from combat to recipes) has been touched. We (finally) have rebinding support. There’s literally a few hundred bugs that have been fixed since the Alpha 2 And other things… we’ll soon be publishing extensive release notes that cover a lot of this in detail.</p>
<p><strong>I know you're using Unreal Engine 5 with Lumen and Nanite. Will you keep updating it as Epic releases new versions?</strong></p>
<p>That is the plan, yes. We’re currently using UE 5.2.1 and have already started working on the upgrade all the way to UE 5.4. We’ll ship the Early Access build with the current engine version and are hoping the first bigger update to the game a few months after the launch will already be using a newer engine version.</p>
<p><strong>You've hinted that the game could eventually require an active subscription to play. However, only three of the oldest MMOs (EVE Online, World of Warcraft, and Final Fantasy XIV) still use that business model. Aren't you worried you might alienate many people unwilling to pay a monthly fee?</strong></p>
<p>The final business model for Pax Dei is not decided yet. In Pax Dei, you’re building your home in the “real” world. Whatever gets built on a given player’s plot must always be maintained - that’s costly (not to mention technically challenging). We also need a system to free up land once players leave the game (or become ‘inactive’). This system will be crucial in keeping the world alive, full of activity and opportunities to meet friends, and avoid having areas of the game become ghost towns. Coupling this with monetization seems to be a well-understood and generally accepted model - in the existing Pax Dei community, at least.</p>
<p>We have yet to fully determine the exact shape and form (and price!). this will take. The good old-fashioned subscription model is certainly something we’re looking at. Still, we are also considering other options, with an eye on balancing the simplicity of usage while allowing players to choose how they want to engage with the game. We also indicated we intended to offer a free tier, allowing players to discover the game before committing to it.</p>
<p>We’re committed to being transparent with our model and we’ll keep our players updated on our progress, with an increasing amount of details and with space to experiment and adjust based on sensitivities and data.</p>
<p><strong>What are the odds you'll expand Pax Dei to consoles after the early access phase?</strong></p>
<p>The funding theory behind Mainframe was to make a game playable on every screen. We’re not excluding anything. That said, let’s get things right on PC first!</p>
<p><strong>Thank you for your time.</strong></p>

				

			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mutant Year Zero: Zone Wars is the year’s goofiest tabletop skirmish game]]></title>
            <link>https://www.polygon.com/tabletop-games/24168167/mutant-year-zero-zone-wars-review</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mutant-year-zero-zone-wars-is-the-year%E2%80%99s-goofiest-tabletop-skirmish-game.889014/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.polygon.com/tabletop-games/24168167/mutant-year-zero-zone-wars-review<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>If you buy something from a Polygon link, Vox Media may earn a commission. See our <a href="https://www.polygon.com/pages/ethics-statement" target="_blank">ethics statement</a>.</p><div>
  <p id="8KK5pH">Skirmish wargaming — traditional miniatures wargaming with a smaller footprint and fewer minis — is having a moment. Used to be there were just a few flavors available, but a new crop of games is suddenly giving all kinds of different energies. Grimdark <a href="https://www.polygon.com/22458895/necromunda-warhammer-40k-getting-started-miniatures-kitbashing-conversions-terrain"><em>Necromunda</em></a>, futuristic <a href="https://www.polygon.com/tabletop-games/22555634/infinity-code-one-crimson-stone-nomad-ariadna-pre-order-release-date-price"><em>Infinity</em></a>, and stalwart <em>Malifaux</em> are all still around, of course. Their action remains brutal, and their rulesets fairly complex. Meanwhile, newcomers <a href="https://www.polygon.com/reviews/23810357/cyberpunk-red-combat-zone-review"><em>Cyberpunk Red: Combat Zone</em></a><em> </em>and <a href="https://www.polygon.com/tabletop-games/24057441/fallout-factions-nuka-world-preview-release-date-price"><em>Fallout: Factions</em></a> are becoming more established thanks to dynamic sculpts, bright colors, and most importantly, far more simplified rules. There’s also <a href="https://www.polygon.com/tabletop-games/23671326/star-wars-shatterpoint-miniatures-skirmish-game-preview-adepticon"><em>Star Wars: Shatterpoint</em></a><em> </em>and <a href="https://www.polygon.com/tabletop-games/24107809/halo-flashpoint-miniatures-game-pictures-rules-preview"><em>Halo: Flashpoint</em></a>, more refined games clearly built for brisk, competitive play.</p>
<p id="2Y5ZbW">Now comes Free League Publishing’s <a href="https://freeleaguepublishing.com/shop/mutant-year-zero/zone-wars-core-set/"><em>Mutant Year Zero: Zone Wars</em></a>, launching today with a<em> </em>new <em>Core Set</em>. It feels like this one is bringing some much-needed comic relief.</p>
<p id="lnGiQO">First launched as <em>Mutant</em> in 1984, the Swedish tabletop role-playing universe has been many things over the years. Funcom’s <a href="https://www.polygon.com/2018/9/13/17854952/mutant-year-zero-pc-xbox-one-ps4-tactical-rpg-xcom"><em>Mutant Year Zero: Road to Eden</em></a> refocused the franchise on its goofiest characters, human-and-animal hybrids with bizarre special abilities. It also helped that one of the main characters looks like an up-armored Howard the Duck. All the while, Free League has been working diligently in the background to keep <a href="https://freeleaguepublishing.com/shop/mutant-year-zero/">the modern version of the TTRPG</a> in circulation around the world.</p>
<p id="KXe1oO"><em>Zone Wars</em> smartly puts our duck friend back on the cover, and this time he’s the linchpin of a powerful band of Stalkers, mutant soldiers who enter the dangerous, irradiated Zone to scavenge for artifacts. It’s a simple premise that opens the door to clever scenario-based gameplay and the potential for linked campaigns.</p>
<p>  <figure>
  <span>
    
    <span data-original="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25473018/mutant_year_zero_zone_wars_minis.jpg">
      
        <picture data-cid="site/picture_element-1717508177_3022_108971" data-cdata="{&quot;asset_id&quot;:25473018,&quot;ratio&quot;:&quot;*&quot;}">
  


  <source srcset="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9cANjOsaERtp5lHOXZhJYPISafs=/0x0:3000x2000/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x2000):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25473018/mutant_year_zero_zone_wars_minis.jpg 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/eo1TZFcB6L-lXREbsK7-5sZ6ytA=/0x0:3000x2000/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x2000):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25473018/mutant_year_zero_zone_wars_minis.jpg 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/vCach-m3n2ae67Fro137g4SubmU=/0x0:3000x2000/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x2000):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25473018/mutant_year_zero_zone_wars_minis.jpg 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/86CeaB4SZmeUWZdfmISX09YLE9k=/0x0:3000x2000/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x2000):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25473018/mutant_year_zero_zone_wars_minis.jpg 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/woy5FbPPQbJjofuQAnvnaJ7AVjQ=/0x0:3000x2000/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x2000):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25473018/mutant_year_zero_zone_wars_minis.jpg 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xNknOkqHN3fg_Gz0rszQ4mIcPsI=/0x0:3000x2000/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x2000):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25473018/mutant_year_zero_zone_wars_minis.jpg 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ewObvD74tP0-n9RGUmp8OOVuIZs=/0x0:3000x2000/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x2000):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25473018/mutant_year_zero_zone_wars_minis.jpg 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/TrV0B18xpTYnqKmdpPUSwSHCh-E=/0x0:3000x2000/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x2000):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25473018/mutant_year_zero_zone_wars_minis.jpg 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3270fk5UBX9DgnLHIVBnwiXV3T8=/0x0:3000x2000/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x2000):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25473018/mutant_year_zero_zone_wars_minis.jpg 1920w" sizes="90vw" type="image/webp">




</picture>

      
    </span>
    
  </span>
  
    <span>
      
        <figcaption>All 10 miniatures come pre-painted with a high-contrast paint, but you’re going to need to put in some work to strip it off if you want to paint them up. The custom plastic pack-in included inside the box gives the whole package a polished feel.</figcaption>
      
      
        <cite>Photo: Charlie Hall/Polygon</cite>
      
    </span>
  
</figure>


</p>
<p id="YmtnF4">The most surprising part is the completeness of this starter set, which includes a few short stacks of unit and ability cards, loads of cardboard terrain, bits and custom dice, but also pre-assembled and pre-shaded monochrome miniatures. Setup took me all of 20 minutes, and just about 30 minutes later I had already grokked most of the mechanics. That’s because the rules in the manual have been put together by Andy Chambers, co-designer of the original <em>Necromunda </em>(1995), and they are rock solid and easy to understand.</p>
<p id="mWANTe">Gameplay is nuanced and engaging, but never tedious. <em>Zone Wars</em> has just enough complexity to keep you on your toes. You’ll need to keep track of where your miniatures are facing, for instance. Charging straight away into melee isn’t always the best move, even when your team has the advantage in numbers. Meanwhile, if you keep your distance it can be hard to level a kill shot. That’s because these little buggers are all pretty resilient!</p>
<p id="V2yCaP">Deal enough damage to a given character, and they’ll become broken. After tipping them on their side, the only available action you can take with them on their turn is recovery. But to recover, you’ll need a special item or a friend nearby to come to your aid. The recovery process involves rolling some dice, combining attributes of the rescuer and the rescued, then tallying up the results. If this succeeds, the broken character leaps to their feet with full health — only to become bloodied. If they go down again they’re absolutely out of action for that particular match, but unlike other more hardcore offerings true character death never happens.</p>

<p id="yxZP9K">The result is a lighthearted game of tactical <em>Whac-a-Mole</em>, filled with endearing critters with charming attributes taking devastating hits. But when they go down in a hail of bullets and feathers, they invariably leap heroically back to their webbed feet, makeshift guns blazing. I know of no other game where a moose-man can run antlers-first into an insect-man to score the winning point.</p>
<p id="CVeGV1">The best part is that even in a linked campaign with multiple missions — of the type offered in the game’s first expansion, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Free-League-Psionics-Expansion-Miniatures/dp/B0CV81X9RB/?tag=polygon05-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank" has-subtag="true" data-cdata="{&quot;rewritten_url&quot;:&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Free-League-Psionics-Expansion-Miniatures/dp/B0CV81X9RB/?ascsubtag=___pl__p_23932208__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder\u0026tag=polygon05-20&quot;,&quot;subtag_max_length&quot;:99,&quot;subtag_delim_length&quot;:3,&quot;subtag_key&quot;:&quot;ascsubtag&quot;,&quot;subtag_data&quot;:{&quot;ascsubtag&quot;:&quot;___pl__p_23932208__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder&quot;,&quot;tag&quot;:&quot;polygon05-20&quot;},&quot;encode_subtag&quot;:false}"><em>Mutant Year Zero: Zone Wars - Robots &amp; Psionics</em></a> — death isn’t really an issue. Even if your favorite character does go down for a second time in the heat of battle, they’ll absolutely be back for the next game. Because if there’s one thing funnier than doming Howard the Duck at range with a scavenged laser rifle, it’s doing it again... and again... and again over the course of a multi-session campaign. </p>
<p id="iBr4Uu"><small><em>Mutant Year Zero: Zone Wars Core Set</em></small><small> and </small><small><em>Mutant Year Zero: Zone Wars - Robots &amp; Psionics</em></small><small> are available now. The products were reviewed using a retail copy provided by Free League Publishing. Vox Media has affiliate partnerships. These do not influence editorial content, though Vox Media may earn commissions for products purchased via affiliate links. You can find </small><a href="https://www.polygon.com/pages/ethics-statement"><small>additional information about Polygon’s ethics policy here</small></a><small>.</small></p>
<hr id="88oQTx">



  
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dragon Ball: Sparking Zero Leak Teases Special Edition & Pricing]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-leak-teases-special-edition-pricing/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-leak-teases-special-edition-pricing.889011/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-leak-teases-special-edition-pricing/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>In <a href="https://x.com/billbil_kun/status/1797968974560518366" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a new post</a> on Twitter/X, consistently reliable leaker @billbil_kun claimed that Dragon Ball: Sparking Zero is getting an Ultimate Edition.</p>



<p>The post also adds that this special edition will be available in physical format, and that it should have a price tag of $109.99. There were no further details about a release window, or other potential editions. </p>



<p>However, the leaker did reiterate that Dragon Ball: Sparking Zero is coming to Summer Game Fest 2024. Insider Gaming can corroborate that the game will be at Summer Game Fest, with retailers ready to put pre-order information live. </p>



<p>It’s unclear if the devs will reveal more information during the event. Summer Game Fest 2024 will premiere later this week on June 7, and it will feature <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/summer-game-fest-2024/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">2 hours of game showcases</a>. </p>



<figure><div>
<blockquote data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>🚨 EDITION &amp; PRICE REVEAL 🚨</p><p>DRAGON BALL: Sparking! ZERO Ultimate Edition<br>(Also available in physical disc)</p><p>Price: 109.99$</p><p>More details on Summer Game Fest 2024 <a href="https://t.co/9RMl0AwBkr">pic.twitter.com/9RMl0AwBkr</a></p></div>— billbil-kun (@billbil_kun) <a href="https://twitter.com/billbil_kun/status/1797968974560518366?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 4, 2024</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>



<p>Bandai Namco announced Dragon Ball: Sparking Zero <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/every-new-game-announced-at-the-game-awards/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">at The Game Awards 2023</a>. Last March, the devs also revealed a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/bandai-namco-reveals-dragon-ball-sparking-zero-roster-and-features/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">promising roster of fighters</a> and key features. That included some big changes, such as a movement boost and new fighting mechanics.</p>



<p>It’s unclear which platforms the Ultimate Edition is coming to, as well as the potential components it will include. However, such editions frequently add exclusive figures, original soundtracks, art books, and more. Such content would certainly help justify the leaker’s claimed price tag. </p>



<p>Billbil-kun has successfully leaked a variety of gaming information. That includes the recent <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/astro-bot-officially-announced-at-playstation-state-of-play/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Astro Bot game announcement</a> from PlayStation’s State of Play event.</p>



<p>Dragon Ball: Sparking Zero will be available on PC via Steam, PlayStation 5, and the Xbox Series X|S. At this time, Bandai Namco has not confirmed anything about the Dragon Ball: Sparking Zero Ultimate Edition or its pricing.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more of the latest gaming industry news, you can read about Prime Video announcing a new live action <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/like-a-dragon-yakuza-series-amazon/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Like a Dragon: Yakuza adaptation</a>, and sign up to receive the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/newsletter/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming newsletter</a>.</p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GTA 6 Trailer At Summer Game Fest Is Not Happening]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-6-trailer-at-summer-game-fest-is-not-happening/1100-6523913/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gta-6-trailer-at-summer-game-fest-is-not-happening.889008/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-6-trailer-at-summer-game-fest-is-not-happening/1100-6523913/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6523913">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>The big Summer Game Fest showcase takes place this Friday, June 7, and people are naturally wondering what they should expect in terms of reveals and announcements. Geoff Keighley, who organzes the show, has now offered some insight into what won't be on hand at the briefing.</p><p><a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/heres-what-we-know-wont-be-at-summer-game-fest" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">As reported by IGN</a>, Keighley confirmed there will be no <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/grand-theft-auto-6-everything-we-know/1100-6503729/" data-ref-id="1100-6503729">Grand Theft Auto VI</a> trailer during Summer Game Fest. It's been more than six months since the first GTA VI trailer was released in December 2023, so some people believed it might be time for the next trailer or any other information. Apparently that's not going to happen, though, and GTA fans will have to wait a while longer.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FZ2Clscn0Jg" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/FZ2Clscn0Jg" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>Keighley also said there won't be Kingdom Hearts 4 news or any reveals for Ken Levine's new game, Judas. Beyond Good &amp; Evil 2 also won't show up, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/dont-expect-a-just-one-more-thing-at-summer-game-fest-live/1100-6523883/" data-ref-id="1100-6523883">nor will there be a big "one more thing" announcement to cap off the event.</a></p><p>In terms of what will be on display during Summer Game Fest, Keighley said there will be announcements regarding updates to existing games, including Palworld and Kingdom Come: Deliverance II. New trailers for Monster Hunter Wilds and Batman: Arkham VR will be on display as well. As for brand-new announcements, Keighley said Blumhouse Games will have something to reveal, while the showcase will debut the first footage of the Among Us animated series.</p><p>Summer Game Fest 2024 takes place place on Friday, June 7 at 2 PM PT / 5 PM ET. The show will now take the spot formerly held by E3, the long-running video game trade show once seen as the premier event in gaming, which was <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/e3-is-permanently-canceled/1100-6519882/">permanently canceled</a> last year.</p><p>Following Summer Game Fest will be the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/xbox-games-showcase-2024-how-to-watch-start-times-and-what-to-expect/1100-6523915/" data-ref-id="1100-6523915">Xbox Games Showcase event on June 9, with a Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 reveal event</a> to follow immediately after. Then on June 10, Ubisoft will host its <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ubisoft-forward-2024-how-to-watch-start-times-and-what-to-expect/1100-6523848/" data-ref-id="1100-6523848">Ubisoft Forward event with news on Assassin's Creed Shadows, XDefiant, and Star Wars Outlaws.</a></p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What do Apple and Google’s direct-to-consumer changes really mean for game developers?]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamesindustry.biz/what-do-apple-and-googles-direct-to-consumer-changes-really-mean-for-game-developers</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/what-do-apple-and-google%E2%80%99s-direct-to-consumer-changes-really-mean-for-game-developers.889005/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamesindustry.biz/what-do-apple-and-googles-direct-to-consumer-changes-really-mean-for-game-developers<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        

        <p>FastSpring also shares advice on how studios can best adopt direct-to-consumer payment solutions</p>

    </div><div>



            <p>The direct-to-consumer payment landscape for mobile game developers is changing. Rapidly. Courts and regulators in both the EU and the US have taken issue with Google and Apple's app store monopolies, which means in the near future, mobile game developers may no longer have to mandatorily surrender a 30% cut on all in-game purchases.</p>
<p>Traditionally, selling in-game items or virtual currency through an external webshop has generally been allowed without additional fees by Apple and Google, so long as you don’t embed payments directly inside your mobile game, or steer players with calls-to-action inside the game to buy items from an external webshop.</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/david-nachman.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption>David Nachman, FastSpring</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Recent regulatory and legal pressure has forced Apple and Google to make concessions on embedded payments. However, these concessions have come with prohibitively high fees that negate most of the financial value of direct-to-consumer. This has spurred lawsuits from app and game publishers like Epic, Spotify, and others, which will further increase pressure. Other game publishers are still in wait-and-see mode as these lawsuits play out.</p>
<p>That said, direct-to-consumer is still a viable growth strategy for mobile game publishers, and there are many excellent examples of success to learn from including Warner Bros' Game of Thrones Conquest, Scopely’s Marvel Strikeforce, and the Supercell store.</p>
<p>How can developers monetise their mobile games with direct-to-consumer today? Well, that's a little more complicated. The freedom of monetizing with direct-to-consumer comes with the complexities of global payment methods, currency localisation, and local sales tax/VAT compliance, all of which need to be scrupulously observed to ensure you don't fall foul of the law. This is where the convenience of a direct-to-consumer payments specialist like FastSpring comes in, saving you not only time but considerable money, too. While it focuses on your payments (and, importantly, fraud prevention), you can stay focused on making great games.</p>
<blockquote><p>"The freedom of monetizing with direct-to-consumer comes with the complexities of global payment methods, currency localisation, and local sales tax compliance</p></blockquote>
<p>"Video game publishers have numerous options when it comes to direct-to-consumer payment providers, making it challenging to determine the best choice," admits David Nachman, CEO of FastSpring. FastSpring is a Merchant of Record (MoR) payment provider, which mean it's a trusted third-party firm that assumes responsibility for processing your payments, and sales tax compliance worldwide. It has almost two decades of experience providing payment solutions to publishers unsure about how best to navigate the complexities of global payments and sales tax compliance.</p>
<p>"Our solution seamlessly integrates payments either directly within video games or on a publisher's webshop. Our comprehensive service facilitates payments through multiple global processors to ensure optimal approval rates, offers a wide variety of payment methods around the globe, manages all global sales tax and VAT compliance automatically, offers robust video game-specific fraud prevention, provides dedicated customer support, and much more."</p>
<p>Nachman says that whilst there's been a lot of progress with lawsuits like Epic v. Google – for which FastSpring was called upon to provide evidence – there's still a lot for developers and publishers to consider even without looming app store rule changes around direct-to-consumer.</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Screenshot-2024-06-03-at-7.08.19AM.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption>FastSpring can help developers go direct-to-consumer</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Because of its 19 years of experience as an all-in-one payments provider, FastSpring considers itself uniquely placed to "allow video game publishers to spend more time making great games and less time selling them." Thanks to its specialized knowledge of local payment methods, video game-specific fraud prevention, and tax compliance, FastSpring has even helped game developers and publishers break into new markets.</p>
<p>"Marketplaces serve as excellent platforms for reaching new audiences for games, while simultaneously offloading the complexities of payment processing and tax compliance. Game studios simply upload their game to the marketplace and receive their earnings monthly," Nachman explains, acknowledging that a lot of game studios use the familiar method of selling their games through Steam, the PlayStation, Xbox, and Nintendo online stores, and/or mobile app stores.</p>
<p>"But for game publishers considering a move beyond marketplaces to direct-to-consumer sales, FastSpring is a great choice because we offer many of the payment and tax compliance benefits of a marketplace thanks to our comprehensive all-in-one platform and Merchant of Record model.</p>
<p>"Like a marketplace, the MoR model offloads the burdens of payment processing and tax compliance. However, it does so within an experience directly embedded in your game or on your webshop, and at a significantly lower cost than marketplaces."</p>
<p>As for publishers already selling directly to their players? FastSpring can still help there, too; its global payments coverage enables studios to expand into all-new markets "or as a redundant provider in their existing payment stack to leverage FastSpring’s high approval rates, or simply as a failover option."</p>
<blockquote><p>"FastSpring is a great choice because we offer many of the payment and tax compliance benefits of a marketplace"</p></blockquote>
<p>While FastSpring is ready to help with direct-to-consumer strategies today, Nachman said FastSpring is still committed to the fight for open commerce in mobile with embedded payments and steering allowed without additional fees in the future.</p>
<p>When the Google vs Epic ruling came down last December, Nachman was quick to respond, stating he and FastSpring were "ecstatic that game developers will have more choice in how they bring their games to market." He called it "a major win" that he suspected would "have a huge impact on gamers across the industry" and enable devs "to deliver better games and pricing for their players." And it's this commitment to consumer choice and developer freedoms that FastSpring champions most.</p>
<p>"At FastSpring, we support open computing and believe that people should have choice when installing games and software on their phones," Nachman explains. "We also believe that game developers should have choice over the payment solutions they support in their games.</p>
<p>"Apple and Google have been responding to the recent lawsuits and regulations by updating their terms to 'comply' but these changes so far have resulted in a great big juicy nothing-burger," Nachman adds. The recent app store term changes – which include a 28% fee for transactions that happen outside of the app and a limited ability to load apps outside the respective app stores – include "mind-bending gotchas" that essentially negate any material benefit for players or game developers.</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Screenshot-2024-06-03-at-7.07.43AM.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption>Supercell operates its own store</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>It's because of this that Nachman expects, in the short term, to see game companies start aggressively pushing the line in their direct-to-consumer strategies with mobile games "now that weaknesses have emerged", along with further lawsuits protesting the recent app store terms changes.</p>
<p>In the mid-to-long term, he opines that ongoing lawsuits may force even more changes to app store terms and conditions that are more in line with rulings and regulations.</p>
<p>"One thing we can confidently predict is that Apple and Google will keep fighting to protect their global duopoly, and everyone else will keep fighting for choice," Nachman insists.</p>
<p>To learn more about FastSpring’s global payments and subscription management platform, get in touch <a href="https://fastspring.com/solutions/gaming/" rel="sponsored" target="_blank">via the website</a>.</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PSVR 2 PC adapter to launch on August 7]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamesindustry.biz/psvr-2-pc-adapter-to-launch-on-august-7</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/psvr-2-pc-adapter-to-launch-on-august-7.889002/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamesindustry.biz/psvr-2-pc-adapter-to-launch-on-august-7<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        

        <p>The device will give access to Steam's VR library from PlayStation's headset</p>

    </div><div>



            <p>Sony is set to launch a PC adapter for its PlayStation VR 2 headset this August.</p>
<p>Scheduled for release on August 7, the adapter will give PSVR 2 players access to Steam's library of VR titles, which includes Half-Life: Alyx, Fallout 4 VR, and more.</p>
<p>The adapter will be available from PlayStation's own store and "select retailers," Sony said, and will have a $59.99 / €59.99 / £49.99 price tag.</p>
<p>In order to have access to Steam's VR library from a PSVR 2, players will also need a DisplayPort cable compatible with DisplayPort 1.4 (that needs purchasing separately), a Steam account, and a PC meeting the minimum requirements detailed in <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2024/06/03/playstation-vr2-players-can-access-games-on-pc-with-adapter-starting-on-august-7/">Sony's blog post</a>.</p>
<p>"PSVR 2 was designed from the ground up specifically for PS5 – so you'll notice that some key features, like HDR, headset feedback, eye tracking, adaptive triggers, and haptic feedback (other than rumble), are not available when playing on PC," Sony's principal product manager Yasuo Takahashi clarified in the announcement.</p>
<p>He added: "While the most immersive way to experience PSVR 2 gaming remains on PS5, we hope players will enjoy the ability to play an expanded lineup of VR games on PC using the same headset."</p>
<p>The PSVR 2 launched on February 22, 2023 and <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/psvr-2-sold-just-shy-of-600000-units-in-six-weeks">sold just shy of 600,000 units in six weeks</a>. The virtual reality headset hasn't been a breakaway success, with reports in March 2024 pointing to <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/sony-reportedly-stops-psvr-2-production-to-clear-the-current-backlog">Sony halting production</a> in order to clear its current backlog of unsold devices.</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Like A Dragon: Yakuza' Live-Action Series Hits Amazon Prime Video This October]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gameinformer.com/news/2024/06/04/like-a-dragon-yakuza-live-action-series-hits-amazon-prime-video-this-october</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/like-a-dragon-yakuza-live-action-series-hits-amazon-prime-video-this-october.888999/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gameinformer.com/news/2024/06/04/like-a-dragon-yakuza-live-action-series-hits-amazon-prime-video-this-october<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p>Amazon has announced <em>Like a Dragon: Yakuza</em>, a live-action television series adaptation of Ryu Ga Gotoku Studios and Sega's long-running Like a Dragon (formerly Yakuza) series. It will be a story centered on series mainstay Kazuma Kiryu and will follow his life in 1995 and 2005 across six episodes.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The first three episodes drop Oct. 25 and the last three episodes hit Amazon Prime Video on Nov. 1, and, according to&nbsp;<a href="https://variety.com/2024/tv/news/like-a-dragon-yakuza-live-action-series-sega-game-prime-video-1236024275/"><em>Variety</em></a>, the series will be subbed and dubbed in 30 languages.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The logline for the series describes it as a story set in two time periods – 1995 and 2005 – and follows the life, childhood friendships, and repercussions of the decisions of Kazuma Kiryu, a Yakuza warrior with a strong sense of justice, duty, and humanity. If you're familiar with the series, given the time periods at play here, it sounds like <em>Like a Dragon: Yakuza</em> could be loosely adapting the storyline of Yakuza 1.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Take Masaharu (<em>100 Yen Love</em>) is directing the series alongside Takimoto Kengo (<i>Kamen Rider</i>), and stars Takeuchi Ryoma (various&nbsp;<em>Kamen Rider&nbsp;</em>movies and series) as Kazuma Kiryu. You can see him in the image below:</p>












<article data-embed-button="image_browser_uploader" data-entity-embed-display="view_mode:file.body_default_rendered" data-entity-type="file" data-entity-uuid="e428a1da-2e12-4759-895e-e02d4a81a896" data-langcode="en" data-entity-embed-display-settings="[]">





</article><p><em>Variety&nbsp;</em>reports <em>Like a Dragon: Yakuza</em> will "depict the lives of fierce yet passionate gangsters and people living in a huge entertainment district,&nbsp;Kamurochō, a fictional district modeled after the violent Shinjuku ward's&nbsp;Kabukichō, that acts as the backdrop of the gameplay." Amazon says the series "showcases modern Japan and the dramatic stories of these intense characters, such as the legendary Kazuma Kiryu, that games in the past have not been able to explore."&nbsp;</p>

<p>Ryu Ga Gotoku Studios studio head and series executive producer Yokoyama Masayoshi told&nbsp;<em>Variety&nbsp;</em>the following:&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Since the day I first put pen to paper on the original Yakuza script, I've never once thought about revisitng any of my work on the series. It's because I understand all too well the challenges and hardships that come with remaking a finished title. However, if I were ever sent to the past through some kind of cosmic joke, this is the experience I'd want to create. If I had to go through the wringer anyhow, I'd want to make the most engaging versions of&nbsp;Kamurochō and Kazuma Kiryu I could - and this show has it all.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"While the games let you experience their world through the subjective lens, this adaptation will be the ultimately objective way to enjoy the show. I have no doubt fans of the series will be drawn to how it brings the games to life and adds new surprises. Newcomers, I'm sure, will find themselves invested simply in the gritty realism of the show."&nbsp;</p>

<p><em>Like a Dragon: Yakuza </em>hits Amazonz Prime Video starting on Oct. 25 and will finish on Nov. 1 this year.&nbsp;</p>

<p>News of this series follows the release of <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/product/like-a-dragon-infinite-wealth">Like a Dragon: Infinite Wealth</a>, the eighth mainline installment in the video game series, back in January. You can read&nbsp;<a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/review/like-a-dragon-infinite-wealth/passing-the-torch"><em>Game Informer's&nbsp;</em>Like a Dragon: Infinite Wealth review here</a>. After that, read&nbsp;<a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/feature/2022/11/24/the-future-of-ryu-ga-gotoku-studio"><em>Game Informer's&nbsp;</em>exclusive interview with the leads behind the Like a Dragon series</a> to learn about the future of Ryu Ga Gotoku studio while visiting its offices.&nbsp;</p>

<hr><p><em>Are you excited about Like a Dragon: Yakuza? Let us know in the comments below!</em></p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dig into Magical Delicacy, a delicious Metroidvania-lite, when it’s served next month]]></title>
            <link>https://www.destructoid.com/dig-into-magical-delicacy-a-delicious-metroidvania-lite-when-its-served-next-month/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=dig-into-magical-delicacy-a-delicious-metroidvania-lite-when-its-served-next-month</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dig-into-magical-delicacy-a-delicious-metroidvania-lite-when-it%E2%80%99s-served-next-month.888996/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.destructoid.com/dig-into-magical-delicacy-a-delicious-metroidvania-lite-when-its-served-next-month/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=dig-into-magical-delicacy-a-delicious-metroidvania-lite-when-its-served-next-month<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p data-characters="243" data-injectable="true" data-video="true">Publisher Whitethorn Games has revealed when fans can get their hungry hands on Skaule’s upcoming main course of a Metroidvania-lite, <em>Magical Delicacy</em>. The game will be available on July 16, offering a new, wholesome twist on the genre. </p> <p data-characters="616" data-current-count="616" data-injectable="true">In just over a month, you’ll be able to get cooking with <em>Magical Delicacy</em> on PC, Nintendo Switch, Xbox One, and Xbox Series X/S from day one. You can even get the game on Xbox Game Pass the same day, meaning there are plenty of places you can settle down to consume its meaty gameplay. The story reminds me very much of <em>Kiki’s Delivery Service</em> as protagonist Flora, a young witch, arrives in the town of Grat to develop her magical skills. As we all know, though, training as a witch is never straightforward, and Grat has several mysteries to get caught up in and a colorful cast of characters to meet. </p>
 <h2 id="h-players-will-collect-recipes-and-ingredients-build-their-dream-kitchen-and-serve-the-local-townsfolk-in-magical-delicacy" data-injectable="false">Players will collect recipes and ingredients, build their dream kitchen, and serve the local townsfolk in <em>Magical Delicacy</em></h2> <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"><p> <iframe title="Magical Delicacy Release Date | PC, Nintendo Switch, Xbox" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Mn-5KMaEJuw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe> </p></figure> <p data-characters="420" data-current-count="720" data-injectable="true">While we don’t know how Flora comes to Grat, once there, she settles down and sets up shop to deliver potions and home-cooked meals to the local townsfolk. <em>Magical Delicacy</em> is a Metroidvania-lite, borrowing some <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/10-best-metroidvania-games-you-can-play-now/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">elements from the genre</a>, such as unlocking tools for gradual progression, while using others, such as 2D platforming and NPC relationships, to help build out the overarching story and linear questline. </p>
 <p data-characters="432" data-current-count="432" data-injectable="true">The core gameplay revolves around cooking and gathering ingredients. Some can be purchased, while others must be foraged from around Grat. As you progress, you’ll unlock new potions and recipes that will open up new areas of the town and access to new townsfolk. Some of these recipes will require kitchen upgrades, but you’ll get to build it as you play until it feels like your ideal countryside cottage cooking area. </p>
 <p data-characters="382" data-current-count="382" data-injectable="false"><em>Magical Delicacy</em>‘s cooking system isn’t a simple one-button affair. It’s pretty complex and allows for experimentation as you figure out what to cook for every individual you meet. As you move through the story, new ingredients, processes, and recipes only make it more in-depth, but based on the trailer, it seems to replicate cooking in the kitchen fairly well. </p> <p data-characters="444" data-current-count="826" data-injectable="true">Whitethorn Games boasts that, much like a good soup, there’s more to Grat than meets the eye. While cooking and serving the townsfolk is one objective, you’ll lose yourself in others, including meeting ancient figures of legend or old masters of their craft who have long been forgotten. It sounds to me like Flora will help modern-day townsfolk understand more about Grat’s past in a similar way to how you did in <em><a href="https://www.destructoid.com/reviews/review-spirittea/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Spirittea</a></em>. </p>
 <p data-characters="540" data-current-count="540" data-injectable="false">What I believe is special about <em><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2231190/Magical_Delicacy/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Magical Delicacy</a></em> is that it takes what is often the heart of a family’s day, sitting around a table together to talk about their day and share a meal, and turns it into an entire game. Flora may cook multiple meals, but it’s the cooking that brings the townsfolk out of their shells and helps you, as the player, understand and appreciate Grat. Just like in real life, food can help you integrate with a small community because it’s a great leveler. After all, everyone’s got to eat. </p>

<hr>
<p><i data-stringify-type="italic"> Destructoid is supported by our audience. When you purchase through links on our site, we may earn a small affiliate commission.&nbsp;</i><i data-stringify-type="italic"><a href="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-stringify-link="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" data-sk="tooltip_parent">Learn more</a></i> </p>

</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mech Engineer's demo is for people who love hateful interface design]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/mech-engineers-demo-is-for-people-who-love-hateful-interface-design</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mech-engineers-demo-is-for-people-who-love-hateful-interface-design.888981/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/mech-engineers-demo-is-for-people-who-love-hateful-interface-design<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>



            <p>
If you heard loud swearing last night in the Watford area it may have been one of two things: 1) me cussing out my (borrowed) Steam Deck while stealthily accessing the wifi from outside a closed public library, as I don't currently have broadband at home, or 2) me subsequently trying to make head or tail of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/mech-engineer">Mech Engineer</a>, in which you take charge of a mobile undersea metropolis and send squads of painstakingly assembled robosoldiers to semi-auto-battle squidgy alien fauna. 
</p>
<p>
Engineering a mech is a Herculean labour whose completion eludes today's puny scientists, and Mech Engineer doesn't aim to make life easier, whatever its putative status as a "means of fun". Mech Engineer is a game with an attitude problem, frankly. I realised this on in-game day two, when the interface coughed up a bunch of damage reports presented as pieces of paper, which I then had to crumple up and toss away individually.
</p>
<!--more-->
<p>
That interface! There's an innocent 30 seconds initially when you think it's just badly designed. But then you realise that it is a creature of foul and labyrinthine purpose. Broadly, it consists of a Dwarf Fortressy grid-based world map, where you can shunt your city about and send mech squads on missions, with tabs for researching new components, fabricating them, and assembling them into conveniently coffin-sized Gundams you can then fill with pilots. There's a calendar which lets you advance to the next day. Reading those sentences back, it sounds practically transparent. Like XCOM but with extra robots, right? Wrong! Mech Engineer is nothing like XCOM. It is like tying your shoelaces with a pair of scissors. It is like doing jigsaw puzzles in a cesspit after the death of the sun.
</p>
<p>
When I mentioned Mech Engineer to Graham he said it reminded him of MicroProse's older interface 'em ups, in which the thrill arises from the quasi-analog, high-fidelity obfuscatoriness of the simulation itself. I subsequently went away and discovered that yes, MicroProse is Mech Engineer's publisher. I do not have the benefit of Graham's greatly advanced years and accompanying experience of recreational inconvenience, but to me Mech Engineer feels almost like a parody of MicroProse's games on par with <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/space-warlord-organ-trading-simulator">Space Warlord Organ Trading Simulator</a>. 
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Mech Engineer 1.0 Launch Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6RT8ijnoUak?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Mech Engineer 1.0 Launch Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6RT8ijnoUak?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/6RT8ijnoUak?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6RT8ijnoUak" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>
The interface is a sour quagmire of analog dials, submarine-style viewports, wireframe graphs and incomprehensible LED readouts, laid out in violent contradiction of present day notions of "flow", with several ways of flipping between screens that compete for your attention constantly, on-screen buttons in place of keyboard controls, a habit of miniaturising the most important elements, and a relentless desire to overcomplicate every little interaction. Again, you might think it to be poorly made, but it's very obviously a labour of love. Each individual fitting has a just-so exactness, from the monochrome firing range simulator through the authentically papery bestiary and landscape illustrations, to the sheer range of alarm SFX and mechanical reports that blare from the guts of the beast as you tootle about pressing the wrong bits and getting your pilots slaughtered.  
</p>
<p>
The actual mech engineering is in-depth and seems engrossing. For instance: you have to construct, test and ignite a mech's reactor before slotting it into the chassis, which feels vaguely cathartic - like putting the cherry on a carefully optimised cake's worth of delicately thinned-out armour plating, optional energy shields, and chonky Gatling guns that can themselves be tweaked and whittled to satisfaction. Battle, meanwhile, is fairly hands-off and visually reminiscent of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/duskers">Duskers</a>: you give your squad waypoints and fiddle with things like spacing while they shoot at Space Invaders in real-time on a scratchy radar display, until they run out of ammo or crumple under the stress. 
</p>
<p>
Your pilots have animated portraits, and my word, they are an unsightly bunch even before you feed them to the extra-terrestrials - not so much an army of Doomguys as a cluster of chatbot gargoyles gawping at you from the abyss. Again, there's a just-so feel to it all that hooks my curiosity even as I whinny in anguish, uninstall the demo in a frenzy, and race back to the library at midnight to download something gentler, like <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/i-made-the-witchy-cottage-of-my-dreams-in-tiny-glade">Tiny Glade</a>. Mech Engineer! How I loathe you, especially as I've just realised that <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-rally-point-putting-mech-engineer-on-trial-and-error">Sin wrote you up three years ago</a> - honestly, it sounds like the only thing that has really changed in the meantime is that you can now <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1428520/Mech_Engineer/">buy the full thing on Steam</a>.</p>




        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hypercharge Unboxed Sells 40,000 Copies in 4 Days on Xbox]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/hypercharge-unboxed/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hypercharge-unboxed-sells-40-000-copies-in-4-days-on-xbox.888978/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/hypercharge-unboxed/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>Hypercharge Unboxed by Digital Cybercherries Limited is out now on Xbox Series X/S and Xbox One.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If you have ever seen a reel or a TikTok of a game where a bunch of toys are causing chaos with weapons in the middle of a toy store, then you know about Hypercharge Unboxed. The 2020 multiplayer and offline shooter is now officially available through the Xbox store. The game is an indie project that has been developed by a team of 6 people and was first available only through <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/523660/HYPERCHARGE_Unboxed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Steam</a>. Commendably, Hypercharge Unboxed has sold more than 40,000 copies within 4 days of its release on the Xbox Store, as per Jake Lucky on X (formerly Twitter).&nbsp;</p>



<figure><div>
<blockquote data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">The viral game where you play as action figures in a toy store is officially out on Xbox, selling over 40,000 copies in it's first 4 days, a dream accomplished for the lead of this indie dev project <a href="https://t.co/KFjo6tkfBx">pic.twitter.com/KFjo6tkfBx</a></p>— Jake Lucky (@JakeSucky) <a href="https://twitter.com/JakeSucky/status/1797666996135555270?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 3, 2024</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>



<p>Talking about the game, the story revolves around an ancient line of action figures that allows humans to retain their childhood memories with their toys through a magical power called Hypercore. In this first and third-person shooter, you get to play as action figures as you fight against hordes of weaponized toys and save the Hypercore from a villainous faction called Major Evil.&nbsp;</p>



<figure>
<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>
</figure>



<p>Moreover, Hypercharge Unboxed features online as well as offline co-op for up to 2-4 players with cross-platform play. The player needs to team up to gather resources, stronger weapons, and mysteries between the waves of enemies to progress. There are two editions of the game available on the Xbox Store. The <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/hypercharge-unboxed/9ngk4zhkbc8x" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Standard Edition</a> provides the base game at the price of $29.99. The second version is the <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/hypercharge-complete-edition/9PPMRSZ3CS7P/0010" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Complete Edition</a> of the game, which includes the contents of the standard edition along with a Supporter Pack and Breaker &amp; Mightus pack. These packs include the following: Breaker action figure, Migtus action figure, Classic Hypercharge action figure, Roadwarrior action figure, more than 18 skins, and weapon materials.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What are your views on Hypercharge Unboxed? Let us know in the comments. </p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read&nbsp;about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/newsletter/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">GAME shutting down its reward scheme</a>, and don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/newsletter/">subscribe to the Insider Gaming Newsletter</a>.<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/league-of-legends-source-code-stolen-from-riot-games/?relatedposts_hit=1&amp;relatedposts_origin=42839&amp;relatedposts_position=0&amp;relatedposts_hit=1&amp;relatedposts_origin=42839&amp;relatedposts_position=0&amp;relatedposts_hit=1&amp;relatedposts_origin=42839&amp;relatedposts_position=0"></a></p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MultiVersus Tournament Player Sees Their Main Character Pulled From the Game Mid-Bracket, Wins Anyway]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/multiversus-tournament-player-sees-their-main-character-pulled-from-the-game-mid-bracket-wins-anyway</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/multiversus-tournament-player-sees-their-main-character-pulled-from-the-game-mid-bracket-wins-anyway.888975/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/multiversus-tournament-player-sees-their-main-character-pulled-from-the-game-mid-bracket-wins-anyway<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>A <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/multiversus">MultiVersus</a> players had to react fast after the developer pulled their main character out of the game in the middle of a tournament.</p><p>A post on the MultiVersus X/Twitter account signaled the removal of Iron Giant from the recently released brawler due to various issues with the character, which players believe include overpowered combos and an infinite chain grab. Garnet was added to the Preview Rotation in response.</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Thank you MVPs for alerting us about the current issues surrounding Iron Giant. We have decided to bring him back into the shop for maintenance. During this time, you will not be able to play with him, but we are working diligently and will update you next week on his status. In…</p>— MultiVersus (@multiversus) <a href="https://twitter.com/multiversus/status/1797780234680569867?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">June 3, 2024</a></blockquote> <p>Fair enough, you’d think. But for one MultiVersus player the removal of Iron Giant couldn’t have come at a worse time. As revealed in an <a href="https://x.com/NickSF_SSB/status/1797790657047863488" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">X/Twitter post by @NickSF_SSB</a>, co-owner of No Style eSports, a player going by the name of ‘FlaSHFReeeze’ was in the middle of a bracket when their main, Iron Giant, was pulled from the game. Cue bemused conversation between the two players. Brilliantly, FlaSHFReeeze switched character and won the set anyway, proving that fighting game players always need a backup in case of emergency.</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">He still won the set tho <a href="https://t.co/ZpsFR7Tlyz" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/ZpsFR7Tlyz</a></p>— NS | NickSF 🔜 Solar Flare &amp; Sunrise 2024 (@NickSF_SSB) <a href="https://twitter.com/NickSF_SSB/status/1797797020012511410?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">June 4, 2024</a></blockquote> <p>This week, developer Player First Games said <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/multiversus-dev-bringing-back-some-missing-features">a number of missing features are on their way back to MultiVersus</a>. After close to a year long hiatus, the Warner Bros. brawler featuring Gizmo from Gremlins, Rick and Morty, Lebron James, Batman, Arya Stark, Bugs Bunny, Shaggy, Tom and Jerry, Jason, and more <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/multiversus-relaunch-draws-many-players-and-many-complaints"><u>returned in May 2024 to many players and many complaints</u></a>.</p><p>"Some of the missing settings and features from the open beta are incoming," wrote game director Tony Huynh on <a href="https://x.com/Tony_Huynh/status/1796903400497684726?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>X/Twitter</u></a>. "Team colors, end of game stats, swapping side and neutral attack, adjustable input buffer settings, etc."</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div><h3>MultiVersus Joker Reveal</h3></div></output><p>Huynh then said the team didn't have time to add these features during Multiversus's offline period. "Many of these features are currently implemented and are in testing and we had planned, but were left out due to time as we had to rebuild every screen and feature again to support our new netcode and Unreal Engine 5 switch," he explained.</p><p>No timeframe for the features was given, though as Huynh said more information is coming soon, the actual release may not be imminent.</p><p><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[XDefiant leaker claims two Assassin’s Creed maps could be coming soon]]></title>
            <link>https://www.destructoid.com/xdefiant-leaker-claims-two-assassins-creed-maps-could-be-coming-soon/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=xdefiant-leaker-claims-two-assassins-creed-maps-could-be-coming-soon</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/xdefiant-leaker-claims-two-assassin%E2%80%99s-creed-maps-could-be-coming-soon.888972/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.destructoid.com/xdefiant-leaker-claims-two-assassins-creed-maps-could-be-coming-soon/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=xdefiant-leaker-claims-two-assassins-creed-maps-could-be-coming-soon<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p data-characters="259" data-injectable="true" data-video="true"><em>XDefiant</em> is Ubisoft’s attempt at creating a <em>Call of Duty</em> killer, but the company has so much more locked away in its IP vault. That’s why it should be no surprise that a leaker has discovered mentions of maps themed around <em>Assassin’s Creed</em>. </p> <p data-characters="321" data-current-count="321" data-injectable="false"><em>CoD</em> is well-known for its weird and wacky crossovers these days, so it’s not a huge shock that <em>XDefiant</em> aims to follow that pattern too. It’s easier when you own a lot of IP as well, as Ubisoft does, so getting them into your game is much easier and doesn’t require negotiations with the rights owners. </p> <p data-characters="296" data-current-count="617" data-injectable="true">According to Rogue, an <em>XDefiant</em> dataminer, two <em>Assassin’s Creed</em> maps should appear in the game at some point in the future, with the leaker posting a clip featuring sounds from the maps, while also stating that they had found a “good amount of things related to” the locations. </p>
 <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"></figure> <p data-characters="410" data-current-count="710" data-injectable="true">It would definitely be interesting to see what those maps would look like, with all of the <em>Assassin’s Creed</em> maps set well in the past. Whether we would see locations from history or maps based on the more modern-day story that is expected to feature in <em>Assassin’s Creed: Infinity</em>. Other leaks have suggested that a new faction called The Brotherhood could also be linked to the long-running series.</p>
 <p data-characters="322" data-current-count="322" data-injectable="false">Of course, it’s worth remembering that these are leaks and rumors, and haven’t been confirmed by Ubisoft. Therefore, it’s worth taking all of this information with a pinch of salt until we get official word from the developers. Still, it’s hard not to let your imagination run wild at the thought. </p>
<hr>
<p><i data-stringify-type="italic"> Destructoid is supported by our audience. When you purchase through links on our site, we may earn a small affiliate commission.&nbsp;</i><i data-stringify-type="italic"><a href="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-stringify-link="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" data-sk="tooltip_parent">Learn more</a></i> </p>

</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ikea is hiring UK workers for its new store in Roblox]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/ikea-is-hiring-uk-workers-for-its-new-store-in-roblox</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ikea-is-hiring-uk-workers-for-its-new-store-in-roblox.888966/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/ikea-is-hiring-uk-workers-for-its-new-store-in-roblox<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>



            <p>Swedish store and home of flatpack furniture Ikea is hiring 10 people from the UK and Ireland to assist with the running of a virtual store in Roblox.</p>
<p>As spotted by <a href="https://www.thegamer.com/ikea-hiring-roblox-players-run-virtual-in-game-store/">TheGamer</a>, this virtual store is part of a "Careers Done Different" campaign, which Ikea hopes will demonstrate possible career paths available within the company.</p>
<p>Successful candidates will be able to serve meatballs in the store's bistro, and help patrons choose furniture in the showroom. As for pay, Ikea is offering an hourly wage of £13.15/€14.80 for this obviously fully remote, limited contract position.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="PlayStation upsets VR fans as it kicks off this year's not-E3 hype cycle" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ev55ao9pf4M?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>PlayStation upsets VR fans as it kicks off this year's not-E3 hype cycle</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ev55ao9pf4M?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/ev55ao9pf4M?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Newscast: PlayStation upsets VR fans as it kicks off this year's not-E3 hype cycle<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ev55ao9pf4M" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>"With us, you have the opportunity to move departments, flex your skill and get promoted," the application's <a href="https://thecoworker.co.uk/">website</a> reads. "At Ikea, career progression is unique because you can grow in any direction. We believe in recruiting people based on our values rather than simply ticking all the right boxes on a CV."</p>
<p>To apply, those interested will need to answer a range of questions including the deeply insightful: "How do you feel about being turned into pixels?" Applicants will also need to think about what they would do if the bistro ran out of pixelated hot dogs during their shift.</p>
<figure data-count="2" role="group">
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Ikea-Roblox.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
</figure>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Roblox-Ikea.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
</figure>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Ikea</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>It is not just Ikea that is using Roblox to expand its reach. <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/netflix-unveils-digital-theme-park-nextworld-on-roblox">Netflix is also coming to Roblox</a>, with the streaming giant recently revealing its "digital theme park" on the gaming platform, known as Nextworld. This will essentially acts as a hub where players can access areas, characters and games based on Netflix properties, such as Stranger Things and One Piece.</p>
<p>For more on Roblox, our Chris Tapsell recently spoke with the studio's head Stefano Corazza about concerns the game exploits children. You can <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/roblox-studio-boss-children-making-money-on-the-platform-isnt-exploitation-its-a-gift">read the full interview here</a>.</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Suda51 says he doesn't know if we'll ever see No More Heroes' Travis Touchdown again]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/suda51-says-he-doesnt-know-if-well-ever-see-no-more-heroes-travis-touchdown-again</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/suda51-says-he-doesnt-know-if-well-ever-see-no-more-heroes-travis-touchdown-again.888960/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/suda51-says-he-doesnt-know-if-well-ever-see-no-more-heroes-travis-touchdown-again<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Untitled-111.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Grasshopper Manufacture</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
Legendary game designer Goichi "Suda51" Suda has said he doesn't know if the world will ever see No More Heroes or its star Travis Touchdown again, following the launch of 2021's climactic No More Heroes 3.
</p>
<p>
Speaking to Eurogamer ahead of his appearance at MomoCon 2024 last month, No More Heroes creator and director Suda acknowledged that the rights to the No More Heroes series remain with Japanese game publisher Marvelous rather than his own studio Grasshopper Manufacture.
</p>
<p>
"Honestly, not even I know that," Suda51 told Eurogamer, when asked if No More Heroes and Travis Touchdown would ever return. "Of course I'd love to see him again, but to be honest it's simply not my call to make."
</p>
<figure>
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<figcaption>Hotel Barcelona announcement trailer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ytZ1cfKMaJE" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>
No More Heroes 3 was designed as a game to cap off the series so far, with Marvelous otherwise focused on its own franchises, such as Rune Factory, Story of Seasons and Daemon X Machina.
</p>
<p>
Suda51, meanwhile, is currently busy building <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/heres-our-first-look-at-hotel-barcelona-a-horror-themed-side-scroller-from-swery-and-suda51">Hotel Barcelona, a collaboration between his Grasshopper Manufacture studio and Hidetaka "Swery" Suehiro</a>, of Deadly Premonition fame. 
</p>
<p>
"A long time ago, before Covid, we did an event in Shibuya where Swery was a guest. We just kinda started talking about doing a collaboration of some sort," Suda51 said of how work on Hotel Barcelona began. "The idea came up, Swery liked it, and he basically brought it all the way to development, and well, now it's a thing.
</p>
<p>"Swery is acting as both director and producer and is doing most of the work; I just kinda started it up with him at beginning. But Swery is having a lot of fun making it, and I'm having a lot of fun giving input here and there, etc. I'm extremely happy to be involved as co-creator."</p>
<p>Fans of Grasshopper's earlier work at least have two other launches to look forward to: remasters of both <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/lollipop-chainsaw-repop-now-a-remaster-not-a-remake-developer-says">Lollipop Chainsaw</a> and <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/shadows-of-the-damned-remaster-announced">Shadows of the Damned</a>.</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Final Fantasy VII Rebirth Glitch Lets You Reach Midgar, Fort Condor, Village of the Gi]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/final-fantasy-vii-rebirth-glitch-fort-condor/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/final-fantasy-vii-rebirth-glitch-lets-you-reach-midgar-fort-condor-village-of-the-gi.888957/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/final-fantasy-vii-rebirth-glitch-fort-condor/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Final Fantasy VII Rebirth features some rather interesting out-of-bounds secrets that can only be experienced by taking advantage of a certain glitch.</p>
<p>As reported by @deltasyn on X/Twitter, the glitch showcased by M_Two on <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mRFqVpMLLIE" target="_blank" rel="noopener">YouTube</a>, which involves the blue Chocobo, which can normally only be ridden in the Nibel Region, allows players to reach some normally impossible to reach locations, such as <a href="https://x.com/deltasyn/status/1797036281618202684">Midgar</a>, <a href="https://x.com/deltasyn/status/1797521060021334380">Fort Condor</a> and the <a href="https://x.com/deltasyn/status/1797798352790184378" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Village of the Gi</a>. While the former two aren't particularly interesting, the latter is far more interesting, as it features some objects that could have some lore and story implications.</p>
<p>On a related note, a new Final Fantasy VII Rebirth patch went live earlier today. The 1.040 patch fixes a variety of bugs, including several unspecified display-related bugs, and improves overall game stability. Full patch notes can be found on the Square Enix <a href="https://www.square-enix-games.com/en_US/documents/notice-regarding-updates-final-fantasy-vii-rebirth">official website.</a></p>
<p>Final Fantasy VII Rebirth is now available on PlayStation 5. Learn more about the game by checking out Kai's <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/final-fantasy-vii-rebirth/">review.</a></p>
<p><em>If there’s one word to describe&nbsp;Final Fantasy VII Rebirth, it would be ambitious. Tetsuya Nomura, Kazushige Nojima, and the rest of Creative Business Unit I at Square-Enix have turned what is merely the remainder of Final Fantasy VII’s Disc One upon leaving Midgar into a 100-hour-long epic. Moments of distracted exploration throughout the massive wide-open environments are often bookended with more linear story segments that balance comedy and somber moments. Players will feel more intimately engrossed with the story of those chosen by the planet and routinely have their fond memories of playing the original tickled with delight.</em></p>

				

			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MSI Announces a Mid-Gen Refresh for The Claw]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/msi-claw/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/msi-announces-a-mid-gen-refresh-for-the-claw.888954/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/msi-claw/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>MSI Claw 8 AI Plus confirmed with a larger battery and screen, as the previous device received Fallout collaboration during Computex 2024.</p>



<p>MSI had a panel today at the Computex 2024 event, announcing a mid-gen refresh for their handheld console, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/msi-claw-us-release-date/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The Claw</a>. As per <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/computing/msi-claw-8-ai-plus-first-look/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Digital Trends</a>, the device is getting an upgraded model called the MSI Claw 8 AI Plus. Interestingly, just like the recently announced <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/rog-ally-x-launch-specifications/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">ROG Ally X</a>, the new model will also feature an 80 Whr battery, a substantial upgrade over the previous model. The most exciting upgrade comes towards its processor, as it will be ditching the existing Meteor Lake chips for Intel’s upcoming Lunar Lake series of processors.&nbsp;</p>



<figure><div>
<blockquote data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Date : June 4 – June 7 2024 <br>Time : 9:30 am – 5:30 pm <br>Venue : Taipei Nangang Exhibition Center, Hall 1, 4F, <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/M0806?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#M0806</a><br>MSI sincerely invites you to dive into the AI Era of Computing and witness our groundbreaking hardware and software innovations at COMPUTEX 2024. <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MSIxComputex2024?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#MSIxComputex2024</a> <a href="https://t.co/7eEVz8JAJz">pic.twitter.com/7eEVz8JAJz</a></p>— MSI (@msitweets) <a href="https://twitter.com/msitweets/status/1796074292666339738?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">May 30, 2024</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>



<p>Furthermore, the report also reveals that we will see an upgrade in the memory and storage of the Claw 8 AI Plus. The RAM will be upgraded to 32GB LPDDR5x, capable of reaching 8.5gbps. The upcoming device will now have upgradeable storage, featuring a 1TB M.2 2280 SSD. The MSI Claw 8 AI Plus will also sport a larger 8-inch screen with a similar resolution and refresh rate, 1080p at 120Hz. These are the only details disclosed about the device thus far. Additional information, such as pricing, availability, and other specifications, shall be available soon.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In addition, the original MSI Claw has received a new limited edition model in collaboration with Fallout. The theme will be inspired by the Vaults, Pip-Boys, and robots from the game, offering fans a chance to immerse themselves even more during their Fallout sessions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What do you think about the MSI Claw 8 AI Plus? Let us know in the comments.&nbsp;</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read&nbsp;about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/game-reward-ending-shut-down/">GAME shutting down its reward scheme</a>, and don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/newsletter/">subscribe to the Insider Gaming Newsletter</a>.</p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bungie Warns Of Known Issues Ahead Of Destiny 2: The Final Shape Release]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/bungie-warns-of-known-issues-ahead-of-destiny-2-the-final-shape-release/1100-6523909/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/bungie-warns-of-known-issues-ahead-of-destiny-2-the-final-shape-release.888951/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/bungie-warns-of-known-issues-ahead-of-destiny-2-the-final-shape-release/1100-6523909/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6523909">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>With not long to go now before <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/destiny-2/" data-ref-id="5000-463450">Destiny 2</a> comes back online for the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/destiny-2-the-final-shape-raid-launch-time-and-everything-we-know/1100-6522790/" data-ref-id="1100-6522790">Final Shape launch</a>, Bungie has warned of <a href="https://www.bungie.net/7/en/News/article/finalshapeknownissues" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a few known issues</a> that will launch with the new content. With issues that will potentially impact progression, audio playback, and other elements of the game, here's what Destiny 2 players need to know.</p><p>Most importantly, players who are taking on the Final Shape campaign in a fireteam should avoid joining missions in progress or swapping characters mid-campaign to ensure progress is correctly recorded.</p><p>Bungie also warns that the game won't currently work with 3D audio, and any players with 3D audio enabled won't get any sound from the game. Players are advised to disable 3D audio settings, including Windows Sonic for Headphones or Dolby Atmos, until this is fixed.</p><p>A number of other minor issues that will launch with the game include placeholder art appearing instead of final pieces, and some small errors in descriptions for items and abilities. Check out the full list below.</p><p>The Final Shape will launch after an <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/destiny-2-the-final-shape-requires-25-hour-downtime-massive-install-sizes/1100-6523838/" data-ref-id="1100-6523838">extended downtime</a> at 10 AM PT / 1 PM ET today, June 4, though players can preload the new expansion while the game is down. After the expansion is live, progress on known issues will continue to be updated through the <a href="https://www.bungie.net/7/en/user/ZendeskAuth?brand_id=360002414611&amp;locale_id=1&amp;return_to=https%3A%2F%2Fhelp.bungie.net%2Fhc%2Fen-us%2Farticles%2F27062192032404&amp;timestamp=1717485651" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Top Issues</a> page. Bungie also encourages players to report issues with the new content through its <a href="https://www.bungie.net/en/Forums/Topics?pNumber=0&amp;tg=Help&amp;tSort=3&amp;tType=0&amp;d=0&amp;lang=en" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Help Forum</a> if they encounter any with the new content.</p><h2>The Final Shape Known Issues</h2><ul><li>Players progressing through The Final Shape campaign<strong> in a fireteam</strong> should avoid joining missions in-progress or swapping characters during the campaign to ensure progress is correctly recorded.</li><li>PC players with <strong>3D audio enabled</strong> will not get any audio output from the game.  <ul><li>As a temporary workaround, players with Windows Sonic for Headphones, Dolby Atmos, or any other 3D audio setting enabled in their Windows Spatial Sound settings should switch the setting to Off when playing the game.</li></ul></li><li>The "<strong>Leaving The Final Shape Campaign</strong>" pop-up is displaying placeholder art.</li><li>Activating Prismatic Hunter's <strong>Blink Dagger super</strong> while mid-Grapple causes the player to fall.</li><li>The Solar Hunter’s <strong>“Knock ‘Em Down” aspect</strong> does not increase the number of Blade Barrage projectiles.</li><li>The ability description for the Hunter <strong>Arc Staff super</strong> does not mention that the three-attack combo or ground slam attack applies Blind.</li><li>The description for the <strong>Deconstruct perk</strong> does not reflect the recent change made in Update 8.0.0.1. Deconstruct now refills ammo from reserves.</li><li><strong>Vestiges </strong>won't auto-convert into a Memory item if another Memory item is in your inventory. Players must obtain another Vestige after the Memory is used for Vestiges to convert into another Memory.</li><li>Some <strong>old seasonal currencies and items</strong> from Seasons 20-23 will not be automatically removed.</li><li><strong>Khvostov 7G 0X</strong>'s trait "Eyes Up, Guardian" incorrectly states that the ricochet shots deal more damage.</li><li>Players who were tracking <strong>Triumphs that were vaulted</strong> with the launch of The Final Shape cannot untrack them.</li><li>During The Final Shape campaign, if players do not open the final chest in <strong>The Blooming Deep Lost Sector</strong> before the cutscene plays, the loot will be lost.</li><li>When Warlocks pick up a <strong>Stasis Shard with the Glacial Harvest aspect equipped</strong>, they will not be granted healing.</li><li>The <strong>Berserker’s Bladefury super</strong> does not consistently apply Woven Mail to allies on super cast when combined with Into The Fray aspect.</li></ul>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[CI Games hires Tencent and PlayStation veteran to spearhead development]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ci-games-hires-tencent-and-playstation-veteran-to-spearhead-development</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ci-games-hires-tencent-and-playstation-veteran-to-spearhead-development.888948/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ci-games-hires-tencent-and-playstation-veteran-to-spearhead-development<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Lords of the Fallen</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> developer CI Games has named former Tencent director Tom O'Connor as its senior vice president of development.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The Polish studio said O'Connor will "spearhead" its strategic development goals and "help coordinate the company's internal and external studios across CI Games and United Label."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">O'Connor will report to CI Games CEO, Marek Tyminski, who feels his experience will enable the studio to build on the "business optimizations" it has made over the past six months.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"On behalf of the executive leadership team–and the company as a whole–I want to welcome Tom to CI Games," said Tyminski. "He joins at a crucial time as we continue to improve the efficiency and quality of our titles–building on the business optimizations we've made over the last six months–and help execute the company strategy through the growth of our owned IPs going forward."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Those "optimisations" saw the company </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/lords-of-the-fallen-developer-ci-games-cutting-10-percent-of-jobs">lay off 10 percent of its workforce</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> in January 2024 to deliver "business strength and stability." A few months later, CI Games </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ci-games-ceo-lauds-record-annual-revenues-months-after-cutting-10-percent-of-jobs">delivered record annual revenues</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> but </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ci-games-sanctions-another-30-layoffs-in-final-targeted-round-of-redundancies-">decided to cut another 30 jobs</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> in a "final, targeted round of redundancies."</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="CI Games eager to realize multi-project ambitions, but at least one title is in trouble">CI Games eager to realize multi-project ambitions, but at least one title is in trouble</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">CI Games is currently developing multiple projects including two codenamed Project III and Project Survive, the latter of which is seemingly in a spot of bother.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">An investor update published in April revealed an external agency hired to evaluate the project found some deficiencies. "The Agency Report indicates that currently some of the mechanics of the game being developed under the project 'Survive' do not meet the assumptions implied by the documentation of this project," </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://cigames.com/en/ci-games-se-20-2024-results-of-project-survive-analysis/">it reads.</a></span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"The Management Board after an initial analysis of the current status of the project 'Survive' and taking into account the results of the Agency Report, concludes that the game’s release date planned for 2025 is significantly jeopardized."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">O'Connor, who also spent 15 years at PlayStation managing a suite of studios, said he will attempt to hone the company's production frameworks to bring those projects to fruition and take CI Games "to the next level."</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author(s)</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">News Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer news editor Chris Kerr is an award-winning journalist and reporter with over a decade of experience in the game industry. His byline has appeared in notable print and digital publications including Edge, Stuff, Wireframe, International Business Times, and&nbsp;</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="http://pocketgamer.biz/">PocketGamer.biz</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. Throughout his career, Chris has covered major industry events including GDC, PAX Australia, Gamescom, Paris Games Week, and Develop Brighton. He has featured on the judging panel at The Develop Star Awards on multiple occasions and appeared on BBC Radio 5 Live to discuss breaking news.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fallout 2 Fan-Made Remake Will Be an Open-World RPG; Steam Release Planned]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/fallout-2-remake-open-world/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fallout-2-fan-made-remake-will-be-an-open-world-rpg-steam-release-planned.888942/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/fallout-2-remake-open-world/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Fallout 2, the second entry in the series, which has recently seen a surge in popularity thanks to the Amazon Prime Video TV show, is getting remade by a team of dedicated fans in the style of the third and fourth entries in the series.</p>
<p>In a new interview with <a href="https://www.thegamer.com/fallout-2-fan-made-remake-interview-project-arroyo/#project-arroyo-will-be-open-world">The Gamer</a>, Damion Daponte, a freelance video editor who leads the Project Arroyo development team of over 100 modders, revealed some details on the project. The project is attempting to remake the second entry in the series as an open-world role-playing game using Fallout 4's engine. As the original game wasn't big enough, the team will also expand the world and offer a condensed-down version of San Francisco to explore.</p>
<p>The Fallout 2 fan-made remake will also rework some of the mechanics of the original, such as random encounters, which are not needed in an open-world RPG, bring back the classic Pip-Boy, and feature some assets lifted from New Vegas, which provided a better look at the New California Republic. Fallout 4's Power Armor will also be back in the remake, as the developer feels the way it works in the game makes more sense compared to how it functions in Fallout 3 and New Vegas.</p>
<p>While a release date for the Fallout 2 Project Arroyo remake has yet to be announced, there's a good chance the fan-made remake will be released on Steam. <em>"It’s just a platform that everyone has,"</em> Daponte said, <em>"it’s easier to access, easier to update, easier to install - it’s more efficient. We would have to figure out all the specificities, making it so you have Fallout 2 and Fallout 4 and all of its DLC to make sure there are no legal issues. But we’re still looking into it.”</em></p>
<p>More information on the Fallout 2 fan-made remake can be found on <a href="https://discord.com/invite/xDcqEb3jgt" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Discord</a>. You can also check out a quick comparison between the original and Project Arroyo in the video below.</p>
<p><iframe title="FALLOUT 2 REMAKE - Remake vs Original Comparison [Project Arroyo]" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/AwJlcesILvY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>The original Fallout 2 is now available on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/agecheck/app/38410/">Steam</a> and <a href="https://www.gog.com/en/game/fallout_2">GOG.</a></p>

				

			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Team Fortress 2 Steam Reviews Drop to ‘Mostly Negative’ as Players Plead With Valve to Do Something About Bots]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/team-fortress-2-steam-reviews-drop-to-mostly-negative-as-players-plead-with-valve-to-do-something-about-bots</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/team-fortress-2-steam-reviews-drop-to-%E2%80%98mostly-negative%E2%80%99-as-players-plead-with-valve-to-do-something-about-bots.888936/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/team-fortress-2-steam-reviews-drop-to-mostly-negative-as-players-plead-with-valve-to-do-something-about-bots<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>The <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/team-fortress-2">Team Fortress 2</a> community has come together in an attempt to brute force developer Valve into fixing a bot problem that has plagued the hero shooter for years.</p><p>Disgruntled players of the near 17-year-old shooter, which remains one of the most-played games on Steam, have taken to user reviews to let their feelings be known about bots. This review campaign has caused Team Fortress 2’s recent reviews user rating to plummet to ‘mostly negative’, with pretty much all the comments complaining about bots.</p><p>“It's time Valve does something about the bots,” reads one review from a user with over 630 hours on Team Fortress 2. “The game has been overrun with people willing to doxx, DDOS, and SWAT anyone who takes action against the problem.”</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/06/04/tf2-1717495240265.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption>Team Fortress 2 is one of the oldest supported video games on the market. Image credit: Valve.</figcaption></figure></output><p>“The current state of this game is borderline unplayable,” reads another review from a user with over 950 hours. “It is CRIMINAL that Valve has done nothing against this issue, and have continued to profit off of this game.”</p><p>“Valve, you've got a gem of a game here that has left a mark on the internet culture for longer than I can remember,” reads another review, this time from a user with over 700 hours of game time. “We're tired of bots running rampant across the casual matchmaking. We want you to step in, we don't want another update, we don't want any cosmetics, we want you to #FixTF2.”</p><p>Team Fortress 2 is one of the oldest actively supported video games on the market, and remains popular enough to place within the top 10 games on Steam based on concurrent player numbers. However, some players have said this active player count is misleading, with cheater bots filling servers instead. Idle bots, meanwhile, farm Team Fortress 2 for free item drops. Some believe Team Fortress 2 has tens of thousands of bots idling in private servers, contributing towards the impressive player count on Steam.</p><p>Frustrating the Team Fortress 2 player base further is the apparent silence from Valve over the issue. The company continues to support the game with events, the latest of which ends on June 30, tournaments, and bug fixes. In April, <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/valve-updates-team-fortress-2-to-64-bit-boosting-performance-of-the-17-year-old-fps">Valve updated Team Fortress 2 to finally add 64-bit support</a>. But there is no fresh word on the bot problem from the company.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>"For the past five years, Team Fortress 2 has become nearly unplayable.</p></div><p>The community has organized an online #FIXTF2 campaign and set up a <a href="https://save.tf/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">website</a> that includes a petition with nearly 200,000 signatures. “For the past five years, Team Fortress 2 has become nearly unplayable,” the campaign website reads. “The game’s official servers have been overrun by hordes of cheating aimbots while Valve has remained steadfast in their refusal to adequately tackle the problem. This lack of developer interference has thrown the game into a state of turmoil with seemingly no end in sight.</p><p>“Despite being aware of the bot crisis, Valve has instead directed their focus towards other ventures, leaving TF2 with insufficient support in its grave time of need. From the outside, Valve appears to be more concerned with generating millions in revenue every month via in-game microtransactions, rather than maintaining a product that should work as expected.</p><p>“There’s no putting it lightly, Team Fortress 2 is in an unacceptable state, and Valve’s apathy in dealing with the issue is nothing short of appalling.”</p><p>Valve currently operates Steam, the Steam Deck handheld, various virtual reality initiatives, and on the video game front competitive shooter Counter-Strike 2, MOBA Dota 2, as well as the Half-Life, Team Fortress, and Left 4 Dead franchises. Valve is reportedly working on a brand new MOBA shooter called <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/deadlock-rumored-title">Deadlock</a>, which it has yet to announce but has suffered significant leaks in recent weeks.</p><p><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Test Drive Unlimited Solar Crown Preview – the first truly social racer?]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/06/04/test-drive-unlimited-solar-crown-preview-the-first-truly-social-racer/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/test-drive-unlimited-solar-crown-preview-%E2%80%93-the-first-truly-social-racer.888927/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/06/04/test-drive-unlimited-solar-crown-preview-the-first-truly-social-racer/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
			
			<p>With a freshly announced <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/05/30/test-drive-unlimited-solar-crown-release-date-confirmed-for-september/">release date in September</a>, the long wait for a new Test Drive Unlimited is coming to an end. Test Drive Unlimited Solar Crown will invite players to visit Hong Kong Island for a unique driving and racing experience.</p>
<p><iframe title="Test Drive Unlimited Solar Crown - Release Date Trailer | PS5 Games" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8GUCrMPJgkE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>You see, Solar Crown is as much about the racing as it is the social aspects. Most racing games only give a cursory nod to your avatar’s customisation with a bundle of race suits to wear, but Solar Crown doesn’t just let you change how you look when in the cockpit and on the podium, it invites you to step out of the car at various times. There’s the lobby of the Solar Hotel – a fictional spire built into the real-world setting – and there’s both open and private areas to the hubs for the Streets and the Sharps, the two rival car racing gangs of the city. You’ll even walk around car dealerships, the workshop where you can upgrade your car, and more.</p>


<p>Starting by picking a Nissan 370Z as my starter car, the handling is fun and accessible by default. Of course, racing game experts will want to switch to having fewer assists, letting more of a car’s natural tendencies come through as you push it to the ragged edge in a race. KT Racing promise individualised handling and characteristics for all of the more than 100 cars that will be in the game at launch, and I look forward to more time with the game to see how they’ve pulled this off.</p>
<p>After picking that first car, though, players will have to be willing to embrace a tangibly slower pace to the progression. Where modern Forza Horizon games will fling so many cars at you to the point that they become almost meaningless, Solar Crown wants to make everything feel earned and desirable. Getting a new car should be exciting, it should be something that you want to drive and master, to upgrade to the max over time as you look to rise up the rankings and the leaderboards.</p>


<p>Through upgrades, parts changes, and driving presets, cars will be adaptable. Of course, you can soup things up to become a street racing demon with slicker tyres, engine upgrades and more, but there’s plenty of off-road areas to explore on Hong Kong Island, and you could make that street car happier on gravel and dirt paths. Alternatively, save up and buy a truck or SUV, which can handle the bumpy uneven terrain much more easily.</p>
<p>Of course, modern gaming sensibilities have shifted over the last 15 years, and so KT Racing has a tightrope to walk to make Solar Crown still feel rewarding to those used to more instantaneous gratification. While they want you to play for many, many hours to earn enough cash to buy a Pagani Zonda, for example, they won’t gate-keep the applicable hypercar races quite so hard, with a lower-priced option available to take part while you save up. And there will also be car-specific events, such as the race we encountered that demanded we first go and grab a cheap and cheerful 500 Abarth to take part.</p>
<p>While you might have to wait to take a car into competition or to show off to your friends that you’ve managed to buy it, that doesn’t mean you can’t try it out. At any time you can visit one of the various opulent car dealerships, each dedicated to a particular country or region, and test drive one of the cars they have there – it’s in the title, after all. This gives you a tight two-minute window to see what a car is all about, and see if it’s actually the car you want to save up for and buy.</p>

<p>One gaming trend that Solar Crown <em>is</em> following is the shift to always online shared spaces and seasons of live content. For one thing, each race you look to take part in is preceded by some matchmaking to try and combine AI with real racers, and there will be other players doing their own thing on the island as you roam, or in the social areas that you wander around with your avatar. Each season will have a competition for players to take part in, looking to rise up the ranks from bronze, silver and up through to the Solar Court, which grants access to a special featured car – an ultimate flex to demonstrate their racing prowess. The very best player will be crowned as the Solar King or Solar Queen – one per region and per platform.</p>
<p>KT Racing has been inviting a select few fans and community members to check out the game and give feedback over the past year, and that’s led to some tweaks and changes that will be ready for the game’s launch. A much-requested feature, you will now have a personal garage space that lets you view up to six of your cars, inspect them in private and get in physically before choosing to join the open world – the slightest disappointment is that you can’t drive out of the garage at this point. For this demo, it also felt like the game was just a little bit too restrained early on, forcing me to repeat races and hunt down speed traps to earn the experience needed to level up and unlock both car upgrades and a new set of races. Our demo wasn’t that of the full game, but getting the early game flow right is the high-wire act that KT Racing will have to get just right for the final release.</p>

<p>On the whole, I feel that Test Drive Unlimited Solar Crown is coming together rather well. There’s so many more individual touches that show the different attitude and tone that it has to other open-world racing games, which will make it a breath of fresh air compared to the competition. I can’t wait to revisit Hong Kong Island in just a few months time.</p>


<!-- AI CONTENT END 1 -->

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The gorgeous Dungeons of Hinterberg getting a demo this week]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/the-gorgeous-dungeons-of-hinterberg-getting-a-demo-this-week</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-gorgeous-dungeons-of-hinterberg-getting-a-demo-this-week.888924/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/the-gorgeous-dungeons-of-hinterberg-getting-a-demo-this-week<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Dungeons-of-Hinterberg_jJfy4Xi.jpg?width=1200&amp;height=1200&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Microbird Games</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
The Dungeons of Hinterberg team has announced a demo for its upcoming Austrian-based Zelda-like adventure.
</p>
<p>
This demo will allow players to explore dungeons - including one described as "gravity-defying" - visit the Glacier Overworld and meet new characters during a full in-game day cycle.
</p>
<p>
The game's first playable demo will go live later this week, on 8th June, over on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1983260/Dungeons_of_Hinterberg/">Steam</a>, where you can also add it to your wishlist.
</p>
<figure>
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<figcaption>Dungeons of Hinterberg launches 18th July.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GqR5xbRUoe8" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>
Dungeons of Hinterberg has caught the attention of many members of the Eurogamer team. After taking part in a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/dungeons-of-hinterberg-has-stolen-my-heart">hands-off demo at Summer Games Fest</a> last year, our Chris Tapsell already felt the game looked "brilliant". He then managed to actually go <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/what-weve-been-playing-indie-preview-special-edition">hands-on with it earlier this year at GDC</a>, and his praise remained. "This game plays like a dream vacation - it's a delight," he wrote. 
</p>
<p>
These feelings were echoed by our Donlan, who has also been hands on with Dungeons of Hinterberg already. In his feature <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/dungeons-of-hinterberg-is-about-a-holiday-which-is-why-everything-feels-so-important">Dungeons of Hinterberg is about a holiday - which is why everything feels so important</a>, he expressed his delight at the game's art style, puzzles and world.
</p>
<p>
"There are hubs and areas to explore dotted with fast travel, but while I love uncovering treasure chests and new dungeons, there's a pleasure found purely in the fiction of where you are," he wrote. "Yesterday I climbed a hill and found a little restaurant at the top. It meant far more to me than any RPG trinket would. I took lots of screenshots and felt like I was on holiday, like I was exploring a place that I wouldn't get to stay in long term, and so I had to make the most of it. Wonderful stuff."
</p>
<p>
<a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/austrian-zelda-like-dungeons-of-hinterberg-gets-release-date">Dungeons of Hinterberg is set for full release next month</a>, on 18th July. It will be available across Xbox Series X/S and Steam, including a day one release on Game Pass.

</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Yakuza TV show is coming out on Amazon Prime in October]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-yakuza-tv-show-is-coming-out-on-amazon-prime-in-october</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-yakuza-tv-show-is-coming-out-on-amazon-prime-in-october.888921/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-yakuza-tv-show-is-coming-out-on-amazon-prime-in-october<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>



            <p>Amazon will air a live-action TV series based on Sega's <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/video-game-franchises/yakuza">Yakuza</a> games in October this year, says the streaming service. Like A Dragon: Yakuza will be a six-part series following characters in the criminal underbelly of Kamurocho, set to straddle between two time periods: 1995 and 2005. The series "showcases modern Japan and the dramatic stories of these intense characters, such as the legendary Kazuma Kiryu, that games in the past have not been able to explore,” said Amazon, who are releasing it through Prime Video, just like their <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/well-whaddya-know-therell-officially-be-a-season-two-of-amazons-very-popular-fallout-tv-show">Fallout series</a>.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>Exactly what the plot of the show will be remains to be seen. But it will follow "the life, childhood friends and the repercussions of the decisions of a fearsome and peerless Yakuza warrior with a strong sense of justice, duty, and humanity," according to <a href="https://variety.com/2024/tv/news/like-a-dragon-yakuza-live-action-series-sega-game-prime-video-1236024275/">Variety</a>. That sounds like our boy Kiryu for sure. </p>
<p>Work on the TV show was first announced <a href="https://variety.com/2020/film/news/yakuza-movie-sega-video-game-1234781210/">back in 2020</a>. And word later came out about the <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/yakuzagames/comments/14lfd0z/ryoma_takeuchi_and_kento_kaku_to_play_kiryu_and/">actors and directors</a> involved. Hard-punching bastion of justice Kiryu Kazama will be played by Ryoma Takeuchi, for example, who played the protagonist in Kamen Rider Drive. I've not seen any Kamen Rider, so I'm not qualified to tell you if this actor is good at channelling the indignant stiffness of a deeply annoyed statue. But that is what is required of him.</p>
<p>The series is being directed by Take Masaharu and Takimoto Kengo, and the original writer of the first game's script, Masayoshi Yokoyama, is on board as an executive producer. He suggests he was reluctant at first but decided to get involved. “Since the day I first put pen to paper on the original Yakuza‘s script," he said, "I’ve never once thought about revisiting any of my work on the series. It’s because I understand all too well the challenges and hardships that come with remaking a finished title. However, if I were ever sent to the past through some kind of cosmic joke, this is the experience I’d want to create.”</p>
<p>We are quite fond of the Yakuza series here in the treehouse. Ed was into <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/like-a-dragon-infinite-wealth">Like A Dragon: Infinite Wealth</a> when it came out earlier this year. "It's a wonderful, happy <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/spawn-point-the-best-jrpgs-for-total-beginners">JRPG</a> and it will never fail to brighten my day," he said in <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/like-a-dragon-infinite-wealth-review">his review</a>. "Thank goodness for Yakuza."</p>
<p>One of my favourite scenes in Yakuza is when Kiryu sees some chumps <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Gl25uwGLATc">throwing rocks at a puppy</a>. The father figure of Tokyo catches a rock in mid-air, inches from the dog's face. Then proceeds to destroy the goons in the only way he knows how. If the TV show adapts this one scene, I will be satisfied.</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Crash Team Racing “Modded” Version Now Supports Online Multiplayer Mode and PC Compatibility]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/crash-team-racing-modded-version-now-supports-online-multiplayer-mode-and-pc-compatibility/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/crash-team-racing-%E2%80%9Cmodded%E2%80%9D-version-now-supports-online-multiplayer-mode-and-pc-compatibility.888918/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/crash-team-racing-modded-version-now-supports-online-multiplayer-mode-and-pc-compatibility/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Well, a modding team has done something intriguing to witness as they integrate multiplayer and PC compatibility into the original Crash Team Racing.</p>
<p>It's surprising what the modding community can do for titles, especially when it comes to reviving them and adding new features. The latest project by a modding team focuses on bringing an online mode into the game. In a demo of the title, the players in the actual game were connected through a worldwide network, with each player in a completely different country. Surprisingly, there weren't any sort of latency issues, and the game ran perfectly.</p>
<p><iframe title="OnlineCTR - The PS1 Crash Team Racing Online Experience (Launch Trailer)" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Fxhz0EMHlCE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Apart from the online play mode, the modded Crash Team Racing also supports "unofficial" compatibility with the PC platform, and the modding team utilizes DuckStation, the PS1 emulator, to do so. Moreover, the title runs at a stable 60 FPS, ensuring smooth gameplay despite being a "tuned" version of a game that was released almost two decades ago. In terms of the experience itself, the modded title allows you to pair up with up to 8 players with multiple tracks and characters similar to the original game.</p>
<p>Well, if you are interested in checking out "Online Crash Team Racing," you can visit the dedicated website <a href="https://www.online-ctr.com/">here</a>. In&nbsp;order to play it on PC, you'll need to have the DuckStation emulator installed as well. Playing the title is a nostalgic experience, and with the multiplayer feature, it's definitely worth trying out.</p>
<p>PC players might be especially interested since they were unfortunately left out of <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/crash-team-racing-nitro-fueled/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Crash Team Racing Nitro-Fueled</a>, the remastered version launched in 2019 for PlayStation 4, Xbox One, and Nintendo Switch.</p>

			<p>News Source: <a href="https://www.dsogaming.com/news/modders-bring-crash-team-racing-to-pc-with-60fps-and-online-multiplayer-support/" target="_blank">DSOGaming</a></p>	

			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>