<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 18:54:30 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Highguard devs say it was always the plan to "go dark" after its reveal, à la Apex Legends' launch]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/highguard-devs-say-it-was-always-the-plan-to-go-dark-after-its-reveal-a-la-apex-legends-launch</link>
            <guid>1416649</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Easier to say in hindsight, though</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Highguard-ice-battle.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Highguard-ice-battle.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Highguard-ice-battle.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Highguard-ice-battle.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Highguard-ice-battle.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Highguard-ice-battle.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Highguard-ice-battle.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Highguard-ice-battle.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Highguard-ice-battle.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Wildlight Entertainment, Inc.</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Good, bad, I don't bloody know yet the thing's only been about for five seconds, but we can certainly say one thing now: <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/highguard-the-new-fps-from-former-apex-legends-and-titanfall-devs-hits-steam-early-access-after-weeks-of-teasing-silence">Highguard is out</a>. Now we can sit and prepare ourselves for more inane and pointless discourse about yet another live service <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-fps-games">shooter</a> that we've probably had several times before. Hooray! But before we get ahead of ourselves, a moment of reflection, courtesy of the devs behind Highguard itself, who have spoken out about all that silence following their Geoffies reveal.
</p>
<p>
"Look, I wish Highguard had been received better. I wish the feedback had been better," Wildlight Entertainment CEO and founder Dusty Welch explained to <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/fps/ultimately-we-could-have-made-a-different-trailer-highguard-ceo-responds-to-that-poorly-received-game-awards-reveal/">PC Gamer</a> in a new interview. "Part of that's on us, right? We didn't put our heads in the sand. We, as a team, saw the feedback. We're gamers ourselves. We're online ourselves reading the feedback. 
</p>
<p>
"I think, ultimately, we could have made a different trailer—a better trailer that wasn't about entertaining, which is what we think [The Game Awards] was about. We could have made something that did a better job of highlighting the unique loop of the game. So that's on us. We take that, but the team is resilient."
</p>
<p>
Welch went on to note that Geoff Keighley is a "friend of the studio" and had played the game prior to reveal, apparently saying he'd "love to do something different and put an indie studio and a free-to-play game" up at The Game Awards. Let's pause for a moment here to highlight that the use of the word indie here feels quite disingenuous, given that Wildlight is a 100+ person studio. Independent, sure, but we all know roughly what indie means, and it's not that. You made bleedin' <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/apex-legends">Apex Legends</a>, come off it!
</p><p>
Anyway, design and creative director Jason McCord also explained that the trailer at The Game Awards was just meant to be a reveal, and then they'd keep quiet. "The plan was to announce, go dark, and then the next thing that we want players to see is the game. If the reception had been totally different, it would have been the same plan. The key is, you've got to play the game." Essentially, an attempt at repeating what Apex Legends achieved on its launch.
</p>
<p>
I probably won't play it, however, as it really doesn't look to be my thing, so I'll let you lot be the ones to decide if this one gets to stay in the very empty hall of live service shooters.

</p>

        </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/highguard-devs-say-it-was-always-the-plan-to-go-dark-after-its-reveal-a-la-apex-legends-launch]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Does Highguard Have Crossplay? Cross-Platform Status, Explained]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/does-highguard-have-crossplay-cross-platform-status-explained/</link>
            <guid>1416640</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Wildlight Entertainment’s Highguard has officially been released to the public after a long month of waiting. The multiplayer FPS is available on <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/highguard-platforms-playstation-5-xbox-series-x-s/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">multiple platforms</a>, but it’s not always guaranteed that these systems can play alongside one another.</p>



<p>For an online game like Highguard, the matter of crossplay is an important one. Some fans out there will want to raid together with their friends, but if it’s platform-exclusive, that can put a serious dent in their plans.</p>







<p>If you’re unsure of what platform to download Highguard on and whether crossplay will be an issue, then read on: Insider Gaming has all the details you’ll need.</p>



<h2 id="h-does-highguard-have-crossplay">Does Highguard Have Crossplay?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Breaking down those platform walls. Image via Steam.</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Yes, Highguard does have Crossplay across all platforms, allowing you to team up with friends across PC, Xbox, and PlayStation.</strong></p>



<p>Gone are the days when everyone had to play games on the same platform, as it’s common courtesy that multiplayer titles offer crossplay across all platforms—or at least as many as possible. </p>



<p>Highguard is no different, and it should prove to be a great feature going forward to get as many onto the newly-released shooter as possible. </p>



<h2 id="h-does-highguard-have-cross-progression">Does Highguard Have Cross-Progression?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Your noble steed. Image by Steam.</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>As things stand, cross-progression remains unconfirmed for Highguard, meaning your progress will probably be limited to one platform. </strong></p>



<p>That makes choosing your starting platform especially important. You won’t want to unlock cosmetics and gear for your Wardens, only to lose them if you decide to play somewhere else. </p>







<p>This could easily change in the future, as it has done for plenty of other titles in the past. If you’re hoping for a cross-progression announcement for Highguard, look nowhere else than Insider Gaming, as this article will be updated as soon as anything changes.</p>



<hr>



<p>What are your first impressions of Highguard? Share your thoughts in the official <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<p>For more Highguard, check out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/complete-highguard-trophy-list-how-to-get-all-achievements-trophies/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the complete trophy list</a>, as well as <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/highguard-free-to-play-price-cost/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">its free-to-play status, explained</a>.</p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/does-highguard-have-crossplay-cross-platform-status-explained/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Highguard Roadmap Reveals An Entire Year of Content Plans]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/highguard-roadmap-reveals-year-of-content/</link>
            <guid>1416637</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Wildlight Entertainment has officially released Highguard, a ‘new breed of shooter’, and by all accounts, it’s doing pretty well for itself. It follows a month of radio silence after the game was unveiled at The Game Awards in December. Earlier today, the team at Wildlight shared a massive, one-year-long roadmap packed with seven episodes of content.</p>



<p>The post-launch spree looks great on the surface, but time will tell if the player counts remain high enough for the delivery to matter. For now, there’s enough meat on the bones to get prospective fans very excited about what’s coming.</p>







<h2 id="h-highguard-2026-roadmap-has-content-drops-every-month">Highguard 2026 Roadmap Has Content Drops Every Month</h2>



<p>The surprising thing about Highguard’s 2026 roadmap is that there’s a content drop planned <strong>every single month</strong>. This isn’t the most standard approach for live-service games, but Wildlight obviously has immense stock in what it has created to reveal so much, so early. We’ve got content stacked in the pipeline way up until December.</p>



<figure></figure>







<p>It all begins with the game’s launch, but the second episode of content will hit in just <strong>two weeks</strong>. It’ll bring a new Warden (read: hero character), a fresh map, <strong>Ranked Mode</strong>, and a new mount, expanding on the bear, horse, and panther that already exist. The second part of that episode will drop in March, bringing a new <strong>base</strong> and a raid tool.</p>



<p>The difference between a map and a base? A Base is what you defend <strong>on </strong>the map, selecting it from a lineup of options when the match kicks off. This is the end zone of a match, and it’s the ultimate objective. The ‘map’ is the environment upon which you play… Simple?</p>



<p>Highguard’s roadmap expands further throughout the year.</p>



<p>There’s a new Warden coming every second month, as well as new bases, following that same launch pattern. We’ll get new maps in Highguard in June and October, and a special, limited-time mode is in the book for July. October and December yield ‘surprise’ events, and in terms of equipment, players can expect a hefty assortment to arrive as the year unfolds.</p>



<p>For instance, a new <strong>weapon </strong>will be added to Highguard in April, June, August, and October, while new <strong>amulets </strong>will appear in May, July, September, and November. Mods will be added in April, June, August, October, and December, and a new <strong>raid tool </strong>is coming in March <strong>only</strong>.</p>



<p>New loot items will be published in Highguard in May and September.</p>



<p>Oh, and all the content is <strong>entirely free</strong>.</p>



<p>This is a pretty dense roadmap, but time will tell how the delivery of it fares.</p>







<p>Are you expecting great things from Highguard? Let us know what you’re thinking on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/highguard-website-crashes-after-games-launch/">Highguard’s website has crashed because of the player influx</a></p>






        <div>
                  <p>
                    Grant's adoration for gaming started on the Amstrad CPC in 1996. Now, he's a multi-platform expert gamer with a deep love for the industry, a passion for esports, and more…                  </p>
                  <p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/author/grant-taylor-hill/">
                    More from Grant Taylor-Hill                  </a>
                </p></div>
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/highguard-roadmap-reveals-year-of-content/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Highguard File Sizes On PS5, Xbox Series X|S & PC—How Much Space Does Highguard Need?]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/highguard-file-sizes-ps5-xbox-pc/</link>
            <guid>1416631</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>It’s here, Highguard is out. The electric and innovative first-person shooter is raiding bases all over PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X|S, and PC. If you plan to download the game, check out the Highguard file sizes.</p>



<p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/highguard-release-times-date/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Highguard</a> has gone from being the quietest and most unmarketed shooter in history to one of the most intriguing shooters of 2026. Backed by a team of world-class devs, Highguard exudes a premium vibe. You’d think it would be optimized with lower file sizes, and this would be good for all hard drives.</p>







<h2 id="h-highguard-file-size-on-playstation-5-explained">Highguard File Size On PlayStation 5, Explained</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Good memory. Image via Wildlight Entertainment</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Highguard only requires 20.13 GB for its initial file size on PS5.</strong></p>



<p>We can’t believe it as much as you can. A brand-new, fast-moving online shooter only requiring 20 GB at launch? It’s unheard of, and it’s magnificent. More games need to be better optimized at launch, and communities shouldn’t have to choose between certain games on limited storage space.</p>



<p>PS5 owners, get downloading, and forget about deleting games to have Highguard on your console.</p>







<h2 id="h-highguard-file-size-on-xbox-series-x-s-explained">Highguard File Size On Xbox Series X|S, Explained</h2>



<p><strong>The Xbox file size for Highguard is 21.09 GB, keeping in line with the PlayStation.</strong></p>



<p>Xbox just can’t catch a break, can it? PlayStation is even winning in terms of Highguard optimization! Only joking, but this is more good news overall. Highguard is a supreme spectacle, and if this only requires 21 GB on a powerful Xbox Series X|S, then other games probably need to take a look in the mirror.</p>



<h2 id="h-highguard-file-size-on-pc-amp-steam-explained">Highguard File Size On PC &amp; Steam, Explained</h2>



<p><strong>PC and Steam users need a measly 20.65 GB of space to have Highguard installed.</strong></p>



<p>That’s pretty much a big tick for all three platforms. 20 GB or so is needed for Highguard at launch. Obviously, more content will be added down the line, and the initial file size will increase. For now, enjoy the first-person shooter taking up a tiny chunk of storage space.</p>



<p>Are you happy with Highaurd’s file size across major platforms? Do we need to get away from the days of 50-100 GB games sapping precious storage space? It’s mostly rhetorical, but still let the IG community know your thoughts on this through the <a href="https://discord.com/channels/1433093283558719611/1433112738133180426" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord Server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>Check out the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/complete-highguard-trophy-list-how-to-get-all-achievements-trophies/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Complete Highguard Trophy List</a> and news on its <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/highguard-free-to-play-price-cost/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">price</a> for more guides and content. Keep checking back as Insider Gaming continues to add more Highuigard guides to the website.</p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/highguard-file-sizes-ps5-xbox-pc/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Highguard now available]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/01/highguard-now-available</link>
            <guid>1416628</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Free-to-play player-versus-player raid shooter is live.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Genres > Free-to-Play [503 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/free-to-play">Free-to-play</a> player-versus-player raid <a title="Genres > Shooter [4,376 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/shooter">shooter</a> <em><a title="Games > Highguard [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/highguard">Highguard</a></em> is now available for <a href="https://store.playstation.com/concept/10012011" target="_blank">PlayStation 5</a>, <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/highguard/9MSQLRB5HNM5/0010" target="_blank">Xbox Series</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [25,340 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/4128260/Highguard/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a>, developer <a title="Companies > Wildlight Entertainment [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/wildlight-entertainment">Wildlight Entertainment</a> announced. It features full cross-play support. <span id="more-1021346"></span></p><p>“We know there’s a lot of eyes on us after our Game Awards trailer debut, and today is finally the time to show the world what we mean by a player-versus-player raid shooter,” said Wildlight Entertainment co-founder and game director Chad Grenier in a press release. “We built <em>Highguard</em> around a loop that doesn’t really exist anywhere else. Every match is about escalation: fortifying, venturing out, clashing, then mounting coordinated raids and defenses until only one base is left standing.”</p><p>Wildlight Entertainment co-founder and CEO Dusty Welch added, “Launch is a huge moment. But our team builds franchises that stand the test of time, and we’re in this for the long haul. <a title="Companies > SUCCESS Corporation [106 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/success-corporation">Success</a> for us is a healthy, growing global community that’s enjoying the game—and a team that’s energized by engaging with players and surprising them with new experiences over time.”</p><div id="carousel_1021348"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Wildlight Entertainment:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><em>Highguard</em> introduces a new competitive structure that blends siege warfare and territory control in an evolving match where power levels escalate until only one base is left standing.</p><p>Players step into the boots of Wardens, arcane gunslingers sent to fight for control of a mythical continent where magic, gunfire, and siege warfare collide:</p><ul><li>Teams of three select a unique base and fortify their defenses, then ride out across vast, uncharted lands to loot, harvest resources, and upgrade their gear while clashing with a rival Warden crew.</li><li>As magical storms roll in, teams battle over the Shieldbreaker, a powerful sword required to breach enemy defenses. Carrying the Shieldbreaker to the opposing base triggers a full raid—forcing teams to attack, defend, adapt, and escalate in power as the match continues.</li><li>Most of the time, victory doesn’t come with a single raid. When that happens, the enemy base shields repair, the siege tower dissipates, and the fight escalates as loot, gear, and weapons all upgrade in the field, and a new Shieldbreaker forms in a different location in the world. From there, the fight for control continues—until only one base is left standing.</li></ul><p><strong>A Competitive Player-Versus-Player <a title="Companies > Experience [213 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/experience">Experience</a> Built for Variety and Replayability</strong></p><p>Each Warden is built specifically for <em>Highguard</em>‘s player-versus-player Raid Mode. Wardens combine guns, raid tools, and arcane abilities, each designed to support raiding, destruction, defense, infiltration, resource acquisition, and <a title="Genres > Open-World [817 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/open-world">open-world</a> combat.</p><p>Mounts allow teams to move quickly across massive maps, fight on the move, and transport the Shieldbreaker. Magical abilities supplement combat, but <em>Highguard</em> is still a gun game at its core. Gunplay remains central, with abilities and tools adding tactical depth.</p><p>At launch, the game features a wide array of content: five large-scale maps, six distinct bases, eight Wardens, three mount types, ten weapons, three raid tools, eleven weapon and raid-tool mods, and a wide range of lootable items. More content will be added via seasonal updates.</p><p><strong>Built With Long-Term Play in Mind</strong></p><p>Wildlight brings decades of experience operating live-service shooters at scale, applying those lessons to <em>Highguard</em>‘s launch and beyond, with a full year of post-launch content already deep in development. <em>Highguard</em>‘s live service is built around Episodes—each lasting roughly two months and split into two parts—with new core content arriving each month throughout 2026, including content such as maps, bases, modes, Wardens, weapons, mounts, raid tools, and additional loot items.</p><p>Core gameplay content—including new maps, bases, Wardens, and modes—will always be free, delivered through regular updates, with the first wave arriving in two weeks following launch. All in-game purchases are cosmetic only, direct purchase only, with no effect on gameplay and no loot boxes or RNG.</p></blockquote><p>Wildlight Entertainment also released numerous new trailers showcasing the game’s base, maps, characters, mounts, and weapons:</p><ul><li><strong>Base</strong><ul><li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hv3-uHACub8" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Bellringer</a></li><li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=N-iQcI-BomY" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Frosthold</a></li><li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=i3lKE6Smt1M" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Hellmouth</a></li><li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sOWlhBgsSyY" target="_blank" rel="noopener">King’s Lair</a></li><li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AOQ7Gxw9jQ4" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Smuggler’s Den</a></li><li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SpKjLf8y24Q" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Wellspring</a></li></ul></li><li><strong>Maps</strong><ul><li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fwWgpoT1pm4" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Dustline</a></li><li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wsbuLd0-eAc" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Kingdom</a></li><li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zFywphC7pp8" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Rivermark</a></li><li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=P7Rr0BE53B0" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Summit</a></li><li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AH9xeEtOWjY" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Vesper City</a></li></ul></li><li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AfLOhwGqTto" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong>Mounts</strong></a></li><li><strong>Wardens</strong><ul><li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Cc0AzBIeZ1o" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Atticus</a></li><li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Q4T5-PA2o5o" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Condor</a></li><li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BJHSfCl7V2I" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Kai</a></li><li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9JEhCue5bAA" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Mara</a></li><li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=r4UpjY1cezU" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Redmane</a></li><li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nCTgcNzeOqY" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Scarlet</a></li><li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=N4y6mslv4OA" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Slade</a></li><li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yS4uFb3S0NU" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Una</a></li></ul></li><li><strong>Weapons</strong><ul><li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bza2aiBCC04" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Big Rig</a></li><li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9KOJH0peiuQ" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Blast Hammer</a></li><li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fnPHbRvD72s" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Corsair</a></li><li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2EiS3DBN3qA&amp;pp=0gcJCXwKAYcqIYzv" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Dynasty</a></li><li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Hn_McWzzaRI" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Kraken</a></li><li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dKbO5k_Gg5o" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Longhorn</a></li><li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xHtjyVSK0MQ&amp;pp=0gcJCXwKAYcqIYzv" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Paladin</a></li><li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BKA2KNHBIIg" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Ranger</a></li><li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ELQ7fKYyV38" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Rocket Launcher</a></li><li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mHG5mJFxVmA&amp;pp=0gcJCXwKAYcqIYzv" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Saber Rifle</a></li><li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PkWS9J0OrIQ" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Vanguard</a></li><li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=L9TQ7A-FxTo" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Viper</a></li><li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6eYIoK4tanA" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Warden’s Axe</a></li><li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lwieqx5nEWQ" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Zipline Gun</a></li></ul></li></ul><p>Watch a new set of general trailers below. View a new set of screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/highguard/january-26-2026/" rel="noopener">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>Launch Showcase</span></h2><p><iframe title="Highguard | Official Launch Showcase" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/0qR9Xbzt5t0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><span>Gameplay Launch Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Gameplay Launch Trailer | Highguard" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/gqFccBZyTaA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><span>Gameplay Deep Dive</span></h2><p><iframe title="Gameplay Deep Dive | Highguard" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_eLKaJ0Ccmg?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><span>Developer Vision Episode 1</span></h2><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Developer Vision - Episode 1 | Highguard" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9IC02ev7qHU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/01/highguard-now-available]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Yoshi Debuts In Second Super Mario Galaxy Movie Trailer]]></title>
            <link>https://gameinformer.com/2026/01/26/yoshi-debuts-in-second-super-mario-galaxy-movie-trailer</link>
            <guid>1416625</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p>This year is poised to deliver an <a href="https://gameinformer.com/opinion/2025/12/26/2026-looks-like-a-great-year-for-nerdy-fandom" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="3491d71a-3d4d-46f4-b62a-ca48bd72f27f" data-entity-substitution="canonical">incredible slate of nerdy entertainment</a>, and one of the first examples of that is <em>The Super Mario Galaxy Movie</em>. The follow-up to 2023's <a href="https://gameinformer.com/movie-review/2023/04/04/the-super-mario-bros-movie-review-1-upping-the-rest" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="baa061f7-68fb-43b0-a170-a578c0fe376b" data-entity-substitution="canonical"><em>Super Mario Bros. Movie</em></a>, which grossed more than $1.3 billion at the box office, <em>The Super Mario Galaxy Movie</em> looks to dramatically expand the scope by not only bringing our beloved heroes to space, but also by introducing several beloved characters to this cinematic continuity.&nbsp;</p><p>The <a href="https://gameinformer.com/nintendo-direct/2025/11/12/the-super-mario-galaxy-movie-casts-brie-larson-as-rosalina-benny-safdie" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="1fc6d77e-b384-4d64-8be3-0e2c24518956" data-entity-substitution="canonical">first trailer</a> gave us looks at Rosalina (voiced by Brie Larson) and Bowser Jr. (voiced by Bennie Safdie), and the second trailer finally paid off the post-credits teaser of the first film by introducing us to Yoshi. While we don't know who voices him, it may be less consequential than who voices the other characters, as, right now, it just seems like he might make various noises with an occasional "Yoshi" thrown into his dialogue.&nbsp;</p><p>Outside of Yoshi's introduction, we also got looks at Tostarena Town and the Sand Kingdom from Super Mario Odyssey, the Frog Suit from Super Mario Bros. 3, Birdo from Super Mario Bros. 2, and plenty of nods from other Mario games.</p><p>You can see the trailer below:</p><p height="360" width="640" url="https://www.youtube.com/embed/yP5RGz_CRFM"><iframe width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/yP5RGz_CRFM" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay" allowfullscreen="true">&nbsp;</iframe></p><p><em>The Super Mario Galaxy Movie </em>arrives in theaters on April 1, 2026, exactly three years after the premiere of the first movie.&nbsp;</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://gameinformer.com/2026/01/26/yoshi-debuts-in-second-super-mario-galaxy-movie-trailer]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[“It Is Hard for Me to Accept That Expedition 33 Is a Better Game Than Elden Ring”, Says Industry Veteran]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/clair-obscur-expedition-33-vs-elden-ring-veterans-react-goty-record/</link>
            <guid>1416598</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>The news that <a href="https://wccftech.com/clair-obscur-expedition-33-most-awarded-game-wccftech-awards-elden-ring/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</strong> has surpassed the total </a><span><a href="https://wccftech.com/clair-obscur-expedition-33-most-awarded-game-wccftech-awards-elden-ring/" target="_blank">number of&nbsp;<strong>Game of the Year</strong>&nbsp;<strong>awards</strong></a>&nbsp;won by the previous record holder, FromSoftware's Elden Ring (<strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/wccftech-awards-25-winners-clair-obscur-gta-6/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">with our very own awards marking the historical occurrence</a></strong>), has circulated widely on the Web over</span> the past few days. </p>



<p>Industry veteran <strong>Rich Vogel</strong>, whom <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/is-the-mmo-genre-dead-for-western-aaa-developers-we-asked-three-industry-veterans/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">we recently interviewed about the state of the MMORPG industry in Western countries</a></strong>, shared his thoughts on the event <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/rich-vogel-093425_i-am-very-happy-that-expedition-has-been-activity-7419821314288410624-rTqW/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=member_desktop&amp;rcm=ACoAAArFoNcBzkxomfY-95d2ZvawwFRKUakif8M" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">in a LinkedIn post</a>. Vogel feels that Expedition 33 is a 'really good game', but also <strong>can't quite wrap his head around it being 'better' than Elden Ring</strong>, which he praised for its brilliant open world design.</p>



<p><em>I am very happy that Expedition has been honored with so many awards. It is a really good game. It is hard for me to accept that Expedition 33 is a better game than Elden Ring. I had more fun playing Elden Ring. The open-world design was brilliant. I like that it did not force you down paths like Skyrim and gave you the freedom to go anywhere in the world. You started out being hunted and became the hunter.</em></p>



<p>Another industry veteran who was part of the aforementioned Wccftech interview on MMOs, <strong>Greg Street</strong>, also replied that Elden Ring is much more replayable. Street <strong>called Expedition 33 a masterpiece</strong> but also noted that the game's emotional story makes people more forgiving of other faults, such as the level design.</p>



<p><em>I imagine I will play Expedition 33 once or twice more in my lifetime, which is typical for single player RPGs for me. I predict I will go back to Elden Ring ten times or more. The replayability potential between the two is hard to compare. I think 33 is a masterpiece for sure, but I think people’s love for the story and characters leads them to overly forgive other places where the game is weaker, such as level design.</em></p>



<p>Of course, the fact that Sandfall's acclaimed turn-based JRPG has earned more Game of the Year awards (436 versus 435, though Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 still has several prizes left to claim) than Elden Ring <strong>does not mean it is objectively 'better'</strong>. For one thing, FromSoftware's game arguably had stronger competition, with <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/review/god-of-war-ragnarok-becoming-a-good-father/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Sony Santa Monica's God of War Ragnarök</a></strong> taking its own share of GOTY awards that year. </p>



<p>Still, the question now has to be asked: which game do you prefer? Vote in the poll and share your opinion in the comments below.</p>



<div id="democracy-1525" data-opts="{&quot;ajax_url&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/wccftech.com\/wp-admin\/admin-ajax.php&quot;,&quot;pid&quot;:1525,&quot;max_answs&quot;:0,&quot;answs_max_height&quot;:&quot;500&quot;,&quot;anim_speed&quot;:&quot;400&quot;,&quot;line_anim_speed&quot;:1500}"><p><strong>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 vs Elden Ring</strong></p></div>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/clair-obscur-expedition-33-vs-elden-ring-veterans-react-goty-record/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Star Wars in 2026: All Currently Announced and Upcoming Star Wars Games]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/features/star-wars-in-2026-all-currently-announced-star-wars-games</link>
            <guid>1416595</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Not long after the original&nbsp;<em>Star Wars</em> trilogy wrapped, fans got the first officially licensed video game with 1982's&nbsp;<em>The Empire Strikes Back&nbsp;</em>on the Atari 2600. Ever since then, the IP has spawned dozens of video games across multiple generations, with more announcements coming every year.</p><p>LucasArts gave us some phenomenal games for decades, and though they rebranded to Lucasfilm Games in 2021, there are many much-anticipated titles on the horizon that fans can look forward to.</p><p>With the rest of 2026 ahead of us, I wanted to take a moment to pause and look at the current state of&nbsp;<em>Star Wars</em>, tallying the upcoming&nbsp;<em>Star Wars</em> games that have been teased or announced. Though some of these games have a release window, there are a few projects that we might not see until next decade.&nbsp;</p><p>Check out which ones are around the corner and which <em>Star Wars</em> release dates we'll have to wait a bit longer for.</p><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/star-wars-galactic-racer.JPG?itok=3mnKP8BL 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="1076">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/star-wars-galactic-racer.JPG?itok=6M-ZZU7p 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="673">
                  

  </picture><h2><em>Star Wars Galactic Racer&nbsp;</em></h2><p>Announced at&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/the-game-awards-2025-recap" rel="nofollow">The Game Awards 2025</a>&nbsp;and likely the next&nbsp;<em>Star Wars</em> game we'll actually be able to play later this year,&nbsp;<em>Star Wars Galactic Racer</em> from Fuse Games will put you behind the controls of a high-speed racer. The&nbsp;<em>Galactic Racer</em> teaser trailer showcases speeder bikes and other racers rocketing across Jakku, but one thing is noticeably missing: pod racers. Distancing itself from 1999's&nbsp;<em>Star Wars Episode 1: Racer&nbsp;</em>will help make this experience feel like a fresh take on the genre in the&nbsp;<em>Star Wars</em> universe.&nbsp;</p><p>Still, I hold out hope that we'll get some level of pod racing introduced before the&nbsp;<em>Star Wars Galactic Racer</em> release date hits later in 2026.&nbsp;</p><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/star-wars-eclipse.JPG?itok=5sNP_SRL 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="793">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/star-wars-eclipse.JPG?itok=X7O-ODs8 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="496">
                  

  </picture><h2><em>Star Wars Eclipse&nbsp;</em></h2><p>A creative collaboration between Quantic Dream and Lucasfilm Games sets&nbsp;<em>Star Wars Eclipse</em> in the High Republic era, centuries before the Skywalker Saga. Branding itself as a "new action-adventure, multiple-character branching narrative game,"&nbsp;Eclipse offers the ability to freely explore the&nbsp;<em>Star Wars</em> galaxy and play as multiple characters with different arcs, abilities, and morality systems.</p><p><em>Star Wars Eclipse</em> has the potential to&nbsp;<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4cJpiOPKH14" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">offer a little bit of everything</a>&nbsp;to any&nbsp;<em>Star Wars</em> fan, but it's likely not a game that we'll see this year. Even though it was revealed at <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/every-announcement-from-game-awards-2021" rel="nofollow">The Game Awards in 2021</a>, the trailer footage was still early development, making the&nbsp;<em>Eclipse </em>release date a bit uncertain.</p><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/star-wars-cal-kestis.JPG?itok=AlgHbib1 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1433" height="802">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/star-wars-cal-kestis.JPG?itok=ga3dUGZR 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="672">
                  

  </picture><h2>The Next&nbsp;<em>Star Wars: Jedi</em> Game</h2><p>Though not officially confirmed by Lucasfilm games, Cal Kestis voice and mocap actor Cameron Monaghan announced in a 2023 panel at Ocala Comic Con that work was underway on the third game.&nbsp;</p><p>As reported by&nbsp;<a href="https://thedirect.com/article/star-wars-jedi-3-cameron-monaghan" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">The Direct</a>, Monaghan said, "We're working on the third [game] and we're in the process of doing it right now… So, that's a big undertaking and there's been some conversations so far. But hopefully, when all things are said and done, we'll be able to go in and make something really cool for you guys again."&nbsp;</p><p>We loved&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/star-wars-jedi-survivor-review" rel="nofollow"><em>Star Wars Jedi: Survivor</em></a>, scoring it a 9 in our TechRaptor review, and eagerly await the next and likely final installment in the Cal Kestis trilogy. Given the five-year gap between the first two games, the next&nbsp;<em>Jedi&nbsp;</em>game could come sometime in 2028.&nbsp;</p><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/star-wars-zero-company.JPG?itok=rdN4s50y 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="1052">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/star-wars-zero-company.JPG?itok=s9HXcgHS 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="658">
                  

  </picture><h2><em>Star Wars: Zero Company</em></h2><p>Star Wars Celebration 2025 in Japan came with a flurry of announcements, including&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/star-wars-zero-company-respawn-bit-reactor" rel="nofollow"><em>Star Wars: Zero Company</em></a> from Respawn and Bit Reactor. Set during the Clone Wars,&nbsp;<em>Zero Company</em> is a single-layer turn-based tactics game that puts you in control of a squad of heroes from across the galaxy.</p><p>Starring a former Republic officer named Hawks,&nbsp;<em>Star Wars: Zero Company</em> will introduce a whole new cast of characters and allow player choices to shape the outcome of your experience. Expected later in 2026, the&nbsp;<em>Star Wars: Zero Company</em> release date is one of the few that should arrive this year, barring any delays.</p><h2>An Amy Hennig&nbsp;<em>Star Wars</em> Project</h2><p>Back in 2022, Skydance New Media announced a collaboration with Lucasfilm Games to develop an original, narrative-driven action-adventure game within the&nbsp;<em>Star Wars</em> universe led by Amy Hennig. The studio is currently hard at work on&nbsp;<em>Marvel 1943: The Rise of Hydra</em>, which, as of a couple months ago, got <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/marvel-1943-rise-of-hydra-delayed-indefinitely" rel="nofollow">delayed indefinitely to "beyond 2026."</a> Given the scope of these two very large projects, it's not surprising that we likely won't see this <em>Star Wars </em>release date for quite some time, but the wait should be worth it.</p><p>Hennig has earned her own accolades in the industry, with credits that include&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/legacy-of-kain-soul-reaver-1-2-remastered-review-cult-of-personality" rel="nofollow"><em>Legacy of Kain</em>&nbsp;</a>when she worked with Crystal Dynamics and&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/features/20-years-jak-and-daxter" rel="nofollow"><em>Jak and Daxter</em></a> while at Naughty Dog. She also created the&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/series/uncharted" rel="nofollow"><em>Uncharted</em></a><em> </em>series and has been working in the industry for nearly 40 years, making her a perfect choice for a&nbsp;<em>Star Wars</em> narrative adventure.</p><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/star-wars-knights-of-the-old-republic-remake.JPG?itok=UrBTN_0u 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1920" height="1029">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/star-wars-knights-of-the-old-republic-remake.JPG?itok=0xDDhTQ0 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="643">
                  

  </picture><h2><em>Star Wars: Knights of the Old Republic Remake</em></h2><p>One of the most beloved&nbsp;<em>Star Wars</em> games of all time is getting a remake, we're just not sure exactly when.&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/games/star-wars-knight-of-old-republic-remake-kotor-remake" rel="nofollow"><em>Star Wars: Knights of the Old Republic Remake</em></a> was originally announced during a PlayStation Showcase in 2021, and there haven't been many updates in the years since. However, a recent&nbsp;<a href="https://www.gamefile.news/p/kotor-ii-restored-content-mod-dlc-switch-killed-disney" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Game File report</a>&nbsp;on a lawsuit discovered references to both&nbsp;<em>KOTOR 1 &amp; 2 </em>remakes, providing hope that the projects aren't dead quite yet.</p><p>Fans can hold out hope that development is still well underway, especially with one of the most recent announcements to come out of The Game Awards 2025, which brings me to….</p><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/star-wars-fate-of-the-old-republic.JPG?itok=xlyJRanP 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1908" height="1065">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/star-wars-fate-of-the-old-republic.JPG?itok=T2O2ppwA 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="670">
                  

  </picture><h2><em>Star Wars: Fate of the Old Republic</em></h2><p>Announced at The Game Awards 2025 alongside&nbsp;<em>Galactic Racer</em>,&nbsp;<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lAmkl1jL0fo" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><em>Star Wars: Fate of the Old Republic</em></a> created a ton of buzz amongst fans with its 90-second teaser trailer. Developed by Arcanaut Studios–founded by&nbsp;<em>Knights of the Old Republic</em> and the&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/games/mass-effect-legendary-edition" rel="nofollow"><em>Mass Effect</em> Trilogy</a> director Casey Hudson–<em>FOTOR </em>has ambitions of putting players on a single-player RPG adventure worthy of its predecessors.</p><p>In&nbsp;<a href="https://www.starwars.com/news/star-wars-fate-of-the-old-republic-trailer" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">an interview with StarWars.com</a>, Hudson said, "<em>Fate of the Old Republic</em>&nbsp;represents an opportunity to explore a contemporary vision of a definitive&nbsp;<em>Star Wars</em> experience, using state-of-the-art technology and game design, and an all-new story crafted specifically to deliver on the combination of player agency and immersion in&nbsp;<em>Star Wars</em> that was at the heart of&nbsp;<em>KOTOR</em>."</p><p>No&nbsp;<em>Fate of the Old Republic</em> release date is in sight yet, but it's a project fans will want to keep a close eye on as a likely next-gen release.</p><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/star-wars-fate-of-the-old-republic-2.JPG?itok=cmJEQprC 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1912" height="1068">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/star-wars-fate-of-the-old-republic-2.JPG?itok=jbKoPfEH 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="670">
                  

  </picture><p>Though hard <em>Star Wars</em> release dates are few and far between when it comes to&nbsp;these projects, there's plenty in development from different creative minds. This should offer a bevy of unique experiences when these games become a playable reality.</p><p>In the meantime, the next big&nbsp;<em>Star Wars</em> project outside of gaming to be excited for is&nbsp;<em>Maul: Shadow Lord</em>&nbsp;that releases this April. After that, hopefully we can get our hands on at least a couple of these titles before 2026 is out.</p></div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Dan is a Boston-based writer who has been with TechRaptor since the end of 2020. He has been working in the online writing, editing and SEO space for nearly… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/dan-rockwood">More about Dan</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/features/star-wars-in-2026-all-currently-announced-star-wars-games]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Arc Raider's Headwinds update asks whether extra XP is enough to go solo in a group lobby]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/arc-raiders-headwinds-update-asks-whether-extra-xp-is-enough-to-go-solo-in-a-group-lobby</link>
            <guid>1416592</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arc-raiders-release-date.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arc-raiders-release-date.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arc-raiders-release-date.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arc-raiders-release-date.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arc-raiders-release-date.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arc-raiders-release-date.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arc-raiders-release-date.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arc-raiders-release-date.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arc-raiders-release-date.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Embark Studios</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Hear ye, hear ye! Embark have shared some more concrete details for <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/arc-raiders">Arc Raider's</a> next main update, Headwinds, which is set to be downloaded onto your platform of choice tomorrow, January 7th. Namely, just what that new matchmaking option is, which is, as it seems, one that won't be for everyone.
</p>
<p>
As previously detailed, this new matchmaking option will only be for those of you that are level 40 and upwards, because it allows you to fly solo into a lobby filled with squads. Aye, that means it's just you and the whims of individual groups. Apparently this particular matchmaking mode will net you extra XP, but that sounds to be about it for now. Doesn't sound particularly worth it given extraction <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-fps-games">shooters</a>' whole thing, but hey, I'm sure some of you out there like the thrill.
</p> <div>
<div data-domain="twitter.com"><blockquote><p dir="ltr" lang="en">📡 Attention, Raiders!<br>The ice has thawed - Unprepared Raiders have fallen, the hardy survivors must press on. Here’s what’s coming tomorrow when Headwinds launches!<br>Solo VS Squads<br>• A new matchmaking option for LV40+ Raiders, take on full squads as a solo Raider for higher risk… <a href="https://t.co/Rg69cT3gil">pic.twitter.com/Rg69cT3gil</a></p>— ARC Raiders (@ARCRaidersGame) <a href="https://twitter.com/ARCRaidersGame/status/2015832160020697466?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 26, 2026</a></blockquote></div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>
There is also a new trophy display feature, which allows you to harvest those nasty old ARCs for "prizes," with a <a href="https://arcraiders.com/news/headwinds-content-update">blog post</a> explaining, "Build out your trophy case, progress through the levels, and unlock valuable items in the process." On top of that, you might start to notice flocks of birds flying around particular spots on the Buried City map. Head to their nests and you may find some convenient loot, but of course this'll be something everyone can find, so keep the challenge in mind as well. Lastly, there's a couple of new cosmetic sets, like the Sandwalker set for some stealthy vibes.
</p>
<p>
Nothing too game changing to be found here, though that new solos vs groups option sounds like it'll be a bit contentious. You can probably place bets on a future patch tweaking how much XP you do or don't get. In any case, Embark recently outlined a bunch of other plans for the game slated to arrive over the next few months, which you can have a gander at <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/arc-raiders-devs-reveal-plans-for-new-large-arc-a-fresh-map-two-expeditions-and-extra-matchmaking-options">here</a>.

</p>

        </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/arc-raiders-headwinds-update-asks-whether-extra-xp-is-enough-to-go-solo-in-a-group-lobby]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Highguard, the new FPS from former Apex Legends and Titanfall devs, hits Steam after weeks of teasing silence]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/highguard-the-new-fps-from-former-apex-legends-and-titanfall-devs-hits-steam-early-access-after-weeks-of-teasing-silence</link>
            <guid>1416589</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>We did get that prank fanart call, though</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/highguard-headline.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/highguard-headline.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/highguard-headline.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/highguard-headline.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/highguard-headline.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/highguard-headline.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/highguard-headline.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/highguard-headline.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/highguard-headline.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Wildlight Entertainment, Inc</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Created by former developers of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/apex-legends">Apex Legends</a> and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/titanfall">Titanfall</a>, Highguard was the final game announced during <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-game-awards-2025-everything-announced-for-pc">December 2025’s Keighley Awards</a>. It’s a free-to-play, guns &amp; sorcery, PvP raid shooter in which magic cowboys in capes vie for control of an uncharted continent. It’s got temples, airships, rideable panthers, fireballs, frost giants, and enchanted siege engines on caterpillar tracks. It’s also out now on Steam. That was quick.</p>

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Highguard - Official Reveal Trailer | The Game Awards 2025" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rh6Pi6h_css?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Highguard - Official Reveal Trailer | The Game Awards 2025</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rh6Pi6h_css?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/rh6Pi6h_css?autoplay=1" title="Highguard - Official Reveal Trailer | The Game Awards 2025">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rh6Pi6h_css" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>


<p>Highguard has kindled a lot of curiosity by having almost zero marketing - a pleasant reprieve from the usual drip-feed of pre-order bait that has provoked acute withdrawal symptoms among news writers addled by years of character spotlight trailers. Geoff Fest trailer aside, the game has cruised along on the strength of <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/4128260/Highguard/">the following scanty Steam blurb</a>: “From the creators of Apex Legends and Titanfall, comes Highguard: a PvP raid shooter where players will ride, fight, and raid as Wardens, arcane gunslingers sent to fight for control of a mythical continent. Battle rival Warden crews for possession of the Shieldbreaker, then break into and destroy the enemy base to secure territory in this all-new breed of shooter.”</p>
<p>I’m not particularly enticed by that elevator pitch, but I do like me a setting that can’t decide whether it's Call Of Duty or God Of War. I also approve of the developer’s possibly calculated silence following the announcement, because it has really annoyed a lot of people and I am a deeply pathetic human being. Pranksters have sought to fill the breach: a fake Bluesky call for fan art last week <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/will.bearwaves.com/post/3mcwfihuups2g">attracted</a> <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/redsutter.bsky.social/post/3mcwsm6232c2m">a</a> <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/tannerofthenorth.bsky.social/post/3mcwt6wmm7k22">few</a> <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vforvalensa.bsky.social/post/3mcwxrlopgk2g">responses</a> of the “I’m John Highguard” variety.</p><p>James included Highguard on his personal list of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/james-most-anticipated-pc-games-for-2026">most anticipated PC games of 2026</a>, despite observing of the aesthetic that “you could lose track of it in a bowl of porridge”. I’m a bit warmer on the visuals than James, but I can well imagine Highguard vanishing without trace. Still, I am also one of the many who didn’t see <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/helldivers-2">Helldivers 2</a> becoming more popular than bread. Perhaps we’ll look back on Highguard’s pre-launch period as a successful example of always leaving ‘em wanting more?</p>

        </div>

      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/highguard-the-new-fps-from-former-apex-legends-and-titanfall-devs-hits-steam-early-access-after-weeks-of-teasing-silence]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This Week at Remap]]></title>
            <link>https://remapradio.com/articles/this-week-at-remap-103/</link>
            <guid>1416586</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
			<div>
					
					
					

					<article>
	
	<div>
		<p>A strange dynamic lately, where I'm still spending many hours in my evenings plucking away at video games, even though the podcasts I'm recording where I'm talking <em>about</em> video games will <em>not</em> include my thoughts on those games. Now, to be fair, several games I'm playing are straight up under embargo, so I can't chat about them <em>anyway</em>, but I'm thinking we might have to sneak in a bonus "what we've been playing" episode before our game of the year stuff wraps up. We'll see. Depends on how much progress we do/don't make on this week's podcast. Hope you're enjoying them!</p><p>-pk, who is also setting up a bunch of future interview pods, too</p><hr><figure><figcaption><span>A schedule for the next week of Remap.</span></figcaption></figure><ul><li><strong>PODCAST: </strong><em>HOA</em> – Rob has inherited a home full of inscrutable cable runs, a haunted DIY home-network environment, and venomous predators. His NAS isn’t speaking to his Roon client, and the whole thing is being powered by ISP-issued routers. In his darkest hour he turns to Brad Shoemaker and Will Smith of <em>Brad and Will Made a Tech Pod</em> for advice on fixing a home networking nightmare versus adapting to the nightmare, the right tools for the diagnostic jobs that lie ahead, and what should form the backbone of a modern smart home. Will also hard-sells Ubiquiti equipment, while Rob soft-pedals the Roon Nucleus.</li><li><strong>STREAM: </strong><em>RV There Yet?</em> – Look, at least we made it past a single goddamn checkpoint in the last stream. What more do you want from us??</li><li><strong>STREAM:</strong> <em>Motorsport Manager</em> – I have no idea where Rob and Chia are at in their journey at the moment, but hey, why is that <em>F1</em> movie nearly three hours?</li><li><strong>PODCAST: </strong><em>Remap Radio</em> – The game of the year podcasts continue, as we move into the upper half of everyone's lists, starting with number five.</li><li><strong>ARTICLE: </strong><em>Letter Series</em> – Fuck ICE, and fuck having to explain to my nine-year-old why there's a video of a guy getting shot on the house television.</li></ul><p><em>If you have any support issues, send details to </em><a href="https://remapradio.com/r/53613e2c?m=c2a53baa-518b-4385-90e8-62545232c3f6"><em><u>support@remapradio.com</u></em></a></p>
		<p><em>Patrick Klepek (he/him) is an editor at Remap. In another life, he worked on horror movie sets, but instead, he also runs&nbsp;<a href="https://crossplay.news/?ref=remap.ghost.io" rel="noreferrer"><em>Crossplay</em></a>, a newsletter about parenting and video games. You can follow him on&nbsp;<a href="https://www.twitter.com/patrickklepek?ref=remap.ghost.io" rel="noreferrer"><em>Twitter</em></a>,&nbsp;<a href="https://www.threads.net/@patrickklepek?ref=remap.ghost.io" rel="noreferrer"><em>Threads</em></a>,&nbsp;<a href="https://mastodon.social/@patrickklepek?ref=remap.ghost.io" rel="noreferrer"><em>Mastodon</em></a>, and&nbsp;<a href="https://bsky.app/profile/patrickklepek.bsky.social?ref=remap.ghost.io" rel="noreferrer"><em>Bluesky</em></a>.</em></p>
			</div>
</article>

				</div>
			<div id="notifications">
	<p>You’ve successfully subscribed to Remap</p>
	<p>Welcome back! You’ve successfully signed in.</p>
	<p>Great! You’ve successfully signed up.</p>
	<p>Success! Your email is updated.</p>
	<p>Your link has expired</p>
	<p>Success! Check your email for magic link to sign-in.</p>
</div>
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://remapradio.com/articles/this-week-at-remap-103/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Highguard Devs Talk Turning Rust Into A Hero Shooter And That Terrible Game Awards Reveal]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/highguard-game-awards-trailer-rust-hero-shooter-interview-2000663137</link>
            <guid>1416574</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        <p><span>Developing games is hard and unpredictable, and marketing them is no different. Sometimes companies make decisions they later regret. Maybe you had a bunch of splashy reveals made announcing one release date, only for a last-minute change to throw things into disarray. Maybe an opportunity presents itself, one that feels too good to pass up, and you shift your entire approach to accommodate it. Sometimes that doesn’t work out either.</span></p> <p><span>The plan had always been to shadowdrop </span><i><span>Highguard</span></i><span>, a multiplayer hero shooter developed by&nbsp;</span><span>Wildlight Entertainment, a studio made up of ex-Respawn Entertainment heavyweights. It’s a strategy that benefitted </span><i><span>Apex Legends</span></i><span>, a </span><i><span>Fortnite</span></i><span> rival that came out of nowhere and quickly muscled its way into the competitive live-service gaming landscape. So why did Wildlight Entertainment decide to drop a trailer revealing the game for the first time at the Game Awards, knowing the team would go radio silent again immediately afterwards?&nbsp;</span></p>

 <p><span>“Look, we always planned for a, you know, a surprise release,” studio cofounder Chad Grenier told </span><i><span>Kotaku</span></i><span> at a preview event earlier this month. “Geoff came in and wanted to do something special and put us in the TGAs. We were gonna do a shadowdrop, you know, since day one, almost since forming this company; we did it with </span><i><span>Apex </span></i><span>and it worked well.”&nbsp;&nbsp;</span></p> <p><span>Instead, Wildlight decided to close gaming’s biggest event of the year with a trailer that left some intrigued but others unimpressed. It was a gamble that ricocheted out across social media in unpredictable ways, with mini-drama cycles sprouting up around the lack of any new information surrounding the game ahead of its January 26 launch. Some even theorized it might secretly get delayed after the poor reaction to the first trailer.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <figure id="attachment_2000663151" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000663151"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000663151">Wildlight Entertainment</figcaption></figure> <p><span>“We’ve known Geoff for a long time, and he said, ‘let me do something,’ that’s maybe a little risky in hindsight<!--StartFragment --><span>—</span><!--EndFragment -->but different, [to] take a free to play PvP Raid Shooter and do something with it,” Grenier said. “So we rushed a trailer together. I wish the reception had been better, but in hindsight we made a trailer to entertain really quickly, and didn’t show the gameplay loop, and what’s different and unique.”&nbsp;</span></p>

 <p><span>Despite the online noise, the team stayed quiet. The next time players saw<em> Highguard</em> it would be live and be able to speak for itself. It’s a tough call. With multiplayer releases, a game lives or dies based on whether it can find a big enough audience; while </span><i><span>Highguard </span></i><span>is free to play, meaning that there’s very little barrier to entry, the odds are still stacked against it. At the preview event where I spoke to members of the team, it was impossible to miss the mix of pride and trepidation about the game’s first proper appearance to the press and influencers.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><span>“So here we are. We’re launching the game now, and the team is resilient and enthusiastic,” Grenier said. “They’ve made a ton of games in their careers; we’ve seen the highs and the lows. I think, ultimately, we believe wholeheartedly in what we’ve created.”</span></p>

 <p><i><span>Kotaku</span></i><span> was one of a number of media outlets and content creators invited to a launch event for </span><i><span>Highguard</span></i><span> in Los Angeles, California on January 21. It’s part hero shooter, part MOBA, part MMORPG raid. Players descend upon the map, race around to collect gear and resources, and ultimately battle over a special artifact that must be deployed inside the enemy team’s base in order to win. It can’t be a lot to wrap your head around.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><span>Heading into the event, I had very little idea of what to expect. While Wildlight includes developers who worked on<em> Titanfall</em> and </span><i><span>Apex Legends</span></i><span>, this is the studio’s debut project</span><i><span>. </span></i><span>Co-founder Grenier and Dusty Welch described the shift to independence as ultimately freeing but noted that about 60 percent of the team’s roughly 100 staff previously worked together at Respawn, eliminating some of the challenges of building up an entirely new team.</span></p> <figure id="attachment_2000663155" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000663155"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000663155">Wildlight Entertainment</figcaption></figure> <p><span>“When Chad and I left and started this company, it was to reunite a group of people,” Welch said. “Like, Chad and [Creative Director Jason McCord] have worked together for 17 years. Chad was my game director on </span><i><span>Apex</span></i><span>; we’ve worked together for quite a long time, and we have 60, 61 people from </span><i><span>Apex</span></i><span> that are working here on a 100-person team. So we wanted to create an environment and a place that was a home to experience the best of game making to our ability.”</span><span><br> </span><span><br> </span><span>He continued, “That home, that freedom to find new, fun things was great<!--StartFragment --><span>—</span><!--EndFragment -->with none of the burns, and none of the blockers, and none of the oversight and the baggage that comes with some of the places that we’ve worked, or the experiences we’ve had.”</span></p>

 <p><span>Wildlight is a “remote first” studio. While Dusty and Chad left Respawn during COVID, </span><i><span>Apex Legends</span></i><span> was developed by a team that already had experience working remotely. The co-founders also made one other thing clear about how they see the team; while they’re aiming for that “AAA” game polish, they stress that they consider themselves an independent developer with all of the pain points that can entail. Wildlight is self-publishing the game. There’s no massive company to offer QA support or provide a marketing machine. </span><i><span>Apex </span></i><span>had EA. This time they’re on their own.</span></p> <p><span>“It’s a fresh start, which is a good opportunity in a lot of ways, but it can take a while to get things up and going at the speed you were accustomed to,” Grenier said. “Luckily, it’s offset by what needs to happen anyways, which is just a lot of long discussions about what we’re making here. So, you’ll have some people working on tech while these long design discussions are happening, and they kind of go hand in hand<!--StartFragment --><span>—</span><!--EndFragment -->but, you know, it’s hard. We don’t have a big publisher to give us anything or help us in any way. We’re very much on our own and learning new things that we’ve never had to do ourselves before.”</span></p>

 <p><span>There’s nothing simple about designing a multiplayer shooter in 2026 either. Creative Director Jason McCord, as well as </span><i><span>Higuard</span></i><span>‘s Lead Game Designer Carlos Pineda, spoke to some of the challenges and inspirations that guided the studio in its early days<!--StartFragment --><span>—</span><!--EndFragment -->including some of the core inspirations behind what would ultimately become </span><i><span>Highguard</span></i><span>‘s unique gameplay loop. The team wanted it to be something that stood out, so the game wasn’t just discarded as yet another free-to-play PvP shooter.</span></p> <p><span>“At the beginning, making the new game…we don’t know what the game is yet. We’re asking ourselves, what is it?” Pineda said. “What’s a game that we could make that people are gonna care about? Something that they’re not just gonna brush off like ‘it’s just another game.’ So we knew we had to not be one of those popular genres, not a battle royale or an extraction shooter.”</span></p> <p><span>The answer ended up lying in an unlikely place. “One day, I walked into the office and was like, hey, have you played </span><i><span>Rust</span></i><span>?” Pineda said.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <figure id="attachment_2000663153" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000663153"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000663153">Wildlight Entertainment</figcaption></figure> <p><i><span>Highguard</span></i><span>’s ambitious goal became distilling the feeling of raiding bases in the popular survival crafting sim, but without the time-intensive preamble of gathering resources and building up small fortresses. Eventually the core concept of the Shieldbreaker, the object that players would fight over to decide who would be raiding who, was born. The entire design process was centered around finding the right balance of maintaining the energy of those shootouts while keeping match time manageable.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><span>At one point in development, victory was determined by fully destroying an enemy Keep. Eventually, the team settled on detonating bombs at objectives like in </span><i><span>Counter-Strike</span></i><span> to streamline things instead. The decision to increase the rarity of gear salvaged with each successive round until a winner had been crowned came as a result of matches during playtesting devolving into menial back-and-forth tug-of-wars that would lose their spark. For a similar reason, the team eventually opted to give the Shieldbreaker a time limit before it automatically activates on the closest Keep.</span></p> <p><span>The team’s passion for the project is infectious, even as the anxiety about the looming launch is plain to see on their faces. McCord tells me about the story behind the axe, and how it ended up serving as both a means of gathering resources and a combat tool. Carlos explains how the “momentum problem” was only really solved in 2025, over three years into development. It stands out to me how open the team has been about the struggles they went through developing </span><i><span>Highguard</span></i><span>, a game they’ve worked on for years but whose fate is at the mercy of a fickle and chaotic online audience.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><span>“We put our heads down and listened and paid attention to what was going on and took it to heart,” Grenier said. “But we stayed silent because we knew that the first time, the next time that we say anything to the audience, it better be the game and let the game speak for itself.”</span></p>      </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/highguard-game-awards-trailer-rust-hero-shooter-interview-2000663137]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hands-On With Highguard: The Apex Devs’ Wild New Shooter Deserves A Chance]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/highguard-impressions-titanfall-2-apex-multiplayer-shooter-2000663136</link>
            <guid>1416571</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        <p><span>Despite its big reveal at the Game Awards last month where it had the coveted “one last thing” slot, nobody outside of the development team had any idea what to expect from </span><i><span>Highguard</span></i><span> as we sat down to play several hours of the game at a launch event in Los Angeles. All we knew was that the team, Wildlight Entertainment, had christened it a “PvP Raid Shooter,” a term that meant close to nothing without knowledge of what the gameplay itself is like. Half a week later, I’m here to tell you that I understand what sort of game it is, and how it won me over.</span></p> <p><span>Getting the inevitable out of the way, </span><i><span>Highguard </span></i><span>is a PvP hero shooter in which each match can be roughly divided into three disparate segments. At the start, players choose their characters, called “Wardens,” each with their own secondary ability and ultimate, and vote to select one of four “Keeps” which will act as the home base they must defend. Each base features three points of interest which the enemy team will want to destroy by planting bombs—think </span><i><span>Counter-Strike—</span></i><span>and at the start of each round teams are given a minute to choose which sections to prioritize for reinforcement with their limited resources. It’s a deceptively short amount of time; a trend that the rest of the gameplay loop follows through with.</span></p>

 <p><span>Keeps can have radically different layouts, each one representing a set of trade-offs that make the choice meaningful. “Hellmouth” comes suspended over lava, making movement for both defenders and raiders considerably more restrictive; “Bellringer” instead goes for a more open floor plan, buoyed by multiple towers and a central zipline. It’s easier to traverse, but leaves defenders and raiders alike out in the open as they make their way to their objective. Just a handful of hours is far from enough to come to grips with the quirks of every Keep in the game, but it’s fair to say that each of the ones I competed on felt unique both visually and in terms of game feel.</span></p> <figure id="attachment_2000663141" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000663141"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000663141">Wildlight Entertainment</figcaption></figure> <p><span>Once the initial timer lifts, players ride out of their keep into the wider map in search of resources; armor, weapons, additional material to reinforce sections of your Keep, and accessories for your Warden as well as saddles to buff your mount. Players have several minutes to prepare before the “Shieldbreaker”—the flag—spawns, and everyone collapses on the same central location marked on the map via a storm cloud. Once it spawns, the game becomes Capture the Flag, with the twist that you’re meant to bring the Shieldbreaker to the opposing team’s base to damage its health and knock down its shields to start a raid. Once the Shieldbreaker has been planted, the defending team has some time for last-minute preparations, as a Siege Tower appears that will act as the opposing team’s spawn point for the duration of the raid.</span></p>

 <p><span>On paper it’s a lot to explain, yet in practice it’s all surprisingly intuitive. Developer Wildlight was formed by folks who had worked on </span><i><span>Apex Legends</span></i><span> and </span><i><span>Titanfall</span></i><span>, and that lineage is apparent in the feel of </span><i><span>Highguard</span></i><span>; while it’s a weightier, more deliberate experience than those games, it still fits like a glove with some excellent-feeling gunplay and responsive controls. The user interface is polished and immediately readable and the game’s art direction is rather strong, with a ton of heart. Scattered across the game’s maps and at each team’s spawn point is Flynn, the shopkeep who can exchange resources mined from the environment for gear, and always has a delightful cross-eyed Owlbear Koala called Gregory by his side.</span></p>

 <p><span>Wardens, too, showcase a lot of personality in action. Kai’s ability to conjure ice walls and send them slamming forward into enemies is delightful enough on its own, but what was even more memorable was some of his banter with other Wardens about his ultimate ability that lets him shapeshift into a frost giant. I wasn’t able to see too many of these conversations between characters, but the ones that I managed to witness ultimately helped endear them to me.</span></p> <p><span>Of course, Wardens come with their own set of kits. Some are more suited for defense, like Una who can summon spirits which lob grenades at enemies in their line of sight. Others excel at subterfuge; Scarlet, for instance, has the ability to shift destructible walls into sand, allowing her to pass through the environment while minimizing the sound left in her wake. Every Warden I tested felt laser-focused on what role they’re meant to fill during a match; watching players learn exactly what those archetypes are over the course of the day was one of the most enjoyable moments of the whole experience.</span></p>

 <figure id="attachment_2000663142" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000663142"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000663142">Wildlight Entertainment</figcaption></figure> <p><span>Throughout the launch event, the devs stressed that they wanted to avoid matches that stall out for hours on end; at most, </span><i><span>Highguard</span></i><span>‘s games are designed to last 30 minutes. Even then, chances are the average will clock in at closer to 15 to 20 minutes. Each time a team successfully defends against a raid, the whole loop starts over again with a twist; the rarity level of gear increases, and weapons and tools alike gain additional perks. A sniper might become full-auto, a shotgun’s reload speed might be reduced, or a zipline gun might cloak anyone riding the ziplines it sets. When the Shieldbreaker is active, if it hasn’t been set after a few minutes the match will shift to Sudden Death in order to force the issue. If that’s not enough, it will automatically activate on the closest base if enough time has elapsed.</span></p> <p><span>It’s an interesting philosophy, and in practice it means that even in matches where both teams trade blows it never feels like you’re at a standstill. Whether those feelings will last after dozens or even hundreds of games remains to be seen, but for now it lends </span><i><span>Highguard</span></i><span> a brisk energy that I didn’t really expect from such an involved gameplay loop. Certainly it accomplishes Wildlight’s stated goal of making something truly unique for the genre; it does feel like a breath of fresh air, even if individual elements are stuff we’ve seen time and again.</span></p> <p><span>My first look at the game, made the poor reception to its reveal sting all the more. </span><i><span>Highguard </span></i><span>has spent the last several weeks being the butt of the internet’s jokes, and it leaves me wondering if players will give it the chance it probably deserves. It’s easy for a developer to claim that they’ve developed something truly new for a genre, and at the same time it’s equally rare for a studio to deliver on that promise. </span><i><span>Highguard</span></i><span> well and truly feels like something special, and like </span><i><span>Titanfall </span></i><span>before it I could see it garnering a rabid fanbase. I just hope it’s afforded that chance.</span></p>      </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/highguard-impressions-titanfall-2-apex-multiplayer-shooter-2000663136]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Highguard Was Meant to be ‘Shadowdrop’, but Geoff Keighley Wanted it at The Game Awards]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/highguard-was-meant-to-be-a-shadowdrop/</link>
            <guid>1416568</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>It’s been an usual couple of months for Wildlight Entertainment’s Highguard, mostly in part to the constant abuse the game has recieved for its lack of marketing since its The Game Awards announcement.</p>



<p>But now, we know why.</p>







<h2 id="h-it-was-meant-to-be-a-shadowdrop">It was Meant to be a Shadowdrop</h2>



<p>During a behind-the-scenes presentation with press and creators, Vice President of Product and Publishing Jason Torfin and Lead Designer Mohammed Alavi sat down with attendees of the event to answer questions. </p>



<p>As expected, one of the main questions was around the games marketing, or should we say lack thereof, and that’ss because the game was always intended to follow a similar release to Apex Legends; a shadowdrop. However, sometime in 2025, The Game Awards host Geoff Keighley put a spanner in the works because he was stoked for the game and wanted to reveal it.</p>



<p><strong><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/complete-highguard-trophy-list-how-to-get-all-achievements-trophies/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">RELATED – Complete Highguard Trophy L</a><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/complete-highguard-trophy-list-how-to-get-all-achievements-trophies/">ist—How To Get All Achievements &amp; Trophies<br></a></strong><br>Speaking at the event (thanks <a href="https://xboxera.com/2026/01/26/highguard-was-meant-to-be-a-shadowdrop/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">XboxEra</a>) on the original plans, Tofin said, “I think the fact that we’re independent and that we’re smart with how we run our business and build our team means that we have those luxuries. We’re not beholden to shareholders or any sort of other corporate shenanigans, and it allows us to have that sort of confidence. And from the get-go, you can’t bank on commercial success right out of the gate. If you do that, you’re probably going to fail most of the time.”</p>







<p>“And that’s why we were going to shadow drop.” he said “Let the game speak for itself. It was always the plan. And then, you know, Geoff came in the past year and he played the game. I mean, he really liked it and he was stoked. And we had an opportunity and we decided, okay, we can make a trailer that would be in our shadow-drop. And so the one we put there [at The Game Awards] was the one that would be the first thing you saw in the shadow-drop, followed by twenty-five minutes of other context. And unfortunately, that trailer wasn’t meant to be the thing to ‘educate’.” </p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Highguard | Official Reveal Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/y_6tjMvckZ0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>So, there you have it. Highguard’s marketing wasn’t bad persay, it just changed on a whim and kind of shot themselves in the foot for a couple of months.</p>



<p>It explains why past rumours said that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/highguard-devs-didnt-pay-for-game-awards-spot/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Highguard wasn’t a paid placement</a>, despite it being the show’s last trailer (something traditionally reserved for the absolute best stuff). It simply was because Geoff Keighley liked it… Case closed!</p>



<p>Whether it means the game is good or not is another story… I guess only time will tell!</p>



<p>Do you think Highguard will be a success? Leave your thoughts down in the comments, and join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/final-fantasy-7-remake-part-3-will-stick-to-unreal-engine-4/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Final Fantasy 7 Remake Part 3 devs finalizing a title and sticking to Unreal Engine 4.</a>&nbsp;Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>


        <div>
                  <p>
                    Tom Henderson is Insider Gaming's Co-Founder and Editor-In-Chief. When he's not running one of the industry's leading independent video game websites, he's probably playing an FPS like Call of Duty,…                  </p>
                  <p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/author/tomhenderson/">
                    More from Tom Henderson                  </a>
                </p></div>
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/highguard-was-meant-to-be-a-shadowdrop/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Invincible VS adds Anissa, Lucan]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/01/invincible-vs-adds-anissa-lucan</link>
            <guid>1416565</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Prepare to be subjugated.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Anissa and Lucan will be playable characters in three-versus-three tag fighting game <em><a title="Games > Invincible VS [7 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/invincible-vs">Invincible VS</a></em>, publisher <a title="Companies > Skybound Games [85 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/skybound-games">Skybound Games</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Quarter Up [7 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/skybound-games/quarter-up">Quarter Up</a> announced. <span id="more-1021319"></span></p><p>“The Viltrumites have never been a larger part of the <em>Invincible</em> universe, so there’s no way we could leave them out of <em>Invincible VS</em>,” said <em>Invincible</em> co-creator Robert Kirkman in a press release. “Between Season 4 of the show, the events in the Battle Beast comic series and now with what’s to come in our game, 2026 is going to be a huge year for the Viltrumites.”</p><p>Here are their character descriptions:</p><blockquote><p><strong>Anissa</strong></p><p>Anissa, one of the Viltrum Empire’s most lethal and loyal enforcers, has a strong-headed nature that fuels her relentless drive to conquer civilizations she believes would be better off under the Viltrumites’ order, with little patience for those who disagree. Extremely powerful and fast, even by Viltrumite standards, she will stop at nothing to ensure planets are ready for takeover. In <em>Invincible VS</em>, Anissa is a premier “Striker” fighter who uses her incredible speed and strength to stay close to opponents with  dashing attacks, multi hit strikes, and rushdown combos.</p><p><strong>Lucan</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Keen on the superiority of his species, Lucan is loyal, ruthless and arrogant, justifying his violence through Viltrumite philosophy and law. He despises “impure” Viltrumite hybrids like Invincible and views all other species as weak. With a blunt, callous personality, Lucan lets his impressive physical abilities do most of the talking. As a strong “Grappler” fighter in <em>Invincible VS</em>, he gains leverage through aerial mobility, taking opponents down with devastating throws, hit grabs and low attacks.</p></blockquote><p><em>Invincible VS</em> is due out for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [11,260 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [8,620 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [25,340 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2353060/Invincible_VS/" target="_blank">Steam</a> and <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/store/productid/9nf8skdhflmg" target="_blank">Microsoft Store</a> on April 30.</p><p>Watch a new trailer below. View a new set of screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/invincible-vs/january-26-2026/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>Anissa and Lucan Gameplay Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Anissa &amp; Lucan Gameplay Trailer | Invincible VS" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/yZbexxHip4w?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><span>Screenshots</span></h2><div id="carousel_1021320"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/01/invincible-vs-adds-anissa-lucan]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ubisoft Launches a “Voluntary” Layoff Program at Ubisoft Paris HQ in an Attempt to Cut up to 200 Jobs]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/ubisoft-launches-voluntary-layoff-program-ubisoft-paris/</link>
            <guid>1416514</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>It seems the news around <strong>Ubisoft</strong> is not stopping anytime soon, as a statement sent to Wccftech (first spotted on <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/ubisoft-launches-voluntary-redundancy-process-to-cut-200-jobs-from-paris-head-office">GamesIndustry.Biz</a>) reveals that the company has kicked off a <strong>"<em>voluntary</em>" layoff program</strong> at its <strong>Ubisoft Paris</strong> headquarters, where it intends to cut as many as <strong>200 employees</strong> from the studio.</p>



<p>This follows after the company <a href="https://wccftech.com/ubisoft-major-reset-cancels-prince-of-persia-sands-of-time-remake/">announced it would undergo a <strong>"<em>major reset</em>"</strong> last week</a>, which saw the entire company get restructured into five different 'Creative Houses,' multiple projects getting delayed or outright cancelled, and caused the <a href="https://wccftech.com/ubisoft-lost-nearly-95-of-value-in-eight-years-34-share-price-drop-after-major-reset/">company's share price to drop to its lowest point since <strong>2011</strong></a>. Now, after a report directly regarding how <a href="https://wccftech.com/french-union-claims-ubisoft-ceo-has-no-knowledge-or-understanding-of-his-company-after-major-reset/">morale within Ubisoft and specifically at Ubisoft Paris is led by <strong>"<em>anger and despair,"</em></strong></a> we've learned that things are getting worse for employees at the Paris HQ.</p>



<p>It should be noted that, due to this being a voluntary program that will cut as many as 200 employees, it's possible that fewer than 200 positions will be made redundant by the program's completion. The statement confirms that this program <strong>only applies</strong> to employees under Ubisoft International with French contracts, and that no cuts will be made final until an agreement is reached with union representatives and validated by French authorities.</p>



<p>"<em>In line with last week’s announcements on its new operating model and the acceleration of cost-reduction&nbsp;initiatives, Ubisoft International (HQ' legal entity) has initiated discussions&nbsp;regarding&nbsp;a potential Rupture&nbsp;Conventionnelle&nbsp;Collective (RCC), <strong>a collective, voluntary mutual&nbsp;termination&nbsp;agreement</strong> that could involve&nbsp;around&nbsp;200 positions at its headquarters in France</em>," the statement reads.</p>



<p>"<em>At this stage, this&nbsp;remains&nbsp;a proposal&nbsp;and will require&nbsp;a collective agreement with&nbsp;unions&nbsp;and validation&nbsp;by French authorities&nbsp;to come into effect.</em> <em>The&nbsp;proposal&nbsp;applies exclusively to Ubisoft International employees under French contracts and has no impact on other French entities or Ubisoft teams worldwide.</em>"</p>



<p>These cuts are part of the layoffs we were told to expect after Ubisoft made it clear that part of its restructure under this "<em>major reset</em>" would be <a href="https://wccftech.com/ubisoft-more-layoffs-return-to-office-mandate/">further cost reduction to the tune of <strong>€200</strong> <strong>million</strong></a> and a return-to-office mandate, two elements that led to a strike taking place outside of Ubisoft Paris this past Thursday, January 22, 2026.</p>



<p>It's clear this is not the end of Ubisoft's woes, but only the beginning of a new chapter of bad news for Ubisoft. Last week, ahead of the strike, French video game union <strong>Solidaires Informatique</strong>, which represents several Ubisoft Paris employees, specifically called out Ubisoft chief executive officer,<strong> Yves Guillemot</strong>, for the company's current issues.</p>



<p>"<em>It is out of the question to let a boss run wild and destroy our working conditions. Perhaps we need to remind him that it is his employees who make the games</em>."</p>



<p>As one of the co-founders, along with his brothers, Yves Guillemot and his family have led Ubisoft since its inception. In the last eight years, with Yves at the helm, Ubisoft lost <strong>95% of its total value</strong>, going from a valuation of <strong>$10 billion</strong> to just <strong>$500 million</strong> as of last week.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/ubisoft-launches-voluntary-layoff-program-ubisoft-paris/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A judge has ruled that RuneScape gold pieces are real property, which is bad news for the ex-dev accused of stealing 705 billion of them]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/a-judge-has-ruled-that-runescape-gold-pieces-are-real-property-which-is-bad-news-for-the-ex-dev-accused-of-stealing-705-billion-of-them</link>
            <guid>1416511</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>The gold is allegedly worth more than £500,000</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/runescape-fara-market.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/runescape-fara-market.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/runescape-fara-market.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/runescape-fara-market.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/runescape-fara-market.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/runescape-fara-market.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/runescape-fara-market.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/runescape-fara-market.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/runescape-fara-market.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Jagex</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>When you were making plant pots in <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/runescape">RuneScape</a> and selling them to other players, you might not have thought you were laying the groundwork for a UK legal precedent that would define in-game gold as intangible property covered by the Theft Act 1968, but, well, here we are.</p>
<p>Lord Justice Popplewell has ruled on appeal that RuneScape's gold pieces are legal property, which is important for the ex-Jagex developer accused of stealing 705 billion of them.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>According to the judgement handed down by <a href="https://caselaw.nationalarchives.gov.uk/ewca/crim/2026/4#end-of-document">the Court of Appeal</a>, while working as a content developer at Jagex, the developer Andrew Lakeman is accused of accessing 68 different players accounts and "stripp[ing] those accounts of hundreds of billions of gold pieces" worth £543,123 if converted into RuneScape bonds, an item that can be bought for gold and exchanged for game membership. Jagex alleges this all took place in 2018. Lakeman and his solicitor dispute the charges.</p>
<p>When the case first went to trial last year, however, the judge dismissed the case agreeing with the defence's argument that RuneScape's in-game gold couldn't be legally defined as property under the <a href="https://www.legislation.gov.uk/ukpga/1968/60/contents">Theft Act 1968</a>.</p>
<p>While the law does exclude certain items from being considered property, such as wild mushrooms and animals, it doesn't, oddly enough, list in-game currencies. However, to be considered a legally stealable item, something also has to be "rivalrous" and not "pure information". Meaning, as quoted within the case report: "if the use or consumption of the thing by a person, or of a specific group of persons, necessarily prejudices the use or consumption of that thing by one or more other persons.”</p><p>The judge ruled in favour of the defence because Runescape's in-game gold isn't "rivalrous", because if one player has gold, it doesn't take away another player's ability to get it. “Gold pieces within [Runescape] are not sufficiently rivalrous to be classed as intangible property," the judge said. "One gold piece is the same as any other, and their supply is infinite. The fact that existing players have wealth does not preclude new players from joining the game and getting more wealth, without taking it from existing players. This means, in my judgment, that even if the Crown is able to prove every single factual assertion that forms the basis of its case, the offences currently charged are not made out in law and I would not be prepared to leave them to a jury.”</p>
<p>However, the judge left their ruling open to appeal and appeal the prosecution bloody well have. The ruling went to the Court of Appeals, and ended up in front of Lord Justice Popplewell. Hold onto your legal pads, reader.</p>
<p>"We differ from the Judge in his reasoning for reaching the contrary conclusion on rivalrousness. The two reasons which the Judge gave in his ruling do not, with respect, bear analysis," Popplewell writes. "The first was that 'one gold piece is like any other, and their supply is infinite'. This does not, however, distinguish them from many other forms of rivalrous property. One paper clip from a given manufacturer is like any other; and the manufacture and supply of them infinite, in the sense that is not capped at any finite number. Yet each paper clip constitutes property. The same is equally true of gold pieces."</p>
<p>Effectively, just because each gold piece in RuneScape is identical and functionally the same, does not make it something that a player can be deprived of.</p>
<p>"The Judge’s second reason was that '[t]he fact that existing players have wealth does not preclude new players from joining the game and getting more wealth without taking it from existing players'," Popplwell continues. "However this too is no answer to the rivalrousness of the in-game wealth which a particular player already has at any given time. It focuses only on different assets which may thereafter be acquired."</p>
<p>After all, if you had had 100 million gold taken from you and someone said, 'Don't worry, at least it won't stop other players from earning gold', you might say that doesn't make a jot of difference to you.</p>
<p>In their conclusion, Popplewell lays out their reasons for granting the prosecution's appeal, saying that RuneScape's gold pieces "are properly described as something which can be stolen as a matter of normal use of language. They do not fall within any of the established exceptions. They are not 'pure knowledge': functionally they exist as identifiable assets distinct from the code which gives rise to them and outside the minds of people. There is no good policy reason for excepting them from the category of property which can be stolen. On the contrary, they are assets which have an ascertainable monetary value and which may be traded for that value both in the game and outside the game. Within the rules of the game they represent money’s worth as the product of purchase of a bond. Outside the game they are regularly traded for money’s worth. They are capable of being subject to dishonest dealing which deprives their possessor of their use and value. It would be surprising and unsatisfactory if such dishonest dealing did not amount to the offence of theft."</p><p>While you may not want to read the whole case document, as it is a pretty extensive read, it is full of interesting examples of other legal precedents. For instance, there was the Oxford student accused of theft for taking an exam paper, even though they returned it, because they now possessed the questions that were in the document. Or the discussion that compares forbidden real money transfers in games to theft of Class A drugs.</p>
<p>With the Court of Appeal's decision now handed down, it would appear that the original case can now proceed.</p>

        </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/a-judge-has-ruled-that-runescape-gold-pieces-are-real-property-which-is-bad-news-for-the-ex-dev-accused-of-stealing-705-billion-of-them]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>