<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 04:37:12 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Cutest Cards We Pulled from Magic: The Gathering Bloomburrow]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/features/cutest-cards-we-pulled-from-magic-gathering-bloomburrow</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-cutest-cards-we-pulled-from-magic-the-gathering-bloomburrow.964164/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/tabletop/features/cutest-cards-we-pulled-from-magic-gathering-bloomburrow<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>The current&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/games/magic-the-gathering"><em>Magic: The Gathering</em></a>&nbsp;set,&nbsp;<em>Bloomburrow</em>, is basically the unofficial&nbsp;<em>Redwall</em>&nbsp;trading card game. It features cute critters, from mice to otters to raccoons, accomplishing adorable and audacious feats. Along with the <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/magic-gathering-foundations-beginner-box-helps-new-players-start">recently revealed Foundations Beginner Box</a>, it's the perfect entry point to&nbsp;<em>Magic.</em></p>
<p>But which ones are the most charming, the most precious? As the objective arbiter of all things cute, I've gone through 45 set boosters and both starter decks to serve you only the best that <i>Magic: The Gathering Bloomburrow</i>&nbsp;has to offer.</p>
<p>Instead of breaking things down by mana, I've separated them by animals that stood out to me, with two extra buckets. So without further ado, let's dive into this empirically derived, scientifically sound list of the cutest cards we pulled in&nbsp;<em>Bloomburrow</em>. Spoiler alert: The best ones are at the bottom.</p>

<h2><em>Magic: The Gathering Bloomburrow</em>'s Ravishing Rabbits</h2>
<p>Just look at this little dapper gentleman. Intrepid Rabbit is just a sweet little scout, searching for carrots and resources in the forest. I couldn't pull its token, but the general Rabbit token is also an adorable foot soldier.</p>

<p>Something that really stood out to me with the rabbits in&nbsp;<em>Magic: The Gathering Bloomburrow</em>&nbsp;is how giddy I get seeing them use human tools. Head of the Homestead is a picturesque representation of a mother taking care of her children, while Druid of the Spade feels like the rabbit is saying, "Look upon my mystic artifact, the spade!"</p>

<p>Continuing the trend of rabbits using tools, look at Finneas, Ace Archer. Finneas looks kind of slick, sort of like a bunny Legolas. And I can't help but think they trained that little tyke on the Short Bow.</p>

<p>To round out the rabbits, Hop to It is such a pure display of celebration and joy, it was hard not to include it here. And the Carrot Cake? My goodness, it's the cutest way to be both incredibly wrong and immensely accurate.</p>
<h2><em>Magic: The Gathering Bloomburrow</em>'s Sweet Squirrels</h2>

<p>Moving onto the squirrels, let's start off with Bushy Bodyguard. I'd trust this little guy with my life, along with his somehow even cuter offspring. No, I will not question the ethics of sending squirrel children into the wars of Bloomburrow.</p>

<p>Squirrels are of course known for foraging for nuts, and these two cards capture that perfectly. Thornvault Forager is just hangin' out, searching for his next meal. And once he gets it, Cache Grab (A+ pun, too) depicts the end result. Just look at those pinchable cheeks!</p>

<p>Foraging squirrels are so cute, it even gave black mana cards an opportunity to be on this list. I'll be honest, I didn't vibe with the black mana cards overall as much, but the desperate squirrels in Consumed by Greed made the cut. And Corpseberry Cultivator, while morbid, also made the mark for me.</p>

<p>But the cutest black mana card in&nbsp;<em>Magic: The Gathering Bloomburrow</em>&nbsp;is easily Stargaze. This squirrel looks so high out of its mind, it's about to go on a vision quest.</p>
<h2><em>Magic: The Gathering Bloomburrow</em>'s Adorable Otters</h2>

<p>Next up are the otters, which I primarily found in red and blue mana. Many are also wizards, and there's something about watching sea dogs be mystical that just hits that cute note so well. Like see how amazed the Coruscation Mage looks?</p>

<p>The Thundertrap Wizard gets ready to cast a spell, whispering to voices only he can hear. Or is he sleeping? Unsure, but when I found the token, I had to put it here. Look at its staff--it's actually an oar!</p>

<p>Daring Waverider and its big brother, Bria, Riptide Rogue, really capture that "dog about to go on a walk" energy. There's so much joy in their faces, and they're just out there, carvin' up some waves.</p>

<p>Otterball Antics, however, was&nbsp;<em>the&nbsp;</em>card that made me want to make this list. That otter just wants to play fetch, and he got that ball because he's a good boy (yes he is!). Pearl of Wisdom had a similar energy to me, with that look of pure happiness.</p>
<h2><em>Magic: The Gathering Bloomburrow</em>'s Trash Pandas</h2>

<p>The raccoons of Bloomburrow, aka the trash pandas, live up to their stereotypes as the scavengers of this animal kingdom. Take Out the Trash, Keen-Eyed Curator, and Peerless Recycling all capture that, and they're all adorable, especially Peerless Recycling. He's a little guy on a mission!</p>

<p>Wandertale Mentor also stood out to me, because it feels like it's telling a story. This raccoon bard has so many friends and is just trying to bring everyone together! It's so sweet.</p>

<p>But when raccoons need to get down to business, they're still pretty cute. Brambleguard Veteran is keeping an eye out, and Brazen Collector has an&nbsp;<em>Ocean's Eleven</em>&nbsp;vibe going on.</p>

<p>But all the other raccoon cards pale in comparison to Kitnap. Just look at this snoozing little baby! And ignore the Mad Hatter vibes in the background.</p>
<h2><em>Magic: The Gathering Bloomburrow</em>'s Mighty Mice</h2>

<p>Finally, we get to arguably the protagonists of this set, the mice. It's honestly unfair--almost all of the mice I found were cute. Like look at Emberheart Challenger; he's definitely a mighty warrior, but I also want to give him pets. Heartfire Hero arguably looks intimidating, but he's a hero. He wouldn't hurt me for petting him.</p>

<p>No matter what these little rascals are doing, they look cute. Brambleguard Captain is rallying the troops,&nbsp; but all I'm doing is staring at its whiskers. And what's Mouse Trapper doing? We caught it mid-Bigfoot walk, and it's owning the moment.</p>

<p>See what I mean? Every one of these mice soldiers are just too sweet, like they're straight out of a children's picture book.</p>

<p>It was really hard to be choosy here. Valley Rally, Blooming Blast, and War Squeak show some of the cutest war criminals ever, but their names are also illustrative of&nbsp;<em>Magic: The Gathering Bloomburrow</em>&nbsp;as a whole. There's a cadence to them that's whimsical. There's rhyme, alliteration, and brilliant word choices. A war cry is barbaric, but a war squeak? Perfection.</p>

<p>Even when these mice are injured or challenged, like in Dewdrop Cure and Early Winter, they're still absolutely adorable. No wonder Disney picked a mouse to be their icon. Just look at their big ears!</p>

<p>To put a bow on the mouse chapter, I want to really drive home just how much this set feels like a children's picture book. Heirloom Epic is so meta, showing a scene of children reading a book with art that looks right out of&nbsp;<em>If You Give a Mouse a Cookie</em>. And Might of the Meek, despite the snake, shows a brave little hero at the climax of his own tail (pun intended, thanks).</p>
<h2><em>Magic: The Gathering Bloomburrow</em>'s Precious Pairings</h2>

<p>Some of the bets of this set comes from the illustrations of unlikely friendships and pairings that tug at your heartstrings. That childlike hunger in the Bakersbane Duo's eyes is just chef's kiss, and the wonder on Lightshell Duo's faces is just as adorable.&nbsp;</p>

<p>While Ruthless Negotiation is a little more violent than Playful Shove, they both show cute scenes of playful antagonism in the animal kingdom.&nbsp;</p>

<p>And between Parting Gust and Brave-Kin Duo, there's a story of a rabbit-rat alliance that has waxed and waned as time has passed.</p>

<p>My absolute favorite card out of all of these, though, is Run Away Together. It's so sweet, the conclusion of a long story about the forbidden love between Libo and Pulla.</p>
<h2><em>Magic: The Gathering Bloomburrow</em>'s Other Standouts</h2>

<p>Now, you might be wondering where the frogs are. And there were a few I found cute; but for the most part, they weren't doing it for me. But Polliwallop has some roguish charm to him, with those piercing eyes. And Sunshower Druid makes me laugh, like he's presenting the sky to you.</p>

<p>Splash Portal might be the cutest frog in&nbsp;<em>Magic: The Gathering Bloomburrow</em>. It's tiny but with big eyes, which is an instant path to the top of the charts. However, I love Overprotect. I want to protect him. I will always call this card Overprotecc.</p>

<p>There are some possums in in this set, and Tender Wildguide felt like a great representation of them. It's like a parent and child, braving the big forest. And the child! It's adorable and hungry!</p>

<p>Lizards don't do it for me much either, in real life or in this set. But Iridescent Vinelasher looks like he's trying to be intimidating but just really isn't, and that sort of juxtaposition always gets me. And the flying lizard in Feather of Flight is so elated!</p>



<p>Speaking of juxtaposition, hear me out on this one. Yes, this terrifying badger definitely lifts, and he is crushing a skull. But also, his name is Hugs. And a few of his scars tell jokes!</p>

<p>The last card I wanted to share is Sugar Coat. The art style stood out to me as the most different across the 45&nbsp;<em>Bloomburrow&nbsp;</em>boosters I pulled, but the shocked rabbit gingerbread cookie was just too hard to pass up.</p>
<p>Obviously, there are many, many more we probably haven't pulled yet that are just as cute if not cuter. After all, this is the unofficial&nbsp;<em>Redwall</em>&nbsp;<em>Magic: The Gathering</em>&nbsp;set (I mean, have you seen Arthur, Marigold Night?). Now I'm off to build the most adorable, very viable Commander deck out there.</p>
<hr><p><em>Wizards of the Coast sent TechRaptor a Magic: The Gathering Bloomburrow starter kit, bundle, and play booster box.</em></p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Taiko no Tatsujin: Rhythm Festival coming to PS5, Xbox Series, and PC on November 7]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/taiko-no-tatsujin-rhythm-festival-coming-to-ps5-xbox-series-and-pc-on-november-7</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/taiko-no-tatsujin-rhythm-festival-coming-to-ps5-xbox-series-and-pc-on-november-7.964158/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/taiko-no-tatsujin-rhythm-festival-coming-to-ps5-xbox-series-and-pc-on-november-7<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Currently available for Switch.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Bandai Namco Entertainment [6,553 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/bandai-namco-entertainment">Bandai Namco</a> will release <em><a title="Games > Taiko no Tatsujin: Rhythm Festival [5 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/taiko-no-tatsujin-rhythm-festival">Taiko no Tatsujin: Rhythm Festival</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [7,790 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [5,976 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [21,067 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2288630/Taiko_no_Tatsujin_Rhythm_Festival/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/taiko-no-tatsujin-rhythm-festival/9PP1KPM20GQP/0010" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Microsoft Store</a> on November 7, the company announced. A demo is available now via <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/product/UP0700-PPSA24085_00-TAIKORFDEMO00000" rel="noopener" target="_blank">PlayStation Store</a>, <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/store/p/taiko-no-tatsujin-rhythm-festival-demo/9nn6fj5kzcd4" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Microsoft Store</a>, and <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2288630/Taiko_no_Tatsujin_Rhythm_Festival/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a>. <span id="more-908729"></span></p><p>The game will be priced at $49.99 / £39.99 / €49.99 for the standard edition, which includes the downloadable content “Namco Game Music Pack,” and $79.99 / £65.99 / €79.99 for the Setlist Edition, which includes the downloadable contents “<a title="Platforms > Anime [317 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/anime">Anime</a> Songs Collection,” “Namco Game Music Pack,” “Pops Collection,” and “Vocaloid Songs Collection.” Digital pre-orders are available now.</p><p>In Japan, the PlayStation 5 version will also be available physically. It is currently unclear whether a physical release is planned for the west.</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Taiko-Rhythm-Fes_08-26-24_PS5-Package-Japan.png"></a></figure><p>Accessory manufacturer <a title="Companies > HORI [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/hori">HORI</a> will release a dedicated controller for the game. It will be available in two SKUs—one compatible with <a href="https://hori.jp/products/p5/spf-042/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">PlayStation 5, PlayStation 4, and PC</a>, and the other compatible with <a href="https://hori.jp/products/xsx/mbs-018/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Xbox Series and PC</a>.</p><p><em>Taiko no Tatsujin: Rhythm Festival</em> first launched on September 22, 2022 in Japan and September 23 worldwide. The new release will mark the first <em>Taiko no <a title="Companies > Tatsujin [10 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/tatsujin">Tatsujin</a></em> game to support 120 frames per second on consoles, and will include new collaboration music and mini-characters exclusive to the new platforms, as well as the “Run! Ninja Dojo” mode added to the Switch version via a post-launch update.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Here is an overview of the game, via its store pages:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Welcome to Omiko City, where everyone’s favorite <em>Taiko</em> elements come together in one place! Together with Don-chan, meet your new friend, Kumo-kyun and aim to become a Taiko Master!</p><p><em>Taiko no Tatsujin: Rhythm Festival</em> is a drum-based <a title="Genres > Rhythm [146 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rhythm">rhythm game</a> featuring songs from genres such as Anime and VOCALOID, and also a variety of game modes! Have fun playing solo or online!</p><p><strong>Taiko Mode</strong></p><p>Drum along to the rhythm of your favorite songs and aim to play them from start to finish! Select from four difficulty modes.</p><p>76 songs across multiple genres such as Anime, VOCALOID, Game Music, and Pop are available in the game! Songs include “Gurenge,” “<em>My Neighbor Totoro</em> – Ending Theme Song,” “Charles,” “MEGALOVANIA,” “Into The Night,” “Feel Special,” and many more! Have fun playing casually with another player or compete for the highest score! You can also use Improvement Support to help you improve your drumming skills!</p><p><strong>Three Types of <a title="Genres > Party [70 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/party">Party</a> Games for Two to Four Players are Available</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Great Drum Toy War</strong> – Play along to songs and deploy toys to push back your opponent’s toys and aim for victory!</li><li><strong>Don-chan Band</strong> – Work as a group of four to perform successful concerts!</li><li><strong>Run! Ninja Dojo</strong> – Become a ninja and race with up to four other players! Overcome multiple obstacles as you compete for 1st place!</li></ul><p><strong>Online Matches</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Online Ranked Match</strong> – Challenge players from all over the world and aim for the top ranks!</li><li><strong>Room Match</strong> – Play casually with friends and players from around the world in Taiko Mode and Great Drum Toy War!</li></ul><p>Have fun playing <em>Taiko</em> solo, or together with friends!</p><p><strong>Taiko Music Pass</strong></p><ul><li>Join the Taiko Music Pass to access over 700 additional songs! New songs are added every month!</li><li>Some songs are also sold individually.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch the announcement trailer below.</p><h2><span>PlayStation 5, Xbox Series, and PC Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><div><blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">◤<a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/TaikonoTatsujin?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#TaikonoTatsujin</a>: Rhythm Festival<br>Will be available on PlayStation®5, Xbox Series X|S, and STEAM® on November 7!✨◢</p><p>For the first time in home-release, the game supports 120 FPS! Look forward to new platform-exclusive collab songs and mini characters~🎵 <a href="https://t.co/fV8YE3vhXX">pic.twitter.com/fV8YE3vhXX</a></p><p>— Taiko no Tatsujin (@taiko_en) <a href="https://twitter.com/taiko_en/status/1828190685939511363?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 26, 2024</a></p></blockquote></div><p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe title="新プラットフォームで登場！『太鼓の達人 ドンダフルフェスティバル』PlayStation(R)5/Xbox Series X|S/Windows PC/STEAM(R)11月7日発売！" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/azFTGYIll1s?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Valve’s worst-kept secret is no longer a secret]]></title>
            <link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=2045368</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/valve%E2%80%99s-worst-kept-secret-is-no-longer-a-secret.964155/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://arstechnica.com/?p=2045368<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
            <h4>
      Officially official    —
</h4>
            
            <h2 itemprop="description"><em>Deadlock</em> is now on Steam and on streams.</h2>
                    </div><div itemprop="articleBody">
                                    
<figure>
  
      <figcaption><p><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/deadlock.jpg" data-height="530" data-width="940">Enlarge</a> <span>/</span> Look! A wild Valve game appears!</p><p>Valve</p></figcaption>  </figure>

  




<!-- cache hit 50:single/related:942df40ddd6398714e204081833d3372 --><!-- empty -->
<p>If you read Ars Technica regularly, you've known <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2024/05/leaks-from-valves-deadlock-look-like-a-pressed-sandwich-of-every-game-around/">since May</a> that Valve is working on <em>Deadlock</em>, a mishmash of genres that has been slowly amassing <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/1422450/charts/#max">SteamDB-tracked players</a> through an invite-only playtest. Over the weekend, Valve took the "hiding" part out of that "hiding-in-plain-sight" test, launching <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1422450/Deadlock/?curator_clanid=4777282">a bare bones Steam page for <em>Deadlock</em></a>, the company's first attempt at developing a new gaming franchise since collectible card game <em>Artifact</em> <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2018/08/exclusive-valve-walks-us-through-artifacts-new-demo-leaves-us-wanting-more/">launched in 2018</a> (and <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2021/03/valve-scraps-revamped-artifact-dumps-free-unfinished-2-0-version-on-steam/">fell apart in 2021</a>).
</p><p>The new page, which went up on Saturday, has precious little information about <em>Deadlock</em>, save for a description as "a multiplayer game in early development" and a 22-second trailer that essentially pans over a piece of concept art. Everything from the game's system requirements to the release date is still "TBD," and players who are lucky enough to get "friend invites via our playtesters" are promised "temporary art and experimental gameplay" on the Steam page.
</p><p>Not that a Steam page is strictly needed for more info on <em>Deadlock</em> at this point. Since the first leaks months ago, the playtest has slowly expanded from hundreds of players to tens of thousands, including some who have <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/8/12/24219016/valve-deadlock-hands-on-secret-new-game">posted extensive impressions</a> of the game. Valve has also reportedly lifted rules regarding streaming for invited playtesters, leading to <a href="https://www.twitch.tv/directory/category/deadlock-1">a surge of players showing off live gameplay on Twitch</a>.</p>                                                                        
                                                                                
<figure><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/deadlock2.png" data-height="720" data-width="1280" alt="See how many genres you can pick out."></a><figcaption><p><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/deadlock2.png" data-height="720" data-width="1280">Enlarge</a> <span>/</span> See how many genres you can pick out.</p><p>Valve</p></figcaption></figure>
<p>Those extended streams and impressions show a six-on-six hero shooter (a la <em>Overwatch</em>) but with teams of NPC drones protecting <em>Dota 2</em>-style battle lanes as well. There's also the requisite <em>Fortnite</em>-style cover construction, <em>Titanfall</em>-style double-jumping and air-dashing, melee attacks and parries, and all the unlockable abilities you could hope for.</p>
<p>Given all that direct info, the presence of a new Steam page mainly serves as an anchor for Wishlist-based reminders, user-defined tagging (bot "MOBA" and "cute" are currently popular), and a lot of spammy/scammy invite-begging in the <a href="https://steamcommunity.com/app/1422450/discussions/">Community hub</a> and <a href="https://steamcommunity.com/app/1422450/discussions/">forums</a>. Still, it's not every day that a completely new title appears on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/search/?sort_by=Released_DESC&amp;supportedlang=english&amp;developer=Valve&amp;ndl=1">Valve's old Steam developer page</a>—we've set a reminder to check for the next one in 2030 or so.</p>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Atari Announces Fatal Run Revival, Fatal Run 2089]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/atari-announces-fatal-run-revival-fatal-run-2089/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/atari-announces-fatal-run-revival-fatal-run-2089.964119/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/atari-announces-fatal-run-revival-fatal-run-2089/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Today, Atari announced its Fatal Run revival, titled Fatal Run 1989. This game was a huge hit globally when it was <a href="https://wccftech.com/atari-acquires-digital-eclipse-to-bolster-its-retro-focused-strategy/">first released in 1990</a>, and it was available on the Atari 7800 and Atari 2600. Fatal Run 2089 is set for a 2025 release on Steam, Epic, Nintendo Switch, PlayStation 5, Xbox One, and Xbox Series X|S.</p>
<p>This title is being developed by MNSTR Studios, and it will be their first game. Their website shows a portfolio full of 3D projects, such as Mech characters, concept art, and illustration. They have helped with a multitude of projects that perhaps haven't been released yet, as they have a banner with Power Rangers on it.</p>
<p>Returning to Fatal Run 2089, the game is being made in Unreal Engine 5, which will make the races much more intense for players eager to get a hit of nostalgia. This game takes place in a post-apocalyptic fantasy landscape, where players will explore four distinctive global regions, each with its own unique characteristics.</p>
<p>Each region will have hairpin turns, branching paths, explosives, and secret routes for players to discover. Fatal Run 2089 will consist of 20 levels in total for players to race through, with a choice between seven different vehicles, which all have their unique specialities, so players will have to choose wisely and experiment with each vehicle to find the one that will secure their victory.</p>
<p>Atari has released the official announcement trailer for Fatal Run 2089, which can be watched below.&nbsp; It showcases the post-apocalyptic world which is now bathed in radiation, and you join a group of determined scientists known as the "Engineers." By joining them, your mission throughout your time with them is to transport ARCs- advanced clean energy devices that will help clear up the radiation and purify the atmosphere so that the earth can begin to be populated once more.</p>
<p><iframe title="Fatal Run 2089 - Announcement Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/kXausJuseIM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>While it is a racing game, that's not all there is to it. Players will get to face off against four difficult bosses, which come with their abilities and strategies that will require you to think outside the box to defeat them. In addition, there are also fun arcade-style challenges to participate in, where you have to race and take shortcuts to beat the clock.</p>
<p>Currently, there is no official store for Fatal Run 2089 as the game is still in early development, and there is no suggestion of its release price. However, an <a href="https://atari.com/products/fatal-run-2089?utm_source=%C3%9CberStrategist+PR+List+-+Leading+Gaming+and+Tech+News+%282023%29&amp;utm_campaign=1a4793c375-EMAIL_CAMPAIGN_2024_08_22_05_16&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_term=0_-1a4793c375-%5BLIST_EMAIL_ID%5D" target="_blank" rel="noopener">official page</a> on Atari provides more details about the game.</p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Report: Activision Canceled A Crash Bandicoot / Spyro Crossover Game]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/crash-bandicoot-5-spyro-crossover-cancelled-activision-1851632213</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/report-activision-canceled-a-crash-bandicoot-spyro-crossover-game.964116/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/crash-bandicoot-5-spyro-crossover-cancelled-activision-1851632213<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="0e29178d8829a460762192712c056588" data-recommend-id="image://0e29178d8829a460762192712c056588" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="An image shows reported concept art of Crash and Spyro. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="An image shows reported concept art of Crash and Spyro. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Activision / Liam Robertson / Did You Know Gaming</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="0e29178d8829a460762192712c056588" data-recommend-id="image://0e29178d8829a460762192712c056588" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="An image shows reported concept art of Crash and Spyro. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>A new report claims that <em>Crash Bandicoot 5</em> was greenlit by Activision, but was then canceled very early in development due to <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/crash-bandicoot-4-its-about-time-the-kotaku-review-1845237873&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/crash-bandicoot-4-its-about-time-the-kotaku-review-1845237873"><em>Crash 4</em></a></span> selling poorly and the publisher wanting to focus more on live-service titles, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/now-every-single-activision-studio-works-on-call-of-dut-1846798677&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/now-every-single-activision-studio-works-on-call-of-dut-1846798677">like <em>Call of Duty: Warzone</em></a></span><em>. </em>Interestingly, this game would have seen the wumpa-fruit-loving marsupial cross over with another platforming mascot, Spyro the Dragon. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196923" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Kotaku’s Hopes For Spyro The Dragon’s (Reported) Comeback" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="355" data-playlist="196923,196086,196918" data-current="196923"><div><p>Kotaku’s Hopes For Spyro The Dragon’s (Reported) Comeback</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196923/196923_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196923/196923_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196923/196923_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196923/196923_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/22494.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>According to a new report from gaming journalist and historian Liam Robertson, formerly Activision-owned studio Toys For Bob began working on a multiplayer <em>Crash Bandicoot </em>game after it had wrapped on the <em>Spyro Reignited</em> <em>Trilogy</em>. But then the company took some of that work and began developing 2020's <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/crash-bandicoot-4-its-about-time-the-kotaku-review-1845237873&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/crash-bandicoot-4-its-about-time-the-kotaku-review-1845237873"><em>Crash Bandicoot 4: It’s About Time</em></a></span>. That game was well-liked by fans and critics, and Toys For Bob began planning a follow-up. </p><p>This new game, known internally as<em> Crash Bandicoot 5</em>, was planned to be a direct sequel to <em>Crash 4 </em>and would be a single-player 3D platformer, like previous entries in the long-running franchise.<br></p><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://youtu.be/PzHwPNPW2VM&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://youtu.be/PzHwPNPW2VM" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Robertson’s video</a></span> includes concept art and possible story ideas for this never-finished <em>Crash </em>sequel. At one point, the developers were planning to include Spyro in the sequel, with the report claiming that the two would have worked together to save their respective universes from a giant cataclysmic event. Both characters would be playable, and players would even see both characters’ universes in this multiverse pitch. </p><p><em>Kotaku </em>has reached out to Activision about the report. </p><p>According to the report, Toys For Bob only worked on<em> Crash 5</em> for around three to four months and largely focused on concept art and early environments. In the winter of 2020, Activision canceled <em>Crash 5,</em> reportedly due to <em>Crash 4</em>'s low sales and the publisher wanting to focus on online games over single-player titles. Toys for Bob then worked on <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/crash-team-rumble-preview-catbat-bandicoot-multiplayer-1850526763&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/crash-team-rumble-preview-catbat-bandicoot-multiplayer-1850526763"><em>Crash Team Rumble</em></a></span>, a short-lived and not very popular online game that you <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/crash-team-rumble-will-be-getting-no-more-content-updates-after-next-week/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/crash-team-rumble-will-be-getting-no-more-content-updates-after-next-week/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">probably forgot even launched</a></span>. </p><p>Thankfully, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/spyro-crash-bandicoot-toys-for-bob-activision-indie-1851298773&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/spyro-crash-bandicoot-toys-for-bob-activision-indie-1851298773">Toys for Bob was able to survive</a></span> all this. In February, the company announced that it was going independent and would work alongside Activision-owner Microsoft on a new project. It’s now rumored that <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/spyro-the-dragon-4-in-development-toys-for-bob-1851459412&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/spyro-the-dragon-4-in-development-toys-for-bob-1851459412">Toys For Bob is working on a new <em>Spyro</em> game</a></span>. <br></p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Black Myth: Wukong Mod Brings Dragon Ball Z Connections Full Circle and Lets You Play as Goku]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/black-myth-wukong-mod-brings-dragon-ball-goku</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/black-myth-wukong-mod-brings-dragon-ball-z-connections-full-circle-and-lets-you-play-as-goku.964107/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/black-myth-wukong-mod-brings-dragon-ball-goku<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>Dragon Ball has many inspirations, none more notable than Journey to the West — the famous Chinese novel that also served as the basis for Black Myth: Wukong. Now Dragon Ball Z and Black Myth: Wukong are being united thanks to a new mod that replaces The Destined One with Son Goku.</p><p>The new mod is a relatively straightforward swap — no kamehameha or going Super Saiyan here — but it is pretty neat to see Goku running around Black Myth: Wukong's incredibly detailed world. He can even zip around on the equivalent of the Flying Nimbus, the magic cloud that itself was borrowed from Journey to the West and appears in Black Myth: Wukong. Check it out in the video below.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>You can download the <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/blackmythwukong/mods/84?tab=images" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Son Goku Black Myth: Wukong mod right here</a>.</p><p>Aside from Son Goku, a host of other <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/blackmythwukong/mods/categories/2/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Black Myth: Wukong mods let players swap in Tifa</a>, swap The Destined One's staff for a double-bladed lightsaber (<a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/blackmythwukong/mods/42" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">very cool</a>), and make tweaks to various aspects of the visuals and performance.</p><p>Whether you play with Goku or not, though, you'll need a <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/black-myth-wukong-review-pc">pretty beefy rig to be able to enjoy Black Myth: Wukong</a>. Our reviewer Mitchell Saltzman utilized a top-of-the-line setup with a GeForce RTX 4090 and he still dealt with numerous crashes and other issues. Still, that hasn't stopped Black Myth: Wukong from <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/black-myth-wukong-sells-an-incredible-10-million-copies-in-just-3-days">enjoying record concurrent numbers on Steam en route to selling 10 million copies in just three days</a>.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3>Best Video Games of 2024 So Far</h3></div></output><p>If you do decide to pick up Black Myth: Wukong, make sure to check out the following guides, which you can find linked below. And of course, make sure to check out the other <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-best-reviewed-games-of-2024">best-reviewed games released in 2024</a>.</p><ul data-cy="list"><li><a href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/black-myth-wukong/Essential_Tips_and_Tricks">Essential Tips and Tricks</a></li><li><a href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/black-myth-wukong/Things_Black_Myth_Wukong_Doesn%27t_Tell_You">Things Black Myth Wukong Doesn't Tell You</a></li><li><a href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/black-myth-wukong/Walkthrough">Walkthrough</a></li><li><a href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/black-myth-wukong/Boss_List_and_Guides">Boss List and Guides</a></li><li><a href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/black-myth-wukong/Armor_and_Gear">Armor and Gear</a></li><li><a href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/black-myth-wukong/Weapons">Weapons</a></li><li><a href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/black-myth-wukong/Transformation_Spells">Transformation Spells</a></li><li><a href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/black-myth-wukong/Gourds">Gourds</a></li><li><a href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/black-myth-wukong/How_to_Increase_Gourd_Uses_and_Healing_Amount">How to Increase Gourd Uses and Healing Amount</a></li><li><a href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/black-myth-wukong/Spirit_Locations">Spirit Locations</a></li></ul><p><em>Kat Bailey is IGN's News Director as well as co-host of Nintendo Voice Chat. Have a tip? Send her a DM at @the_katbot.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Black Ops 6 Movement Is Even More Ridiculous Than You Think]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/black-ops-6-movement-is-even-more-ridiculous-than-you-think/1100-6526129/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/black-ops-6-movement-is-even-more-ridiculous-than-you-think.964104/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/black-ops-6-movement-is-even-more-ridiculous-than-you-think/1100-6526129/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-main">

      
                    
  
              <header id="masthead"><nav></nav></header>      
                            <div id="site-wrapper" role="main">
          <div id="default-content">
        
          <p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p>
  
    <article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6526129">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>For years, "dolphin diving" has been a popular way to travel across the map when playing Call of Duty. The latest installment in the franchise,<a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/call-of-duty-black-ops-6/"> Black Ops 6,</a> aims to evolve this popular method by introducing a new way for players to channel their inner dolphin.</p><p dir="ltr">This feature was discovered shortly after<a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/black-ops-6-multiplayer-trailer-shows-off-whats-new-in-this-years-call-of-duty/1100-6526103/"> Call of Duty posted a multiplayer trailer</a> on its<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GYG_h-L-K2E"> official YouTube channel</a>. The trailer featured many mechanics players have known about for some time, such as the<a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-leaks-continue-this-time-with-a-graphic-new-ability/1100-6525547/https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-leaks-continue-this-time-with-a-graphic-new-ability/1100-6525547/"> meatshield</a> and how<a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/black-ops-6-dev-hopes-omnimovement-system-becomes-a-call-of-duty-standard/1100-6524179/"> omnimovement</a> looks in action. But what caught a lot of people's attention was how players can now Dolphin Dive out of the water and use omnimovement to their advantage to create a Max Payne-like action sequences.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="1541634141" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6464977,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Call%20of%20Duty%3A%20Black%20Ops%206%20-%20Official%20Multiplayer%20Reveal%20Trailer&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:135,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-official-multiplayer-reveal-trailer\/2300-6464977\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464977\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464977\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464977\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6464977&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6464977,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6526129&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;call-of-duty-black-ops-6&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;xbox-series-x,playstation-5,pc,playstation-4,xbox-one&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;activision,microsoft-game-studios&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;franchise&quot;:&quot;call-of-duty&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;franchiseRoot&quot;:&quot;call-of-duty&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6464977},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6464977\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;Publisher Asset&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4356931-11.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/DouYl71e.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1724681520,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="DouYl71e" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 - Official Multiplayer Reveal Trailer</p>
      </div>
<p dir="ltr">For those unaware of "dolphin diving", it's when players launch themselves forward, and once they land, they are immediately prone. While they're in the air, players look like dolphins, and that's where the name comes from.</p><p dir="ltr">This wasn't the only trailer Activision has recently released. Earlier last week,<a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/black-ops-6-liberty-falls-zombies-mode-gets-impressive-and-dramatic-cinematic-trailer/1100-6526085/"> the studio released a new Zombie trailer</a>, which picks up after the events of Black Ops: Cold War's Zombie mode. Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 launches on October 25, but<a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-beta-dates-how-to-get-in/1100-6524124/"> players can try it out early thanks to the beta set to begin on August 30</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article>

    
  

</div>
                      <meta itemprop="seamless-content-list-items" data-list-items="[{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525959&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-campaign-gameplay-revealed-during-gamescom\/1100-6525959\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526085&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/black-ops-6-liberty-falls-zombies-mode-gets-impressive-and-dramatic-cinematic-trailer\/1100-6526085\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526103&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/black-ops-6-multiplayer-trailer-shows-off-whats-new-in-this-years-call-of-duty\/1100-6526103\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526077&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/avowed-will-be-30fps-on-xbox-series-x-allowing-for-juicier-visual-effects\/1100-6526077\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525970&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/vampire-the-masquerade-bloodlines-2-delayed-to-the-first-half-of-2025\/1100-6525970\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526036&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/cod-modern-warfare-3-and-warzone-how-to-unlock-the-torque-35\/1100-6526036\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526035&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/cod-modern-warfare-3-and-warzone-how-to-unlock-the-spear-melee-weapon\/1100-6526035\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526121&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/gta-6-could-prompt-a-shift-to-more-expensive-games\/1100-6526121\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525805&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/an-exciting-twist-makes-lost-records-bloom-and-rage-more-than-a-life-is-strange-imitator\/1100-6525805\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526081&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/the-next-dragon-age-adventure-is-out-very-soon-but-its-not-what-you-think-it-is\/1100-6526081\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526093&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/switch-might-finally-get-a-sims-game-but-maybe-not-the-one-you-expect\/1100-6526093\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525974&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/joker-2-was-originally-envisioned-as-a-broadway-show\/1100-6525974\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525917&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/sniper-elite-resistance-revealed-at-gamescom-with-a-new-main-character\/1100-6525917\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525913&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/inzoi-gamescom-trailer-shows-the-joy-and-pain-of-everyday-life\/1100-6525913\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525935&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/the-first-goat-simulator-is-getting-a-remaster-later-this-year\/1100-6525935\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525975&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/todd-phillips-doesnt-want-to-make-joker-3\/1100-6525975\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525960&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/civilization-vii-releasing-february-11-or-a-week-earlier-with-more-expensive-editions\/1100-6525960\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525977&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/borderlands-4-announced-during-opening-night-live-coming-2025\/1100-6525977\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525985&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/persona-5s-joker-is-coming-to-persona-3-reload-as-an-enemy\/1100-6525985\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525921&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/gamescom-onl-mecha-break-gets-action-packed-new-trailer-closed-beta-on-xbox-coming-soon\/1100-6525921\/&quot;}]">
            </div>
              
    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How Long Is Star Wars Outlaws? Campaign Length And Mission List Revealed]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/how-long-is-star-wars-outlaws-and-mission-list/1100-6526128/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/how-long-is-star-wars-outlaws-campaign-length-and-mission-list-revealed.964101/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/how-long-is-star-wars-outlaws-and-mission-list/1100-6526128/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6526128">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/star-wars-outlaws/" data-ref-id="5000-590940">Star Wars Outlaws</a> has arrived, unofficially kicking off this year's busy autumn and holiday gaming season. As a major studio's semi-open-world action-adventure Star Wars game, it's likely going to be a big deal, even as early opinions are somewhat mixed on Massive Entertainment's post-Division effort. In this guide, we'll explain how long it takes to beat Star Wars Outlaws, giving multiple estimates to cover different play styles, while also highlighting the full mission list for the game's critical path.</p><h2>How long is Star Wars Outlaws?</h2><p>Kay Vess' story sees her exploring multiple planets across the Star Wars universe, and in typical Ubisoft fashion, there's a lot to see whether you're on or off the main mission path. Still, for the type of player only in it for the main storyline, Star Wars Outlaws will take roughly <strong>12-15 hours</strong>. But there's a lot more to see for more dedicated players.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="1336932636" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6464949,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Star%20Wars%20Outlaws%20Everything%20To%20Know&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:390,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/star-wars-outlaws-everything-to-know\/2300-6464949\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464949\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464949\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464949\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6464949&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6464949,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6526128&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;star-wars-outlaws&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;action,adventure&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;xbox-series-x,playstation-5,pc&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;ubisoft&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;franchise&quot;:&quot;star-wars&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;franchiseRoot&quot;:&quot;star-wars&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6464949},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6464949\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;Publisher Asset&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4355359-outlawetk_site.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/83Og0Ndk.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1724341140,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="83Og0Ndk" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> Star Wars Outlaws Everything To Know</p>
      </div>
<p>For a player who wants to beat the main game and see some or much of the side content but doesn't intend to see it all to 100% completion, a playthrough will take more like <strong>16-25 hours</strong>. Lastly, for the most dedicated Star Wars fans wanting to scrub the game's four major planets of all its map markers, gambling minigames, and morally dubious characters offering you rewards for some questionable deeds, a 100% playthrough will take <strong>25-40 hours</strong>.</p><h2>Star Wars Outlaws missions list</h2><p>Lots of players like to see a game's mission list as they play so they know how much more of a story they have before the credits roll. In the case of Star Wars Outlaws, players will tell Kay and Nix's story across 19 main missions. We've listed them all below in roughly chronological order, but take note that sometimes multiple missions are available at the same time, so your final order of completed missions may differ slightly from the adventure we went on.</p><ol><li>Beginnings</li><li>Outlaws</li><li>Crashed</li><li>Underworld</li><li>New Tricks</li><li>False Flag</li><li>The Wreck</li><li>Hyperspace</li><li>The Heavy</li><li>The Safecracker</li><li>The Droidsmith</li><li>Gunsmith</li><li>Breakout</li><li>The Hive</li><li>Viper</li><li>Partners</li><li>Jabba's Favor</li><li>Legacy</li><li>The Truth</li></ol><p>We have a lot more to help you in your Star Wars Outlaws journey, such as <strong><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/star-wars-outlaws-tips-beginners-guide-20-things-to-know/2900-5725/" data-ref-id="2900-5725">20 tips you to know before you explore a galaxy far, far away</a></strong>. We've also detailed <strong><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/star-wars-outlaws-experts-abilities-skills-guide/2900-5726/" data-ref-id="2900-5726">all Star Wars Outlaws abilities</a></strong>, which have an unconventional unlocking method in that they come from experts you meet during your travels. You can find these and lots more in our <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/star-wars-outlaws-guides-hub/1100-6526104/" data-ref-id="1100-6526104"><strong>Star Wars Outlaws guides hub</strong></a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/111003174123010839883?rel=author">Mark Delaney</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[10 New Looks At Metal Gear Solid 3's Very Pretty Remake]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/mgs3-delta-snake-eater-remake-ps5-screenshots-new-1851632108</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/10-new-looks-at-metal-gear-solid-3s-very-pretty-remake.964083/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/mgs3-delta-snake-eater-remake-ps5-screenshots-new-1851632108<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><figure id="" data-id="8459d228d8b43269e3c3686d139be884" data-recommend-id="image://8459d228d8b43269e3c3686d139be884" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="An image shows two screenshots of MGS3's remake. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="An image shows two screenshots of MGS3's remake. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Konami / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="8459d228d8b43269e3c3686d139be884" data-recommend-id="image://8459d228d8b43269e3c3686d139be884" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="An image shows two screenshots of MGS3's remake. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p><em>Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater</em> might not have a release date yet, but Konami has released some new screenshots of the upcoming remake and the game looks awesome. </p><p><em>MGS3</em>'s remake was first announced back in May 2023. Since then we’ve seen some gameplay, some trailers, and some screenshots of the impressive-looking remake of the 2004 entry in the stealth action series<em>.</em> That game was initially released on PS2 and while I think it still looks great today thanks to some really smart art and style choices, there’s no denying that this remake looks more “realistic.” </p><p>On August 26, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://blog.playstation.com/2024/08/26/metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater-hands-on-report/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://blog.playstation.com/2024/08/26/metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater-hands-on-report/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Sony and Konami released 10 new screenshots</a></span> for the upcoming remake via the PlayStation Blog. These new looks at the game come alongside a slew of previews from folks who got a chance to play <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/metal-gear-solid-3-delta-remake-performance-mode-60fps-1851631819&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/metal-gear-solid-3-delta-remake-performance-mode-60fps-1851631819">the first 90 minutes of <em>MGS Delta Snake Eater</em></a></span><em>.</em> According to those previews, the game is basically the PS2 classic, but with a fresh coat of Unreal Engine paint. And that sounds pretty good to me! </p><p>In the new screenshots released by Konami on Monday, we can see all the detail that is being packed into the remake. Sure, you can argue that the PS2 original still holds up, I think it does, but it’s impressive to see such photorealistic depictions of <em>MGS 3 </em>locations, characters, and moments. I don’t think the upcoming remake will replace the original <em>MGS3</em> at all, but as a new spin on the classic stealth action game, it sounds exciting.</p><p><em>Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater</em> is set to arrive sometime this year for PS5, Xbox Series X/S, and PC.</p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Here Come The Gokus In Black Myth: Wukong]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/black-myth-wukong-dragon-ball-z-goku-best-mods-1851632139</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/here-come-the-gokus-in-black-myth-wukong.964080/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/black-myth-wukong-dragon-ball-z-goku-best-mods-1851632139<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="b4879ddfbc0b72b94ef3407571ca9409" data-recommend-id="image://b4879ddfbc0b72b94ef3407571ca9409" data-format="webp" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Goku looks into a snowy forest. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Goku looks into a snowy forest. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Game Science / norskpl</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="b4879ddfbc0b72b94ef3407571ca9409" data-recommend-id="image://b4879ddfbc0b72b94ef3407571ca9409" data-format="webp" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Goku looks into a snowy forest. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>  <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/black-myth-wukong-review-soulslike-pc-ps5-1851629456&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/black-myth-wukong-review-soulslike-pc-ps5-1851629456"><em>Black Myth: Wukong</em></a></span><em> </em>is taking over on PC at the moment, propelling Steam to new heights as players flock to the old-school feeling action game. The fan mods are already flooding in as a result, and it was only a matter of time before <em>Dragon Ball Z</em>’s Goku became a playable hero in the spiritually-linked fantasy tale.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="194440" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Fortnite Totally Nailed Attack on Titan's Thrilling Movement" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="160" data-playlist="194440,193739,195064" data-current="194440"><div><p>Fortnite Totally Nailed Attack on Titan's Thrilling Movement</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/194440/194440_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/194440/194440_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/194440/194440_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/194440/194440_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/19886.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>Both <em>Black Myth: Wukong </em>and<em> Dragon Ball Z </em>take inspiration from the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/dbz/comments/y0y7tm/the_many_connections_between_journey_to_the_west/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/dbz/comments/y0y7tm/the_many_connections_between_journey_to_the_west/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Chinese novel <em>Journey to the West</em></a></span><em>.</em> It includes the trials and tribulations of the powerful Monkey King disciple, which forms the basis for the protagonist of <em>Black Myth</em> as well as part of Goku’s backstory. The manga and anime character’s power pole, nimbus cloud, and great ape transformation are all borrowed from the story. </p><p>The Goku mods for <em>Black Myth</em>, of which there are two so far, swap the Super Saiyan in for Sun Wukong. Both are by Nexus Mods user norskpl and the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.nexusmods.com/blackmythwukong/mods/84&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.nexusmods.com/blackmythwukong/mods/84" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">first one</a></span> swaps in a 2D-looking Goku model for the <em>Black Myth </em>hero’s first costume. Norskpl’s <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.nexusmods.com/blackmythwukong/mods/99&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.nexusmods.com/blackmythwukong/mods/99" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">second Goku mod</a></span> does the same but with the model from the now-defunct 2019 <em>Jump Force</em> fighting game. It’s a much more detailed and congruous fit for <em>Black Myth</em>’s gritty, hyper-realistic look, but also a bit of a Franken-Goku if you ask me. </p><p>The mods for<em> Black Myth </em>will no doubt continue to pour in, especially given the relatively simplicity of swapping out one avatar for another. While the most popular mods currently are for <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.nexusmods.com/blackmythwukong/mods/1&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.nexusmods.com/blackmythwukong/mods/1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">better visuals</a></span>, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.nexusmods.com/blackmythwukong/mods/8&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.nexusmods.com/blackmythwukong/mods/8" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">anti-stutter</a></span>, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.nexusmods.com/blackmythwukong/mods/55&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.nexusmods.com/blackmythwukong/mods/55" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">a better dodge</a></span>, and <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.nexusmods.com/blackmythwukong/mods/60&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.nexusmods.com/blackmythwukong/mods/60" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">a simple map</a></span>, there’s also one that lets you <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.nexusmods.com/blackmythwukong/mods/41&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.nexusmods.com/blackmythwukong/mods/41" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">play as Tifa</a></span> from <em>Final Fantasy VII Remake</em>. One of the warriors who helped bring down Sephiroth should be able to make short work of <em>Black Myth</em>’s hulking monsters. </p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Core Keeper Review - Mining Into Full Launch]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/core-keeper-review</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/core-keeper-review-mining-into-full-launch.964047/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/core-keeper-review<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="105c7ebb-da58-479d-946e-31c72eea19d1" href="https://techraptor.net/games/core-keeper"><em>Core Keeper</em></a> is an exciting mash-up of <em>Terraria</em> and <a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="f896d9a3-1981-402e-9f6e-c0b67ed170cd" href="https://techraptor.net/games/minecraft"><em>Minecraft</em></a>. A sandbox adventure, it mixes farming, exploration, and open-world building in a pixel art top-down world. Featuring a compelling story, unique areas, and epic bosses to face down, it offers hours of content for those wanting a different mining experience.&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>Core Keeper</em> offers tons of content with over 10 different biomes to explore, each with their own specific resources and enemies. Just getting through the main storyline and defeating the nine different bosses can take upwards of 30 hours. That doesn’t include completing collections, taking on side bosses, building a creative base, or adventuring through the endgame biome, The Passage. For players who want a game that has plenty of bang for the buck, <em>Core Keeper</em> is a solid title.&nbsp;</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/core-keeper-cherry-tree.jpg?itok=z-zCd0Rn 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/core-keeper-cherry-tree.jpg?itok=X2Dow0MO 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>The biomes themselves differ from one another, from the fiery <a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="01e3d552-a4c1-4e86-985b-99d3681f3792" href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/guides/core-keeper-molten-quarry-biome-guide">Molten Quarry</a> to the open water of the <a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="e44a1a42-9d12-496a-9fc0-3a1c7a378383" href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/guides/core-keeper-sunken-sea-biome-guide">Sunken Sea</a>. Your character will start in the dirt biome, but quickly expand into the <a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="463ddf9e-fce0-47ad-87f9-b33517bcebd6" href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/guides/core-keeper-clay-caves-biome-guide">Clay Caves</a> with the Larva Hive and the <a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="feebb9da-b498-426b-bb53-e3a00c001842" href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/guides/core-keeper-forgotten-ruins-biome-guide">Forgotten Ruins</a>. From there, even more variety is found as you travel through a lush jungle, hit the sands with the beach, and mine through rock walls to find the scorching desert. Within the areas are different monsters, vegetation, and ore formations.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The story itself is an interesting one and is a fun play on Alice falling down the rabbit hole. You end up underground and are looking for a way out. This underground is closer to what you’d find in <em>Journey to the Center of the Earth</em>, versus an actual cave system. First, you need to power the mysterious Core that you appear near, then vanquish more bosses to help the Core out. The ending has quite a twist, and without spoiling, is definitely worth hunting down all the souls.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The way bosses are found in the game makes the combat experience more rewarding. You need to farm resources to attract most of the creatures to a specific location or along a path they regularly travel. That doesn’t mean you won’t see them flying above you or swimming below your boat. It does mean you'll need to <a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="e3e21d0d-ff28-47c5-a777-48cb0a33554e" href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/guides/core-keeper-monster-farm-guide">farm monsters</a> to call the bosses, even when their shadow follows you. It also means you can defeat them multiple times if you want to challenge yourself or run out of their unique loot.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/core-keeper-ancient-forge.jpg?itok=jNbdoOfN 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/core-keeper-ancient-forge.jpg?itok=aol8hARe 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>All elements of the title are enhanced with the ambient music and sounds that are present as you explore. Popping bubbles on the beach, squelching when facing slimes, and roaring when hitting a boss all add to the immersion. The music tracks are calming and chilling, depending on where you are, and aid in bringing the game to life.&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p>Like all sandbox games, the main downfall of <em>Core Keeper</em> is you can end up grinding for resources, especially towards the endgame. Mining for ore, farming specific monsters, and even getting to the areas you want to reach, can add significant time to your playthrough. If you’re someone that doesn’t like grinding or doing the same actions for a length of time, you still want to check out <em>Core Keeper</em>, but should look into <a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="b83999b8-753b-41f0-9a88-581efe78884c" href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/guides/core-keeper-guides-guide-hub">various guides</a> to get those items efficiently.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/core-keeper-failed-titan.jpg?itok=B8xSWDwT 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/core-keeper-failed-titan.jpg?itok=VHoU6P-u 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>While there may be some repetition and grinding, the game itself is extremely replayable. This is especially the case with the inclusion of world seed and difficulty editing. You can create an easier world for your solo game, but an extremely hard world for playing with friends. You can increase the resources, reduce the possibility of grinding, or decrease certain game aspects you dislike. The customization really brings <em>Core Keeper</em> to the next level when it comes to investing in a game you can continuously play.&nbsp;</p>
<h2>Core Keeper Review | Final Thoughts</h2>
<p>Overall, Core Keeper is a solid mining sandbox game with some survival mechanics mixed in. It has hours of content to explore, multiple bosses to fight, and an interesting storyline to pull you along. There’s endless creativity on display and it’s worth every penny.</p>
<p>Whether you’re looking for a new game to dive into for long gaming sessions or want something that’s easy to pick up and put down, <em>Core Keeper</em> is the title for you.</p>
<hr><p><em><strong>Core Keeper</strong>&nbsp;was reviewed on PC via Steam with a copy provided by the developers over the course of 39 hours of gameplay - all screenshots were taken during the process of review.</em></p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
<div>
<h2>Review Summary</h2>

<p>
Core Keeper is a solid sandbox game with hours of content and replayability perfect for those looking to deep dive into a new title. (<a href="https://techraptor.net/review-score-policy">Review Policy</a>)
</p>
</div>
<div>
<div>
<h3>Pros</h3>
<div><ul><li>Hours of content</li><li>Replay value</li></ul></div>
</div>
<div>
<h3>Cons</h3>
<div><ul><li>Can become repetitive and grindy</li></ul></div>
</div>
</div>
</div></span></p></div><div><p><span><div>
<div><p> | Staff Writer / Contributor</p></div>
<p>Ashley Erickson is an experienced writer focusing on the video games industry since 2013. Starting off with cosplay features, she moved to game guides and… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/ashley-erikson">More about Ashley</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WOTE Hosts $75k All-Women Fortnite Tournament]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/wote-hosts-75k-all-women-fortnite-tournament/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/wote-hosts-75k-all-women-fortnite-tournament.964035/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/wote-hosts-75k-all-women-fortnite-tournament/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Women of the eRena (WOTE) has wrapped up their latest all-women Fortnite tournament, giving competitors a chance to win from a $75,000 prize pool.</p>



<h2 id="h-all-women-fortnite-tournament-hosted-by-wote">All-Women Fortnite Tournament Hosted By Wote</h2>



<p>WOTE’s most recent all-women tournament began this past weekend on August 24, 2024. The top players were able to qualify for the finals event, which was hosted on August 25. </p>



<p>The event was duos and was played over six games, with three of them being on NA-Central servers and the other three being on EU servers. This was to help equalize the lag that players from different parts of the world had to experience. The tournament was also played in the traditional Battle Royale mode. Not Zero Build.</p>







<h2 id="h-albaxna-and-envy-win-wote-fortnite-tournament">Albaxna and Envy win WOTE Fortnite tournament</h2>



<p>Popular Fortnite competitors, Albaxna and Envy, managed to grab first place in the WOTE Fortnite tournament, winning $20,000 together as a duo. This is a huge feat for the European duo.</p>



<p>Albaxna was also awarded the Tournament MVP by eRena, the company hosting the event. </p>



<figure></figure>



<p>The team ended the tournament with 578 points, almost 175 points more than second place, who ended the event with 405 points. </p>



<p>Women’s representation in esports is important and it is amazing seeing companies put on events as such. Hopefully, we see more opportunities in the future like this one.</p>







<h2 id="h-the-milk-cup-to-host-first-all-women-lan-this-october">The Milk Cup To Host First All-Women LAN This October</h2>



<p>Also hosted by eRena, the first all-women major LAN event will be happening this October at Los Angeles Comic-Con. Titled, The Milk Cup, this tournament will feature a $250,000 prize pool and will take place on October 5, 2024.</p>



<p>The tournament marks a historic time in esports, as it will help further the notion that Women belong in esports. It is incredibly exciting to see eRena work this hard to make an event like this come to life.</p>



<p>Stay tuned to Insider Gaming for more <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/category/esports/">esports news</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>
    
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[In Life Sim InZoi, You Can Crash Cars, Ride Rollercosters, And Commune With Ghosts]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/in-life-sim-inzoi-you-can-crash-cars-ride-rollercosters-and-commune-with-ghosts/1100-6526125/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/in-life-sim-inzoi-you-can-crash-cars-ride-rollercosters-and-commune-with-ghosts.964032/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/in-life-sim-inzoi-you-can-crash-cars-ride-rollercosters-and-commune-with-ghosts/1100-6526125/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-main">

      
                    
  
              <header id="masthead"><nav></nav></header>      
                            <div id="site-wrapper" role="main">
          <div id="default-content">
        
          <p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p>
  
    <article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6526125">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>GameSpot checked out the life simulation title InZoi at Gamescom, getting up to hijinks like burning down an apartment, forgetting to eat, and riding every single ride at a beachside amusement park.</p><p>In InZoi you manage both individual "Zois" (think Sims) and the world itself. Each Zoi has personality traits which shape their life goals. You can also customize a daily schedule, letting you manage multiple Zois at once more easily. In contrast to The Sims, you can swap between Zois at any time.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="425478040" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6464969,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;InZOI%20Blew%20Us%20Away%20With%20Just%20HOW%20MUCH%20STUFF%20YOU%20CAN%20DO%20%7C%20gamescom%202024&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:593,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/inzoi-blew-us-away-with-just-how-much-stuff-you-can-do-gamescom-2024\/2300-6464969\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464969\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464969\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464969\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6464969&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6464969,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6526125&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;inzoi&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;simulation&quot;,&quot;collection&quot;:&quot;gamescom&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;pc&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;krafton-inc&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6464969},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6464969\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;GameSpot&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1823\/18237460\/4356476-inzio_site.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/hisP48yF.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1724448600,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="hisP48yF" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> InZOI Blew Us Away With Just HOW MUCH STUFF YOU CAN DO | gamescom 2024</p>
      </div>
<p>As for broader management of the in-game world, you can customize the world's appearance down to furniture and decoration choices. You can also tinker with broad aesthetic sliders, which can make the world more apocalyptic or switch it between biomes. You can even change the general "personalities" of AI-controlled Zois to generally make them amorous, argumentative, inconsiderate, and more.</p><p>The game has a free-roaming structure a la The Sims 3, compared to the lot-based structure of other Sims games. You can leave your apartment or home to explore the rest of the city in a car or on foot. While you can do whatever you want, there is an overarching goal to help the Zois live moral and fulfilling lives. If you succeed, your Zoi will ascend to heaven. If you fail, your Zoi will haunt the city as a ghost. However, you can help ghosts move on by doing more good deeds.</p><p>Take a look at the embedded video for more details. InZoi will launch in early access on PC at a to-be-announced date.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                        
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/103097971921006863809?rel=author">Grace Benfell</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article>

    
  

</div>
                      <meta itemprop="seamless-content-list-items" data-list-items="[{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525913&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/inzoi-gamescom-trailer-shows-the-joy-and-pain-of-everyday-life\/1100-6525913\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525997&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/animal-crossing-fans-will-want-to-keep-an-eye-on-this-adorable-life-sim-set-in-the-clouds\/1100-6525997\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526093&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/switch-might-finally-get-a-sims-game-but-maybe-not-the-one-you-expect\/1100-6526093\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526054&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/borderlands-4-has-someone-far-more-dangerous-than-handsome-jack-waiting-to-be-revealed\/1100-6526054\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526067&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/indiana-jones-continues-machinegames-proud-tradition-of-pummeling-nazis\/1100-6526067\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526085&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/black-ops-6-liberty-falls-zombies-mode-gets-impressive-and-dramatic-cinematic-trailer\/1100-6526085\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525977&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/borderlands-4-announced-during-opening-night-live-coming-2025\/1100-6525977\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526124&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/towerborne-uses-deep-combat-to-modernize-the-side-scrolling-brawler\/1100-6526124\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525992&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/monument-valley-3-announced-exclusively-for-netflix-games-at-gamescom-with-prequel-ports\/1100-6525992\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525921&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/gamescom-onl-mecha-break-gets-action-packed-new-trailer-closed-beta-on-xbox-coming-soon\/1100-6525921\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526039&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/crimson-desert-shows-off-giant-enemy-crab-boss-and-more-in-new-gameplay-videos\/1100-6526039\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526021&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/starfield-adds-60fps-on-xbox-series-s-along-with-other-performance-updates\/1100-6526021\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526118&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/ps5-pro-coming-this-year-could-be-600-playstation-showcase-in-september-report\/1100-6526118\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525996&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/mafia-prequel-announced-more-info-coming-in-december\/1100-6525996\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525985&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/persona-5s-joker-is-coming-to-persona-3-reload-as-an-enemy\/1100-6525985\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525986&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/the-next-dark-pictures-horror-game-directive-8020-will-change-how-the-series-plays\/1100-6525986\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525929&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/dark-and-darker-mobile-opens-up-pre-registration\/1100-6525929\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525933&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-release-date-set-ps5-version-confirmed\/1100-6525933\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525973&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/little-nightmares-studio-reveals-a-new-co-op-horror-game-with-nightmarish-animals\/1100-6525973\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525922&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/dying-light-the-beast-announced-with-a-trailer-teasing-the-return-of-the-first-games-protagonist\/1100-6525922\/&quot;}]">
            </div>
              
    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Magic: The Gathering Ban List Update Bans Nadu From Modern]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/magic-gathering-ban-list-update-bans-nadu-from-modern</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/magic-the-gathering-ban-list-update-bans-nadu-from-modern.964008/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/magic-gathering-ban-list-update-bans-nadu-from-modern<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Wizards of the Coast has updated their <a href="https://techraptor.net/games/magic-the-gathering" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><em>Magic: The Gathering</em></a> ban list. This is a notable update since the ubiquitous card game's banned and restricted list was updated back in June, which was in the middle of its major competitive scene. This new update is part of a new schedule that coincides with major tournaments, and it contains some notable bans.</p>

<p>In an official blog post, Wizards of the Coast explained the update to their <em>Magic: The Gathering</em> ban list schedule. The post begins with updates to the game's different formats, showing cards that have been added or removed from the banned and restricted list.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/magic-the-gathering-ban-list-update-grief-card-artwork.jpg?itok=I9125zqZ 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/magic-the-gathering-ban-list-update-grief-card-artwork.jpg?itok=m8n6qRYB 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>Standard, Alchemy, Historic, Timeless, and Brawl formats are unchanged. In Pioneer and Explorer, <em>Amalia, Benavides Aguirre</em> and <em>Sorin, Imperious Bloodlord</em> are banned. <em>Grief</em> has been banned from Legacy. Vintage format has added <em>Urza's Saga</em> and <em>Vexing Bauble</em> to the ban list. Lastly, <em>Grief</em> and <em>Nadu, Winged Wisdom</em> are banned from Modern.</p>
<p>In the rest of the post, WOTC explains changes to when they will be announcing <em>Magic: The Gathering</em> ban list updates. It acknowledges and apologizes for the issues that come with announcing a ban list during the week of Pro Tour, leading to a breakdown of logistics and player comfort during that time.</p>
<p>Going forward, ban list updates will be aligning with the Regional Championship and Regional Championship Qualifier seasons. This will allow for better adjustments to the competitive play environment and more time to collect and analyze play data. It also means there will be fewer update lists&nbsp; The next one is scheduled for December 2024.</p>
<p>As for the bans themselves, the most notable one is <em>Nadu, Winged Wisdom</em> from Modern format. In a <a href="https://magic.wizards.com/en/news/feature/on-banning-nadu-winged-wisdom-in-modern">separate post</a> dedicated to discussing the ban, Michael Majors stated the card was "a logistical nightmare" and "a design mistake."</p>
<p>A mistake that was demonstrated during the <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/features/are-modern-horizons-3-collector-boosters-worth-it" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><em>Modern Horizons 3</em></a> Pro Tour where decks built around <em>Nadu</em> had a 59% win rate thanks to several dangerous combos. Infinite mana, shutting down and sweeping opposition. Furthermore, these combos would slow games to a crawl since implementation required a high number of permanents changing zones.</p>
<p>The updated <em>Magic: The Gathering</em> ban list goes into effect today.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Ever since he was small, Tyler Chancey has had a deep, abiding love for video games and a tendency to think and overanalyze everything he enjoyed. This… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/tyler-chancey">More about Tyler</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hollow Knight Fans Are Ready to Have Their Hearts Broken Again by Tuesday's Nintendo Direct]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/hollow-knight-fans-are-ready-to-have-their-hearts-broken-again-by-tuesdays-nintendo-direct</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hollow-knight-fans-are-ready-to-have-their-hearts-broken-again-by-tuesdays-nintendo-direct.964002/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/hollow-knight-fans-are-ready-to-have-their-hearts-broken-again-by-tuesdays-nintendo-direct<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">"46th time's the charm."</h2></div><section><p>A pair of <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-direct-partner-showcase-and-indie-world-showcase-announced-for-tomorrow-august-27">back-to-back Nintendo Directs</a> have been announced for tomorrow, one focused on indie games and another focused on larger, third-party partners.</p><p>Which means that Hollow Knight fans are once again preparing for inevitable heartbreak if Hollow Knight: Silksong doesn't appear.</p><p>If you've somehow missed this entire saga, Hollow Knight: Silksong is the eagerly-awaited sequel to  2017 Metroidvania Hollow Knight. Hollow Knight was adored by critics and fans alike (<a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2018/06/22/hollow-knight-review">we gave it a 9.4/10</a>), so in 2019 when developer Team Cherry <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2019/02/14/hollow-knight-sequel-announced-for-pc-and-nintendo-switch">revealed a sequel</a>, it was met with enthusiasm.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>When Silksong was revealed, it didn't come alongside a release window. But ever since its 2019 unveiling, fans have been foaming at the mouth waiting for it to officially come out. We <a href="https://www.ign.com/videos/hollow-knight-silksong-16-minutes-of-gameplay-midgame-at-e3-2019">actually saw</a> the game in action back in 2021, and it's <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/hollow-knight-silksong-trailer">cropped up</a> with <a href="https://www.ign.com/videos/hollow-knight-silksong-pc-gaming-show-video">new trailers</a> a few times since, but still no word on when it'll actually drop. At one point, Xbox <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/hollow-knight-release-window-next-12-months">appeared to confirm</a> that Silksong would drop before June of 2023, but then that didn't happen. Earlier this year, the game <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/hollow-knight-silksong-got-an-xbox-store-page-on-april-fools-day-and-fans-dont-know-how-to-feel">got an Xbox store page on April Fools Day</a> of all days, and you can imagine how that went over. There was <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/hollow-knight-fans-crushed-as-summer-showcases-pass-with-no-silksong-announcement">nothing at any of the major summer showcases in early June</a>, and then <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/hollow-knight-silksong-will-not-be-at-opening-night-live-geoff-keighley-confirms">Geoff Keighley had to head folks off</a> before gamescom Opening Night Live and tell them Silksong wouldn't be there either.</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Just to get this out of the way, no Silksong on Tuesday at ONL. <a href="https://twitter.com/TeamCherryGames?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@TeamCherryGames</a> is still cooking. <a href="https://t.co/FlQHlc26zo" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/FlQHlc26zo</a></p>— Geoff Keighley (@geoffkeighley) <a href="https://twitter.com/geoffkeighley/status/1824923122929119364?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">August 17, 2024</a></blockquote> <p>The result of this long wait is that every single time there's a games showcase of any kind - a Nintendo Direct, an Xbox or PlayStation showcase, anything Keighley puts on - fans immediately start talking about Silksong. Will it show up? Will they be disappointed again? Almost every time, there's a seeming consensus it won't be there, but that vibe tends to come alongside a kind of desperate longing to be wrong. We're seeing it now, with tomorrow's Nintendo Direct. There's a ResetEra poll where, at the time of this writing, <a href="https://www.resetera.com/threads/poll-will-silksong-make-an-appearance-at-the-indie-direct-nintendo-direct-partner-showcase-on-august-27th.963666/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">86% of voters are saying Silksong won't be present</a>. We've got tweets:</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">If there was ever a time for silksong the combination Pizza Hut and Taco Bell would be it <a href="https://t.co/h7M8pKZnEI" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://t.co/h7M8pKZnEI</a></p>— TAHK0 ☕️ (@TAHK0) <a href="https://twitter.com/TAHK0/status/1828070449571680633?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">August 26, 2024</a></blockquote> <p>There's<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/HollowKnight/comments/1f1qvja/surely_this_time/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"> this increasingly desperate meme</a>:</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/08/26/image-18-1724696567671.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption>Image Source: Reddit <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/HollowKnight/comments/1f1qvja/surely_this_time/">https://www.reddit.com/r/HollowKnight/comments/1f1qvja/surely_this_time/</a></figcaption></figure></output><p>So will Silksong be at either Nintendo Direct even tomorrow? We have no idea. Team Cherry's been coyly quiet, probably because the studio is focused on the game and can't get hung up on giant internet mobs of people begging them for news. Perhaps this will finally be the event that calms the Silksong storm and gives us a firm date to hope for. Or maybe we're due for several more years of Silksong-less winter.</p><p>Good luck tomorrow, everyone.</p><p><em>Rebekah Valentine is a senior reporter for IGN. Got a story tip? Send it to rvalentine@ign.com.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Towerborne Uses Deep Combat To Modernize The Side-Scrolling Brawler]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/towerborne-uses-deep-combat-to-modernize-the-side-scrolling-brawler/1100-6526124/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/towerborne-uses-deep-combat-to-modernize-the-side-scrolling-brawler.963996/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/towerborne-uses-deep-combat-to-modernize-the-side-scrolling-brawler/1100-6526124/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6526124">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/towerborne/" data-ref-id="5000-590951">Towerborne</a> is a pretty drastic departure from the Banner Saga series, developer Stoic Studio's impressive set of story-driven strategy games. But even with just a short look at it, it's easy to see some of the familiar Stoic DNA in Towerborne. It carries a beautiful art style that recalls a hand-drawn aesthetic, similar to Banner Saga, and that gives it a powerful vibrancy.</p><p dir="ltr">I played a short demo of Towerborne at Xbox's recent Gamescom event in Los Angeles, which gave a very quick look at its moment-to-moment combat gameplay. Towerborne is a side-scrolling co-op action-RPG that takes its inspiration from beat-em-ups. There's clearly a lot of inspiration being drawn from old-school arcade entries in the genre, but Towerborne separates itself through a combat system that includes a variety of combos and special moves, offering something a little deeper than just mashing buttons.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="1695979538" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6464974,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;7%20Minutes%20of%20Towerborne%20Co-Op%20gameplay%20%7C%20gamescom%202024&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:430,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/7-minutes-of-towerborne-co-op-gameplay-gamescom-2024\/2300-6464974\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464974\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464974\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464974\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6464974&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6464974,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6526124&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;towerborne&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;2d,action,beat-em-up&quot;,&quot;collection&quot;:&quot;gamescom&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;xbox-series-x,pc&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;xbox-game-studios&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6464974},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6464974\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;GameSpot&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1823\/18237460\/4356512-gameplay_towerborne_v1.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/ekgpKZTy.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1724459400,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="ekgpKZTy" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> 7 Minutes of Towerborne Co-Op gameplay | gamescom 2024</p>
      </div>
<p dir="ltr">First, Towerborne lets you adjust your fighting style based on the weapons your character uses, and from the sound of things, you can change those weapons frequently to give yourself new options. I teamed up with another journalist to run through the demo, starting with a character who dual-wielded daggers. The fighting style for that character was pretty fast and frenetic, slashing away at close range and mixing in kicks for heavy attacks.</p><p dir="ltr">Each character has access to light and heavy standard attacks, which can be linked together to create combos that trigger different attack animations. For instance, I could cut up opponents with my daggers using light attacks, or fire off a heavy combo with a series of kicks, but linking them together triggered a new set of combos in which I could kick some enemies up in the air.</p><p dir="ltr">The combo ability was even more notable for the second character in the build who carried a heavy club with two hands. The blunt end of the club contained something like a furnace that could be used to belch flame and set enemies on fire with certain attacks. Light attacks jabbed with the staff end of the club, while slower heavy attacks swung the club around for big damage. The combination of light and heavy, however, caused the character to take a knee and start using the club like a shotgun, belching flame and setting enemies ablaze. In addition to the damage done by the attack, the flaming enemies also burned for a short period, demonstrating that your weapons and their abilities can have a lot of different uses against enemies.</p><p dir="ltr">In addition to standard attacks, you charge up special abilities that are specific to your weapons, all of which run on cooldown timers. My dagger character had a special ability that allowed her to throw a knife at an enemy and then teleport to its location to start an attack, making it easy to cross the battlefield and kick off a fight. I could also throw a series of daggers ahead of me for big damage against a single target, or leap into the air and throw daggers downward, with the knives lingering in the ground to hurt opponents who walked across them. The strongest attack in my arsenal was a magic area-of-effect attack that would cause a massive explosion after a short period. Leaving the trap behind was great to catch small enemies as they charged toward us.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1581/15811374/4357417-towerborne_gameplay6.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4357417" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1581/15811374/4357417-towerborne_gameplay6.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4357417"></a><figcaption>Weapon choices seem to drastically change how a character fights in Towerborne.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1581/15811374/4357417-towerborne_gameplay6.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">The club character had some similar moves, one which caused him to spin around like a top and slam enemies with the club for extended damage, and another that had him leaping in the air and blasting the ground with flame to create a damaging effect. Instead of a magic explosion, his AOE attack caused the ground ahead of him to erupt in a straight line.</p><p dir="ltr">The demo's level was a short one, with the two of us working our way across grasslands, fighting off enemies like moles and bandits on our way from right to left. Occasionally, we'd fight off multiple waves that would keep coming, requiring us to smash up an enemy spawn point like a tent. It's fairly standard beat-em-up stuff, but with the variety of moves Towerborne offers in combat, alongside a dodge quickstep and a roll, the game takes on more of a feeling of an ARPG played from a side-scrolling viewpoint. And like in an ARPG, the combat loop in Towerborne puts a big focus on finding the right times to maximize the effectiveness of your abilities and managing their cooldowns.</p><p dir="ltr">The final moment of the demo culminated in a big boss fight with Pangojira, a huge pangolin creature flanked by a bunch of smaller burrowing monsters. With the two of us, we naturally gravitated toward dividing the labor of the fight--focusing on the boss when possible, and splitting up to take out the smaller enemies as they appeared. If we were quick, we could stop the smaller enemies from attacking at all by hitting them as they were burrowing out of the ground, knocking them out in one hit. That became an important way to manage their numbers, as the game would throw what felt like 30 pangolins at us at a time. In addition to the boss, it could be tough to manage, especially because each pangolin could weather a pretty significant beating before dying.</p><p dir="ltr">The boss itself rolled out the kinds of attacks you might expect to see in a beat-em-up like this. It would jump around the arena, sending shockwaves across the ground that we needed to jump over, or throw rocks into the air that would fall all around the battlefield and force us to dodge away. It attacked pretty frequently, too, which meant that it was important for us to get our hits in as fast as possible before getting clear of its very long reach. Towerborne punishes you if you're not paying attention--big hits will send you flying, leaving you stunned on the ground for a while.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1581/15811374/4357421-towerborne_pangofight3.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4357421" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1581/15811374/4357421-towerborne_pangofight3.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4357421"></a><figcaption>Pangojira will absolutely clobber you if you're not paying attention.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1581/15811374/4357421-towerborne_pangofight3.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">Movement is a bit clunky and slow, too, which means that you can't rely on just running and dodging to get around enemy attacks; instead, you have to watch your opponents, understand how they move, and anticipate their biggest and fastest blows so that you have enough time to get clear of them.</p><p dir="ltr">If we hit the pangolin boss hard enough, however, we could stun it for a bit, allowing us to deal massive damage with all our abilities. The pyroclast could also use its abilities to set the boss on fire for a little extra chip damage, as well. We tended to divide our labor between me, with my daggers, cleaning up the little guys, while my partner laid into the boss with his harder-hitting moves. There were a few points where the fight got a little hairy--take too much damage and, like in most games, you'll drop to your knees, requiring either a teammate to revive, or burning what seemed to be a spare life to revive yourself. For the most part, though, smart use of our special moves was enough to keep the arena clear of enemies while we whittled down the boss's health to finish it off.</p><p dir="ltr">Our look at Towerborne was pretty brief, focusing only on moment-to-moment combat. We know Towerborne has a lot of live-game systems, is heavily focused on chasing loot, and has a very Destiny-like feel for a lot of its systems--Bungie alumni are among the development team and a few of the choices that evoke the decade-old MMO.</p><p dir="ltr">What we saw, though, has promise. It took a bit to get used to the game, especially in its movement and dodge systems, which are slower than you might expect and thus aren't conducive to twitchy, reactive play, instead requiring you to be more deliberate about how you engage enemies. But that's also in keeping with the arcade beat-em-ups of the '90s that Stoic is riffing on, and the ARPG additions to the gameplay like lots of special moves, alongside deploying interesting combos you can use to exploit enemy weaknesses, feel like smart updates to classic gameplay, at least in our short look at it.</p><p dir="ltr">Towerborne is set to release on PC, Xbox Series X|S, and Xbox Game Pass on September 10.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 Open Beta PC Requirements Revealed]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-open-beta-pc-requirements-revealed/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-open-beta-pc-requirements-revealed.963990/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-open-beta-pc-requirements-revealed/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>It's not long until the <a href="https://wccftech.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-multiplayer-trailer-revealed/">Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 Open Beta</a> is available, with Early Access being available to those who pre-ordered the game and Game Pass subscribers accessing the Early Access period between August 30 and September 4. However, those who don't fit that criteria will be able to access the Open Beta, which is available on September 6 through September 9. If you plan on getting stuck into the Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 open beta, you'll need to know the PC requirements.</p>
<p>Luckily, those on console won't need to worry about requirements. However, if you're a PC user, you must ensure your computer can run it. It's pretty well known that Call of Duty games can be quite a burden on your system, especially with how big the downloads are for Call of Duty games. This is something that they are planning on working on so that download sizes are smaller and more tolerable for players. However, we are still a way off of that.</p>
<p>Below are the minimum and recommended PC requirements to be able to get stuck into the Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 Open Beta.</p>
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>Minimum Requirements</td>
<td>Recommended Requirements</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<ul>
<li>OS: Windows 10 64 Bit (latest update)</li>
</ul>
</td>
<td>
<ul>
<li>OS: Windows 10 64 Bit (latest update) or Windows 11 64 Bit (latest update)</li>
</ul>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<ul>
<li>CPU: AMD Ryzen 5 1400 or Intel Core i5-6600</li>
</ul>
</td>
<td>
<ul>
<li>CPU: AMD Ryzen 5 1600X or Intel Core i7-6700K</li>
</ul>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<ul>
<li>RAM: 12 GB</li>
</ul>
</td>
<td>
<ul>
<li>RAM: 16 GB</li>
</ul>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<ul>
<li>Video Card: AMD Radeon RX 470 or NVIDIA GeForce GTX 1060 or Intel Arc A750</li>
</ul>
</td>
<td>
<ul>
<li>Video Card: AMD Radeon RX 6600XT or NVIDIA GeForce RTX 3060</li>
</ul>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<ul>
<li>Video Memory: 3 GB</li>
</ul>
</td>
<td>
<ul>
<li>Video Memory: 8 GB</li>
</ul>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<ul>
<li>Storage Space: SSD Required</li>
</ul>
</td>
<td>
<ul>
<li>Storage Space: SSD Required</li>
</ul>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<ul>
<li>Network: Broadband Internet connection</li>
</ul>
</td>
<td>
<ul>
<li>Network: Broadband Internet connection</li>
</ul>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<ul>
<li>Sound Card: DirectX Compatible</li>
</ul>
</td>
<td>
<ul>
<li>Sound Card: DirectX Compatible</li>
</ul>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>

<p>The minimum requirements listed for the Black Ops 6 Open Beta will most likely be to run the game at 30 FPS consistently throughout gameplay with settings on low or medium at a push.</p>
<p>The recommended requirements are for those who want to play the game consistently at 60 FPS on high settings. However, they have noted that in some situations, the FPS may drop, so your settings may need to be tweaked to make the Black Ops 6 Open Beta run smoothly.</p>
<p>In addition to these settings, you'll need at least 149 GB to download the Open Beta. Considering it's most likely gated content, that is a hefty download size, and doesn't account for the full download size of the actual game upon release date. Currently, <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2933620/Call_of_Duty_Black_Ops_6/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the Steam page</a> doesn't even have the system requirements available other than players needing to have a phone number linked to their Steam account to play the game.</p>

				

			
	<div>
		<h2>Products mentioned in this post</h2>
		
		<!--<p class="story-notice text-center">The links above are affiliate links. As an Amazon Associate, Wccftech.com may earn from qualifying purchases.</p>-->
	</div>

			
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 Multiplayer Trailer Revealed]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-multiplayer-trailer-revealed/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-multiplayer-trailer-revealed.963987/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-multiplayer-trailer-revealed/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The latest game in the Call of Duty franchise is due to release on 25 October 2024. As the date looms closer, more details about the game are surfacing, including a new trailer showcasing Black Ops 6 multiplayer. So far, there have been mixed responses regarding what players got to see in the two-minute trailer. However, there are plenty of fun ways to kill people in the game, which is garnering a lot of attention from Call of Duty fans.</p>
<p><iframe title="Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 - Multiplayer Reveal Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/GYG_h-L-K2E?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Even those who have sworn off the franchise for years are now considering making a comeback from what was revealed in the trailer. It showed off a lot of intense action, from barging through the doors and sliding across the floor while aiming at your opponent to receiving a hatchet to the chest. There are many different ways to execute your opponents, with Treyarch speaking out about some of the features of Black Ops 6, <a href="https://wccftech.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-direct-omnimovement-campaign-zombies-release-date/">such as omnimovement</a>. For those who prefer a solo experience, there is also the promise of an open-ended campaign or zombies for those who want a more nostalgic experience.</p>
<p>Black Ops 6 now provides the option to use fallen soldiers as a meat shield when on the battlefield, allowing you to rest your gun on their shoulder and take aim at your opponents. As with previous Call of Duty games, there will be helicopters that you can shoot at lower ground targets from, as well as calling in an airstrike to a chosen location.</p>
<p>Those eager to get stuck into the Black Ops 6 multiplayer can expect to see 16 new maps to battle on, as well as the classic prestige system and a Gunsmith for you to customize your weaponry.</p>
<p>If you have pre-ordered Black Ops 6 or have an active Game Pass subscription, you'll be able to get stuck into the Early Access period from August 30 through September 4. Don't panic though, if that group of people doesn't include you. You'll also be able to get a glimpse at what to expect from Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 in the Open Beta which runs from September 6 through September 9.</p>
<p>While Black Ops 6 takes place in the Gulf War, the multiplayer is separate from that setting, with the setting looking significantly more modernized. Instead, the battles take place <a href="https://screenrant.com/black-ops-6-multiplayer-zombies-campaign-details/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">between factions</a> named Rogue Black Ops and Crimson One, respectively. There will be 12 Operators for players to choose from, with six Operators being available per faction.</p>

				

			
	<div>
		<h2>Products mentioned in this post</h2>
		
		<!--<p class="story-notice text-center">The links above are affiliate links. As an Amazon Associate, Wccftech.com may earn from qualifying purchases.</p>-->
	</div>

			
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Where to Get Grumpy’s Key in Escape From Tarkov]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/grumpys-key-escape-from-tarkov/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/where-to-get-grumpy%E2%80%99s-key-in-escape-from-tarkov.963984/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/grumpys-key-escape-from-tarkov/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Any long-time veteran of Escape From Tarkov will tell you that it’s a game less focused on PvP and more on the loot. When you engage in PvP, it’s because you want their loot. When you scour the map for hidden rooms and keys, it’s because you want loot. Well, there’s one loot location throwing people for a loop. Here is where to get Grumpy’s Key in Escape From Tarkov!</p>



<h2 id="h-how-to-get-grumpy-s-hideout-key">How to Get Grumpy’s Hideout Key</h2>



<figure></figure>



<p>To acquire Grumpy’s Hideout Key, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-unlock-ref-in-escape-from-tarkov/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">you must first unlock Ref</a>, raise his trader level to two, and then barter with him. To reach level two, you must raise his level to 0.25 and reach level 15 yourself. </p>



<p>Once you’ve met these requirements, interact with Ref and trade him x1 Lega Medal for Grumpy’s Hideout Key, which has five uses. Use them wisely!</p>



<h2 id="h-where-to-find-grumpy-s-hideout">Where to Find Grumpy’s Hideout</h2>



<p>Once you obtain the key, head to Interchange. Once there, you can find Grumpy’s hideout inside the power station to the northeast of the map, near the Power Plant Extract. </p>



<p>Head inside the Power Plant on the main floor to the back corner of the room. There, you’ll spot a white door leading into a small square shack-like structure against the wall. You may unlock this door using the key.</p>







<h2 id="h-loot-you-ll-find-in-grumpy-s-hideout">Loot You’ll Find in Grumpy’s Hideout</h2>



<p>Inside Grumpy’s Hideout, you’ll find a Green Keycard, odd loose loot, x2 Jackets hanging on the walls, and x1 Sports Bag. Furthermore, there’s a chance for:</p>



<p><strong>Weapons</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>CMMG Mk47 Mutant</li>



<li>Desert Tech MDR</li>



<li>Lone Star TX-15 DML</li>



<li>SIX MCX Spear</li>



<li>AWS VAL</li>



<li>SIG MXC .300</li>



<li>FN SCAR-H</li>



<li>HK416</li>



<li>FN P90</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Armor</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Altyn Bulletproof Helmet</li>



<li>Crye Precision AirFrame Helmet</li>



<li>Ops-Core FAST MT Super High Cut Helmet</li>



<li>Peltor Tactical Sport Headset</li>



<li>Walker’s XCEL 500BT Digital Headset</li>



<li>Peltor ComTac IV Hybrid Headset</li>



<li>LBT-6094A Slick Plate Carrier</li>



<li>HighCom Trooper TFO Body Armor</li>



<li>BNTI Zhuk Body Armor</li>



<li>BNTI Ghzel-K Body Armor</li>



<li>DRD Body Armor</li>
</ul>



<p>While armor will keep you alive, the weapons make this hidden loot room worthwhile. Many come with various modifications, allowing you to strip them for parts to sell or customize your gun. Better yet, add the whole kit to your stash!</p>



<hr>



<p>Now that you’re stockpiling loot for the latest season, let’s ask the tough questions. For instance, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/escape-from-tarkov-ever-coming-to-steam-answered/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">when is Escape From Tarkov coming to Steam</a>?!</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>
    
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>