<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 16:57:02 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[iRacing and IndyCar Team Up for New Series of IndyCar Games]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/iracing-indycar-team-up</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/iracing-and-indycar-team-up-for-new-series-of-indycar-games.1280955/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>iRacing Studios, the developer behind the upcoming&nbsp;<em>NASCAR 25</em>, has announced a multi-year partnership to bring a series of IndyCar games to PC and consoles, starting with an inaugural title next year.</p>

<p>In <a href="https://www.indycar.com/news/2025/08/08-26-iracing-console-game" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">a post</a> on the official IndyCar website, the open-wheel racing brand reveals that the first IndyCar title is due to land on PC and current-gen consoles in "the second half of 2026".</p>

<p>It'll mark the first IndyCar game since 2004's&nbsp;<em>IndyCar Series 2005</em>, which was developed by legendary racing studio Codemasters (which also had the&nbsp;<em>WRC&nbsp;</em>series <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/nacon-wrc-games-2027-2032" rel="nofollow">taken away from it by Nacon</a> recently amid rumors of a shutdown).</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/nascar-25-indycar-iracing.jpg?itok=7snhA2KS 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/nascar-25-indycar-iracing.jpg?itok=dlgcele8 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>NASCAR 25&nbsp;</em>studio iRacing will be working alongside IndyCar on a new licensed game next year.</figcaption></figure><p>Technically speaking, Brain in a Jar and Destineer's 2009 title&nbsp;<em>Indianapolis 500 Evolution&nbsp;</em>is a more recent adaptation of an IndyCar event, but that's based specifically on the Indianapolis 500 and not the series as a whole.</p>

<p>iRacing president Tony Gardner says that IndyCar fans have "long been clamoring for a standalone title for consoles", and that the studio's upcoming game will "offer all the excitement of the NTT IndyCar series and an immersive experience that fans of all ages can enjoy".</p>

<p>As for IndyCar's president J. Douglas Boles, he says that the IndyCar series is "the most competitive and challenging racing on the planet", and that as such, it "deserves a dedicated and widely available gaming experience".</p>

<p>You can expect a "robust, multilevel career mode" in iRacing's IndyCar game, as well as licensed drivers from the IndyCar series and Indy NXT. Naturally, the game will also support online multiplayer to help you prove your racing dominance around the world.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/world-of-outlaws-dirt-racing-indycar-iracing.jpg?itok=K5v35BrD 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/world-of-outlaws-dirt-racing-indycar-iracing.jpg?itok=9GyDNTKq 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>You may also know iRacing's name from&nbsp;<em>World of Outlaws: Dirt Racing</em>.</figcaption></figure><p>This upcoming IndyCar title will be the first in a series of games, with iRacing's parent company iRacing.com Motorsport Simulations and IndyCar signing a partnership "long term" for the flagship <i>iRacing&nbsp;</i>simulation as well.</p>

<p>We'll likely learn more about IndyCar and iRacing's collaboration in the months to come, so stay tuned for more. When it launches, it's due on PC, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series X|S, and it looks like it'll support Steam Deck as well.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/iracing-indycar-team-up]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Skate To Enter Early Access On September 16]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/skate-to-enter-early-access-on-september-16/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/skate-to-enter-early-access-on-september-16.1280946/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Electronic Arts is preparing to welcome gamers to San Vansterdam from September 16 as Skate (I’m not writing skate., I hate that title) enters early access. This news was announced on social media earlier today, and it comes after months of closed testing phases have unravelled much of the game’s content.</p>



<p>The Skate team also released a short trailer to celebrate the announcement. It has been more than 15 years since the last Skate game was released, and fans are <strong>hungry</strong>.</p>



<h2 id="h-skate-will-release-in-early-access-next-month">Skate Will Release in Early Access Next Month</h2>



<p>In little more than two weeks, Skate will be released in early access by Electronic Arts. Earlier today, the team posted a small trailer to announce the release date:</p>



<figure></figure>







<p>For months, fans have been testing Skate (stylized as skate.) and running the game through its paces. This has meant that stacks of content have emerged online, giving us a fair indication of what to expect when San Vansterdam opens up on September 16, 2025.</p>



<p>Yesterday, the team revealed the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/new-skate-game-gets-official-cover-art-and-early-access-release-date-teaser/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">cover art for Skate</a>, promising that the early access release date would drop <strong>today</strong>. Well, as you can see from the above, they’ve delivered on that promise.</p>



<p>In June, the biggest update ever made to the playtest product was unveiled, adding more challenges and upping the server limit to 150 players per map. Even in a testing state, Skate featured <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/biggest-skate-playtest-update-revealed-wishlists/">a whopping 140 challenges</a> and activities.</p>



<p>The full game could end up being something pretty monumental, scale-wise.</p>



<p>Will you be picking up Skate when it enters early access on September 16? Let me know what you’re most excited about with this game on the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-division-2-saved-by-team-five-developers-ubisoft/">The Division 2 was saved</a> by a group of just five developers at Massive</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/skate-to-enter-early-access-on-september-16/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EXCLUSIVE: When Did The IndyCar Deal Come Together With iRacing?]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/exclusive-when-did-the-indycar-deal-come-together-with-iracing/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/exclusive-when-did-the-indycar-deal-come-together-with-iracing.1280943/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>On Tuesday, it was announced that iRacing and IndyCar had <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/indycar-game-coming-in-2026-from-iracing/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">reached an agreement</a> on a new game for the second half of 2026. The first console game in over 20 years for IndyCar, this new title is planned to launch on Xbox Series X|S, PlayStation 5, and PC via Steam. </p>



<p>But when did the deal come together? </p>



<p>Back in early 2024, iRacing president Tony Gardner <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/exclusive-iracing-not-planning-an-indycar-console-game-right-now" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">told Insider Gaming</a> that an IndyCar console game wasn’t in a “short-term plan” for the company, but that the door was open. Later that year, the door blew wide open.</p>



<p>Gardner says that while the long-term plan was <a href="https://iracingstudios.com/iracing-studios-to-produce-standalone-indycar-video-game-in-2026" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">to eventually get here</a>, talks really picked up in late 2024.</p>



<p><strong>“We finalized an agreement with them early this year,”</strong> Gardner told Insider Gaming, <strong>“So, it was six to nine months ago and, and we didn’t want to announce it too soon because we’d rather get some development under our belt and whatnot.”</strong></p>



<p>As far as why announce the game now, Gardner said it made sense to do it ahead of the final race of the 2025 season on August 31. </p>



<p><strong>“We need to to start talking more openly to the teams and getting driver feedback on the physics and things like that,” </strong>he said. <strong>“So it’s a good time for us to let the cat out of the bag.</strong>“</p>



<p>In addition to the console game, iRacing will continue to have a relationship with IndyCar on its main platform. The game is <a href="https://www.iracing.com/iracing-development-update-august-2025" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">set to add</a> the Dallara IL-15 from the INDY NXT series is set to join iRacing in season 4 of 2025.</p>



<p>Are you excited about the IndyCar game from iRacing? Let us know down below, and take the discussion further in the official <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums.</a> </p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, check out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/more-nhl-26-be-a-pro-details-surface" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">more details about NHL 26’s Be A Pro</a> mode. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/exclusive-when-did-the-indycar-deal-come-together-with-iracing/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Play Acclaim showcase set for September 10, featuring “surprises, exclusive content, and announcements”]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/08/play-acclaim-showcase-set-for-september-10-featuring-surprises-exclusive-content-and-announcements</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/play-acclaim-showcase-set-for-september-10-featuring-%E2%80%9Csurprises-exclusive-content-and-announcements%E2%80%9D.1280940/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
        </ul>

    
    <p><span>Teaser video offers a glimpse of Acclaim's upcoming lineup.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Acclaim [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/acclaim">Acclaim</a> will host the “Play Acclaim” showcase on <a href="https://www.timeanddate.com/worldclock/fixedtime.html?iso=20250910T1830" target="_blank">September 10 at 11:30 a.m. PT / 2:30 p.m. ET</a>, which will reveal “new surprises, exclusive content, and announcements you won’t want to miss,” the <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2025/03/game-publisher-acclaim-returns-with-focus-on-indie-studios-and-classics">recently revived</a> publisher announced. You will be able to watch it on <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@PlayAcclaim" target="_blank">YouTube</a>. <span id="more-988087"></span></p><p>“We’re not here to chase ghosts,” said Acclaim CEO Alex Josef in a press release. “We’re here to take the energy and chaos that made Acclaim unforgettable and channel it into something new. The old screens are cracking, and what’s coming through is something exciting and different.”</p><p>A teaser video offers a glimpse of Acclaims upcoming lineup of titles while celebrating the brand’s legacy.</p><p>The announcement reads, “Blink and you might miss it. Hidden in the static, behind the glow of CRT screens, are the titles that will lay the foundation for this exciting new chapter for Acclaim. This isn’t nostalgia for its own sake. It’s something else: a kind of retrofuturenostalgia, paying homage to and embracing the brand’s unmistakable DNA and history while charting a bold new course into the future.”</p><p>Josef added, “You can’t rewrite the past. But you can build upon it. This is about owning our story and moving it into a future that feels bold, energetic, and completely fresh.”</p><p>Watch a teaser trailer for the showcase below.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <h2><span>Play Acclaim – Transmission Received: A New Era is Coming</span></h2><p><iframe title="#PlayAcclaim Transmission Received: A New Era is Coming" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/jYGvAEcV_tY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/08/play-acclaim-showcase-set-for-september-10-featuring-surprises-exclusive-content-and-announcements]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lumines Arise demo available now, full game releases November 11th]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/08/26/lumines-arise-demo-available-now-full-game-releases-november-11th/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/lumines-arise-demo-available-now-full-game-releases-november-11th.1280931/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/06/04/lumines-arise-is-a-brand-new-entry-in-the-series-showcasing-everything-the-team-learned-on-tetris-effect/">Lumines Arise&nbsp;</a>was first announced back in June during Sony’s State of Play, marking a new entry into the Lumines series. Today, Enhance Games has released a new limited time demo for Lumines Arise on PS5 and PC via Steam, allowing players get a first taste of the game. The limited window to experience the Lumines Arise demo lasts from today until September 3rd. After that, players will have to wait for the now confirmed release date of November 11th.</p>
<p><iframe title="Lumines Arise - Demo Explainer | PS5 Games" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/4_s7uLivr58?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>The Lumines Arise demo will feature three stages, with those being Arise, Duo Soul, and Chameleon Grove, along with the multiplayer mode of Burst Battle. The Burst feature is indicated by a percentage score that increases as you play, and when it hits 50% or 100% you can activate it. Activating Burst means a shift in how Lumines plays. Instead of blocks clearing when the line passes through them, you will build up blocks to grow the Burst area. The aim is for you to clear as much of the area as possible when the timer expires. In the multiplayer Burst Battle, garbage builds up making the playing area smaller and smaller, but activating burst stops the garbage falling for a time. You want to be able to build up your score and use the Burst at the opportune moment to beat your opponents. To grab the Lumines Arise demo, head to the following links.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/product/UP0751-PPSA31615_00-LABETA0000000001">Lumines Arise Demo PS5</a></li>
<li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3847360/Lumines_Arise_Demo/">Lumines Arise Demo on Steam</a></li>
</ul>
<p>The last game Enhance released was Tetris Effect, and in our review we gave it a 10/10 saying, “<em>There’s a point when you’re playing Tetris and everything else seems to fade away. Tetris Effect takes that one step further by bringing the game to PSVR alongside its regular 4K HDR presentation, where the closed circuit of headset, player and controller is the only reality. In the main Journey mode – a collection of stages strung together in a series of EP-like sets – you’re still attempting to remove lines from the playing field by fitting shapes together, but when you combine the low latency response of the PSVR’s screens, the ever-changing visuals and wire yourself up to the music, Tetris Effect’s heady melody of the physical and the experiential offers one of the most compelling arguments for virtual reality yet.”</em></p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4_s7uLivr58">YouTube</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/08/26/lumines-arise-demo-available-now-full-game-releases-november-11th/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASCAR 25 Developer iRacing Studios to Create New IndyCar Racing Game Series with Debut Game Due Out in 2026]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/iracing-studios-indycar-racing-game-series-2026/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nascar-25-developer-iracing-studios-to-create-new-indycar-racing-game-series-with-debut-game-due-out-in-2026.1280928/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>iRacing Studios, the developer behind the first major NASCAR game since 2021, <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3873970/NASCAR_25/">NASCAR 25</a>, which is due out in October, will produce and develop a series on IndyCar racing games for PC and consoles, with the first of this new series coming to PC, PS5, and Xbox Series X/S sometime in 2026.</p>



<p>The news was announced with a press release on iRacing Studios' <a href="https://www.iracing.com/iracing-studios-to-produce-standalone-indycar-video-game-in-2026/">official website</a>, as iRacing.com Motorsport Simulations and IndyCar have signed "<em>a long-term licensing agreement for iRacing Studios to produce standalone INDYCAR titles for console and PC.</em>"</p>



<p>We don't yet have an official title for this new series, but its significance for racing fans cannot be overstated, as it's the first major IndyCar racing game "<em>in more than two decades</em>," according to iRacing and INDYCAR.</p>



<p>"<em>INDYCAR fans have long been clamoring for a standalone title for consoles, and we're excited to give them what they're looking for in 2026,</em>" said iRacing.com Motorsport Simulations president, Tony Gardner. "<em>iRacing Studios' standalone INDYCAR title will offer all the excitement of the NTT INDYCAR SERIES and an immersive experience that fans of all ages can enjoy. We are already very excited about how the game is coming together."</em></p>



<p>IndyCar president J. Douglas Boles added, "<em>The most competitive and challenging racing on the planet deserves a dedicated and widely available gaming experience. iRacing Studios is the ideal partner for us, trusted and known to our core fans and ready to share our sport with a wider and highly engaged audience.</em>"</p>



<p>According to the press release, this new game will include licensed vehicles and drivers from the NTT INDYCAR SERIES and INDY NXT, featuring online multiplayer, a career mode for players to progress through, and will be made on iRacing Studios' proprietary Orontes game engine.</p>



<p>"<em>Our company has grown significantly in recent years with the addition of new development teams and studios,</em>" Gardner continued. "<em>Our INDYCAR title will benefit from this growth as it will be the sole focus of one of these teams. However, the game will also incorporate elements like car and track assets, technology and driving characteristics from other iRacing Studios products</em>."</p>



<p>iRacing has always been more simulation than arcade focused, so it's not exactly trying to take away players from games like Forza Horizon, but it'll be interesting to see how this new IndyCar game fares when it arrives, and how its coming NASCAR 25 game does in October. It definitely feels like there's more of an interest in the overall sport of racing with major films recently released on the subject, even if they're not IndyCar or NASCAR-focused. We'll see what October 2025, and then 2026, has in store for racing fans.</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/iracing-studios-indycar-racing-game-series-2026/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Skate Early Access Release Date Revealed for September]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/skate-early-access-release-date-september</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/skate-early-access-release-date-revealed-for-september.1280925/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>EA has announced an Early Access release date for its&nbsp;<em>Skate&nbsp;</em>reboot, and the always-online open-world reimagining of the classic skateboarding franchise is due to arrive in just a couple of weeks.</p>

<p>As revealed in a trailer released earlier today,&nbsp;<em>Skate&nbsp;</em>is set to launch across PC and consoles (including last-gen machines, but not including Nintendo's Switch family) on September 16th.</p>

<p>Just to remind you, rather than the more traditional boxed-game approach of its predecessors, the&nbsp;<em>Skate&nbsp;</em>reboot will be a free-to-play experience; EA describes it as an "ever-evolving online skateboarding sandbox, refreshed with a forever vision in mind".</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/skate-reboot-early-access-release-date-church.jpg?itok=P12TtELF 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/skate-reboot-early-access-release-date-church.jpg?itok=gQn6XRht 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>EA's&nbsp;<em>Skate&nbsp;</em>reboot is set to arrive in September.</figcaption></figure><p>EA first revealed that the&nbsp;<em>Skate&nbsp;</em>franchise would be making a return <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/skate-franchise-willed-into-existence-again" rel="nofollow">back in 2020</a>, at which point it had been ten years since we last heard from the series. Original&nbsp;<em>Skate&nbsp;</em>co-creator Cuz Parry said at the time that the reboot had been "willed into existence" by eager fans.</p>

<p>Subsequently, a new studio, Full Circle, <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/skate-4-is-happening-ea-forms-new-studio" rel="nofollow">was created</a> to work on what was then tentatively known as&nbsp;<em>Skate 4</em>, with the project <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/skate-4-now-titled-skate-will-be-free-to-play" rel="nofollow">officially being renamed</a> to simply "<em>Skate</em>" and gaining free-to-play status in 2022.</p>

<p>Following that, in September last year, EA <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/skate-reboot-early-access-2025" rel="nofollow">revealed</a> that&nbsp;<em>Skate&nbsp;</em>would be making its way to Early Access sometime in 2025, and a financial statement from the publisher <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/split-fiction-sales-4m-battlefield-skate" rel="nofollow">later confirmed</a> it would arrive sometime before March 2026.</p>

<p>If you're wondering exactly what this&nbsp;<em>Skate&nbsp;</em>reboot will offer, you can check out EA's new Early Access release date announcement trailer below. It should give you some idea of what you're in for if you decide to check it out.</p>




<p>According to EA, the new&nbsp;<em>Skate</em>'s setting of San Vansterdam will offer "new spots to discover, hundreds of challenges to conquer, and a constantly dynamic scene driven by community". It'll also feature a new iteration of the&nbsp;<em>Skate&nbsp;</em>series' signature "Flick-It" trick system.</p>

<p>Unfortunately, if you're hoping to play&nbsp;<em>Skate&nbsp;</em>offline, you won't be able to do so; EA confirmed back in April that the game <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/ea-skate-reboot-no-offline-mode" rel="nofollow">won't feature an offline mode</a>, so you'll need an internet connection if you want to check it out.</p>

<p>In any case,&nbsp;<em>Skate&nbsp;</em>launches in Early Access on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3354750/skate/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC</a>, <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/concept/10006353" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PlayStation</a>, and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/skate/9PHF9K5Q6ZLZ" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Xbox</a> on September 16th. Stay tuned for more.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/skate-early-access-release-date-september]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EA’s free-to-play Skate revival hits early access in September]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/761186/ea-skate-free-to-play-early-access-release-date</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ea%E2%80%99s-free-to-play-skate-revival-hits-early-access-in-september.1280922/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span id="follow-author-standard_article_details-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTIz"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span></span><span>Jay Peters</span></span></span></p> <p><span>is a news editor covering technology, gaming, and more. He joined The Verge in 2019 after nearly two years at Techmeme.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>More than three years after revealing “pre-pre-pre-alpha” footage of its new <em>Skate</em> title, EA has finally announced that the free-to-play live service game will be launching for everyone in early access on September 16th.</p><p>The game takes place in the city of “San Vansterdam,” where you can cruise around to find places to pull off tricks, take on challenges, or just hang out with your friends. <em>Skate</em> uses a rebuilt version of the “Flick-It” control system from <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oyUcmzOr_mA">the original <em>Skate</em> games</a>, so if you’re familiar with the older titles, you should be able to jump right into the new version. And EA has built in a lot of social features into the new <em>Skate</em>, including the ability to drop things like ramps and rails right into the world that you and the other skaters nearby can use. Up to 150 skaters can be in a server at a time.</p><p>You’ll be able to buy in-game cosmetics for your custom skater from the in-game shop, though they’re optional and don’t provide any gameplay benefit. Like other free-to-play live service games, <em>Skate</em> will have seasonal content and its version of a battle pass with free and paid rewards.</p><p>The new <em>Skate</em> will be available on PS5, PS4, Xbox Series X / S, Xbox One, and PC, and it will support crossplay and cross-progression. A mobile version for iOS and Android is in development as well.</p><p><span><a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/761186/ea-skate-free-to-play-early-access-release-date#comments">0<!-- --> <!-- -->Comments</a></span></p><div><p><span><strong>Follow topics and authors</strong> from this story to see more like this in your personalized homepage feed and to receive email updates.</span></p><ul><li id="follow-author-article_footer-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTIz"><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span><span>Jay Peters</span></span></span></li><li></li><li></li><li></li></ul></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/news/761186/ea-skate-free-to-play-early-access-release-date]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[skate. launches in Early Access on September 16 for PS5, Xbox Series, PS4, Xbox One, and PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/08/skate-launches-in-early-access-on-september-16-for-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-xbox-one-and-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/skate-launches-in-early-access-on-september-16-for-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-xbox-one-and-pc.1280913/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><a title="Genres > Free-to-Play [432 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/free-to-play">Free-to-play</a> physics-based skateboarding game <em><a title="Games > skate. (2025) [7 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/skate-2025">skate.</a></em> will launch in Early Access for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [10,245 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [7,804 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [28,293 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox One [14,157 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [24,092 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3354750/skate/" target="_blank">Steam</a>, <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/p/skate-2ddbd6" target="_blank">Epic Games Store</a> , and EA App on September 16, publisher <a title="Companies > Electronic Arts [1,781 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/electronic-arts">Electronic Arts</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Full Circle [6 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/electronic-arts/full-circle">Full Circle</a> announced. The studio hopes to move toward a full release approximately one year from the start of Early Access. <span id="more-987962"></span></p><p>“<em>skate.</em> is not just a return, it’s a complete evolution of the franchise that’s built to last,” said <em>skate.</em> executive producer Mike McCartney in a press release. “Our goal with <em>skate.</em> is to capture the freedom, creative expression and community of skateboarding, and share it with as many people as possible. From day one, our priority has been to honor the legacy of the franchise while pushing it into a bold new future—one built in partnership with our players.”</p><p><em>skate.</em> head of creative Jeff Seamster added, “Community is the heart of skateboarding, and it’s the heart of <em>skate.</em> From day one, we’ve aimed to create an open, welcoming space shaped by players. We’ve built this game alongside our community—listening, learning, and evolving together. Whether you’re a seasoned skater or just dropped in, <em>skate.</em> is a place to express yourself, connect and grow. No gatekeepers, no barriers—just a city built for skating and a community that keeps it alive. Early Access is a huge milestone in that journey, and we’re hyped to keep growing San Vansterdam with our crew around the world.”</p><div id="carousel_988096"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Electronic Arts:</p><blockquote><p>Set in the vibrant city of San Vansterdam, <em>skate.</em> is a <a title="Genres > Multiplayer [582 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer">multiplayer</a> skateboarding destination offering a massive open world where players discover unique skate spots, land insane tricks and connect—or compete—with friends online. With four unique neighborhoods—Hedgemont, Gullcrest, Market Mile and Brickswich—each offering its own distinct vibe and challenges, the city is a huge playground for skaters. From parks and plazas to rooftops and massive ramps, every corner is packed with skateable spots, including the House of Rolling Reverence, a former church transformed into a trick haven for skaters.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>At the core of <em>skate.</em> is the restored and improved Flick-It System, brought back to life through the Frostbite Engine to deliver the best skateboarding experience we have ever offered. With unparalleled precision and control, Flick-It brings the magic of the franchise back to life for a new generation of players. <em>skate.</em> also introduces a variety of new tricks—such as wallies, slappies and firecrackers—offering fresh ways to ride. Skatepedia serves as the ultimate resource for mastering tricks and styles, while ensuring accessibility for new players. </p><p>In <em>skate.</em>, players can discover new ways to explore and get vertical with new off-board controls, giving them total freedom to roam, climb and find epic new spots. Additional features like Quick Drop allow players to place ramps, rails, benches and more anywhere in the world to fine-tune their perfect spot. <em>skate.</em> offers players the ability to find their own fun with endless activities, including rotating world map challenges—such as Line Challenges, Own The Spot and <a title="Games > Session: Skate Sim [8 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/session-skate-sim">Session</a>s – as well as high-energy Throwdowns with friends. The new Spectate mode lets players instantly find the <a title="Genres > Action [2,984 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a> and use Spectaport to jump straight into any live session.</p><p>Collaborative development with <em>skate.</em> fans and the community have always been a priority throughout our development process. Player feedback has been welcome all throughout playtesting and something Full Circle will continue to look at during the game’s Early Access period. During Early Access, players can expect to see new content every season, offering fresh challenges, cosmetics, music, world updates, and new events each season.</p></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below. View a new set of screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/skate-2025/august-26-2025/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>Early Access Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="skate. | Early Access Release Date Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/p14MSdRtNIo?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/08/skate-launches-in-early-access-on-september-16-for-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-xbox-one-and-pc]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Skate Early Access Kicks Off On September 16]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/skate-early-access-kicks-off-on-september-16/1100-6534267/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/skate-early-access-kicks-off-on-september-16.1280910/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6534267">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>EA has announced the official date for the early-access release of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/skate-4/">Skate</a>, which will start on September 16 for PC, PlayStation, and Xbox players.</p><p>Fifteen years have passed since the release of the last game in the Skate series, 2010's Skate 3. After a lengthy hiatus, EA originally announced the Skate reboot back in 2021, this time as a free-to-play live-service game designed to attract both series veterans and newcomers.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="959276592" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6466303,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;skate.%20%7C%20Early%20Access%20Release%20Date%20Reveal%20Trailer&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:75,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/skate-early-access-release-date-reveal-trailer\/2300-6466303\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466303\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466303\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466303\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6466303&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6466303,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6534267&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;skate&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;skateboardingskating,sports&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;pc,playstation-5,xbox-series-x,playstation-4,xbox-one&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;electronic-arts&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;franchise&quot;:&quot;skate&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;franchiseRoot&quot;:&quot;skate&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6466303},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6466303\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;Publisher Asset&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4556771-22.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/JYShBJdP.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1756224420,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="JYShBJdP" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> skate. | Early Access Release Date Reveal Trailer</p>
      </div>
<p>While details on Skate remained under wraps during its early development period, the last year has seen a trickle of new information released <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/tim-robinson-basically-did-an-i-think-you-should-leave-sketch-to-reveal-skates-story/1100-6524066/">and at least one memorable promo</a> featuring skateboarder and I Think You Should Leave star Tim Robinson. What we do know is that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/eas-new-skate-game-is-always-online-reconfirmed-for-2025-launch/1100-6531121/">Skate will be an always-online game</a> <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/skate-somehow-has-microtransactions-before-it-even-hits-early-access-report/1100-6530068/">supported by microtransactions</a>, and in terms of gameplay, players can pull off some impressive tricks using the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/skate-dev-explains-new-flick-it-system-and-its-ever-changing-city/1100-6524008/">redesigned Flick-it system</a>. The game will also feature a new approach to soundtracks and lots of customization options.</p><p>Skate is kick-flipping its way back into gaming at a time when skateboarding games have experienced a resurgence. Over the last couple of years, we've seen spiritual successors to Skate like Skater XL and Session: Skate Sim, while the franchise's biggest rival, Tony Hawk's Pro Skater, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/tony-hawks-pro-skater-3-4-review/1900-6418379/" data-ref-id="1900-6418379">returned this year with a remake of the THPS 3 and 4 games</a>.</p><p>Additionally, we've also seen several well-received projects from the indie side of game development--like the OlliOlli series from the now-shuttered Roll7 and The Ramp--help to herald in the current era of skateboarding games.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/skate-early-access-kicks-off-on-september-16/1100-6534267/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[All Items In Peak Explained: Strange Gem, Crystal Skull, And More]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/all-items-in-peak-explained-strange-gem-crystal-skull-and-more/1100-6534216/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/all-items-in-peak-explained-strange-gem-crystal-skull-and-more.1280907/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="default-content">
        
          <p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p>
  
    <article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6534216">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Every item in <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/peak/">Peak</a> serves an important purpose. Some are vital survival tools, aiding your injuries or keeping your tummy full to keep you climbing for longer. Others can jeopardize an entire expedition in an instant. Depending on who you're playing with, the latter can be dangerous--there's always that one player who won't hesitate to create a TikTok-worthy moment.</p><p>Here's the trick with items in Peak: While the game tells you its name, it doesn't actually explain what an item does. Some are easy enough to guess from looks alone, but more often than not, you should be wary of using something to avoid being penalized or affecting the run by accident. Don't fret, though--if you're wondering what things like the <strong>strange gem</strong> or the <strong>crystal skull</strong> do, the list below includes <strong>every item in Peak and what they do</strong>, so you can have a helpful page at hand to dispel doubts in the group chat.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1814/18142392/4554843-20250628031112_1.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4554843" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1814/18142392/4554843-20250628031112_1.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4554843"></a><figcaption>I'm sorry, Bing Bong. I'm just doing research.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1814/18142392/4554843-20250628031112_1.jpg"></figure><h2>Peak Items List and What They Do</h2><p>The list includes every item up to the Mesa update of Peak, which was officially released on August 11. There have been quite a few smaller patches, but by and large, here are all the items available thus far. Note that we're skipping most of the food, as their purpose is largely self-explanatory.</p><table data-max-width="true"><thead><tr><th scope="col">Item</th><th scope="col">What it does</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>Ancient Effigy</td><td>Revives any dead player or players.</td></tr><tr><td>Ancient Idol</td><td>You gain invulnerability to everything... as long as you hold it, that is.</td></tr><tr><td>Antidote</td><td>Cures poison partially</td></tr><tr><td>Anti-rope Cannon</td><td>When shot at a surface, it releases a rope that "falls" upwards instead, starting from the point of impact.</td></tr><tr><td>Anti-rope Spool</td><td>It releases a rope that "falls" upwards instead.</td></tr><tr><td>Backpack</td><td>It can carry up to four items</td></tr><tr><td>Bandages</td><td>Restores health partially.</td></tr><tr><td>Berrynana</td><td>You can throw it on the ground to cause other people to fall.</td></tr><tr><td>Big Lollipop</td><td>Grants infinite stamina for about seven seconds, and inflicts the drowsy status immediately after.</td></tr><tr><td>Bing Bong</td><td>Basically just a cute plushie, and part of a tough achievement that involves finishing a run while carrying it, in a similar fashion to Gnome Chompski in Left 4 Dead 2.</td></tr><tr><td>Binoculars</td><td>No abnormal effect here. They're just binoculars.</td></tr><tr><td>Blowgun</td><td>Shoots a dart that clears negative status except for the curse status. The player who receives the shot will be temporarily drowsy.</td></tr><tr><td>Bounce Fungus</td><td>Creates a mushroom platform when thrown at a surface, making for a good spot to rest while climbing.</td></tr><tr><td>Bugle</td><td>Plays a song, or heinous sounds, depending on your taste. If you use it around the capybaras in Alpine, you'll get an achievement.</td></tr><tr><td>Bugle of Friendship</td><td>Boosts everybody's stamina momentarily.</td></tr><tr><td>Cactus</td><td>It does nothing, but beware of its thorns if you throw it around.</td></tr><tr><td>Chain Launcher</td><td>Shoots a chain to the spot you're aiming at. Be mindful of your current stamina before committing to it.</td></tr><tr><td>Compass</td><td>Points north, which matches the peak of the mountain.</td></tr><tr><td>Conch</td><td>It does nothing. You can throw it at your friends if you want, though.</td></tr><tr><td>Cure-All</td><td>Cures all negative statuses.</td></tr><tr><td>Cursed Skull</td><td>Heals allies at the expense of your own health.</td></tr><tr><td>Dynamite</td><td>Causes an explosion, which can also cook items.</td></tr><tr><td>Energy Drink</td><td>Increases speed momentarily while inflicting the drowsy status afterward.</td></tr><tr><td>Faerie Lantern</td><td>Gets rid of all negative statuses. It doesn't help with hunger.</td></tr><tr><td>First Aid Kit</td><td>If injured, it restores all of your health, while also curing poison.</td></tr><tr><td>Flare</td><td>This emits a big smoke cloud that alerts others of your location. It's also used at the peak to call the helicopter.</td></tr><tr><td>Flying Disk</td><td>You can just have some fun with this.</td></tr><tr><td>Heat Pack</td><td>When used, it gradually removes cold for some time. Useful for blizzards in the Alpine biome.</td></tr><tr><td>Lantern</td><td>Emits light, and its heat also removes cold gradually.</td></tr><tr><td>Magic Bean</td><td>It summons a beanstalk, which is great for climbing.</td></tr><tr><td>Pandora's Lunchbox</td><td>It removes all negative effects upon use, but you also get a random assortment of new effects, which can be either positive or negative. Thanks, Pandora.</td></tr><tr><td>Parasol</td><td>Along with protecting you from the sun, you can use it for gliding.</td></tr><tr><td>Pirate's Compass</td><td>Points toward suitcases nearby.</td></tr><tr><td>Piton</td><td>Adds a piton on any suitable surface that you can grab onto to restore stamina.</td></tr><tr><td>Portable Stove</td><td>Useful for cooking items and reducing cold.</td></tr><tr><td>Remedy Fungus</td><td>It creates a healing mist when thrown against the ground. If you're playing with others, make sure you're all gathered together first.</td></tr><tr><td>Rope Cannon</td><td>Shoots a harpoon to where you're aiming, which releases a rope in the place of impact.</td></tr><tr><td>Rope Spool</td><td>Releases a rope. You can adjust the height and, once ready, press the action button again to anchor it to the surface you're standing on so it stays in place.</td></tr><tr><td>Torch</td><td>A great source of light, albeit limited.</td></tr><tr><td>Scout Cannon</td><td>You can shoot yourself from a long distance with it.</td></tr><tr><td>Scout Efficy</td><td>Revives another player. If more than one player is dead, the item picks one at random.</td></tr><tr><td>Scoutmaster's Bugle</td><td>If you're playing solo, using this rare bugle summons the Scoutmaster. Useful for an achievement.</td></tr><tr><td>Scroll</td><td>There's a chance of seeing them at the summit of biomes. You can use them to create Torn Pages.</td></tr><tr><td>Shelf Fungus</td><td>It creates a mushroom platform when thrown at a surface, great for climbing or to provide an extra platform when attempting long jumps.</td></tr><tr><td>Strange Gem</td><td>It does nothing. At least for now.</td></tr><tr><td>Torn Page</td><td>Mostly for an achievement, which tasks you with collecting eight Torn Pages.</td></tr><tr><td>Weird Shroom</td><td>No weird side effects, it just restores your health partially.</td></tr><tr><td>More to come at some point</td><td>There'll likely be more items added in the future.</td></tr></tbody></table><p>That's all the items available in Peak at the time of writing. Have fun climbing!</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article>

    
  

        
  
</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/all-items-in-peak-explained-strange-gem-crystal-skull-and-more/1100-6534216/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cover Reveal – Ninja Gaiden 4]]></title>
            <link>https://gameinformer.com/cover-reveal/2025/08/26/cover-reveal-ninja-gaiden-4</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cover-reveal-%E2%80%93-ninja-gaiden-4.1280904/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p>Ninja Gaiden 4, the long-awaited fourth mainline entry in the iconic action franchise, graces the next cover of <em>Game Informer</em>, and we could not be more excited to feature both the new protagonist, Yakumo, and his counterpart, the series' longtime hero, Ryu Hayabusa, on the full spread of our cover art. The digital issue goes live today at <a href="https://gameinformer.com/ninjagaiden4">GameInformer.com/NinjaGaiden4</a>, with print subscriptions rolling out in a few weeks. If you haven't subscribed yet, <a href="https://gameinformer.com/subscribe">there's still time to get the Ninja Gaiden 4 issue shipped to your mailbox</a>.&nbsp;</p><p>The Ninja Gaiden franchise has been dormant for more than a decade, but 2025 has been a big comeback year for the series. Koei Tecmo kicked off the year with an Unreal Engine 5 remaster of the beloved Ninja Gaiden 2, followed by Dotemu and The Game Kitchen's incredible retro-facing <a href="https://gameinformer.com/review/ninja-gaiden-ragebound/a-retro-revelation" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="0fc156cb-d76d-423a-8fd8-c650e1b0aef4" data-entity-substitution="canonical">Ninja Gaiden: Ragebound</a>. However, the franchise's 2025 is far from over, as the first mainline entry in more than 13 years is set to hit this October. Just like Ninja Gaiden 4 delivers action starring two ninjas, it also unites two fabled game studios: series developer Team Ninja and the acclaimed action team at PlatinumGames.&nbsp;</p>










<article data-entity-type="file" data-entity-uuid="46fa9c3f-90fa-4c31-b99b-05b84a1d56fe" data-embed-button="image_browser_uploader" data-entity-embed-display="view_mode:file.body_default_rendered" data-entity-embed-display-settings="{&quot;link_url&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;link_target&quot;:0,&quot;link_original&quot;:1,&quot;image_source&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;embed_source&quot;:0,&quot;image_caption&quot;:&quot;Click to view at higher resolution&quot;,&quot;embed_caption&quot;:0,&quot;content_warning&quot;:0}" data-langcode="en">

	

<a data-featherlight="image" href="">
</a>





<p>Click to view at higher resolution</p>

</article>
<p>We flew to Tokyo, Japan, to spend a day in PlatinumGames' headquarters, talking to various members of the team from both studios and playing through the first several chapters of the story. Our cover story explores how Team Ninja united with the studio behind such beloved titles as Nier: Automata, Astral Chain, and the Bayonetta series, plus a deep dive into what to expect when the game launches in October.</p><p>The Ninja Gaiden 4 cover story is the centerpiece, but our next issue is so much more than that article. If you're new to Ninja Gaiden, our editor-in-chief Matt Miller <a href="https://gameinformer.com/feature/2025/08/26/legacy-of-the-ninja">runs down the history and importance of the franchise</a>. Wesley LeBlanc spent a week in Beijing and Shanghai, China, to go in-depth with the promising action title <a href="https://gameinformer.com/feature/2025/08/26/kung-fu-punk">Phantom Blade Zero</a>. Marcus Stewart caught up with the indie masters at Shovel Knight developer Yacht Club Games to dig into what makes <a href="https://gameinformer.com/feature/2025/08/26/digging-for-gems">Mina the Hollower</a> such an exciting prospect. Charles Harte spoke with the team behind <a href="https://gameinformer.com/feature/2025/08/26/suiting-back-up">Dispatch</a> about rising from the ruins of Telltale Games to create a humorous superhero game. We also have a <a href="https://gameinformer.com/feature/2025/08/26/a-conversation-with-matt-mercer">conversation with prolific voice actor and <em>Critical Role</em> dungeon master extraordinaire Matt Mercer</a>, as well as a piece from award-winning comedy writer Mike Drucker about <a href="https://gameinformer.com/feature/2025/08/26/roberta-quest">the legacy of King's Quest and its creator Roberta Williams</a>.&nbsp;</p>










<article data-entity-type="file" data-entity-uuid="2dba0df2-f08d-42d6-8016-81c60e201861" data-embed-button="image_browser_uploader" data-entity-embed-display="view_mode:file.body_default_rendered" data-entity-embed-display-settings="{&quot;link_url&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;link_target&quot;:0,&quot;link_original&quot;:1,&quot;image_source&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;embed_source&quot;:0,&quot;image_caption&quot;:&quot;Click to view at higher resolution&quot;,&quot;embed_caption&quot;:0,&quot;content_warning&quot;:0}" data-langcode="en">

	

<a data-featherlight="image" href="">
</a>





<p>Click to view at higher resolution</p>

</article>
<p>We've rounded out this issue with a diverse selection of previews and reviews. Within the pages of this issue, we have previews for Pokémon Legends: Z-A, Skate, Ghost of Yōtei, Battlefield 6, Call of Duty: Black Ops 7, and more. You'll also find reviews for games like Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater, Ninja Gaiden: Ragebound, Madden NFL 26, Wuchang: Fallen Feathers, Donkey Kong Bananza, and more.&nbsp;</p><p>If you're not subscribed yet, <a href="https://gameinformer.com/subscribe">this is an excellent issue to sign up for</a>, and if you do it today, you'll be just in time to get a physical copy of this issue in your mailbox. Print copies will ship out in the coming weeks, but all subscribers can log in to our website and access the content the same way you're accessing this article starting today.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://gameinformer.com/cover-reveal/2025/08/26/cover-reveal-ninja-gaiden-4]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Random: Zelda: Majora's Mask Short With Ghibli-Inspired Visuals Is Breathtaking]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/random-zelda-majoras-mask-short-with-ghibli-inspired-visuals-is-breathtaking</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/random-zelda-majoras-mask-short-with-ghibli-inspired-visuals-is-breathtaking.1280877/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Includes a look at 'gameplay'</p>
</section></header><div><section>

<p>Following the <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2023/11/random-ghibli-inspired-animation-of-zeldas-castle-town-looks-even-better-in-third-person">exceptional work</a> carried out to reimagine <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/n64/legend_of_zelda_ocarina_of_time">Zelda: Ocarina of Time</a> with Ghibli-inspired visuals, animator <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@RwanLink">RwanLink</a> is back with another stunning short film.</p>
<p>This time, it's focused on <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/n64/legend_of_zelda_majoras_mask">Zelda: Majora's Mask</a> to celebrate the game's 25th anniversary, which commenced back in April to align with the game's release in Japan in 2000. And holy moly, the short film is absolutely stunning! Not only are the visuals alone simply beautiful to look at, but the overall direction is stellar, and the soundtrack from 'Mosik' really adds to the emotion.</p>
<p>The whole thing took around 8 months to complete, with RwanLink pouring around 40 hours a week into the passion project. The result is absolutely astonishing; there are just so many cool little details, including the cheeky inclusion of some <em>actual</em> Ghibli characters in and around Clock Town.</p>
<p>Of course, in addition to the cutscene-style presentation, we also get a glimpse at what gameplay might look like if Zelda: Majora's Mask were built with Ghibli-inspired visuals. It's pretty neat. Finally, in a rather touching conclusion, RwanLink himself removes his own mask to reveal his face, thanking fans and Patreon members for their support over the years.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/zelda/related-articles:157805,186805 @ 1756225806 -->
<p><em>What are your thoughts on this Majora's Mask short film? Leave a comment down below and let us know.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0BjijPlmecM" rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0BjijPlmecM">youtube.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/zelda/related-info/cc809e591594b4a939b6845a8204a4bb @ 1756225277 --></div></article><div><p>Nintendo Life’s resident horror fanatic, when he’s not knee-deep in Resident Evil and Silent Hill lore, Ollie likes to dive into a good horror book while nursing a lovely cup of tea. He also enjoys long walks and listens to everything from TOOL to Chuck Berry.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Olliemar28"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/ollie-nl.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Olliemar28');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/random-zelda-majoras-mask-short-with-ghibli-inspired-visuals-is-breathtaking]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Another NetEase-Backed Studio Has Closed Without Releasing a Game]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/rich-vogel-t-minus-zero-entertainment-netease-shut-down</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/another-netease-backed-studio-has-closed-without-releasing-a-game.1280874/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Another NetEase studio has had its funding pulled without releasing a game, and this time, it's the turn of T-Minus Zero Entertainment and its founder, BioWare and Sony veteran Rich Vogel.</p>

<p>The news was announced by Vogel <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/rich-vogel-093425/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">over on LinkedIn</a>, where he says that T-Minus Zero Entertainment's "journey" with NetEase is "coming to an end". Vogel says that he and his studio have been unable to "secure the funding [it needs] at this time" due to "current market conditions".</p>

<p>Although Vogel doesn't technically say that T-Minus Zero is shutting down, he does say later in the post that the studio's "talented team members will continue to explore new opportunities", so even if the studio is only entering hibernation, it sounds like Vogel doesn't expect a windfall anytime soon.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/star-wars-the-old-republic-rich-vogel-netease.jpg?itok=VIRUv5Ax 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/star-wars-the-old-republic-rich-vogel-netease.jpg?itok=090kj6Rc 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>You might know Rich Vogel's name from games like&nbsp;<em>Star Wars: The Old Republic</em>.</figcaption></figure><p>Vogel founded T-Minus Zero Entertainment <a href="https://ir.netease.com/news-releases/news-release-details/netease-games-introduces-t-minus-zero-entertainment-new-global" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">back in 2023</a>, at which point he also revealed that his studio was working on an "online multiplayer-focused third-person action title set in a sci-fi universe".</p>

<p>In his LinkedIn post, Vogel says that the project (which is presumably the same one that was revealed at the studio's founding) had a "fully playable hands-on demo", but that this demo was unable to attract funding despite garnering "a lot of interest".</p>

<p>Perhaps Vogel can take some solace in the fact that his is far from the only studio to have NetEase pull the plug on it. Back in November last year, Worlds Untold, the studio founded by&nbsp;<em>Mass Effect</em>'s Mac Walters, <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/worlds-untold-netease-pause-shutdown" rel="nofollow">made the decision to "pause operations"</a> amid NetEase pulling its funding.</p>

<p>It's not just studios that didn't manage to release any games, either; the NetEase outfit responsible for&nbsp;<em>Marvel Rivals</em>, which was based largely in Seattle, was <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/marvel-rivals-studio-shockingly-closed-by-netease-laying-off-everyone" rel="nofollow">closed down back in February</a>&nbsp;despite the fact that&nbsp;<em>Marvel Rivals&nbsp;</em>appears to be a resounding success.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/marvel-rivals-netease-rich-vogel.jpg?itok=PYUfhNj9 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/marvel-rivals-netease-rich-vogel.jpg?itok=mtQx0FdZ 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Even&nbsp;<em>Marvel Rivals</em>' success couldn't prevent its development team from being shut down.</figcaption></figure><p>It's not clear what Vogel intends to do next, but it looks pretty certain that we've heard the last of T-Minus Zero Entertainment, unfortunately. Stay tuned for more on this and all other things industry-related.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/rich-vogel-t-minus-zero-entertainment-netease-shut-down]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Here's a Steam demo for Lumines Arise, the latest toe-tapping head exploder from the Tetris Effect devs]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/heres-a-steam-demo-for-lumines-arise-the-latest-toe-tapping-head-exploder-from-the-tetris-effect-devs</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/heres-a-steam-demo-for-lumines-arise-the-latest-toe-tapping-head-exploder-from-the-tetris-effect-devs.1280871/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Time is a line at which we gurn</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Enhance</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/tetris-effect">Tetris Effect</a> developers Enhance have released a new demo for their forthcoming <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/lumines-arise">Lumines Arise</a> on Steam, alongside news that the spacey rhythm attack game will launch on November 11th. If you missed Tetris Effect, it's a game about making deletable lines out of falling blocks while standing in the middle of a very musical supernova.</p>
<p>Lumines Arise, meanwhile, sees you arranging clumps of blocks into 2X2 scoreable combinations, which are removed from the playing field by a horizontally sweeping Time Line. While standing in the middle of a very musical supernova.</p><!--more-->

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Lumines Arise Demo Explainer | PS5, Steam" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/kwFuF8U0zeI?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Lumines Arise Demo Explainer | PS5, Steam</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/kwFuF8U0zeI?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/kwFuF8U0zeI?autoplay=1" title="Lumines Arise Demo Explainer | PS5, Steam">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kwFuF8U0zeI" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>


<p>There have been eight previous Lumines releases, including remasters, on various platforms since the first game's appearance in 2004. This one is a collaboration with Monstars Inc, who also worked on <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/rez-infinite">Rez Infinite</a>. I played a bit of Lumines Arise earlier this year, and spoke to an Enhance developer about its new emphasis on expressing "the human", which is what sets it apart thematically from Tetris Effect. I'll get that write-up turned around before the release date. If I don't, feel free to quote this piece at me aggressively in the comments on any and all subsequent news articles.</p><p>In the short term, I'll say that Arise is yet another pacey and flamboyant puzzler that drizzles your occipital lobe in (for example) footage of frenzied chameleons, while challenging your primary motor cortex to save you from total visual constipation. Yes, it's making bits of your brain fight each other. I like when games do that.</p>
<p>Beyond that, I'm interested to make sense of Arise being a more "human" game than Effect. Much as I enjoyed Tetris Effect, I entertain suspicions that Enhance's framing of Arise might be bullshit artistry. Perhaps "more human" just means there are more human figures in the background art. Come to think of it, I'm not sure the devs mentioned Enhance's most recent game, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/humanity">Humanity</a>, during my hands-on - RPS reviewer Kim Armstrong <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/humanity-review">witheringly summarised</a> that as "perfect puzzles pumped with existential hot air".</p>
<p><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3847360/Lumines_Arise_Demo/">Here's the Steam link for the demo</a>, which will be available from today, August 26th till September 3rd. It includes three stages from the single-player Journey mode and a bit of new multiplayer mode Burst Battle, which can be played online cross-platform. The full game has VR compatibility but there's none of that nonsense in the demo, and they've locked the difficulty to easy. They don't want to scare you away, after all.</p>
<p>Those damn fool editors of RPS gone by never found time to review Tetris Effect, but they did put it on our list of the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-vr-games">best VR games</a>.</p>

        </div>
      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/heres-a-steam-demo-for-lumines-arise-the-latest-toe-tapping-head-exploder-from-the-tetris-effect-devs]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Leak Suggests Deadpool Is Coming To Marvel Rivals]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/marvel-rivals-deadpool-daredevil-leak-audio-voice-lines-overwatch-2-lady-gaga-2000620344</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-leak-suggests-deadpool-is-coming-to-marvel-rivals.1280865/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Good morning and good day. I welcome you all back to Morning Checkpoint. Drink some coffee. Eat a bagel. Go to the bathroom. Now with all that out of the way, let’s get to some news and other stuff. Today, we have a <em>Marvel Rivals</em> leak, a giant <em>Zelda</em> collection, trouble in <em>Roblox</em>, and a new <em>Lumines</em> demo that won’t be around for long. Oh, and some new gameplay of a <em>Fallout/Doom</em> mod that looks sweet.</p> <h2><strong><em>Marvel Rivals</em> leak seemingly reveals Deadpool is coming</strong></h2> <p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-leak-teases-deadpool-daredevil/">As spotted by <em>Insider Gaming</em>,</a> a <em>Marvel Rivals</em> leaker has shared some new voice lines that seemingly reveal Deadpool is coming to the popular online free-to-play hero shooter. In a video posted on Twitter on August 25, leaker XOXLeak shared two alleged Deadpool voice lines as well as a host of replies from other characters in <em>Marvel Rivals</em> referencing the Merc With A Mouth. That same leaker also shared evidence that Daredevil is coming to <em>Rivals</em>, too.</p> <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">Hero voice interactions w/ Deadpool <a href="https://t.co/MSGT2fSTtU">pic.twitter.com/MSGT2fSTtU</a></p> <p>— X0XLEAK (@X0X_LEAK) <a href="https://twitter.com/X0X_LEAK/status/1960089802709356544?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 25, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <p>It’s possible these audio files are fake or were included in the game’s data to throw off dataminers. <a href="https://www.gamesradar.com/games/third-person-shooter/no-marvel-rivals-developer-netease-isnt-intentionally-planting-fake-leaks-to-mess-with-everyone-but-its-datamined-characters-arent-guaranteed-to-appear-in-the-future-either/">The devs behind the game have explained</a> that not <em>every</em> piece of content datamined from the game will end up in <em>Rivals</em>. And AI voice-gen tools are better than ever these days, so these audio lines could all be fake.&nbsp; But Deadpool has been a rumored <em>Rivals</em> character for a bit now, and he’s a very popular Marvel hero, so it seems likely he’ll be added in the future.</p>

 <h2><strong><em>Lumines Arise</em> gets a demo, but just for a week</strong></h2> <p>Rejoice, as we now have a release date for <em>Lumines Arise</em>, the next entry in the wonderful music puzzler series. It’s out in November on PS5 and PC. Nice! <a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/lumines-arise-gets-a-demo-on-ps5-and-steam-to-celebrate-its-release-date-announcement-but-its-for-one-week-only/">And a demo for the game has been shadow-dropped on PS5 and Steam</a>, which is cool. But sadly, this demo will only be around for a week. Bleh. But hey, I can’t complain about getting to play more <em>Lumines</em> for free, even if it’s just for a week. We must all cherish the good news during these dark days.</p> <h2><strong><em>Roblox</em> players were disappointed by Lady Gaga’s <em>Dress To Impress</em> event</strong></h2> <p>Over the weekend, one of <em>Roblox’s</em> biggest games, <em>Dress To Impress</em>, held a large in-game event featuring Lady Gaga. The famous singer and actress was actually playing the game and fans were excited to meet her and hear her speak. However, that didn’t happen. Lady Gaga hung out in a separate server where only a few select players and influencers could interact with her, and she communicated via text chat. When some fans got angry about this, a community manager for the game reportedly said on stream: “None of you are forced to be here. If you’re unhappy, just leave.” Needless to say, it was a mess.</p> <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">Hi everyone. We would like to take the opportunity to apologise to you and take accountability. We took the time to read over messages sent by a lot of you in the chat.</p> <p>I want to begin by apologising for my defensiveness personally. As a community manager, it is not professional…</p> <p>— Dress To Impress (@_Dress2Impress) <a href="https://twitter.com/_Dress2Impress/status/1959707211262734787?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 24, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/dress-to-impress-lady-gaga-meet-and-greet-leaves-fans-disappointed/1100-6534261/">On August 23, as reported by <em>GameSpot</em>,</a> <em>Dress To Impres</em>s posted <a href="https://x.com/_Dress2Impress/status/1959707211262734787">a lengthy apology on Twitter</a>. In the message, the community manager apologized for her behavior, and the devs explained why the event was so limited. They blamed <em>Roblox’s</em> tech limits for the lack of Lady Gaga’s voice being broadcast to players and said limited server space was to blame for the lack of a real meet and greet. The folks behind the online dress-up game are promising to do better in the future.</p>

 <h2><strong>The largest collection of <em>Zelda</em> stuff in the world</strong></h2> <p>Constantine Adams, a software engineer from Fairfax, Virginia, has the largest collection of <em>Legend of Zelda</em> memorabilia in the world, according to The Guinness Book of World Records. <a href="https://patch.com/virginia/fairfaxcity/legend-zelda-collection-fairfax-city-worlds-largest-guinness">As reported by Patch,</a> the collection contains over 4,000 items and is housed in the collector’s large basement. In July, Guinness confirmed it to be the largest in the world.</p> <p>“I’ve been very quiet about my collection for a long time,” Adams told the outlet. “It was just a goal, right? There was something challenging to do, and I enjoyed it. It was hard at times. I’m not jumping up and down because of it. But now’s my time to show it off and say, ‘Here it is.’”</p>

 <h2><strong><em>Overwatch 2</em>‘s director is aware of the game’s horrible Steam rating</strong></h2> <p>Things are looking up for <em>Overwatch 2</em> these days. The game’s Stadium mode has been celebrated by many players, and its new characters have been popular. But over on Steam, <em>Overwatch 2</em>‘s overall rating is still a “mostly negative” 25 percent. <a href="https://www.pcgamesn.com/overwatch-2/gamescom-2025-interview"><em>PCGamesN</em> asked</a> <em>Overwatch 2</em> game director Aaron Keller if he was aware of the low score.</p> <p>“It’s something that I do think about a lot. Our active players are telling us, ‘Hey, the game is in the best state that it’s ever been in, or has been in for a really long time. You have to reconcile that with the reputation from a much broader gaming community,” Keller told the outlet.</p> <p>“[That reputation] is one of the reasons we’re taking bigger swings&nbsp; – we’re trying to break through some of that noise and let players who may have written<em>&nbsp;Overwatch 2</em>&nbsp;off know that there’s still really exciting things happening in this game. I think if the players who stopped playing a year ago or two years ago jumped in right now, they’d recognize that there is something&nbsp;very different&nbsp;about the game, and that it’s come a really long way. I think that it has leveled up as a competitive&nbsp;FPS game. It’s giving players more strategic choice inside of a match, and, if you look at Stadium, there’s more ways to transform the way any hero plays.”</p> <h2><strong>ICYMI:&nbsp;</strong></h2> <ul> <li><a href="https://kotaku.com/replaced-release-date-cyberpunk-pixel-art-batman-arkham-2000620061"><em>Replaced</em>, that cool-looking cybernoir action game, has a new release date</a></li> <li><a href="https://kotaku.com/metal-gear-delta-3-remake-ps5-pro-performance-mode-2000620023">That new <em>Metal Gear Solid</em> remake isn’t running well on consoles</a></li> <li><a href="https://kotaku.com/us-open-tennis-medvedev-bonzi-delay-crowd-yelling-booing-racket-smash-2000620025">The US Open was delayed for a bit because the crowd wouldn’t stop booing</a></li> </ul> <h2>Watch this:</h2> <p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Fallout: Bakersfield Extended Gameplay Footage" width="500" height="281" src="about:blank" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen="" data-rocket-lazyload="fitvidscompatible" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/L0Wv6kkloCU?feature=oembed"></iframe></p> 
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/marvel-rivals-deadpool-daredevil-leak-audio-voice-lines-overwatch-2-lady-gaga-2000620344]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Helldivers 2 Dust Devils Premium Warbond Release Date—Exact Start Times Confirmed]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/helldivers-2-dust-devils-warbond-release-date/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/helldivers-2-dust-devils-premium-warbond-release-date%E2%80%94exact-start-times-confirmed.1280859/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Helldivers 2’s long-awaited Xbox arrival is far from the end of the road, and a new Premium Warbond is right around the corner. Here, we’ve got all the details for the Dust Devils launch.</p>



<p>Though the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/helldivers-2-halo-odst-legendary-warbond-price-rewards/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Halo ODST Legendary Warbond</a> understandably took the headlines following the Xbox launch, new content is coming thick and fast. The Dust Devils Warbond is just a part of this, which comes alongside the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/helldivers-2-into-the-unjust-launches-next-week/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Into the Unjust update</a>.</p>



<p>We’ve got all the details on the Helldivers 2 Dust Devils Warbond here, including the exact start time and what it includes.</p>



<h2 id="h-helldivers-2-dust-devils-warbond-release-date-amp-start-times">Helldivers 2 Dust Devils Warbond Release Date &amp; Start Times</h2>



<figure><figcaption>New gear. Image via Arrowhead</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>The Dust Devils Premium Warbond in Helldivers 2 releases on September 4, with an exact start time of 2am PT.</strong></p>



<p>Helldivers 2’s latest Premium Warbond is added in the days following the Into the Unjust update, with the store rotation on September 4 coming alongside the Dust Devils Warbond.</p>



<p>The release is slightly earlier than the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/helldivers-2-halo-odst-warbond-release-time/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Halo ODST Legendary Warbond</a>, which was pushed back from the usual update time to align with the long-awaited release of Helldivers 2 on Xbox.</p>



<p>We’ve created the table below for easier viewing, showing the exact start times for the Dust Devils Warbond in Helldivers 2.</p>



<figure><table><thead><tr><th data-align="center">Time Zone</th><th data-align="center">Dust Devils Warbond Start Time</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td data-align="center">Pacific Time (PT)</td><td data-align="center">02:00 – Sept. 4</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Central Time (CT)</td><td data-align="center">04:00 – Sept. 4</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Eastern Time (ET)</td><td data-align="center">05:00 – Sept. 4</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">British Summer Time (BST)</td><td data-align="center">10:00 – Sept. 4</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Australian Eastern Standard Time (AEST)</td><td data-align="center">19:00 – Sept. 4</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<h2 id="h-what-to-expect-in-the-helldivers-2-dust-devils-premium-warbond">What to Expect in the Helldivers 2 Dust Devils Premium Warbond</h2>



<p><strong>The Dust Devils Premium Warbond in Helldivers 2 adds a bunch of new cosmetic items, including a new Armor, alongside key additions like new weapons and Stratagems.</strong></p>



<p>In a post on the <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2025/08/26/helldivers-2-into-the-unjust-launches-september-2/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">PlayStation blog</a>, a breakdown stated the Dust Devils Warbond will include one primary weapon, a new throwable, and three unique Stratagems. Also included are Capes, Player Cards, an Emote, a Player title, and a new Pattern for your vehicles and Hellpods.</p>



<p>Here’s everything we know is included in the pass:</p>



<ul>
<li>AR-2 Coyote Assault Rifle</li>



<li>G-7 Pineapple Cluster Frag Grenade</li>



<li>S-11 Speargun</li>



<li>EAT-700 Expendable Napalm</li>



<li>MS-11 Solo Silo</li>



<li>DS-42 Federation’s Blade</li>



<li>DS-191 Scorpion</li>



<li>Burier of Heads Title</li>



<li>Raider’s Cheer Emote</li>



<li>Rattlesnake Pattern</li>
</ul>



<p>Are you planning on picking up the Dust Devils Premium Warbond? Let us know in the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Helldivers 2, check out the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/does-helldivers-2-have-cross-progression/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">crossplay status in the game</a>, and see <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnites-new-season-feels-like-we-have-helldivers-at-home-arrowhead-says/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">what Arrowhead had to say about the ongoing Fortnite season</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/helldivers-2-dust-devils-warbond-release-date/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Reportedly 'Almost Discouraging' Switch 2 Development as Studios Told to Launch Games on Switch 1 and Rely on Backwards Compatibility Instead]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-reportedly-almost-discouraging-switch-2-development-as-studios-told-to-launch-games-on-switch-1-and-rely-on-backwards-compatibility-instead</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-reportedly-almost-discouraging-switch-2-development-as-studios-told-to-launch-games-on-switch-1-and-rely-on-backwards-compatibility-instead.1280856/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">"They can't get the hardware. It's really difficult right now."</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">A fresh report has detailed the difficulties faced by some developers keen to launch games for Switch 2 — but who remain unable to do so due to a lack of Nintendo support.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">According to <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=N0SW7R5H5wY" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Digital Foundry</a>, Nintendo is still restricting its supply of Switch 2 development hardware and instead telling some studios to launch their titles as Switch 1 games that can then be played via backwards compatibility.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">This has sparked frustration among a number of developers, including at least one major AAA studio unable to launch a Switch 2-native version of their game, while hardware is given to some indie creators — including the team behind a campfire simulator.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">"There's been a lot of talk about this lately, that Nintendo seems to be almost discouraging Switch 2 development to some degree," Digital Foundry's John Linneman said during the team's most recent podcast. "I've spoken with plenty of developers where they were told that their game, they should just ship it on Switch 1 and rely on backwards compatibility.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"There's a lot of developers that are unable to get Switch 2 dev kits," Linneman continued. "We talked to a lot of devs at Gamescom this year, and so many of them said the same things. They want to ship on Switch 2. They would love to do Switch 2 versions. They can’t get the hardware. It's really difficult right now."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">One particular frustration has been the lack of transparency from Nintendo on why some studios have been given Switch 2 development kits, while others have not. IGN has contacted Nintendo for comment. </p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Nintendo Switch 2 System and Accessories Gallery</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">"I don't really know what Nintendo’s mindset was with these sets of decisions," Digital Foundry's Oliver Mackenzie said. "I don’t really understand the strategy because, like you said, even now developers are struggling to get systems, and I know that some months ago when we were hearing things through the grapevine and talking to people, there were some weird exclusions with some big developers struggling to get kits for games.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"From what we've heard, there were some weird inclusions as well," he continued. "Some indies were included, which is nice to see. But there’s that campfire game, you know, the camera campfire game, and they’re getting kits. And some big developers, on the other hand, who developed AAA stuff, aren’t necessarily in the pipeline there for kits."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The camera campfire game here in question is <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/chillin-by-the-fire">Chillin' by the Fire</a>, an indie hangout game set around a campfire which makes use of the Switch 2 camera. On the one hand, the simple fact this makes use of GameChat and the Switch 2's camera capabilities makes this impossible to launch on Switch 1, meaning that development hardware for Nintendo's newer console would be required. On the other, it's understandable why some AAA developers might be surprised to see this launch, after being told they wouldn't yet receive a Switch 2 development kit for themselves.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">"There's weird stuff about discouraging Switch 2 development explicitly for some games, a limited subset of games like if you're doing a pixel art game at 240p, you probably don't need a Switch 2 kit," Mackenzie added. "But there are very few games on the Switch 1 that wouldn't benefit from being ported explicitly to Switch 2. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">"The thing that’s really stark to me too is, at this point, we’ve seen very few proper Switch 2 Editions post-launch. I don’t think we’ve seen any, hardly at all really, from third-party developers in particular. Obviously we saw No Man’s Sky, I think one or two other games in the mix there. But really, it’s been a very slow trickle of titles earning that Switch 2 Edition badge. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">"I really want to see more movement on that front. I hope it’s a temporary thing," Mackenzie concluded. "I hope that in a year or two, we’re looking back and we’re like, that was a really weird decision, but it was fixed in time. I hope that’s what we’re looking at."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Earlier today, it was reported that <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-direct-reportedly-set-for-september-as-metroid-prime-4-release-date-and-mario-40th-anniversary-speculation-mounts">Nintendo was planning a fresh Direct due this September</a>, with fan hopes high for word on Metroid Prime 4 and Mario details.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Tom Phillips is IGN's News Editor. You can reach Tom at tom_phillips@ign.com or find him on Bluesky </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/tomphillipseg.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@tomphillipseg.bsky.social</a></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-reportedly-almost-discouraging-switch-2-development-as-studios-told-to-launch-games-on-switch-1-and-rely-on-backwards-compatibility-instead]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Three Years Later, Pokémon Go Is Finally Unlocking Mythical Creature Keldeo for All — but Those Who Previously Paid $8 for One Won't Get Another]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/three-years-later-pokemon-go-is-finally-unlocking-mythical-creature-keldeo-for-all-but-those-who-previously-paid-8-for-one-wont-get-another</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/three-years-later-pok%C3%A9mon-go-is-finally-unlocking-mythical-creature-keldeo-for-all-%E2%80%94-but-those-who-previously-paid-8-for-one-wont-get-another.1280853/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">The next season of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/pokemon-go">Pokémon Go</a> will include the long-awaited return of Mythical unicorn Keldeo — though players who paid $7.99 to own the creature during its original release will not be given a second, IGN has been told.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Pokémon Go's 20th season, Tales of Transformation, will mark the first time Keldeo has been available in the game since December 2022, when a limited-time Special Resarch including the creature was briefly sold. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The lengthy wait for it to become available again has been a growing source of frustration among players over the last few years, especially newer fans who have been waiting to unlock its Pokédex entry.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">All players will be given research centering on Keldeo as part of the season's main storyline — something which will also unlock the beast's previously unobtainable Resolute Form. However, IGN was told in a pre-announcement briefing that existing Keldeo owners will not receive a second Keldeo as part of this research, and will instead simply receive more Keldeo candy.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Today's new season details come amid a flurry of reveals from the Pokémon Go team, including yesterday's <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-go-boosting-level-cap-and-rebalancing-experience-in-first-major-xp-change-for-5-years">major announcement that the game's level cap will be raised from 50 to 80 in October</a>. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">In other (less major but very cute) news, an in-game celebration was announced this morning for the Netflix stop-motion series Pokémon Concierge, including a special Psyduck in a rubber ring costume. Looking ahead, datamining suggests that details of 2025's year-end Pokémon Go Wild Area event are on the horizon, while evidence points to some kind of remote trading option also being worked upon.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Tom Phillips is IGN's News Editor. You can reach Tom at tom_phillips@ign.com or find him on Bluesky </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/tomphillipseg.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@tomphillipseg.bsky.social</a></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/three-years-later-pokemon-go-is-finally-unlocking-mythical-creature-keldeo-for-all-but-those-who-previously-paid-8-for-one-wont-get-another]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Framework Laptop 16 update brings Nvidia GeForce to the modular gaming laptop]]></title>
            <link>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/08/framework-laptop-16-update-brings-nvidia-geforce-to-the-modular-gaming-laptop/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/framework-laptop-16-update-brings-nvidia-geforce-to-the-modular-gaming-laptop.1280850/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
                      
                      
          
<p>It's been a busy year for Framework, the company behind the now well-established series of repairable, upgradeable, modular laptops (and one paradoxically less-upgradeable desktop). The company has launched a version of the Framework Laptop 13 with Ryzen AI processors, the new Framework Laptop 12, and the aforementioned desktop in the last six months, and last week, Framework <a href="https://frame.work/blog/we-have-something-big-coming">teased</a> that it still had "something big coming."</p>
<p>That "something big" turns out to be the first-ever update to the Framework Laptop 16, Framework's more powerful gaming-laptop-slash-mobile-workstation. Framework is updating the laptop with Ryzen AI processors and new integrated Radeon GPUs and is introducing a new graphics module with the mobile version of Nvidia's GeForce RTX 5070—one that's also fully compatible with the original Laptop 16, for upgraders.</p>
<p>Preorders for the new laptop open today, and pricing starts at $1,499 for a DIY Edition without RAM, storage, an OS, or Expansion Cards, a $100 increase from the price of the first Framework Laptop 16. The first units will begin shipping in November.</p>
<p>While Framework has launched multiple updates for its original Laptop 13, this is the first time it has updated the hardware of one of its other computers. We wouldn't expect the just-launched Framework Laptop 12 or Framework Desktop to get an internal overhaul any time soon, but the Laptop 16 will be pushing 2-years-old by the time this upgrade launches.</p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2024/01/review-frameworks-laptop-16-is-unique-laudable-fascinating-and-flawed/">The old Ryzen 7 7840HS CPU version of the Laptop 16</a> will still be available going forward at a slightly reduced starting price of $1,299 (for the DIY edition, before RAM and storage). The Ryzen 9 7940HS model will stick around until it sells out, at which point Framework says it's going away.</p>
<h2>GPU details and G-Sync asterisks</h2>
<figure>
    
          <figcaption>
        <div>
    
    <p>
      The Laptop 16's new graphics module and cooling system, also exploded.

              <span>
          Credit:

          
          Framework

                  </span>
          </p>
  </div>
      </figcaption>
      </figure>

<p>This RTX 5070 graphics module includes a redesigned heatsink and fan system, plus an additional built-in USB-C port that supports both display output and power input (potentially freeing up one of your Expansion Card slots for something else). Because of the additional power draw of the GPU and the other new components, Framework is switching to a 240 W default power supply for the new Framework Laptop 16, up from the previous 180 W power brick.</p>

          
                      
                  </div></div><br/><br/>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/08/framework-laptop-16-update-brings-nvidia-geforce-to-the-modular-gaming-laptop/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Helldivers 2 Is Putting Up Some Huge Numbers Today]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/helldivers-2-is-putting-up-some-huge-numbers-today/1100-6534275/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/helldivers-2-is-putting-up-some-huge-numbers-today.1280844/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6534275">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Helldivers 2 is having a big day. The game <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/playstation-xbox-trade-exclusives-today-with-helldivers-on-xbox-and-gears-on-ps5/1100-6534266/" data-ref-id="1100-6534266">launched today, August 26, on Xbox Series X|S</a>, and it also got a big new update, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/helldivers-2-odst-crossover-will-add-4-iconic-halo-weapons-and-more/2900-6890/" data-ref-id="2900-6890">including a Halo crossover</a>. All of the excitement has led to a surge in players and sales for Helldivers 2--here are some of the key things to know about Helldivers 2's latest success.</p><h2><strong>No. 1 on Steam</strong></h2><p>On Steam, Helldivers 2 is the <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/charts/topselling/US" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">top-selling game overall in the US based on revenue</a>. Helldivers 2 is also No. 2 in the UK. Filtered by global stats, Helldivers 2 is No. 2, only behind Counter-Strike 2.</p><p>In terms of player numbers on Steam, Helldivers 2 reached more than 114,000 peak concurrent players today, August 26, meaning the game is inside <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/charts/mostplayed" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Steam's top 10 overall most-played games.</a> This is the highest figure since June.</p><p>Across all platforms, Helldivers 2 has reached more than 200,000 players today, <a href="https://x.com/TheColeBrewTv/status/1960346775736459287" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">according to the game's own data.</a> Specific player-number data for PS5 and Xbox Series X|S, however, is unknown.</p><h2><strong>Mysterious new patch</strong></h2><p>Helldivers 2 got a new update today, but the patch notes have not been posted. As such, people are theorizing that the update is hiding things that the developer wants players to discover organically. The lack of patch notes has <a href="https://x.com/Helldivers_NOW/status/1960264615679390163" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">inspired some memes.</a> The studio also announced more upcoming Helldivers 2 content, including<a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/helldivers-2-dust-devils-warbond-all-skins-guns-and-rewards/2900-6952/" data-ref-id="2900-6952"> Into the Unjust</a>, which launches on September 2.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qXeRkqH2Gos" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/qXeRkqH2Gos" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><strong>Launch party and an Xbox button</strong></h2><p>Developer Arrowhead Studios held a <a href="https://x.com/Pilestedt/status/1960250153467531332/photo/1" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">launch party for Helldivers 2 on Xbox</a> and the studio also had a dedicated Xbox button that the studio's CCO Johan Pilestedt ceremoniously pressed to launch the game.</p><p>Helldivers 2 is one of PlayStation's first releases on Xbox. The MLB The Show series is now on Xbox, but it's co-published with Major League Baseball. Also released today was Gears of War: Reloaded for PlayStation 5, meaning <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/playstation-xbox-trade-exclusives-today-with-helldivers-on-xbox-and-gears-on-ps5/1100-6534266/" data-ref-id="1100-6534266">PlayStation and Xbox swapped former console exclusives today.</a></p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/helldivers-2-is-putting-up-some-huge-numbers-today/1100-6534275/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Baby Steps And Other Indie Games Are Being Delayed To Avoid Silksong's Launch]]></title>
            <link>https://gameinformer.com/2025/08/26/baby-steps-and-other-indie-games-are-being-delayed-to-avoid-silksongs-launch</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/baby-steps-and-other-indie-games-are-being-delayed-to-avoid-silksongs-launch.1280841/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p>The announcement of <a href="https://gameinformer.com/2025/08/21/hollow-knight-silksong-launches-on-september-4">Hollow Knight: Silksong’s release date</a> has created a ripple effect in the indie game community. With the game launching on such short notice – next week, on September 4 – several indie titles that were slated to release on or near that date are collectively jumping out of its blast radius to avoid being overshadowed. Devolver Digital’s <a href="https://gameinformer.com/state-of-play/2023/09/14/baby-steps-launches-on-ps5-and-pc-next-summer">Baby Steps</a> joins this list.</p><p>The upcoming physics-based walking adventure by the creators of Ape Out and Getting Over It with Bennett Foddy was set to launch on September. 8. Although it wouldn’t have arrived until one week after Silksong, publisher Devolver Digital isn’t taking chances and has delayed Baby Steps to September 23. The game, first announced in 2023, follows an "unemployed loser" named Nate who takes his literal first steps into a fantastical world. Players must master the physics-based walking to awkwardly/humorously traverse environments.</p><p>“Nate, the wary, onesie-donned failson at the heart of the eccentric adventure in literal walking simulator Baby Steps, has stumbled after attempting to ascend his greatest challenge yet: launching the week after Hollow Knight: Silksong's surprise release date,” reads Devolver’s press release.</p><p>A cute trailer announcing the new release date shows Nate awkwardly climbing atop a giant model of Hornet, the protagonist of Silksong. When Baby Steps launches, it will be available on PlayStation 5 and PC.</p><p height="360" width="640" url="https://www.youtube.com/embed/l5apDFK64tI"><iframe width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/l5apDFK64tI" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay" allowfullscreen="true">&nbsp;</iframe></p><p>Baby Steps isn't alone. Yesterday, publisher Ysbryd Games <a href="https://gameinformer.com/2025/08/25/demonschool-delayed-to-avoid-releasing-near-hollow-knight-silksong">delayed its tactical RPG Demonschool</a> from September 3 to November 19. The Early Access cozy sim title <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1594940/Little_Witch_in_the_Woods/">Little Witch in the Woods</a>, which pushed its long-awaited 1.0 launch from September 4 to September 15.</p><p>Indie Metroidvania <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2710920/Aeterna_Lucis/">Aeterna Lucas</a> was also planned to release this month, and is now delayed all the way <a href="https://x.com/aeternathegame/status/1958804217373634579/photo/1">into next year</a>. Retro RPG <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1280080/Faeland/">Faeland</a> was set to launch out of Early Access on September 9, but this has been postponed to a yet-to-be-determined date. <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3314790/CloverPit/">CloverPit</a>, a roguelite slot machine game, had its launch moved to September 26 from its original September 3 date. All of these delay announcements specifically cite Hollow Knight: Silksong as the primary culprit.&nbsp;</p><p>This phenomenon will likely continue, as there are still plenty of smaller titles launching well within Silksong's blast radius. Titles like <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2865670/JETRUNNER/">Jetrunner</a>, Atari's <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1292460/Adventure_of_Samsara/">Adventure of Samsara</a>, Deep Silver's <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/990380/METAL_EDEN/">Metal Eden</a>, and Bandai Namco's <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3135840/Hirogami/">Hirogami</a> are just a few titles arriving right alongside Team Cherry's hotly anticipated sequel. It wouldn't surprise me if these developers are having difficult conversations about whether it's wise, or even financially feasible, to delay their titles or to weather the storm and hope for the best.&nbsp;</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://gameinformer.com/2025/08/26/baby-steps-and-other-indie-games-are-being-delayed-to-avoid-silksongs-launch]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[City The Animation Turns Every Single Episode Into A Visual Flex]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/city-the-animation-review-anime-nichijou-kyoto-animation</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/city-the-animation-turns-every-single-episode-into-a-visual-flex.1280835/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure><figcaption><span><p>Credit: Amazon Prime Video/Kyoto Animation.</p>
</span></figcaption></figure></div><div><p>It’s been a hell of a summer for anime: We have <a href="https://aftermath.site/horror-anime-crunchyroll-netflix-hikaru-takopi" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>The Summer Hikaru Died</em></a>, <em>Dan Da Dan</em>, <a href="https://aftermath.site/panty-stocking-studio-trigger-cat-vibe-amazon-prime" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>New Panty &amp; Stocking with Garterbelt</em></a>,<em> </em><a href="https://aftermath.site/coming-of-age-anime-call-of-the-night-vampires" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Call of the Night</em></a>, and so much more. But both Isaiah and Chris have been floored by one show in particular: <em>City the Animation</em>. We sat down to talk about the ambitious slice of life anime from the Kyoto Animation.</p><p><strong>Isaiah:</strong> Upon your very glittery recommendation, I finally took some time away from watching and writing about shonen anime to check out <em>City the Animation</em> on Prime Video. I'm glad I did, because the show is one of the most ambitious and comfy shows I've seen, well, since <em>Nichijou</em>.</p><p><strong>Chris:</strong> I'm glad! And with good reason!</p><p>If readers have never seen <em>Nichijou</em> I'd highly recommend it. Like <em>City</em>, it was also based on a manga by Keiichi Arawi, and animated by Kyoto Animation.&nbsp;</p><div><figure><p><iframe title="TVアニメ『CITY THE ANIMATION』ノンクレジットオープニング主題歌映像／Furui Riho「Hello」" width="710" height="399" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/10eZAXGuVT4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></figure></div><p><strong>Isaiah:</strong> And for more background, we should probably say what the show is about. So, while <em>Nichijou</em> is basically about the slice of life misadventures of middle school girls and all the kooky folks who make up their small town (including a robot lady), <em>City the Animation</em> is about well...a whole town of people as they go about their lives. Episodically, the show, alongside Trigger's <em>New Panty &amp; Stocking With Garterbelt</em>, does a whole assortment of short stories within its episodes. Only unlike <em>Panty &amp; Stocking</em>, there's a bit more consideration in having its little adventures have a sense of continuity with one another. It shouldn't be remarkable for an old school, cool studio like Kyoto Animation bringing back a throwback to anime conventions like this, but that's what makes the show such a fun watch.</p><div><figure><p><iframe title="Nichijou My Ordinary Life Opening | Hyadain no Kakakata☆Kataomoi - C" width="710" height="399" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/qUk1ZoCGqsA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></figure></div><p><strong>Chris:</strong> Right, a lot of the joy in both <em>City</em> and <em>Nichijou</em> also comes from the contrast of how goofy and lighthearted the topics are coupled with some of the most high effort, impressive sakuga that you have ever seen. Even the tiniest thing is given obscene amounts of love and attention.</p><p><strong>Isaiah:</strong> And its art style is the kind of vibrant bright colors within every frame with the kind of warm, inviting energy of flipping through a Little Golden Books children's story or some of a throwback Disney hand-drawn animated short (which the show plays a nod to with the typography of its logo). I usually perk up whenever the show swings to its resident dad and ramen owner Tsurubishi Makabe trying to become a cool regular at other restaurants to the point he can waltz through the door and say, "I'll have the usual," on some peak old man shit I'm also close to cinching in my own neighborhood. I also adore whenever the show focuses on its middle schooler duo of Eri Amakazari and Matsuri Makabe Rosencrantz and Guildenstern-ing their way through the show as its resident dumbasses with jester's privilege. I'm also partial to the show adapting around the manga's apparent yuri ship of tomboy Midori Nagumo and Niikura as they butt heads throughout the show as its main trio alongside Wako Izumi whose documents their every misadventure with her trusty camera.</p><figure><figcaption>Credit: Amazon Prime Video/Kyoto Animation.</figcaption></figure><p><strong>Chris P:</strong> Midori has such a sick look. I love the hoodie and shorts combo.&nbsp;</p><p>Eri and Matsuri's plotline also gets much more complicated as time goes on, and I got very emotional at the end of the 6th episode. There's also an ongoing arc of the publishing of a 4 panel (four koma) comic called <em>Mr. Bummer</em> about a guy who sucks and is always having horrible stuff happen to him and the drama of the creators having to deal with its continued publication.</p><p>Many of the plotlines in this are fairly lighthearted shaggy dog stories, but Kyoto Animation will wring so much out of them. Like there is a kinda nonsense bit in episode 7 about Tsurubishi trying to make fried rice, and he's on a train ride and they animate the living hell out of the wind catching his mustache. It's this TINY detail that clearly was a huge pain in the ass to get right, but it stuck with me.</p><figure><figcaption>Credit: Amazon Prime Video/Kyoto Animation.</figcaption></figure><p><strong>Isaiah:</strong> I was trying to surmise what makes <em>City</em> such a breath of fresh air to my friend yesterday, and I went on a tangent about how a single episode in an anime winds up being the thing you show off to folks as a display of what the show is cooking. Ironically, in my example being <em>Kill La Kill</em>'s fifth episode where Ryoko and Mako rush to get to school without being tardy, <em>City</em>'s fifth episode is one of the most awe-inspiring things I've seen committed to animation in a long ass time. The best way I can describe it is that the show goes nut nut mode with a live action diorama of a tower it animates its story around that suddenly shows up in the middle of town. Somewhere down the line, Midori and Wako battle their way down the tower in a reverse <em>Game of Death</em> scenario. While all that is a bunch of fun with most of their foes defeating themselves, the show combines the rest of its other characters’ plot threads in one of those picture-in-picture sportscast ads that TV sellers pitch to football dads so they can watch more than one game at a time. But here, the show animates what everyone is doing in upwards of nine tiny squares on your television, swapping out the most essential storyline to take up the biggest square on the screen as everyone wanders through their little misadventure.</p><div><figure><p><iframe title="【わちゃわちゃ】『CITY THE ANIMATION』毎週日曜日 好評放送＆配信中！#アニメCITY" width="710" height="399" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/804JeZgaKnY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></figure></div><p>As if that wasn't impressive enough, the show ends on a little water bubble animation where all of its cast walk to an impromptu city-wide BBQ. But because Kyoto Animation doesn't skimp, they do like a bazillion bubbles outlining every character walking into frame, combining, until they make an entire mural of the town.</p><p><strong>Chris:</strong> It's bar none the most elaborate, high effort piece of animation I've seen all year. It's the kind of thing you end a season on, and it's in episode five. One of the biggest flexes.</p><figure></figure><p><strong>Isaiah:</strong> It was so good, I immediately started rewatching <em>Nichijou</em> episodes to feel something again and to remind myself if they were cooking on this level way back in 2011.&nbsp;</p><p>And what's funny about that is whenever anime fans online talk about older shows, they treat the feat of its animation the same way gamers would a graphical update in a game, as if older shows couldn't possibly have the same quality (if not more so) than modern anime. As if time and resources versus production demand over the years means new shows should look better, when the case tends to skew the reverse with how there's more shows being made now than there were back in the day. Needless to say, me nearly doubling over laughing at a gag about Yuuko trying to eat her little bento box hotdog octopus only to drop it in a cacophony of hijinks, <em>Nichijou</em> still holds up.</p><p><strong>Chris: </strong>That conversation always annoys me because it always sidesteps an analysis of material conditions in anime production and what underpinned a lot of these production budgets. Like, anime has its good and bad eras (a lot of early mixed CGI and the transition to digital was a little rough, for example), but there's almost always someone willing to put the extra effort into it. That's why <em>Nichijou</em> holds up so well.</p><p>And both <em>City</em> and <em>Nichijou</em> as anime owe so much to Keiichi Arawi art, because he also puts so much work into it and to do either manga a disservice would be mortifying.&nbsp;</p><p>Also the manga are both very good!</p><figure><figcaption>Credit: Amazon Prime Video/Kyoto Animation.</figcaption></figure><p><strong>Isaiah:</strong> It's also a testament to how much of an industry darling Kyoto Animation is. Coming off the tragic arson fire, which <em>Chainsaw Man</em> creator Tatsuki Fujimoto referenced in <em>Look Back</em>, it's been gratifying to see the studio remain a tour de force in the industry. Be it with sprawling steampunk period pieces like <em>Violet Evergarden</em>, gripping dramas like <em>A Silent Voice</em>, sci-fi epics like <em>Beyond the Boundary</em>, or slice of life gag manga like it's made a career of with shows like <em>Miss Kobayashi's Dragon Maid</em>. With <em>City</em>, I realized I'd been yearning for more shows where characters float toward the smell of delicious bread, sleep with giant snot bubbles, or put more effort than none at all with niche delights like the art of eating ramen raw from the packaging.</p><figure><figcaption>Credit: Amazon Prime Video/Kyoto Animation.</figcaption></figure><p><strong>Chris:</strong> Ghibli Food is an annoying meme but they absolutely sell food so well in this. Like they convey the shame and joy of midnight snacking on a raw block of ramen and sticking your tongue into the soup powder packet as a cycle akin to samsara.</p><figure><figcaption>Credit: Amazon Prime Video/Kyoto Animation.</figcaption></figure><p><strong>Isaiah:</strong> It's a real delight to watch with every episode not just how hard they'll go on its animation to sell a joke or which wrestling move its cast will break out (as they're wont to do) sporadically--it's to see what your friends in <em>City</em> are up to today. Kyoto Animation really nailed the same kind of feeling we're currently celebrating with James Gunn making <em>Superman</em> feel like a buddy you want to hang out with for everyone in their cast. And in a season where its only slice of life competition is <em>King of the Hill</em>, it's not even close with all the good vibes <em>City</em> has. I mean, even its eye catches for commercial breaks in between short stories are a vibe.</p><figure></figure><p><strong>Chris:</strong> It's been an incredible season for anime (including <em>King of the Hill</em>) that just gives you a warm feeling inside.</p></div><div><h2>Stay in touch</h2><p>Sign up for our free newsletter</p></div><div><h2><span>More from Aftermath</span></h2><div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/grimwild-backerkit-ttrpg-rpg-designer-missing"><h3>RPG Designer Goes Missing After Crowdfunding Award-Winning Game</h3></a><p>'Fulfilment of the project appears to be on hold indefinitely until Maxwell can be located'</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/overwatch-2-interview-pvp"><h3>Overwatch 2 Developers Say They’re Leaning Into What Works</h3></a><p>'We are trying to take bigger swings, bigger risks, and bring more change to the game faster than we did in the past.'</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/aftermath-hours-podcast-silksong-gta-vi-elder-scrolls-vi"><h3>What’s Going To Be The Next Silksong?</h3></a><p>"Given that Silksong is real and about to come out, what other super long-awaited games are left?"</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/silksong-indie-delays"><h3>Indie Devs Are Delaying Their Games Because Of Silksong [Updated]</h3></a><p>'I feel like a little krill trying to not get eaten by a blue whale,' wrote one developer</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/video-game-trailer-capture-director-maker"><h3>A ‘Game Capture Director’ Is The Person Who Gets The Gameplay Footage For A Video Game Trailer</h3></a><p>'The coolest thing I’ve ever done is probably put references to both Jaws and Pac-Mac in a single trailer'</p></div></div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/all">See all posts<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="#000" stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round"><path d="M5 12h13m-6-7 7 7-7 7"></path></svg></a></div></div><br/><br/>https://aftermath.site/city-the-animation-review-anime-nichijou-kyoto-animation]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gears of War: Reloaded Review]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/08/26/gears-of-war-reloaded-ps5-review/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gears-of-war-reloaded-review.1280826/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
			
			<p>We’re back. Your loadout is prepared with power armour, Chainguns and Roadie Runs readied, and Sera is under attack again, but where there was once the reassuring feel of an Xbox controller in your hand, you look down to find a PlayStation 5 DualSense instead. Is this some Locust trick? No, this is gaming in 2025, and while it’s likely proof that the console wars are basically over, Marcus Fenix can never rest, with a new battleground to protect.</p>
<p><iframe title="Gears of War: Reloaded | Official Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/VzJDY6V6C4s?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Gears of War: Reloaded is the original Gears game, but tugged, tightened and scrubbed up to fit into a newer, shinier suit of armour, ready for battle on the enemy console. For the veteran, there’s not a whole lot to find, pulling together the additional campaign act from the original PC release and <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2015/08/25/gears-of-war-ultimate-edition-review/">the 2015 Ultimate Edition</a>, alongside all of the previous DLC, and there’s cross-platform play as well as cross-save.</p>


<p>Unfortunately, though, it’s only cross-save across the brand-new Reloaded version of the game, as opposed to any other rendition of this game. It’s the kind of thing Fenix would shrug at, and so should you, but I found it a little odd that the cross-save is a feature limited to this outing, when Xbox gamers will have played it a number of times.</p>


<p>At this point, I could genuinely reload a Lancer in my sleep – assuming you only have to hit a shoulder button at the right time to do so. I’ve played through this campaign more times than I can count, but it still hits the same beats, still ramps up the drama, and is still capable of putting you on the back foot, especially on the higher difficulty settings.</p>
<p>The steady stream of iconic moments, from your first steps through the city, the fight through darkened alleyways filled with avian Kryll, or luring a Berzerker through narrow corridors, are as much of an adrenaline rush as ever. We don’t see many of these types of shooters anymore, and in the absence of modern or even remastered Killzone and Resistance, there’s a welcoming little slot on PlayStation that I think Gears will fit nicely into.</p>
<p>Multiplayer will play a large part in that, and co-op and competitive play is still a massive part of the gung-ho Gears experience. Adding in cross-play to bolster the community should mean that there’s always someone to play with or against, though I have to wonder how newcomers will fare against a legion of players who’ve been honing their reloads and shotgun blasts for the best part of twenty years. If you’ve got the tech, multiplayer is also available in 120fps on consoles and even higher on PC, which is frankly mind-blowing, making the game feel more fluid than it ever has before.</p>
<p>It’s still pretty brown and grey, though. That’s utterly indicative of the time, of course – it wasn’t until Gears 3 that the series really found a new palette – and for all that this looks pretty damn arresting at times, I still wanted some more vibrancy beyond the blood red COG logos and shining blue armour highlights. Reloaded builds on the work done for the Ultimate Edition a decade ago, enhancing it further, most strikingly with the lighting. If you want to be sold on a decaying, dehumanised civilisation, it does a good job of that, and with the campaign running with upscaled 4K at 60fps on PS5 and with HDR, it’s never looked better. PS5 Pro can push a touch further with resolution, shadow quality and PSSR, but it looks great on the base console.</p>

<p>For all that Gears might be the poster boy for the frat-boy, mid-2000s era of gaming, your comrades are even dumber than I remember. While Dom, Baird and Cole will do some work along the way, they’ll also stand in your way, run back and forth under enemy fire, and on occasion be more of a nuisance than you’d want. Sometimes you’ll just hear them thumping around somewhere nearby, and when those thumps are as loud as they are in Gears, it’s an unnecessary distraction.</p>
<p>Tie that up with a few graphical glitches – my favourite saw a painting end up stuck on Dom’s neck for a while, like he’d inadvertently ended up in a comedy skit with some Locust playfully hitting him over the head with it – and you can still see the Xbox 360 origins if you scrape away a few layers of the shiny paint.</p>
<p>There are a few little PlayStation 5 exclusive features here, and one of them is that the speaker in your DualSense delivers all the comm messages from Anya as well as the area-cleared audio notes, which is a nice touch, albeit one that reminds you that your speaker is probably turned up too loud. You can, of course, turn it off if you want to.</p>

<p>I hope that this is the start of Microsoft bringing across the rest of the Gears games, though it does feel like we should be getting something more like the Master Chief Collection at this point, at least for the first three games. There’s still a hell of a lot to like in the first Gears game – it is a classic that launched a thousand over-the-shoulder third-person cover shooters after all – but the series gets better, with 2’s campaign and 3’s multiplayer still holding position as the true highlights. The iconic Horde mode didn’t arrive until Gears 2 as well, and a Gears game without that now feels strangely lopsided.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/08/26/gears-of-war-reloaded-ps5-review/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Feature: Nintendo's New App Reminds Me Of A Universal Truth: It Feels Good To Squash Mario's Face]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/features/nintendos-new-app-reminds-me-of-a-universal-truth-it-feels-good-to-squash-marios-face</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/feature-nintendos-new-app-reminds-me-of-a-universal-truth-it-feels-good-to-squash-marios-face.1280823/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
<figure><a title="Hello, Mario!" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/0dce8bd23c131/hello-mario.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Jim Norman / Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure><p>There are three things that you should know about me before we dive into this feature. 1) I am, to all intents and purposes, a 'grown-up'. 2) I do not have any children, nor any tiny relatives to test this app on. 3) I'm a sucker for a bit of N64 nostalgia.</p>
<p>Keeping these first two points in mind, you might assume that <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/hello_mario">Hello, Mario!</a> — Nintendo's new Japan-only mobile/Switch app, laser-focused on pulling some sensory smiles out of a new generation of Mario fans — was not made for me. You would be right. I've spent 20 minutes with it, seen all that it has to offer, and it's unlikely that I'll ever open it again. But that doesn't mean that there aren't some smiles to be had for the old and wizened like myself, even if I am very much not the target market.</p><div><figure data-videoid="C1rrCdi_XjA" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><iframe title="YouTube Video" src="javascript:''" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" type="text/html" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed3be067urytjw&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><figcaption><p><a title="Watch This Video on YouTube" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=C1rrCdi_XjA" rel="noopener">Watch on <strong><span></span> YouTube</strong> <span></span></a></p>
<p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>832k</span></a></p>
</figcaption></figure></div>
<p>First, some background information. Hello, Mario! marks the beginning of Nintendo's expansion project into the untapped world of toddler fandom. I mean, come on, those babies are just sitting there, without a single piece of Mushroom Kingdom merch on them! <em>The horror!</em></p>
<p>This 'My Mario' line has wormed its way into a bunch of different avenues already, from books and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/gallery-heres-a-closer-look-at-the-super-mario-wood-block-sets-doubling-as-amiibo">wooden blocks</a> (which double as amiibo, because you're never too young for some NFC goodness) to <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/nintendo-releases-its-me-mario-stop-motion-shorts-watch-them-right-here">stop-motion animated shorts</a>, but Hello, Mario! 'gameifies' the whole thing — and I use 'game' very loosely there.</p>

<p>For the most part, this is an interactive soundboard. Mario's ever-grinning face pops up in the middle of the screen, and you're free to squish and squash it in any way you please, all while he utters the general chorus of "<em>Ooh!</em>", "<em>Haa!</em>", and "<em>Wa-Haa!</em>" with every poke.</p>
<p>There's a small menu in the top left where you can choose to put Mario in a handful of different situations --beef him up with a Mushroom, bring on the rainbow with a Star, get inky with a Blooper, or hit the music block to see the prized plumber perform a rendition of an iconic tune while his surrounding shifts to an underwater scene or icon-filled backdrop.</p>
<p>Nintendo couldn't resist adding a <em>little</em> bit of 'game' to the whole affair. Spinning Mario's face in a circle or firing him through a pipe (also accessed from the menu) brings up a little bubble-popping challenge, where you can tap the bubbles or drag Mario's face into them, each pushing a counter up towards 100. Nothing outside of a small confetti burst happens when you reach triple-digits, but it's <em>just</em> enough to hit every beat in that 3-5-year age bracket, I suppose.</p>
<p>It's super simple and rather sweet. As anyone who ever spent an afternoon with the <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/n64/super_mario_64">Super Mario 64</a> start screen will tell you, there's something in the unending positivity of Mario's smile that makes squashing his face feel... good. The app's 2D sprite is a lot cleaner and marginally less disturbing than its polygonal predecessor, but there's something in my human nature that means, given the opportunity, I <em>have</em> to pull his moustache and see his reaction.</p>
<figure><a title="Hello, Mario!" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/d36b36afa7bff/hello-mario.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Jim Norman / Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure>

<p>There are even some surprises that cropped up as I poked and prodded Jumpman to hear his different responses. Repeatedly tapping his eyes makes him don a pair of shades, tickling his nose produces a big sneeze and results in a wacky 'tache, and leave him for long enough and he'll start to play peek-a-boo with you. It's all designed to get a chuckle out of little ones, but it'll get a little grin out of N64 fans, too.</p>
<p>After 10 minutes or so, Mario becomes sleepy, the music fades out, and the background is replaced by the night sky. The dozing face drops from the screen, and a message pops up telling you to close and reopen the app if you'd like to play again. It's a built-in measure for managing your kid's playtime, I'd assume, but it's also a neat way of wrapping things up.</p>
<p>If you can read that final message, then the app's not designed for you and you likely will have seen everything it has to offer by that point; if you <em>can't</em> read it...then what the heck are you doing here at the bottom of the feature?</p>
<hr>
<p><em>Hello, Mario! is available to download now on Switch for anyone who can <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/guides/how-to-change-your-nintendo-account-region-and-play-mother-3-on-switch">access the Japanese eShop</a>, and it's also available on iOS and Android in Japan. There's no word on a wider release just yet, but we imagine it'll be coming soon.</em></p>
<p><em>Have you checked out Hello, Mario! yet? Let us know your thoughts so far in the comments.</em></p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/super-mario/related-articles:187035,186249,186242 @ 1756224077 --></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/features/nintendos-new-app-reminds-me-of-a-universal-truth-it-feels-good-to-squash-marios-face]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Dino Crisis Trademark Has Been Filed In Brazil, Suggesting Series’ Revival May Be in the Cards]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/new-dino-crisis-trademark-revival/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-dino-crisis-trademark-has-been-filed-in-brazil-suggesting-series%E2%80%99-revival-may-be-in-the-cards.1280817/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The Dino Crisis series could be among the next classic CAPCOM series to be revived, judging from some recent findings.</p>



<p>As reported by <a href="https://residentevil.com.br/lab/registros-de-resident-evil-requiem-e-dino-crisis-no-inpi-brasil/">Brazilian publication REVIL</a>, a new Dino Crisis trademark has been recently registered with the National Institute of Industrial Property. The July 3 filing is separate from the 1999 filing for the original and has been submitted around the time the Resident Evil Requiem registration has, suggesting that this new filing isn't meant for the updated PC versions of the first entries in the series released earlier this year, but for something different altogether. Interestingly enough, the trademark's class is the same as that used for the Resident Evil Requiem trademark, entertainment and video games class, so there's definitely the chance something related to the series is in the works, possibly a new entry in the series, a remake or even a remaster in the vein of the <a href="https://wccftech.com/onimusha-2-samurais-destiny-hands-on-preview-aging-like-fine-wine/">Onimusha 2: Samurai's Destiny remaster.</a></p>



<p>The new Dino Crisis series registration with the National Institute of Industrial Property in Brazil isn't the only recent indication that the long-dormant series may be close to a return to the spotlight, following other series' revivals like <a href="https://wccftech.com/onimusha-way-of-the-sword-announced-for-pc-and-consoles-with-a-2026-release-date/">Onimusha</a> and <a href="https://wccftech.com/okami-2-re-engine/">Okami</a>. <a href="https://wccftech.com/dino-crisis-has-been-trademarked-in-japan-by-capcom-reigniting-hopes-for-a-comeback/">Back in March</a>, CAPCOM trademarked Dino Crisis again in Japan, which is usually done in Japan not just to protect rights to a property, but also when there's an intention to use the IP again. As CAPCOM did something similar with Onimusha, it looks increasingly likely that the series will be making some sort of comeback in the future.</p>



<p>As already mentioned, Dino Crisis made a small return <a href="https://wccftech.com/dino-crisis-1-and-2-pc-enhancements/">earlier this year</a> with the GOG release of the first two entries in the series. Both games have been updated with new features, such as improved DirectX game renderer, new rendering options including V-Sync control, gamma correction, integer scaling, anti-aliasing and more, increased rendering resolution to 4K and color depth to 32-bit, improved geometry calculation, smoother animation, video and music playback, cloud saves support, and much more</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/new-dino-crisis-trademark-revival/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Framework is now selling the first gaming laptop that lets you easily upgrade its GPU — with Nvidia’s blessing]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/laptops/765528/framework-is-now-selling-the-first-gaming-laptop-that-lets-you-easily-upgrade-its-gpu-with-nvidias-blessing</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/framework-is-now-selling-the-first-gaming-laptop-that-lets-you-easily-upgrade-its-gpu-%E2%80%94-with-nvidia%E2%80%99s-blessing.1280814/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Framework CEO Nirav Patel said he would deliver “<a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/3/23/23652967/framework-laptop-16-modular-upgradable-graphics">the holy grail for gamers</a>” with the Framework Laptop 16. In 2023, he suggested it’d be the first consumer notebook to fulfil the promise of modular, upgradable graphics cards like a desktop PC. We at <em>The Verge</em> were skeptical, because <a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2020/5/13/21256845/alienware-area-51m-r1-r2-specs-upgradable-parts-gpu-dgff-limited">the last time</a> we heard someone tell that story, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/7/19/22313742/alienware-area-51m-lawsuit-gpu-upgrade-arbitration-settlement">it ended in lawsuits and forced arbitration</a>.</p><p>But today, some eighteen months after shipping the Framework Laptop 16, the company has done what no laptop maker has done <a href="https://hackaday.com/2024/04/18/mxm-powerful-misused-hackable/">in modern memory, if ever</a>: it’s created a newer, faster discrete graphics card you can easily swap into its existing laptop.</p><p>In 2024, that laptop originally shipped with a optional AMD Radeon RX 7700S, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/22665800/framework-laptop-16-hands-on-preview-modular-gaming-laptop#:~:text=Fun%20fact%3A%20both%20the%20supposedly%20upgradable%20Alienware%20Area%2D51m%20and%20the%20Framework%20Laptop%2016%20have%20a%20common%20champion">with AMD’s support</a>, using a clever expansion bay system designed to be futureproof. (<a href="https://www.theverge.com/22665800/framework-laptop-16-hands-on-preview-modular-gaming-laptop#:~:text=isn%E2%80%99t%20the%20only%20important%20thing%20Framework%20has%20done%20to%20evolve%20modular%20GPUs%2C%20though">More details here</a> on how it works.) Now, Nvidia is on board too, letting you purchase a mobile Nvidia GeForce RTX 5070 8GB that you can physically swap in <a rel="sponsored" href="https://tiktok.pxf.io/c/482924/2160485/27618?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.tiktok.com%2F%40verge%2Fvideo%2F7267920268520082731">as little as two minutes</a>.</p><p>That’s right: you can even swap between AMD and Nvidia. Framework says it doesn’t have final benchmarks, but says you’ll see a 30 to 40 percent uplift from AMD’s 7700S to Nvidia’s 5070, and it’ll come with a revised cooling solution that features fans with a new blade design and Honeywell PTM7950 thermal interface material.</p><p>Like the 7700S, the new 5070 will have 100 watts of sustained power and cooling to work with; not as much as beefier gaming laptops, but more than thinner machines typically get.</p><p>In the end, it wasn’t that hard to convince Nvidia to sign on, Framework CEO Nirav Patel tells<em> The Verge</em>. “They saw the success of the company, and it was clear we were an up and coming startup worth working with,” he says. Framework began working with Nvidia in early 2024, he recalls, not long after the Framework 16 began to ship. “We were able to clear that hurdle just through the success of the product,” he says, though he won’t share any sales numbers with me.</p><p>Then why did he <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/619586/framework-laptop-16-update-one-key-but-not-done">dodge my questions for so long</a> about whether there’d truly be GPU upgrades waiting for the first generation of Laptop 16 buyers? “If we find some massive roadblock and just can’t get it to work […] we want to make sure it’s done and it’s working,” he tells me.</p><p>But he says they didn’t actually hit any massive roadblocks — even though the Nvidia RTX 5070 isn’t the only upgrade awaiting buyers today.</p><p>In addition to the new GPU option, the second-generation Framework Laptop 16 will ship with a new mainboard featuring <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/618769/framework-laptop-13-2025-amd-ryzen-ai-300-strix-point">AMD’s AI 300 / Strix Point processors</a>, offering up to a 12-core/24-thread Ryzen HX 370 with Radeon 890M graphics in a chip that can comfortably run at a “sustained” 45W TDP. The new mainboard also now supports display outputs on four of its six expansion card slots, up from three, so you won’t need to think as hard about <a href="https://knowledgebase.frame.work/en_us/expansion-card-slot-functionality-on-framework-laptop-16-amd-ryzen-7040-series-rkUjGm7cn">which ports support which capabilities</a>, and a new mux lets the laptop drive its internal display more directly from the discrete GPU for lower latency.</p><p>It’ll also come with <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/5/29/24167310/framework-laptop-13-screen-webcam-core-ultra-sd-upgrades">the better second-gen webcam</a> that came to the Framework Laptop 13 last year, a more rigid top cover, AMD’s newer RZ717 Wi-Fi 7 module, and Framework may become <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/765542/framework-240w-usb-c-pd-charger-first-framework-16">the very first laptop maker to ship a 240W USB-C PD power adapter</a> so a fully loaded Framework Laptop 16 will no longer slowly drain its battery as you play, something that could occasionally happen with the previous 180W charger.</p><p>Four of the laptop’s USB-C ports support 240W power input, or five if you count the new and improved USB-C port on the back of the RTX 5070 GPU, which not only supports DisplayPort output but also 240W input and USB 2.0 for a mouse or keyboard. Just note the Laptop 16 maxes out at four simultaneous displays, including the internal screen, so you can’t get five or six screens at a time. (Were you truly hoping?)</p><p>And like the Framework Laptop 13, you won’t need to buy these upgrades as a complete package: Framework will sell most if not all of them individually for the existing Framework Laptop 16. For now, Framework is opening preorders for the new laptop starting at $1,499 (memory, storage, and OS cost extra), the 240W power adapter for $109, the new mobile RTX 5070 for a pricey $699, and the new Ryzen AI 300 mainboards starting at $749. A full pre-built laptop with the new GPU, 16GB/512GB and six USB-C ports costs $2,499 and goes up from there.</p><p>Like previous products, Framework will ship them in batches, with the first set arriving in November. <a rel="sponsored" href="https://framework.pxf.io/c/482924/1459308/17284?u=https%3A%2F%2Fframe.work%2Fproducts%2Flaptop16-amd-ai300%2Fconfiguration%2Fnew">It’s taking preorders now. </a></p><p>Framework will also sell also a revamped version of the Radeon RX 7700S graphics module for $449 with the same new fans and Honeywell thermal interface too, and it will reduce the price of the original RX 7700S module to $399, down from $499 originally.</p><p>The new cooling might be the part I’m most interested in, as my <a href="https://www.theverge.com/24185827/framework-laptop-16-six-months-later-review">biggest complaints about the original</a> were heat and noise when using the graphics module (whose fans also cool the laptop’s CPU). Patel won’t promise that my issues have been fixed, only that it’s “something users are going to have go try,” but he says both acoustic performance and thermals should be better than the original for many reasons. It’s not just the graphic module improvements, but also a revised heatspreader and Honeywell thermal interface material on the CPU, which may itself run more efficiently than AMD’s previous generation of parts. I guess I’ll find out!</p><p>Note that Framework <em>isn’t</em> announcing any physical changes to the Framework Laptop 16’s unique “input modules” this year. It will be shipping a firmware update to keep every Laptop 16 from waking up if keys are pressed when the lid is closed, but there are no new modules or colorful spacers being announced today, though the keyboards themselves now offer versions with the Microsoft Copilot logo, or with no Windows logo at all “for all the Linux users out there.” You can also still buy Framework’s clear RGB keyboard, macropad, and LED matrix panels if you want to look flashy.</p><p>Speaking of Linux, Patel tells me his company will officially be supporting Bazzite on the Framework Laptop 16, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/games/761025/framework-desktop-bazzite-linux-steam-machine-pc-game-console-impressions">the SteamOS-like distro that we recently installed on the Framework Desktop</a> to great effect. Framework will publish its own guides, and he says the Nvidia RTX 5070 should work there too. With the latest kernel and drivers, he says Nvidia gamers “should be able to play anything on Steam on Linux and have it work well.”</p><p>There’s no getting around the fact that this is a pricey laptop, with graphics cards that cost more money for less performance than the equivalent desktop parts — even if you opt for the RTX 5070, you’re probably looking at playing the latest games at high settings at the laptop’s native 2560 x 1440p resolution, and lower settings if you opt for 4K, Patel suggests to me.</p><p>But with Framework, you’re paying for the promise of a laptop you can upgrade again and again, year after year, instead of buying a brand-new machine each time. The company did it with its 13-inch laptop, and it seems it might genuinely do it with its 16-inch laptop, too. It’s never been done before.</p><p>Just don’t expect Patel to get any looser-lipped about which future GPU upgrades might be available, or when. “If AMD announces something, obviously we’d want to talk to them,” he says. “We have a good relationship with Nvidia; obviously, when the future comes, we’ll be able to show you what we have.”</p><p><span><a href="https://www.theverge.com/laptops/765528/framework-is-now-selling-the-first-gaming-laptop-that-lets-you-easily-upgrade-its-gpu-with-nvidias-blessing#comments">0<!-- --> <!-- -->Comments</a></span></p><div><p><span><strong>Follow topics and authors</strong> from this story to see more like this in your personalized homepage feed and to receive email updates.</span></p><ul><li id="follow-author-article_footer-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MzQz"><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span><span>Sean Hollister</span></span></span></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li></ul></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/laptops/765528/framework-is-now-selling-the-first-gaming-laptop-that-lets-you-easily-upgrade-its-gpu-with-nvidias-blessing]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Out very soon, Helldivers 2's giant Terminid caving update is a feast of nods to Aliens and Dune, plus dragons]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/out-very-soon-helldivers-2s-giant-terminid-caving-update-is-a-feast-of-nods-to-aliens-and-dune-plus-dragons</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/out-very-soon-helldivers-2s-giant-terminid-caving-update-is-a-feast-of-nods-to-aliens-and-dune-plus-dragons.1280811/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>PlayStation</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/helldivers-2">Helldivers 2</a>'s homaging of Starship Troopers and/or parodying of real-life fascist interventionalism continues with Into the Unjust, a sizeable game update that will take you out to the Terminid Hive Worlds for a spot of cave combat. According to multiple geographers interviewed by RPS, caves are located underground. That's going to cause problems if, for example, your entire military strategy depends on being able to call in air support whenever you choose. The same geographers also allege that caves are dark. That's going to cause problems if you like to see the things you're shooting at.
</p>
<p>Helldivers 2 Into the Unjust launches 2nd September, and why read the rest of this evidently stupid news piece when you can just watch this seven minute "deep dive" (comedy whoopee cushion sound effect)?
</p><!--more-->

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Helldivers 2 - Into the Unjust Deep Dive" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/dJi8VsvnkoE?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Helldivers 2 - Into the Unjust Deep Dive</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/dJi8VsvnkoE?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/dJi8VsvnkoE?autoplay=1" title="Helldivers 2 - Into the Unjust Deep Dive">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dJi8VsvnkoE" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>


<p>Did you skip the video? Bless you for your loyalty to the written word. Your reward is a hasty summary of Into The Unjust from me, plus more bad jokes. Basically, Hive Worlds are big jaggedy deserts made out of congealed snot and custard. The Terminids here appear vastly more annoying than the ones you'll find on, lol, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/helldivers-2s-battle-for-super-earth-makes-chinese-news-following-the-successful-and-slightly-review-bomby-defense-of-equality-on-sea">Super Earth</a>, because they have the ability to burrow. 
</p><p>That extends to the Chargers, who can actually charge while burrowing. I would need to consult with the geographers again, but I'm not sure that should be allowed. At the very least, they should have to use a new word for it. I would recommend "churrowing" but that makes it sound like you're being assaulted by delicious fried dough. "Barging" is already a word, unfortunately, and "burraging" sounds like you tripped and bit your tongue while ordering an artillery strike. Can we please just move onto the next paragraph already.
</p>
<p>There are two new types of mission to undertake on Hive Worlds. Firstly, journeys underground in search of a horrible giant lung that's coughing up a bunch of poison fog. These missions readily evoke Aliens, and naturally put a strong emphasis on teamwork than many surface-level shoot-outs: in darker spots, one player may need to shoulder flashlight duties, sacrificing participation in the carnage for the good of the squad. I'm sure this won't lead to any broken friendships.
</p>
<p>The second type of mission sees you escorting a mobile oil drill with a big cannon on it. It's Dune and also, a pisstake of US oil politics. It seems like the new Dragonroach enemies will be a particular hindrance during these missions: they can fly and have acidic breath. The key to prevailing over Dragonroach appears to be forcing them to land by blasting their wings, and if that isn't grounds for modding Fus Ro Dah functionality into Helldivers 2, my name isn't Hey You, You're Finally Awake.
</p>
<p>The video includes details of some forthcoming Helldivers 2 warbonds, aka DLC packs. There's a crossover with <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/halo-3-odst">Halo 3: ODST</a>, which has been in the wind for a while, and lets you wreak war with such UNSC armaments as the Battle Rifle and Magnum (but will it capture the interplay between the former's shield-stripping and the latter's finishing shots?). There's also a Dust Devil warbond tailored to the new Hive World maps, which includes an assault rifle with incendiary rounds, a new napalm rocket, a gas harpoon, and a missile silo helpfully housed in a hellpod.
</p><p>Some recent Helldiverse happenings: they've <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/helldivers-2-patch-puts-a-stop-to-the-warp-packs-cheekiest-party-trick-because-you-are-done-it-is-time-to-go-home">put a stop to an exploit that let you warp out of the extraction shuttle</a>. They're <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/helldivers-2-wants-you-to-make-sure-virtual-citizens-dont-wet-the-bed-and-also-heres-another-free-cape">handing out free capes like they're going out of style</a> - a foolish observation of mine, for what is style if not cape. They're also <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/helldivers-3-is-hopefully-many-years-away-says-arrowheads-ceo-who-did-not-vote-for-gun">not making Helldivers 3 anytime soon</a>, unless Helldivers 2 updates itself so much that it becomes <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/helldivers">Helldivers</a> 3 by default.</p>
</div>
      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/out-very-soon-helldivers-2s-giant-terminid-caving-update-is-a-feast-of-nods-to-aliens-and-dune-plus-dragons]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>