<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 16:23:20 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Interview – Sohei Niikawa on Etrange Overlord and life after the board room]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/11/20/interview-sohei-niikawa-on-etrange-overlord-and-life-after-the-board-room/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/interview-%E2%80%93-sohei-niikawa-on-etrange-overlord-and-life-after-the-board-room.1359457/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>For many people, the absolute pinnacle of a career is the seat at the top of the table, to be president or CEO of a big international company. What people seldom think of is what happens after you step down. For Sohei Niikawa, who was president of Nippon Ichi Software until three years ago, it’s a chance to start over. This do-over, as he calls it, is one step towards his vision for a happier world.</p>
<p>On a crisp November’s day, Niikawa sat down with me to discuss not only his first game as an indie developer, Etrange Overlord, but how he got here and, most importantly, what comes next.</p>
<p><iframe title="Etrange Overlord - Announcement Trailer (Nintendo Switch, PS4, PS5, and Steam)" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_tbshWzk10c?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>“So in Japan, we’re calling it a ‘Sushi Lane Musical Action Adventure’,” he tells me, after watching the trailer together. “For the West, we’re calling it a ‘Revolving Lane Musical Action RPG’.”</p>
<p>These sushi lanes carry various power-ups and special weapons to our heroine, Étrange von Rosenburg — a duke’s daughter who was wrongfully accused of treason, condemned to hell and sentenced to death. Waking up after her execution, she finds herself beset by demons. Unperturbed, she sets about conquering Hell so that she can live her best afterlife.</p>

<p>It’s a light-hearted dark comedy that fits perfectly with the franchise Niikawa is best known for: Disgaea.</p>
<div id="attachment_135137"><p id="caption-attachment-135137">Sohei Niikawa was producer and writer for most of the Disgaea series to date.</p></div>
<p>The Disgaea series is set across various Netherworlds, and sees antihero demons embark on humorous stories between rounds of tactical RPG action. <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/10/06/disgaea-7-complete-review/">Disgaea 7 Complete</a>, which was released earlier this year, is the latest edition of this, and we gave it a whopping 9/10.</p>
<p>“The thing that I really like about Etrange Overlord,” Niikawa said, “is the main character. She has a very free spirit. There’s a lot of overlap between her and I, with me also having begun my own sort of second life after leaving my previous company.</p>
<p>“I’m working really hard in a lot of ways because I want her to be popular.”</p>
<div id="attachment_466125"><p id="caption-attachment-466125">Étrange von Rosenburg front and centre in Etrange Overlord</p></div>
<p>Niikawa-san continues, “This will be the first title that I’m releasing since I started working independently from NIS.” This do-over, as he calls it, also has him starting from scratch as he claims to be in a relatively weak position within the games industry right now. He is, after all, an indie developer releasing the first game he wrote under his new pen name, Roman Kitayama, and his new company, Super Niche.</p>
<blockquote>
<h4>“I’m working really hard in a lot of ways because I want her to be popular.”</h4>
</blockquote>
<p>Naturally, that hasn’t stopped him from adding an impressive roster of names to Etrange’s credits.</p>
<p>“In Japan there’s a famous developer called Gemdrops, and the president of this company happens to be the same age as me.” This president famously worked on Niikawa’s first game, Rhapsody: a Musical Adventure. “As soon as he knew that I had left the company, he reached out to me saying he would like to make a game, and so that’s how Estrange Overlord came about.</p>
<p>“This will be the first time we’re making games together in about 30 years! Essentially, Etrange Overload is kind of a mix of that Rhapsody title we first worked on together and Disgaea.”</p>
<p>And this isn’t the only pedigree going into Etrange. “The character designer for the game is actually Shinichirou Otsuka, who’s very famous for his work on the RE:Zero series,” Niikawa adds.</p>
<h2>Famous names</h2>
<p>The talk of famous names turned our conversation towards Roman Kitayama, the name Niikawa used to pen Etrange Overlord. I asked what this name meant and why he chose it.</p>
<p>“So of course, in Japanese, ‘Kitayama’ can mean a ‘Northern mountain’. And the first place where I built my home was a northern mountain.”</p>
<p>But these are not the kanji Niikawa picked for himself. And in true Japanese fashion, there’s some wordplay at hand. Instead of the obvious 北山, Niikawa chose 喜多山 for Kitayama.</p>
<blockquote>
<h5>“That’s a really uncool name, dad…”</h5>
</blockquote>
<p>The Yama bit (mountain) is the same, as a nod towards his home. “But for ‘Kita’, I purposefully used the kanji for both ‘to enjoy’ or ‘to be excited about something’ as well as the kanji for ‘a lot’. So, it means ‘to have a lot of enjoyment’.”</p>
<p>The Roman bit is a bit more complicated. “In Japanese, the phrase romantic doesn’t refer to romantic comedies etc, but more of a classical, romanticised idea —&nbsp;that sense of dreams or the kinds of things that that interest us or excite us.</p>

<p>The problem, however, is that as cool as Niikawa thinks his new name is, the younger generation may disagree.</p>
<p>“My daughter tells me that’s a really uncool name, dad…”</p>
<h2>Current games</h2>
<p>In the spirit of our regular What We Played column, and because it’s interesting to know what games fuel game makers, I asked Niikawa to name the last game he played that really stuck with him.</p>
<p>The problem, of course, is that Niikawa is working so hard on writing novels and designing games that he can only play games in short bursts —&nbsp;”I really like games that are very replayable, and I only need to play them for 5–10 minutes, here and there.”</p>
<p>“Solitaire is the game I’m playing most right now! To be honest with you, I never played Solitaire until this year. I’m like ‘Wow, Solitaire is really fun!’ So I’m actually doing a little bit of experimenting on my own right now to see if maybe I can make a game that’s like Solitaire but with a little bit of me in it?”</p>
<h2>Starting over</h2>
<p>Returning to Niikawa’s career arc, the idea of a career do-over by starting his second life at the same time as Etrange is a beautiful way to look at things.</p>
<p>“I want to take both my failures and my successes from my time at NIS into my second life,” he explains. “I’m in a very interesting situation where it’s kind of like I’m playing a roguelite.</p>
<p>“I’ve jumped in, I’ve built up experience and then I got game over. Now I’m starting over from the beginning, but I get to utilise my experience to drive me forward.”</p>
<p>Those experiences are clear, both in terms of game design and running a company.</p>
<blockquote>
<h5>“I’m starting over from the beginning, but I get to utilise my experience to drive me forward.”</h5>
</blockquote>
<p>In terms of game design, the tone is the most obvious thing he is carrying through. The mix of dark underworld vibes with light-hearted tone and at-times slapstick writing is something of a signature for Niikawa.</p>
<p>“There’s a couple of reasons for that,” Niikawa explains, when I asked what draws him to the theme of lighthearted darkness. “One is that there’s not too many other people that tend to do that, but then the other part is just simply because I like it.”</p>

<p>Ultimately, Niikawa says, games are entertainment, and he wants his games to bring people joy. This, he says, drives how he builds his games. They have to be both kind to the user and easy to understand. The problem is that if they’re too difficult to get into, the player won’t get to the bit that makes the game interesting.</p>
<p>“What really gives you a good idea about whether you’re going in the right direction is when somebody sits down to play your game and gets a game over. Do they still want to continue playing despite that?”</p>
<p>“I think what becomes important there is how interesting the story is and how interesting the mechanics are, but also is there a sense of ‘If I just keep going or keep trying a little bit more you know can I get a little bit further?’</p>
<p>“So whenever I’m working on a game I tend to pay close attention to those first two hours of gameplay to see if it meets those requirements: is it kind of the player and is it easy to follow?”</p>
<h2>Legacy</h2>
<p>It’s difficult to look forward all the time, especially with such an impressive past. We are, after all, we’re all human. And as creators, it’s easy to get caught up in past projects. Not so for Niikawa. When asked if there were aspects of past projects he would revisit, his answer was instant.</p>
<p>“I don’t really think about it that much, to be honest! I don’t focus on the past. I just think about what I’ve learned so far and I build on it to keep making things better.”</p>

<p>So, what does Niikawa think about his legacy, if he’s not one to look over his shoulder?</p>
<p>“For NIS, I feel like the company itself is my legacy. I genuinely think that had it not been for Rhapsody and Disgaea, it wouldn’t exist as the company it is now. I take great meaning from having worked at NIS America and helped to build that company.</p>
<p>“But moving forward with Super Niche, I want my legacy to be more focused around not just games necessarily but all kinds of forms of entertainment.</p>
<p>“I’m 52 years old. I don’t know if I’ll live to be 70 or 80, but honestly right up till the end I want to keep making new content.</p>
<p>“And that could be multiple things — not just games but light novels, manga and board games. There’s a lot of different things that I’d like to work on.”</p>
<blockquote>
<h5>“I’m 52 years old. I don’t know if I’ll live to be 70 or 80, but honestly right up till the end I want to keep making new content”</h5>
</blockquote>

<p>Niikawa’s love for entertaining people really shines through as he picked up a Super Famicon cartridge that had been repurposed as a business card holder.</p>
<p>“This is actually an Indie game that’s in development right now,” he tells me. “There’s a man named Yoshitsuna Kobayashi who worked with me on the very first Disgaea, and he’s the person putting this video game together.</p>
<p>“He’s actually already quit the games industry once, but I’ve always thought he is a genius game creator and if he were to disappear from the industry I think it would be a huge blow. So I’ve kind of invited him to sort of come home, as it were, and work with me on making games in the future.</p>
<p>“And I look at that as a very meaningful activity. My greatest desire is actually to fill the world with more and more interesting pieces of media, whether it’s my own works that I’m invested in doing or helping someone else put their work out to the world as a producer.</p>
<p>“Really, behind all of that is just the idea that the more positive things that we can put out into the world for people to enjoy, the better. If people can enjoy them, and if that helps the world become a more peaceful place, nothing could make me happier.”</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/11/20/interview-sohei-niikawa-on-etrange-overlord-and-life-after-the-board-room/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ys X: Proud Nordics Launches on PC, PlayStation 5, Nintendo Switch]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/ys-x-proud-nordics-launches-on-pc-playstation-5-nintendo-switch/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ys-x-proud-nordics-launches-on-pc-playstation-5-nintendo-switch.1359454/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>Ys X: Proud Nordics will launch on PC, PlayStation 5, and Nintendo Switch 2 on February 20, 2026 in North America and Europe.</p>



<p>The release date for the definitive edition of the tenth entry in the long-running action role-playing game series by Falcom, and the previously unannounced PlayStation 5 release, have been revealed today with a new trailer focusing on the additional features of this new version of the game, which include:</p>



<ul>
<li>A new story centered around Öland and the mysterious Canute and Astrid</li>



<li>A new time-trial Muspelheim dungeon where every second counts</li>



<li>Improved visuals and performance</li>



<li>New quality-of-life updates</li>



<li>New mechanics, such as Mana Hold, will allow players to manipulate the world around Adol and Karja in new ways.</li>
</ul>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Ys X: Proud Nordics - Release Date Announcement Trailer (Nintendo Switch 2, PS5, and PC)" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/22hVG49Ofps?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>Alongside the announcement trailer, publisher NISA also shared some brand new Ys X: Proud Nordics to provide another look at the new features. You can find them below.</p>


<figure>
<div>

<figure>
<figure><figcaption><em>Ys X: Proud Nordics will come with plenty of new features, including a new story, a new challenging dungeon and more</em></figcaption></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>
</figure>
<div>
				    		
				    		
					    	<p><span>2 of 9</span>
				    	</p></div>
</div>
</figure>



<p>The new Ys X: Proud Nordics is set to make the tenth entry in the Falcom series an even better game. Although the game starts slow, making the first five or so hours a little off-putting, the game eventually blooms in one of the finest entries in the series, thanks to an engaging story and great combat mechanics which force players to balance offense and defense, and push the series forward beyond the party-based system introduced in <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/ys-seven-pc-start-new-era/">YS Seven.</a> You can learn more about the game by<a data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" href="https://wccftech.com/review/ys-x-nordics-one-more-memorable-adventure/"> checking out my review.</a></p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/ys-x-proud-nordics-launches-on-pc-playstation-5-nintendo-switch/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Reanimal, Tarsier Studio’s First New Game Since Little Nightmares 2 Arrives In February 2026, Demo Out Now]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/reanimal-release-date-tarsier-studios/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/reanimal-tarsier-studio%E2%80%99s-first-new-game-since-little-nightmares-2-arrives-in-february-2026-demo-out-now.1359451/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>Tarsier Studios, the team behind the first two Little Nightmares games, has announced the release date for its first new game since it released Little Nightmares 2. Reanimal, the latest horror adventure from the team will arrive on PC, PS5, Nintendo Switch 2, and Xbox Series X/S this coming February 13, 2026.</p>



<p>This announcement comes just hours before the team is set to show off more of Reanimal <a href="https://wccftech.com/microsoft-announces-xbox-partner-preview-thursday/">during Xbox's Partner Preview event later today</a>, and <a href="https://wccftech.com/tarsier-studios-reanimal-release-date-q1-2026/">it solidifies what Tarsier told us in August</a>, which was that the game would arrive sometime during Q1 2026.</p>



<p>You can pre-order the game now on all platforms for $39.99 USD, though if you're unsure you'd want to jump into this new title from Tarsier, the studio has also put out a demo that is now available on PS5 and Xbox Series consoles as well as PC. A Nintendo Switch 2 demo is also on its way, though it will be available at a later date.</p>



<p><a href="https://wccftech.com/reanimal-gamescom-preview-a-nightmare-of-a-different-kind/">At Gamescom 2025, Wccftech's Francesco De Meo got the chance to demo the game ahead of release, </a>and though he concluded it wasn't enough time to definitively say whether Tarsier has something very special on its hands, it was enough time to know that this studio still knows what its doing. Reanimal could be the beginning of a new massive franchise that'll bloom in the way Little Nightmares has, which <a href="https://wccftech.com/little-nightmares-showcase-announces-little-nightmares-iii-release-date-little-nightmares-enhanced-edition-a-little-nightmares-vr-game-and-more/">now has multiple projects in the works across multiple mediums</a>, not just video games.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/reanimal-release-date-tarsier-studios/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Arc Raiders' latest update nerfs an overperforming pistol, rebalances boom damage and also has ducks]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/arc-raiders-latest-update-nerfs-an-overperforming-pistol-rebalances-boom-damage-and-also-has-ducks</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/arc-raiders-latest-update-nerfs-an-overperforming-pistol-rebalances-boom-damage-and-also-has-ducks.1359448/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arc-raiders-update-130-gun-nerf-ducks-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arc-raiders-update-130-gun-nerf-ducks-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arc-raiders-update-130-gun-nerf-ducks-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arc-raiders-update-130-gun-nerf-ducks-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arc-raiders-update-130-gun-nerf-ducks-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arc-raiders-update-130-gun-nerf-ducks-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arc-raiders-update-130-gun-nerf-ducks-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arc-raiders-update-130-gun-nerf-ducks-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arc-raiders-update-130-gun-nerf-ducks-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Embark Studios</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Show me your quacking war face. Well, show the swarm of rubber ducks <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/arc-raiders">Arc Raiders</a> devs Embark have seemingly unleashed upon your character's living quarters your quacking war face. Otherwise you'd better be careful where you put your feet, lest you upset them and loose avian anarchy on the world. Also, a gun which might have been your favourite for decimating squads of poor <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-fps-games">shootery</a> fools with other loadouts has been nerfed.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>"The fully upgraded Venator has been over-performing recently, capable of outgunning full squads using close range weapons," Embark admit in the <a href="https://arcraiders.com/news/duck-update-patch-notes-1-3-0">notes</a> for patch 1.3.0. "We’re re-tuning the fire-rate gained from upgrades to pull down the pacing a bit, while still keeping its damage and accuracy intact. This should encourage players to take some more time with their shots rather than mag-dumping the first poor soul they encounter. The community also rightfully pointed out that the weight of the Venator was inconsistent with the weights of our other pistols, so we’ve corrected that as well."</p>
<p>Its upgraded fire rate's been dialled down from 22/44/60% to 13/26/40%, while its weight's more than doubled from 2kg to five. Meanwhile, the Deadline mine's been made more valuable when buying or selling, less plentiful in the inventories of traders, and requires more components to craft. Staying in the resupply zone, launcher ammo can now be crafted without blueprints, power cells sell for less cash, and any explosive weapons you strap to your back have had their damage rejigged.</p>
<p>In terms of that last bit, Embark have "adjusted explosive damage to make it more consistent across the board, and we’ve re-balanced the damage of the Hullcracker to account for that change". So, you'll need to be more precise to keep on taking down the likes of larger drones quickly with the launcher, while smaller foes should still behave largely as they did before if you try to blow them up.</p><p>Beyond those, two things have been made less rare. First, Aphelion blueprints. Second, rubber ducks. "Your Raider Den has been ducked out," the devs either warn, threaten or just say depending on your view of small birds. There are also plenty of tweaks to maps, including on stopping people using barricades to cheekily clip through walls into locked rooms where they might find a safe, duckless refuge.</p>
<p>If you're still busy raiding the non-lost arcs, make sure to check out our guides for everything from the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/arc-raiders-best-guns-tier-list">best guns</a> to <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/arc-raiders-eyes-in-the-sky-quest-walkthrough">doing stuff with tripods</a> so you aren't left running around like a headless rubber duck.</p>

        </div>

      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/arc-raiders-latest-update-nerfs-an-overperforming-pistol-rebalances-boom-damage-and-also-has-ducks]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon Goes Hard on Apple, 2025 iPads Now Going for Less Than No-Name Budget Alternatives]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/amazon-goes-hard-on-apple-2025-ipads-now-going-for-less-than-no-name-budget-alternatives-2000645748</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/amazon-goes-hard-on-apple-2025-ipads-now-going-for-less-than-no-name-budget-alternatives.1359433/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Apple launched the 11-inch iPad with an A16 chip back in March of this year, and now <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4533/">Amazon’s dropping the 128GB/Wi-Fi mode to a record low of $279 for Black Friday, down from its $349 retail price</a>. You won’t find this discount on Apple’s official website or in their retail stores because the company keeps tight pricing controls.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4533/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>iPhone Performance to Tablet Form</h2>
<p>The A16 Bionic chip delivers processing power that rivals many laptops and maintains the instant responsiveness that iPads are known for. The 6-core CPU splits tasks between performance and efficiency cores that balance speed and battery life based on workload demands. The 5-core GPU accelerates graphics rendering, gaming performance, and augmented reality applications. It allows the <strong>16-core Neural Engine to process 17 trillion operations per second</strong>&nbsp;and powers machine learning functions like Live Text, subject isolation in Photos, and real-time translation.</p>
<p>The <strong>11-inch Liquid Retina display pushes 2360 by 1640 resolution with True Tone technology</strong> that adjusts color temperature based on ambient lighting. The display covers the P3 wide color gamut, reproducing vibrant colors that look accurate for photo editing and creative work. The IPS panel maintains excellent viewing angles, so colors and contrast stay consistent when viewing the screen from the side.</p>



<p>A 128GB storage configuration provides enough space for essential apps and working files without forcing you into constant cloud storage management. Modern apps and high-resolution photos consume storage fast, and 128GB is the minimum viable capacity required to enjoy comfortable use. You can store dozens of apps, thousands of photos, hours of offline video content, and still have room for documents and downloads.</p>
<p>With WiFi 6 connectivity, this <strong>iPad offers faster and wireless speeds and better performance</strong> in crowded network conditions than earlier WiFi standards. The increased efficiency reduces battery drain when using the internet for several hours continuously, while the low latency further enhances video calls and online gaming. WiFi 6 routers are slowly becoming commonplace in many homes and businesses, and this iPad fully leverages the new and improved technology.</p>
<p>The<strong> Touch ID built into the power button</strong> allows for secure authentication without the TrueDepth camera setup of Face ID. The fingerprint sensor instantly unlocks the iPad, authorizes purchases, and allows you to switch between user profiles with the touch of a finger. This method of authentication works in any environment with no light limitation and does not require you to position your face in front of the device. Finally, <strong>with all-day battery life, up to 10 hours of web surfing</strong> or video playback on a single charge covers full work days, long flights, or weekend road trips without needing a charger.</p>
<p>The<strong> iPad runs iPadOS</strong> with access to millions of tablet-optimized apps that take advantage of the larger screen compared to the apps on the iPhone. The operating system supports multitasking with <em>Split View</em> and <em>Slide Over</em> which let you run multiple apps at the same time. Support for the Apple Pencil allows for note-taking, digital art, and document annotation, though the stylus sells separately.</p>
<p>For $279, this iPad is cheaper than a lot of budget Android tablets that deliver far worse performance, worse displays and app ecosystems that pale in comparison.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4533/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/amazon-goes-hard-on-apple-2025-ipads-now-going-for-less-than-no-name-budget-alternatives-2000645748]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battlefield 6 Is Already Toppling Some Call Of Duty Records]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/battlefield-6-sales-black-ops-7-charts-2000645794</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/battlefield-6-is-already-toppling-some-call-of-duty-records.1359430/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>It only took <a href="https://kotaku.com/battlefield-6-review-steam-ps5-campaign-multiplayer-2000633379"><em>Battlefield 6</em></a> one month to become the top-grossing game released so far this year in the U.S. But that doesn’t even tell the whole story of how well the multiplayer shooter franchise’s return to form has gone. It’s also the best-selling game in any single month in the last three years, meaning it sold even better than <em>Call of Duty: Modern Warfare 3</em> did when it debuted in 2023.</p> <p>“<em>Battlefield 6</em> produced the highest single month US physical &amp; digital full game tracked dollar sales total in 3 years,” Circana director of game research Mat Piscatella <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/matpiscatella.bsky.social/post/3m62wm6voxa2s">announced on Bluesky today</a>. “The last title to generate a larger full game tracked dollar sales total in a single month was <em>Call of Duty: Modern Warfare II</em> in October 2022.”</p>

 <p>EA previously confirmed that <em>Battlefield 6</em> had sold over 7 million copies shortly after launch. Its continuing popularity has been enough not only to make it the best-selling game for October 2025 in the U.S. but also to immediately rocket it up to the top of the best-sellers chart for the entire year so far, past <em>NBA 2K26</em>, <em>Monster Hunter Wilds</em>, <em>Borderlands 4</em>, and <em>EA Sports College Football 26</em>.</p>   <p>Those stats certainly add more fuel to the fire of the renewed <a href="https://kotaku.com/black-ops-7-free-battlefield-6-call-of-duty-rivalry-2000633176"><em>Battlefield</em>/<em>Call of Duty</em> rivalry</a>. While people have been picking over weak concurrent numbers on Steam following the <a href="https://kotaku.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-review-campaign-is-it-good-zombies-multiplayer-2000645198">launch of <em>Black Ops 7</em></a>, the proof will be in the November sales data that arrives next month. Last year’s <em>Black Ops 6</em> was the first <em>Call of Duty </em>game to be free on day one with a Game Pass subscription and it’s still the seventh best-selling game of <em>this</em> year.</p>

 <p>Microsoft recently hiked the price of Game Pass to $30 a month, incentivizing more players to pay outright for this year’s <em>Call of Duty</em> rather than rent it through the subscription service. Still, <a href="https://www.thegamebusiness.com/p/call-of-duty-under-attack"><em>The Game Business</em> reports</a> that In the UK at least, physical launch sales for <em>Black Ops 7</em> are down 61 percent over last year’s entry. It also notes that this fall is extra competitive in the shooter space with the launch of <em>Arc Raiders</em> and<em> Fortnite</em>‘s big <em>Simpsons</em> season.</p> <p>Other notable data points for the month include PS5-exclusive<em> Ghost of Yotei</em> breaking into the top 10 best-selling games of the year and <em>The Outer Worlds 2</em> ranking seventh for the month, despite being on Game Pass. <em>Borderlands 4</em> fell off in a big way, dropping to 10th for the month. My personal favorite stat, however, is that <em>Final Fantasy Tactics: The Ivalice Chronicles</em> is hanging around at number 14. It seems likely to break 1 million sales if it hasn’t already. I still have my fingers crossed that we’ll <a href="https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-tactics-ivalice-remaster-cloud-wiegraf-cid-sequel-2000622717">get that sequel after all</a>.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/battlefield-6-sales-black-ops-7-charts-2000645794]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokémon Ascended Heroes Release Date—All Cards & Products]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-ascended-heroes-release-date-products/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pok%C3%A9mon-ascended-heroes-release-date%E2%80%94all-cards-products.1359424/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Pokémon TCG sets continue to come thick and fast, and, while Phantasmal Flames has only just hit the shelves, the countdown has begun until the next big set, Ascended Heroes, releases.</p>



<p>Ascended Heroes is the next holiday set in the Pokémon TCG, following on from fan favourites like Prismastic Evolutions and 151, which have set a high bar to meet. However, with the return of Mega Evolution having caught the eye, expectations are high.</p>



<p>If you want to make sure you don’t miss out on the drop of any Pokémon TCG Ascended Heroes products, Insider Gaming has all the crucial details.</p>







<h2 id="h-when-is-the-pokemon-ascended-heroes-release-date">When is The Pokémon Ascended Heroes Release Date?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Coming soon. Image via The Pokemon Company</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>The Ascended Heroes Pokémon</strong> <strong>TCG set releases on January 30, 2026, as confirmed by The Pokémon</strong> <strong>Company, and will be the first set of the new year.</strong></p>



<p>Ascended Heroes will be the third set in the Mega Evolution line, following on from Phantasmal Flames and the base set, featuring the TCG debut of many Mega Pokémon introduced in Pokémon Legends: Z-A, including Mega Dragonite, Mega Hawlucha, and Mega Eelektross.</p>



<p>Not all products are released at once, however, and they are staggered throughout the year. </p>



<h2 id="h-all-pokemon-ascended-heroes-products">All Pokémon Ascended Heroes Products</h2>



<p><strong>Ascended Heroes Pokémon</strong> <strong>TCG products have various release dates, with the first in the line releasing on January 30. </strong></p>



<p>However, many of the most popular products, like Elite Trainer Boxes and Booster Bundles, don’t release on the same date. Additionally, as the set is classed as a holiday set, there is no Booster Box of 36 packs available—similar to Black Bolt, White Flare, and Prismatic Evolutions in 2025.</p>



<p>The table below highlights all the announced products so far for Ascended Heroes and the release dates.</p>



<figure><table><thead><tr><th data-align="center">Product</th><th data-align="center">Contents</th><th data-align="center">Release Date</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td data-align="center">Ascended Heroes Collection</td><td data-align="center">– 2x Booster Packs<br>– 1x Coin<br>– 1x Promo Card</td><td data-align="center">Jan. 30, 2026</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Ascended Heroes Tech Sticker Collection</td><td data-align="center">– 3x Booster Packs<br>– 1x Promo Card<br>– 1x Sticker Sheet</td><td data-align="center">Jan. 30, 2026</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Ascended Heroes Elite Trainer Box</td><td data-align="center">– 9x Booster Packs<br>– 1x Promo Card<br>– Gameplay Accessories</td><td data-align="center">Feb. 20, 2026</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Ascended Heroes Pokémon Center Elite Trainer Box</td><td data-align="center">– 11x Booster Packs<br>– 2x Promo Cards<br>– Gameplay Accessories</td><td data-align="center">Feb. 20, 2026</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Ascended Heroes Mini Tin</td><td data-align="center">– 2x Booster Packs<br>– 1x Art Card<br>– 1x Sticker Card</td><td data-align="center">Feb. 20, 2026</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Ascended Heroes Premium Poster Collection</td><td data-align="center">– 10x Booster Packs<br>– 1x Promo Card<br>– 1x Two-Sided Poster</td><td data-align="center">March 20, 2026</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Ascended Heroes Booster Bundle</td><td data-align="center">– 6x Booster Packs</td><td data-align="center">– April 24, 2026</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<h2 id="h-all-pokemon-ascended-heroes-cards">All Pokémon Ascended Heroes Cards</h2>



<p><strong>The Ascended Heroes set will feature cards initially printed in the Japanese Mega Dream ex set and Start Deck 100s, though the set lists won’t be identical,</strong> as some cards will be saved for future sets<strong> or pulled to feature as promos.</strong></p>



<p>Only a handful of English cards have been officially revealed so far; Mega Charizard Y ex, a special illustration rare Mega Gengar ex, and basic cards for N’s Vanilluxe and Entei.</p>



<p>Other cards have been revealed in Japanese, however, including a Psyduck art rare, new Team Rocket cards, Mega Froslass ex. With the set releasing on November 28, the majority of cards featuring in Ascended Heroes will be revealed then.</p>



<p>However, the Start Deck 100 in Japan doesn’t release until early December. Not every card printed in the Start Deck will feature in Ascended Heroes, with many set to be reprints of cards released in previous sets this year.</p>



<hr>



<p>What are your thoughts on the Ascended Heroes Pokémon TCG set so far? Share your thoughts in the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord</a>.</p>



<p>For more Pokémon, read <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-next-pokemon-tcg-set-is-a-master-set-nightmare/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">how Mega Dream ex is going to be a nightmare for master set collectors</a>, and check out the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-pokopia-trailer-reveals-new-pikachu-snorlax-variants/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">reveal of Peakychu and Mosslax</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-ascended-heroes-release-date-products/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Silent Hill 2 Already for Sale on Australian Xbox Store]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/silent-hill-2-already-for-sale-on-australian-xbox-store/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/silent-hill-2-already-for-sale-on-australian-xbox-store.1359418/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-159088">

    <header>
        

        

    </header>

    


    <div>
        
<p>The Xbox Partner Showcase is at 1pm ET/10 am PT on Thursday, but it appears one of the bigger announcements has been spoiled ahead of time. Silent Hill 2, which has long been rumored to be coming to Xbox Series X|S this month, has appeared on the Australian Xbox Store. But here’s the kicker, it’s <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-AU/games/store/SILENT-HILL-2/9PNVDQKPJRQV">already for sale</a> for 50% off.</p>



<p>The store listing also confirms that the game will be an Xbox Play Anywhere title. That means if you buy it on your console or PC, you can play on both systems.</p>







<p>This isn’t the first time that the Xbox store has leaked plans for Silent Hill 2. Earlier this month, the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/microsoft-store-leaks-silent-hill-2-xbox-release-date/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">store revealed</a> a release date of November 21, though it was quickly removed. </p>



<p>As of publishing, Silent Hill 2 has a “generally favorable” rating of&nbsp;<a href="https://www.metacritic.com/game/silent-hill-2/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">86 on Metacritic</a>&nbsp;from 105 reviews while the user score is even higher at 9.1 from 3,998 user ratings.</p>



<p>Are you going to pick up Silent Hill 2 for Xbox when it officially releases worldwide? Leave your thoughts down in the comments below and&nbsp;join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read about Battlefield 6 already <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-breaks-franchise-sales-record/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">setting franchise sales records</a>. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/final-fantasy-7-remake-will-be-close-to-100gb-on-switch-2/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/final-fantasy-7-remake-will-be-close-to-100gb-on-switch-2/">
                                Final Fantasy 7 Remake Will Be Close to 100GB on Switch 2                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Final Fantasy 7 Remake Intergrade’s storage requirements for the Switch 2 have been changed, now closer to 100GB. </p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/reanimal-release-date-confirmed/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/reanimal-release-date-confirmed/">
                                Reanimal Release Date Confirmed                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Reanimal’s release date has been confirmed, and pre-orders for the title are now live. Here’s what you need to know. </p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-breaks-franchise-sales-record/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-breaks-franchise-sales-record/">
                                Battlefield 6 Breaks Franchise Sales Record                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>According to the latest data, Battlefield 6 has broken its franchise sales record in just its first month.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-was-the-uss-best-selling-game-of-october-2025/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-was-the-uss-best-selling-game-of-october-2025/">
                                Battlefield 6 Was the US’s Best-Selling Game of October 2025                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>According to the latest sales data, Battlefield 6 was the best-selling game for October 2025 with five other new games in the top 20.</p>
                    </div>

                                                    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/silent-hill-2-already-for-sale-on-australian-xbox-store/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[When is The Next Black Ops 7 Double XP Weekend?]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-7-double-xp-weekend/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/when-is-the-next-black-ops-7-double-xp-weekend.1359415/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Black Ops 7 is now firmly set as the latest Call of Duty experience, with players naturally wondering when exactly the double XP events will kick off, and Insider Gaming has everything there is to know.</p>



<p>Although Black Ops 7 may not be everyone’s cup of tea, and has split opinions since its release, Call of Duty remains as one of the industry’s heavy hitters, and special events attract thousands of players into the game.</p>



<p>Whether you have a gun you’re looking to max out or want to get through Prestige as quickly as possible, this guide has all the details about double XP events.</p>







<h2 id="h-when-is-black-ops-7-s-next-double-xp-weekend">When is Black Ops 7’s Next Double XP Weekend?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Bonuses. Image via Activision</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>No official dates have been set for the first double XP weekend in Call of Duty: Black Ops 7, but leakers have shared some crucial information.</strong></p>



<p>According to reliable data miner <a href="https://x.com/realityuk/status/1989775184182611976" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Reality</a>, the first event in Black Ops 7 is right around the corner and will last longer than the usual event.</p>



<p>It’s stated that the first double XP event will kick off on November 25 and will run until December 1, giving players six full days to grind through Prestiges much quicker. However, this event is yet to be confirmed, and will remain as speculation until Activision lifts the lid.</p>



<p>If the dates are correct, though, expect news about the first double XP event in Black Ops 7 to be shared imminently. From there, the events may be more regular, with the launch of Season 1 on the horizon, and major events like Christmas and New Year’s.</p>







<h2 id="h-how-frequent-are-double-xp-weekends">How Frequent Are Double XP Weekends?</h2>



<p><strong>It’s not yet known how frequent double XP weekends will be in Black Ops 7, but the format from Black Ops 6 gives hints of what players can expect.</strong></p>



<p>After the first double XP event in Black Ops 6, Activision settled into a routine that saw double XP events happen at least once a month, with the majority of months having two.</p>



<p>November, December, February, April, May, and July in Black Ops 6 all had at least two double XP events in the month, so expect to see them appear regularly in the latest title </p>



<hr>



<p>How often should double XP events appear in Black Ops 7? Share your thoughts in the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord</a>.</p>



<p>For more Black Ops 7, read about the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-7-endgame-available-campaign-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">full unlock of the endgame mode for all players this week</a>, and check out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/when-is-black-ops-7-warzone-coming-out-black-ops-7-warzone-integration/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">when Warzone integration is expected</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-7-double-xp-weekend/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How Hades 2 Fails Its Protagonist]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/how-hades-2-fails-its-protagonist/1100-6536369/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/how-hades-2-fails-its-protagonist.1359412/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="">

            
          
  

<section><p>While Hades showed audiences how deep storytelling can be in a roguelike experience, Hades II fails to reach that same hallmark by giving us a protagonist who has little agency of her own.</p></section>
        
        
                    
              <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr"><em>Minor spoilers for Hades and Hades II to follow--read at your own discretion.</em></p><p dir="ltr">Since its inception, Supergiant Games has built up a reputation around high-quality story experiences with deep gameplay systems to match. Yet while all the San Francisco-based studio's games are worthy of praise, it was the first Hades game that raised the bar when it came to roguelike games and their storytelling. It only makes sense, then, that it also became the first Supergiant title to earn a sequel.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="432338010" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6466378,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Hades%202%20Review&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:888,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/hades-2-review\/2300-6466378\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466378\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466378\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466378\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6466378&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6466378,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;feature_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6536369&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;hades,hades-ii&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;action,role-playing&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;pc,nintendo-switch,macintosh,xbox-series-x,xbox-one,playstation-5,playstation-4,ios-iphoneipad,nintendo-switch-2&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;supergiant-games,private-division,take-two-interactive,netflix&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;franchise&quot;:&quot;hades&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;franchiseRoot&quot;:&quot;hades&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6466378},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6466378\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;GameSpot&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1823\/18237460\/4573809-hades2_review_site_only.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/92zeqptV.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1758726000,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="92zeqptV" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> Hades 2 Review</p>
      </div>
<p dir="ltr">Hades II carries over a lot of the features that made its predecessor such a beloved title, with one exception: its protagonist. This shift presented Supergiant with an exciting opportunity to explore new themes, making it disappointing that the end result instead plays into matronly stereotypes. While the first game had a protagonist who started out a cocky, sarcastic jackass before undergoing a deep and meaningful character arc, Hades II forgoes this in favor of making its female protagonist overtly stoic and duty-bound, playing into the misogynistic societal expectations for female-identifying people.</p><p dir="ltr">Set in the Greek mythology version of the underworld, Hades told the story of Zagreus, son of the titular god of the Underworld. Unhappy with his life of luxury and comfort in the Underworld, Zagreus decides to leave and join the rest of the gods in Olympus. Along his way he fights numerous enemies in the underworld and the fields of Elysium in a Dante’s Inferno-esque journey.</p><p dir="ltr">Across Hades’ dozens of hours, players got to learn about Zagreus and witness his transformation from melancholic spoiled brat to suave, care-free warrior--the very embodiment of cool. He received a proper and fulfilling arc, one that helped cement the game as an instant classic and proved Supergiant could take a subject as vast as Greek Mythology and deliver a personal story about growth. Through their attempts to escape as Zagreus, players saw his character change, and demeanor soften. What could have been a modern-day interpretation of gods and mythology instead became a personal fable of growth, gratitude , and maturity. Hades’ tale strikes a chord and has universal appeal, no matter the audience.</p><p dir="ltr">Enter Hades II, the unexpected sequel. How can a studio even follow up on a game that felt so complete? Sure, Greek mythology allows for countless tales and settings, but Hades felt so personal and laser-focused that one can’t help but wonder where to even go from there.</p><p dir="ltr">Hades II follows new protagonist Melinoë, the daughter of Hades and younger sister of Zagreus. After the home of Hades was sieged by Chronos, the God of Time, Mel was raised in the field of Elysium by the witch Hecate. Because Chronos launched his attack when she was a baby, Mel has never met her family and instead only knows them through information that she learned from others. Mel, desiring the family she has never known, decides to train with Hecate to kill Chronos and help her family reclaim their home, all while dealing with a war and invasion of Olympus in the process.</p><p dir="ltr">And herein lies the problem with the fable of Molinoë. Hades II starts in the middle of its story--Mel is already well into her training and the house of Hades has already fallen. We don’t know much about her as a character and even though we’re drip-fed information about her backstory throughout the game in the form of flashbacks, we never quite get to know her beyond her wanting to save her family.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394322/4607705-scka7g.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4607705" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="2560" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394322/4607705-scka7g.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4607705"></a><figcaption>Melinoe vows to slay Chronos.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394322/4607705-scka7g.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">The first Hades game gave us a fully fleshed-out character and allowed them to grow throughout the narrative. Zagreus was allowed to be flawed, to take time to learn his own lessons, and to go through a rich, fulfilling character arc. Mel in Hades II, on the other hand, has her story and value tied to her family. She’s portrayed as having very few flaws aside from failing over and over again to save a family that she doesn’t know. Even when she gets wrapped up in a war for Olympus, she’s always solving other characters' problems. Throughout the game, we learn so little about her. Mel even loses agency in her own narrative when Zagreus gets involved in the third act, and it’s a staggering disappointment.</p><p dir="ltr">The problem with Mel’s quest being so intrinsically tied to her family is that it’s evocative of misogynistic ideologies--ideologies that proclaim a woman’s value is tied inherently to her family and that it should be the focus of her life and ambitions. Zagreus was allowed to be a cocky, smartass problem child who showed his flaws by going on a self-centered quest, so why isn’t Mel allowed something similar? Why isn’t she allowed to show flaws to a similar degree, or have a reckless attitude about certain situations?</p><p dir="ltr">I’m not asking for her to be a beat-for-beat repeat of Zagreus, but there was so much potential to explore certain themes with a female protagonist that Hades II fails to deliver on. At the start of Hades II, Mel is shown to be mature and established, as if she went through an entire character arc off-screen that we’re only drip-fed information about. Hades II having a protagonist like this only reinforces societal expectations that women need to mature faster, keep order, and focus on tasks at hand at the expense of self-exploration. Hades II could’ve done some interesting exploration of feminist themes using this set-up but instead forgoes it in favor of a stoic protagonist to offset their cheeky protagonist of the first game.</p><p dir="ltr">In many ways, Hades II is an improvement on the first game--from the combat and upgrade systems, to the moment-to-moment gameplay. It’s just such a shame that Hades II fails its protagonist in such deep ways that it blemishes the entire experience. While Hades showed audiences how deep storytelling can be in a roguelike experience, Hades II fails to reach that same hallmark by giving us a protagonist that has little agency of her own and is often a fixer of other characters' problems.</p>
  
                                                              </div>
    

              <div>
  <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>
  
    </div>
      
        
        
  
              


  

    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/how-hades-2-fails-its-protagonist/1100-6536369/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[We've Never Seen Anything Like Switch 2's Sales Before]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/weve-never-seen-anything-like-switch-2s-sales-before/1100-6536384/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/weve-never-seen-anything-like-switch-2s-sales-before.1359409/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536384">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Circana has released its latest monthly sales report, revealing which games and hardware sold the best during October 2025. Battlefield 6 topped the software charts and Nintendo's Switch 2 came out on top for hardware. </p><p><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/matpiscatella.bsky.social/post/3m62wm3ps7c2s" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">According to Circana</a>, the Switch 2 sold 328,000 units in the US in October. It's now pacing ahead of the original Switch by 68% and is also ahead 3% of the PlayStation 4's "previous record velocity" for sales.</p><p>The Switch 2 helped lift US hardware sales in October to $351 million, which was up 36% year-over-year. The Switch 2 did so well it offset the year-over-year declines experienced by the original Switch (down 52%), Xbox Series X|S (down 37%), and PlayStation 5 (down 22%). </p><p>Nintendo's own official sales data for the Switch 2 showed that the console sold <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-continues-to-be-a-massive-hit-selling-over-10-million-units-in-six-months/1100-6535903/" data-ref-id="1100-6535903">more than 10 million units by the end of September</a>, which is when the company's latest quarter ended. </p><p>The Switch 2 launched in June and is now entering its first holiday season. Nintendo's own <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/us/whatsnew/nintendo-announces-holiday-offers-for-black-friday-and-cyber-monday-2025/?srsltid=AfmBOooQvSBIuFD-mn3BFsQa049PQl90FzMqp5xetiL1D7r1Jm51NPUL" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">official Black Friday/holiday discounts</a> do not include any price drops or extra bundles for the system itself, but <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/best-nintendo-switch-and-switch-2-black-friday-game-deals-available-now/1100-6535728/" data-ref-id="1100-6535728">dozens of Switch 2 games are on sale.</a></p><p>As for Circana's report on game sales in October, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/2025-best-selling-games/2900-6281/" data-ref-id="2900-6281">Battlefield 6 had a record-breaking debut</a> and quickly became <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/2025-best-selling-games/2900-6281/" data-ref-id="2900-6281">2025's best-selling game overall in the US.</a></p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/weve-never-seen-anything-like-switch-2s-sales-before/1100-6536384/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Capcom wanted mouse support in Resident Evil Requiem on Switch 2, but it "confused the gameplay"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/capcom-wanted-mouse-support-in-resident-evil-requiem-on-switch-2-but-it-confused-the-gameplay</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/capcom-wanted-mouse-support-in-resident-evil-requiem-on-switch-2-but-it-confused-the-gameplay.1359406/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>

  <figure>
      <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Resident-Evil-Requiem-image-showing-a-fair-haired-lady-in-a-red-jacket-and-white-shirt.-she-is-holding-a-torch.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Resident-Evil-Requiem-image-showing-a-fair-haired-lady-in-a-red-jacket-and-white-shirt.-she-is-holding-a-torch.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Resident-Evil-Requiem-image-showing-a-fair-haired-lady-in-a-red-jacket-and-white-shirt.-she-is-holding-a-torch.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Resident-Evil-Requiem-image-showing-a-fair-haired-lady-in-a-red-jacket-and-white-shirt.-she-is-holding-a-torch.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Resident-Evil-Requiem-image-showing-a-fair-haired-lady-in-a-red-jacket-and-white-shirt.-she-is-holding-a-torch.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Resident-Evil-Requiem-image-showing-a-fair-haired-lady-in-a-red-jacket-and-white-shirt.-she-is-holding-a-torch.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Resident-Evil-Requiem-image-showing-a-fair-haired-lady-in-a-red-jacket-and-white-shirt.-she-is-holding-a-torch.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Resident-Evil-Requiem-image-showing-a-fair-haired-lady-in-a-red-jacket-and-white-shirt.-she-is-holding-a-torch.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Resident-Evil-Requiem-image-showing-a-fair-haired-lady-in-a-red-jacket-and-white-shirt.-she-is-holding-a-torch.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Capcom</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>The next entry in Capcom's <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/resident-evil-games-order">Resident Evil series</a> will be arriving in just a few months time and, while it was originally announced for PC, PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X/S, it will also be coming to <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/platforms/switch-2">Switch 2</a>. But, will it be making the most of the Switch 2's functions?</p>
<p>Well, according to Resident Evil Requiem producer Masato Kumazawa, the team did try to get the game working with the Switch 2's mouse controls, but this just made things a bit more complicated than anticipated.</p>
<!-- code from Primis - Eurogamer.net - eurogamer.net -->
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<!-- code from Primis -->
<p>Kumazawa-san was asked by <a href="https://press-start.com.au/news/nintendo/2025/11/15/resident-evil-requiem-wont-support-mouse-mode-on-nintendo-switch-2/">PressStart</a> about challenges unique to development for the Switch 2, which the producer began by saying there weren't any. "Looking back on Switch, there were Resident Evil games before on the Switch, so what we did, is we used the past experience of developing these games on the Switch to help develop Nintendo Switch 2," Requiem's producer explained.</p>
<p>"But also, we made a lot of versions of the games for PC as well. In fitting with PCs that have a wide variety of specs, we could also just make sure the game was optimised for the Nintendo Switch 2 too. So it wasn't too hard, so to speak."</p>
<p>OK, so it was all plain sailing... Except, when it wasn't. "We tried really hard to implement mouse controls for Nintendo Switch 2," Kumazawa-san continued. When we put it in, it confused the gameplay and became too complicated."</p>
<p>Because of this complication and confusion, the team is instead using gyro controls instead.</p>
<figure>
 


<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Capcom</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Resident Evil Requiem is set to launch on 27th February, 2026, across <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/resident-evil-7-re-engine-resi-switch-2">PC, PlayStation 5, Nintendo Switch 2 and Xbox Series X/S</a>.</p>
<p>Earlier this week, Capcom assured its Resi fans the team is <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/dont-worry-resident-evil-requiem-wont-have-pc-woes-like-monster-hunter-wilds-says-capcom">working to ensure Resident Evil Requiem will perform well on PC</a>, after a multitude of technical issues this year with <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/monster-hunter-wilds">Monster Hunter Wilds</a>.</p>

        </div>

  
      </article>



  



  

  <section>
    <span>Related topics</span>

    
  </section>
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/capcom-wanted-mouse-support-in-resident-evil-requiem-on-switch-2-but-it-confused-the-gameplay]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Video: We've Played Tomb Raider: Definitive Edition On Switch 2 - Here's 18 Minutes Of Gameplay]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/11/video-weve-played-tomb-raider-definitive-edition-on-switch-2-heres-18-minutes-of-gameplay</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/video-weve-played-tomb-raider-definitive-edition-on-switch-2-heres-18-minutes-of-gameplay.1359388/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Definitive?</p>
</section></header><section>

<p>Earlier this week, Aspyr surprised us all by shadow dropping <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/tomb-raider-definitive-edition">Tomb Raider: Definitive Edition</a> on the Switch and Switch 2 eShop. The 2013 adventure game from Crystal Dynamics is back with a bang, and we've been checking it out so you can see what's in store on Nintendo consoles.</p>
<p>In the above video, we've got a whopping 18 minutes of Switch 2 gameplay footage, showcasing the opening escape sequence, some woodland hunting and, of course, a spot of tomb raiding. There's a mixture of gameplay and cutscenes for you to feast your eyes on too, so don't worry about any surprises.</p>
<p>And for those wondering how things compare on Switch 2 between playing with a Pro Controller and Mouse Mode, we've split the video into two, right around the halfway mark, so you can easily compare the control methods.</p>
<p>Overall, it looks... fine. The visuals are a little lacking for a Switch 2 'Definitive Edition' release, but we have to remember that this one has also landed on Switch 1, which is potentially what the game was optimised for in the first place.</p>
<p>Either way, Tomb Raider 2013 is back, and we're pleased with the chance to play it on the go! We'll have our full review with you shortly, so keep an eye out to see what we make of Lara's latest (re)adventure.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:194025,194040 @ 1763652603 -->
<p><em>What do you make of this Tomb Raider gameplay footage? Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section></article><div><p>Jim came to Nintendo Life in 2022 and, despite his insistence that The Minish Cap is the best Zelda game and his unwavering love for the Star Wars prequels (yes, really), he has continued to write news and features on the site ever since.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/JimNorman"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/jimnormann.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('JimNorman');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/11/video-weve-played-tomb-raider-definitive-edition-on-switch-2-heres-18-minutes-of-gameplay]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Outlaws + Handful of Missions: Remaster Review - A Fistful of Improvements]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/outlaws-handful-of-missions-remaster-review-fist-full-of-improvements</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/outlaws-handful-of-missions-remaster-review-a-fistful-of-improvements.1359385/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>It's been a minute since we've had a good ol' Wild West game, and while&nbsp;<em>Outlaws + Handful of Missions: Remaster</em>&nbsp;technically isn't recent, this new port from <a href="https://techraptor.net/companies/nightdive-studios" rel="nofollow">Nightdive Studios</a> comes with a number of improvements to revitalize this lesser-known FPS.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Like many westerns, tragedy is at the heart of this tale. James Anderson, former lawman and current badass, is on a quest for revenge after his peaceful life in retirement is ruined. With his wife deceased at the hands of some outlaws, and his daughter kidnapped by the very same, it's time to put the "Wild" in Wild West.</p>



<h2>Another Great Remaster Treatment from Nightdive</h2>

<p>Like most games from 1997, there's always some jank to be expected. That's why we can always trust Nightdive Studios to do a good job to make games feel modern and revitalized, which is the case here with&nbsp;<em>Outlaws + Handful of Missions: Remaster.&nbsp;</em></p>

<p>The most noticeable difference between the original and its remaster is a fresh coat of paint. Every aspect of this title gets an improvement, visually. Weapon and enemy models are touched up, textures (from the ground you're standing on to the skyboxes above) are expertly recreated, all the while retaining their retro charm.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Other noticeable improvements can be found in its cutscenes. Now,&nbsp;<em>Outlaws + Handful of Missions: Remaster</em>&nbsp;stands out a bit with its cartoonish cutscenes, with the excellent animation of characters making the story feel more like a classic, animated movie. These cutscenes are also brushed up to look cleaner for the modern day.&nbsp;</p>



<p>All of these visual improvements are enhanced even further with support for high refresh rates and resolutions. If you're familiar with Nightdive remasters, none of this should be a surprise. What I&nbsp;<em>really</em>&nbsp;like about this remaster is that you can switch from the new graphics to the old seamlessly, so it's always fun to see how areas are improved over the original.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Other quality of life improvements come in this package. Controller support, for example, feels great to use even if I much prefer keyboard and mouse. Still, I didn't need to fiddle with the keybindings for my Xbox controller, and I was able to adapt to the control scheme almost immediately, so it's good news for those who prefer gamepads.&nbsp;</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/outlaws-handful-of-missions-remaster-menu-options_0.jpg?itok=1J0o1jhw 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/outlaws-handful-of-missions-remaster-menu-options_0.jpg?itok=wQTrJTlq 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Gyro aim? Now we're talkin'.</figcaption></figure><p>I didn't encounter many bugs, if any at all, though one issue I encountered might qualify. The height of my jump would be really inconsistent; for example, I encountered a tower I had to scale, but my character couldn't jump up the stair-like ledges. I took a break from&nbsp;<em>Outlaws</em>, came back the next day, and the jump worked.</p>

<p>This weird inconsistency was a source of great frustration since it could essentially softlock me in several areas, but it would somehow fix itself if I kept trying or came back later. I really can't tell if this is an error on my part or the game's, but it's worth noting that this might happen to you.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Another issue that isn't related to bugs or anything like that is visibility.&nbsp;<em>Outlaws</em>&nbsp;can be&nbsp;<em>very</em>&nbsp;dark in some areas, and if you run out of lamp oil, you'd better pray you're going the right way. Similarly, crucial objects like keys and crowbars to pry blocked doors felt practically invisible, so these were missed a lot. The pickup radius for these items is also extremely small.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/outlaws-handful-of-missions-remaster-keys.jpg?itok=P1rfJgGu 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/outlaws-handful-of-missions-remaster-keys.jpg?itok=saRIsP2m 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Hands up, sir, I'm here for the keys. And directions.</figcaption></figure><h2>Where in Tarnation Do I Go?</h2>

<p>Although it is perhaps more narrative-focused than other FPS games from its time,&nbsp;<em>Outlaws</em>&nbsp;is still a classic shooter at its core. This particular FPS is created by the&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/star-wars-dark-forces-remaster-review-return-of-kex" rel="nofollow"><em>Star Wars: Dark Forces</em></a>&nbsp;team, and that happens to be one of my favorite games of the genre.&nbsp;<em>Outlaws,</em>&nbsp;then, should be a slam dunk, right?</p>

<p>Well, I'm a bit mixed on this one. Let's start with the setting: It's the Wild West. I was never the biggest fan of westerns, and level design is usually my favorite aspect of boomer shooters. They do a decent job at creating a variety of stages, but I was never blown away by them, perhaps because of my personal biases.</p>

<p>Wild West towns, heavily armed forts, and even a moving train -- these are some of the levels you can expect in&nbsp;<em>Outlaws</em>. The train level is probably my favorite, as they usually are, because of their tight quarters and close-ranged combat. That, and I actually knew where to go (forward, obviously), whereas most levels are maze-like to the extreme.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/outlaws-handful-of-missions-remaster-fort.jpg?itok=coIxVkUK 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/outlaws-handful-of-missions-remaster-fort.jpg?itok=IkvJWBBv 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Plenty of things to hide, even in a single fort.</figcaption></figure><p><em>Star Wars: Dark Forces</em>' level design was also maze-like at times, but I never felt lost with the exception of a level or two. In&nbsp;<em>Outlaws</em>, the later levels continued to frustrate me as I bumbled around, looking for whatever the heck this game wanted me to do. Some of the solutions are puzzle-based, which require picking up certain items and interacting with specific objects.</p>

<p>The puzzle design in a number of levels here is obtuse and devoid of fun, and sometimes it was hard to find where you needed to place certain items. I'd wager half of my playtime with&nbsp;<em>Outlaws</em>&nbsp;was because I was lost, which is just so frustrating. The issue with keys being super hard to see in environments exacerbates this issue.</p>

<p>Some levels, particularly in the "Handful of Missions" portion (these are just extra missions separate from the story), feel more well-designed. The Civil War level is an exciting and enemy-heavy level with a fun theme around it, and the Marshal Training missions are shorter but more combat-focused as well -- bonus, you usually don't get lost in these ones.&nbsp;</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/outlaws-handful-of-missions-remaster-combat.jpg?itok=MUhw57UL 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/outlaws-handful-of-missions-remaster-combat.jpg?itok=dnGY2KBl 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Don't mess with a seasoned lawman.&nbsp;</figcaption></figure><h2>Gunslingin' in&nbsp;<em>Outlaws + Handful of Missions Remaster</em></h2>

<p>The gunplay in&nbsp;<em>Outlaws</em>&nbsp;feels a bit different than your traditional boomer shooter. Weapons have high stopping power, often dropping enemies in one or two hits. Even the base pistol, your trusty revolver, can drop most enemies no problem. It's not super accurate at long range, but if you use your alt-fire to fan the gun's hammer, it's a force to be reckoned with.</p>

<p>The rifle with its scope attachment is crucial, and it's super satisfying to take out a bunch of enemies from afar like a sniper. This is pretty crucial to succeed in&nbsp;<em>Outlaws</em>, or else you'll end up dead, and fast.</p>

<p>Enemies are just as lethal as the player, with their guns dealing a large amount of damage any time you're hit. Walk into a room full of enemies without a plan and you'll get dropped in a second, and that makes for quite an exciting time, at least when you're not bumbling around looking for where to go next.&nbsp;</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/outlaws-handful-of-missions-remaster-guns.jpg?itok=2OCwZKj9 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/outlaws-handful-of-missions-remaster-guns.jpg?itok=JXmBCkMw 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>A shotgun can be useful&nbsp;<em>sometimes</em>.&nbsp;</figcaption></figure><p>In terms of weapon variety, I find&nbsp;<em>Outlaws</em>&nbsp;to be lacking. There aren't all that many weapons to begin with, and three of them are shotguns. The shotguns all feel the same to use, and frankly, aren't all that viable when you have to reload after each shot. Most of my time was spent using the rifle and revolver, and their ammo is plentiful.</p>

<p>You have dynamite, which is a bit like grenades but more dangerous, and the throwing mechanics for it seem a bit clunky, as well as some knives that I also couldn't figure out how to throw well. If all else fails, you can use your fists and kill most enemies in one hit -- which is actually pretty funny -- but it's dangerous to get in close.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/outlaws-handful-of-missions-remaster-vault.jpg?itok=rkQFbl8p 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/outlaws-handful-of-missions-remaster-vault.jpg?itok=XyehT7Ek 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Some fun behind-the-scenes content is included, as they are in most Nightdive titles.</figcaption></figure>

<p><em>Outlaws + Handful of Missions: Remaster</em>&nbsp;was a FPS I wasn't all too familiar with, despite my quest to consume every boomer shooter ever invented. I was glad to have played this one, especially with Nightdive's improvements, but I don't see myself coming back. Level design is just a bit too obtuse. At this point,&nbsp;<em>Outlaws</em>&nbsp;is nearly 30 years old, so there's not much that can be done but to enjoy what is an adequate, if frustrating, shooter in this new remaster.&nbsp;</p>

<hr><p><em><strong>Outlaws + Handful of Missions: Remaster</strong> was reviewed on PC using a code provided by the developer over the course of 10 hours of gameplay - all screenshots were taken during the process of review.</em></p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Austin cut his teeth writing various&nbsp; fan-fiction stories on the RuneScape forums when he was in elementary school. Later on, he developed a deep love for… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/austin-suther">More about Austin</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/outlaws-handful-of-missions-remaster-review-fist-full-of-improvements]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This Ultra-Slim 15″ 1080p Portable Monitor Goes for Pennies as Amazon Goes All In on Black Friday]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/this-ultra-slim-15-1080p-portable-monitor-goes-for-pennies-as-amazon-goes-all-in-on-black-friday-2000645738</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/this-ultra-slim-15%E2%80%B3-1080p-portable-monitor-goes-for-pennies-as-amazon-goes-all-in-on-black-friday.1359382/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Laptop screens restrict your productivity to a cramped workspace, and portable gaming consoles like the Nintendo Switch merit something way more than their diminutive built-in displays. The <em>Arzopa</em> 15.6-inch <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5746/">portable monitor just hit an all-time low of $74 for Black Friday over at Amazon, down from the usual $104</a>. This ultra-slim display solves your need for extra screen real estate without having to carry around bulky monitors. This <strong>monitor weighs in at just 1.6 pounds and measures 0.35 inches thick</strong> which makes it portable – not just technically movable.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5746/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Full HD IPS Display That Looks Good</h2>
<p>The <strong>15.6-inch IPS panel pushes 1920 by 1080 resolution</strong>&nbsp;which provides crisp text for productivity work and detailed visuals for gaming. IPS technology delivers accurate colors and maintains image quality<strong> across a 178-degree viewing angle</strong> so you don’t see color shifting or contrast loss when viewing the screen from the side. The display adeptly handles everything from work documents to game graphics. The 1080p resolution nets you enough pixels to comfortably read small text or see fine details in games without everything looking blocky.</p>



<p>This ultra-slim design makes the monitor genuinely travel-friendly: At 1.6 pounds, <strong>you hardly notice it in a backpack beside your laptop</strong> while its 0.35-inch thickness lets it slide into laptop sleeves or backpack pockets designed for tablets. Arzopa built the monitor with metal materials that feel solid without adding any unnecessary weight. The compact form factor fits easily on airplane tray tables, coffee shop counters, or hotel desks where space is at a premium.</p>
<p>An<strong> integrated kickstand negates the need to carry around separate stands</strong> or lean the monitor against a stack of books. The stand adjusts across multiple angles, letting you position the screen for comfortable viewing as you sit at a desk or recline on a couch. It reliably holds position, without slowly creeping closed during use. The integrated approach means you have all you need for setting up without any extra accessories cluttering your bag.</p>



<p>Multiple display modes adapt to different use cases without complicated configuration. Duplicate mode simply mirrors your primary display, ideal for presentations or showing content to others. Extend mode gives you more workspace, expanding your desktop across both screens and effectively doubling your screen real estate. Second screen mode makes the portable monitor a stand-alone display for phones or tablets.</p>
<p>The <strong>USB-C and HDMI connectivity covers</strong> just about every device that you might want to connect. With modern laptops that come with USB-C ports, you can send out video and power over a single cable, meaning no need for a separate power adapter if your laptop provides enough juice. HDMI input handles game consoles, older laptops, and any device with standard HDMI output. Thanks to plug-and-play functionality, you connect the cable and the display works right off without drivers installed or visiting configuration menus.</p>
<p><strong>Wide compatibility across laptops, desktops, Macs, phones, Xbox, PlayStation, and Nintendo Switch</strong> means no adapter hassles or workarounds.</p>
<p>For $74, this portable monitor is less than many people spend on a single dinner out and promises legitimate productivity and entertainment value. You get a full HD IPS display with metal construction, integrated stand and universal connectivity for almost 30% off of the regular price.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5746/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/this-ultra-slim-15-1080p-portable-monitor-goes-for-pennies-as-amazon-goes-all-in-on-black-friday-2000645738]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[JBL Flip 5 Bluetooth Speaker Hits Its Deepest Price Cut Ever the Moment Amazon Black Friday Begins]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/act-fast-to-snag-the-jbl-flip-5-for-80-after-this-early-black-friday-deal-dropped-it-by-20-2000645565</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/jbl-flip-5-bluetooth-speaker-hits-its-deepest-price-cut-ever-the-moment-amazon-black-friday-begins.1359379/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><span>Good music means good vibes. The right speaker can bring any party or gathering to life. If you have been after something that delivers powerful sound that’s rich and deep, yet balanced for all your tracks, without spending big bucks, Amazon is making the upgrade easier than ever.</span></p>
<p>The retailer is now offering its early Black Friday sales across a wide range of categories, including audio gear. We are spotting deep discounts on headphones, earbuds, and even some top-rated Bluetooth speakers. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5740/">One of our favorite markdowns from the sale? The JBL Flip 5, which is now going for just $80 after a sweet 20% discount.</a> The offer applies to almost all color options, so there’s plenty to choose from. These include black, red, white, teal, and even the most stunning pink!</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5740/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>
<p>Both Prime and non-Prime members can snag the deal, but Prime members will enjoy free shipping with their purchase. This is the lowest price this speaker has dropped to in the last 30 days, but we don’t expect the discount to stay around for long. Snap it up before it expires for good.</p>

<h2>Portable Yet Powerful</h2>
<p>This can-sized Bluetooth speaker is easy to carry around with you on the go. It features a durable fabric and rugged rubber housing that prevents it from everyday wear and tear. You won’t have to continuously worry about keeping it safe on your trips. Just toss it in your bag and you’re good to go.</p>
<p>Don’t let the size fool you, though. With up to 20 watts of power, it delivers JBL signature sound that’s both rich and balanced. It captures all the highs and lows exceptionally well, making podcasts come through clearly and bringing your favorite tracks to life. The sound is big enough to spread evenly through most places, but you can always pair two JBL PartyBoost-compatible speakers for stereo sound or multiple compatible speakers for a much larger experience. This way, you can host your very own private concerts right there in the yard!</p>
<p>The IPX7 rating means you can take your speaker with you on the beach, by the pool, or even in the shower without a worry. In fact, the JBL Flip 5 is waterproof up to three feet deep, so even an accidental drop in water won’t hurt these. You can focus on enjoying the songs instead of babysitting the speaker all the time.</p>



<p>The built-in 4800mAh rechargeable battery lasts up to 12 hours on a single charge. That’s enough to keep the party going all night long. Just plug these in the morning for an hour or so, and enjoy all your favorite tracks the entire night with friends. The speaker works well with a range of devices, and you just need to have a stable Bluetooth connection to get started. All that you need to do is turn the speaker on, enable Bluetooth on your desired device, and choose the speaker from the list of available options. It shouldn’t take more than a few minutes. There’s also a quick start guide included in the box, which you can refer to if you run into any issues while pairing it.</p>
<p>All things considered, this tiny but mighty Bluetooth speaker not only offers powerful, rich sound but also gets you an impressive battery life. It’s reliable enough to take with you on the go, as can handle everyday wear and tear well. If you’re planning to host some fun gatherings during the holiday season or just want to enjoy your favorite songs in a more immersive way, now is the time to act.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5740/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/act-fast-to-snag-the-jbl-flip-5-for-80-after-this-early-black-friday-deal-dropped-it-by-20-2000645565]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Final Fantasy 7 Remake Will Be Close to 100GB on Switch 2]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/final-fantasy-7-remake-will-be-close-to-100gb-on-switch-2/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/final-fantasy-7-remake-will-be-close-to-100gb-on-switch-2.1359376/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Final Fantasy 7 Remake Intergrade’s storage requirements have been changed for the Nintendo Switch 2, now coming in close to 100GB. </p>



<p>We have been hearing a lot about Final Fantasy 7 Remake Part 3 recently, with devs stating they are considering a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/final-fantasy-7-remake-devs-are-considering-a-full-title-after-part-3/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">whole new game</a> after the release of the final part. However, in the meantime, development on FF7 Remake Intergrade continues for Switch 2, and it seems the game will take up almost half of Switch 2’s base storage space. </p>



<h2 id="h-final-fantasy-7-remake-will-take-up-almost-half-of-switch-2-s-storage-space">Final Fantasy 7 Remake Will Take Up Almost Half of Switch 2’s Storage Space</h2>



<p>The announcement about changes towards Final Fantasy 7 Remake Intergrade 2’s storage size on the Switch 2 was revealed through a new official post on <a href="https://x.com/finalfantasyvii/status/1991431395873530291" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">X</a> (formerly Twitter). The standard edition of the title will now range from 90GB to 95GB, up from the previously announced 87.8GB. The Limited Early Purchase Edition and the Limited Early Purchase Digital Deluxe Edition will be priced between 93.8GB and 99GB. These changes will reflect on the Nintendo Store pages soon. </p>



<p>Final Fantasy 7 Remake Intergrade will release for the Switch 2 on January 22, 2026, where players adventure with Avalanche, a ragtag group of idealists who aim to protect the planet. The game follows the story of Cloud Strife, a former soldier turned mercenary who has joined Avalanche to blow up Reactor 1. This edition also includes FF7R EPISODE INTERmission, where players get to play as Yuffie Kisaragi, a young ninja from Wutai, as she infiltrates Midgar on a mission to steal the ultimate materia from the Shinra Electric Power Company.</p>



<p>In other news, Final Fantasy 9 Remake might be ‘<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/final-fantasy-9-remake-might-be-on-ice-its-claimed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">on ice</a>‘ according to information shared by a reliable insider. Additionally, FF7 Remake Trilogy has been <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/final-fantasy-7-remake-trilogy-officially-confirmed-for-xbox-and-switch-2/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">officially confirmed for Xbox and Switch 2.</a> What are your thoughts on the new storage requirements for Final Fantasy 7 Remake Intergrade on Switch 2? Leave your thoughts down in the comments, and join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/reanimal-release-date-confirmed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Reanimal’s release date</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/final-fantasy-7-remake-will-be-close-to-100gb-on-switch-2/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battlefield 6 Just Had the Best Month of Sales in the U.S. of Any Game in the Last Three Years]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/battlefield-6-just-had-the-best-month-of-sales-in-the-us-of-any-game-in-the-last-three-years</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/battlefield-6-just-had-the-best-month-of-sales-in-the-u-s-of-any-game-in-the-last-three-years.1359370/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">October was an incredible debut month for Battlefield 6: it's officially the best-selling title in franchise history in the U.S., and the best-selling game in the U.S. as of last month.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">This comes from Circana's monthly report, which states that Battlefield 6 is the best-selling game of 2025 on both Xbox and PC, and the second best-selling on PlayStation so far, behind NBA 2K26. It<em> also </em>says that Battlefield produced the highest single month tracked full game dollar sales total of any video game in three years. That means it sold more than the last few Call of Duty games did in their debut months, including Call of Duty: Modern Warfare II in October of 2022. Is this troubling news for Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 when the November report comes out? We'll see.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Battlefield 6 is followed by Pokemon Legends: Z-A, which is the second best-selling game of October and, per Circana, the best-selling physical game year-to-date. Notably, because Nintendo does not share digital sales data, its second-place spot is entirely based on physical sales.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Other debut games for October included The Outer Worlds 2 at No.7, Little Nightmares III at No.8, and Ninja Gaiden 4 at No.11. Dragon Quest I &amp; II HD-2D Remake didn't make it to the top 20, but it was No.6 on Nintendo platforms for the month. There weren't any other major outliers in the charts this time around.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Hardware spending was up 36% year-over-year to $351 million, with the Nintendo Switch 2 offsetting declines in the other three major consoles: Nintendo Switch (sales down 52% year-over-year, wonder why?), Xbox Series (down 37%), and PlayStation 5 (down 22%). The Nintendo Switch 2 sold approximately 328,000 units in October, 68% ahead of the original Nintendo Switch's pace and 3% ahead of the PlayStation 4, which was the previous record-holder.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Nintendo Switch 2 System and Accessories Gallery</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Thanks to Battlefield, the Nintendo Switch 2, and a good month for mobile, overall game hardware, content, and accessories spending was $4.9 billion for the month, up 3% year-over-year.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">October 2025 U.S. Top 20 Best-Selling Games:</h2><ol data-cy="list"><li>Battlefield 6 (NEW)</li><li>Pokemon Legends: Z-A (NEW)*</li><li>Ghost of Yotei</li><li>NBA 2K26</li><li>EA Sports FC 26</li><li>Madden NFL 26</li><li>The Outer Worlds 2 (NEW)</li><li>Little Nightmares III (NEW)</li><li>Digimon Story: Time Stranger</li><li>Borderlands 4</li><li>Ninja Gaiden 4 (NEW)</li><li>EA Sports College Football 26</li><li>Super Mario Galaxy + Super Mario Galaxy 2*</li><li>Final Fantasy Tactics: The Ivalice Chronicles</li><li>Sonic Racing: CrossWorlds</li><li>Silent Hill: f</li><li>Minecraft*</li><li>Helldivers II</li><li>Grand Theft Auto V</li><li>Red Dead Redemption II</li></ol><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>* Indicates that some or all digital sales are not included in Circana's data. Some publishers, including Nintendo, do not share certain digital data for this report.</em>
</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Rebekah Valentine is a senior reporter for IGN. Got a story tip? Send it to rvalentine@ign.com.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/battlefield-6-just-had-the-best-month-of-sales-in-the-us-of-any-game-in-the-last-three-years]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[INDIE Live Expo: November 29, 2025 to feature over 100 titles]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/11/indie-live-expo-november-29-2025-to-feature-over-100-titles</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/indie-live-expo-november-29-2025-to-feature-over-100-titles.1359367/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
        </ul>

    
    <p><span>Core Keeper, SacriFire, Magical Princess, and more.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>The November 29, 2025 edition of INDIE Live Expo will feature updates and announcements on over 100 independent titles, organizer Ryu’s office announced. <span id="more-1008070"></span></p><p>Some of the games set to appear include:</p><ul><li><em><a title="Games > Core Keeper [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/core-keeper">Core Keeper</a></em>, the <a title="Genres > Survival [483 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/survival">survival</a> <a title="Genres > Crafting [47 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/crafting">crafting</a> sandbox <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,700 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a> with over three million copies sold worldwide developed by <a title="Companies > Pugstorm [6 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/pugstorm">Pugstorm</a> and published by both <a title="Companies > Fireshine Games [87 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/enad-global-7/fireshine-games">Fireshine Games</a> and bilibili.</li><li><em><a title="Games > SacriFire [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/sacrifire">SacriFire</a></em>, the supernatural pixel art <a title="Genres > JRPG [1,841 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg/jrpg">JRPG</a> developed by <a title="Companies > Pixelated Milk [8 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/pixelated-milk">Pixelated Milk</a>.</li><li>A brand-new project from <a title="Companies > room6 [39 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/room6">room6</a>, the publisher behind <em>Unreal Life</em> and <em><a title="Games > ghostpia Season One [4 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/ghostpia-season-one">ghostpia Season One</a></em>.</li><li><em><a title="Games > Yunyun Syndrome!? Rhythm Psychosis [4 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/yunyun-syndrome-rhythm-psychosis">Yunyun Syndrome!? Rhythm Psychosis</a></em>, the psychological rhythm adventure co-developed by both <a title="Companies > Alliance Arts [17 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/alliance-arts">Alliance Arts</a> and <a title="Companies > WHO YOU [4 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/who-you">WHO YOU</a>.</li><li><a title="Games > Magical Princess [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/magical-princess">Magical Princess</a>, the child-rearing simulator based on the beloved Magical <a title="Genres > Board Game [63 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/board-game">board game</a> series created by <a title="Companies > MAGI Inc. [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/magi-inc">MAGI Inc.</a>, and developed by <a title="Companies > Neotro [10 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/neotro">Neotro</a>.</li></ul><p>The broadcast will feature INDIE Live Expo-signature segments, starting with dozens of rapid-fire updates during “INDIE Waves,” an extended look at hand-selected titles during “INDIE Spotlight,” and an honoring of 2025’s standout independent titles during “INDIE Live Expo Awards.”</p><p>The panel of judges for this year’s awards segment feature eight industry veterans from four countries, including Shuhei Yoshida (former head of <a title="Companies > Sony Interactive Entertainment [5,084 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sony-group-corporation/sony-interactive-entertainment">Sony Interactive Entertainment</a>’s indie initiative) and Keiichiro Toyama, (creator of <em><a title="Companies > Sile" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sile">Sile</a>nt Hill</em> and <em>SIREN</em>, and CEO of&nbsp;<em><a title="Games > Slitterhead [14 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/slitterhead">Slitterhead</a></em> developer <a title="Companies > Bokeh Game Studio [20 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/bokeh-game-studio">Bokeh Game Studio</a>).</p><p>INDIE Live Expo will air on <a href="https://www.timeanddate.com/worldclock/fixedtime.html?iso=20251129T0900" target="_blank" rel="noopener">November 29 at 1:00 a.m. PT / 4:00 a.m. ET / 18:00 JST</a>. You will be able to watch it on YouTube (<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nEey0hulKHk" target="_blank" rel="noopener">English</a>, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=o5oO-pWlwGA" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Japanese</a>, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dRR828BBujE" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Korean</a>), Twitter (<a href="https://twitter.com/INDIELiveExpoEN" target="_blank" rel="noopener">English</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/INDIELiveExpo" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Japanese</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/INDIELiveExpoKR" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Korean</a>), Twitch (<a href="https://www.twitch.tv/indie_live_expo_en" target="_blank" rel="noopener">English</a>, <a href="https://www.twitch.tv/indie_live_expo_jp" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Japanese</a>), <a href="https://site.nicovideo.jp/game/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Niconico</a>, <a href="https://space.bilibili.com/585934475/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Bilibili</a>, and Steam.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/11/indie-live-expo-november-29-2025-to-feature-over-100-titles]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Carmageddon: Rogue Shift announced for PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/11/carmageddon-rogue-shift-announced-for-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/carmageddon-rogue-shift-announced-for-pc.1359364/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div role="main">
  
  <article>

    
<header>

  <div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Full reveal set for December 4.</span>
      </p></div>

  

</header>  

<!-- Moved from templates/posts/default.php -->

    <div><p><a title="Companies > 34BigThings [13 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/saber-interactive/34bigthings">34BigThings</a> has announced <a title="Genres > Roguelite [308 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/roguelite">roguelite</a> <a title="Genres > Racing [304 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/racing">racing</a> <a title="Genres > Action [3,207 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action game</a> <em><a title="Games > Carmageddon: Rogue Shift" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/carmageddon-rogue-shift">Carmageddon: Rogue Shift</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > PC [24,812 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> (<a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1712100/_Rogue_Shift/" target="_blank">Steam</a>). A full reveal is planned for <a href="https://www.timeanddate.com/worldclock/fixedtime.html?iso=20251204T1200" target="_blank">December 4 at 4:00 a.m. PT / 7:00 a.m. ET</a>. <span id="more-1008231"></span></p><p>While the game’s name appears as the blacked-out “<em>███████████: Rogue Shift</em>” on Steam, the <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/1712100/history/" target="_blank">SteamDB application history</a> shows it was renamed from <em>Carmageddon: Rogue Shift</em>.</p><p>Here is the description of the game on its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1712100/_Rogue_Shift/" target="_blank">Steam page</a>:</p><blockquote><p><em>Carmageddon: Rogue Shift</em> ██ █ ████-███████████ combat-racing roguelite ██ ███ ████ ████ ███████ ███ ██████ ███ ██████ II – 34BigThings.</p><p>██ day ███ skyline ████████; ██ night zombie ██████ – ███ ██████ – █████ █████ avenue. ████ ████ way out ██ ██ win ███ ███████████. █ chain ██ lethal ███████████ races █████ ████████ █████ █ ████ ██ ███ ████ █████████ beyond the mountains.</p></blockquote><p>Watch the teaser trailer below.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <h2><span>Teaser Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Carmageddon: Rogue Shift - Teaser Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/gN-KxoBd-eg?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div>

        
    
  </article>
</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/11/carmageddon-rogue-shift-announced-for-pc]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Get Dragon Ball Sparking Zero And Kakarot Daima Edition For Just $30 Each In This Black Friday Deal]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/get-dragon-ball-sparking-zero-and-kakarot-daima-edition-for-just-30-each-in-this-black-friday-deal/1100-6535995/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/get-dragon-ball-sparking-zero-and-kakarot-daima-edition-for-just-30-each-in-this-black-friday-deal.1359361/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-main">

      
                    
  
              <header id="masthead"><nav></nav></header>      
                            <div id="site-wrapper" role="main">
          <div id="default-content">
        
          <p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p>
  
    <article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6535995">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Dragon Ball fans have eaten well lately with a feast of games based on the hit manga and anime series, and if you're looking to relive the adventures of Goku and his allies, you can get a great <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/black-friday/">Black Friday</a> deal on two excellent games in the franchise. Amazon has discounted <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DZQGXWSH?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Dragon Ball Z: Kakarot - Daima Edition</a> to $30 (was $50) for the PS5 version, while the massive fighting game <a href="https://www.amazon.com/DRAGON-BALL-Sparking-ZERO-PlayStation-5/dp/B0CPTBRK93?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Dragon Ball: Sparking Zero</a> has gotten a 50% discount and is available for $30 on both PS5 and Xbox Series X.</p><div title="[Black Friday 2025] Dragon Ball Sparking Zero And Kakarot Deals" data-embed-type="buylink" data-ref-id="4897" data-template="4" data-size="buylink__listicle" data-title="[Black Friday 2025] Dragon Ball Sparking Zero And Kakarot Deals" data-collection="">                                                                     <div>             <h2>                    <a href="https://www.amazon.com/stores/page/preview?isSlp=1&amp;isPreview=1&amp;asins=B0CPTBRK93,B0CPTBQGRQ?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/stores\/page\/preview?isSlp=1&amp;isPreview=1&amp;asins=B0CPTBRK93,B0CPTBQGRQ?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/stores/page/preview?isSlp=1&amp;isPreview=1&amp;asins=B0CPTBRK93,B0CPTBQGRQ?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20">Dragon Ball: Sparking Zero</a>       </h2>                                   <h3>                      <a href="https://www.amazon.com/stores/page/preview?isSlp=1&amp;isPreview=1&amp;asins=B0CPTBRK93,B0CPTBQGRQ?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/stores\/page\/preview?isSlp=1&amp;isPreview=1&amp;asins=B0CPTBRK93,B0CPTBQGRQ?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/stores/page/preview?isSlp=1&amp;isPreview=1&amp;asins=B0CPTBRK93,B0CPTBQGRQ?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20">$30 (was $60)</a>         </h3>                                                                                                                      <div><p>Dragon Ball: Sparking Zero is the most recent video game release in the franchise, and it's an anime-inspired slugfest with a massive roster of characters pulled from every era of Dragon Ball. Everyone from Goku to Vegeta is included in the game's lineup, and while the combat does have a steep learning curve, once you nail it you'll be throwing out Final Flash and Kamehameha attacks like a pro. The game also looks stunning in action, and if you grew up playing the Dragon Ball Budokai Tenkaichi games, then this will appeal to you as it's a continuation of that series.</p><ul><li><a href="http://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CPTBRK93?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">PS5</a> -- $30 (<del>$60</del>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CPTBQGRQ?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Xbox Series X</a> -- $30 (<del>$60</del>)</li></ul></div>                      </div>                                                                     <div>             <h2>                    <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DZQGXWSH?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/dp\/B0DZQGXWSH?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DZQGXWSH?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20">Dragon Ball Z: Kakarot - Daima Edition</a>       </h2>                                   <h3>                      <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DZQGXWSH?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/dp\/B0DZQGXWSH?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DZQGXWSH?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20">$30 (was $50)</a>         </h3>                                                                                                                      <p>In comparison, Dragon Ball Z: Kakarot is an action-RPG that blends fast-paced fisticuffs with level-grinding. The game also gives you a world to explore as you take part in Goku's greatest battles across the Dragon Ball storyline, and since launch, publisher Bandai Namco has expanded on the game with several story DLC drops inspired by classic OVA series and Dragon Ball Super. The Daima Edition does <em>not </em>include those expansions, but it does come bundled with the two-part Daima DLC, which is based on the Dragon Ball Daima anime series. One thing to note here is that only the first part has been released so far, and Part Two will arrive in early 2026.</p>                      </div>   </div><h2>More Early Black Friday Deals at Amazon</h2><p><strong>Video Game Deals</strong></p><ul><li><a href="https://amzn.to/48ivKJW" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">PS5 Game Deals</a></li><li><a href="https://amzn.to/3K5Vm3y" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Nintendo Switch Game Deals</a></li><li><a href="https://amzn.to/4p8zbIU" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Xbox Series X Game Deals</a></li></ul><p><strong>Video Game Accessory Deals</strong></p><ul><li><a href="https://amzn.to/4p2B5eJ" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">PS5 Accessory Deals</a></li><li><a href="https://amzn.to/47JNduJ" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Switch Accessory Deals</a></li><li><a href="https://amzn.to/4pe08uO" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Xbox Accessory Deals</a></li></ul><p><strong>Controller Deals</strong></p><ul><li><a href="https://amzn.to/4i06ETu" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Switch 1/2 Controller Deals</a></li><li><a href="https://amzn.to/4oMC9TI" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">PS5 Controller Deals</a></li><li><a href="https://amzn.to/49sUOiJ" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Xbox Controller Deals</a></li><li><a href="https://amzn.to/3K2LwPQ" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">PC Controller Deals</a></li></ul><div data-embed-type="pinbox" data-ref-id="4304">  <ul>                              <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/evercade-exp-r-tomb-raider-cartridge-bundle-retro-gaming-amazon-black-friday-deals/1100-6534530/">Evercade Retro Handhelds &amp; Cartridges Get Rare Price Cuts In Amazon's Black Friday Sale</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/kirby-air-riders-nintendo-switch-2-preorder-guide/1100-6534089/">Kirby Air Riders Buying Guide: Release-Day Delivery Still Available At Amazon</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/meta-quest-3s-vr-headset-best-black-friday-deals/1100-6532962/">Meta Quest 3S Black Friday Deal - Save Up To $70 And Get $50 Amazon Credit</a></li>                          <li>         <span>+ Show More More Gaming, Tech, and Entertainment Deals &amp; Preorders Links (5)</span>       </li>          <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-gamecube-third-party-controller-switch-2-pc-amazon-holiday-deal/1100-6532458/">Grab A Wireless GameCube-Style Controller For Switch 1/2 &amp; PC For Only $40</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/lunar-remastered-collection-amazon-exclusive-physical-edition-deal-switch-playstation-xbox/1100-6528818/">Amazon-Exclusive Lunar Remastered Collection Gets First Price Cut</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/final-fantasy-magic-the-gathering-set-deals-restock-preorder-buying-guide/2900-6271/">Final Fantasy Magic: The Gathering Deal - Save $45 On Play Booster Box</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-hunger-games-sunrising-on-the-reaping-gift-edition-book-box-set-deals/1100-6535218/">Sunrise On The Reaping New Collector's Gift Edition Is Already Discounted At Amazon</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/lego-dc-batman-construction-figure-and-bat-pod-bike-the-dark-knight-amazon-deal/1100-6535073/">Lego DC Batman Figure &amp; Bat-Pod Is Over 50% Off At Amazon, Sold Out Everywhere Else</a></li>   </ul> </div>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article>

    
  

        <div>
	<p>
		Latest in
		Dragon Ball Z: Kakarot
	</p>

	
</div>
  
</div>
                      <meta itemprop="seamless-content-list-items" data-list-items="[{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6536120&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/tmnt-splintered-fate-collectors-edition-preorder-gets-early-black-friday-discount\/1100-6536120\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525146&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/arcane-season-2-4k-blu-ray-steelbook-edition-steeply-discounted-for-black-friday\/1100-6525146\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6536295&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/alan-wake-2-deluxe-editions-are-20-off-for-black-friday\/1100-6536295\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6527818&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/wd-black-c50-xbox-series-x-storage-expansion-card-black-friday-2025-deal\/1100-6527818\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6536087&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/logitech-g-astro-a50-x-premium-headset-gets-massive-discount\/1100-6536087\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6532962&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/meta-quest-3s-vr-headset-best-black-friday-deals\/1100-6532962\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6536121&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/pac-man-world-2-re-pac-is-just-20-for-black-friday\/1100-6536121\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6536300&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/new-lord-of-the-rings-the-hobbit-illustrated-box-set-gets-limited-time-price-cut\/1100-6536300\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6536077&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/little-nightmares-3-gets-its-first-big-discount-for-black-friday\/1100-6536077\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6536328&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/poppy-playtime-triple-pack-on-switch-is-at-its-lowest-price-in-30-days\/1100-6536328\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6536317&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/guild-wars-reforged-isnt-quite-a-remaster-of-the-classic-mmo-but-its-close\/1100-6536317\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6536326&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/doom-the-dark-ages-update-makes-its-horde-mode-more-customizable-and-shareable\/1100-6536326\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6536322&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/battlefield-6-california-resistance-update-how-to-unlock-all-new-weapons-and-items\/1100-6536322\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6536320&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/nier-creator-yoko-taro-says-his-games-keep-getting-canceled\/1100-6536320\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6536321&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/eas-f1-series-undergoing-strategic-reset-skipping-2026-release\/1100-6536321\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6536319&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/arc-raiders-devs-last-game-shutting-down-on-one-platform\/1100-6536319\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6536323&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/the-underground-kirby-air-ride-community-finds-new-life\/1100-6536323\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6536337&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/theres-a-free-new-fortnite-skin-you-probably-cant-get\/1100-6536337\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6536343&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/baldurs-gate-3-studio-reacts-to-the-game-awards-nomination-what-the-fk\/1100-6536343\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6536330&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/megabonk-just-withdrew-itself-from-the-game-awards\/1100-6536330\/&quot;}]">
            </div>
              
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/get-dragon-ball-sparking-zero-and-kakarot-daima-edition-for-just-30-each-in-this-black-friday-deal/1100-6535995/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[An Unexpected Developer Is Behind Some Big Free Switch 2 Updates]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/an-unexpected-developer-is-behind-some-big-free-switch-2-updates/1100-6536382/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/an-unexpected-developer-is-behind-some-big-free-switch-2-updates.1359355/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536382">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">Four notable free Switch 2 updates for big-name Nintendo games--such as Super Mario Odyssey--surprisingly came from outside the company. Instead of an internal developer, Panic Button has confirmed working on the following titles for the new hybrid console: Super Mario Bros. U Deluxe, Super Mario 3D World + Bowser's Fury, and Arms.</p><p dir="ltr"><a href="https://x.com/panicbuttongame/status/1991264499676930507?s=46" rel="nofollow ">On X</a>, Panic Button revealed its involvement on <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/all-free-nintendo-switch-2-game-updates-changes/2900-6591/#3">the free Switch 2 updates</a>. "Nintendo asked us to help demonstrate new capabilities of the Nintendo Switch 2 system, while remaining faithful to the original games," the Austin-based developer stated on social media. The improvements included HDR support for Arms, Super Mario Odyssey, and Bowser's Fury. In addition, GameShare support was added to Super Mario Odyssey and Super Mario 3D World + Bowser's Fury.</p><div data-embed-type="tweet" data-src="https://x.com/panicbuttongame/status/1991264499676930507?s=46" data-has-image="true"><blockquote data-conversation="none" data-mce-disable-toolbar="true"><p dir="ltr">Panic Button was honored to be selected by Nintendo to help update marquee games from the Nintendo Switch™ library. Nintendo asked us to help demonstrate new capabilities of the Nintendo Switch 2 system, while remaining faithful to the original games. <a href="https://t.co/5P96V9DFUq" rel="nofollow ">pic.twitter.com/5P96V9DFUq</a></p>  — Panic Button (Official) (@PanicButtonGame) <a href="https://twitter.com/PanicButtonGame/status/1991264499676930507?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 19, 2025</a></blockquote>              </div><p dir="ltr">For those unfamiliar, Panic Button has a well-regarded history of bringing games to Switch platforms. For instance, the team was behind Doom and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/doom-eternal-is-still-coming-to-nintendo-switch/1100-6461091/">Doom Eternal for the original Switch</a>. Panic Button assisted on <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/warframe-out-now-on-nintendo-switch-an-impressive-/1100-6463299/">porting Warframe to Switch</a> as well. Most recently, the developer <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/forza-horizon-5-on-ps5-releases-in-april/1100-6529770/">worked on Forza Horizon 5 for PS5</a>--marking the first time the racing franchise has appeared on a PlayStation platform.</p><p>In other Nintendo-development news, the company actually <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-buys-hogwarts-legacy-mortal-kombat-port-studio-ahead-of-switch-2-launch/1100-6523597/" data-ref-id="1100-6523597">acquired Shiver Entertainment</a>--a studio known for porting games like Hogwarts Legacy to Switch--last year. Shiver reportedly assisted in bringing <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/wwe-2k25-release-date-trailer-news/2900-6171/#2">WWE 2K25</a> to Switch 2. Meanwhile, Panic Button is a private company. Speaking of ports, Switch and Switch 2 just saw the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/tomb-raider-definitive-edition-just-surprise-released-on-switch-and-switch-2/1100-6536324/">surprise release of Tomb Raider: Definitive Edition</a> earlier this week.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/an-unexpected-developer-is-behind-some-big-free-switch-2-updates/1100-6536382/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kill Bill's The Bride Rides Into Fortnite In Chapter 7 Teaser]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/kill-bills-the-bride-rides-into-fortnite-in-chapter-7-teaser/1100-6536383/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/kill-bills-the-bride-rides-into-fortnite-in-chapter-7-teaser.1359352/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536383">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>While Fortnite is currently in the midst of a Springfieldian takeover by The Simpsons, the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fortnite-chapter-7-start-date-new-map-and-everything-we-know-so-far/1100-6536068/" data-ref-id="1100-6536068">next chapter of the battle royale's overarching story</a> will soon be upon us. Epic Games has ramped up the teases for what's to come, including a short trailer featuring a certain yellow-clad bride bent on revenge.</p><p>The trailer shows many of the main collaborations from Chapter 6--Godzilla, Homer Simpson, and the Megazord among them--before The Bride from Kill Bill speeds into the scene to save Jonesy from danger. The teaser then confirms the end-of-Chapter-6 event will take place November 29 at 11 AM PT / 2 PM ET.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Mwh7WFCW3f8" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/Mwh7WFCW3f8" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>Last night, Fortnite took over the Vista Theater in Hollywood, California for a massive Chapter 7 kickoff event for media and influencers that featured even more hints. Logos on decorations around the theater seem to confirm Chapter 7 Season 1's name as Pacific Break, while the DeLorean from Back to the Future also appeared in the theater itself.</p><p>One particularly interesting tidbit involves a poster for <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DRQXUuwgZjX/?utm_source=ig_web_button_share_sheet" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Yuki's Revenge,</a> which appeared on official Fortnite social media accounts. Yuki's Revenge was meant to be a chapter of Kill Bill Volume 1, but it was removed from the final cut before the film released.</p><p>Among those spotted at the Vista included <a href="https://x.com/Fortnite/status/1991320132698927573" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Kill Bill director Quentin Tarantino</a> and star Uma Thurman, and KPop Demon Hunters star Rei Ami--which could lend credence to rumors of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fortnite-might-be-getting-kpop-demon-hunters-jam-tracks-after-all/1100-6536009/" data-ref-id="1100-6536009">more KPop Demon Hunters</a> content coming to the game soon.</p><p>Since the event, leaker ShiinaBR on X has reported multiple new details about the upcoming season, including hot-air balloons, the ability to drive Reboot Vans, and a Marty McFly skin.</p><div data-embed-type="tweet" data-src="https://x.com/ShiinaBR/status/1991464160996344068" data-has-image="true"><blockquote data-conversation="none" data-mce-disable-toolbar="true"><p dir="ltr">LEAKED CHAPTER 7 INFO FROM CREATOR EVENT 💀 <br>- Hot air balloons <br>- Driveable Reboot Vans<br>- Solo VS Bots mode <br>- Rift A Palooza events that spawn rifts<br>- Gameplay UI update<br>- Battle Pass has Marty McFly and The Bride <a href="https://t.co/l9lBrLZMIz" rel="nofollow ">pic.twitter.com/l9lBrLZMIz</a></p>  — Shiina (@ShiinaBR) <a href="https://twitter.com/ShiinaBR/status/1991464160996344068?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 20, 2025</a></blockquote>              </div><p>Fortnite is available now as a free download on Xbox Series X|S, Xbox One, PlayStation 4, PlayStation 5, Nintendo Switch, Nintendo Switch 2, PC, and mobile devices.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/kill-bills-the-bride-rides-into-fortnite-in-chapter-7-teaser/1100-6536383/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[R-Type Delta: HD Boosted Launch Trailer Is An Explosion Of Nostalgia]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/11/r-type-delta-hd-boosted-launch-trailer-is-an-explosion-of-nostalgia</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/r-type-delta-hd-boosted-launch-trailer-is-an-explosion-of-nostalgia.1359334/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Is that... Mr. Biffo?</p>
</section></header><section>

<p>Clear River Games has released <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/r-type_delta_hd_boosted">R-Type Delta: HD Boosted</a> for the Switch, and to celebrate its arrival, a new launch trailer has hit the web, and it's a <em>doozy</em>.</p>
<p>The live-action trailer stars none other than Paul Rose, who served as the editor for <strong>The Digitiser</strong>, a video games magazine for Teletext back in the '90s and early '00s. You might know him best as Mr. Biffo, and his short appearance here is undeniable.</p>
<p>Elsewhere, we've got a small cameo from the <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/8bitdo-arcade-controller-for-switch-plus-switch-2-the-best-way-to-play-street-fighter-6">8BitDo Arcade Stick</a> at the beginning, while the rest is a nostaligia-filled look at the classic R-Type gameplay, remastered for the Switch. It's looking slick with smooth visuals and 60fps gameplay, and we can't wait to dive in.</p>
<p>Let's remind ourselves of the story:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"The year is 2163, and the badly damaged R9 Arrowhead fighter has just returned to Earth after its mission to destroy the Bydo Empire. The vessel is rescued by the battle-cruiser Croque-Monsieur and transported to an orbital space station. One year later, astronomers in Central Asia observe mysterious objects falling from the sky, and moments later, control is lost over the orbiting annihilation platform Moritz-G. This high-tech machine, capable of destroying the entire planet, descends over a city and levels it to the ground. Although its planet-destroying weapons have not yet been activated, its advanced defense systems make Moritz-G virtually impossible to approach. A desperate military operation is launched, and the prototype ship R9aII Delta is deployed to resolve the situation. Thus begins the epic battle that is R-Type Delta!"</p>
</blockquote>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-articles:192302 @ 1763654568 -->
<p><em>Will you be picking up R-Type Delta: HD Boosted for the Switch? What do you make of this launch trailer? Let us know with a comment.</em></p></section></article><div><p>Nintendo Life’s resident horror fanatic, when he’s not knee-deep in Resident Evil and Silent Hill lore, Ollie likes to dive into a good horror book while nursing a lovely cup of tea. He also enjoys long walks and listens to everything from TOOL to Chuck Berry.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Olliemar28"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/ollie-nl.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Olliemar28');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/11/r-type-delta-hd-boosted-launch-trailer-is-an-explosion-of-nostalgia]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Reanimal picks the most horrifying date possible for its February 2026 launch]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/11/20/reanimal-picks-the-most-horrifying-date-possible-for-its-february-2026-launch/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/reanimal-picks-the-most-horrifying-date-possible-for-its-february-2026-launch.1359331/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>THQ Nordic and Tarsier Studios have settled on a release date for their co-op horror platformer, <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/reanimal">Reanimal</a>, settling on Friday, 13th February 2026.</p>
<p>The game is coming from the creators of Little Nightmares I &amp; II, and it sticks with their particular penchant for dark and unsettling imagery and creatures tormenting small people. In this game a brother and sister have to try and go through this hell to rescue missing friends and escape an island they once called home.</p>


<p>Pre-orders are now open across PS5, Xbox Series X|S and PC, and today also sees the release of a demo for the game on consoles (already available on PC) for fans to try out. The co-op demo starts at the beginning of the game, reuniting the protagonists and presenting you early environments at the Mill and the Trainyard to play through.</p>
<p>The demo is also coming to Switch 2 at a later date, and pre-orders for Nintendo’s handheld will be on hold until then.</p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/2129530/view/613180506112000708?l=english">Steam</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/11/20/reanimal-picks-the-most-horrifying-date-possible-for-its-february-2026-launch/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battlefield 6 and Pokémon Legends Z-A Top US Sales Charts for October 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/battlefield-6-pokemon-legends-z-a-tops-us-sales-charts-october-2025/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/battlefield-6-and-pok%C3%A9mon-legends-z-a-top-us-sales-charts-for-october-2025.1359328/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>Circana executive director and video game industry analyst Mat Piscatella has released the latest monthly charts for US video game sales for October 2025, and the two games at the top of the charts are the two games you would have expected to be there: Battlefield 6 and Pokémon Legends Z-A.</p>



<p>Those were the top two games, with <a href="https://wccftech.com/tag/battlefield-6/">Battlefield 6</a> in first place and Pokémon Legends Z-A in second, though it's worth remembering that Nintendo doesn't share its digital sales data with any of the big analytics firms, Circana included, which means that on physical sales alone, it had a stronger month than 18 other games, some of them new releases, some of them sales-charts-topping regulars like EA Sports FC 26 and NBA 2K26.</p>



<p>It also could mean that, were digital sales properly included, Pokémon Legends Z-A might have been listed as the actual best-selling premium game in the US for October 2025. But we can't know its digital sales, so that crown goes to Battlefield 6.</p>







<p>Number one on the sales charts for the month of October in the US isn't the only crown Battlefield 6 is walking away with, as it also launched right to the top of the list for best-selling premium games in the US in 2025 so far.</p>



<p>According to Piscatella, not only did Battlefield 6 become the best-selling game in the US in 2025 so far, it also "<em>produced the highest single month US physical and digital full game tracked dollar sales total in three years. The last title to generate a larger full game tracked dollar sales total in a single month was Call of Duty: Modern Warfare II in October 2022</em>."</p>







<p>It's all coming up roses for Battlefield 6 on the commercial front, but it's one month away from perhaps the biggest victory it could hope for, which would be maintaining its top spot over Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 when the November 2025 sales numbers are in.</p>



<p>Of course, we'll have to wait a while for those numbers, but for now, Battlefield 6 can bask in its top spot for the month, for the year, and in the history of the franchise. Also, it's worth noting that while Battlefield 6 may be the best-selling game in the US in 2025 so far, when it comes to exclusively physical sales, the best-selling game in the US so far is Pokémon Legends Z-A.</p>



<p>Other notable elements of the list include <a href="https://wccftech.com/borderlands-4-tops-us-sales-charts-ghost-of-yotei-matched-tsushima-covid-era-numbers/">September 2025's best-selling game in the US</a> dropping all the way to the tenth best-selling game, with Borderlands 4 going from the top spot to halfway down the top-20 list.</p>



<p>The Outer Worlds 2 was also able to squeeze into the top-10 in seventh place, just ahead of another new release, Little Nightmares III, which made the list in eighth place. Ninja Gaiden 4, another big new release for October 2025, made the top-20 list, but not the top-10, as it fell just outside the top-10 in eleventh place. </p>



<p>On the hardware side of things, the Nintendo Switch 2 continues to be the best-selling console, though what's more impressive is how far ahead it is compared to Nintendo Switch sales for the same time period of its launch year. "<em>It is 68% ahead of the sales pace set by the original Nintendo Switch and is 3% ahead of PlayStation 4's previous record velocity</em>," writes Piscatella.</p>



<p>Another notable hardware tidbit is that spending on ASUS PC portable hardware saw a 4.8x spike led by he release of the ASUS ROG Xbox Ally and ROG Xbox Ally X. You can find out more about both devices in <a href="https://wccftech.com/asus-talks-rog-xbox-ally-and-rog-xbox-ally-x-this-is-the-way-forward-for-us/">my interview with ASUS executives last month,</a> and <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/asus-rog-xbox-ally-x-this-is-an-xbox/">in my review of the ROG Xbox Ally X</a>.</p>



<p>Overall, October 2025 was a strong month for video game sales in the US. It saw a 3% growth over October 2024, and included a couple of the year's best-selling games so far. However, the real bout of the year for US sales is currently happening right now, between Call of Duty and Battlefield, with both games officially out and available for players to buy. We'll see which game ends up at the top of the charts for November 2025.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/battlefield-6-pokemon-legends-z-a-tops-us-sales-charts-october-2025/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[AMD Is Powering Every Next-Gen Console And Its GPUs Are About To Get Even More Expensive]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/amd-gpu-prices-radeon-ps5-xbox-steam-machine-2000645803</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/amd-is-powering-every-next-gen-console-and-its-gpus-are-about-to-get-even-more-expensive.1359319/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Fans of AMD’s GPUs, which are typically more cost-effective than those made by Nvidia, might be in for some sticker shock in the near future. Team Red is likely to start raising the price of its goods. And unfortunately, there’s a chance this will affect more than just your graphics card.</p> <p>As <a href="https://videocardz.com/newz/amd-rumored-to-raise-gpu-prices-just-as-radeon-rx-9070-xt-finally-reaches-msrp">reported by <i>VideoCardz</i></a>, AMD has informed its partners of an impending price hike for its GPUs. Last month the company reportedly adjusted prices for its corporate partners to reflect changes in the market, though it managed to save retail customers from the shift. This time around, however, retail prices are likely to get hit. The culprit? Well, if you’ve been paying attention to the price fluctuations of computer components, you may already know: the cost of DRAM components, which provide the memory for computers and other electronics, is going up as <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/samsung-hikes-memory-chip-prices-by-up-60-shortage-worsens-sources-say-2025-11-14/">the AI industry</a> <a href="https://youtu.be/wM8LDVIiwhA">wolfs down</a> the earth.</p>

 <p>And if you’re familiar with what goes inside consoles like the PS5 and Xbox Series machines, or even the upcoming Steam Machine, then you know AMD chips power those too.</p> <p>Retail prices haven’t gone up just yet, but the prospect is frustrating.Sure, PC gaming has always been more expensive than just grabbing the latest Sony/Microsoft/Nintendo box and plugging it in, but it’s continued to get worse. And given the central role AMD plays in all of these devices, PC gamers aren’t the only ones likely to get a haircut.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/amd-gpu-prices-radeon-ps5-xbox-steam-machine-2000645803]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Damn, Pokémon Fans Really Don’t Like This Digimon-Ass Mega Evolution]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/pokemon-legends-z-a-mega-zeraora-reaction-industry-plant-2000645789</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/damn-pok%C3%A9mon-fans-really-don%E2%80%99t-like-this-digimon-ass-mega-evolution.1359316/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><span>Yesterday, Game Freak announced </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-legends-za-mega-dimension-zeraora-trailer-reveal-2000645432"><span>Mega Zeraora</span></a><span> will be one of the new Mega Evolutions coming in </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-legends-za-review-switch-2-bugs-performance-2000637719"><i><span>Pokémon Legends: Z-A</span></i><span>’s</span></a> <i><span>Mega Dimension </span></i><span>DLC. It’s one of the few “cool” Mega designs in the RPG, which has otherwise leaned pretty heavily into silly and exaggerated designs with monsters like </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-legends-za-mega-starmie-jokes-memes-videos-art-2000638556"><span>Starmie</span></a><span> and </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-legends-za-mega-feraligatr-totodile-art-redesign-2000645515"><span>Feraligatr</span></a><span>. I like a silly Mega as much as the next guy, but it’s nice to have some that don’t look like jokes, as well. Mega Zeraora, however, is proving surprisingly divisive among Pokémon fans, and those who already had problems with Zeraora’s original art aren’t holding back.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><span>Zeraora is a mythical Pokémon from Generation VII. It debuted in </span><i><span>Ultra Sun </span></i><span>and </span><i><span>Ultra Moon</span></i><span> as an event-exclusive monster, which means if you didn’t catch it on the 3DS games back in 2018, it’s been mostly unobtainable since. There was a brief window in 2020 where a shiny version was catchable through a </span><i><span>Pokémon Home </span></i><span>event, but </span><i><span>Legends: Z-A </span></i><span>is the first time Zeraora has left the vault in five years. That’s usually how mythical Pokémon go, so it’s not that different from Pokémon like Mew or Celebi, who set the precedent for mythicals to only be available for a limited time.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <p><span>For a Pokémon that isn’t in that many games, you’d think fans wouldn’t hold as much hate in their heart as they do for Zeraora, but folks are dogpiling on its Mega for looking mostly like a recolored fighting game skin and having “zero aura.” Get it? Because its name is Zeraora?</span></p>

 <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">The 7 Levels Of Industry Plants! It All Comes Together! <a href="https://t.co/G75CIKPuVK">https://t.co/G75CIKPuVK</a> <a href="https://t.co/tQ5QQLhrTl">pic.twitter.com/tQ5QQLhrTl</a></p> <p>— ◓ (@KuroBlitz96) <a href="https://twitter.com/KuroBlitz96/status/1991149656978411637?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 19, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">Needed to Mega evolve just to take on Some zubats, haunters, and scolipedes. This is the most homeless bum ass sonic for hire mythical we've ever had in Pokemon <a href="https://t.co/JToT0j45LW">https://t.co/JToT0j45LW</a></p> <p>— Niggapokemon333 (@willsgardevoir) <a href="https://twitter.com/willsgardevoir/status/1991167378999353719?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 19, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">BEHOLD THE MEGA INDUSTRY PLANTINITE <a href="https://t.co/Mi9dUWxFAk">https://t.co/Mi9dUWxFAk</a> <a href="https://t.co/DnPz7sq76l">pic.twitter.com/DnPz7sq76l</a></p> <p>— Lewtwo (@Lewchube) <a href="https://twitter.com/Lewchube/status/1991148114640597110?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 19, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">UnovaGPT 🇺🇸 please 🙏 generate me an alolan mega that undella town fans will love to use on their overlevelled legendary-only team 🖥️ BZZT BZZT 🤖 Your next mega will be called “Zeraora” <a href="https://t.co/4XcbiKp3SB">https://t.co/4XcbiKp3SB</a></p> <p>— Cheese (@Cheese_Mans) <a href="https://twitter.com/Cheese_Mans/status/1991185675211743361?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 19, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">If someone showed me this and asked me to guess what game it’s from, I’d have said Palworld. <a href="https://t.co/nfDpomFYiY">https://t.co/nfDpomFYiY</a></p> <p>— DistantCoder (@TheDistantCoder) <a href="https://twitter.com/TheDistantCoder/status/1991152463391432958?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 19, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">It really is Zero Aura <a href="https://t.co/ccnkR6Fwi5">https://t.co/ccnkR6Fwi5</a></p> <p>— CEO of Lilligants (@j_stocky) <a href="https://twitter.com/j_stocky/status/1991242987771445379?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 19, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">Everyone with pokemon trying to push the zeraora agenda again: <a href="https://t.co/qtzXjxT83i">pic.twitter.com/qtzXjxT83i</a></p> <p>— VCreateArt (COMMS CLOSED): (@VCreateArt) <a href="https://twitter.com/VCreateArt/status/1991207212644028855?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 19, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">this is a smash bros alt color <a href="https://t.co/WvZWbJ84M3">https://t.co/WvZWbJ84M3</a></p> <p>— Aurora 🐊 (@SpectralAurora_) <a href="https://twitter.com/SpectralAurora_/status/1991149652326994298?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 19, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">let’s not get it twisted tho guys greninja is still by far the biggest industry plant in the series<br>zeraora may be a failed industry plant but greninja succeeded and most of u fell for the trap (myself included)</p> <p>— edith . 🏳️‍⚧️👹👻🎃 (@ruggyscruggy) <a href="https://twitter.com/ruggyscruggy/status/1991290440599867507?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 19, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">abysmal dogshit has become even more abysmally dogshit. truely incredible how little I care about this pokemon <a href="https://t.co/axUCSFgJjw">pic.twitter.com/axUCSFgJjw</a></p> <p>— scepticskeptic 🕷️| comms closed 🇵🇸 (@Scepticskeptic1) <a href="https://twitter.com/Scepticskeptic1/status/1991147763795468777?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 19, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">???: I have a mission for you, Zeraora.</p> <p>Mega Zeraora: What is it, Father? </p> <p>???: Generate fake hype. Make the public think you're a future goat before sending yourself straight to the low tiers.</p> <p>*the mon steps out of the shadows*</p> <p>Electivire: Do not disappoint me… son. <a href="https://t.co/dxTMZrDwna">pic.twitter.com/dxTMZrDwna</a></p> <p>— Sarin (@ToxicWeave) <a href="https://twitter.com/ToxicWeave/status/1991291738044952681?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 19, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">Honestly, it's not that it's ugly or poorly designed; technically, it's “cool,” but it has nothing else going for it. It simply exists, and that's it. It leaves me completely indifferent. <a href="https://t.co/rCRujWwc3v">https://t.co/rCRujWwc3v</a></p> <p>— Gaegral (@Gagaegral) <a href="https://twitter.com/Gagaegral/status/1991195613275312406?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 19, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">I think calling Mega Zeroara “zero aura” might be the most scalding thing ive seen someone say about a Pokemon design</p> <p>— artsyRC😴 (@rceezus) <a href="https://twitter.com/rceezus/status/1991344913204801912?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 20, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">They saying this like I’ll have any intention of finding one✌️😂 <a href="https://t.co/Jw7maPijKd">https://t.co/Jw7maPijKd</a></p> <p>— DanDaDanchie (@DNCHI77) <a href="https://twitter.com/DNCHI77/status/1991152465958289766?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 19, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">I really really dislike the sentiment of “industry plants” or purposely designing Pokemon to make it “popular”.</p> <p>That being said, Zeraora is the most blatant example of an “industry plant” to ever exist. <a href="https://t.co/yLbUWoQ6eL">https://t.co/yLbUWoQ6eL</a></p> <p>— 🐍Sneksnack⭐ (@Snek_Snack) <a href="https://twitter.com/Snek_Snack/status/1991250162719596644?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 19, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="zxx" dir="ltr"><a href="https://t.co/6BF13WDlLi">pic.twitter.com/6BF13WDlLi</a></p> <p>— Golurk (@Smogolem) <a href="https://twitter.com/Smogolem/status/1991180906627829940?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 19, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <p><span>While Zeraora has been missing from the mainline games, the furry bait cat has been featured pretty heavily in other </span><i><span>Pokémon </span></i><span>games and media, like being a playable character in the </span><i><span>Pokémon Unite</span></i><span> MOBA and having a starring role in the </span><i><span>Power of Us </span></i><span>movie. It definitely feels like The Pokémon Company wants to make Zeraora “happen” with its “cool” design and frequent features, leading some fans to accuse it of being an “industry plant.”&nbsp;</span></p>

 <p><span>This title has been given to several Pokémon over the years when they are featured heavily in marketing or “shoehorned” into projects like the anime and games. However, Zeraora is arguably one of The Pokémon Company’s least successful attempts to astroturf a Pokémon to popularity, as evidenced by how people are looking at Mega Zeraora’s design with the same exasperation you feel towards someone who keeps showing up to your parties uninvited.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><span>Personally, I have never had big feelings for Zeraora one way or the other, and though I’m glad to see a more serious Mega design, I’m not won over by its Mega Evolution. It will be interesting to see if some people latch onto it when this new form debuts in </span><i><span>Legends: Z-A</span></i><span>’s </span><i><span>Mega Dimension </span></i><span>DLC when it launches on December 10.</span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/pokemon-legends-z-a-mega-zeraora-reaction-industry-plant-2000645789]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>