<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 19:36:41 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Friendly Neighborhood Spider-Man Actor Was Relieved It's Not 'Annoying And Woke']]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/spider-man-disney-woke-osborne-friendly-neighborhood-1851749480</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/friendly-neighborhood-spider-man-actor-was-relieved-its-not-annoying-and-woke.1094085/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/spider-man-disney-woke-osborne-friendly-neighborhood-1851749480<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/your-friendly-neighborhood-spider-man-season-2-season-3-1851748696&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/your-friendly-neighborhood-spider-man-season-2-season-3-1851748696"><em>Your Friendly Neighborhood Spider-Man</em></a></span> is an animated remix paying tribute to the character’s 1960s comic book roots. It takes the character back to a high school setting in a modern age but an alternate universe from that in the MCU. Voice actor Hudson Thames is reprising his role as Spidey from Marvel’s popular <em>What If ... ?</em> series and recently shared one of his favorite things about the new show. Namely that it’s not “annoying and woke.” </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196032" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Kotaku Unboxes The Spider-Man 2 Limited Edition PS5" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="270" data-playlist="196032,195896,195859" data-current="196032"><div><p>Kotaku Unboxes The Spider-Man 2 Limited Edition PS5</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196032/196032_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196032/196032_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196032/196032_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196032/196032_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21556.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>The character was originally supposed to be played by Tom Holland back when it was a tie-in for Marvel’s MCU <em>Spider-Man </em>movies, but the project eventually transformed into something separate. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/spiderman-disney-animated-cartoon-trailer-date-suit-1851730014&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/spiderman-disney-animated-cartoon-trailer-date-suit-1851730014"><em>Your Friendly Neighborhood Spider-Man</em>’s first trailer</a></span> showed Norman Osborn mentoring Peter Parker instead of Iron Man, as well as the tech CEO gifting him the white and black variant suit from the <em>Fantastic Four</em>. The show begins streaming on Disney+ on January 29. </p><p>  “I thought it was awesome,” Thames <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://collider.com/your-friendly-neighborhood-spider-man-star-woke-concerns-hudson-thames/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://collider.com/your-friendly-neighborhood-spider-man-star-woke-concerns-hudson-thames/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">told <em>Collider</em></a></span> in a new interview regarding the show’s re-envisioning of the comic book character. “I mean, my biggest fear was that it was gonna be annoying and woke, and it wasn’t, and I was like, ‘Yes, this is great, it’s so well written,’ like it feels real. I’m the oldest of five boys, so I feel like I kind of know what’s happening in their lives and in high school, and it felt like it was doing that justice.”</p><p>It’s not clear what Thames meant when raising the specter of a possible “woke” version of <em>Your Friendly Neighborhood Spider-Man</em>, and the partial transcript by<em> Collider </em>didn’t immediately include further context, or its interviewer’s response to the MAGA-pilled answer. “Woke” has become a catch-all phrase in recent years, usually deployed online to denigrate anything that doesn’t make white men the center of the universe. </p><p>One of the updates featured in <em>Your Friendly Neighborhood Spider-Man </em>is a Black Norman Osborn, played by Colman Domingo. It <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/Spiderman/comments/1hswaem/the_norman_and_harry_race_swap_controversy_is/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Spiderman/comments/1hswaem/the_norman_and_harry_race_swap_controversy_is/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">reignited debates</a></span> among fans about race-swapping existing characters vs. creating new ones. But as showrunner Jeff Trammell recently pointed out, the Osborn in <em>Your Friendly Neighborhood Spider-Man </em>is subverting expectations in larger ways.</p><p> “I remember watching <em>Spectacular Spider-Man</em>, and when you find out Norman is the Goblin, I was like, ‘Oh, I didn’t expect it,’ because they do such a good job of making me not think that he’s the Goblin, even though I <em>know</em> he’s the Goblin,” Trammell <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.gamesradar.com/entertainment/marvel-tv-shows/your-friendly-neighborhood-spider-man-showrunner-says-he-wanted-to-subvert-fan-expectations-by-having-a-new-take-on-classic-marvel-villain-norman-osborn/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.gamesradar.com/entertainment/marvel-tv-shows/your-friendly-neighborhood-spider-man-showrunner-says-he-wanted-to-subvert-fan-expectations-by-having-a-new-take-on-classic-marvel-villain-norman-osborn/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">told<em> Gamesradar</em></a></span>. “That was a really big inspiration for this Norman, as well as just, you know, keep you on your toes a bit, let you meet this guy, and see if he can win you over the same way he’s managed to do everyone.” </p><p>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[When Is Nintendo’s Next Earnings Report? Date, Time, and What To Expect]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/when-is-nintendos-next-earnings-report-date-time-and-what-to-expect/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/when-is-nintendo%E2%80%99s-next-earnings-report-date-time-and-what-to-expect.1094082/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/when-is-nintendos-next-earnings-report-date-time-and-what-to-expect/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Nintendo remains one of the largest and most popular gaming companies in the world. Known for its Mario, Legend of Zelda, and Pokémon franchises, Nintendo has become a household name over the last 40+ years. That’s why Nintendo’s quarterly earnings reports are closely watched by analysts, investors, and consumers alike.</p>



<p>It’s important to know when the next earnings report is, what time it starts, and how you can follow it live. These quarterly updates provide insights into Nintendo’s financial health, performance from its hardware and games, and general outlooks for the months ahead.</p>



<p>What is Nintendo’s current focus on the heels of recent game releases and the Nintendo Switch 2 announcement? Are there any concerns to address? All that gets answered with each call.</p>



<h2 id="h-when-is-the-next-nintendo-earnings-report-date">When Is The Next Nintendo Earnings Report Date?</h2>



<p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tag/nintendo/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Nintendo</a> is currently scheduled to deliver its third quarter (Q3) earnings for fiscal year (FY) 2025 on Tuesday, February 4.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As to why the company is releasing its third quarter earnings in February, Nintendo’s fiscal calendar runs from April 1-March 31. Their third quarter runs from October 1-December 31, meaning the latest call will include information from the holiday sales season.</p>



<p>The company’s quarters are structured as follows:</p>



<ul>
<li>Q1: April 1 – June 30</li>



<li>Q2: July 1 – September 30</li>



<li>Q3: October 1 – December 31</li>



<li>Q4: January 1 – March 31</li>
</ul>



<h2 id="h-next-nintendo-earnings-report-start-time">Next Nintendo Earnings Report Start Time</h2>



<p>The next Nintendo earnings report is scheduled to start after trading closes in Japan on February 4, 2025. For those in the United States, that would put it somewhere between 2am and 5am ET.</p>



<h2 id="h-how-to-access-to-nintendo-s-earnings-report">How To Access To Nintendo’s Earnings Report?</h2>



<p>If you want to read Nintendo’s quarterly earnings report, you can do so via the company’s website. You have to simply do the following:</p>



<ol>
<li>Go to Nintendo’s <a href="https://www.nintendo.co.jp/ir/en/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Investor Relations page</a></li>



<li>Under “What’s New” there will be the option to select the “Nine Months Financial Results…” from the list. There will be options to view presentation material and view the Q&amp;A summary. Just select which material you want to view.</li>
</ol>



<h2 id="h-what-to-expect-from-nintendo">What To Expect From Nintendo</h2>



<p>In its upcoming earnings call, Nintendo is likely to mention the Nintendo Switch 2, which was revealed in January. The call comes before the full Nintendo Direct presentation for the new console, so specific information on the system might be scarce. We’re also likely to get updates on Nintendo game sales totals for titles like Mario Kart 8 Deluxe, Super Mario Party Jamboree, and more. Lastly, Nintendo will give an updated forecast for its year-end and fourth quarter financials.</p>



<h2 id="h-the-last-nintendo-earnings-report">The Last Nintendo Earnings Report</h2>



<p>When Nintendo last reported its quarterly earnings, it announced that the Nintendo Switch had sold 146.04 million units in its lifespan. It was also revealed, however, that general revenue was down to $1.82 billion year-over-year, marking a a 19.8% decline. Regarding its games, The Legend of Zelda: Echoes of Wisdom sold 2.58 million copies in just four days of sales while Luigi’s Mansion 2 HD sold 1.57 million copies during the quarter.</p>



<h2 id="h-what-are-earnings-calls">What Are Earnings Calls?</h2>



<p>Quarterly earnings calls are meetings held publicly traded companies to provide updates on their overall financial performance. Typically, these calls are open to shareholders, analysts, and media to call in and ask questions. The public, regardless if they’re a shareholder or not, is also able to listen to these calls live as they happen.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Alongside the calls themselves, companies will often put out a press release and presentation with important details included ahead of the call taking place. This allows investors, analysts, and media to prepare coverage or questions based on the information provided.</p>



<p>If you want to know more about upcoming earnings calls for various gaming and technology companies are, visit our <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tag/earnings-reports/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">earnings report hub.</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[One Of WoW's Most Famous Pieces Of Cut Content Is Playable Today]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/one-of-wow-most-famous-pieces-of-cut-content-is-playable-today/1100-6529076/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/one-of-wows-most-famous-pieces-of-cut-content-is-playable-today.1094079/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/one-of-wow-most-famous-pieces-of-cut-content-is-playable-today/1100-6529076/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529076">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>One of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/world-of-warcraft/" data-ref-id="5000-3919">World of Warcraft's</a> most famous pieces of cut content, the Karazhan Crypts, is finally playable today as dungeon. The new piece of endgame content is part of WoW's more experimental <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/wow-classic-season-of-discovery-looks-to-make-a-20-year-old-game-surprising-again/1100-6519561/" data-ref-id="1100-6519561">Season of Discovery</a> servers. </p><p dir="ltr">WoW is filled with unused areas or places that were never fully fleshed out, and vanilla WoW's Karazhan Crypts are one of them. It's a dark, moody area below the tower of Karazhan (which itself wouldn't actually become a raid until the game's first expansion) in the original version of WoW that has long captured the imagination of players. Now, as part of a new content phase for WoW Classic's current seasonal servers, the Karazhan Crypts have been transformed into a five-man dungeon for players to explore.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rLT6rP4L-Pc" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/rLT6rP4L-Pc" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p dir="ltr">As detailed by WoW Youtuber <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rLT6rP4L-Pc" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">WillIE</a> (in partnership with Blizzard), the dungeon itself is unlike others players may be used to. Inspired by classic dungeon-crawling RPGs, the Karazhan Crypts are shrouded in a darkness that can only be dispelled with a magical torch. There's no mini-map to rely on, so players will need to stick together as they explore the dark reaches of the crypt and encounter new horrors. In keeping with the "discovery" aspect of the season, players will want to keep an eye out for secrets inside the dungeon that may aid their adventuring party.</p><p dir="ltr">It's a dungeon designed for players who have already acquired some endgame gear, and the new loot found within the crypts will be comparable to gear earned from raids like Blackwing Lair and the Temple of Ahn' Qiraj. Because of how powerful the gear found in the dungeon is, the Karazhan Crypts will be on a 24-hour lockout, allowing players to run it once per day.</p><p dir="ltr">Blizzard originally teased the addition of the Karazhan Crypts back when Season of Discovery was first announced at BlizzCon 2023. However, it's not the first new dungeon added to vanilla WoW as part of the season. Blizzard previously added Demon Fall Canyon, another mostly unused area of the game's world, as a dungeon--one where players face off against the phantom of Grommash Hellscream himself.</p><p dir="ltr">In addition to the new dungeon, Season of Discovery's new content phase additionally revamps its infamous Naxxramas raid. Blizzard is already teasing another new piece of endgame content as well in the form of what looks to be a Scarlet Crusade-themed raid, though players will have to wait for more details.</p><p dir="ltr">As for the modern version of WoW, its next big <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/wow-the-war-within-next-major-update-is-going-full-goblin-mode/1100-6527723/" data-ref-id="1100-6527723">update will be focused on the goblins of Undermine</a>, all while Blizzard works on the new <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/after-20-long-years-wow-is-getting-player-housing-in-its-midnight-expansion/1100-6527718/" data-ref-id="1100-6527718">player housing feature</a> announced to be coming as part of the game's next expansion.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[It looks like someone at Activision is leaking Slack screenshots to right-wing X users]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/it-looks-like-someone-at-activision-is-leaking-slack-screenshots-to-right-wing-x-users</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/it-looks-like-someone-at-activision-is-leaking-slack-screenshots-to-right-wing-x-users.1094076/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/it-looks-like-someone-at-activision-is-leaking-slack-screenshots-to-right-wing-x-users<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="captioned-content" data-testid="featured-image"><p><span>Image via Activision/Microsoft.</span></p></div><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Activision Blizzard employees are facing increased harassment on X (formerly Twitter) and YouTube following the distribution of what appear to be leaked internal messages between employees discussing the state of diversity, equity, and inclusion (DEI) programs at the company.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The messages—which appear to have been sent via Slack, a communications tool used at Activision Blizzard—have been directly posted by far-right users attacking the company for continuing to support diversity in the workplace. It appears someone with access to Activision's Slack channel is sending screenshots and photos of these messages directly to these users.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Activision Senior QA tester Sam Hudson appeared to confirm the ongoing harassment in a post on LinkedIn on January 25 and stated several of their colleagues had been "doxxed."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"This employee took screenshots of ABK wide discussions about the safety of our protected information (like name changes and visa statuses) and sent them to an an extremely racist, sexist, and transphobic individual on Twitter who has over a 100 thousand followers," they added.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"It is even more dangerous to be trans or an immigrant at Activision now apparently, as someone who works with us has no problems doxxing people."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer reviewed the leaked message and identified the names of several current employees of Activision and its subsidiaries.</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/mad-mushroom-cofounder-asmongold-to-step-away-from-company-after-islamophobic-remarks" target="_self" data-discover="true">Mad Mushroom cofounder Asmongold to 'step away' from company after anti-Muslim remarks</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">These leaks raise questions about what Activision is doing to protect its employees, and what action it will take against the person or persons who shared the screenshots if they work for the company. The company's </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="http://chrome-extension//efaidnbmnnnibpcajpcglclefindmkaj/https://www.activision.com/cdn/documents/Activision-The-Rundown2.0-External.pdf">publicly-posted diversity policy</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> promises it will create "safe spaces to build community" at the studio. The continued leaking of employee messages raises concerns over if that promise is being kept.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The first of these screenshots </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://x.com/YellowFlashGuy/status/1881502180504641998">appeared</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> on January 20, around the time of President Donald Trump's inauguration, and reference his presidency as a point of concern over policies and software choices at the company. The first leaked messages shows an employee raising concerns over the security of an HR platform called "Workforce," indicating it may be vulnerable to leaks and exposing the names of transgender employees who have filed for name changes during their time at Activision.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Twitter account "YellowFlashGuy" shared several messages over the next 24 hours, including one where employees realized their messages were being leaked to X, and were asking Activision what it was doing to protect their security. The names and profile pictures of Activision employees were on display in the shared messages.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">On January 27, user Mark Kern (</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/mark-kern-reportedly-fired-from-his-job-as-ceo-of-red-5-studios">formerly CEO of Red 5 Studios</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">) got in on the action, showing a photograph of a Slack message from Activision president Rob Kostich telling employees the company would be continuing the DEI policies run by the Inclusive Growth team. In follow-up posts, he singled out a technical artist at the company for posts they had liked on Facebook and called for veterans groups to cut ties with Activision over these policies.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Other far-right users on X and YouTube have circulated these screenshots, ridiculing the employees and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://youtu.be/C1O5fM1pSqg?si=ivRMgWwlub7u2922">encouraging others to join in</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Online harassment campaigns continue to target developers in 2025">Online harassment campaigns continue to target developers in 2025</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game developers have endured a resurgent right-wing harassment campaign lashing out over the depiction of underrepresented characters in games since early 2024. Around that time, content creators and Steam users in the far-right ecosystem began a campaign targeting work-for-hire game narrative studio </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/why-are-valve-and-discord-permitting-harassment-against-sweet-baby-inc-">Sweet Baby Inc.</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, accusing it of attempting to impose a censorious agenda on its clients, including Insomniac Games, Remedy Entertainment, and Rocksteady. Some employees of these companies faced additional harassment after speaking up in support of their collaborators.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">In the wake of this campaign and other events, organizations like </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.takethis.org/mental-health-resources/">Take This</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://gameshotline.org/">Games And Harassment Hotline</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> assembled lists of resources for developers targeted by online harassment.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">One such creator was streamer and Mad Mushroom </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/mad-mushroom-explains-what-devs-might-expect-from-a-streamer-owned-publisher">cofounder</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> "Asmongold," who repeatedly discussed the campaign in a number of 2024 videos, agreeing with the claims against Sweet Baby Inc. Asmongold "</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/mad-mushroom-cofounder-asmongold-to-step-away-from-company-after-islamophobic-remarks">stepped down</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">" from Mad Mushroom and other businesses he co-founded under </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://otknetwork.com/pages/creators">One True King,</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> an influencer network he cofounded with a number of other streamers and YouTubers. This followed a series of anti-Muslim remarks during a Twitch stream that led to him being temporarily banned from the platform.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">At GDC that year, online extremism researcher Dr. Rachel Kowert </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/production/silence-from-sony-remedy-other-studios-could-worsen-harassment-campaign">explained to Game Developer</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> that this harassment was likely to continue if major companies like Sony, Remedy, etc. didn't publicly speak up against it. "The problem is that when leadership is not speaking up, it sets and reinforces cultural norms," she said.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Her words are given new weight following the inauguration of President Trump, who has issued </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/2025/01/ending-radical-and-wasteful-government-dei-programs-and-preferencing/">executive orders</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> ending DEI programs at government agencies.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">For now, Activision employees are left with a message from company leadership saying it will continue to support its inclusion efforts. But they do not appear to be safe from individuals eager to end expanding inclusivity in the game development community.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer has reached out to Activision Blizzard and parent company Microsoft for comment on this story and will update it when a response is issued.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Game Developer and GDC are sibling organizations under Informa</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Senior Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Bryant Francis is a writer, journalist, and narrative designer based in Boston, MA. He currently writes for Game Developer, a leading B2B publication for the video game industry. His credits include Proxy Studios' upcoming 4X strategy game Zephon and Amplitude Studio's 2017 game Endless Space 2.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Baldur's Gate 3's Patch 8 adds long-awaited split-screen co-op for Xbox Series S]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/baldurs-gate-3s-patch-8-adds-long-awaited-split-screen-co-op-for-xbox-series-s</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/baldurs-gate-3s-patch-8-adds-long-awaited-split-screen-co-op-for-xbox-series-s.1094073/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/baldurs-gate-3s-patch-8-adds-long-awaited-split-screen-co-op-for-xbox-series-s<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div>
        

        <p>As its stress test gets underway.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/bg3-split.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Larian Studios/Eurogamer</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Following a bit of a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/baldurs-gate-3s-eagerly-awaited-patch-8-out-now-on-ps5-but-larian-says-it-shouldnt-be">false start</a> yesterday, <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/baldurs-gate-3-a-critical-success-with-critical-failures">Baldur's Gate 3</a>'s Patch 8 stress test is now officially underway on Xbox Series X/S, PS5, and PC, giving select participants the opportunity to explore a range of new features ahead of its full release - with split-screen co-op support for Xbox Series S being the surprise (and long-awaited) inclusion.
</p>
<p>
Developer Larian <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/baldurs-gate-3-is-getting-new-subclasses-cross-play-and-more-next-year">detailed Baldur's Gate 3's Patch 8</a> back in November, promising 12 new sub-classes, cross-play, new camera features, and more. At the time, it revealed it would holding a closed stress test ahead of a full launch - in order to help it "catch things before they can become an issue" - with registrations having been open since then.
</p>
<p>
And now, the first wave of invites has gone out to successful applicants, and Patch 8's stress test is live. Larian covers some key details relating to the release in an <a href="https://baldursgate3.game/news/community-update-33-patch-8-stress-test-now-live_134">accompanying blog post</a>, providing notes on the use of mods during cross-play, as well as instructions on requesting additional keys for participants wishing to explore cross-play with friends not yet in the test.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="How to Get Started With Cross-Play" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/qX4ffv7xLsI?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>How to Get Started With Cross-Play</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/qX4ffv7xLsI?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/qX4ffv7xLsI?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Here's how to get cross-play up and running in Patch 8.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qX4ffv7xLsI" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
The big surprise, though, is confirmation that Patch 8 will also finally introduce split-screen co-op to Xbox Series S after an extremely long wait. The feature has proven to be a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/split-screen-is-a-must-for-baldurs-gate-3-on-xbox-series-s-says-larian">bit of a headache</a> for Larian, and was initially blamed for Baldur's Gate 3's delayed release on Xbox back in 2023, as the studio struggled to optimise it sufficiently for Microsoft's lower-spec console. In the end, Series S split-screen was <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/larian-drops-series-s-split-screen-as-solution-to-bring-baldurs-gate-3-to-xbox-this-year">dropped completely</a> and wasn't included when the game finally launched for Xbox Series X/S in December 2023.
</p><p>
And it seemed like that was that. But now - more than 12 months later - Larian has confirmed the feature has made the cut for Patch 8, meaning it's just squeaked into Baldur's Gate 3's very last content update. There's not much more to report on its inclusion, however, with Larian simply noting stress test participants on Xbox can try it out early starting today.
</p>
<p>
Larian hasn't yet said how long it expects the stress test to last before Patch 8's full release, but Baldur's Gate 3 players eager to get involved can <a href="https://larian.com/stress-test-register">still register their interest</a> on its website.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Perfect Video Game Run Won’t Solve My Problems]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/long-dark-dlc-perfect</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-perfect-video-game-run-won%E2%80%99t-solve-my-problems.1094067/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://aftermath.site/long-dark-dlc-perfect<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>In the Aftermath newsletter last week, I wrote about the tragic end of a recent run I was on in <em>The Long Dark</em>, my favorite survival game. I almost immediately started a new run, determined to do everything better–no, <em>perfectly–</em>this time. Stop me if you’ve learned this life lesson already, but trying to do everything perfectly isn’t much fun at all.</p><p>In the survival sandbox of <a href="https://www.thelongdark.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>The Long Dark</em>,</a> you’re given a huge, snowy world to survive in as long as possible, and how you go about doing that is up to you. As I’ve <a href="https://aftermath.site/long-dark-survival" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">written before</a>, despite hundreds of hours in the game, my runs have never lasted very long. My last run was only about 35 in-game days, but it was solid: I had good gear, had crafted a bow and a ton of arrows, and was well on my way to getting to check out the recently-added safehouse customization when I lost it all due to bad luck and panic. Lessons learned, I thought, promptly starting again.</p><p>I hit the wrong button when starting my new run, because I spawned in the game’s remote DLC maps instead of the main map that I intended to. It wasn’t my ideal place to start a run, but it did mean I was well set up to check out the narrative that the DLC added, which I’ve never pursued in earnest. I decided to embrace my mistake and make that my plan, focusing on trekking across the game’s world repairing the required transmitters and finding their related bunkers.</p><p>I’m ashamed to admit I almost immediately took to (let’s call it what it is) cheating by looking up guides to the locations. When I learned that one might take me back into the path of the <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/rcmacleod.bsky.social/post/3lgk4aeeg4223" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">cougar</a> that ended my previous run, I became fixated on the idea of completing that part of the story before the cougar spawned. This wasn’t hard–in the difficulty I’m playing on, I had plenty of time–but it stressed me out a lot. I beelined across the game’s world, grabbing what I could get on my way. This single-minded focus led to a couple mistakes, wearing way too heavy clothes and missing places where I could have grabbed some good loot, including some of the items needed to repair the transmitters. This latter mistake slowed me down once I realized it, but once I repaired the necessary transmitter, I raced toward the bunker. I panicked when I got lost in a transition mine, and I fell through thin ice several times as I split my attention between the radio required to locate the bunker and glancing around wildly for extra-dangerous <a href="https://thelongdark.fandom.com/wiki/Aurora" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">aurora</a> predators.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><p>Right now, my character is in that bunker, well before the cougar has spawned. I know where the other transmitters and their bunkers are because I’ve watched unnecessary hours of YouTube videos and pored over player-made maps. I keep running over my plan in my head: I’ll drop my collected gear at my favorite base, hit the next transmitter early in the morning so I can be right where the next bunker is when the aurora starts, then hit the last transmitter and bunker on my way to another good looting spot. Closing out this part of the DLC will require going back to an area I don’t terribly want to trek to, and I’m torn between locking in the ending so I can pursue the next part of the DLC on a different save if I die, and trusting myself to survive long enough to let it happen naturally.</p><p>Logging out for the night with my character safely ensconced in the bunker, I realized I was feeling distinctly stressed out and <em>weird</em> about the run, and about a game that I really love. In many ways, <em>The Long Dark</em> is a game about fucking up, about embracing impermanence and coming to peace with seeing your hard work vanish in an instant. For the decade I’ve been playing the game, I’ve never been too attached to a run, but now that I’m trying to play it “right,” I find myself feeling like I’m not playing it right at all. I’m afraid to take risks or encounter wildlife, feel like exploring is just wasted time, and trying to optimize every choice and path in ways that seem to come naturally to players far more skilled than me, but which loses the feeling of free-flowing adventure that I like best about the game, even when it leads to disaster.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><p>It has of course occurred to me that I got <em>really into</em> this game again around the recent election and its subsequent horrors. <em>The Long Dark</em> is a wilderness full of unpredictable dangers, which certainly fits the current vibe, and an empty world far away from people, which certainly fits with my desire to fade away into the woods when things in my life get tough. I’m sure a therapist would point out that my fixation on getting everything in a video game to go exactly my way stands in contrast to the helplessness of the current administration’s <a href="https://19thnews.org/2025/01/trump-transgender-executive-order/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">attacks on trans people</a> like me. This is all one big exercise in sublimation and avoidance, though at least it’s one aimed at a video game I really like instead of the <a href="https://kotaku.com/how-to-play-games-sober-1839509936" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">more destructive directions</a> I used to favor.</p><p>But I feel like I’m ruining my favorite game for myself by playing it this way; my approach feels like it’s against both the spirit of the game and the way I most like to play it. I’m making myself a little crazy in a way that I at least had the self-awareness to realize is not entirely about a video game, and I have enough stress in my life to not need to make myself stressed about a video game, of all things, too.&nbsp;</p><p>While I don’t tend to go in on the idea of video games as escapism, I want to hold that it’s OK for me to distract myself from the ongoing onslaught of horrors. But if I’m going to use a game in that way, I want to make sure I’m not just making myself feel worse. I want games to feel fun and joyous, or at least the good kind of stressful. I don’t want my run to be about control and perfection; I want to explore more of <em>The Long Dark</em>’s maps and mess around with mechanics I haven’t engaged with much, to see what happens when I play around in one of my favorite video game worlds. And games need to be just one way I find an outlet for my feelings, instead of hanging them all on the perfect run.</p></div><div><h2>Stay in touch</h2><p>Sign up for our free newsletter</p></div><div><h2><span>More from Aftermath</span></h2><div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/ubisoft-phoenix-labs-layoffs-studio-closure-far-cry-dauntless"><h3>Another Big Day For Layoffs In Another Big Year For Layoffs</h3></a><p>Ubisoft is closing its third studio in two months, and Phoenix Labs is bidding farewell to "the majority" of its workforce</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/quartz-ai-articles-go-media"><h3>G/O Media Is Publishing AI Slop Again</h3></a><p>News site Quartz is publishing a whole lot of AI-generated articles</p></div></div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/all">See all posts<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="#000" stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round"><path d="M5 12h13m-6-7 7 7-7 7"></path></svg></a></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[“To keep games off other platforms… it’s not a path for us,” says Microsoft’s Phil Spencer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/01/28/to-keep-games-off-other-platforms-its-not-a-path-for-us-says-microsofts-phil-spencer/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/%E2%80%9Cto-keep-games-off-other-platforms%E2%80%A6-it%E2%80%99s-not-a-path-for-us-%E2%80%9D-says-microsoft%E2%80%99s-phil-spencer.1094034/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/01/28/to-keep-games-off-other-platforms-its-not-a-path-for-us-says-microsofts-phil-spencer/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Microsoft’s Phil Spencer has given a new interview and explained that Xbox exclusives are a thing of the past as they no longer make financial sense. <a href="https://x.com/DestinLegarie/status/1883243143342231655">Destin Legarie</a> asked Phil if Starfield, one of 2023’s big Xbox exclusive games would be “staying put” and after a few moments Phil replied with a firm “No.”</p>
<p>“There’s no specific game… this kinda goes back to my red line answer, there’s no reason for me to put a ring fence around any game and say this game will not go to a place, where it would find players, where we would have business success for us.” He then adds “To keep games off other platforms, that’s not a path for us.”</p>


<p>The statements come almost exactly <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/02/15/four-xbox-games-are-coming-to-other-consoles-but-not-starfield-or-indy/">a year after Microsoft’s presentation i</a>n which they announced the first four games that would be coming to PlayStation and Nintendo, during which they specifically stated Starfield was not coming to other consoles, so a lot has changed in the last year.&nbsp;<a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/01/10/rumours-suggest-more-xbox-games-will-be-coming-to-ps5-and-switch/"> Rumours suggest</a> Flight Simulator, Hellblade 2, and the Halo Collection will be coming to PlayStation sometime this year.</p>
<p>Two reliable sources – NateTheHate and Windows Central’s Jez Corden – have been posting about the games in question.</p>
<p>“So, games that I have heard will be released multiplatform in 2025 beyond the obvious include Flight Simulator, which will come to PlayStation 5 and Switch 2, and&nbsp;<a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2014/11/07/halo-the-master-chief-collection-review/">Halo: The Master Chief Collection</a>&nbsp;will be coming to PS5 and Switch 2 as well,” states Nate on his&nbsp;<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AIhoTirZxlk">podcast.</a></p>
<p>Jez has confirmed he had also heard about Flight Simulator and Halo, and<a href="https://www.windowscentral.com/gaming/xbox/a-new-rumor-suggests-final-fantasy-7-remake-is-finally-coming-to-xbox-in-2025-with-rebirth-heading-across-in-2026-as-more-xbox-games-head-to-ps5-and-nintendo">&nbsp;adds</a>&nbsp;“I’ve heard that also Hellblade 2, Age of Mythology, and potentially Gears of War 1 Ultimate Edition are all also slated for PlayStation 5 this year, although I’m unsure if that includes the Nintendo Switch 2.”</p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://x.com/DestinLegarie/status/1883243143342231655?" target="_blank" rel="noopener">X</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EVE Online 2025 Roadmap Shared in Directors’ Stream; Two Expansions Coming]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/eve-online-2025-roadmap-shared-in-directors-stream-two-expansions-coming/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/eve-online-2025-roadmap-shared-in-directors%E2%80%99-stream-two-expansions-coming.1094031/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/eve-online-2025-roadmap-shared-in-directors-stream-two-expansions-coming/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Today, CCP Games shared their 2025 roadmap for the space MMO EVE Online during a Directors' stream. During this stream, it was announced that there will be two major expansions released, as well as the return of a fan-favorite in-game event, such as the EVE Fanfest 2025. This particular event will take place on May 1-3 at Reykjavik's Harpa Concert Hall. For those who want to watch the Directors' Stream from today, it is available to watch on the official CCP Games <a href="https://www.twitch.tv/ccp" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Twitch</a> and<a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/ccpgames" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> YouTube</a> Channel.</p>

<figure></figure>

<p>Diving into the roadmap for EVE Online,<a href="https://wccftech.com/eve-online-receives-revenant-expansion-bringing-new-ships-dens-and-more-customizations/"> the Revenant storyline</a> will continue to play out across Q1 as the tensions continue to rise between the Deathless and the Drifters. This will then carry players over to the next expansion for EVE Online, which is set to release in Summer 2025, with a focus on empowering the players, offering new enhanced tools for customization and content creation.</p>
<p>"This year, we're putting even more power in the hands of our capsuleers," said Snorri Arnason, Game Director for EVE Online. "From customizing sovereign space to crafting missions that spark new alliances, the 2025 roadmap is all about letting players create and shape their own moments, their own stories, and ultimately being part of the history books of New Eden itself."</p>
<p>Aside from the summer expansion, as mentioned earlier, fan-favorite events will be making a return to EVE Online. This includes events such as Capsuleer Day, Crimson Harvest, and Winter Nexus. The second expansion for EVE Online is set to release in the Winter of 2025. There haven't been many details about this expansion yet, as more details for the Summer expansion will be yet to come.</p>
<p>For those interested, tickets for EVE Fanfest 2025 are on sale but are nearly sold out. Those who want to attend can purchase tickets from <a href="https://www.eventbrite.co.uk/e/eve-fanfest-2025-tickets-716031949837" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Eventbrite</a>, with the price starting at $35. However, for those who want the full experience of Fanfest, the Festival Pass will cost you $295, which includes access to the party at the Top of the World, exclusive in-game content, an EVE Fanfest 2025 t-shirt, and a goodie bag.</p>
<p>"2025 will be monumental for EVE Online. We've listened to player feedback to refine our development process and create high-quality expansions that empower capsuleers. Join us in New Eden to experience a year filled with characters to meet, alliances to forge - or break - and thrilling stories to uncover. It's a year you don't want to miss!" says Bergur Finnbogason, EVE Online's Creative Director.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Daredevil: Born Again Showrunner Says The Penguin Is Its 'Direct Competition']]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/daredevil-born-again-the-penguin-disney-marvel-1851749356</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/daredevil-born-again-showrunner-says-the-penguin-is-its-direct-competition.1094016/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/daredevil-born-again-the-penguin-disney-marvel-1851749356<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>You know the era of gritty superhero depictions on television has arrived when two of the biggest comic-book brands in existence are in direct competition with their own moody shows. During a recent interview with <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.gamesradar.com/entertainment/sci-fi-movies/daredevil-born-again-showrunner-teases-that-the-mcu-show-is-even-more-grounded-than-dc-spin-off-the-penguin-going-as-far-as-a-disney-plus-show-has-ever-gone/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.gamesradar.com/entertainment/sci-fi-movies/daredevil-born-again-showrunner-teases-that-the-mcu-show-is-even-more-grounded-than-dc-spin-off-the-penguin-going-as-far-as-a-disney-plus-show-has-ever-gone/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>SFX Magazine</em></a></span>, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/daredevil-born-again-disney-marvel-news-1851714637&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/daredevil-born-again-disney-marvel-news-1851714637"><em>Daredevil: Born Again</em></a></span> showrunner Dario Scardapane says the upcoming Disney+ series is in competition with the current king of dark superhero dramas, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/the-penguin-the-batman-part-ii-questions-connections-1851693100&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/the-penguin-the-batman-part-ii-questions-connections-1851693100"><em>The Penguin</em></a></span>.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="197298" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Live Forever in the Universe of 'New World: Aeternum'" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="108" data-playlist="197298,197284,197260" data-current="197298"><div><p>Live Forever in the Universe of 'New World: Aeternum'</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"></video></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>We first found out <em>Daredevil: Born Again </em>was <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://variety.com/2022/tv/news/daredevil-disney-plus-series-matt-corman-chris-ord-1235272299/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://variety.com/2022/tv/news/daredevil-disney-plus-series-matt-corman-chris-ord-1235272299/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">in development</a></span> in May 2022, nearly three years prior to its scheduled March 4, 2025 release date, and eight months after we first learned about <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://variety.com/2021/tv/news/the-batman-spinoff-series-penguin-hbo-max-1235063438/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://variety.com/2021/tv/news/the-batman-spinoff-series-penguin-hbo-max-1235063438/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>The Penguin</em> going into development</a></span>. The 2023 Writers Guild of America strike halted production of both shows, but only <em>Daredevil: Born Again</em> was further delayed by Marvel Studios deciding to <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/tv/tv-news/daredevil-marvel-disney-1235614518/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/tv/tv-news/daredevil-marvel-disney-1235614518/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">overhaul the entire series</a></span> in late September 2023 and find new directors and writers. <em>Daredevil: Born Again</em> got its act together and <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/tv/tv-news/daredevil-born-again-resumes-filming-echo-1235793539/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/tv/tv-news/daredevil-born-again-resumes-filming-echo-1235793539/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">resumed filming</a></span> in January 2024, a month before <em>The Penguin </em><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.cbr.com/the-penguin-max-wrap/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.cbr.com/the-penguin-max-wrap/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">finished filming</a></span>. Scardapane intimated that this headstart for <em>Penguin</em>, which released its Season 1 premiere in September 2024, made things a bit weird in the superhero TV show world.</p><p>“It’s really strange. You work in a vacuum and then something else comes out and you go, ‘Oh, wow.’ I would say in many ways <em>The Penguin</em> is our direct competition [but] we’re a little faster, meaner, cleaner in our storytelling.”</p><p>Marvel and DC Studios may be enemies among hardcore comic book fans, but rarely does that competitive nature get promoted by people involved with actually continuing each brand’s legacy. How true Scardapane’s comments are will be judged when <em>Daredevil: Born Again</em> debuts, but it’s going to be a tall order. While <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/penguin-hbo-season-2-batman-part-2-colin-farrell-1851695078&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/penguin-hbo-season-2-batman-part-2-colin-farrell-1851695078"><em>The Penguin</em></a></span><em> </em>prioritized meticulous dissections of the psyches of characters like Oswald ‘Oz’ Cobb (Colin Farrell) and Sofia Falcone (Cristin Milioti) over weekly bloodfests, there were still enough mother-son incinerations, shootouts, and climactic deaths to satiate the bloodthirsty.</p><p>On the other hand, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/daredevil-born-again-disney-wilson-fisk-matt-murdock-1851740074&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/daredevil-born-again-disney-wilson-fisk-matt-murdock-1851740074"><em>Daredevil: Born Again</em>’s two-minute trailer</a></span> has more bone-breaking hand-to-hand combat than likely the entirety of <em>The Penguin</em>’s first season, along with Matt Murdock (Charlie Cox) exhibiting similar existential antihero turmoil as what Cobb struggled with in <em>The Penguin</em>. And that earned Farrell a <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/marvel-dc-dune-penguin-golden-globes-1851716634?_gl=1*pw49ub*_ga*MzQzNjkwNDM2LjE2NDY2NjQ1NzQ.*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczODA4MzU3Ny4zNDYuMS4xNzM4MDgzNTk0LjQzLjAuMA..&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/marvel-dc-dune-penguin-golden-globes-1851716634?_gl=1*pw49ub*_ga*MzQzNjkwNDM2LjE2NDY2NjQ1NzQ.*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczODA4MzU3Ny4zNDYuMS4xNzM4MDgzNTk0LjQzLjAuMA..">Golden Globe</a></span>. </p><p>Either way, when creatives are in competition, the winners are always the viewers. So, let’s sit back and enjoy the start of a true dark superhero drama renaissance. </p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Legacy: Steel & Sorcery launches in Early Access on February 12]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/01/legacy-steel-sorcery-launches-in-early-access-on-february-12</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/legacy-steel-sorcery-launches-in-early-access-on-february-12.1094010/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/01/legacy-steel-sorcery-launches-in-early-access-on-february-12<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Expected to remain in Early Access for at least 12 months.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Player-versus-player-versus-environment third-person <a title="Genres > Action RPG [1,478 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg/action-rpg">action RPG</a> <em><a title="Games > Legacy: Steel &amp; Sorcery [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/legacy-steel-sorcery">Legacy: Steel &amp; Sorcery</a></em> will launch in Early Access for <a title="Platforms > PC [22,216 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2344320/Legacy_Steel__Sorcery/" target="_blank">Steam</a> on February 12, developer <a title="Companies > Notorious Studios [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/notorious-studios">Notorious Studios</a> announced. <span id="more-940862"></span></p><p>The Early Access release is described as an “unfinished” experience that will be refined, expanded, and improved. The core gameplay experience is fully in place, and there are four playable classes (Warrior, Hunter, Rogue, and Priest) and one main map (Greenwood). Over the course of Early Access, the game will be updated with new classes (Paladin and Wizard), new maps (Dungeon Crpyt, Goldbrook Farm Map, etc.),  new monsters, and more. The game is expected to remain in Early Access for at least 12 months.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2344320/Legacy_Steel__Sorcery/" target="_blank">Steam page</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>Legacy: Steel &amp; Sorcery</em> is a third-person <a title="Genres > Action [2,446 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a> player-versus-player-versus-environment <a title="Genres > RPG [16,952 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg">RPG</a> featuring distinctive fantasy classes. Go on <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,016 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a>s solo or with friends to search for treasures, level up, and defeat any who stand in your way.</p><p><strong>Destroy Your Enemies</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Combat has been designed from the ground up for player-versus-player. Feel the impact of your attacks and use your abilities to carve out the flow of battle. Quick decisions and precision are necessary to win.</p><p><strong>Take What You Will</strong></p><p>In the wilds, the spoils go to the victor. The world is more real when everyone’s hard-earned loot is on the line. Victories are savored while defeat hardens resolve.</p><p><strong>Prepare for Battle</strong></p><p>Respite awaits behind the stone walls of the city. Fortify your elixirs and armaments at shops. Rest in your private room at the inn, organize your stash, and cook a meal for the next adventure.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li>Go on solo adventures, or bolster your strength with up to two other friends.</li><li>Actively dodge, block, sprint, attack, and cast when you engage in combat.</li><li>Level up each character to unlock new abilities and traits.</li><li>The world is part of combat. Warriors can charge through walls and hurl boulders, while priests can levitate over dangers and away from enemies. Each class has unique ways in which they interact with the environment.</li><li>Improve your reputation with vendors to craft the most impressive gear and get them to sell you the best stuff.</li><li>Upgrade your permanent lodging with higher quality furnishings. Better amenities mean more benefits on your adventures.</li><li>Embark on quests for unique rewards and much needed supplies.</li><li><a title="Companies > Experience [210 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/experience">Experience</a> a community-wide fresh start when major updates reset progression, deliver new content and gameplay changes.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Early Access Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Legacy: Steel and Sorcery - Early Access Trailer 2025" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/k4faUc3opFk?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cozy Games May Help Improve Players' Mental Health, Researchers Say]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cozy-games-may-help-improve-players-mental-health-researchers-say/1100-6529075/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cozy-games-may-help-improve-players-mental-health-researchers-say.1094007/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cozy-games-may-help-improve-players-mental-health-researchers-say/1100-6529075/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529075">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Most of the early research into video games seemed to be designed to find a link between in-game violence and its effects on players in the real world. More recently, there have been studies about the adverse affects of gaming addiction. However, there's now research that suggests playing games may actually be beneficial for players, depending upon the type of the game.</p><p>According to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/graphics/VIDEO-GAMES/MENTAL-HEALTH/akpeewkqgpr/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Reuters</a>, the majority of the research into the benefits of gaming focuses on cozy video games like <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/animal-crossing-new-horizons-review-island-getaway/1900-6417431/" data-ref-id="1900-6417431">Animal Crossing: New Horizons</a>. These casual games are designed to be soothing to play and almost impossible to lose. That genre also avoids putting players into overly stressful situations.</p><p>Hiroyuki Egami, an assistant professor at Nihon University, published a study conducted in Japan between 2020-2022 which found that participants experienced greatly reduced stress and an increase in mental health if they spent one extra hour playing games each day. A separate study by McMaster University assistant professor Michael Wong compared the benefits of casual gaming to meditation.</p><p>"To our surprise, there really wasn't a difference between the two forms of interventions," explained Wong. "For blood pressure and heart rate, there was no statistically significant difference between playing a video game and engaging in meditation."</p><p>This is an area of study that still remains largely unexplored, but these results are encouraging for players who have touted the benefits of gaming for years.</p><p>Improved mental health for players isn't the only way games are creating positive change. Players have also come together to help <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/awesome-games-done-quick-2025-raises-over-2-5-million-for-prevent-cancer-foundation/1100-6528769/" data-ref-id="1100-6528769">Awesome Games Done Quick 2025 raise $2.5 million</a> for the Prevent Cancer Foundation. Last year at the BAFTA Game Awards, a UK gaming charity called <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gaming-charity-specialeffect-will-receive-prestigious-bafta-special-award/1100-6522222/" data-ref-id="1100-6522222">SpecialEffect was given a special award</a> for its efforts to improve access to video games for people with physical disabilities. At its best, gaming can bring people together, and it's a side of the industry worth celebrating when given the chance.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Call Of Duty 2025 -- Everything We Know About Rumored Black Ops 2 Sequel]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-2025-everything-we-know-about-rumored-black-ops-2-sequel/1100-6529073/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/call-of-duty-2025-everything-we-know-about-rumored-black-ops-2-sequel.1094004/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-2025-everything-we-know-about-rumored-black-ops-2-sequel/1100-6529073/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529073">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>The Call of Duty series is an annual franchise, so it's expected that Microsoft's Activision division will launch a new Call of Duty this year, like it has every year since 2005. In fact, 2025 will mark 20 years in a row of Activision releasing a new Call of Duty game (the series debuted in 2003 but had no release in 2004).</p><p>It's still early days, and to be clear, Activision has not announced the new Call of Duty game that's expected to release in 2025. But there have been a handful of leaks and rumors about Call of Duty 2025, including a rumor that it's a sequel to Black Ops 2 set in the 2030s.</p><p>In this post, we're rounding up everything we know, and what's been rumored, about the next Call of Duty.</p><h2>What is Call of Duty 2025?</h2><p>If <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-2-call-of-duty-2025/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Insider Gaming</a>'s sources are correct, Call of Duty 2025 is a new Black Ops game, a sequel to 2012's Black Ops II--set in the early 2030s. 2024's Call of Duty game was also a Black Ops game--Black Ops 6--and this would mark the first time Black Ops games were released in back-to-back years. Specifically, Call of Duty 2025 is expected to pick up where Black Ops II left off--that game was set in 2025.</p><h2>When will Call of Duty 2025 be released?</h2><p>If Activision and Microsoft keep to the standard formula, fans can expect Call of Duty 2025 to launch in October or November 2025. It is likely to be announced at least a few months before that, with Activision almost assuredly using Call of Duty: Warzone to tease the next game, as it's done in the past.</p><h2>Will Call of Duty 2025 have a beta?</h2><p>Call of Duty 2025 is expected to have a pre-release multiplayer beta, as all recent entries in the series have. Now that Microsoft owns the franchise, fans can expect the beta to launch on all platforms at the same time, at least if the company sticks to the gameplan from Black Ops 6. Previously, Call of Duty betas were held first on PlayStation due to a co-marketing deal between Activision and Sony. The Black Ops 6 beta took place in August 2024, so it's reasonable to assume the Call of Duty 2025 beta could take place in August 2025.</p><h2>Preorder Call of Duty 2025</h2><p>While a new Call of Duty game coming out each year is one of the safest bets a person could make in the video game landscape, Call of Duty 2025 hasn't been announced yet and thus isn't available for preorder. If history serves as precedent, preorders for the game are likely to open around the time the game is officially announced.</p><h2>Call of Duty 2025 trailer information</h2><p>As of yet, Activision has not released any official trailers for Call of Duty 2025.</p><h2>Call of Duty 2025 platforms</h2><p>Activision has not announced the next Call of Duty, but it's likely to show up for Xbox, PlayStation, and PC. Microsoft Gaming CEO Phil Spencer has also <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/it-sure-sounds-like-xbox-games-are-coming-to-switch-2/1100-6529052/" data-ref-id="1100-6529052">alluded to bringing games to Nintendo Switch 2</a>, but whether or not this will include the next Call of Duty is unknown.</p><h2>Will Call of Duty 2025 be on Game Pass?</h2><p>Microsoft put Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 on Game Pass at launch, and it's expected the company will do the same for Call of Duty 2025.</p><h2>Call of Duty 2025 story, setting, and characters</h2><p>Insider Gaming reported that Call of Duty 2025 is a Black Ops II sequel set in the early 2030s, picking up after the events of Black Ops II. The Black Ops storyline is <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/get-ready-for-black-ops-6-with-this-explainer-of-the-story-so-far/2900-5855/" data-ref-id="2900-5855">full of twists and turns and wild political conspiracies</a>, and it's expected that the new Call of Duty would continue this trend if it is indeed a new Black Ops game.</p><div tabindex="0" data-id="73178005" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6465298,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Call%20of%20Duty%3A%20Black%20Ops%206%20-%20Black%20Ops%20Story%20So%20Far%20Trailer&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:104,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:false,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-black-ops-story-so-far-trailer\/2300-6465298\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465298\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465298\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465298\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6465298&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6465298,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6529073&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;pc,xbox-series-x,playstation-5&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6465298},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6465298\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;Publisher Asset&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4380589-11.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/4ritACm0.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1728396900,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="4ritACm0" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle" data-embed-type="video" data-ref-id="2300-6465298" data-src="/videos/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-black-ops-story-so-far-trailer/2300-6465298/" data-width="100%" data-height="100%" data-video-start="0"><div><p>Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 - Black Ops Story So Far Trailer</p><div><p>         Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?       </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!       </p></div></div><p>       Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.     </p><p>       This video has an invalid file format.     </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div><h2>Call of Duty 2025 game engine</h2><p>The Call of Duty franchise is now developed on a singular, proprietary game engine for all major new releases, and this is expected to continue in 2025.</p><h2>Who's developing Call of Duty 2025?</h2><p>The Insider Gaming report that contained a number of apparent details on Call of Duty 2025 does not name a developer for the project. In any event, Call of Duty games are not developed by one team alone, as Activision historically recruits multiple internal and external development teams to assist with each new release.</p><h2>What else is new for Call of Duty in 2025?</h2><p>Call of Duty is much more than just one big new release each year. Activision also supports its battle royale game, Call of Duty: Warzone with a regular stream of new updates. In 2025, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-warzone-is-finally-returning-to-verdansk-in-2025/1100-6526178/" data-ref-id="1100-6526178">Warzone is bringing back the OG Warzone map, Verdansk, later this year.</a> Beyond that, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/cod-black-ops-6-and-warzone-season-2-patch-notes-detail-major-camo-and-weapon-changes/2900-6170/" data-ref-id="2900-6170">Black Ops 6 is getting a full suite of new maps and modes through its seasonal model</a>, while Call of Duty: Mobile and Call of Duty: Warzone Mobile are expected to continue to expand throughout 2025.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Techland teases  "multiple" unannounced Dying Light projects, including board games and a webcomic]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/techland-teases-multiple-unannounced-dying-light-projects-including-board-games-and-a-webcomic</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/techland-teases-multiple-unannounced-dying-light-projects-including-board-games-and-a-webcomic.1094001/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/techland-teases-multiple-unannounced-dying-light-projects-including-board-games-and-a-webcomic<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div>
        

        <p>As zombie series marks 10th anniversary.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/dying-light-montage.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Techland/Eurogamer</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Developer Techland has teased plans for "multiple unannounced projects" set in the Dying Light universe - including new video games, board games, and a webcomic - as the zombie series celebrates its tenth birthday.
</p>
<p>
Dying Light 1 released on 26th January, 2015 and proved to be a massive hit for Techland, selling <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/dying-light-2-has-surpassed-5m-copies-sold-since-launching-in-february">over 20m copies as of 2022</a>. A sequel followed in 2022, and an 18-hour standalone adventure, Dying Light: The Beast, is <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/dying-light-the-beast-is-a-new-18-hour-standalone-game-that-began-life-as-dlc">set to arrive this summer</a>.
</p>
<p>
And that's far from the end of Techland's Dying Light ambitions. The studio has now revealed it's planning "multiple unannounced projects" as it aims to position the series as the "ultimate zombie experience". According to the developer, these will "go beyond video games", and include the likes of board games, a webcomic series, merchandise, and "more".
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Dying Light: The Beast — MEET THE BARON - THE GAME AWARDS 2024 TRAILER" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8Tkwem4M1uw?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Dying Light: The Beast — MEET THE BARON - THE GAME AWARDS 2024 TRAILER</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8Tkwem4M1uw?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/8Tkwem4M1uw?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Dying Light: The Beast arrives this summer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8Tkwem4M1uw" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
"Our goal is to bring the world of Dying Light to even more people," Techland writes. "From the ongoing support of our currently released games to Dying Light: The Beast and beyond, there's never been a better time to be a Dying Light fan."
</p><p>
In the more immediate term, Techland is releasing new updates for Dying Light 1 &amp; 2 "very soon". The first game is poised to see the return of old events alongside new rewards, and will receive a range of "enhancements", including improved visual quality, a remastered soundtrack, and more. As for Dying Light 2: Stay Human, it's getting "further prologue changes", and its roguelite Tower Raid mode is set to become permanent.
</p>
<p>
Additionally, for those that haven't yet dipped their toes into Techland's open-world zombie series, Dying Light 1 &amp; 2 are both currently discounted on Xbox and PC.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Monastery escape tactics sim The Stone Of Madness is out now and has me thinking about time]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/monastery-escape-tactics-sim-the-stone-of-madness-is-out-now-and-has-me-thinking-about-time</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/monastery-escape-tactics-sim-the-stone-of-madness-is-out-now-and-has-me-thinking-about-time.1093986/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/monastery-escape-tactics-sim-the-stone-of-madness-is-out-now-and-has-me-thinking-about-time<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div>
  

        <p>From the Blasphemous devs</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/3_gDK4eQg.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Tripwire Presents</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Today is release day for The Game Kitchen's <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/the-stone-of-madness">The Stone Of Madness</a>, an isometric tactical stealth game set in an 18th century monastery - "isometric tactical stealth game" being a pretty clinical way to describe the plight of sundry lost souls exploring a maze of hellish Catholic art populated by guards and ghouls. 
</p><!--more-->
<p>
As in Commandos, you control a group of characters with different skills, strengths and weaknesses. Unlike in Commandos, your characters have sanity bars and a range of narratively-grounded foibles and phobias - either present from the get-go, or sprouted in response to the hardships you put them through. Lewis Gordon <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-stone-of-madness-review">done a review for Eurogamer</a> and he makes it sound extremely appealing, half-cooked plot and tricksy controls notwithstanding.
</p>
<p>
I'm interested in The Stone Of Madness partly because it's from the Spanish studio behind <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/blasphemous">Blasphemous</a>, a terrific study in religious horror, and partly because I've been thinking lately about the role of monastic orders in developing "modern" European understandings of time. For the philosopher Michel Foucault, the hourly and daily rites of forgotten generations of monks paved the way for the 9-to-5. Writing in <a href="https://archive.org/details/disciplinepunish0000fouc_j5k6">Discipline And Punish</a>, he describes the monasteries as "the specialists of time, the great technicians of rhythm and regular activities", and explores how they influenced the secular world by way of attached schools and poorhouses and eventually, industrial workplaces that "long retained a religious air".
</p>
<p>
This ancient discipline of timekeeping, as Foucault describes it, can also be traced to the variably time-locked worlds of video games. Being a game set in a monastery, The Stone Of Madness naturally makes the connection explicit. Its challenges and opportunities follow an elaborate day-night cycle, requiring you to match the right character to the right hour if you're to succeed. It takes inspiration on this count from another, much older Spanish production, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/La_Abad%C3%ADa_del_Crimen">The Abbey Of Crime</a>, itself a loose adaptation of Umberto Eco's gargantuan monastic mystery novel The Name Of The Rose. 
</p><p>
All this makes me wonder whether "monastic time" is a concept worth pursuing to other, non-monastic games, as both alternative and precursor to the better-known idea of the "game as a job", encapsulated by live service looting simulators. I'll hopefully have something lengthier to say about all that in the next few weeks. For the moment, The Stone Of Madness seems worth a stab. There's still <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1309710/The_Stone_of_Madness/">a Steam demo</a> live at the time of writing.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Final Fantasy Creator Has One More RPG In Him, Calls It A 'Successor' To Final Fantasy VI]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-6-sequel-hironobu-sakaguchi-fantasian-1851749344</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/final-fantasy-creator-has-one-more-rpg-in-him-calls-it-a-successor-to-final-fantasy-vi.1093980/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-6-sequel-hironobu-sakaguchi-fantasian-1851749344<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Final Fantasy VI</em> is <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-vi-retrospective-simply-the-best-1792398695&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-vi-retrospective-simply-the-best-1792398695">one of the best games ever made</a></span>. Fans have been coasting off that high for decades, even as modern homages seek to recreate the magic of the original. The lead creative behind the beloved RPG series, Hironobu Sakaguchi, now says making a proper successor to the 1994 SNES classic will be his final mission.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196055" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="6 Things To Know Before Starting Persona 5 Tactica" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="227" data-playlist="196055,195519,196599" data-current="196055"><div><p>6 Things To Know Before Starting Persona 5 Tactica</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196055/196055_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196055/196055_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196055/196055_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196055/196055_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21584.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>Sakaguchi left <em>Final Fantasy</em> publisher Square Enix in 2004 and founded the smaller  studio Mistwalker. He’s ben making RPGs there ever since, from cult-classics like Xbox 360 exclusive <em>Lost Odyssey </em>to smaller mobile games like <em>Terra Battle</em>. Most recently his team shipped <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/fantasian-final-fantasy-hironobu-sakaguchi-nobuo-uemats-1851729068&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/fantasian-final-fantasy-hironobu-sakaguchi-nobuo-uemats-1851729068"><em>Fantasian: Neo Dimension</em>, an excellent old-school RPG</a></span> that began life as an Apple Arcade release in 2021, before recently getting remastered for consoles and PC. </p><p><em>Fantasian</em> definitely felt heavily inspired by <em>Final Fantasy VI</em>. It starred an amnesiac fighter trying to save a world on the brink of chaos, aided by an eclectic group of noble misfits. The details were different but the overall mood and focus on narrative drama felt reminiscent of SNES-era Final Fantasy games. Sakaguchi reportedly replayed <em>Final Fantasy VI</em>, which he helped write and produce, before making <em>Fantasian </em>and considered both games <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.ign.com/articles/fantasian-tied-final-fantasy-6-hironobu-sakaguchi-love-family?amp=1&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/fantasian-tied-final-fantasy-6-hironobu-sakaguchi-love-family?amp=1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">kindred spirits through their mutual focus on family</a></span>. </p><p>But his next project will apparently feel even more closely inspired by one of his old franchise’s peak games. “It’s generally going to follow a similar style to my previous works, and it’ll be something that can be a successor to<em> Final Fantasy VI</em> in a good way—our goal is to create something old but new at the same time,” the veteran creator <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/24/24350575/hironobu-sakaguchi-interview-fantasian-neo-dimension&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/24/24350575/hironobu-sakaguchi-interview-fantasian-neo-dimension" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">recently told <em>The Verge</em></a></span>. “It’ll be part two of my farewell note.”</p><p>Sakaguchi said he had intended for <em>Fantasian</em> to be his final game, but had too much fun working with the team behind it to actually retire when it was done. “Humans are greedy creatures, aren’t we?” he told <em>The Verge</em>. “For that reason, I’m currently working on a new project with the same team that worked on <em>Fantasian Neo Dimension</em>.” </p><p>We don’t yet know what being a successor to<em> Final Fantasy VI </em>will mean for Mistalker’s next game. Retro HD-2D graphics? A sprawling cast of disparate characters brought together through shared tragedy and common purpose? A show-stopping opera scene foiled by a giant octopus? Or maybe Sakaguchi intends the connection to be more subtle and philosophical than that. </p><p>Fans will always pine for the direct sequel to <em>Final Fantasy VI</em> <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-6-remake-hd-2d-dragon-quest-3-square-enix-1851702829&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-6-remake-hd-2d-dragon-quest-3-square-enix-1851702829">they’ve dreamed of but never got</a></span>. The legendary RPG maker, on the other hand, has much grander ambitions. He said, “In the distant future, or maybe after I have already left this world, I imagine this game will find its meaning if someone chooses to look into the legacy of either myself or <em>Final Fantasy</em>.”</p><p>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Preorder Split Fiction and Get a Free Keychain (Plus a Friend Plays Free)]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/where-to-buy-split-fiction-preorder-bonuses</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/preorder-split-fiction-and-get-a-free-keychain-plus-a-friend-plays-free.1093974/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/where-to-buy-split-fiction-preorder-bonuses<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Split Fiction is coming to PS5, Xbox Series X|S, and PC on March 6. A co-op sci-fi game from Hazelight Studios, the makers of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/it-takes-two-review">It Takes Two</a>, Split Fiction is available to preorder now (<a href="https://zdcs.link/zJ2ddm?object_uuid=6f9ea730-eb61-4f27-a0df-50396190197e&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" data-aps-asin="B0DQF6GRT8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">see it at Amazon</a>) for $39.99. And just like Hazelight’s previous games, anyone who buys it gets a free Friend’s Pass that lets a friend play the whole game with you in co-op for free.</p><p id="where-to-preorder"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Where to Preorder">Split Fiction - Where to Buy It</h2></p><p id="how-the-friends-pass-works"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="How the Friend's Pass Works">How Does Split Fiction’s Friend’s Pass Work?</h2></p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/01/28/split-fiction-friends-pass-1738080740983.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">The main unique thing about Split Fiction is that you must play it in co-op mode. There’s no single-player option. So you can play it in couch co-op split-screen mode on a single display, <em>or</em> you can play it via online co-op, with just a single copy of the game. This even works cross-platform, meaning you can play it with a friend even if they’re using a different console or PC platform than you are.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">To play with a friend online, just have your friend download “Split Fiction - Friend’s Pass” from the digital marketplace of their choice after the game comes out, on March 6. This version is free, and it lets your buddy play the game with you at no additional cost after you send them an invite. Hazelight did a similar thing for for its previous games It Takes Two and A Way Out. The only caveat is that your non-paying friend can’t play it without pairing up with someone who has purchased the game.</p><p id="what-is-split-fiction"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="What Is Split Fiction?">What Is Split Fiction?</h2></p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/split-fiction-is-josef-fares-new-co-op-adventure-game-the-game-awards-2024">Split Fiction</a> is a co-op-only two-player action adventure game about a pair of writers – one who writes sci-fi and one who writes fantasy – who get sucked into their fictional worlds. The two players have to work together to fight enemies and solve puzzles in levels that spring from science fiction and fantasy respectively. So in one level you might find yourselves riding Tron-style motorcycles and navigating gravity plates, while in another you’ll shape-shift into fantasy characters in an enchanted forest.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Levels also contain portals to “side stories,” which are basically minigames you can play, like riding on a Dune-like “sand fish” as it swims through the desert, or water skiing behind a drone flying across the sea.</p><p id="other-preorder-guides"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Other Preorder Guides">More Games Up for Preorder: </h2></p><div><ul><li data-cy="article-subtitle"><a data-cy="catalog-dealItem" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/assassins-creed-shadow-release-date-collectors-edition">Assassin's Creed Shadows Preorder Guide<!-- --> </a></li><li data-cy="article-subtitle"><a data-cy="catalog-dealItem" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/where-to-buy-avowed-xbox-pc-premium-edition">Avowed Preorder Guide<!-- --> </a></li><li data-cy="article-subtitle"><a data-cy="catalog-dealItem" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/where-to-preorder-capcom-fighting-collection-2">Capcom Fighting Collection 2 Preorder Guide<!-- --> </a></li><li data-cy="article-subtitle"><a data-cy="catalog-dealItem" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/where-to-buy-doom-the-dark-ages">Doom: The Dark Ages Preorder Guide<!-- --> </a></li><li data-cy="article-subtitle"><a data-cy="catalog-dealItem" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/where-to-buy-kingdom-come-deliverance-2-edition-differences">Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2 Preorder Guide<!-- --> </a></li><li data-cy="article-subtitle"><a data-cy="catalog-dealItem" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/where-to-buy-like-a-dragon-pirate-yakuza-in-hawaii-collectors-edition">Like a Dragon: Pirate Yakuza in Hawaii Preorder Guide<!-- --> </a></li><li data-cy="article-subtitle"><a data-cy="catalog-dealItem" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater-heres-what-comes-in-each-edition">Metal Gear Solid Delta Preorder Guide<!-- --> </a></li><li data-cy="article-subtitle"><a data-cy="catalog-dealItem" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/where-to-buy-monster-hunter-wilds">Monster Hunter Wilds Preorder Guide<!-- --> </a></li><li data-cy="article-subtitle"><a data-cy="catalog-dealItem" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/where-to-preorder-rune-factory-guardians-of-azuma">Rune Factory: Guardians of Azuma Preorder Guide<!-- --> </a></li><li data-cy="article-subtitle"><a data-cy="catalog-dealItem" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/sid-meiers-civilization-7-heres-what-comes-in-each-edition">Sid Meier's Civilization VII Preorder Guide<!-- --> </a></li><li data-cy="article-subtitle"><a data-cy="catalog-dealItem" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/where-to-buy-sniper-elite-resistance-ps5-xbox-pc-deluxe-edition">Sniper Elite: Resistance Preorder Guide<!-- --> </a></li><li data-cy="article-subtitle"><a data-cy="catalog-dealItem" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/where-to-buy-split-fiction-preorder-bonuses">Split Fiction Preorder Guide<!-- --> </a></li><li data-cy="article-subtitle"><a data-cy="catalog-dealItem" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/where-to-buy-suikoden-i-ii-hd-remaster">Suikoden 1 &amp; 2 HD Remaster Preorder Guide<!-- --> </a></li><li data-cy="article-subtitle"><a data-cy="catalog-dealItem" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/where-to-preorder-xenoblade-chronicles-x-definitive-edition">Xenoblade Chronicles X: Definitive Edition Preorder Guide<!-- --> </a></li></ul></div><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Chris Reed is a deals expert and commerce editor for IGN. You can follow him on Bluesky </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/chrislreed.com" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>@chrislreed.com</em></a><em>.</em></p></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Jan 28, 2025 5:13 pm</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[First in a Trilogy of Trailers Released for KARMA: The Dark World, Paying Homage to David Lynch]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/first-in-a-trilogy-of-trailers-released-for-karma-the-dark-world-paying-homage-to-david-lynch/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/first-in-a-trilogy-of-trailers-released-for-karma-the-dark-world-paying-homage-to-david-lynch.1093947/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/first-in-a-trilogy-of-trailers-released-for-karma-the-dark-world-paying-homage-to-david-lynch/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p><a href="https://wccftech.com/martha-is-dead-playstation-cut-content-face-peeling-masturbation/">Wired Productions</a> and Pollar Studio have released the first of three trailers for Karma: The Dark World in the lead-up to the release of the title. Karma: The Dark World is an upcoming first-person psychological horror that's set to channel iconic movie and game directors such as Lynch, Kojima, and Nolan. The first trailer is called 'ROAM.' At the moment, the release date for Karma: The Dark World still hasn't been announced, but it's said that it will soon be announced, most likely coinciding with the trailers that will be released. You can watch the brand-new trailer for the game below.</p>
<p><iframe title="KARMA: The Dark World | ROAM Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/gQA9fdoVetQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>As said above, this is the first of three trailers to be released for Karma: The Dark World, with the developers planning to release them to release key aspects of the game's story, as well as showing off the immersive world and intense gameplay mechanics that you'll have to contend with when playing the game. This first trailer is used to set the stage for the game, so players know what they are getting into when jumping into this first-person psychological horror.</p>
<p>"We are deeply saddened by the passing of director David Lynch. His art has had a profound influence on our game development, inspiring us to pay tribute to and learn from his work," said Ke Yang, Art Director of Pollard Studio. Even in the above trailer released, a quote by the iconic director is used to help set the scene.</p>
<p>For those who are hearing about this game for the first time, Karma: The Dark World is a psychological horror title where players will be playing as a Roam Agent and investigating the deepest and darkest secrets of their suspects' minds. The game takes place in an alternate timeline after the war in Germany. In the alternate timeline, Germany has instead fallen into a dystopian state that is ruled over by the Leviathan Corporation. The corporation uses mass surveillance and mind-bending technology to keep an eye on the citizens of the country, providing no privacy at all. Playing as Daniel McGovern, you investigate crime scenes and interview suspects to then report your findings back to Leviathan. However, it's not quite as it seems, and the world begins to crumble around him, where he doubts everything and anyone, including himself.</p>
<p>Karma: The Dark World has been developed in Unreal Engine 5 and will be <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1376200/KARMA_The_Dark_World/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">released soon on PC</a>, PlayStation 5, and Xbox.</p>
<p>Will you be playing Karma: The Dark World when it releases?</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Game Freak Is Giving Out Two Previously Unobtainable Shiny Pokémon]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/pokemon-home-shiny-enamorous-manaphy-bdsp-legends-1851749346</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/game-freak-is-giving-out-two-previously-unobtainable-shiny-pok%C3%A9mon.1093941/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/pokemon-home-shiny-enamorous-manaphy-bdsp-legends-1851749346<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="1bc64c59788745ec6c962d0ee19159b6" data-recommend-id="image://1bc64c59788745ec6c962d0ee19159b6" data-format="png" data-width="1855" data-height="1044" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Manaphy smiles at something off-screen." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Manaphy smiles at something off-screen." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->The Pokémon Company / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="1bc64c59788745ec6c962d0ee19159b6" data-recommend-id="image://1bc64c59788745ec6c962d0ee19159b6" data-format="png" data-width="1855" data-height="1044" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Manaphy smiles at something off-screen." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>If you’re the type of <em>Pokémon </em>fan who cares about collecting every variation of its 1,000+ monsters, that means constantly seeking out special events to receive a rare critter or searching for hours to find one with a low spawn rate hiding in the tall grass. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/pokemon-shiny-odds-scarlet-violet-ivs-red-gyarados-1850248457&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-shiny-odds-scarlet-violet-ivs-red-gyarados-1850248457">Shiny Pokémon</a></span> are the rarest of the rare, with a color scheme different from the regular versions of any given pocket monster. Some rare legendaries are even “shiny-locked,” meaning they will never appear in games with the alternate coloring. But good news: two of them are finally being made available, although you’ll have to complete the entire Pokédex in <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/pokemon-legends-arceus-gameplay-model-scarlet-violet-1849105177&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-legends-arceus-gameplay-model-scarlet-violet-1849105177"><em>Pokémon Legends: Arceus</em></a></span> or <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/the-new-pokemon-diamond-and-pearl-remakes-are-barebones-1848113404&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/the-new-pokemon-diamond-and-pearl-remakes-are-barebones-1848113404"><em>Brilliant Diamond </em>and <em>Shining Pearl</em></a></span><em> </em>to claim them.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196165" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="What’s Coming Out Beyond Pokémon: The Indigo Disk | The Week In Games" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="95" data-playlist="196165,195519,195905" data-current="196165"><div><p>What’s Coming Out Beyond Pokémon: The Indigo Disk | The Week In Games</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196165/196165_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196165/196165_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196165/196165_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196165/196165_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21711.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>Enamorous was one of the new Pokémon introduced in <em>Legends: Arceus</em> and has been shiny-locked since her debut in 2022. Game Freak is giving a shiny version out to anyone who has completed the Hisui Pokédex and deposited those Pokémon into the <em>Pokémon Home </em>storage app. So if you’ve caught all the Pokémon in <em>Legends: Arceus</em> and registered the completed Pokédex in <em>Home</em>, you’ll be rewarded with a shiny Enamorus: a brighter shade of pink than her normal form. There is no expiration on this offer, so if you haven’t finished the Pokédex, you don’t need to worry about scrambling to claim the shiny Fairy/Flying genie.</p><p>The second shiny Pokémon Game Freak is giving out is Manaphy. The fourth-generation mythical water-type creature was introduced as an event Pokémon in the original <em>Diamond </em>and <em>Pearl</em>. Until now, its shiny form was only obtainable <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5HQk_dJeYH4&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5HQk_dJeYH4" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">by an exploit</a></span>, but now you can claim one if you complete the Sinnoh Dex in Switch games <em>Brilliant Diamond </em>or <em>Shining Pearl</em>. To be clear, this does not mean you have to finish the entire National Dex including every Pokémon from all four generations—you’ll just need to catch the 151 from Turtwig to Manaphy, and then you’ll get a Manaphy with a blue-green color scheme.</p><p>Whether you’re a shiny hunter or not, everyone will have new Pokémon to chase later this year when <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/pokemon-legends-z-a-predictions-mega-evolution-kalos-1851316456&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-legends-z-a-predictions-mega-evolution-kalos-1851316456"><em>Pokémon Legends: Z-A</em></a></span><em> </em>launches on the Switch. We still haven’t seen the game in action, but did get a teaser at last year’s Pokémon Day. The Pokémon Company hasn’t announced any plans for a <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/pokemon-presents-day-stream-2024-direct-legends-z-a-tcg-1851289574&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-presents-day-stream-2024-direct-legends-z-a-tcg-1851289574">Pokémon Day</a></span> stream this year, but considering it’s become an annual tradition, we’ll likely see <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/pokemon-legends-z-a-kalos-war-az-switch-teaser-trailer-1851290552&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-legends-z-a-kalos-war-az-switch-teaser-trailer-1851290552"><em>Legends: Z-A</em></a></span><em> </em>on February 27.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cheating in VALORANT Spiked During Riot’s Holiday Break]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/cheating-in-valorant-spiked-during-riots-holiday-break/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cheating-in-valorant-spiked-during-riot%E2%80%99s-holiday-break.1093929/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/cheating-in-valorant-spiked-during-riots-holiday-break/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>In the the weeks before and after the start of 2025, when Riot Games employees are taking their annual holiday rest, recorded instances of cheating in VALORANT doubled across all regions. While the rise in cheating is now under control, the spike shows that it is a never-ending battle between developer and cheater.</p>



<p>But how did cheating in VALORANT get so bad during the holiday break? The head of VALORANT’s anti-cheat explained in a <a href="https://x.com/deteccphilippe/status/1883945555102957617" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">lengthy post</a> yesterday.</p>



<h2 id="h-cheating-in-valorant-reached-historic-levels-in-brazil">Cheating in VALORANT Reached Historic Levels in Brazil</h2>



<p>According to head of VALORANT anti-cheat Phillip “mirageofpenguins” Koskinas, Riot’s holiday break opened the door for cheaters to take advantage. During this time, with less resources and people available to detect cheaters and roll out fixes, “the cheaters that weren’t immediately detected started multiplying.”</p>



<figure><figcaption>Image via @deteccphilippe on X.</figcaption></figure>



<p>From the days before Christmas through the first week of January, the percentage of matches with a cheater detected rose in all regions, but none as dramatically as Brazil. In Brazil, which already had the highest percentage of cheaters of any region, the percentage of matches with a cheater spiked from just under 5% to around 12%. According to Riot, Brazil cheaters regularly use a “pixelbot” that reads the screen, identifies enemy outlines and heads, and then submits mouse events to the OS that points the cheater towards that enemy.</p>



<p>The pixelbot cheats popular amongst Brazil cheaters are supposedly cheap and easy to install, but Riot says they’re also easy to spot. Once the Riot holiday break ended and normal anti-cheat detection resumed, the cheater percentage in Brazil (and other regions) dropped dramatically to a lower level than it was before the break. Riot says the the January 10-13 weekend featured its “highest sustained ban velocity on record, with almost seven suspensions occurring every minute.”</p>



<p>In yesterday’s post, Riot admitted that the fight against cheaters will never end. Because VALORANT is free and there’s little to no barrier to entry, no cheater can be truly permanently exiled. While Riot team remains committed to disrupting cheaters, they also plan to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/valorant-2025-new-agents-more-map-variety-ranked-protections/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">implement ranked rollback in the next act</a>, which restore rank rating to players that lost against caught cheaters.</p>



<p>Did you notice a spike in cheaters when you played VALORANT during the holiday? Let us know in the comments below or on our&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more esports news, check out our <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/into-the-breach-shuts-down-after-esports-ceo-embezzles-thousands/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">coverage of an esports org CEO embezzling thousands from his organization.</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MLB The Show 25 announced for PS5, Xbox Series, and Switch]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/01/mlb-the-show-25-announced-for-ps5-xbox-series-and-switch</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mlb-the-show-25-announced-for-ps5-xbox-series-and-switch.1093923/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/01/mlb-the-show-25-announced-for-ps5-xbox-series-and-switch<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Not available via Game Pass this year.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>PUblisher <a title="Companies > Sony Interactive Entertainment [4,945 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sony-group-corporation/sony-interactive-entertainment">Sony Interactive Entertainment</a> and developer <a title="Companies > San Diego Studio [42 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sony-group-corporation/sony-interactive-entertainment/san-diego-studio">San Diego Studio</a> have <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2025/01/28/mlb-the-show-25-cover-athletes-revealed-paul-skenes-elly-de-la-cruz-and-gunnar-henderson/" target="_blank">announced</a> <em><a title="Games > MLB The Show 25 [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/mlb-the-show-25">MLB The Show 25</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,721 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [6,615 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, and Switch. It will launch on March 18, with early access for Digital Deluxe Edition buyers beginning March 14. Unlike previous years, <em>MLB The Show 25</em> will not be available via Game Pass. <span id="more-940834"></span></p><p>Paul Skenes, Elly De La Cruz, and Gunnar Henderson will be featured on <em>MLB The Show 25</em>‘s first-ever three-athlete cover. Here are short profiles for each player:</p><blockquote><ul><li><strong>Paul Skenes</strong>&nbsp;– Paul Skenes’ journey began in high school and continued through college, where he cemented his status as one of the most talented young pitchers in baseball by winning a national championship before being selected as the No. 1 overall pick by the Pittsburgh Pirates in the 2023 MLB Draft. The following season, Skenes made his MLB debut and became the first player in MLB history to start the All-Star Game just one year after being drafted. He capped off an incredible 2024 season by earning National League Rookie of the Year honors and being named to the All-MLB First Team. His story and skillset align perfectly with Road to the Show, where you can chart your own path to greatness.</li><li><strong>Elly De La Cruz</strong> – Elly De La Cruz’s meteoric rise from the minors to the majors perfectly captures the excitement of working up to a big league debut and becoming a star. Since making his Major League debut in 2023 with the Cincinnati Reds, Elly has consistently proven to be one of the most electrifying players on the field. He became one of the youngest players in MLB history to hit for the cycle and is renowned for his blazing speed on the bases and his cannon-like arm, further cementing his status as one of the league’s most promising talents. The 2024 All-Star showcases an impressive five-tool skillset and a dynamic switch-hitting approach—exactly what <em>MLB The Show</em> fans dream of when developing or acquiring their starting shortstop in Franchise mode.</li><li><strong>Gunnar Henderson</strong> – Rounding out this triple play of talent is the 2023 American League Rookie of the Year, Gunnar Henderson. Selected 42nd overall in the 2019 MLB Draft, Gunnar quickly ascended through the Orioles’ farm system, making his MLB debut late in the 2022 season. Heading into 2023, he was named the #1 prospect on MLB’s Top 100 list. In his first full season in the majors, Gunnar became a cornerstone of the Orioles’ young core, helping lead the team to its first postseason appearance in seven years. His outstanding performance earned him AL Rookie of the Year honors and a Silver Slugger Award. Gunnar’s star continued to rise in 2024, as he was selected to start in the MLB All-Star Game and compete in the Home Run Derby. His MLB journey resonates deeply with <em>MLB The Show</em> fans who strive to dominate head-to-head competition in their pursuit of greatness on the diamond.</li></ul></blockquote><p>And here is a short description of the game:</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <blockquote><p>Forge your baseball dreams in <em>MLB The Show 25</em>—the definitive baseball journey, powered by you.</p><p>Ignite your passion and build your very own path to greatness—from high school all the way to the Hall of Fame! Along the way, connect with iconic baseball stars in fan-favorite modes—updated with new ways to play. <em>MLB The Show 25</em> is built by baseball fans, for baseball fans.</p><p>This lovingly crafted entry in the series comes complete with a comprehensive suite of gameplay and quality-of-life enhancements. All this, designed from the ground up to get you to the action faster.</p></blockquote><p>The first gameplay trailer for <em>MLB The Show 25</em> will premiere on <a href="https://www.timeanddate.com/worldclock/fixedtime.html?iso=20250204T1700" target="_blank">February 4 at 9:00 a.m. PT / 12:00 p.m. ET</a>. You will be able to watch it on <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@SonySanDiego" target="_blank">YouTube</a>.</p><p>Watch the cover athletes reveal trailer below.</p><h2><span>Cover Athletes Reveal Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="MLB The Show 25 | Cover Athletes Reveal" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/kXJBM9PAXD0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WWE 2K25 Preorders Are Live At Amazon - Get 5 Bonus Wrestlers For MyFaction]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/wwe-2k25-preorders-are-live-at-amazon-get-5-bonus-wrestlers-for-myfaction/1100-6529068/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/wwe-2k25-preorders-are-live-at-amazon-get-5-bonus-wrestlers-for-myfaction.1093920/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/wwe-2k25-preorders-are-live-at-amazon-get-5-bonus-wrestlers-for-myfaction/1100-6529068/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-main">

      
                    
  
              <header id="masthead"><nav></nav></header>      
                            <div id="site-wrapper" role="main">
          <div id="default-content">
        
          <p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p>
  
    <article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529068">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>WWE 2K25 is now <a href="https://www.amazon.com/stores/page/preview?isSlp=1&amp;isPreview=1&amp;asins=B0DV9TT5XT,B0DV9TPVMP,B0DV9TVSXG&amp;tag=gamespot-preorders-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">available to preorder</a> ahead of its <strong>March 14</strong> release, with Roman Reigns serving as the cover star. The latest entry in the annual wrestling sim series will feature a slew of quality-of-life updates as well as brand-new game modes. Most notably, 2K is introducing The Island, an online world where you can interact and compete with other players. WWE 2K25 sounds like it could be one of the most expansive wrestling sims to date. If you're interested in stepping into the ring on launch day, you can get a handful of cool bonuses by preordering your copy early.</p><p>From the basic standard edition to the premium Bloodlines Edition that grants one-week early access, here’s a look at what’s included with every version of WWE 2K25</p><h2>WWE 2K25 Preorder Bonuses</h2><p>Regardless of which version of WWE 2K25 you preorder, you’ll get the Wyatt Sicks DLC pack, which comes with five playable Superstars for the card-collecting MyFaction mode. Here are the five Persona Cards you'll get with your preorder:</p><ul><li>Uncle Howdy</li><li>Dexter Lumis</li><li>Nikki Cross</li><li>Joe Gacy</li><li>Erick Rowan</li></ul><p>If you’re playing on PS5 or Xbox Series X, you’ll get Uncle Howdy and Nikki Cross mask cosmetics for The Island. And if you preorder a digital version, the WWE 2K24 Cross-Gen base game is also included with your purchase.</p><div title="6529068 - WWE 2K25 Preorder Guide" data-embed-type="buylink" data-ref-id="3109" data-template="4" data-size="buylink__listicle" data-title="6529068 - WWE 2K25 Preorder Guide" data-collection="">                                                                     <div>             <h2>                    <a href="https://www.amazon.com/stores/page/preview?isSlp=1&amp;isPreview=1&amp;asins=B0DV9TT5XT,B0DV9TPVMP,B0DV9TVSXG&amp;tag=gamespot-preorders-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/stores\/page\/preview?isSlp=1&amp;isPreview=1&amp;asins=B0DV9TT5XT,B0DV9TPVMP,B0DV9TVSXG&amp;tag=gamespot-preorders-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/stores/page/preview?isSlp=1&amp;isPreview=1&amp;asins=B0DV9TT5XT,B0DV9TPVMP,B0DV9TVSXG&amp;tag=gamespot-preorders-20">WWE 2K25 Standard Edition</a>       </h2>                                   <h3>                      <a href="https://www.amazon.com/stores/page/preview?isSlp=1&amp;isPreview=1&amp;asins=B0DV9TT5XT,B0DV9TPVMP,B0DV9TVSXG&amp;tag=gamespot-preorders-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/stores\/page\/preview?isSlp=1&amp;isPreview=1&amp;asins=B0DV9TT5XT,B0DV9TPVMP,B0DV9TVSXG&amp;tag=gamespot-preorders-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/stores/page/preview?isSlp=1&amp;isPreview=1&amp;asins=B0DV9TT5XT,B0DV9TPVMP,B0DV9TVSXG&amp;tag=gamespot-preorders-20">$70</a>         </h3>                                                                                                                      <p>Featuring Roman Reigns as the cover star, this edition of the game gets you the base game plus any eligible preorder bonuses. It includes dual entitlement across PS5 and PS4 or Xbox Series X and Xbox One. Physical preorders are live at <a href="https://www.amazon.com/stores/page/preview?isSlp=1&amp;isPreview=1&amp;asins=B0DV9TT5XT,B0DV9TPVMP,B0DV9TVSXG&amp;tag=gamespot-preorders-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Amazon</a>, <a href="https://howl.link/xlbc7fk5j7c62?article_name=Gamespot&amp;article_url=https://www.gamespot.com/17380792646093?u1=subid_value" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Best Buy</a>, and <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fclick.linksynergy.com%2Fdeeplink%3Fid%3DVZfI20jEa0c%26mid%3D24348%26u1%3Dsubid_value%26murl%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Fvideo-games%2Fplaystation-5%2Fproducts%2Fwwe-2k25---playstation-5%2F421403.html&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fwwe-2k25-preorders-are-live-at-amazon-get-5-bonus-wrestlers-for-myfaction%2F1100-6529068%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">GameStop</a>, while digital copies can be found on the <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/product/UP1001-PPSA22695_00-WWE2K25000000000/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">PS Store</a>, <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/wwe2k25-standardedition/9P6NQMP5LXD6" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Xbox Store</a>, and <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2878960/WWE_2K25/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Steam</a>.</p>                      </div>                                                                     <div>             <h2>                    <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/product/UP1001-PPSA22695_00-WWE2K25DEADMANED/" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/store.playstation.com\/en-us\/product\/UP1001-PPSA22695_00-WWE2K25DEADMANED\/&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/product/UP1001-PPSA22695_00-WWE2K25DEADMANED/">WWE 2K25 Deadman Edition</a>       </h2>                                   <h3>                      <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/product/UP1001-PPSA22695_00-WWE2K25DEADMANED/" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/store.playstation.com\/en-us\/product\/UP1001-PPSA22695_00-WWE2K25DEADMANED\/&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/product/UP1001-PPSA22695_00-WWE2K25DEADMANED/">$100</a>         </h3>                                                                                                                      <div><p>Featuring The Undertaker as its cover star, this version is loaded with digital goodies. Along with the Wyatt Sicks DLC pack, here’s what else is included with the Deadman Edition:</p><ul><li>Mattel Elite “Greatest Hits” Undertaker</li><li>Original Undertaker</li><li>Mattel Elite “Greatest Hits” Undertaker Persona Card</li><li>Original Undertaker Persona Card</li><li>Useable Urn Object</li><li>Undertaker ’95 Mask</li><li>Brother Love Manager</li><li>Season Pass (Unlocks 5 Characters)</li><li>15,000 VC</li></ul></div>                      </div>                                                                     <div>             <h2>                    <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/product/UP1001-PPSA22695_00-WWE2K25BLOODLINE/" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/store.playstation.com\/en-us\/product\/UP1001-PPSA22695_00-WWE2K25BLOODLINE\/&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/product/UP1001-PPSA22695_00-WWE2K25BLOODLINE/">WWE 2K25 Bloodline Edition</a>       </h2>                                   <h3>                      <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/product/UP1001-PPSA22695_00-WWE2K25BLOODLINE/" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/store.playstation.com\/en-us\/product\/UP1001-PPSA22695_00-WWE2K25BLOODLINE\/&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/product/UP1001-PPSA22695_00-WWE2K25BLOODLINE/">$130</a>         </h3>                                                                                                                      <div><p>It’s not cheap, but this premium version of WWE 2K25 includes heaps of DLC content plus the Ringside Pass. You’ll also gain <strong>early access to the game on March 7 instead of March 14</strong>. Along with everything in the above versions, here’s what else is part of the Bloodline Edition.</p><ul><li>Ringside Pass (Season Pass plus Superstar Mega-Boost)</li><li>The Rock Nation of Domination Pack: Persona Card and Playable Character</li><li>Mattel Elite Series 114 Jey Uso Persona Card</li><li>Mattel Elite “Greatest Hits” Roman Reigns Persona Card</li><li>Mattel Elite Series 114 Jey Uso</li><li>Mattel Elite “Greatest Hits” Roman Reigns</li><li>Family Above All Hoodie (PS5 and Xbox Series X)</li><li>OTC Shirt (PS5 and Xbox Series X)</li><li>Yeet Tank Top (PS5 and Xbox Series X)</li><li>Yeet Sunglasses (PS5 and Xbox Series X)</li><li>32,500 VC (Steam)</li><li>WrestleMania 41 Arena</li><li>WrestleMania 41 Main Event Superstars Persona Cards</li><li>WrestleMania 41 Playable Characters</li></ul><p>Much of the WrestleMania 41 content details are yet to be announced, though it’ll likely be a fantastic inclusion and a good reason to snag the Bloodline Edition. We’ll update this when official details on playable characters are announced.</p></div>                      </div>   </div><div data-embed-type="pinbox" data-ref-id="4304">  <ul>                              <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/super-mario-world-lego-set-is-discounted-at-amazon-but-probably-not-for-long/1100-6525283/">Super Mario World Lego Set Is Discounted At Amazon, But Probably Not For Long</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fortnite-festival-riffmaster-wireless-guitar-controller-gets-rare-discount/1100-6528970/">Fortnite Festival Riffmaster Wireless Guitar Controller Gets Rare Discount</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/donkey-kong-country-returns-hd-is-discounted-on-launch-day/1100-6524388/">Donkey Kong Country Returns HD Is Discounted On Launch Day</a></li>                          <li>         <span>+ Show More More Gaming, Tech, and Entertainment Deals &amp; Preorders Links (5)</span>       </li>          <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/last-chance-to-grab-3-movies-on-4k-blu-ray-for-only-33-at-amazon/1100-6528683/">Last Chance To Grab 3 Movies On 4K Blu-Ray For Only $33 At Amazon</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/final-fantasy-7-remake-ps5-reprint-restocked-at-amazon/1100-6528630/">Final Fantasy 7 Remake Physical Edition Gets PS5 Reprint - Snag It While You Can</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-2500-piece-legend-of-zelda-lego-set-is-now-available-at-amazon/1100-6523747/">The 2,500-Piece Legend Of Zelda Lego Set Is Now Available At Amazon</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/mario-kart-lego-sets-are-available-now-check-out-all-six-in-the-launch-lineup/1100-6528603/">Mario Kart Lego Sets Are Available Now - Check Out All Six In The Launch Lineup</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fortnite-lego-sets-launch-at-major-retailers-including-amazon-and-walmart/1100-6528629/">Fortnite Lego Sets Launch At Major Retailers, Including Amazon And Walmart</a></li>   </ul> </div>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/105566936584242225941?rel=author">Jon Bitner</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article>

    
  

</div>
                      <meta itemprop="seamless-content-list-items" data-list-items="[{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6528999&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/the-stylish-new-rpg-clair-obscure-expedition-33-a-collectors-edition\/1100-6528999\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6528927&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/save-on-thousands-of-pc-games-and-unlock-free-steam-keys-during-fanaticals-lunar-new-year-sale\/1100-6528927\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6528961&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/several-popular-gaming-subreddits-are-banning-content-pulled-from-x\/1100-6528961\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6528964&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/dragon-age-the-veilguard-had-far-fewer-players-than-ea-expected\/1100-6528964\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6528966&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/celeste-devs-next-project-earthblade-officially-canceled\/1100-6528966\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6528932&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/netflix-is-raising-prices-again-as-it-discusses-vision-for-video-games\/1100-6528932\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6528936&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/new-xbox-console-update-essentially-removes-external-storage-drive-limits\/1100-6528936\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6528939&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/mortal-kombat-1-adds-a-secret-fight-against-pink-floyd-kind-of\/1100-6528939\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6528937&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/death-stranding-2-crosses-new-development-milestone-as-deadpool-actor-finishes-scenes\/1100-6528937\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6528935&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/sign-up-for-new-sega-account-system-get-a-free-like-a-dragon-pirate-yakuza-costume\/1100-6528935\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6528933&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/switch-2-video-reveals-how-snappy-joy-con-removal-works\/1100-6528933\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6528934&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/chappell-roans-idea-of-a-fun-night-involves-eating-an-edible-and-playing-video-games\/1100-6528934\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6528944&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/wolverine-dev-refuses-to-comment-on-2025-release-date-acknowledges-pent-up-excitement\/1100-6528944\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6528538&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/quentin-tarantinos-kill-bill-duology-is-now-available-on-4k-blu-ray\/1100-6528538\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6528940&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/borderlands-is-up-for-worst-movie-and-more-at-the-razzies\/1100-6528940\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6528945&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/insomniac-games-teases-potential-return-to-the-movies-under-its-new-leadership\/1100-6528945\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6528938&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/cod-black-ops-6-and-warzone-season-2-trailer-reveals-brand-new-maps-dual-katanas-and-zombies-staffs\/1100-6528938\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6528950&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/diablo-4-season-7-all-seasonal-journey-rewards-and-objectives\/1100-6528950\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6528946&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/house-the-complete-series-releases-on-blu-ray-next-week\/1100-6528946\/&quot;}]">
            </div>
              
    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MLB The Show 25 Launches In March, But Won't Be On Game Pass This Year]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/mlb-the-show-25-launches-in-march-but-wont-be-on-game-pass-this-year/1100-6529072/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mlb-the-show-25-launches-in-march-but-wont-be-on-game-pass-this-year.1093917/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/mlb-the-show-25-launches-in-march-but-wont-be-on-game-pass-this-year/1100-6529072/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529072">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Sony Santa Monica has <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2025/01/28/mlb-the-show-25-cover-athletes-revealed-paul-skenes-elly-de-la-cruz-and-gunnar-henderson/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">announced</a> that MLB The Show 25 will launch on March 18 for PS5, Nintendo Switch, and Xbox Series X|S. Unlike the previous three entries, MLB The Show 25 will not be on Xbox Game Pass at launch.</p><p>MLB The Show 25 is celebrating its 20th anniversary, and is featuring three cover athletes instead of just one this year: Pittsburgh Pirates' Paul Skenes, Cincinnati Reds' Elly De La Cruz, and Baltimore Orioles' Gunnar Henderson.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/scale_super/1646/16465123/4434517-image_2025-01-28_112647787.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4434517" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1088" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/scale_super/1646/16465123/4434517-image_2025-01-28_112647787.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4434517"></a><figcaption>MLB The Show 25's cover athletes</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/scale_super/1646/16465123/4434517-image_2025-01-28_112647787.jpg"></figure><p>Sony Santa Monica also clarified that MLB The Show 25 "will not be on platform subscription services in 2025." This rules out the game being added to PlayStation Plus or Xbox Game Pass this year, but it's still possible that it could be added to gaming subscriptions in 2026 and beyond. This is a big departure given that when the series went multiplatform starting with <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/sonys-mlb-the-show-21-is-included-on-xbox-game-pass-on-april-20/1100-6489677/" data-ref-id="1100-6489677">MLB The Show 21</a>, it and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/one-of-playstations-biggest-games-of-the-year-will-be-on-game-pass-again/1100-6520708/" data-ref-id="1100-6520708">each subsequent entry</a> also released for Xbox Game Pass on launch day.</p><p>Preorders start on February 4, and those who preorder the Digital Deluxe Edition will receive early access to the game on March 14. You can also sign up for the MLB The Show Scouting Report. Starting in April 2025, subscribers will receive a unique pack each month filled with in-game rewards through December 2025.</p><p>MLB The Show 25's first gameplay trailer will be revealed on February 4 at 9 AM PT / 12 PM ET, along with a features deep dive from MLB Network host Robert Flores at a later date.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/115776530127739146123?rel=author">George Yang</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>