<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 20:03:05 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fallout Creator Tim Cain Is Out of Retirement and Back With Obsidian]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/tim-cain-return-obsidian-fallout</link>
            <guid>1374793</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Legendary industry veteran and <em>Fallout </em>creator Tim Cain has announced that he's made a return to Obsidian Entertainment, and it's the real deal; he's no contractor, but rather a "full-time employee".</p><p>In a video posted on his YouTube channel today, Cain explained that he's returned to the <em>Fallout: New Vegas </em>and <em>Grounded </em>studio "in person" rather than remotely, and that this means he's no longer "working in other places", although there's at least one project on which Cain worked apart from Obsidian that has yet to be released.</p><p>Cain says that the period between 2020 and 2025 was "a weird time in the industry", and as such, there are games on which he's worked that he isn't sure will see the light of day, too. How tantalizing!</p><figure role="group">
<article>
  
      
  

  </article>

<figcaption><em>Fallout </em>creator Tim Cain has returned to Obsidian Entertainment.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Unfortunately, Cain also says he can't elaborate on the project on which he's currently working at Obsidian, but that "you're not gonna guess right" if you try to guess what it is, so it sounds like a novel idea, whatever it might be.</p><p>He also says he's "a lot less retired now than [he] was before", so his previous state of "semi-retirement" is no longer applicable. Additionally, Cain's YouTube channel will remain operational, since "no-one at Obsidian has even remotely suggested that [he has] to stop it".</p><p>Tim Cain first joined Obsidian in 2011, going on to work on the studio's successfully Kickstarted RPG <em>Pillars of Eternity</em>, as well as serving as one of the directors for <a href="https://techraptor.net/games/outer-worlds" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="cd8a1852-2307-4184-b0df-b9afab69154e" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">2019's <em>The Outer Worlds</em></a>. He also worked as a creative consultant on <a href="https://techraptor.net/games/outer-worlds-2" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="f7b9881c-df25-4849-881d-eafe092b40f7" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">this year's <em>The Outer Worlds 2</em></a>, albeit not as a full-time employee.</p><p>You can check out Cain's full video, in which he also discusses other recent events in his life, right here.</p>
<p>It remains to be seen exactly what Tim Cain will do with Obsidian now he's back with the company; let's hope that Microsoft sees sense and opts to give the studio another chance at a <em>Fallout </em>game. Stay tuned for more.</p></div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/tim-cain-return-obsidian-fallout]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Horses is a hit, but its studio might still be in trouble]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/839164/horses-interview-santa-ragione-steam-ban-censorship</link>
            <guid>1374790</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>After indie narrative horror game <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/837278/horses-banned-steam-epic-games-store"><em>Horses</em></a> was banned from Steam two years ago, it put the studio, Santa Ragione, at risk of closure. Studio cofounder and <em>Horses </em>producer Pietro Righi Riva had to make a difficult phone call to the game’s director, Italian filmmaker Andrea Lucco Borlera. “I was terrified for him,” Riva said in an interview with <em>The Verge</em>. “This was his first game and he put so much work, so much passion, so many years, and it was supposed to be his big breakthrough.”</p><div><p>But <em>Horses</em> has broken through even without Steam. Riva’s <a href="https://www.horses.wtf/BannedFromSteam/index.html">detailed accounting of the game’s multiple storefront bans</a> caught the attention of journalists, developers, and curious gamers eager to see <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/games/2025/dec/05/horror-game-horses-has-been-banned-from-sale-but-is-it-as-controversial-as-youd-think">just what was so objectionable</a> that the game couldn’t be sold on Steam alongside the likes of <em>Sex Standing</em> or <em>Sex with Hitler 2</em>. That attention has made <em>Horses</em> the video game cause célèbre of the moment, <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/santaragione.com/post/3m73jkbnhxk2i">catapulting it to bestseller status on GOG.com</a>.</p></div><p>But while this all sounds like a happy ending, Riva isn’t ready to breathe easy just yet. “I’m relieved because with all this attention, I’m probably going to be able to give back most of the money [roughly half of $100,000] that I had to borrow,” he said. “But we’re not out of the [woods] yet, no.”</p><div><p><cite>Image: Santa Ragione Game Studio</cite></p></div><p><em>Horses</em> is a short, crunchy-looking game, boasting Dreamcast-era graphics with gameplay that’s no more involved than clicking things to put them in and take them out of your inventory. And while Santa Ragione has had success with <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/video-games/reviews/saturnalia-review/"><em>Saturnalia</em></a> and <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/milky-way-prince-the-vampire-star-review-an-artfully-told-oppressively-bleak-story"><em>Milky Way Prince</em></a> before the bans, it was largely a little-known developer. Riva is aware of how that looks, acknowledging that the bans have been instrumental in <em>Horses</em> punching through the noise.</p><p>“There is no way the same kind of interest would have happened,” he said. And despite that first difficult call, Riva says Borlera is quite pleased at what the bans have done for his game. “He’s extremely happy with the reception that the game is getting,” Riva said. “People are reading into the game and [...] engaging with it in a way that he hoped.”</p><div><p>“There is no way the same kind of interest would have happened.”</p></div><p>That engagement, though, isn’t enough to make up for the access Steam could have provided. While Riva is grateful for the support of gamers and storefronts like GOG, it’s not enough, and he’s still very much in fear of Santa Ragione’s future. “Even with all the publicity, all the reporting, all the reviews, everything else,” he said. “This still does not compare to the kind of audience we would have on Steam.”</p><p>Steam has an outsize influence on the PC video game market. The indie studios that cannot afford the costs of porting their games to consoles are at the mercy of Valve’s <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/12/18/16783394/you-must-be-18-or-older-to-enter-game-banned-porn-steam">vague</a>, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/6/1/17417790/steam-pornography-rules-guidelines-porn-visual-novels">capricious</a>, and often <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/15/24297364/steam-extremist-content-moderation-us-senator-warner-letter">inconsistent</a> moderation whims. Though <em>Horses </em>has found a roundabout way to relative success without it, Riva said that journey has been traumatic, affecting not just him and his team but his peers and future projects.</p><p>“I think there is going to be, in my case, and in other people’s case, a certain degree of self-censorship,” he said. “It’s terrifying, and it’s going to make people make safer and safer games, me included.”</p><div><p><span><strong>Follow topics and authors</strong> from this story to see more like this in your personalized homepage feed and to receive email updates.</span></p><ul><li id="follow-author-article_footer-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTAy"><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span><span>Ash Parrish</span></span></span></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li></ul></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/news/839164/horses-interview-santa-ragione-steam-ban-censorship]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Netflix to buy Warner Bros for $82.7 billion, including the creators of Batman Arkham, Mortal Kombat and Mad Max]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/netflix-to-buy-warner-bros-for-827-billion-including-the-developers-of-batman-arkham-mortal-kombat-and-mad-max</link>
            <guid>1374787</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Press release puts the focus on TV and film</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arkham-city-header.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arkham-city-header.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arkham-city-header.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arkham-city-header.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arkham-city-header.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arkham-city-header.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arkham-city-header.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arkham-city-header.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arkham-city-header.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Warner Bros. Interactive Entertainment</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>It’s after 5pm on a Friday, but no force on this Earth can stop me hurrying back to my desk to report on a large financial transaction. Also, we should have written this up earlier, but we were busy deciding which are the objectively correct <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-pc-games-of-all-time">100 best PC games</a>. </p>
<p>I’m not… sure we put any Warner Bros games in that list. I’ve just done a CTRL-F for “Batman” and got zero results. I know, WTF - Arkham Asylum is amazing. Mark needs to stop driving things and think about capes for a change. I’m sure Warner Bros aren’t too bothered about this gross oversight right now, though. Netflix have just revealed plans to buy their entertainment business for $82.7 billion in stock and cash.</p><!--more-->
<p>The deal follows an announcement in June that Warner would split in two, with one “Streaming &amp; Studios” operation including Warner Bros. Motion Picture Group, DC Studios and HBO, while the other, “Global Networks”, encompasses sports and TV news such as TNT and CNN. Netflix want to buy the Streaming &amp; Studios part, pending regulatory approvals in the next 12-18 months, which includes several game studios: <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/hogwarts-legacy">Hogwarts Legacy</a> creators Avalanche (who've also developed <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/just-cause">Just Cause</a> games for other people), Lego devs TT Games, Mortal Kombat studio NetherRealm and Rocksteady of Batman Arkham fame, who also made Suicide Squad: Kill The Justice League. </p>
<p>As with any large corporate acquisition, it seems likely all this is going to lead to layoffs and cancellations as the acquiring company seek to recoup some of their outlay, and show the shareholders they're running a tight ship. Assuming the deal goes through, Netflix have said they hope "to realize at least $2-3 billion of cost savings per year" over three years.</p><p>Warner’s games division haven’t been doing well lately, and there have already been some major cuts. Suicide Squad was a <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/suicide-squad-failed-for-all-the-reasons-you-could-have-guess-it-failed-report-says">disaster</a>, leading to layoffs at Rocksteady this January. In February, Warner <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/warner-bros-close-monolith-creators-of-fear-condemned-shadow-of-mordor-and-wonder-woman">closed Monolith, Player First Games and Warner Bros Games San Diego</a>. In March, Bloomberg reported <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-03-27/warner-bros-cancels-planned-hogwarts-legacy-game-expansion">that a Hogwarts Legacy expansion had been cancelled</a>. In May, Warner <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/warner-and-dc-smash-em-up-multiversus-joins-the-pile-of-dead-live-service-games">pulled support for comicbook Smash ‘em up MultiVersus</a><a></a> while announcing the end of major updates for NetherRealm’s Mortal Kombat 1; they also revealed <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/warner-bros-failed-to-launch-a-game-last-quarter-resulting-in-48-drop-in-gaming-revenue">a 48% revenue drop for their most recent financial quarter</a>.</p>
<p>It’s naturally a bit worrisome in this context that Netflix’s press release announcing the proposed acquisition <a href="https://about.netflix.com/en/news/netflix-to-acquire-warner-bros">doesn’t really mention games</a>, save for Squid Game and Game Of Thrones. The focus is firmly on broader “entertainment”, streaming and Warner’s various intellectual properties. Netflix already have a videogame business, of course, but they’ve experienced <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/netflixs-team-blue-of-halo-overwatch-and-god-of-war-vets-close-without-a-single-game-to-their-name">reversals of their own</a> in the past couple of years, and seem inclined to focus right now on TV and film.</p>

        </div>

      </article>




        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/netflix-to-buy-warner-bros-for-827-billion-including-the-developers-of-batman-arkham-mortal-kombat-and-mad-max]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No Matter What The Game Awards Hell Statue Is For, Geoff Keighley Wins]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/game-awards-statue-elder-scrolls-6-geoff-keighley-2000651010</link>
            <guid>1374784</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><span>For one night in 2005, the Mojave Desert glowed green. Microsoft inexplicably launched its then-new console, the Xbox 360, with a release event in a hangar in the desert. A Microsoft executive told Gizmodo in 2005 </span><a href="https://gizmodo.com/xbox-360-zero-hour-burning-man-as-interpreted-by-micro-138815"><span>that it was supposed to resemble Burning Man</span></a><span>, the art festival where Silicon Valley’s rich reenact the prelude to a </span><i><span>BioShock</span></i><span> game.. Another executive called it an “</span><a href="https://mashable.com/article/xbox-360-launch-event-zero-hour-photos"><span>Xbox 360 oasis</span><span>.</span></a><span>” Journalists and Xbox fans—it was both a press event and a player launch party—lounged on beanbags to play the hottest new console at one of dozens of stations. Microsoft served alcohol from paneled domes that are now synonymous with </span><a href="https://www.npr.org/sections/health-shots/2020/12/31/950178368/yurts-igloos-and-pop-up-domes-how-safe-is-outside-restaurant-dining-this-winter"><span>covid-era outdoor dining</span></a><span>.</span></p> <p><span>These sorts of big budget gaming events, where companies spared no expense on luring press and fans into weird places—all in the name of promoting new hardware or games—don’t exist much anymore. But 20 years later, an artifact channeling that bygone era has reemerged, once again, this time in the Colorado desert: a </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/geoff-keighley-desert-statue-tga-diablo-4-2000649133"><span>mysterious demonic statue</span></a><span> with the bodies of the damned etched into its sides.</span></p>

 <h2>The Game Awards’ portal to hell</h2> <p><span>The Game Awards overseer Geoff Keighley posted a photo of the mysterious statue with a </span><a href="https://what3words.com/regal.inspiring.thickness"><span>geocode pointing people to an area of Joshua Tree National Park</span></a><span>, just off of Yucca Mesa Road. Tendrils glow red from the statue at night, illuminating the screaming skeletons of both humans and creatures. Several people who’ve visited the statue have posted about it on social media and Reddit. Apparently, a security guard watches over the relic—”cool dude,” </span><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/gaming/comments/1pcvnhp/so_i_got_to_visit_the_statue/"><span>according to Reddit user TautSexyElfKing</span></a><span>—and the statue makes sounds. Another person instructed others to knock on the door, saying something else will knock back.</span></p>

 <p><span>“It was very ambient and hellish sounding,” TautSexyElfKing said. “Almost like it was a doorway and on the other side was a large cavern with demons lurking about the other side. Maybe some light growling-ish sounds. There wasn’t anything I could make out in particular that would be a hint or anything”</span></p>

 <p><span>To the unaware, it looks like the kind of thing you might find at Burning Man, or maybe an altar for worshipping the devil. But Keighley’s post is a signal to gamers that this is an Easter egg—a marketing stunt. It’s working, not because it’s hyping people up for any specific game or console, but because it’s pushing people toward Keighley’s pride and joy: an end of year bash produced, owned, and hosted by the man himself.</span></p>

 <p><span>The statue itself is ambiguous enough that spectators can map it onto whatever’s at the top of their Game Awards World Premier wishlist. It’s off Yucca Mesa Road, so it must be for </span><i><span>Half-Life 3</span></i><span>. The demonic symbols are an obvious reference to </span><i><span>Diablo 4</span></i><span>‘s next expansion. No, wait—</span><a href="https://x.com/BT_BlackThunder/status/1994865924206452744"><span>maybe that’s </span><i><span>God of War</span></i></a><span>. It’s essentially a hell portal, which clearly means </span><i><span>Doom</span></i><span>. I don’t know, maybe </span><i><span>Elder Scrolls 6</span></i><span>? Or, perhaps, </span><a href="https://x.com/NoMansSky/status/1995954970626326556"><span>Keighley is simply himself opening a portal to hell</span></a><span> and </span><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/gaming/comments/1pdt9n9/what_if_its_not_teasing_a_game_at_all_and_geoff/"><span>intends to destroy the whole dang world</span></a><span>.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">no one is considering that Geoff is simply opening a hell portal <a href="https://t.co/XKEgj6N3e6">https://t.co/XKEgj6N3e6</a></p> <p>— Sean Murray (@NoMansSky) <a href="https://twitter.com/NoMansSky/status/1995954970626326556?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 2, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <p><span>Apparently everyone is wrong, </span><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/PS5/comments/1pcf4dp/jason_schreier_says_that_the_game_awards_statue/"><span>according to</span><i><span> Bloomberg</span></i><span> reporter Jason Schreier</span></a><span>, who said it’s not </span><i><span>Diablo 4</span></i><span> or </span><i><span>Elder Scrolls 6</span></i><span>. “</span><span>I don’t currently plan on reporting what it is, sorry, but it’s a good one,” he wrote </span><a href="https://www.resetera.com/threads/geoff-keighley-posts-cryptic-image-with-the-caption-regal-inspiring-thickness-up-not-diablo-up2-new-message-from-tga-account.1368046/page-7#post-148323163"><span>on a gaming forum</span></a><span>. </span><span>” Regardless of the answer, The Game Awards wins—the statue has gotten enough buzz that people will, certainly, tune in to see what the statue is teasing.</span></p>

 <p><span>It’s a little more easily digestible than, say, </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/the-two-year-mystery-is-over-this-is-frog-fractions-2-1790505179"><span>the </span><i><span>Frog Fractions 2</span></i><span> ARG</span></a><span> that went unsolved for literally two years spanning nearly two dozen games on Steam and a book in a California library. Then there’s the </span><i><span>Halo 2</span></i><span> ARG called I Love Bees, which spanned three months, jars of honey, and several pay phones,&nbsp; or when Electronic Arts launched copies of </span><i><span>Mass Effect 3 </span></i><span>into space using weather balloons. (</span><a href="https://kotaku.com/early-mass-effect-3-winners-may-have-jumped-into-legal-5888619"><span>The people who found the copies</span></a><span>, inevitably plummeting back to earth, could play the game early.)</span></p> <p><span>Keighley’s Game Awards statue doesn’t seem to necessarily be an alternate reality game. It’s hard to say if it’s really leaving any clues for gamers to decode or just there to power the hype cycle. It feels more aligned with the chaotic churn of algorithmic virality that everyone’s seeking these days—a weird thing in a weird place, easily photographed or videotaped and circulated on TikTok, Reddit, and elsewhere. </span><a href="https://www.tiktok.com/search?q=game%20awards%20statue&amp;t=1764954890852"><span>It’s working</span></a><span>.&nbsp;</span></p> <h2>The new AAA realty</h2> <p><span>Companies have done these sorts of things for highly-anticipated, big budget games like </span><a href="https://imgur.com/a/2GpQl"><i><span>Overwatch</span></i></a> <span>(big action figures in big boxes), </span><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GodofWarRagnarok/comments/10p0i4x/giant_leviathan_axe_appeared_in_london/"><i><span>God of War</span></i></a><span> (big axe in London), and </span><a href="https://www.techradar.com/news/life-size-horizon-forbidden-west-clawstrider-statues-could-win-you-a-ps5"><i><span>Horizon Forbidden West</span></i></a><span> (big mechanical monsters). The difference, of course, is that it’s obvious what these installations were promoting. The danger in the Game Awards statue is that people will end up let down by whatever game it’s tied to.</span></p>

 <p><span>Events like The Game Awards were born to market AAA games; Keighley fills the show with commercials for the latest and greatest big-budget blockbusters from the industry’s mega-companies, backed by a booming voice boasting a world premiere announcement or new gameplay trailer. The biggest of these, games like </span><i><span>The Witcher 4</span></i><span> or </span><i><span>Marvel’s Wolverine</span></i><span>, barely need the extra eye-balls while everything else gets lost in the shuffle. Homegrown debut hits like </span><i><span>Balatro</span></i><span> and </span><i><span>Expedition 33: Clair Obscure</span></i><span>, meanwhile, come out of nowhere and dominate the zeitgeist without the help of giant marketing machines. While some companies hope to manufacture a fraction of that cachet with big showcase moments, it’s no longer obvious that they’re for sale. To hear some tell it, the old AAA gaming model has reached “</span><a href="https://www.thegamebusiness.com/p/the-man-who-signed-arc-raiders-the"><span>the end of days</span></a><span>.” We’re a long way from cosplaying Area 51 for a midnight console launch.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><span>But I suppose that’s not Keighley’s problem. People might not remember whatever the statue ends up being for but they’ll tune into The Game Award to find out. He gets to hype his show either way.</span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/game-awards-statue-elder-scrolls-6-geoff-keighley-2000651010]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[It’s Wild That Nintendo’s New Game Is An FPS That Runs At 120FPS]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/nintendo-switch-2-metroid-prime-4-mario-120fps-perfomance-mode-2000650994</link>
            <guid>1374781</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><a href="https://kotaku.com/metroid-prime-4-beyond-graphics-comparison-switch-2-ugly-2000650585"><em>Metroid Prime 4: Beyond</em></a> technically isn’t the first Nintendo-published Switch 2 game to offer 120FPS support, but I don’t count that weird paid tech demo known as <a href="https://kotaku.com/switch-2-worst-games-nintendo-metacritic-drag-x-drive-welcome-tour-2000617517"><em>Switch 2 Welcome Tour</em></a> that launched with the system. No, <em>Prime 4</em> is Nintendo’s first 120FPS Switch 2 experience, and it’s amazing. It is also a bit odd coming from Nintendo, but it makes me really hope this is an option in future games from the <em>Mario</em> company.</p> <p>Out now on Switch 2 and the OG Switch, <a href="https://kotaku.com/metroid-prime-4-reviews-is-it-good-switch-2-nintendo-2000649621"><em>Metroid Prime 4: Beyond</em></a> is the next entry in the popular sci-fi shooter series that is itself a spin-off of the 2D <em>Metroid</em> games.<a href="https://kotaku.com/metroid-prime-4-impressions-first-level-volt-forge-titanfall-2-factory-2000650657"> And while I found the opening hour to be a bit meh</a>, the game really picks up once you reach Volt Forge. But one thing that was great and remained excellent from the very start was <em>Metroid Prime 4</em>‘s performance mode on Switch 2, which offers up 120 buttery smooth frames per second if your TV can handle it. Gunplay, platforming, driving, and even puzzle solving are just so much nicer at the higher framerate.</p>

 <p>And this isn’t some hidden mode. No, the moment you first boot up <em>Prime 4</em>, it asks you to select between two modes: a 4K/60FPS option and a 1080p/120FPS option. I’ve played the game both ways, and while the 60FPS option is great and looks a tad sharper, I’ve primarily played Prime 4 in the 120FPS mode because it feels so nice and smooth. At first, I was worried that the Switch 2 would struggle to maintain that high framerate. But in my hours with the game so far, I’ve only seen one or two dips, and that was only in the open world desert portions of <em>Prime 4.</em></p>

  <p>It’s tricky to share 120FPS videos on the internet. Even using YouTube is challenging, as the ability to watch 120FPS content depends on the video, your device, etc. So unfortunately, I can’t show you how good <em>Prime 4</em> looks running at a high framerate. <a href="https://www.digitalfoundry.net/news/2025/12/metroid-prime-4-is-switch-2s-first-true-120hz-3d-showcase">But trust me, it’s great and totally worth the small trade-off</a> of the image looking a little softer compared to the 4K/60FPS mode. And yeah, it’s weird to even be talking about modes like this in a Nintendo first-party release. I’m not upset about it at all, though, as I’ve long wanted Nintendo’s visuals and tech to catch up with the rest of the industry, and this is a big step in that direction.</p> <p>Now all I can do is think about how great it would be for the next mainline 3D <em>Mario</em> to offer a 120FPS mode. <a href="https://kotaku.com/let-us-all-remember-the-great-f-zero-gx-5920082">Can you imagine a new <em>F-Zero</em> running at 120FPS</a>? Or what about a <em>Smash Bros</em> sequel offering a high framerate mode? I know not all Nintendo-published games moving forward will support 120FPS, but I hope we get a few more every year as the company’s games often look and feel better than usual when you have all those extra frames.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/nintendo-switch-2-metroid-prime-4-mario-120fps-perfomance-mode-2000650994]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[CoD: Black Ops 7 Zombies Wonder Weapon - How To Get The LGM-1 In Astra Malorum]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cod-black-ops-7-zombies-wonder-weapon-how-to-get-the-lgm-1-in-astra-malorum/1100-6536739/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>1374775</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536739">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/cod-black-ops-7-and-warzone-season-1-adds-more-maps-weapons-and-warzone-integration/2900-7281/">Call of Duty Season 1</a> is live in Black Ops 7, bringing the brand-new Astra Malorum map to Zombies mode. This is a traditional round-based map set in space, and it has a unique UFO-themed Wonder Weapon called the LGM-1. In this guide we'll walk you through how to get the LGM-1 Wonder Weapon for your next match of Zombies on Astra Malorum.</p><p dir="ltr">If you need help with Ashes of the Damned, we have full guides for unlocking the map's unique <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/cod-black-ops-7-zombies-wonder-weapon-how-to-get-the-necrofluid-gauntlet-in-ashes-of-the-damned/2900-7261/">Necrofluid Gauntlet Wonder Weapon</a> as well as getting <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/black-ops-7-zombies-how-to-repair-and-upgrade-ol-tessie/1100-6536336/">Ol' Tessie repaired and upgraded</a>.</p><div data-embed-type="toc"><p><span><strong>Table of Contents</strong> [<a data-toggle="collapse" href="#toc_list">hide</a>]</span></p><ul id="toc_list"><li><a href="#The_LGM_1_explained">The LGM-1 explained</a></li><li><a href="#Activate_power_for_the_map">Activate power for the map</a></li><li><a href="#Find_the_parts_for_the_Wonder_Weapon">Find the parts for the Wonder Weapon</a><ul><li><a href="#Absolute_Zero_fragments">Absolute Zero fragments</a></li><li><a href="#Wiring_part">Wiring part</a></li><li><a href="#Battery_part">Battery part</a></li><li><a href="#Damaged_Drone_part">Damaged Drone part</a></li></ul></li><li><a href="#Oscar_trap_trials">Oscar trap trials</a><ul><li><a href="#Luminarium_trap">Luminarium trap</a></li><li><a href="#Observatory_Dome_trap">Observatory Dome trap</a></li><li><a href="#Museum_Infinitum___Absolute_Zero_fragments">Museum Infinitum - Absolute Zero fragments</a></li></ul></li></ul></div><h2 dir="ltr" id="The_LGM_1_explained">The LGM-1 explained</h2><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394540/4616795-lgmwonderweapon.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4616795" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="2240" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394540/4616795-lgmwonderweapon.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4616795"></a><figcaption>LGM-1 Wonder Weapon</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394540/4616795-lgmwonderweapon.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">LGM-1 doesn't sound like a very interesting name for a Wonder Weapon, but it stands for "Little Green Menace," and it shoots UFO-like projectiles that swarm nearby targets with laser-fire attacks. This gun has infinite ammo, and it can also be Pack-a-Punched.</p><p dir="ltr">Completing the map's LGM-1 quest will only reward you with one Wonder Weapon, no matter how many people are in your party.</p><p dir="ltr">To get another LGM-1 Wonder weapon for your party, you'll need to get lucky with the randomness of the Mystery Box or use a Wonderbar GobbleGum. However, the Wonderbar GobbleGum only guarantees your next spin of the Mystery Box will be a Wonder Weapon, but it could give you the Ray Gun instead.</p><h2 dir="ltr" id="Activate_power_for_the_map">Activate power for the map</h2><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394540/4616796-pap.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4616796" data-ratio="0.56263736263736" data-width="1820" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394540/4616796-pap.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4616796"></a><figcaption>Pack-a-Punch machine</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394540/4616796-pap.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">The game holds your hand for this part, so all you need to do is follow the orange quest markers that guide you through finding the missing components to repair the oculus, and then complete these guided steps to turn on the power and activate the Pack-a-Punch machine.</p><p dir="ltr">Note: During these early steps you'll find purple Aether crystals around the map. <strong>Do not shoot these yet</strong>. They don't seem to spawn frequently, and you'll need them for the step below, which also requires you to save up salvage to get the Cryo Freeze ammo mod on your gun.</p><h2 dir="ltr" id="Find_the_parts_for_the_Wonder_Weapon">Find the parts for the Wonder Weapon</h2><h3 dir="ltr" id="Absolute_Zero_fragments">Absolute Zero fragments</h3><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394540/4616797-purplecrystal.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4616797" data-ratio="0.56263736263736" data-width="1820" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394540/4616797-purplecrystal.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4616797"></a><figcaption>Purple Aether crystal</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394540/4616797-purplecrystal.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">As mentioned above, you need the Cryo Freeze ammo mod on your gun. Shoot the purple Aether crystals that spawn randomly all around the map. You need to be using the gun with Cryo Freeze, and this will cause the crystals to drop an Absolute Zero fragment part.</p><p dir="ltr">Shoot three different crystals and <strong>collect the Absolute Zero fragment parts</strong> for each. You also want to <strong>avoid shooting any additional crystals</strong> on the map, as you might need more fragments if you fail a later step.</p><h3 dir="ltr" id="Wiring_part">Wiring part</h3><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394540/4616798-blinkinglightexample.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4616798" data-ratio="0.56263736263736" data-width="1820" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394540/4616798-blinkinglightexample.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4616798"></a><figcaption>Outdoor light blinking in my match</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394540/4616798-blinkinglightexample.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">You also need to collect wires. This is done by shooting a blinking outdoor light, and an example of one is shown in the image above.</p><p dir="ltr">There are a lot of outdoor lights, but only one light blinking each match. The blinking is very noticeable, so just walk around the exterior of the map until you find it. Shoot the lamp, and <strong>collect the Wiring part</strong> it drops.</p><h3 dir="ltr" id="Battery_part">Battery part</h3><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394540/4616799-battery.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4616799" data-ratio="0.56263736263736" data-width="1820" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394540/4616799-battery.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4616799"></a><figcaption>Battery from Ol' Tessie</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394540/4616799-battery.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">You need a Pack-a-Punched gun for this step. Go back to Ol' Tessie in the spawn area of the map and shoot the hood of the truck. <strong>Pick up the Battery part</strong> that drops out.</p><h3 dir="ltr" id="Damaged_Drone_part">Damaged Drone part</h3><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394540/4616800-oscardrones.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4616800" data-ratio="0.56263736263736" data-width="1820" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394540/4616800-oscardrones.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4616800"></a><figcaption>Shoot Oscar's drones</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394540/4616800-oscardrones.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">This part requires Oscar, who is the map's new robot enemy type. Oscar starts spawning into your rounds after you've unlocked Pack-a-Punch. This robot will have little flying drones hovering above and trying to protect him. Shoot and destroy one of the drones and <strong>pick up the Damaged Drone</strong> part it drops.</p><p dir="ltr">Also, don't waste your bullets trying to kill Oscar in this step. This is a boss you need to keep around and use for the steps below.</p><h2 dir="ltr" id="Oscar_trap_trials">Oscar trap trials</h2><p dir="ltr">There are three trials you need to do involving traps and Oscar. Again, don't waste your ammo trying to kill Oscar, but instead, you want to lure him to one of the three trap areas on the map to complete a trial.</p><p dir="ltr">These trials are best attempted at the end of the round when you only have one or two zombies left. This keeps you from getting overwhelmed with enemies. They can also be completed in any order, but you will need to have collected all parts mentioned above. Oscar will <strong>drop the LGM-1 Wonder Weapon reward</strong> after he's defeated in the last trial you complete.</p><h3 dir="ltr" id="Luminarium_trap">Luminarium trap</h3><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394540/4616801-oscaroverchargemeter.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4616801" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="2240" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394540/4616801-oscaroverchargemeter.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4616801"></a><figcaption>Battery Overcharge step in Luminarium</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394540/4616801-oscaroverchargemeter.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">Lure Oscar to the Observatory's Luminarium and interact with the trap inside the room to place the Battery part. Now you need to survive in the room, while keeping Oscar nearby.</p><p dir="ltr">There's a meter that appears on your screen for a Battery Overcharge. Keep Oscar close to the trap until the meter is full. You also want to make sure you're destroying the drones that protect him, as they make him invulnerable to the traps.</p><p dir="ltr">If he's invulnerable with drones when the Overcharge meter fills, you'll fail the step and need to repeat it on the next round.</p><h3 dir="ltr" id="Observatory_Dome_trap">Observatory Dome trap</h3><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394540/4616803-steamvalve.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4616803" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="2240" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394540/4616803-steamvalve.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4616803"></a><figcaption>Steam valve</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394540/4616803-steamvalve.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">Head to the Observatory Dome (Pack-a-Punch) room. Oscar doesn't need to be inside the room for the first part of this step, so if you have a teammate, get them to lead Oscar and zombies away while you search for a broken steam valve.</p><p dir="ltr">The valve can spawn all around the inside of the Pack-a-Punch room, and you can hear an audible hiss when you're close. Find it, shoot it, and another valve will appear. Repeat this process of shooting the steam valves until you have done this for five valves. Make sure you're looking on the lower level and the upper level above you. Once all five are successfully shot, you'll get an audio cue.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394540/4616804-alignthesun.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4616804" data-ratio="0.56265432098765" data-width="3240" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394540/4616804-alignthesun.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4616804"></a><figcaption>Align the sun with the telescope trap</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394540/4616804-alignthesun.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">Now, you need to bring Oscar close to the Pack-a-Punch machine before you interact with the telescope trap across from it. When you interact with the trap, it will change your view to the viewfinder of the telescope, and you're looking up at the sky. You need to adjust the telescope to align with the sun.</p><p dir="ltr">Most of your view from the telescope is just pink and purple colors in space, but move it until you see the sun. The sun seems to be positioned the same in every match, so move the viewfinder up and to the right. You'll see a yellow glowing orb, and that's the sun.</p><p dir="ltr">Once you line up the sun, you're kicked out of the telescope view, and Oscar should be close enough to zap with the sun beam that shoots down inside the room. Again, this is the area directly in front of Pack-a-Punch, and the beam is going to be centered in between the PaP and the trap.</p><h3 dir="ltr" id="Museum_Infinitum___Absolute_Zero_fragments">Museum Infinitum - Absolute Zero fragments</h3><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394540/4616805-rockettrap.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4616805" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="2240" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394540/4616805-rockettrap.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4616805"></a><figcaption>Rocket trap activated</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394540/4616805-rockettrap.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">Lead Oscar to the Museum Infinitum room with the rocket trap. You need to get Oscar really close to the back of the trap, and then quickly interact with the trap controls to blast Oscar with the rockets. This is a much faster process than the Luminarium step, but you also have to time it correctly, because the rockets will only blast for a few seconds.</p><p dir="ltr">This can be difficult solo, but with additional teammates, you can have one person at the controls while another baits Oscar to the trap.</p><p dir="ltr">If you fail this step, then you'll need to go collect three more fragments from the purple Aether Crystals and try again.</p><p dir="ltr">Once all three trials are complete, Oscar will drop the LGM-1 Wonder Weapon for you to pick up.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cod-black-ops-7-zombies-wonder-weapon-how-to-get-the-lgm-1-in-astra-malorum/1100-6536739/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Metroid Prime 4: Beyond's Ending Does Samus Dirty (Spoilers)]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/metroid-prime-4-beyonds-ending-does-samus-dirty-spoilers/1100-6536738/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>1374772</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536738">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">Metroid Prime 4: Beyond is intended as both a continuation and a new start for the long dormant franchise. Though Nintendo has never quite said it overtly, it has seemed likely that this is meant to launch a new series of Prime games--possibly even a second trilogy, for the sake of dramatic rhyme. And the ending of Prime 4 accents that feeling, leaving the door wide open for more story--but in the process, diminishing the character of protagonist Samus Aran.</p><p dir="ltr"><strong>Spoilers for Metroid Prime 4: Beyond follow.</strong></p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="618416576" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6466560,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Metroid%20Prime%204%20Beyond%20Review&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:902,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/metroid-prime-4-beyond-review\/2300-6466560\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466560\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466560\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466560\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6466560&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6466560,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6536738&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;metroid-prime-4-beyond&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;3d,action,first-person,shooter&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;nintendo-switch,nintendo-switch-2&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;nintendo&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;franchise&quot;:&quot;metroid-prime&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;franchiseRoot&quot;:&quot;metroid&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6466560},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6466560\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;GameSpot&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4614944-review_metroidprime4_site.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/Md0zcQMB.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1764687600,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="Md0zcQMB" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> Metroid Prime 4 Beyond Review</p>
      </div>
<p dir="ltr">As many eager Metroid fans know from preview coverage and reviews, Metroid Prime 4: Beyond features a wide cast of Federation characters, who have been stranded on Viewros with Samus. As you explore the corners of Sol Valley you eventually meet five in total: engineer Myles MacKenzie, sniper Reger Tokabi, Sergeant Ezra Duke, Private Nora Armstrong, and mech unit VUE-995. Each talks with Samus and relates to her in different ways. Myles is out of his element and needs Samus' rescue. Armstrong is a bona fide Samus superfan. Tokabi opens up to her about his religion and upbringing.</p><p dir="ltr">Your mileage may vary on how much you care about these characters--in my review I said they're mostly broad military archetypes--but it's clear that the game <em>wants</em> you to care about them. They're functionally your crew. They all stay back at base camp and help you out in different ways. When the time comes to break into the Lamorn's shielded tower, all of you go together. Your mission to reactivate the Master Teleporter is to open a way back home. The unspoken element of this is that you're trying to save them, too. They're all stranded far from home just like you are.</p><p dir="ltr">Naturally, as you start to activate the Master Teleporter, Sylux chooses that moment to attack. A major portion of the final battle involves fighting alongside all five of the Federation squad at once, providing emergency help when they're downed, and taking down Sylux's shields so that they can all concentrate fire on him. But just when it seems he's beaten and you can all go home, he reemerges. The teleporter is damaged and can only hold out so long, and it can only work if Samus is the one operating it. Sylux is dead-set on attacking Samus to the exclusion of all the others, and if she gets hurt, the teleporter won't have an operator. So in a moment of selfless heroism, they each grab onto Sylux, stalling him just long enough, as they tell Samus to escape. At the height of the dramatic tension, you have to press A to teleport, leaving your comrades behind as they cling to Sylux to protect you.</p><p dir="ltr">That is: The five <em>Federation</em> characters act selflessly and heroically, while Samus saves herself.</p><p dir="ltr">Now to be fair, the stakes of the moment make it clear Samus has no choice. In fact, if you abstain from activating the teleporter, you simply die and need to start one phase of the boss battle over again. So Samus is not actually being selfish, but she's not exactly being heroic either. This is living legend Samus Aran--her reputation precedes her. All of these characters knew who she was and implicitly trusted her. Throughout this campaign and many others, we've seen her do the impossible. So at this moment, it's just hard to buy the dramatic conceit that she couldn't have figured out any other way than to leave her comrades behind.</p><p dir="ltr">If Prime 4's ending is intended as the starting point for a new series, it immediately raises questions about what comes next. Sylux is still out there, albeit seemingly marooned on a dying planet without any way to escape. Sylux is still in command of the Metroids, and still presumably has the loyalty of his loose assemblage of space pirates. Your five Federation companions are there with him--he either killed them immediately after you escaped, or, more optimistically, they got away and went back to base camp. Except now the Master Teleporter has no operator and they have no viable path off-planet.</p><p dir="ltr">So what happens now? Will the entire series focus on this war with Sylux? Is Samus going back to Viewros to rescue her companions? Does she even know where Viewros is, or is it just one of billions of uncharted planets in the furthest reaches of space? The brief moment that we see a starmap strongly suggests the latter. But the ending as a whole leaves us with almost no clarity as to where Samus's story might be headed after Prime 4, and gives this revival a listless quality. As a result of the lack of any propulsive force toward the next chapter, we're left lingering with this final, unflattering impression of the great Samus Aran.</p><p dir="ltr">We do see a somber and genuinely affecting moment where Samus honors her comrades. But that doesn't offer much clue as to what the future holds. For the time being, it's a downer. The triumphant return of the Metroid Prime series left us with Samus failing to protect people who were depending on her, and with a small band of new characters getting the heroic climax. Regardless of how you feel about the characters themselves, I was left feeling like Samus had been pushed out of the spotlight in her own series.</p><p dir="ltr">When you're in the final area accompanied by your companions, you can talk to them each individually before proceeding to the final battle. They all make comments aligned with their personalities. Some are funny, others are more reflective. VUE apologizes for wrecking Betsy, the massive mech that you used to punch a hole through the forcefield. Tokabi remarks that this place feels sacred. As you move your way through, the troops start to talk about finding the teleporter, and how eager they are to leave. Armstrong, the enthusiastic private who has looked up to Samus since they first met, says just one thing: "Finally, we get to go home."</p><p dir="ltr">I'm sorry Armstrong, but no we don't. Not all of us. Not yet.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/metroid-prime-4-beyonds-ending-does-samus-dirty-spoilers/1100-6536738/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Report: iam8bit sues Skybound, alleging fraud]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/report-iam8bit-sues-skybound-alleging-fraud</link>
            <guid>1374769</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="captioned-content" data-testid="featured-image"><p><span>via Annapurna Interactive</span></p></div><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Newsbrief:</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> Physical media company (and game publisher) iam8bit is suing its business partner Skybound Game Studios, alleging that the latter committed fraud, failing to provide accurate financial reports according to contract. As reported by </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.engadget.com/gaming/iam8bit-is-suing-skybound-game-studios-alleging-fraud-and-theft-of-designs-000822886.html">Engadget</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, the two companies began a partnership in 2021, but iam8Bit is now accusing Skybound of conducting a "multi-year accounting scheme."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The complaint, filed in LA Superior court, includes accusations that Skybound Games "padded its expenses with millions of dollars in fake line items" and that "Skybound failed to provide the monthly reports as agreed." It also accuses Skybound of interfering with a deal iam8Bit was working on for promotional materials for indie darling </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Stray</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, claiming "Skybound used confidential information about iam8bit’s royalty split with [publisher] Annapurna Interactive to cut out its business partner," and also claims Skybound produced “'almost exact copies' of its creative output for marketing."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">iam8Bit started up in 2005, eventually evolving into a storefront for premium physical editions of games, soundtracks, and other collectible items. It also publishes games under its iam8bit Presents imprint, including </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Escape Academy</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">. Skybound Games Studios also lists </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Escape Academy</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> among its publishing achievements.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/yes-netflix-is-acquiring-warner-bros-games" target="_self" data-discover="true">Yes, Netflix is acquiring Warner Bros. Games</a></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Editor-in-Chief, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Danielle is the editor-in-chief of Game Developer, with previous editorial posts at Fanbyte, VICE, and Polygon. She’s also a lecturer in game design at the Berklee College of Music, and a hobbyist game developer in her spare time.</span></p></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/report-iam8bit-sues-skybound-alleging-fraud]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[You can now use Pixel phones as a Switch 2 webcam]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/839133/google-pixel-smartphone-nintendo-switch-2-webcam</link>
            <guid>1374748</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="__next"><p><a href="#content"><span>Skip to main content</span></a></p><nav aria-label="Sticky Nav"></nav><div><main id="content"><div><article><div><div><p>﻿You may not need to buy a separate webcam to take full advantage of the Switch 2’s GameChat feature.</p></div><div><p>﻿You may not need to buy a separate webcam to take full advantage of the Switch 2’s GameChat feature.</p><div><p><span><span>by</span> <!-- --> <span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"></span></span></p><p><span><time datetime="2025-12-05T18:46:37+00:00">Dec 5, 2025, 6:46 PM UTC</time></span></p></div></div></div><div><div><div><p><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span id="follow-author-standard_article_details-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTYw"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span></span><span>Andrew Liszewski</span></span></span></p> <p><span>is a senior reporter who’s been covering and reviewing the latest gadgets and tech since 2006, but has loved all things electronic since he was a kid.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><div><p>When it launched the Switch 2’s <a href="https://www.theverge.com/nintendo/682008/which-webcams-work-with-nintendo-switch-2">compatibility with various webcams was hit or miss</a>. A webcam isn’t a necessary accessory, but since the Switch 2 lacks one of its own, you need one to <a href="https://www.theverge.com/video/685229/nintendo-switch-2-gamechat-c-button-mario-kart">take full advantage of the console’s GameChat feature</a> that can livestream players’ faces during multiplayer matches. Switch 2 <a href="https://www.theverge.com/report/693182/nintendo-switch-2-webcam-mystery-1080p-480p-uvc-iso-bulk-ugreen-elgato">webcam compatibility has since improved</a>, but if you don’t already own one, you can now use your Pixel smartphone, <a href="https://www.androidauthority.com/pixel-phone-as-switch-2-webcam-3622443/">according to <em>Android Authority</em></a>.</p></div><p>Despite Nintendo’s claims that the Switch 2 works with most USB webcams, our own testing confirmed that Pixel smartphones could not be used as webcams at launch, even with the device’s settings switched to the USB webcam mode that Google introduced with Android 14. Switch 2 users eventually found that Android phones and iPhones could be used as a webcam for the console, but with the help of <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wGH_VF-Gx4Y">additional USB-C to HDMI adapters</a>, and HDMI capture cables.</p><p>But extra hardware is no longer needed to use a Pixel smartphone as a Switch 2 webcam. We tested a Pixel 9 Pro connected directly to the Switch 2’s top USB-C port with a single cable and, after switching the USB preferences to “Webcam” mode, we were able to use the smartphone as the camera for GameChat. If you’re playing multiplayer games like <em>Mario Kart World</em>, GameChat lets you not only speak with other competitors around the world, but also see them superimposed over a livestream of them playing if you’re using a webcam.</p><p>It’s not known if recent updates on Google’s or Nintendo’s end are responsible for making this work (the Pixel 9 Pro we tested it with is running the Android 16 December release), but it’s a welcome upgrade for those who frequently travel with their Switch 2 and don’t want to lug a separate webcam everywhere they go.</p><div><p><span><strong>Follow topics and authors</strong> from this story to see more like this in your personalized homepage feed and to receive email updates.</span></p><ul><li id="follow-author-article_footer-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTYw"><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span><span>Andrew Liszewski</span></span></span></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li></ul></div></div></div><div><form><div><h2>The Verge Daily</h2><p><span>A free daily digest of the news that matters most.</span></p></div></form></div></div></article></div></main></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/news/839133/google-pixel-smartphone-nintendo-switch-2-webcam]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Printable Metroid Prime 4 'Databook' Has Us Feeling Nostalgic For Instruction Booklets]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/12/printable-metroid-prime-4-databook-has-us-feeling-nostalgic-for-instruction-booklets</link>
            <guid>1374706</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Manual override</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure data-uuid="6c2a811573665"><a title="Metroid Prime 4 Booklet" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/6c2a811573665/metroid-prime-4-booklet.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Jim Norman / Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure><p>Bar a few exceptions, the days of opening your boxed copy of a new game and eagerly flipping through the instruction booklet are behind us. But it looks like Nintendo isn't ready to give up on the nostalgia just yet, as it has released a printable 'databook' for <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/metroid_prime_4_beyond">Metroid Prime 4: Beyond</a>, that just makes our hearts sing (thanks for the heads up, <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/ninpatentswatch.bsky.social/post/3m75hnarurk2b">@ninpatentswatch</a>).</p>
<p>The booklet is only available on the <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/jp/games/switch2/bgw5a/databook/index.html#page1">Japanese Nintendo website</a> at the time of writing — with all of the text in Japanese, natch — but it scratches such a retro itch for us that we're amazed the big N doesn't do something similar for all its releases.</p><div><figure data-videoid="6TAq6m9hxyY" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6TAq6m9hxyY?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><div><iframe id="yt6TAq6m9hxyY" title="YouTube Video" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/6TAq6m9hxyY?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6TAq6m9hxyY?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed76f4cezqynrj&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>840k</span></a></p>
</div></figure></div>
<p>The 24-page 'World Databook', to give it its official title, is full of a lot of things you would expect from a classic instruction manual, including game controls and character introductions, but there are also rundowns of the game's main locales and mechanics, with a sneaky bit of lore peppered in there, too.</p>
<p>Here's a couple of pages, so you can get a taste for what's inside:</p>

<p>The <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/jp/games/switch2/bgw5a/databook/pdf/PDFmanual.pdf">full PDF</a> has instructions for how to print and fold the booklet, so you can rest easy knowing that it'll slot nicely into those under-utilised plastic clips that occupy the top half of all modern game cases.</p>
<p>Would opening the in-game menu and looking up the controls that way be an awful lot easier? Sure it would. But come on, where's the fun in that?</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:194214 @ 1764964947 -->
<p><em>Will you be printing out your own copy? Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://www.nintendo.com/jp/games/switch2/bgw5a/databook/index.html#page1" rel="noopener" href="https://www.nintendo.com/jp/games/switch2/bgw5a/databook/index.html#page1">nintendo.com</a>, via <a title="External Link: https://bsky.app/profile/ninpatentswatch.bsky.social/post/3m75hnarurk2b" rel="noopener" href="https://bsky.app/profile/ninpatentswatch.bsky.social/post/3m75hnarurk2b">bsky.app</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-info/ef57e1d0836b33f196522fde222423a6 @ 1764964467 --></div></article><div><p>Jim came to Nintendo Life in 2022 and, despite his insistence that The Minish Cap is the best Zelda game and his unwavering love for the Star Wars prequels (yes, really), he has continued to write news and features on the site ever since.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/JimNorman"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/jimnormann.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('JimNorman');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/12/printable-metroid-prime-4-databook-has-us-feeling-nostalgic-for-instruction-booklets]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mortal Kombat, Hogwarts Legacy, And Batman: Arkham Are Going To A Company That Closed Its Only AAA Game Studio]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/netflix-wb-batman-arkham-hogwarts-legacy-mortal-kombat-2000650918</link>
            <guid>1374697</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Netflix is bidding <a href="https://kotaku.com/netflix-warner-bros-deal-batman-hbo-max-2000650875">over $80 billion to buy Warner Bros.</a>, and it’s probably not doing it for the games. But the company will still come away with a ton of them if the merger goes through. Warner Bros. Games is one of the few major publishers left in the U.S. following years of big acquisition deals. What might be closer to a rounding error relative to the larger movie and TV portfolio still marks a huge shift for the industry. And Netflix’s incredibly chaotic fumbling of gaming over the last several years raises some alarm bells.</p> <p>The king of streaming confirmed during a conference call presentation about the newly revealed deal that games would be part of the transaction, but <a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/yes-netflix-is-acquiring-warner-bros-games">never discussed them outright</a>. Instead, they were relegated to the smallest square on a presentation slide outlining the various components of the merger. They were lumped in with “Games &amp; Consumer Product &amp; Experiences” alongside much bigger brands like HBO, DC, Harry Potter, and Superman.</p>

 <figure id="attachment_2000650991" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000650991"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000650991">Netflix / Kotaku</figcaption></figure> <p>Even with its massive success, the best-selling game of 2023, <em>Hogwarts Legacy</em>, was clearly nowhere close to top-of-mind for Netflix co-CEOs Ted Sarandos and Greg Peters. The open-world wizarding game already has a sequel in development at Avalanche Software, and it’s supposed to have <a href="https://kotaku.com/hogwarts-legacy-2-hbo-harry-potter-tv-release-date-1851690168">some level of crossover</a> with the upcoming HBO <em>Harry Potter</em> reboot. The first <em>Hogwarts Legacy</em> sold over 30 million copies. In revenue terms at least, that puts it way ahead of the global box office for something like James Gunn’s first<em> Superman </em>movie.</p>

 <p>Then there’s TT Games, the UK-based maker of the recent hit <em>Lego Star Wars: The Skywalker Saga</em>. It announced a new adaptation of <em>Batman</em> earlier this year called <em>Lego Batman: The Legacy of the Dark Knight,</em> which acts as a best-of sizzle reel for the comic book hero’s peak movie moments <a href="https://kotaku.com/lego-batman-legacy-of-the-dark-knight-preview-arkham-2000633994">in an<em> Arkham</em>-style open world</a>. There’s no release date yet, but it seems likely to arrive sometime in 2026. If it’s anything like the <em>Skywalker Saga</em>, it’ll be another top-seller.</p>

 <p>Netflix will also become the new home of <em>Mortal Kombat</em>. While a new movie launches next year, fans have been waiting for NeatherRealms to return to the DC universe with <em>Injustice 3</em>. The studio <a href="https://x.com/MortalKombat/status/1926020816879206810">announced earlier this year</a> that it was done shipping new DLC for 2023’s <em>Mortal Kombat 1</em> and would switch to focusing on its “next project” instead. Unless Ed Boon’s team is quietly at work on a completely new cross-over fighting game, a return to the alternate DC universe where Superman is bad still seems like the safest bet.</p>

 <h2>The fate of Rocksteady Studios</h2> <p>After that, things at Warner Bros. Games start to get really messy, thanks to years of seemingly short-sighted and chaotic executive decisions. Rocksteady Studios, once the team behind premier blockbusters like <em>Batman: Arkham City</em> and<em> Batman: Arkham Knight,</em> has been licking its wounds after the dismal failure of last year’s live service spin-off,<em> Suicide Squad: Kill The Justice League</em>. <a href="https://kotaku.com/suicide-squad-hogwarts-legacy-rocksteady-arkham-1851522893">Encouraged by publisher leadership</a> despite misgivings from the studio floor, the multiplayer loot shooter lost over $200 million, <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-06-06/-suicide-squad-warner-bros-s-200-million-flop-haunts-the-gaming-industry">according to<em> Bloomberg</em></a>.</p>

 <p>The studio is reportedly back to focusing on the Arkham franchise that made it famous, but a new entry would still be years away during a time when AAA development is more expensive and precarious than ever. Earlier this year, Warner Bros. Games took an ax to many of its other studios, including <em>MultiVersus</em> maker Player First Games, WB San Diego, which was making a free-to-play AAA game, and Monolith Productions, which was working on a long-in-development adaptation of <em>Wonder Woman</em>. The latter had a storied history, including developing the <em>Middle-earth: Shadow of Mordor</em> series, but <a href="https://www.tweaktown.com/news/103578/full-backstory-revealed-on-why-wb-games-axed-monolith-productions/index.html">lost key leadership</a> after it was forced to pivot from a new IP to adapting <em>Wonder Woman</em>.</p>

 <p>All of this turmoil resulted in publishing head David Haddad being fired from Warner Bros. Games after a decade-plus tenure. The game division’s struggles may have also been compounded by whip-lash from above, amid Warner Bros. Discovery CEO David Zaslav’s ongoing whirlwind tour through the unraveling conglomerate. Despite casually trampling on marketing plans by <a href="https://www.polygon.com/23612615/mortal-kombat-12-announced-2023-release-date/">revealing projects early</a> during investor calls, Zaslav never seemed to be interested in providing Warner Bros. Games with a clear mission or mandate other than “help make stock price go up.”</p> <h2>The Netflix Gaming debacle</h2> <p>News of the sale might be more reassuring if Netflix management didn’t seem equally at a loss when it comes to games. The streamer snatched up a bunch of small studios, including notable indie darlings like<em> Oxenfree</em> maker Night School Studio and <em>Cozy Grove</em> maker Spry Fox over the years. It loaded up its mobile app with tons of critically-acclaimed games from<em> Hades</em> to <em>The Rise of the Golden Idol</em>. It sought big-name additions like the<em> GTA Trilogy Remastered</em>. It even plunged ahead with an AAA studio called Team Blue that pulled veterans from&nbsp;<em>Overwatch</em>,&nbsp;<em>Halo</em>, and&nbsp;<em>God of War</em>.</p> <p>But despite bundling top games with its standard subscription service, <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2023/10/23/netflix-takes-slow-approach-to-video-games.html">almost nobody played them</a>. It started abandoning indie game deals, cutting resources, and <a href="https://www.gamefile.news/p/netflix-team-blue-socal-studio">quietly shuttered</a> its AAA team last year. Just this week, <a href="https://www.gamefile.news/p/netflix-sells-game-studio-spry-fox">Netflix announced</a> it was selling off Spry Fox, which it bought only three years ago, though the ambitious 3D Studio-Ghibli-meets-<em>Animal-Crossing</em>-chillfest called <em>Spirit Crossing</em> will remain in development. Instead, the company’s big focus moving forward will be party games and quick-turn-around licensed junk for its biggest streaming hits like <em>Squid Games</em> and <em>Bridgerton</em>. It’s the latest example of a <a href="https://kotaku.com/netflix-squid-game-unleashed-app-subscription-team-blue-1851755122">tech company racing into gaming and falling flat on its face</a>.</p>

 <p>So where does that leave Warner Bros. Games and its checkered portfolio of major games and studios? It’s hard to say. In some ways, it complements all of the areas of gaming where Netflix has already failed or retreated. It may not be high up on the list of synergies, but maybe the possibility of an eventual <em>Lego Stranger Things</em> anthology is still part of the streaming platform’s overall ambitions for the merger. Or maybe gaming, and AAA blockbuster gaming in particular, is so peripheral to Netflix’s broader business that Warner Bros. Gaming will find itself in an even more precarious position.</p> <p>Giant acquisitions are rarely as neat and tidy in practice as they appear on paper or in a PowerPoint presentation, even in the best of times, let alone when they’re thrown together in the midst of bidding wars, tumultuous legacy media transformations, and a race toward industry consolidation in order to achieve monopoly pricing power. The only thing worse is the alternatives: <a href="https://www.wsj.com/business/media/i-wanna-blow-this-up-how-bari-weiss-is-trying-to-overhaul-cbs-news-7c222dcd?gaa_at=eafs&amp;gaa_n=AWEtsqf__sU79yafyMQJEMfHCSs4fmigQ3B1FDTDxd4VSdFIXnEqE9fLO4kOIFOfdrE%3D&amp;gaa_ts=693321bd&amp;gaa_sig=YVIiDhsSG8Saq0NhdsXVZfrJk7xIcIWtlf4iFEqprJZt9Q0pE5poRMAJo7dIKNvDDygD-VXenQ654oZeVxoqcQ%3D%3D">the Bari Weis network</a>, <a href="https://kotaku.com/xbox-microsoft-price-hike-game-pass-layoffs-new-console-2000638546">Microsoft</a>, or <a href="https://kotaku.com/ea-saudi-arabia-ownership-trump-jared-kushner-2000649726">Saudi Arabia</a> aren’t great options either.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/netflix-wb-batman-arkham-hogwarts-legacy-mortal-kombat-2000650918]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sword of Convallaria X The Witcher 3: A Commemorative Interview]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/sword-of-convallaria-x-the-witcher-3-a-commemorative-interview</link>
            <guid>1374694</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">XD released Sword of Convallaria, a tactical RPG for iOS, Android, and PC to audiences in the west in August ’24 (around a year after the game’s East Asian launch). Heavily influenced by Tactics Ogre and Final Fantasy Tactics, the game has captivated fans with its meticulously crafted war story and highly strategic battles, all played out to a beautiful soundtrack.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Just over a year following its release, a truly major collaboration between Sword of Convallaria: For This World of Peace and CD PROJEKT RED's open-world RPG The Witcher 3: Wild Hunt has been fully realised and delivered to gamers. <a href="https://youtu.be/sEGNfoSPAXg?si=7s8jqQG1yfoKBR-5" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer sponsored">Geralt, Yennefer, Triss, and Ciri now appear in Sword of Convallaria as playable characters</a>; allowing players to enjoy collaborative stories and quests surrounding the Lord of the Forest from another world.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/12/05/sword-of-convallaria-the-witcher-3-wild-hunt-collaboration-teaser-0-35-screenshot-1764947962246.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Geralt and Yennefer in the Sword of Convallaria x The Witcher 3: Wild Hunt - Official Collaboration Trailer</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Bartosz Sztybor, Franchise Creative Director at CD PROJEKT RED, explained his take on the collaboration and how it came together:</strong> “At CD PROJEKT RED, storytelling is at the heart of everything we do, and we take a hands-on approach even when collaborating with external partners. For our partnership with Sword of Convallaria, our Franchise Creative team worked closely with developer XD International to craft a story that captures the essence of The Witcher universe, both for the anime trailer and the collaboration quest. Working with a partner who shares our passion for The Witcher is always a privilege, and we’re thrilled with the results of what we’ve created together. We’re looking forward to sharing the fruits of this partnership with the community, and can’t wait to see their response!”</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>CD PROJEKT RED’s Satoru Homma, Japan Country Manager, offered further insight into their partnership with XD Games:</strong> “For the collaboration between Sword of Convallaria and The Witcher 3: Wild Hunt, I was responsible for project management on behalf of CD PROJEKT RED. I am personally a huge fan of Sword of Convallaria, and I had a strong desire to see The Witcher 3’s characters — rendered in beautiful pixel art — playable within a tactical RPG. With the deep love and understanding Sword of Convallaria’s team holds for The Witcher 3, and under the thorough supervision of our in-house lore specialists, we were able to deliver grounded and authentic storytelling in the collaboration quest. I sincerely hope that The Witcher 3 players who may be unfamiliar with the tactical RPG genre will take the time to enjoy this content, which is infused with a deep appreciation for the world and its characters.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Director of Sword of Convallaria, Guo Lei (of XD Games)spoke about this collaboration in more detail — as well as the circumstances that led to it becoming a reality.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Inspired by <em>Tactics Ogre</em>, which he played in high school, Guo always wanted to become a game creator. He is also a fan of <em>The Witcher 3</em>, and his favourite characters are Geralt and Yennefer.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Guo on Sword of Convallaria passing the first anniversary of its western release and how he feels looking back on the past year:</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph">Sword of Convallaria got off to a successful start, but there was a period when we were searching for the right direction to go in. However, thanks to the support of our fans, we were able to turn things around and successfully celebrate our first anniversary. From now on, we will continue to develop the game with confidence and enjoyment for the fans who have high expectations for it.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Regarding the game's content, the Global version saw the release of Iria, and the story of her stepping into the world that lies beyond was depicted on the first anniversary. In the future, Sword of Convallaria will enter its 2.0 story arc, taking players on adventures beyond Iria, and develop a story in which the player protects peace. We hope you will look forward to it.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>— On how the  The Witcher 3 collaboration came about:</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Guo:</strong> From the beginning, our team had already been acquainted with the CDPR China team. During one of these casual conversations, we mentioned that it would be exciting if we could one day work on something together based on Sword of Convallaria and The Witcher 3.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Later, we had the opportunity to meet the CDPR Japan team in person at Tokyo Game Show 2024. During our discussions there, I showed them my personal love for The Witcher 3 and the interest in exploring whether we might create something together. They encouraged us to submit a formal proposal, which set the collaboration into motion. The Witcher 3 is a game that boasts worldwide popularity, so I was over the moon when he positively considered our proposal for a collaboration. After considerable effort, the collaboration was officially approved. From that point onward, both teams dedicated nearly a full year to development, ultimately bringing this collaboration to life in the form you see today.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/12/05/sword-of-convallaria-the-witcher-3-wild-hunt-collaboration-teaser-1-12-screenshot-1764948504837.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Play as Geralt, Yennefer, Triss, and Ciri in Sword of Convallaria</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>What it was about </strong><em><strong>The Witcher 3</strong></em><strong> that particularly appealed to him:</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph">First of all, it's the sense of immersion that comes with being so realistic. You get the feeling that you're immersed in the world, something you can't experience in other games. Also, it's the story element. What's great about it is that it depicts so many stories that you can empathise with. It's very unique in that you make painful choices that change the outcome of the story. I was overwhelmed by how the fascinating characters play an active role in the story.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>How the story was designed, its core themes, and the creative collaboration behind it</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph">We wanted to create the worldview of <em>The Witcher 3</em> within the world of <em>Sword of Convallaria</em>. However, it goes against Geralt's beliefs to get involved in conflicts between nations, and in fact, if we were to depict an epic story involving <em>The Witcher 3</em>, we felt that it would be quite a high hurdle to figure out how to resolve it. For this reason, we decided to aim for a down-to-earth story.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The story revolves around the Leshen from <em>The Witcher 3</em> appearing and causing trouble, and Geralt and his friends teaming up with the Leader to defeat it. Behind the scenes, the story also depicts the malice of people. For example, when a problem occurs, people assume that it is the work of those from a different background to themselves and blame them. The theme of the story poses a question of morality, as Geralt and Yennefer intervene to try to resolve this.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In The Witcher 3, Geralt and Yennefer are portrayed as unusual people who present differently from the average person. Naturally, they have differing personalities and ways of conducting themselves. We made it a priority to carefully express the various facets of these characters in the collaborative story.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">We made sure to communicate closely with CD PROJEKT RED. We created shared documents, edited those documents, and received feedback, all of which allowed us to proceed with development meticulously and efficiently. This resulted in a fun development experience unlike any other.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>How they approached reimagining The Witcher 3 characters into the pixel-based world of Sword of Convallaria:</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph">The Witcher 3 has a realistic 3D visual style, but when translating that into pixel art, our first priority was to think about how to express the movement in a way that would satisfy players.
</p><p data-cy="paragraph">However, the designers also love The Witcher 3, so they had fun designing it  with care, for example, to make it clear the difference between a silver sword and a steel sword. As a result, I got the impression that the visuals went smoothly.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>The regions that were  main target for the collaboration:</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph">Worldwide. Sword of Convallaria is available in four languages: Chinese, Japanese, English, and Korean. As with The Witcher 3, we have a global perspective and want game fans around the world to enjoy Sword of Convallaria Sword IP. Therefore, every region is important to us.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">If I had to say, we're particularly interested in English-speaking countries. We see the English-speaking world as a region where we still want to gain more fans for Sword of Convallaria. It goes without saying that The Witcher 3 has already gained many English-speaking fans, so we hope that this collaboration will help us further appeal to the English-speaking world.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Aspects that particularly stood out for him during this collaboration:</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph">I think this was a true collaboration. The fact that both parties were working together in the same direction was a feeling I'd never had before, and it was a lot of fun. It was a wonderful experience for us. So, this time, we were able to communicate directly with CDPR, and not only was it very efficient, but we also felt that everyone gained something from this project.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>The part of the collaboration that symbolised its success, or made him especially proud to be a part of it:</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph">What’s necessary when collaborating with other artists is love for the work. I think that only when we have a strong love for the work can we create something that satisfies our collaborators. We ourselves had always wanted to collaborate with The Witcher 3, but it was thanks to CDPR that we were able to make it happen. We are truly happy. We have also prepared skins for Geralt, Yennefer, and Triss. We have created skins based on the scenes that moved us the most while we were playing The Witcher 3. Geralt usually wears armor, but for this skin we created one that realistically expresses the love between father and daughter when Ciri visits Geralt.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As for Triss, in The Witcher 3, Triss and Geralt attend a dance party. However, the two of them aren't very interested in the dance party, so they sneak out midway through and enjoy a date in the garden. We recreated that atmosphere with the skin.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Each skin was created with love, so I hope all players will check them out.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/12/05/sword-of-convallaria-the-witcher-3-wild-hunt-collaboration-teaser-1-26-screenshot-1764948378963.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Yennefer stands in front of a portal in the Sword of Convallaria x The Witcher 3: Wild Hunt - Official Collaboration Trailer</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph"> 
<strong>His message to the Sword of Convallaria players who are looking forward to the collaboration:</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph">I would like to take this opportunity to express my gratitude to all of our fans. It is thanks to you all that Sword of Convallaria has grown so much over the past year or so, and that we have been able to safely reach our first anniversary. Thank you so much! Thanks to everyone's support, we were able to collaborate with The Witcher 3. How will Geralt and his friends play a role in the world of Sword of Convallaria? We hope that not only the Leaders but also fans of The Witcher 3 will enjoy the event.
</p><p data-cy="paragraph">©<strong>XD Inc.</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph">The Witcher® is a trademark of CD Projekt S.A. The Witcher game ©CD Projekt S.A. All rights reserved. The Witcher game is based on a novel by Andrzej Sapkowski. All other copyrights and trademarks are the property of their respective owners.</p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/sword-of-convallaria-x-the-witcher-3-a-commemorative-interview]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Developer of New Postal Game Shuts Down Studio After Game Was Announced, Then Canceled Over Gen AI Allegations]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/developer-of-new-postal-game-shuts-down-studio-after-game-was-announced-then-canceled-over-gen-ai-allegations</link>
            <guid>1374691</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">The studio behind the Postal franchise just announced that it will be publishing a brand new Postal game, to be developed by Goonswarm Games. Unfortunately, it even more recently announced it would be cancelling said game, due to accusations that Goonswarm had used generative AI in its development. And now, Goonswarm is shutting down.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The game, entitled Postal: Bullet Paradise, was announced earlier this week on Wednesday with a reveal trailer and press release. It purports to be a "timeline-hopping, dystopian bullet heavne first-person shooter" set in the Postal universe, where players can select from 11 unlockable Postal Dudes from different timelines and, well, shoot people.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">However, not long after the trailer debuted, Postal fans began pointing out that the game had a lot of hallmarks of assets made with generative AI. When we went to embed the trailer into this article for you to watch, our access to the video file had been cut off and the official version had been removed from YouTube. You can <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/4162690/POSTAL_Bullet_Paradise/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">still watch it through the Steam page here</a> and judge for yourself.</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/12/05/unnamed-1764952300064.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Checking in on the Postal subreddit, you can see some of the feedback. Fan spoint out that the pixel sprites' mouths "don't make sense", and elements such as shading and pixel placement are off somehow. They also point out that Goonswarm has almost certainly used generative AI in its games before (a close watch of <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3642560/SCP_Control_Error/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">this trailer</a> has a number of pretty obvious indicators), making it not impossible that it would do so again.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">When accusations initially began flying, both Goonswarm and Running With Scissors denied the use of generative AI. As Goonswarm <a href="https://www.pcgamesn.com/postal-bullet-paradise/canceled-ai-use" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">told PCGamesN in a statement</a>:</p><blockquote>No generative AI was used for the reveal trailer or for the game. All assets were created by our human artists using standard tools. We've already shared layered PSDs, work-in-progress files, and other materials to confirm this. Any mistakes or rough spots in those files are being misinterpreted as 'proof' of AI, but they simply reflect the normal, human art-creation process</blockquote><p data-cy="paragraph">Meanwhile, while Running With Scissors <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/postal/comments/1pdxamc/important_update_to_the_whole_ai_situation/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">initially promised to investigate further</a>, studio co-owner Mike Jeret <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/postal/comments/1peg2v8/wow_mike_j_great_customer_service_skills_go_to/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">angered the Postal audience further</a> by not just vehemently denying there was generative AI in the game, but also using fairly strong language toward the accusers, referring to them as "ignorant assholes" and telling anyone who thought the game used generative AI to "excuse yourself from our Discord."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">But finally, today, the publisher has taken a definitive stance. Running With Scissors announced it would be canceling the game entirely, saying that the audience feedback had caused "extreme damage to our brand and our company reputation" and that it no longer trusted the development team.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Here's Running With Scissors' statement in full:</p><blockquote>After revealing Postal: Bullet Paradise, a title Running With Scissors was planning on publishing but not developing, we've been overwhelmed with negative responses from our concerned Postal Community. The strong feedback from them is that elements of the game are very likely AI-generated and thus has caused extreme damage to our brand and our company reputation.</blockquote><blockquote>We’ve always been, and will always be, transparent with our community. Our trust in the development team is broken; therefore, we've killed the project. We have a lot of good things coming (some you know and some you don’t).</blockquote><blockquote>Since forming Running With Scissors in 1996, we’ve always said that our fans are part of the team. Our priority is to always do right by the millions who support the Postal franchise. We are grateful for the opportunity to make the games we want to play, and will continue to focus on our new projects and updates coming in 2026 and beyond. We can’t wait to share more!</blockquote><p data-cy="paragraph">Fan feedback in response to this seems generally positive, with <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/postal/comments/1peewit/postal_bullet_paradise_cancelled/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">a number of people suggesting</a> they were excited about the premise of the game and hoped it could be passed on to a different developer. Some are still hoping for an apology from Jeret for his language toward the community, but that has not yet manifested.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">But there's one group of folks who aren't happy, and that's Goonswarm. In a statement posted to Twitter, the studio announced it would be <a href="https://x.com/goonswarmgames/status/1996984553257279918?s=46" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">shutting down due to the cancellation of its game</a>. Here's their statement in full as well:</p><blockquote>Our project, and everything we built over the psat six years, was canceled in just a few days.</blockquote><blockquote>Our studio was mistakenly accused of using AI-generated art in our games, and every attempt to clarify our work only escalated the situation. In the last few hours, we've received a large number of threats, insults, and mockery, which pushed us toward a very difficult decision.</blockquote><blockquote>We're truly sorry for the artists who put their soul into this and supported our studio, only to face false AI accusations. It's tough to pour so much energy into a game and end up caught in the middle of an AI war by accident.</blockquote><blockquote>We've decided to shut down the studio and end all future activities.</blockquote><blockquote>Thank you for being with us. Stay strong, play games.</blockquote><p data-cy="paragraph">This is far from the first time the Postal games, which are essentially about various guys committing mass shootings, have been embroiled in controversy. The last mainline game, Postal 4: NoRegerts, released in 2022 to <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/postal-4-no-regerts-review">a rare 2/10 from us</a>. Our reviewer said that "the comedy is lazy and embarrassing, the combat is messy and painfully unsatisfying, and it runs so poorly on high-end hardware that it can scarcely be enjoyed at all even by those just hoping for some campy shock humor." Running With Scissors has also released multiple spinoffs in recent years, such as 2022's Postal: Brain Damaged by CreativeForge Games and a 2023 April Fool's joke in POOSTALL Royale.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Rebekah Valentine is a senior reporter for IGN. Got a story tip? Send it to rvalentine@ign.com.</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/developer-of-new-postal-game-shuts-down-studio-after-game-was-announced-then-canceled-over-gen-ai-allegations]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2XKO for PS5, Xbox Series launches in January 2026]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/12/2xko-for-ps5-xbox-series-launches-in-january-2026</link>
            <guid>1374688</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Wishlisting now available.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>The <a title="Platforms > PS5 [10,973 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a> and <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [8,388 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a> versions of <a title="Genres > Free-to-Play [485 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/free-to-play">free-to-play</a> fighting game <em><a title="Games > 2XKO [18 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/2xko">2XKO</a></em> will launch in January 2026, developer <a title="Companies > Riot Games [49 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/riot-games">Riot Games</a> <a href="https://2xko.riotgames.com/en-us/news/announcements/2xkos-plans-for-competitive-play-in-2026/" target="_blank">announced</a>. Wishlisting is available now via <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/concept/10005841" target="_blank">PlayStation Store</a> and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-us/games/store/2xko/9pnwbq5561ck" target="_blank">Microsoft Store</a>. <span id="more-1012071"></span></p><p><em>2XKO</em> first launched in Early Access for PC via <a href="https://2xko.riotgames.com/en-us/pc-download" target="_blank">client download</a> on October 7.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Riot Games:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Team up. Tag in.</p><p>Welcome to <em>2XKO</em>, the free-to-play fighting game from the makers of <em>League of Legends</em> and <em><a title="Games > VALORANT [9 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/valorant">VALORANT</a></em>.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong>About</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Two-Versus-Two Combat</strong> – In <em>2XKO</em>, good teamwork makes the difference between victory and defeat. Fight solo to control both champions on your team, or grab a friend to duo with. Switch up your game every match with Fuses, powerful playstyle modifiers that change the rules your team plays by.</li><li><strong>Legendary Fighters</strong> – <em>League of Legends</em>‘ iconic champions take the stage with fresh movesets inspired by the MOBA and reimagined for fighting games. Immerse yourself in the world of Runeterra with beautifully crafted stages, cutting-edge 2D graphics, and original music tracks that bring your battles to life.</li><li><strong>Lobbies and Matchmaking</strong> – Step into a virtual <a title="Genres > Arcade [99 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/arcade">arcade</a> where your next duo partner—or rival—awaits. Ranked, Casual, and Private lobbies let you play your way whether you wanna compete, spectate, or just mash. Plus, with best-in-class rollback netcode and anti-cheat systems, <em>2XKO</em> delivers fair, lag-free gameplay every time you queue up.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new developer diary below.</p><h2><span>Console Release and Competitive Series 2026</span></h2><p><iframe title="2XKO Console Release &amp; Competitive Series 2026" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8kcEAE-ZOVY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/12/2xko-for-ps5-xbox-series-launches-in-january-2026]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SteamOS vs. Windows on dedicated GPUs: It’s complicated, but Windows has an edge]]></title>
            <link>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/12/steamos-vs-windows-on-dedicated-gpus-its-complicated-but-windows-has-an-edge/</link>
            <guid>1374685</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
          
          
<p>Other results vary from game to game and from GPU to GPU. <em>Borderlands 3</em>, for example, performs quite a bit better on Windows than on SteamOS across all of our tested GPUs, sometimes by as much as 20 or 30 percent (with smaller gaps here and there). As a game from 2019 with no ray-tracing effects, it still runs serviceably on SteamOS across the board, but it was the game we tested that favored Windows the most consistently.</p>


<p>In both <em>Forza Horizon 5&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>Cyberpunk 2077,</em> with ray-tracing effects enabled, you also see a consistent advantage for Windows across the 16GB dedicated GPUs, usually somewhere in the 15 to 20 percent range.</p>
<p>To Valve’s credit, there were also many games we tested where Windows and SteamOS performance was functionally tied.&nbsp;<em>Cyberpunk</em> without ray-tracing, <em>Returnal</em> when not hitting the 7600’s 8GB RAM limit, and&nbsp;<em>Assassin’s Creed Valhalla</em> were sometimes&nbsp;<em>actually</em> tied between Windows and SteamOS, or they differed by low-single-digit percentages that you could chalk up to the margin of error.</p>


<p>Now look at the results from the integrated GPUs, the Radeon 780M and RX 8060S. These are pretty different GPUs from one another—the 8060S has more than three times the compute units of the 780M, and it’s working with a higher-speed pool of soldered-down LPDDR5X-8000 rather than two poky DDR5-5600 SODIMMs.</p>

<p>But <em>Borderlands&nbsp;</em>aside, SteamOS actually did quite a bit better on these GPUs relative to Windows. In both&nbsp;<em>Forza&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>Cyberpunk</em> with ray-tracing enabled, SteamOS slightly beats Windows on the 780M, and mostly closes the performance gap on the 8060S. For the games where Windows and SteamOS essentially tied on the dedicated GPUs, SteamOS has a small but consistent lead over Windows in average frame rates.</p>

          
                  </div></div><br/><br/>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/12/steamos-vs-windows-on-dedicated-gpus-its-complicated-but-windows-has-an-edge/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A $5 Million Gift From Sega Saved Nvidia]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/a-5-million-gift-from-sega-saved-nvidia/1100-6536736/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>1374682</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536736">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Nvidia today is the world's most valuable company with a market cap of more than $4 trillion, thanks in large part to the AI boom of the past few years. But Nvidia's success was far from guaranteed.</p><p>CEO and co-founder Jensen Huang recalled recently how a $5 million gift following a failed business deal with Sega gave the company the lifeline it needed at the time, allowing the fledgling company to stay in business and eventually become what it is today.</p><p>Appearing on the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3hptKYix4X8&amp;t=5567s" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Joe Rogan Experience podcast</a>, Huang talked about how, back in the 1990s, he and his two co-founders were trying to drum up business for their start-up PC company. They traveled to Japan and pitched Sega management on the idea that Nvidia could build the company's Dreamcast console.</p><p>Nvidia wasn't able to get it done, however, discovering that it didn't have the technical ability to give Sega what it needed (Sega would end up partnering with VideoLogic for the Dreamcast). However, Huang still wanted the last $5 million that Sega was due to pay Nvidia for its work on the contract. He told Sega management that Sega could give Nvidia the money as an investment, but Huang frankly admitted that "it is most likely to be lost" given Nvidia's lack of business opportunities.</p><p>At the same time, if Sega didn't give Nvidia the money, Nvidia would go out of business, Huang said. The Sega management team informed Huang that, even with the $5 million investment, Nvidia would likely still go out of business. "It was completely true," Huang said.</p><p>But a top Sega boss apparently took a liking to Huang and decided to give him the money as an investment because "Jensen was a young man [the CEO] liked. That's it." Huang said there was about a 0% chance that Nvidia would be able to return Sega the money.</p><p>Nvidia took that money and used it to help build and grow its business in the world of video games, and when Nvidia went public in 1999 at a valuation of $300 million, Sega cashed out. "If he would have kept that $5 million investment, I think it would be worth probably about $1 trillion today," Huang said.</p><p>Nvidia continues to be a big player in the gaming space with its GPUs and it runs the GeForce Now cloud-gaming platform. <a href="https://www.investopedia.com/how-nvidia-makes-money-4799532" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">How Nvidia makes its money</a> today derives more from sales to AI companies.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/a-5-million-gift-from-sega-saved-nvidia/1100-6536736/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Review: HautePad M-Ultra Gen2 Arcade Controller For Switch & Switch 2 - Just A Hair From Perfection]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/hautepad-m-ultra-gen2-arcade-controller-for-switch-and-switch-2-just-a-hair-from-perfection</link>
            <guid>1374661</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
<figure data-uuid="67780ae09ad49"><a title="M-Ultra Gen2 1" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/67780ae09ad49/m-ultra-gen2-1.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Ollie Reynolds / Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure><p>Cosmox Gaming offers up a <em>lot</em> of arcade controllers, including the modular <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/hautepad-x-arcade-controller-for-switch-and-switch-2-a-modular-masterclass-at-a-premium-price">Hautepad X</a> at a more premium price and the remarkably affordable <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/hautepad-c16-and-c16-s-arcade-controllers-for-switch-1-and-2-affordable-and-unique-in-equal-measure">Hautepad C16</a>.</p>
<p>Now, the company has launched the <strong>M-Ultra Gen2</strong>, an aluminium-built leverless that sits somewhere in-between the two. If the C-16 is primarily aimed at beginners and the X is for the more hardcore enthusiasts, then the M-Ultra Gen2 is, theoretically, for <em>everybody</em>. It’s quite possibly Cosmox’s best controller yet.</p>
<p>Priced at just over <strong>£110</strong> (or <strong>$149.99</strong> in the US), the Gen2 is more expensive than the aforementioned C-16 and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/8bitdo-arcade-controller-for-switch-plus-switch-2-the-best-way-to-play-street-fighter-6">8BitDo’s Arcade Controller</a>, but still sits comfortably toward the more ‘affordable’ end of the spectrum. You wouldn’t think that after going hands on with it, though. With its aluminium build, the Gen2 is a solid, heavy device that feels a lot more comparable to the Hautepad X.</p><div><figure data-videoid="-13CJKg9tJk" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/-13CJKg9tJk?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><div><iframe id="yt-13CJKg9tJk" title="YouTube Video" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/-13CJKg9tJk?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/-13CJKg9tJk?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed5c0dc7sqtvnh&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>840k</span></a></p>
</div></figure></div>

<p>The surface is slightly textured, meaning it won’t attract any nasty fingerprints when handled over time. With models available in both black and blue, I can’t say for definite whether the black version also repels smudges and grime, but the blue model has remained completely spotless after my time with it.</p>
<p>Like the previous models, the Gen2 is compatible with the Switch and Switch 2 right out of the box – just hold down the relevant button to enable Switch Mode while plugging the device in, and you’re good to go. Naturally, you can use the controller with most modern systems, but just keep in mind that you’ll need an extra authenticator to use it with a PS5 or Xbox.</p>
<p>Speaking of plugs, you get a braided USB-A to USB-C cable, which can either go into the top of the controller or over on the left hand side. If you opt for the top, Cosmox has included a new security clasp to lock the cable in place. You just pull the small switch down to open it up, and the actual port is housed about an inch inside. Once the cable is plugged in and the clasp is locked, there’s no way of accidentally yanking it back out – very handy.</p>

<p>The 16 button layout is pretty standard, with four directional inputs, eight action inputs, and four additional programmable buttons. They utilise Shadow Hunting switches, which are comfortably the lowest-profile yet, and this makes actuation exceedingly quick. In fact, the low profile makes advanced techniques like sliding easier than ever, while they still allow for other methods like double-tapping a single button with two fingers.</p>
<p>So all of this combined with the relatively close spacing between the buttons themselves make general gameplay feel more comfortable than ever. Seriously, if you thought pulling off combos in <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/street-fighter-6-years-1-2-fighters-edition">Street Fighter 6</a> was easy on the C-16, then you’ve seen nothing yet – I wouldn’t be surprised if the Shadow Hunting switches just become the new standard going forward. It's incredibly comfortable to use, and I’ve no doubt it’ll give you an edge if you play competitively.</p>
<p>Taking inspiration from the C-16, all switches include customisable RGB rings which you can tinker with on the device itself via several button combinations. If you want to go even further, you can connect the Gen2 to a PC or Mac and follow the URL address displayed on the controller’s screen to reach the web configurator. Here, you can set the RGB rings to whatever colour you wish and remap the inputs, setting several profiles depending on what kind of game you’re playing.</p>

<p>As is the standard now for Cosmox, the Gen2 also features its own OLED screen to display button-presses in real-time along with your input mode and SOCD mode (plus you can upload custom pixel art via the configurator if you want to personalise it even more). It’s larger than ever this time, which is great if you’re after a bit more clarity, though I’d probably prefer it to be situated more in the middle of the device rather than toward the left. Symmetry ‘n’ all that.</p>
<p>And of course, you’ve got a tournament lock switch on the top left alongside one to toggle the RGB lights on and off. Over on the right are your function buttons like start, select, home, etc. Everything’s labelled nicely, including the main face buttons, but keep in mind that when you’re in Switch Mode, the labels won’t match up with the actual in-game inputs. You’re not going to be looking at the buttons much either way, so it probably won’t matter, but if you’re sensitive about this kind of thing, it’s worth keeping in mind. If it really bothers you, then just remap the inputs via the configurator to match the labelling.</p>
<figure data-uuid="36fb367f2eebd"><a title="M-Ultra Gen2 8" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/36fb367f2eebd/m-ultra-gen2-8.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Ollie Reynolds / Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure>
<h2>Conclusion</h2>
<p>I can’t overstate just how <em>nice</em> the M-Ultra Gen2 feels to use. With each new release, it feels like Cosmox Gaming is making more and more small tweaks to achieve eventual perfection. It’s not <em>quite</em> there yet – the 8BitDo Arcade Controller’s ability to dynamically change the button labelling is still a marvel – but the way the buttons feel and the overall build quality of the Gen2 is incredible. Simply put, this is the company’s strongest effort yet, and one of the best leverless arcade controllers available if you’re on a budget.</p>



<p>Please note that some external links on this page are affiliate links, which means if you click them and make a purchase we may receive a small percentage of the sale. Please read our <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/advertising">FTC Disclosure</a> for more information.</p>

<p><em>Thanks to Cosmox Gaming for providing the sample used in this review.</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/hautepad-m-ultra-gen2-arcade-controller-for-switch-and-switch-2-just-a-hair-from-perfection]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Five Nights At Freddy’s 2 Reviews Are Even Worse Than You Think]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/five-nights-at-freddys-2-reviews-are-even-worse-than-you-think-2000650964</link>
            <guid>1374655</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><em><a href="https://kotaku.com/fnaf-2-five-nights-freddys-2-movie-trailer-teaser-foxy-1851786887">Five Nights at Freddy’s 2</a>,</em> out now in theaters, doesn’t sound like a good movie. And sure, the first film wasn’t a cinematic masterpiece, but according to critics, the sequel is even worse. It’s already one of 2025’s worst-rated movies, beating out some real stinkers.</p> <p><em>Five Nights at Freddy’s 2</em> is the follow-up to 2023’s <em>Five Nights at Freddy’s</em> and, like that movie, is a live-action adaptation of the popular horror game franchise that features a lot of evil animatronic figures and tons of confusing and bizarre lore. <a href="https://kotaku.com/five-nights-at-freddys-fnaf-movie-review-box-office-1850974086">The original film was a big hit at the box office</a>, but took a beating from critics and ended up with an abysmal <a href="https://www.rottentomatoes.com/m/five_nights_at_freddys">33% on</a> <em>Rotten Tomatoes.</em> I bet Blumhouse and Universal would love for the newly released sequel to have that score. Instead, critics seem to hate this new entry even more, with <em>Freddy’s 2</em> sitting at a truly awful 12% on the review aggregate site. Ouch.</p>

 <p>Here’s what various critics think about this latest horror sequel:</p> <blockquote><p>“Clunky, overstuffed, and strangely lifeless, <em>Five Nights at Freddy’s 2</em> trades genuine scares for incoherent lore. Even the animatronics can’t save a sequel that feels more like brand maintenance than an actual movie.” – <strong>Dionar Hidalgo, <em>Algo Más Que Cine</em></strong></p> <p>“[Its] sole imperative appears to be boring its audience to death.” – <strong>Nick Schager, <em>The Daily Beast</em></strong></p> <p>“<em>Five Nights at Freddy’s 2</em> plays best for die-hard fans; for everyone else, it’s a stitched-together sequel with few scares and even fewer surprises.” – <strong>Allison Rose, <em>FlickDirect</em></strong></p> <p><em>“Five Nights at Freddy’s 2</em> is one of Blumhouse’s worst sequels, nothing more than a cynical cash grab that treats its audience and fanbase like mindless children.” -T<strong>yler Taing, <em>Discussing Film</em></strong></p></blockquote> <p><a href="https://www.rottentomatoes.com/m/five_nights_at_freddys_2/reviews">And it goes on and on and on.</a> The consensus is that the movie is primarily designed to appeal to younger teens who are already obsessed with the franchise and will pick up on all the lore, Easter eggs, and secrets buried in the PG-13 horror flick. So it will likely make a lot of money, like the last one. But for everyone else, including people who like good movies, <em>Freddy’s 2</em> sounds like a bad time and one to avoid.</p>

 <p>Compared to some other stinkers released this year, <em>Five Nights at Freddy’s 2</em> is up there. It has a worse <a href="https://www.rottentomatoes.com/m/star_trek_section_31">Rotten Tomatoes score than the awful <em>Star Trek</em> movie</a> we got this year, which most people thankfully don’t know about. <a href="https://www.rottentomatoes.com/m/a_minecraft_movie">It also has a worse <em>RT</em> rating</a> than the <a href="https://kotaku.com/minecraft-movie-review-bad-jack-black-kids-movie-steve-1851775345">utterly awful Jack Black led <em>Minecraft</em> film</a>, which is wild. It even has a <a href="https://www.rottentomatoes.com/m/disneys_snow_white">worse score</a> than <a href="https://kotaku.com/snow-white-seven-dwarfs-trailer-cgi-ugly-bad-disney-1851712570">Disney’s terrible <em>Snow White</em> remake</a>, which, yes, came out this year. Remember that movie? Probably not.</p> <p>Oh, and if you are wondering, no, according to <em>Rotten Tomatoes, Freddy’s 2</em> is better than the <em>Borderlands</em> movie. But just barely, as that disaster of a flick from Eli Roth has <a href="https://www.rottentomatoes.com/m/borderlands">a 10% rating.</a> Better than <a href="https://kotaku.com/borderlands-movie-review-rotten-tomatoes-cast-release-1851616912"><em>Borderlands</em></a> isn’t much, but it is something to brag about, I guess?</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/five-nights-at-freddys-2-reviews-are-even-worse-than-you-think-2000650964]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GTA 6 Dev Announces $60 Candle That Smells Like Vice City]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-6-dev-announces-60-candle-that-smells-like-vice-city/1100-6536735/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>1374649</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536735">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>While the gaming world eagerly awaits the launch of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/grand-theft-auto-6-everything-we-know/1100-6503729/" data-ref-id="1100-6503729">Grand Theft Auto 6</a> in 2026, Rockstar Games has announced a <a href="https://www.rockstargames.com/newswire/article/o3285972548k19/new-at-the-rockstar-store-apparel-collectibles-and-more?utm_source=twitter&amp;utm_medium=o_social&amp;utm_campaign=rockstar_announcement_storeupdate-20251205" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">variety of new themed products for the holidays</a>, including a $60 candle that smells like "Vice." This is likely a reference to Vice City, the setting of 2002's GTA: Vice City and next year's GTA 6.</p><p>Developed in collaboration with Joya Studios, the <a href="https://store.rockstargames.com/merchandise/buy-vice-candle?_gl=1*s8ktvb*_ga*NjgzMjQzODA5LjE3Mzc2NTQ4MDQ.*_ga_PJQ2JYZDQC*czE3NjQ5NTUzOTkkbzEwOCRnMSR0MTc2NDk1NjE0NCRqNTIkbDAkaDA." data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Vice candle </a>comes in a frosted white glass with the Rockstar Games logo and has notes of lemon California, yerba mate, thyme, fig leaf, petitgrain, orange oil, and terpenes. Your nose may also notice notes of tuberose, mimosa, jasmine petals, lily, lotus, cyclamen, wild grass, and raspberry blossom. Beyond those, the candle also contains notes of Texas Cedarwood, galbanum, and smoked patchouli.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4616716-screenshot2025-12-05at12.38.16%E2%80%AFpm.png" data-ref-id="1300-4616716" data-ratio="0.56257449344458" data-width="839" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4616716-screenshot2025-12-05at12.38.16%E2%80%AFpm.png" data-ref-id="1300-4616716"></a><figcaption>All the new Rockstar products for the holidays.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4616716-screenshot2025-12-05at12.38.16%E2%80%AFpm.png"></figure><p>There is also a <a href="https://store.rockstargames.com/merchandise/buy-liberty-candle" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">"Liberty" candle</a> that comes in a frosted black glass with notes of blood orange, black pepper, green cardamom, cedar, and clove leaves. The burn time for these candles is about 65 hours, Rockstar said, or just under $1 per hour if you want to look at it that way.</p><p>Beyond the $60 candles, the Rockstar Games store was updated for the holidays with new $90 crewneck sweatshirts with the Rockstar Games logo emblazoned on them, a 32oz Nalgene water bottle, a series of t-shirts screen printed with screenshots of past Rockstar games like GTA 5 and Red Dead Redemption 2, along with a $50 "Say Sorry Be Nice" door mat, along with new pins and stickers.</p><p>You can <a href="https://store.rockstargames.com/new-arrivals" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">visit the Rockstar Games Store</a> to see all the new products.</p><p>As for GTA 6, the long-awaited open-world game launches on November 19, 2026 for PS5 and Xbox Series X|S. As mentioned, the game returns to Vice City and lets players explore the city itself--a stand-in for Miami--along with the wider state of Leonida (AKA Florida).</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-6-dev-announces-60-candle-that-smells-like-vice-city/1100-6536735/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How Dave The Diver's New DLC Uses A Dash Of Animal Crossing To Shake Things Up]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/how-dave-the-divers-new-dlc-uses-a-dash-of-animal-crossing-to-shake-things-up/1100-6536730/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>1374643</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536730">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">Dave the Diver is a modest game that has expanded like Dave's belt size. The underwater adventure and restaurant management sim mash-up was a surprise hit, and has since spawned crossover efforts with fishing game Dredge, the kaiju Godzilla, and even Ichiban Kasuga of the Like A Dragon series. Now the game is preparing to dive back in with the In The Jungle expansion in early 2026. The DLC will see Dave and his crew heading to a new freshwater biome and catching lake-dwelling creatures to make their dishes. GameSpot spoke with Mintrocket CEO and Dave the Diver game director Jaeho Hwang about the upcoming expansion, how the studio has responded to the game's success, and the delicious research that goes into making a game all about food.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=P3ZsbGrCQ58" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/P3ZsbGrCQ58" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p dir="ltr"><strong>GameSpot: What was the genesis of the "In the Jungle" concept? What was the team trying to achieve with this new biome?</strong></p><p dir="ltr"><strong>Jaeho Hwang: </strong>In Dave the Diver, we felt we had done a fair job showcasing the mystique of the ocean, so we wanted to explore a completely different world this time.</p><p dir="ltr">The jungle biome was something we had been eager to try since the early days of developing Dave the Diver. We couldn't include fascinating freshwater creatures like alligators or piranhas before, and players have been asking for them a lot. You may have seen massive, fierce fish like catfish or tigerfish in documentaries or on YouTube. We thought it would be fun for Dave to catch and battle these kinds of creatures.</p><p dir="ltr">Besides the lake, we also plan to bring the jungle's diverse wildlife and insects to the game. You'll see Dave chasing wild butterflies or even getting attacked by monkeys.</p><p dir="ltr"><strong>Did you learn any lessons from the main campaign and previous DLCs that you've applied to this one?</strong></p><p dir="ltr"><strong>Hwang:</strong> Rather than simply expanding the main game experience like most DLCs do, our goal was to create a DLC that offers a completely different experience. Of course, we've kept the fun core elements of management and exploration from the main game, but beyond that, we aim to deliver that enjoyment through new systems. Expanding the game using the original systems and mechanics will continue through other DLCs or updates, while In the Jungle DLC focuses on introducing new experiences and experimental systems. We are trying to distinguish and offer two different concepts.</p><p dir="ltr">For example, in this DLC, time flows in real time at the village. There are also gathering and crafting elements. Unlike the original game where the story has linear progression and the NPCs appear automatically, Dave will need to actively approach and talk to them this time. Of course, there still are unique guests who show up unexpectedly.</p><p dir="ltr">Maintaining the entertainment of the original game while presenting it in a new way is as challenging as creating an entirely new game. The development process has certainly been difficult, but we're continuously improving the quality and believe we would be able to present a satisfying experience to our players when the DLC launches.</p><p dir="ltr"><strong>What kind of research goes into developing new underwater biomes and sushi recipes? Trips to the aquarium and great sushi restaurants?</strong></p><p dir="ltr"><strong>Hwang:</strong> This time, since the theme is freshwater fish, the main dishes will surprisingly be grilled fish instead of sushi!</p><p dir="ltr">[That may] sound a bit reckless for us to remove one of the most beloved elements. But that's actually why we're releasing this as a DLC rather than a full sequel. A sequel would need to preserve and build upon the appealing elements of the original game.</p><p dir="ltr">When we design new regions or ecosystems, I try to experience the atmosphere firsthand as much as possible. For the jungle environment, I drew a lot of inspiration from a trip to Indonesia--although I didn't get the chance to dive into a lake.</p><p dir="ltr">Most of the dishes in Dave the Diver are fictional, but many team members love scuba diving and often share food experiences from their travels, which we incorporate into the game. We also had team gatherings at the aquarium to observe fish behavior in real life.</p><p dir="ltr">For In the Jungle DLC, we referenced some fish directly from our office aquarium, including discus and snakehead.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1585/15855271/4616685-mintrocket_officeaquarium.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4616685" data-ratio="0.66666666666667" data-width="6192" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1585/15855271/4616685-mintrocket_officeaquarium.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4616685"></a><figcaption>Mintrocket's office aquarium</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1585/15855271/4616685-mintrocket_officeaquarium.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr"><strong>The new lake setting would seem to make a big difference to the types of fish available. Does it impact other aspects of the underwater segments?</strong></p><p dir="ltr"><strong>Hwang:</strong> As shown in the trailer, the biggest change is the introduction of creatures like alligators and catfish.</p><p dir="ltr">There are also differences in the resources you can gather underwater at the lake. For example, since it's not the ocean, you won't be collecting coral or starfish.</p><p dir="ltr">In this DLC, we've reduced the randomness of obtaining weapons underwater and instead focused on upgrading the equipment in various forms in the village. You'll also find new weapons tailored to the region.</p><p dir="ltr">The lake in the DLC actually starts off polluted due to a certain incident, and there are some elements triggered from this. It can also be purified through a certain process.</p><p dir="ltr">I can't reveal a whole lot just yet, but there are also some gimmicks from ancient civilization elements found in the lake.</p><p dir="ltr"><strong>How do you approach paid vs free DLC updates?</strong></p><p dir="ltr"><strong>Hwang:</strong> Dave the Diver has been far more successful than we have expected, so we've tried to provide as much content as possible for free. So far--aside from the Like a Dragon collaboration--everything, including the Nintendo Switch 2 upgrade, has been offered at no cost. Our players have been supporting us with incredible passion, and we've never felt that this approach has caused us any loss.</p><p dir="ltr">However, In the Jungle DLC content would be around 10 hours of gameplay and we've put in a significant amount of development effort behind this. For this reason, it will be released as paid add-on content. We've heard some disappointment from our community regarding the high price of the Like a Dragon DLC ($6.99) compared to its volume, so this time we're committed to setting a fair price and delivering content that exceeds expectations in quality as we have done in the past.</p><p dir="ltr"><strong>How has the game's success impacted your process for handling DLC? Did you add more post-launch plans once it took off or was the plan always to provide this much post-launch support?</strong></p><p dir="ltr"><strong>Hwang:</strong> As a director, I've always dreamt that if the base game succeeded, we would have the chance to expand its universe through collaborating with other games. Thankfully, Dave the Diver's success gave us the opportunity to work with many amazing IPs--and even bring some of my personal favorites, like Godzilla and Ichiban Kasuga, into our world.</p><p dir="ltr">Jungle-themed DLC was always part of our plan, but it would have been difficult to commit to it if the game hadn't received such a positive response. I want to take this chance to thank our players for giving us the opportunity to keep moving forward.</p><p dir="ltr">Even after the In the Jungle DLC, I have some fun crossover and content ideas that I'd love to pursue. I can't reveal anything just yet, but I hope there will be another chance to share them someday through GameSpot.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/how-dave-the-divers-new-dlc-uses-a-dash-of-animal-crossing-to-shake-things-up/1100-6536730/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Riot's 2XKO Arrives On Consoles In January]]></title>
            <link>https://gameinformer.com/2025/12/05/riots-2xko-arrives-on-consoles-in-january</link>
            <guid>1374640</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p>We first learned about 2XKO as Project L back in 2019. The title was borne out of Riot Games' <a href="https://gameinformer.com/b/news/archive/2016/03/08/riot-games-purchases-radiant-entertainment-seth-killians-rising-thunder-alpha-closing.aspx" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="3efb48ae-7f46-4920-aad1-afa162f2b23e" data-entity-substitution="canonical">acquisition of Radiant Entertainment</a>, which was in the process of developing <a href="https://gameinformer.com/games/rising_thunder/b/pc/archive/2015/07/20/a-street-fighter-veteran-enters-the-ring-with-a-new-take-on-the-genre.aspx" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="9dc9ee31-4691-4fd7-afe5-4e6166808215" data-entity-substitution="canonical">Rising Thunder</a>, a technically proficient yet approachable fighting game, back in 2016. We've known about 2XKO for years now, and the game has been playable as an early access release on PC since October, but we now have an idea of when we'll play it on consoles.</p><p>Riot Games has announced that 2XKO is coming to PS5 and Xbox Series X/S in January 2026. Season 1, which introduces a new champion and extended progression, will coincide with that launch across all platforms. During this time, players will gain access to unlocked content, including champions, skins, mastery rewards, and more, regardless of which platform you play on, with a catch-up mechanic to help console players earn content from the PC early access period.&nbsp;</p>



<article data-entity-type="file" data-entity-uuid="f34fd60d-3720-422e-aaa9-35187dd51fa1" data-embed-button="image_browser_uploader" data-entity-embed-display="image:responsive_image" data-entity-embed-display-settings="{&quot;responsive_image_style&quot;:&quot;content_body&quot;,&quot;image_loading&quot;:{&quot;attribute&quot;:&quot;lazy&quot;},&quot;image_link&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;link_url&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;link_target&quot;:0,&quot;link_original&quot;:0,&quot;image_source&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;embed_source&quot;:0,&quot;image_caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;embed_caption&quot;:0,&quot;content_warning&quot;:0}" data-langcode="en">

  
          <picture>
                  <source srcset="https://gameinformer.com/sites/default/files/styles/body_default/public/2025/12/04/d887b127/2xko_gameplay_3.jpg.webp 1x" media="all and (min-width: 851px)" type="image/webp" width="800" height="450">
              <source srcset="https://gameinformer.com/sites/default/files/styles/content_default_mobile_/public/2025/12/04/d887b127/2xko_gameplay_3.jpg.webp 1x" media="all and (min-width: 315px) and (max-width: 450px)" type="image/webp" width="450" height="253">
              <source srcset="https://gameinformer.com/sites/default/files/styles/content_default_mobile_/public/2025/12/04/d887b127/2xko_gameplay_3.jpg.webp 1x" media="all and (max-width: 314px)" type="image/webp" width="450" height="253">
                  

  </picture>


  
  
  
</article>

<p>Season 1 brings with it Frame Perfect, a new competitive-themed skin that will see Riot donating a portion of the proceeds to directly support tournament organizers and help fund prize pools and production costs. Additionally, Riot unveiled the 2026 Competitive Series, which is a program built in direct partnership with tournament organizers across the globe. The 2026 Competitive Series will include 20 official Riot events, including 5 Majors. The first event kicks off on January 29.</p><p>It all begins when 2XKO arrives on PS5 and Xbox Series X/S in January alongside the start of Season 1 across all platforms.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://gameinformer.com/2025/12/05/riots-2xko-arrives-on-consoles-in-january]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Here’s Why You’re (Probably) Not Finding Blueprints In Arc Raiders]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/arc-raiders-blueprint-locations-night-raid-map-2000650966</link>
            <guid>1374619</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Of the many progression paths to follow in extraction shooter <i>Arc Raiders</i>, perhaps one of the most rewarding are blueprints. They expand your arsenal by giving you access to craft all sorts of new weapons, gun mods, grenades, and more. Once you hit max level, finish all your quests (you get blueprints for many of these!), and even wrap up the expedition project, collecting blueprints is the true end-game grind.</p> <p><b>Read More: </b><a href="https://kotaku.com/arc-raiders-screenshots-photo-mode-hud-binoculars-2000650620">One Player Turned 2025’s Hit Extraction Shooter Into A Stunning War Photography Sim</a></p> <p>But blueprints are often quite tricky to find. Outside of the ones you earn for completing quests, most players come across blueprints randomly, without much rhyme or reason as to why they’re found in certain areas.</p>

 <p>In my extensive time with the game, blueprints can be very hard to source reliably, unlike much of the game’s loot, which typically is found in specific environmental categories. It truly feels random.</p> <p><b>Read More:</b> <a href="https://kotaku.com/arc-raiders-leaper-kill-spaceport-trials-into-the-fray-2000649665">This Is The ‘Easiest’ Way To Kill A Leaper In <i>Arc Raiders</i></a></p> <p>But don’t despair, there are some clear strategies that can amplify your chances of finding new blueprints. Let’s get into it.</p>

 <h2>Blueprint hunting? Prioritize Night and Electromagnetic Storm Raids</h2> <figure id="attachment_2000650972" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000650972"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000650972">© Screenshot: Embark Studios / Kotaku</figcaption></figure> <p><i>Arc Raiders</i>’ five unique maps see a regular rotation of activities, such as Night Raids, raids with intense lightning storms, and <a href="https://kotaku.com/arc-raiders-hidden-bunker-wall-hack-glitch-keys-2000650571">Spaceport’s exclusive Hidden Bunker activity</a>. These activities have fewer extraction points, as well as environmental conditions that can prove more dangerous than a normal run.</p>

 <p>But in my experience, they seem to dramatically improve your chances of finding blueprints. Also, running an activity like a Night Raid will double the amount of trial points you get for completing certain activities, and it’s not uncommon to earn a blueprint from completing a trial.</p>

 <p><b>Read More:</b> <a href="https://kotaku.com/arc-raiders-inventory-full-stash-loadout-crafting-cheat-sheet-2000643629">The Hoarder’s Guide To Managing Your <i>Arc Raiders</i> Inventory</a></p> <p>These activities are dangerous, however, so you want to go in well-equipped <i>or</i> without much to lose. Whether you want to bring in your valuable weapons or minimize your losses is up to you, but if there’s one thing I’ve learned by hitting Night Raids and similar activities, it’s to avoid running with a Free Loadout when possible.</p>

 <h2>Don’t use Free Loadouts when hunting for blueprints</h2> <p>Free Loadouts are wonderful. They’re a quick way to warm up without much risk of loss. But they don’t include a safe pocket, which lets you stash away a single item (that isn’t a gun or shield) to be preserved even if you fail to extract with it.</p>

 <p>So yes, while rolling into a Night Raid with a Free Loadout situates you with nothing to lose and everything to gain, scoring a blueprint on a run won’t do you much good if you get taken out without the ability to safely secure that item.</p> <p>By the time you start&nbsp; grinding for blueprints and hitting up the more challenging map conditions, you should have enough loot to at least put together a basic loadout with an augment that includes a safe pocket.</p> <p><b>Read More:</b> <a href="https://kotaku.com/arc-raiders-guns-blue-green-purple-gold-best-2000644142">The Best Guns For Every Possible Situation In <i>Arc Raiders</i></a></p> <p>Remember, you can always trade a Free Loadout augment for any of the starting augments from Lance in the Traders tab of the main menu.</p>

 <p>Once you find a blueprint, toss that thing into your safe pocket immediately. Don’t take any chances.</p> <h2>Now that you have a safe pocket for blueprints, where should you look?</h2> <figure id="attachment_2000650971" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000650971"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000650971">© Screenshot: Embark Studios / Kotaku</figcaption></figure> <p>There might be a blueprint hiding in some random hood of a car in a parking lot. There could be one in a trash can tucked away in an alley somewhere. They’re exceedingly random in their hiding spots, and it’s hard to predict just where you’ll find one.</p> <p>For that reason, you’re going to want to prioritize locations with <i>tons</i> of loot containers, especially office buildings that have no shortage of desk drawers, lockers, and cabinets to rifle through.</p>

 <p>In my experience, it’s not so much that things like desk drawers and lockers have a higher likelihood of containing a blueprint, but it’s that in a room filled with them, you’re simply opening far more containers and are thus increasing your odds of finding a blueprint by numbers alone. Think of them like loot boxes (that you don’t pay for). Do you want to open one or two with the chance of finding something good? Or a dozen of them?</p> <p><b>Read More:</b> <a href="https://kotaku.com/arc-raiders-cheat-sheet-crafting-guns-ardb-wiki-2000644449"><i>Arc Raiders</i>: The Best Cheat Sheets And Third-Party Resources</a></p> <p>I recommend searching the following locations as they’re filled with lockers and drawers:</p> <h3>Spaceport</h3> <ul> <li aria-level="1">Arrival Building</li> <li aria-level="1">Departure Building</li> <li aria-level="1">Control Tower A6</li> </ul> <h3>Dam Battlegrounds</h3> <ul> <li aria-level="1">Research &amp; Administration</li> <li aria-level="1">Control Tower</li> <li aria-level="1">Testing Annex</li> </ul> <h3>Buried City</h3> <ul> <li aria-level="1">Plaza Rosa (especially the locked pharmacy)</li> <li aria-level="1">Library</li> <li aria-level="1">Space Travel</li> <li aria-level="1">Research</li> <li aria-level="1">Hospital</li> </ul> <p>As for the remaining two maps, you can certainly end up finding blueprints on them, but Blue Gate, in my experience, doesn’t have as many office suites filled with tons of drawers to improve your lottery chances. That said, the Reinforced Reception area is pretty good, but that location is likely to be hot with other players as there’s some great weaponry to be found down there.</p>

 <p>Similarly, Stella Montis, the game’s tiniest map, has quickly made a name for itself as a slaughterfest. It’s basically the unofficial PvP map. So, while you might stand to find some good blueprints here, expect some overwhelming fights. If you’re dead set on going here to hunt blueprints, you probably want to prioritize Medical Research, Loading Bay, or the many discarded suitcases in Lobby. Still, Stella Montis is typically such a dangerous map that I wouldn’t advise going here unless you’re looking for a brawl. You might find a blueprint, only to be killed moments later without a chance to even stash it away in your safe pocket.</p> <p><b>Read More:</b> <a href="https://kotaku.com/arc-raiders-trade-fruit-loot-scrappy-lemons-mushrooms-2000649233">Extraction Shooter Player Puts Down Guns And Starts Selling Fruit Instead</a></p> <p>Finally, trash cans <i>seem </i>like they have a higher percentage of containing a blueprint. Don’t worry, that doesn’t mean you need to run up to every single trash can you see. You can tell if a trash can has loot if it has an extra cover on top, making it appear taller than other receptacles.</p> <h2>Search <i>everything</i> in key rooms</h2> <p>In general, it’s best to loot the locked rooms during Night Raids and similar activities. But as with the locations listed above, be <i>thorough</i> in your searches of these rooms. I recommend bringing Door Blockers and Barricade Kits, as well as other items to booby trap these rooms once you get in. That will buy you time to sift through every possible loot container in case <a href="https://kotaku.com/arc-raiders-pvp-betrayal-bounty-rat-camp-2000649163">another player tries to jump you</a> while you’re looting the now-unlocked room.</p> <hr> <p>Blueprints are essential for piecing together a new <i>Arc Raiders </i>loadout that’s powerful and effective after a crushing loss.</p> <p>Happy hunting!</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/arc-raiders-blueprint-locations-night-raid-map-2000650966]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A New Postal Game Was Announced, Then Canceled Over AI Slop, Within Just 48 Hours]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/postal-bullet-paradise-running-with-scissors-ai-canceled-2000650949</link>
            <guid>1374616</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p id="featured-image">
                              <figure id="attachment_featured" aria-describedby="featured-caption">
                                                                          <figcaption id="featured-caption">
                    <span>Some blurry mess of sprites.</span> © Running With Scissors
                  </figcaption>
                </figure>
                                                      </p><div>
              
              <p>The&nbsp;<em>Postal</em> games have always been what you might call “slop.” Running With Scissors’ series of puerile, drearily unfunny action games have somehow regularly been released since 1997, relying entirely on their hamfisted “shock factor” to try to impress an audience that delights in “politically incorrect” or “anti-woke” dross, without also remembering the important elements of “fun.” But the most recently revealed entry in the 30-year series, <em>Postal: Bullet Paradise</em>, earns the “slop” mantle for a different reason, after massive backlash against its prolific use of AI has seen it canceled in the same week it was announced!</p> <p>Revealed just two days ago, on December 3,&nbsp;<em>Postal: Bullet Paradise&nbsp;</em>was due to be a&nbsp;<em>Vampire Survivors</em>-like spin-off from the franchise, developed by a separate team called Goonswarm Games. Described as a “bullet-heaven shooter with online co-op,” Running With Scissors promoted the upcoming game with <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/4162690/POSTAL_Bullet_Paradise/">a Steam page</a>, YouTube trailers, and a <a href="https://runningwithscissors.com/postal-bullet-paradise-brings-nonstop-action-pc-consoles/">section on its own website</a>. Of them all, the only thing that fully remains two days later is the post, with the Steam page delisted and the game removed from RWS’s and Goonswarm’s pages.</p>

 <p>Based on the game’s cancellation announcement <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/postal/comments/1pdenph/rws_using_ai_is_incredibly_disappointing/">on Running With Scissors’ X page</a>, it seems potential fans launched a sizable backlash after noticing&nbsp;<em>Postal: Bullet Paradise</em>&nbsp;allegedly contained AI-generated material. Users on the franchise’s Reddit were complaining about AI art appearing in the trailer, and alleging Goonswarm had used AI in its previous work. “You see can very clearly that all the pixel sprites are ai generated,” <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/postal/comments/1pdenph/rws_using_ai_is_incredibly_disappointing/">claimed on Reddit poster</a>, adding, “It just sucks that rws is going down the path of ai since they’ve been so supportive of art for a long time.”</p>

 <p>Then came the announcement declaring the entire project flushed. “After revealing <em>POSTAL: Bullet Paradise</em>, a title Running With Scissors was planning on publishing but not developing,” says the statement, “we’ve been overwhelmed with negative responses from our concerned&nbsp;<em>POSTAL</em> Community. The strong feedback from them is that elements of the game are very likely AI-generated and thus has caused extreme damage to our brand and our company reputation.”</p>

 <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">After revealing POSTAL: Bullet Paradise, a title Running With Scissors was planning on publishing but not developing, we've been overwhelmed with negative responses from our concerned POSTAL Community. The strong feedback from them is that elements of the game are very likely…</p> <p>— Running With Scissors (@RWSstudios) <a href="https://twitter.com/RWSstudios/status/1996715985437388817?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 4, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <p>The statement goes on to express RWS’s desire to be transparent before stating that <em>Bullet Paradise</em> has been canceled, effective immediately. “Our trust in the development team is broken,” it reads, “therefore we’ve killed the project.”</p>

 <p>This is especially embarrassing for the publisher, given that it had only a few days ago publicly disagreed with Epic’s Tim Sweeney over the need to declare AI use in game development.</p> <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">Customers deserve to know if a game was crafted with creativity, soul and actual talent rather than some machine that craps out anything from a prompt.</p> <p>We don't know what the future holds, but AI apologists like Mr. Sweeney are making this shit unbearable already. <a href="https://t.co/eHszQu5STP">https://t.co/eHszQu5STP</a></p> <p>— Running With Scissors (@RWSstudios) <a href="https://twitter.com/RWSstudios/status/1994033855934644492?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 27, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <p>The original&nbsp;<em>Postal</em>, a top-down shooter about playing a postal worker who goes on a mass murder spree throughout the town of Paradise, Arizona, went out of its way to court controversy and notoriety when it first appeared. Its final level was set in an elementary school (albeit where the main character, Postal Dude, has a complete breakdown after none of his weapons work on the children), and its deliberately crass approach was designed to get as much negative attention as possible, presumably to drive sales. However, the mediocre game never sold all that well, and after an equally crap 3D sequel five years later, the company began outsourcing development to Russian studios. 2011’s <em>Postal III</em> was made by Trashmasters, and was so terrible RWS apologized for the game in the aftermath, <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130629223127/http://runningwithscissors.com/main/index.php?topic=625.0">eventually deleting it from their store entirely</a>. A 2016 redux version of <em>Postal 2</em> sold so poorly on PC that console versions were canceled (until years later), until RWS finally returned to making their own game with 2022’s <em>Postal 4: No Regrets</em>.</p> <p>It’s probably not a good thing when your franchise’s highlight is a Uwe Boll movie. And to be clear, <a href="https://www.metacritic.com/movie/postal/">that too was atrocious</a>.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/postal-bullet-paradise-running-with-scissors-ai-canceled-2000650949]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battlefield 6 Winter Offensive Update Will Add a Limited-Time Map and Game Mode]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-winter-offensive-update-will-add-a-limited-time-map-and-game-mode/</link>
            <guid>1374613</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Battlefield 6 Winter Offensive content update details have been revealed, and it seems we are receiving a new time-limited map, game modes, and a whole set of bug fixes. </p>



<p>The update highlights for Battlefield 6 Winter Offensive were revealed <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-winter-offensive-update-details-revealed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">earlier this week</a>, with developers discussing audio issues, mode adjustments, combat system, soldier visibility, and more. Now, the patch notes for Battlefield 6 Update 1.1.3.0 are live, detailing everything new before it drops on December 9. </p>







<h2 id="h-what-s-new-in-battlefield-6-winter-offensive">What’s New in Battlefield 6 Winter Offensive?</h2>



<p>Starting with all the new content in Battlefield 6 Winter Offensive, players will receive a new time-limited map called Ice Lock Empire State, a winter version of the map with frozen streets and seasonal environmental visuals. Along with the players will get a new themed event game mode, which can be played across Domination, Conquest, and Gauntlet mission variations on Ice Lock Empire State. The event will also come with a time-limited mechanic called freeze. </p>



<p>Moreover, Battlefield 6 Winter Offensive will also add a new melee weapon, the Ice Climbing Axe, which will be available on the latest battle pass. The battle pass for this event is called Winter Offensive Bonus Path, and it features an 11-tier, time-limited reward track featuring event cosmetics, XP Boosters, and the Ice Climbing Axe. Lastly, the new Ice Lock Empire State map will also be supported for Portal Experience during its availability period. </p>



<h2 id="h-complete-battlefield-6-winter-offensive-patch-notes">Complete Battlefield 6 Winter Offensive Patch Notes</h2>



<p>Apart from the new content, Battlefield 6 developers will be implementing a plethora of bug fixes with the Winter Offensive update, and you can check out the patch notes for update 1.1.3.0 below: </p>



<p><strong>PLAYER:</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Fixed a clipping issue when dragging a soldier on an inclined surface when being prone.</li>



<li>Fixed a clipping issue with character shoulders when jumping.</li>



<li>Fixed a rare issue where fall damage wouldn’t be applied immediately after being revived.</li>



<li>Fixed snapping and aggressive camera movements when performing takedowns on prone enemies from specific angles.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue allowing players to use vaulting to avoid being roadkilled by an enemy vehicle coming at high speed.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue causing controller haptic feedback to continue indefinitely when a reload was interrupted by swapping to another weapon or gadget.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue causing hit registration to fail when firing while making extremely rapid aim adjustments. We’re continuing to investigate additional edge cases and reviewing player reports related to hit registration.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue causing soldier legs to rotate incorrectly with the body when falling while prone.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue causing soldier movement to feel slow while walking on uneven terrain.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue causing the character’s hands to appear misaligned when vaulting through windows.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue causing vaulting while charging a defibrillator to make the soldier’s hands disappear.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue that caused getting revived after dying mid-fall to trigger fall damage the next time the player jumped.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue that caused the player to continue controlling their soldier after dying in water.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue that could cause the player to become stuck when entering water while crouching.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue that could prevent melee damage from being dealt to soldiers in water.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue that could prevent melee damage from being dealt to soldiers seated in exposed vehicle seats.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue that made it difficult to traverse some stairs, especially at slow movement speeds.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where climbing down ladders with a grenade equipped caused misaligned animations.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where first-person grenade animations appeared incorrectly when spectating another player.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where getting hit by melee damage prevented the victim from performing melee attacks.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where hands clipped into ladders when in first-person view.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where interrupting a drag and revive would not cancel revive progress as expected.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where jumping in and out of vehicles could lead to later hit-registration for soldiers on foot.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where landing on a vehicle prevented the player from taking any fall damage.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where melee animations would not play correctly when attacking while vaulting over mid-height obstacles.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where melee attacking and returning to an Assault Ladder caused the player to appear to attack with the ladder.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where performing zoomed aiming while colliding with a wall during sprint would offset the player’s aim.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where soldier models glowed incorrectly in front of the thermobaric visual effect when illuminated by a flashlight.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where the death camera could appear beneath the map when dying inside a vehicle.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where the melee weapon briefly appeared in an incorrect pose when holding the M87A1 shotgun.</li>



<li>Fixed first-person stair locomotion animations starting with a delay when moving on stairs.</li>



<li>Fixed third-person mounting clipping issues with the HK433 when using certain bottom-rail attachments.</li>



<li>Improved first- and third-person vault-up and vault-over mid-height animations for smoother transitions.</li>



<li>Improved hit registration reliability when multiple players were within close proximity.</li>



<li>Improved how recoil and aim input interact, resulting in more reliable accuracy when compensating for recoil.</li>



<li>Improved melee animation when attacking while prone.</li>



<li>Improved movement responsiveness at the start and end of drag and revive interactions.</li>



<li>Improved soldier animation smoothness when entering and exiting prone.</li>



<li>Improved visibility of soldiers at close range by applying brightness adjustments at 0 metres with a higher minimum intensity.</li>



<li>Resolved an animation issue where quickly applying armour immediately after using a melee weapon could result in an unintended transitional animation.</li>



<li>Updated third-person prone animations to improve clarity, reduce static poses, and enhance soldier visibility.</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>VEHICLES:</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Fixed an issue where heavy machine-gun fire from some vehicles would not consistently register damage against soldiers.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where some vehicle seats were incorrectly classified, preventing the correct passenger reticule from appearing while spectating another player.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where the soldier compass could appear simultaneously with the vehicle compass when sitting in certain gunner seats.</li>



<li>Fixed issues with damage zones on armoured vehicles that caused them to take higher-than-intended damage in certain situations.</li>



<li>Fixed UI behaviour for the Quadbike’s spawn camera to ensure it displays correctly upon deployment.</li>



<li>Partially fixed an issue where vehicle audio could stop functioning during live gameplay due to suspected memory-related issues.</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>WEAPONS:</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Fixed a bug where players could become stuck in the weapon inspect animation when entering a vehicle.</li>



<li>Fixed a rare visual glitch that could cause scopes to be displayed incorrectly.</li>



<li>Fixed a visual issue where the Adjustable Angled Grip sat slightly higher on the weapon than intended.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue causing the first bullet fired during early zoom transitions on certain weapons and scopes to be more inaccurate than intended.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue that caused quick melee attacks to sometimes not return the player to their previous weapon after striking.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where some scopes unintentionally received thermal or depth-of-field blur.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where target dummies in the firing range remained down after being shot.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where the effects of FMJ ammunition were incorrectly applied to additional ammunition types.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where underslung attachments were not always restored correctly when picking up another soldier’s kit.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue with the flashlight weapon attachment being misaligned when sprinting at high FOV values.</li>



<li>Fixed the “peekaboo” timing bug affecting target dummies on the firing range.</li>



<li>Increased the minimum time between shots by 100 ms on the Mini Scout to improve pacing and reduce rapid-fire inconsistencies.</li>



<li>Reduced recoil magnitude but increased recoil variation on the M250, NVO-228E, RPKM, SG 553R, and SOR-300SC. These weapons now perform less effectively at long range, with the SG 553R receiving the most noticeable adjustment.</li>



<li>Reduced the cost of the L110 and M123K 200-round magazines from 55 to 50, and removed the penalty to ADS movement dispersion.</li>



<li>Tweaked haptic feedback for weapon reloads on PS5 controllers.</li>



<li>Updated melee behaviour to allow players equipped with a melee weapon to choose between a takedown (F/RS) or a bash attack (Mouse 1/RT).</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>GADGETS:</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Fixed an issue where Assault Ladders did not allow smooth traversal by increasing the maximum ramp angle from 45° to 52°. Players can now run up the ladder without shifting into a climbing stance.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where gadgets that should be hidden by occlusion were still visible through geometry.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where lock-on indicators appeared for Engineers without a lock-on capable launcher equipped.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where Supply Crates deployed by enemy players were visible on the mini map.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where Throwing Knife animations lasted longer than intended.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where XFGM-6D Recon Drones spawned facing the wrong direction instead of matching the soldier’s facing direction when being deployed.</li>



<li>Reduced Throwing Knife dispersion so that headshots are reliably achievable up to 15 metres.</li>
</ul>



<p><em>LWCMS Portable Mortar</em></p>



<ul>
<li>Fixed an issue where an incorrect shell type was used during firing and reload animations.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where firing a Smoke Shell did not shake the camera or tube.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where Smoke Shell clouds were smaller than intended.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where the fire rate was lower than intended.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where the Smoke Shell always regenerated via Supply Crates.</li>



<li>Logistics Expert in the Fire Support tree now slightly enhances the Supply Crate’s effect on the Portable Mortar’s fire rate.</li>



<li>Smoke Shell ammunition now starts at 0 and regenerates every 45 seconds.</li>
</ul>



<p><em>Supply Pouch</em></p>



<ul>
<li>Fixed an issue where the Supply Pouch instantly regenerated health on deployment.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue with incorrect ammunition setup that caused inconsistent resupply behaviour.</li>



<li>Removed the initial heal on gadget deployment; the Supply Pouch now only heals over time.</li>



<li>Thrown Supply Pouches now prioritise players who are low on, or have requested, health or ammunition.</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>MAPS &amp; MODES:</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Adjusted Conquest and Escalation capture areas on Manhattan Bridge so objectives can no longer be captured from rooftop positions.</li>



<li>Extended rooftop out-of-bounds areas on Empire State, Manhattan Bridge, and Saints Quarter.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where deaths were not tracked correctly in Strikepoint.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where players were not properly credited for a kill caused by the destruction of the crane on Mirak Valley.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where vehicle selection in Escalation became temporarily unavailable if the player was on the deploy screen when a territory changed hands.</li>



<li>Made improvements to reduce cases of players matching into games that were near the end of a round.</li>



<li>The out-of-bounds timer on Manhattan Bridge is now correctly set to 10 seconds.</li>



<li>Updated M-COM placement on Liberation Peak and Manhattan Bridge to improve attacker flow based on player feedback.</li>



<li>Updated spawning behaviour for Battle Pickups:</li>



<li>In Breakthrough, Battle Pickups now spawn when their associated sectors are enabled.</li>



<li>In Conquest and Escalation, Battle Pickups now spawn when their associated capture points are owned by a team.</li>
</ul>



<p>Following feedback since launch, several Breakthrough layouts have been updated to address attacker–defender win/loss imbalance and improve overall flow, vehicle balance, and capture-zone clarity across multiple maps.</p>



<p><em>Manhattan Bridge</em></p>



<ul>
<li>Removed Defender vehicles in Sector 2 and Sector 3.</li>



<li>Added an additional Attacker IFV in Sector 3.</li>



<li>Updated capture volumes across Sectors 1, 2, and 3 to support more consistent attacker progress.</li>
</ul>



<p><em>Mirak Valley</em></p>



<ul>
<li>Removed Defender vehicles in all sectors.</li>



<li>Adjusted Attacker vehicle counts:</li>



<li>Sector 1: Reduced Attacker IFVs from 2 to 1; increased Attacker tanks from 1 to 2.</li>



<li>Sector 2: Added 1 Attacker IFV.</li>



<li>Sector 3: Added 1 Attacker IFV.</li>



<li>Updated capture volumes across all sectors to make attacking easier.</li>
</ul>



<p><em>New Sobek City</em></p>



<ul>
<li>Sector 2: Added 1 Defender tank and one Defender IFV.</li>



<li>Sector 3: Added 1 Attacker IFV; removed Defender tank and light transport.</li>



<li>Updated capture volumes in both sectors to improve attacker flow.</li>
</ul>



<p><em>Operation Firestorm</em></p>



<ul>
<li>Sector 2: Adjusted Defender armour (added and removed tank spawns).</li>



<li>Sector 3: Added 2 Attacker tanks and 1 Attacker IFV; removed the Defender tank.</li>



<li>Updated capture zones across affected sectors to support attacker momentum.</li>
</ul>



<p><em>Liberation Peak</em></p>



<ul>
<li>Sector 3: Removed Defender tank.</li>



<li>Sector 5: Added 2 Attacker IFVs; removed the Defender transport.</li>



<li>Updated capture volumes to improve attacker advancement.</li>
</ul>



<p><em>Siege of Cairo</em></p>



<ul>
<li>Added an additional Attacker tank in sector 1 and 3.</li>



<li>Updated capture areas on B flag to improve sector push potential.</li>
</ul>



<p><em>Empire State</em></p>



<ul>
<li>Sector 1: Updated capture volume on B flag.</li>



<li>Sector 2: Updated capture volumes on A and B flags.</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>PROGRESSION:</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Fixed an issue where enemies spotted by the LTLM II Portable Laser Designator did not count towards the “Spot enemies with Recon Gadgets” weekly challenge.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where the Incendiary Airburst Launcher did not track progress for the “Support Specialist 2” challenge when dealing damage with its lingering fire cloud.</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>UI &amp; HUD:</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Added a loading popup when entering a tournament code to provide better feedback on what’s happening.</li>



<li>Added “Free Look” helicopter game hint to be part of pilot hints..</li>



<li>Enemies can no longer be spotted from the big map.</li>



<li>Ensured players who trigger crane destruction now have their killer ID correctly logged in the scoreboard’s score log.</li>



<li>Ensured the “Cut Parachute” prompt appears correctly in Multiplayer modes outside of REDSEC.</li>



<li>Fixed a mini map issue where empty vehicle icons did not transition correctly into a friendly vehicle icon when entering a vehicle.</li>



<li>Fixed a rare issue where objective icons could disappear when redeploying.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where a teammate’s armour briefly appeared as soft-armour colour when their armour broke, causing a momentary incorrect visual.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where camos in the Challenges section did not show their name or category.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where hints for “Re-Enter” and “Deploy” were displayed in the wrong order when using a controller with the EOD Bot.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where killcards did not always appear when players were killed inside vehicles.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where loading screen combat zone descriptions did not update correctly based on the active game mode.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where loading screen combat zone descriptions were incorrect for Sabotage on Eastwood.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where loading screen combat zone text displayed incorrectly on Sabotage across all maps.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where Store offers did not scroll correctly when fast-scrolling along the same row.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where the deploy camera could appear incorrectly rotated when spectating a soldier or vehicle.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where the different painted states of the LTLM II Portable Laser Designator weren’t correctly represented by the gadgets HUD warning label.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where the Helicopter HUD would disappear when the color was set to black in the settings.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where the LMR27 and ES 5.7 attachment lists were not sorted correctly.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where the LWCMS Portable Mortar icon had visual inconsistencies between the big map and the minimap.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where the Traverse Mark 2 displayed duplicate LMG text in the second seat, despite having only one mounted weapon.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where the vehicle 3D preview did not update when switching loadout presets.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where zooming in on the big map would sometimes result in a black screen.</li>



<li>Fixed issues that prevented Resupply Station icons from appearing on the big map as intended.</li>



<li>Improved Commorose behaviour by correcting the request distances for “Need Repair” and “Need Pick Up”.</li>



<li>Improved image cropping to better align artwork in the Battle Pass purchase screens.</li>



<li>Improved ping behaviour on friendly soldiers, revive requests, and stationary weapons.</li>



<li>Improved the text used to describe unlock conditions for Bonus Mission for better clarity.</li>



<li>Reduced man down icons to only show the two closest downed team mates.</li>



<li>Removed the ability to cycle between classes on the deploy screen using Q and E to prevent unintended class changes before spawning.</li>



<li>Snap Zoom (Aim Assist) has been clarified in the menu: this option is only available in Single Player and Portal modes, not in Multiplayer.</li>



<li>Squad and friendly in-world nametags now blink when the player regains health or receives ammunition.</li>



<li>Stationary weapons no longer show pickup provider icons when a player is requesting to be picked up.</li>



<li>Unlocked cosmetics now appear above locked ones in selection lists.</li>



<li>Updated back-navigation logic so consoles can no longer back out far enough to trigger the quit-game popup unintentionally.</li>



<li>Updated the countermeasure hint to only display when a weapon lock-on state makes the prompt relevant.</li>



<li>Updated the lock-on warning behaviour so that lock-on alerts can take priority over painted labels when appropriate, ensuring threats are more noticeable.</li>



<li>Updated the Saints Quarter loading screen to display correct combat zone text.</li>



<li>Updated underbarrel launchers so the correct type icons appear in the HUD.</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>SETTINGS:</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Fixed a bug where changing the “Command Console” option would not apply until the game was restarted.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where navigating back from the Options menu could behave incorrectly when accessed through Pause Menu.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where the “Edit Controller Schemes” menu title could disappear in Options.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where vehicle aim sensitivity displayed an incorrect value in the vehicle control settings.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue with options sliders “stepping” functionality being broken and not allowing players to step through decimals.</li>



<li>Improved the “Dynamic” response curve option for controller stick aiming to better match player expectations and player feedback.</li>



<li>The range for Infantry and Vehicle mouse sensitivity options are now doubled and can go twice as high.</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>SINGLE PLAYER:</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Fixed an issue where the out-of-bounds timer did not correctly account for player death or Mandown state in Single Player.</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>AUDIO:</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Added new vehicle-specific hostile type identifiers for more accurate callouts.</li>



<li>Added safeguards so background environmental soldier audio no longer triggers during moments with no combat.</li>



<li>Adjusted the balance of the bootflow logo music and sound effects.</li>



<li>Fixed an audio issue that occurred when crawling while aiming down sights.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue that caused health-replenishing audio to play multiple times.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where background environmental soldier audio wasn’t affected by the voice over volume slider.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where end-of-round music would sometimes not play, or play the incorrect track.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where players could experience a stuck “Low Health” audio cue after remaining at low health for 30 seconds in modes without health regeneration.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where round-start music could play before the round actually began.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where Supply Crate sound effects could repeatedly trigger on downed soldiers.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where the “Advance to Next Sector” audio cue played “Out-of-Bounds” sound effect.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where the incorrect nearby-friendly voice over line would play when a mortar shell landed beside the player.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where the proper sound effect did not play when performing a combat dive.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where the Rorsch Mk-2 SMRW Rail Gun’s charge loop sound effects did not play correctly.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where vehicle prop-fuse fire effects were missing their intended audio.</li>



<li>Fixed missing audio when performing weapon inspections.</li>



<li>Optimised memory handling and improved prioritisation for most in-game sounds, reducing cases where important audio, such as vehicles or footsteps, sometimes failed to play.</li>



<li>Partially fixed an issue where vehicle audio could stop functioning during live gameplay due to suspected memory-related issues.</li>
</ul>



<p><em>Footsteps</em></p>



<ul>
<li>Balanced enemy-specific layers for clearer cloth and gear cues.</li>



<li>Further reduced or removed the momentary dampening of enemy movement audio triggered by damage, low-health states, game notifications, or occlusion effects.</li>



<li>Improved distance-based acoustics for clearer separation between close, mid, and far ranges.</li>



<li>Improved distant world reflections to better convey space and positioning.</li>



<li>Increased enemy movement audio at distance for greater readability.</li>



<li>Increased overall enemy movement volume, with an additional boost when an enemy is behind the player.</li>



<li>Reduced how heavily sneaking stances (crouch walking, crawling) lower enemy movement audio.</li>



<li>Reduced how much the “Spec-Op” trait lowers footstep audio when sneaking.</li>



<li>Reduced scuff and scrape audio from movement against walls and ground.</li>



<li>Reduced self and friendly footstep volume in Wartapes, Wartapes VAL, and REDSEC.</li>



<li>Refactored footstep triggers to be more reliable across different speeds and stances.</li>



<li>Removed limitations on the maximum number of close-range enemy audio sources.</li>



<li>Small balancing tweaks to footsteps on different materials for outliers, such as slow speed on gravel and different directions (up, down, sideways) on wooden stairs.</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>PORTAL:</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Fixed an issue where AI squadmates in Portal did not display class identifiers on the insertion screen.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where mod.PlaySound() and mod.PlayVO() accepted any object type as input. These functions now correctly require sound effects and voice over object types respectively. While existing syntax remains unchanged, any TypeScript code that explicitly references generic object types will now need to specify mod.SFX or mod.VO as appropriate.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where mod.PlayVO() always played the voiceover for the Alpha flag, regardless of the flag specified by the script.</li>



<li>SDK Assets for MainStreet, ClubHouse, and Marina have been corrected to only use relevant assets.</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>AI:</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>AI bots can now respond to ammo, healing, and pickup requests.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue that caused AI repairing friendly vehicles to be less responsive than intended.</li>



<li>Fixed cases where AI attempted to take cover in ways that left them static or unresponsive. Bots will now correctly move toward locked objectives in King of the Hill.</li>



<li>Fixed instances where AI soldiers could take too long to find a valid path to their objective, causing them to remain stationary.</li>



<li>Improved AI responsiveness when performing revives.</li>



<li>Improved AI revive logic and movement to make their actions more consistent and reliable.</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>REDSEC</strong> <strong>PLAYER:</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Fixed a rare issue where a Second Chance respawn could place players over 1,000 metres in the air.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where incorrect mouse sensitivity was applied to the MH-47’s third-person camera during insertion.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where players could be kicked for inactivity while spectating.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where players could not claim a second custom weapon dropped as a mission reward.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where takedown prompts did not appear consistently when approaching enemies from behind.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where the wrong animation would play when switching from a call-in grenade to a different weapon.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where weapon swap animations broke after switching away from the Resupply Drop Call-In.</li>



<li>Triggering a redeploy tower or beacon now disables or destroys any other active tower or beacon for the same team.</li>
</ul>



<p>Gauntlet</p>



<ul>
<li>Fixed an issue where mission objects would not drop if the carrier disconnected.</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>VEHICLES:</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Fixed an issue where tanks and ambulances would be clipping through each other.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where vehicle containers could occasionally be empty after being opened.</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>WEAPONS:</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Adjusted damage for the Rorsch Mk-2 SMRW Rail Gun against fully armoured soldiers. Headshots now kill the opponent on one shot while a bodyshot will leave the opponent with 10 HP.</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>GADGETS:</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Fixed an issue with incorrect textures on the projectile deployed by the XFGM-6D Recon Drone</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where the XFGM-6D Recon Drone’s altitude unintentionally decreased as the match went on.</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>CALL-INS:</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Fixed an issue where Smoke Cover could not be activated during the late stages of a match.</li>



<li>The UAV now fully explodes on impact when shot down.</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>MAP:</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Fixed an issue where a Razer keyboard lightning event did not trigger when interacting with antennas on the “Signal Hack” mission.</li>
</ul>



<p><em>Battle Royale</em></p>



<ul>
<li>Improved loot box placement across the map for more reliable accessibility.</li>
</ul>



<p><em>Gauntlet</em></p>



<ul>
<li>Fixed an issue where M-COMs in Wreckage would not reactivate after being destroyed.</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>UI &amp; HUD:</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Fixed an issue where the armour bar of your team mates were showing even though they were at full capacity.</li>
</ul>



<p><em>Battle Royale</em></p>



<ul>
<li>Added clearer distinction between player and squad member inventory requests.</li>



<li>Added upgrade notifications to the loot feed when a weapon is improved.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where ping icons of lootable vehicles would disappear from the mini map when the players get more than 25m away from them.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where the Tank Hunter mission UI could remain active if the targeted squad destroyed its own tank.</li>



<li>Updated the artwork for mission rewards to reflect new keycard changes.</li>
</ul>



<p><em>Gauntlet</em></p>



<ul>
<li>Added correct interaction prompts for counter-mission teams when defusing explosives in Wreckage.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where the scoreboard was sorted by deaths instead of score.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where the Loadout screen overlay could incorrectly appear over the Gauntlet Mission Briefing on Aftermath.</li>



<li>Fixed team-ownership colours for M-COMs in Wreckage missions.</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>AUDIO:</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Fixed an issue where subtitles would not appear correctly during insertion.</li>



<li>Fixed missing UI audio when unlocking the first Field Upgrade.</li>



<li>Increased the volume of armour-break audio for both incoming and outgoing hits.</li>
</ul>







<p>The patch notes for Battlefield 6 Winter Offensive update 1.1.3.0 were found through a post by the official BattlefieldComms <a href="https://x.com/BattlefieldComm/status/1996972887769485561" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">X</a> account (formerly Twitter). </p>



<p>In other news, Battlefield 6’s anti-cheat has <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-anti-cheat-million-attempts/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">blocked 2.4 million cheat attempts</a>. What are your thoughts on all the new content and bug fixes coming with Battlefield 6’s Winter Offensive update? Leave your thoughts down in the comments, and join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/gta-5-michael-coming-back-aged/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">GTA 5’s Michael coming back to the game after 12 years</a>.&nbsp;Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-winter-offensive-update-will-add-a-limited-time-map-and-game-mode/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>