<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 18:49:40 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A Whole Bunch Of Awesome Shooters Are Cheap Right Now On Steam]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/boomer-shooter-dusk-mycopunk-demos-sale-event-boomstock-2025-pc-2000627990</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/a-whole-bunch-of-awesome-shooters-are-cheap-right-now-on-steam.1305789/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Boom! Bang! Kablam! Etc. and so on. There will be a lot of that happening today as a big new event on Steam has a whole host of fantastic retro-inspired first-person shooters on sale for the rest of the week.</p> <p><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/sale/boomstock2025">On September 23, Boomstock 2025 started on Steam</a>. The event celebrates “all boomer shooters and retro-inspired” FPS games and features a ton of new trailers, demos, and of course, a load of games on sale. This includes some genuine bangers, like<em> Dusk</em>, <em><a href="https://kotaku.com/mullet-madjack-anime-fps-roguelike-hades-review-steam-1851475865">Mullet Madjack</a></em>,<em> Project Warlock</em>, <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1592280/Selaco/"><em>Selaco</em></a>, and<em> Sulfur</em>.&nbsp; But don’t wait too long, as the event wraps up on September 27, which is just a few days away. If you need help picking out a new shooter to buy, here are some of the best and biggest deals we spotted from the event:</p> <ul> <li><em>Nightmare Reaper</em> – $15 ($25)</li> <li><em>Brutal John 2</em> – $9 ($13)</li> <li><em>Selaco</em> – $19 ($25)</li> <li><em>Forgive Me Father</em> – $10 ($20)</li> <li><em>Forgive Me Father 2</em> – $15 ($25)</li> <li><em>Wizordum</em> – $15 ($20)</li> <li><em>Dusk</em> – $7 ($20)</li> <li><em>Sulfur</em> – $16 ($22)</li> <li><em>Zero Protocol</em> – $7 ($12)</li> <li><em>Project Warlock 1+2</em> – $12 ($27)</li> <li><em>Mullet Madjack</em> – $15 ($20)</li> <li><em>Warhammer 40K Boltgun</em> – $11 ($22)</li> <li><em>Blood We</em>st – $9 ($25)</li> <li><em>Heavy Bullets</em> – $2 ($10)</li> <li><em>Viscerafest</em> – $10 ($20)</li> <li><em>Supplice</em> – $15 ($22)</li> <li><em>Wild Bastards</em> – $9 ($35)</li> <li><em>Shadow Warrior</em> (2013) – $3 ($30)</li> <li><em>Shadow Warrior 2</em> – $3 ($30)</li> <li><em>HROT</em> – $10 ($20)</li> <li><em>Gravelord</em> – $15 ($20)</li> <li><em>Quatermain and the Cult of Cthulu</em> – $2.50 ($3)</li> <li><em>Hard Reset</em> – $1.50 ($15)</li> <li><em>Hard Reset Redux</em> – $2 ($20)</li> <li><em>Serious Sam 2</em> – $2.50</li> <li><em>Mycopunk</em> – $11 ($14)</li> <li><em>Graven</em> – $5 ($23)</li> </ul> <p>I’d also like to shout out some demos for upcoming games that you can play for free right now. You totally should check out these games if you love classic shooters. Or <em>Tetris</em>. You’ll see what I mean. Anyway, here are some Boomstock demos worth playing:</p> <ul> <li><em>Sportal</em> – A boomer shooter all about using sports equipment like bats and tennis rackets.</li> <li><em>Blocks for Babies –</em> <em>Tetris</em> meets <em>Doom</em>. It mixes 2D and 3D gameplay. It’s an odd one, but worth checking out.</li> <li><em>Slyders</em> – This one is part<em> Serious Sam</em> and part roguelike, which is already a great pitch, but then you add in a cool cartoon fox protagonist, and you’ve got something special.</li> <li><em>The Last Exterminator</em> – This is the <em>Duke Nukem 3D</em> sequel we deserved. This isn’t a new demo; <a href="https://kotaku.com/duke-nukem-3d-last-exterminator-demo-boomer-shooter-pc-1850918547">I covered it last year</a>, but it’s a part of the event and still worth checking out.</li> </ul>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/boomer-shooter-dusk-mycopunk-demos-sale-event-boomstock-2025-pc-2000627990]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Baby Steps is the most gloriously frustrating game I’ve ever struggled through]]></title>
            <link>https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/09/baby-steps-is-the-most-gloriously-frustrating-game-ive-ever-struggled-through/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/baby-steps-is-the-most-gloriously-frustrating-game-i%E2%80%99ve-ever-struggled-through.1305786/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="main">
            <article data-id="2118489">
  
  <header>
  <div>
    <div>
      <p><span>
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 40 40"><defs><clipPath id="section-gaming_svg__a"><path fill="none" d="M0 0h40v40H0z"></path></clipPath><clipPath id="section-gaming_svg__b"><path fill="none" d="M0 0h40v40H0z"></path></clipPath></defs><g clip-path="url(#section-gaming_svg__a)"><g fill="none" clip-path="url(#section-gaming_svg__b)"><path fill="currentColor" d="M30.7 39.7c-.7-1.1-1.7-1.8-2.5-2.8-.9-1.2 0-2 .8-3 .6-.9 1-1.9.8-3-.6-2.7-3.4-3.3-5.8-3.6-.7-.1-1.8-.2-2.3-.7s-.5-1.4-.5-2.1v-.4l15.5-3.6c2.3-.5 3.7-2.8 3.2-5.1l-2.8-12C36.6 1.1 34.3-.3 32 .2L3.3 6.8C1 7.4-.4 9.7.1 12l2.8 12c.5 2.3 2.8 3.7 5.1 3.2l11.1-2.6c0 1 .2 2.1.7 2.9 1.7 2.7 6 .8 7.6 3.3.8 1.2-.5 2.3-1.1 3.3-.6.9-.9 2-.4 3 .4 1.1 1.4 1.8 2.2 2.6 0 .1.2.2.3.3h2.4c0-.1-.1-.2-.2-.3m.7-28.7c1.3-.3 2.7.5 3 1.9.3 1.3-.5 2.7-1.9 3-1.3.3-2.7-.5-3-1.9-.3-1.3.5-2.7 1.9-3m-6-3.7c1.3-.3 2.7.5 3 1.9.3 1.3-.5 2.7-1.9 3-1.3.3-2.7-.5-3-1.9-.3-1.3.5-2.7 1.9-3m-9.9 13.2-2.7.6-1-4.1-4.1 1-.6-2.7 4.1-1-1-4.1 2.7-.6 1 4.1 4.1-1 .6 2.7-4.1 1z"></path></g></g></svg>
  </span>
  <span>
    A real "walking simulator"
  </span>
</p>
    </div>

    

    <p>
      <em>QWOP</em> meets <em>Death Stranding</em> meets <em>Getting Over It</em> to form wonderfully surreal, unique game.
    </p>

    

    <div id="caption-2118498">
    
    <p>
      Watch out for that first step, it's a doozy!

              <span>
          Credit:

          
          Devolver Digital

                  </span>
          </p>
  </div>

    <div>
    
    <p>
      Watch out for that first step, it's a doozy!

              <span>
          Credit:

          
          Devolver Digital

                  </span>
          </p>
  </div>
  </div>
</header>


  

  
      
    
    <div>
                      
                      
          


<p>There's an old saying that life is not about how many times you fall down but how many times you get back up. In my roughly 13 hours of walking through the surreal mountain wilderness of <em>Baby Steps</em>, I'd conservatively estimate I easily fell down 1,000 times.</p>
<p>If so, I got up 1,001 times, which is the entire point.</p>
<p>When I say "fell down" here, I'm not being metaphorical. In <em>Baby Steps</em>, the only real antagonist is terrain that threatens to send your pudgy, middle-aged, long-underwear-clad avatar tumbling to the ground (or down a cliff) like a rag doll after the slightest misstep. You pilot this avatar using an intentionally touchy and cumbersome control system where each individual leg is tied a shoulder trigger on your controller.</p>
<p>Unlike the majority of 3D games, where you simply tilt the control stick and watch your character dutifully run, each step here means manually lifting one foot, leaning carefully in the direction you want to go, and then putting that foot down in a spot that maintains your overall balance. It's like a slightly more forgiving version of <a href="https://www.foddy.net/Athletics.html">the popular '00s Flash game <em>QWOP</em></a> (which was also made by <em>Baby Steps</em> co-developer Bennett Foddy), except instead of sprinting on a 2D track, you take your time carefully planning each footfall on a methodical 3D hike.</p>
<figure>
    <div id="caption-2118495"><p>
              Keep wiggling that foot until you find a safe place to put it.
                              </p><p>
                  Credit:
                                      Devolver Digital
                                  </p>
                          </div>
          <figcaption>
        <div>
    
    <p>
      Keep wiggling that foot until you find a safe place to put it.

              <span>
          Credit:

          
          Devolver Digital

                  </span>
          </p>
  </div>
      </figcaption>
      </figure>

<p>At first, you'll stumble like a drunken toddler, mashing the shoulder buttons and tilting the control stick wildly just to inch forward. After a bit of trial and error, though, you'll work yourself into a gentle rhythm—press the trigger, tilt the controller, let go while recentering the controller, press the other trigger, repeat thousands of times. You never quite break into a run, but you can fall into a zen pattern of marching methodically forward, like a <em>Death Stranding</em> courier who has to actually focus on each and every step.</p>

          
                      
                  </div>
                    
        
          
    
    <div>
          
          
<p>As you make your halting progress up the mountain, you'll infrequently stumble on other hikers who seem to lord their comfort and facility with the terrain over you in manic, surreal, and often hilarious cut scenes. I don't want to even lightly spoil any of the truly gonzo moments in this extremely self-aware meta-narrative, but I will say that I found your character's grand arc through the game to be surprisingly touching, often in some extremely subtle ways.</p>
<h2>Does this game hate me?</h2>
<p>Just as you feel like you're finally getting the hang of basic hiking, <em>Baby Steps</em> starts ramping up the terrain difficulty in a way that can feel downright trolly at time. Gentle paths of packed dirt and rock start to be replaced with narrow planks and rickety wooden bridges spanning terrifying gaps. Gentle undulating hills are replaced with sheer cliff faces that you sidle up and across with the tiniest of toe holds to precariously balance on. Firm surfaces are slowly replaced with slippery mud, sand, snow, and ice that force you to alter your rhythm and tread extremely lightly just to make incremental progress.</p>
<figure>
    <div>
            <p>
              Grabbing that fetching hat means risking an <em>extremely</em> punishing fall.
                          </p>
          </div>
          <figcaption>
        <div>
    
    <p>
      Grabbing that fetching hat means risking an <em>extremely</em> punishing fall.

          </p>
  </div>
      </figcaption>
      </figure>

<p>And any hard-earned progress can feel incredibly fragile in <em>Baby Steps</em>. Literally one false step can send you sliding down a hill or tumbling down a cliff face in a way that sets you back anywhere from mere minutes to sizable chunks of an hour. There's no "reset from checkpoint" menu option or <a href="https://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/SaveScumming">save scumming</a> that can limit the damage, either. When you fall in <em>Baby Steps</em>, it can be a very long way down.</p>
<p>This extremely punishing structure won't be a surprise to anyone who has played <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/240720/Getting_Over_It_with_Bennett_Foddy/"><em>Getting Over It With Bennett Foddy</em></a>, where a single mistake can send you all the way back to the beginning of the game. <em>Baby Steps</em> doesn't go quite that hard, giving players occasional major checkpoints and large, flat plains that prevent you from falling back too far. Still, this is a game that is more than happy to force you to pay for even small mistakes with huge portions of your only truly irreplaceable resource: time.</p>

          
                  </div>
                    
        
          
    
    <div>
          
          
<p>On more than one occasion during my playthrough, I audibly cursed at my monitor and quit the game in a huff rather than facing the prospect of spending 10 minutes retracing my steps after a particularly damaging fall. Invariably, though, I'd come back a bit later, more determined than ever to learn from my mistakes, which I usually did quickly with the benefits of time and calm nerves on my side.</p>

<figure>
    <div id="caption-2118494"><p>
              It's frequently not entirely clear where you're supposed to go in <em>Baby Steps</em>.
                              </p><p>
                  Credit:
                                      Devolver Digital
                                  </p>
                          </div>
          <figcaption>
        <div>
    
    <p>
      It's frequently not entirely clear where you're supposed to go in <em>Baby Steps</em>.

              <span>
          Credit:

          
          Devolver Digital

                  </span>
          </p>
  </div>
      </figcaption>
      </figure>

<p><em>Baby Steps</em> is also a game that's happy to let you wander aimlessly. There's no in-game map to consult, and any paths and landmarks that could point you in the "intended" way up the mountain are often intentionally confusing or obscured. It can be extremely unclear which parts of the terrain are meant to be impossibly steep and which are merely designed as difficult but plausible shortcuts that simply require pinpoint timing and foot placement. But the terrain is also designed so that almost every near-impossible barrier can be avoided altogether if you're patient and observant enough to find a way around it.</p>
<p>And if you wander even slightly off the lightly beaten path, you'll stumble on many intricately designed and completely optional points of interest, from imposing architectural towers to foreboding natural outcroppings to a miniature city made of boxes. There's no explicit in-game reward for almost all of these random digressions, and your fellow cut-scene hikers will frequently explicitly warn you that there's no point in climbing some structure or another. Your only reward is the (often marvelous) view from the top—and the satisfaction of saying that you conquered something you didn't need to.</p>
<h2>Are we having fun yet?</h2>
<p>So was playing <em>Baby Steps</em> any fun? Honestly, that's not the first word I'd use to describe the experience.</p>

          
                  </div>
                    
        
          
    
    <div>

        
        <div>
          
          
<p>To be sure, there's a lot of humor built into the intentionally punishing designs of some sections, so much so that I often had to laugh even as I fell down yet another slippery hill that erased a huge chunk of my progress. And the promise of more wild cut scenes serves as a pretty fun and compelling carrot to get you through some of the game's toughest sections.</p>
<figure>
    <div id="caption-2118503"><p>
              I've earned this moment of zen.
                              </p><p>
                  Credit:
                                      Devolver Digital
                                  </p>
                          </div>
          <figcaption>
        <div>
    
    <p>
      I've earned this moment of zen.

              <span>
          Credit:

          
          Devolver Digital

                  </span>
          </p>
  </div>
      </figcaption>
      </figure>

<p>More than "fun," though, I'd say my time with the <em>Baby Steps</em> felt meaningful in a way few games do. Amid all the trolly humor and intentionally obtuse design decisions is a game whose very structure forces you to consider the value of perseverance and commitment.</p>
<p>This is a game that stands proudly against a lot of modern game design trends. It won't loudly and explicitly point you to the next checkpoint with a huge on-screen arrow. You can't inexorably grind out stat points in <em>Baby Steps</em> until your character is powerful enough to beat the toughest boss easily. You can't restart a <em>Baby Steps</em> run and hope for a lucky randomized seed that will get you past a difficult in-game wall.</p>
<p><em>Baby Steps</em> doesn't hand you anything. Your abilities and inventory are the same at the game's start as they are at the end. Any progress you make is defined solely by your mastery of the obtuse movement system and your slowly increasing knowledge of how to safely traverse ever more treacherous terrain.</p>
<figure><p><iframe allow="fullscreen" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/XBaOE-FpIBw?start=0&amp;wmode=transparent"></iframe></p></figure>
<p>It's a structure that can feel punishing, unforgiving, tedious, and enraging in turns. But it's also a structure that leads to moments of the most genuinely satisfying sense of achievement I can remember having in modern gaming.</p>
<p>It's about a miles-long journey starting with a single, halting step. It's about putting one foot in front of the other until you can't anymore. It's about climbing the mountain because it's there. It's about falling down 1,000 times and getting up 1,001 times.</p>
<p>What else is there in the end?</p>


          
                  </div>

                  
          






  <div>
    

    <p>
      Kyle Orland has been the Senior Gaming Editor at Ars Technica since 2012, writing primarily about the business, tech, and culture behind video games. He has journalism and computer science degrees from University of Maryland. He once <a href="https://bossfightbooks.com/collections/books/products/minesweeper-by-kyle-orland">wrote a whole book about <em>Minesweeper</em></a>.
    </p>
  </div>


  <p>
    <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/09/baby-steps-is-the-most-gloriously-frustrating-game-ive-ever-struggled-through/#comments" title="14 comments">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 80 80"><defs><clipPath id="bubble-zero_svg__a"><path fill="none" stroke-width="0" d="M0 0h80v80H0z"></path></clipPath><clipPath id="bubble-zero_svg__b"><path fill="none" stroke-width="0" d="M0 0h80v80H0z"></path></clipPath></defs><g clip-path="url(#bubble-zero_svg__a)"><g fill="currentColor" clip-path="url(#bubble-zero_svg__b)"><path d="M80 40c0 22.09-17.91 40-40 40S0 62.09 0 40 17.91 0 40 0s40 17.91 40 40"></path><path d="M40 40 .59 76.58C-.67 77.84.22 80 2.01 80H40z"></path></g></g></svg>
    14 Comments
  </a>
      </p>
              </div>
  </article>


  


  


  
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/09/baby-steps-is-the-most-gloriously-frustrating-game-ive-ever-struggled-through/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Former Pokemon Legal Chief "Wouldn't Touch" Homeland Security Video That Used Ash Ketchum]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/former-pokemon-legal-chief-wouldnt-touch-homeland-security-video-that-used-ash-ketchum/1100-6534960/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/former-pokemon-legal-chief-wouldnt-touch-homeland-security-video-that-used-ash-ketchum.1305783/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6534960">

            
            
  

<section><p>By  on <time datetime="2025-09-23T11:10:45-0800">September 23, 2025 at 11:10AM PDT</time></p></section>
        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>In response to the Department of Homeland Security's video using Ash Ketchum to promote ICE, The Pokemon Company's ex-legal chief said he "wouldn't touch" it, suggesting some possible reasons why the company might not pursue legal action.</p><p>This week, Homeland Security <a href="https://x.com/DHSgov/status/1970251208322621530" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">posted a video to X</a> of an arrest compilation. In between footage of ICE agents handcuffing people at their homes and in their cars are clips from the OG Pokemon TV series, with the famed "Gotta catch 'em all" theme playing in the background. When Ash Ketchum looks up at the sky, the text "The Department of Homeland Security" populates the screen in Pokemon's iconic yellow-and-blue font. As a Poke Ball closes, the camera zooms in on wrists in cuffs. And at the very end of the video, those arrested appear as Pokemon cards with their "crime" described under their picture.</p><p>Fans were understandably upset about this, with many in the comments begging for The Pokemon Company to sue the DHS. However, the company's former legal chief, Don McGowan, <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/fans-want-pokmon-to-sue-after-department-of-homeland-security-video-uses-ash-ketchum-to-promote-ice-but-the-companys-former-legal-boss-says-he-wouldnt-touch-this" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">explained to IGN</a> why The Pokemon Company likely won't do anything about the video.</p><p>"I don't see them doing anything about this for a few reasons," McGowan started. "First, think of how little you see [The Pokémon Company International]'s name in the press. They are insanely publicity-shy and prefer to let the brand be the brand. Second, many of their execs in the USA are on green cards. Even if I was still at the company I wouldn't touch this, and I'm the most trigger-happy CLO [Chief Legal Officer] I've ever met. This will blow over in a couple of days and they'll be happy to let it."</p><p>It's unclear what The Pokemon Company proper will do or say in response to the DHS's co-opting of Pokemon and Ash Ketchum. The video is still up and has been reposted by the government body's official account, so it appears as though DHS is happy to continue using Ash and the "Gotta catch 'em all" theme as ICE promotional material.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/former-pokemon-legal-chief-wouldnt-touch-homeland-security-video-that-used-ash-ketchum/1100-6534960/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NetEase Debuts Marvel Rivals New K’un-Lun: Heart of Heaven Map Arriving This Week]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/marvel-rivals-new-kun-lun-heart-of-heaven-map/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/netease-debuts-marvel-rivals-new-k%E2%80%99un-lun-heart-of-heaven-map-arriving-this-week.1305777/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>NetEase has revealed the new convergence mode K'un-Lun: Heart of Heaven map that will be arriving in Marvel Rivals later this week, on September 25, 2025. The Summer Special Vol.2 is also now live in the game, and players can start to earn free cosmetics from the limited event until it closes on October 17, 2025. </p>



<p>This is the latest update since Marvel Rivals' <a href="https://wccftech.com/marvel-rivals-ps4-release-date-season-4/">Season 4 debuted earlier this month on September 12</a>, which also brought a new hero, Angela, to the game. Though perhaps more important was the fact that Season 4 marked the addition of a new playable platform for Marvel Rivals, with the game making its way to PlayStation 4.</p>



<p>The map reveal trailer shows off the vistas and intricately decorated hallways that will provide the backdrop for players' clashes, though as with any shooter, you won't get to really be familiar with the map until you've had the chance to play it yourself. At least the trailer allows you to take in the work NetEase put into the visual design of the map, since you'll likely be too focused on the match to notice when in-game.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="K'un-Lun: Heart of Heaven | Map Reveal | Marvel Rivals" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/WkTmJp0dcUA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>New character cosmetics for Hela will also arrive alongside the map on Thursday, which you can see in the clip NetEase shared to X (formerly Twitter) below.</p>



<figure><div>
<blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>The Goddess of Death shows no mercy.</p><p>"Extra! Extra! Get your Timely Bulletin! Fear stalks Timely, folks! Our new Sheriff, Red Wolf, has vanished—gone like a ghost in the dust! And who rode the Skeletal Horse into the Valley of Doom right after? A Grim Lady from Europe, dressed… <a href="https://t.co/ev7YKbm2jz">pic.twitter.com/ev7YKbm2jz</a></p></div>— Marvel Rivals (@MarvelRivals) <a href="https://twitter.com/MarvelRivals/status/1970533620856045829?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 23, 2025</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>



<p>Shortly after Marvel Rivals came to PS4, NetEase introduced the game's technical director, Fanfan, to players in a new video series called 'Technically Speaking.' In its inaugural video, Fanfan addressed concerns that have surfaced from players around the game's performance and offered some explanation as to what the studio is doing to try to fix the issues.</p>



<p>He also pointed to a standard test that PC players can run on their devices, to help determine where their graphical settings should be to ensure they get the smoothest, most stable experience possible during gameplay. Switching around your settings won't solve every issues players have, but it's the best place to start trying.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Marvel Rivals Technically Speaking Vol. 01 | Marvel Rivals" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/kUUK-yXjVYk?start=202&amp;feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/marvel-rivals-new-kun-lun-heart-of-heaven-map/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WoW Legion Remix Brings Back Almost Every Artifact Skin, Except The One You're Missing]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/wow-legion-remix-brings-back-almost-every-artifact-skin-except-the-one-youre-missing/1100-6534959/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/wow-legion-remix-brings-back-almost-every-artifact-skin-except-the-one-youre-missing.1305753/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6534959">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/world-of-warcraft/" data-ref-id="5000-3919">World of Warcraft's</a> upcoming <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/how-wow-legion-remix-event-is-taking-inspiration-from-diablo/1100-6533961/" data-ref-id="1100-6533961">Legion Remix event</a> will include plenty of new and returning transmog options for players to collect, but one highly coveted set of Artifact appearances from the original Legion expansion won't be among them.</p><p dir="ltr">Legion, originally released in 2016, is one of WoW's most popular expansions. That popularity is, in part, due to its Artifact-weapon system. Every player was granted an iconic weapon from Warcraft lore to upgrade over the course of the expansion. Because WoW's real endgame is transmog, each Artifact weapon also sported a variety of different skins and color variations for players to pursue and collect.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4573453-wowlegionremixschedule.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4573453" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4573453-wowlegionremixschedule.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4573453"></a><figcaption>WoW Legion Remix's content schedule.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4573453-wowlegionremixschedule.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">Now, as part of Legion Remix, players are getting a second chance at the expansion. In a <a href="https://eu.forums.blizzard.com/en/wow/t/not-adding-non-mage-tower-artifact-appearances-to-remix/589492/2" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">forum post</a> from WoW community manager Kaivax, Blizzard clarified that nearly all of Legion's original Artifact-weapon appearances (minus ones available only through PvP, since Legion Remix is a PvE-only event) will be available during the event. Many of these Artifact appearances are technically still earnable in the modern version of the game, though Legion Remix's increased leveling speeds and power levels will make leveling new characters for the event and blasting through some of the prerequisites faster.</p><p dir="ltr">"In Legion Remix, you'll have a great opportunity to obtain Artifact appearances that you haven't already," Kaivax said.</p><p dir="ltr">However, there is one notable exception--Mage Tower Artifact appearances. One of Legion's most innovative additions, the Mage Tower was introduced later on in the expansion and served as a challenge mode for various class specializations. Completing the different Mage Tower challenges originally granted exclusive Artifact weapon tints. However, once Legion ended, the Mage Tower was removed, as were its rewards. While Blizzard did eventually <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/wow-popular-mage-tower-is-becoming-a-permanent-feature/1100-6501781/" data-ref-id="1100-6501781">bring the Mage Tower back</a> with new rewards, many of the original rewards, including exclusive Artifact-weapon tints, weren't made available.</p><p dir="ltr">Those Artifact appearances won't be obtainable in Legion Remix, either, and will thus remain unobtainable for all of those who didn't complete the various Mage Tower challenges back when it was originally available.</p><p dir="ltr">Many players have long hoped Blizzard would bring back the ability to earn the original Mage Tower appearances, first when it was reintroduced in 2022 and now as part of Legion Remix. Blizzard, however, laid out its reasoning for excluding these rewards when Legion Remix was first announced, and is continuing to stick to its guns.</p><p dir="ltr">"Many times throughout the history of World of Warcraft, there have been items, titles, and other kinds of rewards that belong in a category of the most prestigious and historic accomplishments--rewards that we believe should be preserved in a historical context for only those players who earned them at the time," Kaivax wrote in a July <a href="https://us.forums.blizzard.com/en/wow/t/whats-your-wishlist-for-lemix-part-1/2085628/153" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">forum post</a>.</p><p dir="ltr">WoW Legion Remix will launch as part of WoW's 11.2.5 patch on October 7. Like last year's Mists of Pandaria Remix event, those looking to participate won't need to purchase WoW's latest expansion but will need a subscription or game time in order to play.</p><p dir="ltr">Legion Remix will speedrun through the expansion's original content by releasing its content patches in chunks every two weeks. Players will be able to earn all kinds of new and returning cosmetic rewards, as well as level up their Artifact to even greater levels than ever before. That extra power can then be put to the test with the event's new, Diablo-inspired Heroic World Tier and Timeworn Mythic+ Keystone dungeons.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/wow-legion-remix-brings-back-almost-every-artifact-skin-except-the-one-youre-missing/1100-6534959/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Game Pass For PC Getting This Cat-And-Mouse City-Builder As A Day-One Release]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/game-pass-for-pc-getting-this-cat-and-mouse-city-builder-as-a-day-one-release/1100-6534958/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/game-pass-for-pc-getting-this-cat-and-mouse-city-builder-as-a-day-one-release.1305750/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6534958">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Whiskerwood, a cat-and-mouse city-building game from Hooded Horse Minakata Dynamics, is coming to to <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/best-xbox-game-pass-games/2900-4001/" data-ref-id="2900-4001">PC Game Pass</a> at launch on November 6.</p><p>Whiskerwood has players controlling industrious mice who live under the "oppressive paw" of cat overlords. Players will travel the seas, explore new lands, and build cities as they make the best of things while the "oppressive demands" of the cat overlords are asking for more and more.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ouXnSla_wUI" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/ouXnSla_wUI" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>"Establish waste management and healthcare facilities, ensure buildings are properly heated and maintained, and send forth your mice to fell trees, mine mountains, and tend to the fields and fish," reads a line from the game's description. "The cats will demand their due, and your own citizens will abandon the colony if their needs aren't met on a daily basis--you must strike a perfect balance between the needs of the mouse and the demands of the cat."</p><p>Players must build complex systems to like pipelines for water flow, conveyor belts, and ramps to move goods quickly from one place to another, and spend time R&amp;D efforts to find new technologies to "bring a bright future for mousekind."</p><p>"There's only so far a mouse can be pushed before it must push back--the demands of the cat grow more unreasonable by the day, and they care not for the suffering with which these demands are met," reads a line from the game's description. "Come rain or shine, the shipments must be fulfilled to feline satisfaction lest they call upon their henchmen to violently remind you of your duties. Will you forever serve this oppressive paw? Or will you raise your whiskers in defiance?"</p><p>In other news, an Xbox boss recently said Game Pass is getting its <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/game-pass-gets-largest-investment-to-date-this-year-xbox-boss-says/1100-6534902/" data-ref-id="1100-6534902">"largest investment" to date this year</a>, amid criticisms of the service from a range of people, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-downside-of-game-pass-according-to-a-former-xbox-boss/1100-6534539/" data-ref-id="1100-6534539">including former Xbox executives</a>.</p><p><em>For more: </em><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/upcoming-game-pass-titles/1100-6534406/" data-ref-id="1100-6534406">Upcoming Game Pass Titles In 2025 And Beyond</a></p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/game-pass-for-pc-getting-this-cat-and-mouse-city-builder-as-a-day-one-release/1100-6534958/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Painkiller will get a roguelike mode called Rogue Angel]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/09/23/painkiller-will-get-a-roguelike-mode-called-rogue-angel/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/painkiller-will-get-a-roguelike-mode-called-rogue-angel.1305726/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>3D Realms and Anshar Studio have announced that Painkiller will get a roguelike mode called Rogue Angel, the day the game launches. This new mode is separate to the story mode and will take players to an area of Purgatory where the levels are procedurally generated which are home to a mix of bosses. Players will be able to collect weapons, tarot cards, and items as they progress through the levels to take on the challenges that will lay ahead.</p>
<p><iframe title="Painkiller - Rogue Angel Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/b06H_XLzfwM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>Painkiller’s story puts you in Purgatory where you have been given a chance to redeem yourself after transgressing against Heaven. The way to redeem yourself is by blasting away the demons of purgatory in an attempt to stop the fallen angel Azazel’s invasion of Earth. Painkiller can be playable solo and will also support co-op for up to three players.</p>
<p>There are two versions of Painkiller available for pre-order including the standard version and the deluxe edition. The standard edition is priced at €39.99/£34.99 with a pre-order bonus of the Iron Crusade skin pack. This pack includes skins for all four of the game’s characters, who are Ink, Void, Sol, and Roch. The Iron Crusade pack also has skins for six of the game’s weapons, with those being the Electrodriver, Stakegun, Shotgun, SMG, Hand Cannon and Rocket Launcher. You can check out the weapons in action&nbsp;<a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/04/18/painkillers-latest-trailer-showcases-some-of-its-weapons/">Painkiller’s last trailer that showcased t</a>hem. The Painkiller Deluxe Edition is priced at €49.99/£44.99 will have the Iron Crusade pack, as well as three other post launch DLC packs that will each have six weapon skins and four character skins.</p>

<p>Painkiller is due to release on October 21st for PC, PS5, and Xbox Series XS.</p>
<p><em>Source: Press Release</em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/09/23/painkiller-will-get-a-roguelike-mode-called-rogue-angel/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The LEGO Minecraft Advent Calendar Is Selling for Pennies, but Only if You Buy Early]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/the-lego-minecraft-advent-calendar-is-selling-for-pennies-but-only-if-you-buy-early-2000627983</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-lego-minecraft-advent-calendar-is-selling-for-pennies-but-only-if-you-buy-early.1305717/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>LEGO has just rolled out its new Advent calendars, and they’re giving early shoppers a real treat. Every year it’s the same story: prices are friendliest at launch then as December gets closer, demand sends them climbing back up.</p>
<p>Right now, <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4264/">the LEGO Minecraft advent calendar (2025 edition) is going for only $38 instead of the usual $44</a>. No wonder it’s already the fan favorite among all the LEGO calendars this season, from Harry Potter to Star Wars – but <strong>Minecraft is the #1 best-seller on Amazon</strong>.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4264/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<p>LEGO just released its new Advent calendars, and they’re treating early buyers to a welcome bargain. Year after year: prices are kindest at introduction, then closer to December, demand pushes them on the rise. Currently, the LEGO Minecraft Advent Calendar 2025 is available for as low as $38 rather than its normal price of $44.99, which is its lowest ever on Amazon. No wonder it’s already the holiday favorite of all the LEGO calendars available this year, whether it’s Harry Potter or Star Wars—but Minecraft is in the spotlight.</p>



<h2>A Christmas Deal That Brings Minecraft to Life</h2>
<p>Why this set is exciting is pretty simple: children and adults like counting down to Christmas, and LEGO and Minecraft is as good a sure bet as you’re ever likely to get. Instead of a second box of chocolates, <strong>you’re getting 24 buildable surprises</strong> that extend the suspense through the morning.<strong> Constructed from 300 pieces</strong>, the set creates a full-sized Minecraft world to discover one day at a time.</p>



<p><strong>8 classic Minecraft mini-figures are shipped inside</strong>: Alex and Steve are present, of course, but you also get a Creeper, stray, drowned, zombie, snow golem, and even a villager in Santa clothes. They all come with holiday-themed accents that still fit the vibe of the holiday countdown without losing the characteristic Minecraft look.</p>
<p>What’s really cool is <strong>the way the pieces interact with one another</strong>: There’s something new every day and collectively, they build a Minecraft-themed winter village scene. That playmat background in the box acts as the glue to hold everything together so instead of having 24 separate builds, kids see their own Lego world come together over the space of a month.</p>
<p>This Advent calendar isn’t a separate collection: it’s <strong>compatible with the entire range of LEGO Minecraft</strong>. For someone who already has Minecraft Lego pieces lying around, this slots right into the existing collection. Kids can expand on their worlds, bridge scenes together or start with it and build something even bigger.</p>
<p>And there’s more than just nostalgia at play: LEGO calendars like this one don’t stick around at low launch prices. Historically, these drop right around release week before climbing steadily into mid-November, as the frenzy for Advent calendars kicks in. Waiting until December almost guarantees you’ll pay list price—or risk a sell-out altogether.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4264/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/the-lego-minecraft-advent-calendar-is-selling-for-pennies-but-only-if-you-buy-early-2000627983]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Baby Steps Review]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/baby-steps-review</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/baby-steps-review.1305714/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">As someone who lives for the unexpected, unique, and downright weird, it only took about five seconds for the absolute craziness of Baby Steps to steal my heart. This spiritual successor to pain-inducing cult classics QWOP and Getting Over It with Bennett Foddy (who is also one of the developers here) is a similarly exasperating physics-based walking simulator that asks you to control the most unwieldy human ever created as you push yourself through increasingly arduous obstacles. The result is one of the most hilariously infuriating journeys it has ever been my pleasure to rage through. With writing that consistently cracked me up, a story with more heart than I expected, and brilliant branching paths that let you choose your own level of anguish as you explore the dreamlike world, I had a hard time staying mad at this wonderfully bizarre odyssey even in its most maddening moments.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Like just about everything in Baby Steps, the story told here is eccentric, to say the very least. You play as Nate, a 35-year-old neckbeard who has sleepwalked through his entire life and suddenly finds himself on a hiking trip he’s laughably unprepared for. After inexplicably refusing to accept help from anyone as he fumbles around without so much as shoes on his feet (presumably because he avoids social interaction almost as much as he does cardio), he goes toe-to-toe with formidable environmental hazards all while wearing a dirty, stretched-out onesie that looks like he hasn’t removed it in several years. But despite being one of the most immediately unlikeable characters of all time, I found this sad sack gradually growing on me in a big way, as his awkwardness peels away to reveal an isolated and depressed softie I couldn’t help but root for. </p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Baby Steps Review Screenshots</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The goofy characters you meet along the way are oddly compelling. They are all voiced by the same handful of people delivering what I suspect is highly improvised dialogue that sorta meanders through each cutscene, which works shockingly well. For example, Jim, who tries to serve as Nate’s onboarding guide but is repeatedly rebuffed until he effectively becomes a bitter antagonist of sorts, never failed to amuse me with each unwelcome appearance. I cackled loud enough to annoy my neighbors twice in the first hour alone, and found myself peculiarly drawn to the lewd cast and absurdist story that unfolds. Granted, no small part of that is the fact that Baby Steps is deeply inappropriate at every turn, which definitely appeals to my depraved sense of humor and lust for nonsense. But even when its jokes don’t quite land, it still won me over just by being so unlike all the humdrum Hero’s Journey tales I’ve seen a thousand times, instead favoring outlandish and unconventional ideas that kept me guessing every step of the way.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>Putting one foot in front of the other is way, <em>way </em>harder than it sounds.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Of course, as a quite literal walking simulator, you spend the vast majority of the time on your own just trying to put one foot in front of the other, which is way, <em>way </em>harder than it sounds. That’s because instead of pressing one button to move forward, Baby Steps forces you to control each leg independently, often resulting in you face planting into the dirt like a four-year-old operating a broken pair of stilts. If this doesn’t sound particularly hard to you, guess again: it took me several hours before I could walk on even slightly bumpy terrain without treating my face to a three-course meal of rocks. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The counterintuitive magic of Baby Steps, however, is that what start off feeling like insurmountably ass-backwards controls eventually become second nature, and there’s actually a ton of depth baked into Nate’s awkward movements that reveals itself the longer you commit to it. For example, the pressure you apply when pulling each trigger determines the precise height you will raise the corresponding foot, and lifting one causes Nate to press against whatever’s under the other with much greater force – something that can both cause you to slip or save you from a spill depending on the situation. By the end of my 20-hour voyage I was carved out of goddamned wood, scaling sheer walls with the dexterity and grace of a mountain goat trained in the ancient art of ninjitsu and performing feats that would have seemed downright impossible mere hours earlier. </p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>By the end of my 20-hour voyage I was carved out of goddamned wood.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Don’t get me wrong: there were still plenty of times where I fell to the ground while just walking around on normal terrain, even as I neared the end, and it never stops feeling like a pain in the derriere just to pull off basic movement. But I also ended up developing a deep respect for the system that was given to me, which has so much nuance and so many tricks to learn that I felt like the only limit to what I could pull off was my own skill. For a hypercompetitive person like myself, this pulled me into an inescapable pursuit of mastery that kept me awake long into the night cursing my creators as I tumbled to the ground for the 50th time in a row.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Most of the time, the frustrations I felt while trying to move my unwieldy avatar through mountain ranges and dark caves felt extremely harsh but fair, and I was almost always learning something new about Nate’s dumb body as I flailed around through convoluted puzzles. That said, there were also times where I felt not so much in control of my own success. For example, sometimes Nate would get caught on an object or move in some bizarre, unexpected way that would lose me 20 minutes of progress as I tumbled helplessly down a massive obstacle course I had just climbed, and these made for some of the most rage-inducing moments in my adventure. To be clear, these moments were very rare, and my failures were overwhelmingly a case of me just needing to git gud – but when you’re already getting sand kicked into your open eyes while everything is working as expected, feeling like you had no control over your own success even 1% of the time makes it hurt a lot more.</p><div data-cy="playlist-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="title3">TieGuyTravis' Funniest Games List</h3><p>If you like a little gaming with your jokes, these are the games to play.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Although Baby Steps can be incredibly frustrating to play and has challenges so grueling I regularly considered if I’d prefer to just tumble down a hill myself, it also deliberately makes the vast majority of these hurdles completely optional and almost always placed thoughtfully within view as you make your hike ever upwards. This meant that, although I often felt devastating pain at repeated failed attempts to, for example, climb to the top of a crumbling temple in the jungle, I couldn’t really get too mad in the knowledge that I voluntarily subjected myself to that torment, and could just as easily move on along the main path where the level of difficulty was much more manageable. It’s actually an awesome structure, because it allowed me to take on spicier paths when I was feeling up to it, then move on if I ever felt like I wasn’t improving my skills by beating my head against the current trial (though I was almost always too stubborn to do so). I really appreciated this approach, which lets you pick your own level of suffering and grow at your own pace, and I always felt rewarded for taking the more extreme route by triggering a goofy cutscene or little story bit at the end.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>The environments run the gamut, and never stopped providing fresh ideas throughout my run.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">It also helps keep things fresh that each leg of your hike up the giant mountain is accompanied by a new, unique-looking area, from sandy deserts that make it even harder to get around as the ground moves beneath your feet, to a derelict mine with dark tunnels and splintered wood that require extreme precision to navigate. The environments run the gamut, and never stopped providing fresh ideas throughout my run, like one part where I had to learn how to delicately ride a water turbine, or another where slippery frozen lakes forced me to master balance and intentional movement. </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s worth noting that none of this, from the levels themselves to the characters you meet, looks particularly good. In fact, Baby Steps is downright ugly most of the time, and has a surprising amount of pop-in for a game where all you do is walk really slowly. But with how unhinged everything else is, the lofi, identical trees and blurry faces kinda work with its generally gross vibe.</p></section><div data-cy="verdict"><h3 data-cy="title3">Verdict</h3><p data-cy="article-verdict-paragraph">I wasn’t expecting one of my favorite games of 2025 to be about a socially awkward blob in a stained onesie with such poor motor skills that he ragdolls to the ground on the slightest of uneven surfaces, but here we are. Baby Steps is a triumphantly quirky physics game that asks you to challenge yourself, both with alluring hiking obstacles that had me screaming to the heavens and a shockingly unconventional story and characters that ended up feeling like family by the end. Despite centering itself around intentionally awkward controls, it has a deceptive level of depth that made me eager to master it, and I got incredibly lost in the sauce as I tried to best its most daunting challenges. If you like a good laugh, extreme difficulty, or just hate yourself, then I can’t recommend Baby Steps enough.</p></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/baby-steps-review]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Side-scrolling tactical RPG Wishfarers announced for PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/09/side-scrolling-tactical-rpg-wishfarers-announced-for-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/side-scrolling-tactical-rpg-wishfarers-announced-for-pc.1305711/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>Wishfarers</em> is a turn-based, tactical <a title="Genres > RPG [17,639 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg">RPG</a> with streamlined platformer movement, explosive combat, and destructible terrain.</p><p>Wishing season is finally here, and the wishfarers are ready to get granting! Join a plucky band of <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,576 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a>rs as they chase shooting stars, face mysterious foes, fulfill wishes both big and silly, and find a decent pair of socks.</p><p><strong>Play Explosive RPG Battles With Destructible Environments</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Players and enemies wield an arsenal of magical abilities to use in battle: Classic fireballs and lightning bolts, helpful healing spells, buffing bard songs, otherworldly summons, astral armaments, and the pinnacle of spell slinging—Miracle Moves.</p><p><strong>Challenge Bosses Across the Archmages’ Archipelago</strong></p><p>The Wishfarers will battle many magnificent bosses in their star-studded quest, including the storm guardians of Mt. Plumeria, the champion of the Sasquatch Superdome, an ancient psychic gem turtle, and more!</p><p><strong>Jump Into Turn-Based, Tactical Combat Streamlined With <a title="Genres > Platformer [749 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/platformer">Platformer</a> Movement</strong></p><p>Players move primarily by running and jumping about the map via simple platformer controls. Additionally, characters can learn magical movement abilities such as explosive leap, kunai dash, and wind walk.</p><p><strong>Customize Characters With Seven Classes, Over 100 Abilities, and a Multitude of Magical Socks</strong></p><p>As the Wishfarers improve their combat prowess, players can customize each party member with a secondary suite of spells, magical movements, enchantments, and counterspells. Characters can be further outfitted with magic gloves, boots, and up to two special socks!</p><p><strong>Explore a Whimsical World of Falling Stars and Lost Wishes</strong></p><p>The world of <em>Wishfarers</em> is a wild and magical place where wizard duels break out at the drop of a sock. Rowdy monsters roam the land looking for fights. The Zodiac guild is collecting wishes to sell to the highest bidder. The Plumerians are in political turmoil. The Sasquatches will scrap as a means of saying hello. And there’s a rumor that the Scion of Stars will grant any wish in exchange for a star—even if it is not your own.</p></div><p>Watch the announcement trailer below.</p></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/09/side-scrolling-tactical-rpg-wishfarers-announced-for-pc]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Top Hat Studios and Molegato announce 3D platformer Twinkle’s Galactic Tour for PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/09/top-hat-studios-and-molegato-announce-3d-platformer-twinkles-galactic-tour-for-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/top-hat-studios-and-molegato-announce-3d-platformer-twinkle%E2%80%99s-galactic-tour-for-pc.1305705/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Travel the galaxy and bash enemies to the beat.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Top Hat Studios [42 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/top-hat-studios">Top Hat Studios</a> and <em><a title="Games > Frogun [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/frogun">Frogun</a></em> developer <a title="Companies > Molegato [4 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/molegato">Molegato</a> have announced 3D <a title="Genres > Platformer [749 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/platformer">platformer</a> <em><a title="Games > Twinkle's Galactic Tour" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/twinkles-galactic-tour">Twinkle’s Galactic Tour</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > PC [24,310 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> (<a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3938440/Twinkles_Galactic_Tour/" target="_blank">Steam</a>). A release date was not announced. <span id="more-994767"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3938440/Twinkles_Galactic_Tour/" target="_blank">Steam page</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Travel the galaxy to rescue Twinkle’s debut concert’s audience in a low-poly, 90s anime styled, musical platforming <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,576 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a>!</p><p>Play each level to the beat of a song as enemies, platforms and items all move following the beat, the melody or the drums. Uncover musical minigames or explore the personal story of an struggling (but never surrendering!) young aspirant singer.</p><p><strong>Galaxy Round Tour</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Explore neon-and-pastel alien cities, travel on Twinkle’s best friend and roadie Bav’s space van, help the locals by completing missions, sample the local cuisine or shop around for useful gear or fashionable costumes!</p><p><strong>Collect Everything</strong></p><p>Optional objectives in levels like finishing one try, time trials or finding the hidden CDs will grant you materials to craft power ups and tools. Find lots of secondary missions and hidden items in the open cities and return to previous areas once you’ve got new tools to reach new places!</p><p><a title="Companies > Experience [212 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/experience">Experience</a> Twinkle’s and each character’s narratives through completing missions and the ‘hangout system’, in a story that is all about what it feels trying to make it out in life as an artist.</p><p><strong>Loving the Art</strong></p><p>Will Twinkle catch the culprit and serve justice? Find out her footing in the harsh career of music? Which friends will you choose to make? Maybe even find your love in the midst of it all?</p><p>So be a star and help Twinkle and her friends save everyone beat after beat, song after song!</p></blockquote><p>Watch the announcement trailer below.</p><h2><span>Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Twinkle's Galactic Tour ► Official Reveal Trailer At Top Hat Studios Tokyo Game Show Showcase" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NWz2u32lXXQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/09/top-hat-studios-and-molegato-announce-3d-platformer-twinkles-galactic-tour-for-pc]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Slime Rancher 2 Is Out Of Early Access, Now Available On PC And Consoles]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/slime-rancher-2-is-out-of-early-access-now-available-on-pc-and-consoles/1100-6534936/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/slime-rancher-2-is-out-of-early-access-now-available-on-pc-and-consoles.1305702/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6534936">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>After a few years in early access, the full version of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/slime-rancher-2/">Slime Rancher 2</a> has now launched for PC, PS5, and Xbox Series X|S. The cozy slime-wrangling and life-simulator game has also been enhanced with the new "A Hero in Time" update, adding several new and returning features to the adventures of Beatrix LeBeau as she tracks down and raises slimes for her ranch.</p><p>One of the big additions to the game will be Quantum Drones, a new version of the autonomous devices that can help you run your ranch and explore the world. Developer Monomi Park has also outlined its plans for endgame content, as the Grey Labyrinth will offer players the opportunity to journey to previously unseen areas. Additionally, the 1.0 release of Slime Rancher 2 will add even more areas to explore, new slimes to discover, and gadgets to master.</p><p>To celebrate the full release, Monomi Park will offer the game at a discounted price on Steam, as well as an Ultimate Bundle that includes base games for both titles, the original soundtracks, the second volume of the Slime Rancher 2 soundtrack, and more. <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?fntitle=Slime+Rancher+2+Is+Out+Of+Early+Access%2C+Now+Available+On+PC+And+Consoles&amp;fnauthor=darranged&amp;fndate=2025-09-23+10%3A30%3A00&amp;fnupdated=2025-09-23+10%3A51%3A08&amp;fnarticle_id=6534936&amp;fntype1=Games&amp;fntype2=News&amp;fntype3=Standard+News&amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.jdoqocy.com%2Fclick-100770772-13797872%3Fsid%3Dsubid_value%26url%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.fanatical.com%2Fen%2Fgame%2Fslime-rancher-2&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fslime-rancher-2-is-out-of-early-access-now-available-on-pc-and-consoles%2F1100-6534936%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">You can pick up a Steam key for Slime Rancher 2</a> through Fanatical for $18.59 (was $30), giving you a pretty impressive 38% discount.</p><p>Themed in-person events are also being scheduled with Boba Guys flagship locations in the US, <a href="https://www.bobaguys.com/slimerancher2" rel="nofollow ">and you can check where these will be held through this link</a>.</p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/most-anticipated-games-leaving-early-access-in-2025/2900-6151/">Slime Rancher 2 is one of several big games exiting early access this year</a>, following its <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/slime-rancher-2-gameplay-trailer-reveals-fall-2022-release-window/1100-6504604/">arrival in early access</a> all the way back in 2022. One of the biggest will be the 1.0 release of Hades 2--the follow-up to one <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/best-games-of-2020/">2020's best games</a>--and this will be out on September 25 for PC and Switch consoles.</p><p><em>Disclosure: GameSpot and Fanatical are both owned by Fandom.</em></p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/slime-rancher-2-is-out-of-early-access-now-available-on-pc-and-consoles/1100-6534936/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Baldur's Gate 3 Native Steam Deck Build Features Better Framerate And Faster Load Times]]></title>
            <link>https://gameinformer.com/2025/09/23/new-baldurs-gate-3-native-steam-deck-build-features-better-framerate-and-faster-load</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-baldurs-gate-3-native-steam-deck-build-features-better-framerate-and-faster-load-times.1305696/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p>Larian Studios has released Hoxfix 34 for Baldur's Gate 3, and it brings with it a native Steam Deck build of the game. The team says this build should feature better framerate, lower loading times, and smoother gameplay.&nbsp;</p><p>Before today's hotfix, Baldur's Gate 3 ran decently on Steam Deck via a Proton build, but it came with some noticeable drawbacks, like a sometimes-unstable framerate and fuzzy resolution. Though we haven't tested it ourselves, it sounds like Larian's new native Steam Deck build will be the best way to play Baldur's Gate 3 on the go moving forward.&nbsp;</p><p height="360" width="640" url="https://www.youtube.com/embed/hpAGlgJMYLc"><iframe width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/hpAGlgJMYLc" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay" allowfullscreen="true">&nbsp;</iframe></p><p>"This is not just good news for Steam Deck users either," the hotfix notes read." The work the team has put into this build also means that everyone will get to enjoy overall improvements to the way game models are streamed on all platforms, which should reduce framerate spikes in busy areas, such as the Lower City in Act 3."</p><p>Elsewhere in the notes, Larian has addressed various questions players might have about their saves and other aspects of transitioning to this new native build. Head <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1086940/view/511843343389426278">here</a> for more on that. Hotfix 34 is now live.</p><p>While waiting for your game to update, check out <a href="https://gameinformer.com/review/baldurs-gate-3/a-true-soul-stirrer"><em>Game Informer's </em>Baldur's Gate 3 review</a>.&nbsp;</p><hr><p><em>Are you going to play Baldur's Gate 3 on Steam Deck with this new build? Let us know in the comments below!</em></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://gameinformer.com/2025/09/23/new-baldurs-gate-3-native-steam-deck-build-features-better-framerate-and-faster-load]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I Love Silksong Even When It Bugs Me]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/silksong-problems-runback-criticism</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/i-love-silksong-even-when-it-bugs-me.1305687/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>I am shocked at the degree to which I’m enjoying <em>Silksong</em>. <em>Hollow Knight</em> slid over me, so I wasn’t anticipating a game that fulfills my pervert need for intense, unforgiving, white knuckle difficulty. There is so much I love in this complex, post-lapsarian bug mound. It is undoubtedly a labor of love, one full of strong, opinionated choices and intentional friction. Unfortunately, some of those choices are ambiently annoying to me personally, tiny little irritants in an otherwise unspeakably beautiful and once–in-a-generation platformer.</p><h2><strong>On the nature of perversion</strong></h2><p>Lest this devolve into an annoying <em>Cuphead</em>/<em>Souls</em> fight about difficulty, I would like to state that I am, in the gaming sense, a pervert. I say this not for approval or as a signifier to an in-group, but for context: My favorite experiences are often the gaming equivalent of <a href="https://aftermath.site/sigma-ruined-ninja-gaiden-2-ninja-gaiden-sigma-2-so-a-modder-is-fixing-it" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">getting your hand repeatedly slammed in a car door</a>. I love <a href="https://aftermath.site/psycho-patrol-r-early-access-impressions-review-cruelty-squad-consumer-softproducts" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">grotesque indies that kill you instantly and unfairly</a>, and <a href="https://aftermath.site/beyond-citadel-indie-retro-shooter" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">retro shooters that border on pornography</a>. In the case of <em>Silksong</em>, I love when a game hits me on the head with a big cartoon mallet until I memorize its inscrutable little patterns. There is a bliss when ego dies that can only be found in the solace of the pain cave.</p><p>But being a game pervert is not a uniform experience; there is no big dial labeled “freaky” that goes from 1-10. Every game pervert has different preferences, often shaped by some unplayable dreck that duckling imprinted when they were trapped with it at an impressionable age. A pervert can explain away certain unforgivable choices as “actually genius" or non-offensive in a way that does not personally bother them, while finding something benign to be grounds for war crime tribunals. Perversion is best when it marries the cold, detached ego of a great critic and with the depraved id of someone who learned Japanese by playing every game in an intellectually interesting 7.5/10 series that goes back to the PC Engine CD.&nbsp;</p><p><em>Silksong</em> is undoubtedly for perverts–it is a game of strong choices and is mostly “my shit.” There are some choices, like the lack of a healthbar, that I agree with despite other people <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/hollowknightsilksong/mods/28" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">wanting one enough to mod it into the game</a>. The parts where it is not for me I find tremendously annoying in a way that another pervert would not bat an eye at. This is not a discussion of the many things the game does well, but rather where the game falls apart for me. Perhaps your perversions are similar to my own.</p><p><strong><em>The following post features minor naming and mechanical spoilers for Act 1 and one part of Act 2 of Silksong. </em></strong></p><h2><strong>There should just be a homeward bone</strong></h2><figure><figcaption>This is the homeward bone in this game.</figcaption></figure><p>A tiny thing the game doesn’t tell you when you are playing is that you can return to the last bench you rested at instantly with all your stuff intact. This can be done by selecting “<a href="https://steamcommunity.com/app/1030300/discussions/0/546746241084757814/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">quit to menu</a>” and reloading your game. Instead of picking up where you left off, the game places you back at the bench with all your rosaries in hand instead of Hornet having to backflip her bug ass back after an annoying cocoon run.</p><p>This would be a fantastic feature if it were telegraphed, as it is clutch if you’re trying to retrieve your cocoon after a death or engage in certain farming routes early on for rosaries. The problem is that while this has to be intentionally in the game mechanically, it presents as an unofficial workaround rather than something the player is meant to use.</p><p>I find its presence as a weird hack to be incoherent. If the player is allowed to warp back to the last saved bench, there should just be an item in the menu that does that – like the homeward bone in <em>Dark Souls</em> or the homeward idol in <em>Sekiro</em>. I understand why Team Cherry might implement this mechanic in a way that doesn’t call attention to it, but if it’s already in the game it should just be implemented honestly.</p><h2><strong>The shell shard economy is pointless and tedious</strong></h2><figure><figcaption>Going broke doing this.</figcaption></figure><p>Hornet can equip tools like throwing knives, boomerangs and spike mines to dispatch enemies as an alternative to melee combat. In order to refill many of those tools, the player must use shell shards picked up from killing small enemies, or purchase shard bundles from a vendor. Tools are most useful against annoying medium-sized enemies and bosses. Often, it makes the most sense to save your shards for a particularly brutal fight. In one way, the shard economy functions not unlike blood vials in <em>Bloodborne </em>or Spirit Emblems in <em>Sekiro</em> – a resource that is helpful but must be collected.</p><p>Here’s the thing: though mechanically I like blood vials, they are ultimately one of the worst design decisions in <em>Bloodborne</em>. And while you may need to farm vials and emblems, neither are nearly as punishing from an exchange rate as <em>Silksong</em>’s shell shards. <em>Silksong</em>’s shards take <a href="https://www.reddit.com/search/?q=silksong%20shards&amp;cId=2287a9cf-f635-497c-a141-22a54ac62701&amp;iId=57c76529-3aaf-4a57-8e3d-b92fab21cfb1" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">one of the worst parts of a great game</a> and lean into it.</p><p>If you’re naturally good at <em>Silksong</em>, you might not rely on tools as much as a player who is still attempting to learn the encounter. If you could reload your tools by picking up shards in the field, the mechanic would make sense. But because tools are refilled at benches, forcing an economy around them only serves to add busywork to a frustrated player banging their head against the boss fight.&nbsp;</p><p>The player can skew the shard economy by farming rosaries to purchase bundles of shards from the Forge Daughter, Mottled Skarr, or the vendor in Bellhart, but this feels like an elaborate band-aid to a mechanic that feels clunky, and optimizing rosary farming for shards feels like homework. Improving the exchange rate for refilling tools or removing the shard economy outright and having tool refills be free at benches would not harm the game a single bit (you would have to tweak how one crest works.) What’s more, you can still have resource scarcity with rosaries, which is a place in the game where scarcity often feels good and forces the player to make interesting purchasing decisions.</p><figure></figure><p>I will concede that shards serve exactly one purpose, and that’s narrative. The distinction between which bugs drop shards and which drop rosaries distinguishes which bugs have or once had fear of a divine presence and thus cognition. But it does so at the cost of a mechanic that should have been reworked in playtesting.&nbsp;</p><p>Even if I was to be charitable and say that the mechanic was attempting to encourage the player to explore other areas instead of having them repeatedly attempt a boss fight unsuccessfully, I don’t believe it succeeds on those terms. It is a mechanic that exclusively punishes novice players who are attempting to learn an encounter, and while the rejoinder of “don’t rely on tools” is indeed a fair argument, the mechanic itself discourages the process by which a bad player becomes good by disrupting the flow of repeated attempts. After all, why go into a boss fight unprepared? And even if it was working as well as the economy in either <em>Sekiro</em> or <em>Bloodborne</em>, it’s totally lopsided economically. That said, I will concede that there’s probably a sick freak out there who gets off on farming shards.</p><h2><strong>The runback haters are more correct than not</strong></h2><figure><figcaption>Hate these little freaks.</figcaption></figure><p>Lord knows I’ve played a lot of <em>Souls</em> games, and a lot of them have had some nasty boss runbacks, or areas of traversal between the save point and the boss. But I will give FromSoftware credit in one area: they got slightly more merciful when it comes to putting a freaky gauntlet of enemies before a particularly challenging boss. While I don’t think <em>Silksong</em> has this problem uniformly, it happens intermittently enough to make me go “c’mon man.”&nbsp;</p><p>I should stress that a good runback serves a distinct purpose: It gives the player time and space to consider what they did right and wrong, to strategize, and to breathe. A good runback is a meditative exercise unto itself. A bad runback is either an abrasive gauntlet that distracts from the flow state of repeated boss attempts or a weird pebble in your shoe. And while I understand the utility in making the runback scene-setting to the encounter, it is often counterproductive from a gameplay perspective. One of the <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/hollowknightsilksong/mods/46" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">most popular <em>Silksong</em> mods</a> takes inspiration from the <a href="https://eldenring.wiki.fextralife.com/Stakes+of+Marika" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Stakes of Marika</a> in <em>Elden Ring</em>, creating soft respawn points outside of boss encounters.</p><figure><figcaption>The cage trap and ant warrior before the Savage Beastfly can be jumped over but the runback does not add much to the encounter.</figcaption></figure><p>I am of two minds with the runbacks in this game, but err on the side of the haters on the grounds that, in practice, <em>Silksong</em>’s runbacks are monotonous. The one right before the Savage Beastfly (itself a boring-ass boss that does not <a href="https://www.gamesradar.com/games/action/silksong-players-hate-the-savage-beastfly-so-much-that-theyve-formed-a-community-of-haters-called-and-i-quote-f-savage-beastfly/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">deserve its own subreddit</a> and drops a crest I dislike) is not challenging enough to be interesting, but it adds enough friction between attempts to be occasionally distracting (although if you manage to do this when Shakra is there, the path is clear).</p><figure><figcaption>The Last Judge runback is easier if you bolt right past the flier and go straight up the chimney. I recorded this later so ignore the movement upgrades.</figcaption></figure><p>The runback that has gotten the most amount of hate is the one before The Last Judge. While I think it does a fantastic job in setting the tone, and that it’s mostly fine if you sprint past the first drillfly and take the little chimney path, doing it repeatedly can become tiresome given how many hits that boss takes. Getting good at the runback can occasionally feel cool, and The Last Judge is supposed to be <em>Silksong</em>’s <a href="https://ninjagaiden.fandom.com/wiki/Alma" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Alma</a>: an unforgiving end of Act 1 skill check, and the culmination of a huge part of the narrative (provided you take the logical route there). But something is clearly not working for a lot of people despite how beautiful both the setting and the design of the Judge are. The question is: Is the issue the runback, <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/kayin.moe/post/3lyqshkmyq223" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the design of the encounter itself</a>, or the way that both of those things work in concert? If a runback is understood as part of the boss battle itself, does it subtract from the encounter?</p><p>The most depraved runback is in Bilewater, which I will concede is specifically designed to be torturous, and thus is working as intended. I cannot stress <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Silksong/s/HuFVITOLlw" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">how much people hate this place</a>. But even if you agree with the choice of creating a poison swamp more sadistic than any imagined by Hidetaka Miyazaki, I will counter that (respectfully) whoever designed it is one of gaming’s greatest monsters.</p><div><figure><p><iframe title="The Worst Runbacks In Silksong" width="710" height="399" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/zU-oPJiZBvM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></figure></div><h2><strong>Some flying enemies in this game suck a little bit more than I’d like</strong></h2><p>This is perhaps the pettiest of all my gripes, but I don’t like how this game handles flying enemies. I think a bird enemy that screws with you mid-jump is a foundational component of any brutal platformer, but many of <em>Silksong</em>’s flying foes tend to hover just out of range and input read instead of homing in predictable patterns. I would not be opposed to this behavior in a vacuum, but the game also loves spawning a bunch of little flying freaks in runbacks and boss encounters, often to their detriment. Eventually you get the clawline and that solves most of the issues with flying enemies, but that happens in the middle of Act 2, and by that time you’ve had to deal with these freaks for a while. Perhaps you like them, but that’s a matter of taste.</p><h2><strong>Bring back float override input as an option&nbsp;</strong></h2><figure><figcaption>Bring it BACK.</figcaption></figure><p><em>Silksong</em> throws a ton of movement upgrades at you. The Drifter’s Cloak upgrade not only has the funniest animation (Hornet’s cloak becomes a big ass parachute and she kinda dangles like Peach in <em>Mario 2</em>) but it's also clutch in combat. In the middle of Act 2 you get the Faydown Cloak, which allows you to double jump on top of this, but in the process it <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/HollowKnight/comments/1ngwqw4/a_certain_movement_upgrade_feels_a_bit_offspoiler/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">fucks up</a> how you have been using the float up until this point and forces you double jump before floating even when you don’t need to. Apparently the game had a “float override input” that let you force the float by pressing down when you jump, but this was screwing with too many players and <a href="https://www.teamcherry.com.au/blog/silksong-patch-1" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Team Cherry patched this out of the </a><a href="http://game.if/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">game.</a> It kinda feels like they backed themselves into a corner with this one, but I think the override should be optional at the very least. If the counter-argument is “you should simply relearn the movement,” then the double jump should have been put out earlier instead in the ass end of Act 2.</p><p>Also, while I’m on the topic of movement abilities, Hornet’s Swift Step being on RT trigger by default doesn’t work as well as it should unless you have the ability to bind it to a back paddle or switch your trigger to a short throw one. This is mainly a preference, as I feel there’s too much travel time on a trigger for the dash to be deployed rapidly. I have short throws on my ZD-0 Ultimate Legend that turn RT into a clicky button and I can’t imagine going back.</p><h2><strong>Contact Damage is a land of contrasts</strong></h2><p>Contact damage has been a part of platformers for eternity, so I cannot help but respect it (even if I believe spiritually that just touching a guy shouldn’t hurt you). Contact damage turns the world into a big minefield, where in a platformer you want the presence of enemies to pose an active risk. I understand its usage in <em>Hollow Knight,</em> <em>Silksong </em>and the majority of old school platformers. Eyepatch Wolf has a pretty good argument for this when comparing <em>Silksong</em> to <em>Shinobi,</em> and how it turns even basic enemies like the ant warrior into an active threat every single time. In the field, <em>Silksong</em>’s contact damage can feel very good and forces the player to actively learn proper spacing, a skill many of us have all forgotten.</p><div><figure><p><iframe title="Eyepatch Wolfs Opinion on Hollow Knight SilkSong" width="710" height="399" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/g-JD6O3yzns?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></figure></div><p>But how contact damage is implemented in boss fights can be occasionally irritating. Bosses tend to have weird, unwieldy hitboxes, and downed enemies still give contact damage. This topic led to an <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/HollowKnight/comments/1ndjbpf/contact_damage_is_annoying_but_if_it_must_stay/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">exceedingly active conversation</a> within the subreddit that is worth reading if only for the contrast in the responses. I understand why Team Cherry did this: It makes sense that contact damage should be consistent from a design perspective even during a stun, and I understand the pedant’s argument of “well if you get hurt by a downed boss that’s your dumbass fault for not learning spacing.” But my main issue is that boss hitboxes <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/HollowKnight/comments/1nil29z/the_real_problem_with_contact_damage/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">can shift almost arbitrarily on occasion</a>. In the few times it has backfired on a downed boss, it has felt quite bad. If an enemy touching you constitutes an attack, then the boundary of that attack should always be crystal clear.</p><p>There’s also been a longer discussion about how Team Cherry has implemented contact damage generally. I do think the balance of contact damage feels weirdly inconsistent, but I will concede that health in games is a somewhat relative and arbitrary value. There’s a much longer and more interesting conversation to have about the psychological perception of damage; why does a certain amount of damage <em>feel </em>less fair? This is also an issue where I expect to see the most post-launch tuning, and thus any detailed writing about it could quickly become irrelevant.</p><h2><strong>Perverts everywhere</strong></h2><p>Though many of these choices annoy me, I understand the logic that led to each one of them being made and the type of perverts they were made for. I see, with the cold clarity of a deviant, why none of these little bits would bother an ardent and loyal degenerate, and how someone could react poorly to prodding at those choices: “Why should it bother you if it doesn’t bother me?” or the more frequent “<em>Hollow Knight</em> did that, are you saying <em>Hollow Knight</em> is bad?” I can also see the process by which Team Cherry methodically made something that felt correct for them, an extension of their previous game that’s tuned to their tastes and to those of their audiences.</p><p>In the past, challenging games like <em>Silksong </em>have suffered from two problems – a misunderstanding of the conversation between the developers and intended audience on the side of critics, and a frequent dismissal of what little real criticism is left on the grounds that critics are not sufficiently “one of them.” This often plays out in a way that is reactionary and boring, leading to a wall of noise where nobody has a productive conversation about why games make certain choices.</p><p>But in my experience, the few people left who are paid to write about these games love punishment more than most people. To be a pervert, both inside and outside of gaming, is not rarified these days. Consensus reality has collapsed and every one of us lives in a cocoon tailored to our own predilections. To the extent that anything is big, <em>Silksong </em>and <em>Elden Ring</em> are the definition of mainstream. There are perverts everywhere for those with eyes to see.</p><p>If you understand what these games actually are and contextualize them as such, then the conversation has the opportunity to become more interesting and layered. If a game has a streak of sadism, then a discussion of the potential failing of its mechanics can be rendered as a failure to properly calibrate that sadism. In a world where perversion is the mean, punishing games can be rendered as a polite disagreement between different breeds of masochists over their preferred form of punishment. After all, <a href="https://youtu.be/NJ0VSmkebwk?feature=shared" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">it is all a matter of taste, isn’t it</a>?&nbsp;</p></div><div><h2>Stay in touch</h2><p>Sign up for our free newsletter</p></div><div><h2><span>More from Aftermath</span></h2><div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/ea-skate-review-impressions"><h3>No Thank You</h3></a><p>'I would rather lick the paint off my door than see another lootbox screen'</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/aftermath-hours-podcast-charlie-kirk-killer-steam-discord"><h3>What A Shock, The Government Is Scapegoating Video Games Again</h3></a><p>"That nihilism isn’t really reflected or addressed in either political party"</p></div></div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/all">See all posts<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="#000" stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round"><path d="M5 12h13m-6-7 7 7-7 7"></path></svg></a></div></div><br/><br/>https://aftermath.site/silksong-problems-runback-criticism]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Avatar: Frontiers of Pandora From the Ashes expansion revealed with release date]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/09/23/avatar-frontiers-of-pandora-from-the-ashes-expansion-revealed-with-release-date/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/avatar-frontiers-of-pandora-from-the-ashes-expansion-revealed-with-release-date.1305675/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Ubisoft has announced the Avatar: Frontiers of Pandora – From the Ashes expansion, with this new content looking like it will be bringing in the Mangkwan Clan, also known as the Ash People. This clan is going to be focal point of the next Avatar movie, Avatar: Fire &amp; Ash. In terms of release date, Avatar: Frontiers of Pandora – From the Ashes will be launching on December 19th, a few days after Avatar: Fire &amp; Ash hits cinemas.</p>
<p><iframe title="Avatar: Frontiers of Pandora – From the Ashes: EXPANSION REVEAL TEASER" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/24Lc7E-Vt80?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>This won’t be the only content coming to Avatar: Frontiers of Pandora in December either. <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/07/21/avatar-frontiers-of-pandora-third-person-patch-is-coming-in-december/">A third person patch</a> was confirmed earlier this year, with a release date pencilled in for December 5th. The third-person mode is seeing Massive Entertainment completely overhauling character animations, tweaking controls and audio, and the camera to adapt the game from first person to third person. In addition, Beyond that, a New Game+ mode will be added, letting you replay the story and keep inventory and skills, while facing tougher enemies. Now we know there will be some new enemies to take on.</p>
<p>We loved Avatar: Frontiers of Pandora when it launched late last year. In&nbsp;<a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2023/12/19/avatar-frontiers-of-pandora-review/">our review</a>, Dom said, <em>“Avatar: Frontiers of Pandora is an astonishing achievement, with exquisite visuals and a remarkable balance between pacifism and action. This is an enthralling alien world that plays host to a unique FPS.”</em></p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=24Lc7E-Vt80">YouTube</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/09/23/avatar-frontiers-of-pandora-from-the-ashes-expansion-revealed-with-release-date/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Review: Agatha Christie - Death On The Nile (Switch) - Monsieur Poirot Shimmies Into The '70s In Style]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/switch-eshop/agatha-christie-death-on-the-nile</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/review-agatha-christie-death-on-the-nile-switch-monsieur-poirot-shimmies-into-the-70s-in-style.1305672/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><section>
<figure><a title="Agatha Christie - Death on the Nile Review - Screenshot 1 of 5" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/159047/large.jpg"></a><figcaption>Captured on Nintendo Switch (Handheld/Undocked)</figcaption></figure><p>Isn’t it comforting to settle in with a good book that you already know? Microids certainly seem to hope so, as their Studio Lyon is snuggling yet another Christie classic right into your Switch.</p>
<p>A follow-up to 2023’s <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/agatha_christie_-_murder_on_the_orient_express">Murder on the Orient Express</a>, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/agatha_christie_-_death_on_the_nile">Death on the Nile</a> may not be as big as that choo-choo colossus, but it nearly is. So, Studio Lyon has brought the same challenge upon itself: how can a classic this classic be made to feel fresh? And how can you make a mystery game when so many of the audience are already expecting the solution? Luckily, the devs hit upon a formula for it last time, and now it’s back with bells and whistles.</p>
<p>For one thing, the setting has been updated from the 1930s to the '70s. We open on a swishing pair of bell-bottoms, the camera panning up to snaking hips on their way into a disco. This slinky customer is none other than the latest rendition of Hercule Poirot, the legendary detective, now with a collar wider than his trademark moustache and a cravat that suits him to a T. It may be Agatha Christie via <strong>Starsky and Hutch</strong>, but some things don’t change.</p>
<figure><a title="Agatha Christie - Death on the Nile Review - Screenshot 2 of 5" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/159049/large.jpg"></a><figcaption>Captured on Nintendo Switch (Docked)</figcaption></figure>
<p>From dancefloor to detective work, we Moog and wah-wah our way into a third-person adventure perspective, free to stroll around and start chatting up the clientele. This is the backbone of the game: explore, examine, discuss, and solve mysteries from major to trifling. This may mean unravelling the social complexities of a love triangle, cracking the titular river-based murder, or simply arranging suitcases in the boot of a car. The mini challenges like that last one are tacked on a little roughly, however, ranging as they do from simply using a rotary phone to mending a jukebox via five different Christmas-cracker logic puzzles.</p>
<p>Another hallmark of the Poirot games under Microids’ stewardship is the “mind map”. This is a 2D, visual representation of the web of interconnected facts and deductions that make up the case in each chapter. These various observations must be collected during play, then connected and expanded upon in this liminal space inside Poirot’s head. Previous games — especially before Studio Lyon took the reins — made these connections a baffling mix of the obtuse and the obvious, driving you to guesswork to grind out the truth the game wants from you. Death on the Nile is comfortably the most coherent go at the idea yet.</p>
<figure><a title="Agatha Christie - Death on the Nile Review - Screenshot 3 of 5" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/159048/large.jpg"></a><figcaption>Captured on Nintendo Switch (Handheld/Undocked)</figcaption></figure>
<p>But the standout addition to this visualised reasoning is a timeline-building mode that drops the world into an almost sci-fi purple and orange glowing wireframe. You walk around these spaces, associating characters with actions at each step in time. It’s like a cross between a <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/cyberpunk-2077-ultimate-edition">Cyberpunk 2077</a> braindance and a spaced-out hippie’s lava lamp dream.</p>
<p>And that really sums up the essence of the game: it’s an easy ride. Lots of relaxed conversations, low-key, '70s-tinged music, easy puzzles, and slow-paced cutscenes are the order of the day. It may not be everyone’s cup of fussily prepared tea, but it absolutely suits the concept of revisiting a good old classic story. Success always feels like a foregone conclusion, so relax and enjoy the river cruise. A pop-up instruction that summed it up for me read, “New objective: go to dinner” – and that’s dinner on the type of boat that has a cocktail lounge and smoking room. Nice.</p>
<figure><a title="Agatha Christie - Death on the Nile Review - Screenshot 4 of 5" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/159046/large.jpg"></a><figcaption>Captured on Nintendo Switch (Handheld/Undocked)</figcaption></figure>
<p>Some measures have been taken to liven things up – in response, the developers say, to player feedback. These include difficulty modes that strip away guidance layer by layer — a bit antithetical to the game’s raison d’être in my view — and collectibles scattered around the chapters. If you haven’t found a golden moustache in a bidet, have you had a true Poirot experience? Yes, actually. Thankfully, these additions are completely optional and non-judgmental. You’ll get a chapter report of your collectibles, hint count, and so on, but it doesn’t come with a great big “D” rating if you weren’t up to scratch. No pressure here.</p>
<p>But the biggest contrast to the happy cruise of Poirot-by-numbers is Jane Royce, private investigator. Jane is a new side character with a mission of her own: to avenge the death of her close friend who’d uncovered a conspiracy. This leads her into the gritty streets of The Bronx – a strong counterpoint. She runs about to intense prog rock; Poirot sips wine to easy jazz.</p>
<p>Jane also introduces some tension with consequence-carrying decisions that affect the story. If you thought this was a snuggled-up cruise through a well-loved classic, then — wakey wakey — there’s a drive-by to deal with.</p>
<figure><a title="Agatha Christie - Death on the Nile Review - Screenshot 5 of 5" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/159043/large.jpg"></a><figcaption>Captured on Nintendo Switch (Handheld/Undocked)</figcaption></figure>
<p>While all this does work to give a change of pace, it also feels a little incongruous. Just as you’re getting into the flow of one narrative, you’re passed back to the other. It might have been nice if the two threads were woven together more closely earlier in the adventure. Some light action scenes can also feel a touch disjointed. Steering a boat or taking on an impromptu stealth challenge add variety, but they don’t really fit with the game’s greatest strength, which is cosy coasting through a timeless story.</p>
<p>Visually, things look pretty great. The most significant quibble is probably the animation in cutscenes: characters sometimes move like puppets in a way that’s almost nostalgic for the PS2 era – or <strong>The Clangers</strong>, since we’re in the 70s. They almost look like they’re carved from wood, too, which is an art style that looks good without striving for the latest AAA standards. The environments, meanwhile, are varied and attractive, bringing the period to life with the expected staples: dungarees, egg chairs, and the colour brown. Performance isn’t as smooth as Poirot’s wardrobe, but it’s plenty good enough for this type of game.</p>
</section><section id="conclusion"><h2>Conclusion</h2>
<p>With Death on the Nile, Microids Studio Lyon has settled into a great formula for a Poirot adventure: a supporting playable character brings novelty and gives the moustachioed star room to ham it up as a lightly comic persona. Some mildly disjointed pacing and a dozily relaxed speed might put some people off, but if you want the cosy feeling of curling up with a good mystery novel, then this is absolutely the game for you.</p></section>

</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/switch-eshop/agatha-christie-death-on-the-nile]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[You can grab Alan Wake 2 and eight other Remedy games for just $27 right now]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/tech/783776/remedy-30th-anniversary-humble-bundle-alan-wake-2-control-deal-sale</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/you-can-grab-alan-wake-2-and-eight-other-remedy-games-for-just-27-right-now.1305669/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span id="follow-author-standard_article_details-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6Njg3NzIw"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span></span><span>Brandt Ranj</span></span></span></p> <p><span>is a commerce reporter for <em>The Verge </em>writing about the best deals and gadgets. He previously wrote for <em>Business Insider, Rolling Stone, </em><em>Futurism, </em>and <em>Popular Science.</em></span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Remedy Entertainment is one of the few game studios that’s seemingly <a href="https://www.theverge.com/games/691964/remedy-entertainment-profile-alan-wake-control-fbc-firebreak">been doing well</a> in an industry where its <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/762933/bioshock-cloud-chamber-take-two-2k-layoffs">competition is downsizing</a> and console makers are continually raising <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/782079/microsoft-xbox-console-price-increase-us">hardware prices</a>. The studio turned 30 on August 18th, and Humble is celebrating with <a href="https://humblebundleinc.sjv.io/c/482924/2091208/25796?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.humblebundle.com%2Fgames%2Fremedy-games-30th-anniversary-bundle" rel="sponsored">a 10-item bundle</a> for $27 ($211 off the full MSRP). To put the price into perspective, <em>Alan Wake 2 Deluxe Edition</em>, one of the included games, currently retails for $69.99 in the <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/en-US/p/alan-wake-2--deluxe-edition">Epic Games Store</a>. You can also choose a bundle that costs $5 or $12 but includes fewer games, and each is available until October 10th.</p><p>While <em>Alan Wake 2 Deluxe Edition</em> is the standout game in the bunch — and a <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23934662/alan-wake-2-review-ps5-xbox-pc"><em>Verge</em> favorite</a> from 2023 — you’ll also get a mix of classics, including 2002’s <em>Max Payne</em> and a 2012 remake of 1996’s <em>Death Rally</em>, which was initially released for MS-DOS. You’ll also get a 25 percent off coupon for <em>FBC: Firebreak</em>, Remedy’s latest title. If you don’t want to jump into <em>Alan Wake 2, </em>a remastered version of the original game and the standalone side story <em>Alan Wake’s American Nightmare </em>are also included. Playing the games in order will allow you to witness how the studio has progressed, including popularizing the bullet time game mechanic with <em>Max Payne </em>and the psychological horror genre with the <em>Alan Wake </em>series.</p><p>If you pick up the bundle, you’ll receive a mix of Steam keys and Epic Games Store keys, which can be redeemed on their respective platforms. All of the games run on Windows, and some titles are playable on the Steam Deck, which is currently 20 percent off <a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=1025X1701640&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fstore.steampowered.com%2Fsteamdeck" rel="sponsored">from Steam</a> in its entry-level LCD configuration. Part of the proceeds from your purchase even support <a href="https://www.savethechildren.org/">Save the Children</a> — <strong>an organization that provides health, education, and protection programs for children across 113 countries</strong> — in addition to the publishers and Humble. You can also adjust the amount that goes to each entity using the “adjust donation” slider on the landing page.</p><div><form><div><h2>The Verge Daily</h2><p><span>A free daily digest of the news that matters most.</span></p></div></form></div><p><span><a href="https://www.theverge.com/tech/783776/remedy-30th-anniversary-humble-bundle-alan-wake-2-control-deal-sale#comments"><span>0<!-- --> <!-- -->Comments</span></a></span></p><div><p><span><strong>Follow topics and authors</strong> from this story to see more like this in your personalized homepage feed and to receive email updates.</span></p><ul><li id="follow-author-article_footer-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6Njg3NzIw"><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span><span>Brandt Ranj</span></span></span></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li></ul></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/tech/783776/remedy-30th-anniversary-humble-bundle-alan-wake-2-control-deal-sale]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Baldur's Gate 3's latest hotfix brings some good news for those of you on Steam Deck]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/baldurs-gate-3s-latest-hotfix-brings-some-good-news-for-those-of-you-on-steam-deck</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/baldurs-gate-3s-latest-hotfix-brings-some-good-news-for-those-of-you-on-steam-deck.1305666/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture data-src-full="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/baldurs-gate-3-shadowheart-glow.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" src="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/baldurs-gate-3-shadowheart-glow.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/baldurs-gate-3-shadowheart-glow.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 690px) and (min-resolution: 2x)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/baldurs-gate-3-shadowheart-glow.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 690px)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/baldurs-gate-3-shadowheart-glow.jpg?width=414&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-resolution: 2x)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Larian Studios</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Another day, another <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/baldurs-gate-iii">Baldur's Gate 3</a> hotfix, this one being number 34, or version 4.1.1.6931813 of the game if you really want to be specific. There's a number of fixes we'll get to in a minute, but first the thing you're probably most excited to hear: it has a native Steam Deck build now! Developer Larian Studios shared word of this change in a Steam news post today, and what exactly it means for you.
</p>
<p>
The big things you should now notice while playing on Steam Deck is that the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-rpgs">RPG</a> has a more stable framerate, that loading times won't be quite as long, and just generally smoother gameplay. As explained in the news post, this hotfix has made some changes to how game models are streamed in, meaning across all platforms areas like the Lower City in Act 3 that are known for their framerate spikes will work better too.
</p>
<p>
In turns of the big difference between the previous version of Baldur's Gate 3 and this one for Steam Deck users, before it was a Proton version that ran on the Steam Deck via a Proton compatibility layer. This meant it was more intensive on the handheld's CPU, but now that it runs natively it'll need less CPU usage and memory consumption overall!"
</p>
<p>
There's some details on where to find your saves in both versions of the game, and if you use Steam Cloud saves, you'll find your saves post-update anyway. As long as you're logged into your Larian account, all mods you're subscribed to should be downloaded when the game transitions into the native build.
</p><p>
Now, some of the other more general fixes! On the gameplay side, the Hound of Ill Omen and the Accursed Spectre's HP will no longer be affected by difficulty modifiers for enemy characters. An annoying bug that caused the Apostle of Myrkul to gain HP every time you would load a save mid-combat in Tactician and Honour Mode has also been fixed.
</p>
<p>
There are a bunch of audio fixes in this one too, like an issue where it sounded like smokepowder explosions going off on the floor above on the ground floor of Felogyr's Fireworks would send like they're happening next to you instead.
</p>
<p>
Perhaps my favourite fix is in the cinematics section, which simply reads, "Told one of the imps on the nautiloid to stop looking in the wrong direction." You tell 'em, patch notes writer. You can read the full list of patch notes <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1086940/view/511843343389426278">here</a>.

</p>

        </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/baldurs-gate-3s-latest-hotfix-brings-some-good-news-for-those-of-you-on-steam-deck]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Watch Dogs Movie Still Exists, Is ‘Not The Game,’ Says Star]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/watch-dogs-movie-still-exists-is-not-the-game-says-star-2000627949</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/watch-dogs-movie-still-exists-is-%E2%80%98not-the-game-%E2%80%99-says-star.1305660/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p id="featured-image">
                              <figure id="attachment_featured" aria-describedby="featured-caption">
                                                                          <figcaption id="featured-caption">
                    <span>Grumpy old man Aiden wears his lovely cap.</span> © Ubisoft
                  </figcaption>
                </figure>
                                                      </p><div>
              
              <p>After years of development hell, a couple of Ubisoft’s many non-gaming projects appear to be genuinely happening. The <a href="https://kotaku.com/splinter-cell-deathwatch-anime-netflix-2000619516"><em>Splinter Cell</em> animated series</a> begins airing next month after forever in development. Meanwhile, a year after filming was said to be completed on a <em>Watch_Dogs</em> movie, signs of life have appeared in the form of some recent reshoots and the declaration from one of the film’s actors that it’s nothing like the games.</p> <p>Post-production is obviously a lengthy process in projects bursting with CG, with most movies now enlisting the work of multiple SFX studios once shooting has wrapped. But a year without a single piece of news, early teaser, or even a leak still makes you wonder, especially as this silence came after <a href="https://kotaku.com/watch-dogs-movie-live-action-film-ubisoft-decade-later-1851575957">the extraordinary ten-year gap</a> between the <a href="https://kotaku.com/watch-dogs-isnt-out-yet-but-theres-a-movie-in-the-wo-1172993658">film’s announcement</a> and actually getting it in the can. However, news of reshoots <a href="https://screenrant.com/watch-dogs-movie-game-tom-blyth-comparison/">reported by&nbsp;<em>ScreenRant</em></a> suggests things are definitely still progressing. What’s more intriguing, however, is the claim from the movie’s lead, Tom Blyth, that the result is “very different” from the source material. “It’s not the game,” he says.</p> <p>That might immediately sound bad, because films that have wandered far from their original point tend to be aimless, meandering noise. But <em>Watch_Dogs</em> didn’t exactly have a memorable storyline, and is best remembered for its hacking within an all-consuming surveillance system, so ideally the film would lean successfully in this direction: thwarting the underground criminal world of Chicago through grey-hat hacking. It would have been great if it could have offered us this without fridging the protagonist’s niece at the start for some deeply lazy motivation, but there’s plenty there to serve as the basis for an action romp with a sci-fi edge.</p>

 <p>Blyth (speaking to&nbsp;<em>ScreenRant</em> about his current movie&nbsp;<em>Plainclothes</em>) expanded a little. “They’ve done an amazing job of making…I don’t want to spoil too much. I’m trying to pick my words carefully, but they’ve done an amazing job of making the game into a film. It feels very film. It doesn’t feel like they’ve tried to copy and paste the game onto the screen. It feels like its own thing, and it feels like the beginning of a world-building exercise.”</p>

 <p>It feels very film.</p> <p>Super-fans of the original game might be disappointed to not get a highly faithful cinematic retelling of it, but given <em>Watch_Dogs</em> released in 2014, the vast majority of people have forgotten the story entirely. An exciting movie set in the world of hacking, surveillance and untouched criminal networks sounds like it could entertain me well enough, should director Mathieu Turi do a half-decent job with it all. Turi is still something of an unknown quantity, having been AD on movies like <em>Inglorious Basterds</em> and the <a href="https://www.metacritic.com/movie/united-passions/">infamously terrible</a>&nbsp;<em>United Passions</em>, with just 2020’s&nbsp;<em>Meander</em> seeing him succeed at the helm. (His other films have not troubled the attention of critics.)</p> <p>But, if nothing else, we know the&nbsp;<em>Watch_Dogs</em> movie feels, at the least, very film.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/watch-dogs-movie-still-exists-is-not-the-game-says-star-2000627949]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Disney Chose A Wild Time To Hike Everyone’s Subscription Prices]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/disney-plus-price-raising-bluey-season-4-jimmy-kimmel-2000627947</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/disney-chose-a-wild-time-to-hike-everyone%E2%80%99s-subscription-prices.1305654/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Are you ready to pay more for <em>Bluey</em>? Disney thinks so. The company has announced it’s raising prices for a bunch of its subscription tiers <a href="https://kotaku.com/disney-streaming-inside-out-price-hike-increase-when-1851614922">just a year after the last hike</a>. This reveal of the new streaming tax also comes just a day after the company announced Jimmy Kimmel <a href="https://kotaku.com/disney-announces-jimmy-kimmel-return-tuesday-boycott-back-abc-not-canceled-2000627662">would be back on the air, sorta</a>, following calls for a boycott of all Disney products after his late-night show was indefinitely pulled.</p> <p>According <a href="https://www.vulture.com/article/disney-plus-hulu-espn-streaming-price-hikes-kimmel-2025.html">t</a><a href="https://www.vulture.com/article/disney-plus-hulu-espn-streaming-price-hikes-kimmel-2025.html">o <em>Vulture</em></a>, the new prices start a month from today on October 23. At that point, four of Disney’s subscription tiers will go up in price with the largest increase a whopping 20 percent. Here are the new prices:</p> <ul> <li data-editable="text" data-uri="www.vulture.com/_components/clay-paragraph/instances/cmfwpfb0i00333b78zwbaf199@published" data-word-count="32">Disney+ and Hulu Bundle (with ads) – $13 a month (was $11)</li> <li data-editable="text" data-uri="www.vulture.com/_components/clay-paragraph/instances/cmfwpfb0i00333b78zwbaf199@published" data-word-count="32">Disney+ Premium (no ads) –&nbsp;$19 a month (was $16)</li> <li data-editable="text" data-uri="www.vulture.com/_components/clay-paragraph/instances/cmfwpfb0i00333b78zwbaf199@published" data-word-count="32">Disney+ (with ads)&nbsp;– $12 a month (was $10)</li> <li data-editable="text" data-uri="www.vulture.com/_components/clay-paragraph/instances/cmfwpflqj00383b78uboz5qhu@published" data-word-count="33">Hulu + Live TV (with ads) –&nbsp;$90 a month (was $87)</li> </ul> <p data-editable="text" data-uri="www.vulture.com/_components/clay-paragraph/instances/cmfwpflqj00383b78uboz5qhu@published" data-word-count="33">Not all of the prices are going up. The Disney+ and Hulu Premium Bundle without ads will still be $20 a month and Hulu Premium without adds will still be $19. Still, I mean, $90 a month for live TV? In this economy? Why did any of us bother cutting the cord in the first place?</p>

 <p>All entertainment is getting more expensive right now. The streaming wars might as well be called the pricing wars now, except that everyone’s racing to bump prices up instead of undercut one another. Disney’s price hikes come at a weird time, and not only because it just tossed the First Amendment in the trash to appease a sunsetting authoritarian president. There’s also just not a whole lot going on with the service right now outside of the ESPN bundle with fall sports. The next phase of the MCU is delayed, <em>Star Wars</em> is on a post-<em>Andor</em> hiatus until <a href="https://kotaku.com/star-wars-mandalorian-grogu-trailer-reactions-2000627675"><em>The Mandalorian and Grogu</em></a>, and even season four of <em>Bluey</em> is nowhere in sight. A feature-length movie adaptation of the hit Australian dog cartoon isn’t due until 2027.</p> <p>Simply put, if you only watch your local football team, whose games are free to watch on broadcast television, there’s simply never been a better time to ditch Disney+. Unless you are my son, who’s excited for Halloween and keeps hounding me to watch <em>The Nightmare Before Christmas</em>.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/disney-plus-price-raising-bluey-season-4-jimmy-kimmel-2000627947]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ubisoft’s Overlooked Avatar Game Is Getting New DLC Two Years After Launch]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/ubisoft-avatar-frontiers-of-pandora-dlc-expansion-fire-and-ash-avatar-3-price-2000627958</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ubisoft%E2%80%99s-overlooked-avatar-game-is-getting-new-dlc-two-years-after-launch.1305651/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Later this year,<a href="https://kotaku.com/avatar-3-fire-and-ash-trailer-fire-clan-james-cameron-1851787146"> <em>Avatar: Fire and Ash</em>,</a> the third entry in James Cameron’s blockbuster sci-fi saga, will arrive in theaters. And as that movie hits cinemas, a big new expansion related to the sci-fi sequel will launch for Ubisoft’s <a href="https://kotaku.com/video/avatar-frontiers-of-pandora-open-world-ubisoft-far-cry-1851209744">overlooked<em> Avatar: Frontiers of Pandora.</em></a><em>&nbsp;</em></p> <p><a href="https://kotaku.com/avatar-frontiers-of-pandora-impressions-review-ubisoft-1851077773">2023’s<em> Avatar: Frontiers of Pandora</em></a> is a solid open-world game that plays a lot like <em>Far Cry</em> and features a gorgeous alien jungle to explore as a giant blue cat person, aka a Navi warrior. While the game didn’t set the world on fire at launch, it has developed a loyal following of players and received some post-launch DLC and updates. And now Ubisoft has announced a whole new expansion for the under-the-radar game that will connect it directly to the next <em>Avatar</em> film.</p> <p>The upcoming DLC, <em>From the Ashes,</em> is set to launch on December 19 for consoles and PC alongside the new movie, which arrives on the same day in theaters. It will cost $20 for people who own the main game already, and Ubisoft plans to sell a $40 version that bundles the game and the expansion together for new players.</p>

 <p>Here’s the official trailer for the new expansion, as well as Ubisoft’s plot summary:</p> <blockquote><p>“<em>From the Ashes</em> sees players embark on the journey of So’lek, a battle-hardened Na’vi warrior from the Trr’ong clan. Ambushed and left for dead by the RDA and their new allies—the ruthless Ash clan—So’lek awakens to a world in flames and his Sarentu family scattered. Driven by grief and vengeance, he sets out to reunite with and protect his loved ones.”</p></blockquote>  <p>“<em>From the Ashes</em> takes place a few weeks after the events of the upcoming film<em> Fire and Ash</em> and roughly six months after <em>Frontiers of Pandora</em> and both story packs,” the DLC’s creative director Omar Bouali <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/avatar-frontiers-of-pandora-from-the-ashes-dlc-announced-release-timed-with-fire-and-ash-movie">explained to <em>IGN</em></a>. “<em>From the Ashes</em> is set in a ravaged and occupied version of the Kinglor Forest, which includes a new sub-region, The Ravines. It mirrors the themes of the film as it sees the RDA ally with the Ash Clan, fierce Na’vi warriors who thrive on chaos and pain as they intensify their efforts to eliminate threats to their regime. So, whilst the film and expansion are set in different regions of Pandora, there is some shared DNA and we’ve worked closely with Lightstorm to ensure both pieces of <em>Avatar</em> media are complementary.”</p> <p>Shortly before the launch of the third movie and this new DLC, <em>Avatar: Frontiers of Pandora</em> will receive a big, free update. <a href="https://kotaku.com/avatar-frontiers-pandora-cheap-third-person-new-game-1851786644">As previously announced</a>, this new update will arrive on December 5 and add new game+ and a third-person camera option. Then two weeks later, this new DLC arrives. For fans of <em>Frontiers of Pandora</em>, all 46 of you out there (myself included), this is some good news and a great way to end the year. Let’s just hope the DLC and new movie are good.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/ubisoft-avatar-frontiers-of-pandora-dlc-expansion-fire-and-ash-avatar-3-price-2000627958]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kingdom Shell now available for PS5, Xbox Series, PS4, Xbox One, and Switch]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/09/kingdom-shell-now-available-for-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-xbox-one-and-switch</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/kingdom-shell-now-available-for-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-xbox-one-and-switch.1305645/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Top Hat Studios [42 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/top-hat-studios">Top Hat Studios</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Cup of Pixels" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/cup-of-pixels">Cup of Pixels</a> have released <a title="Genres > Side-Scrolling [1,109 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/side-scrolling">side-scrolling</a> <a title="Genres > Action [3,058 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action game</a> <em><a title="Games > Kingdom Shell [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/kingdom-shell">Kingdom Shell</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [10,422 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [7,946 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [28,367 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox One [14,207 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a>, and <a title="Platforms > Switch [17,727 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a> for $17.99. <span id="more-994580"></span></p><p><em>Kingdom Shell</em> first launched for PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1154090/Kingdom_Shell/" target="_blank">Steam</a> on October 5, 2023.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Top Hat Studios:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>The magical Shell that has protected the Kingdom for centuries has been shattered. Hordes of nightmarish creatures now overrun the Kingdom, terrorizing its inhabitants.</p><p>The White Temple, which has stood guard over the Kingdom for centuries, cannot face this threat alone. They are forced to seek help from Elias, a half-blood in whose veins flows the blood of nightmares. He may be the Kingdom’s only hope.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Explore the lands of the Kingdom, fight hordes of nightmarish creatures and powerful bosses, find secrets, help inhabitants in distress and stop the impending catastrophe.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li>Discover the world of the Kingdom, rich in lore and atmosphere.</li><li>Stunning hand-drawn pixel art and animation.</li><li>Engage your foes up close, executing impressive combos, dodge attacks, and strike them with a variety of spells.</li><li>Meet the inhabitants of the Kingdom. Some of them have rumors that can be investigated.</li><li>Engage in challenging and intriguing boss fights, with over a dozen in the game, including secret bosses.</li><li>Explore the Kingdom’s world, filled with hidden places and mysteries.</li><li>Find items, spells, and abilities to aid you in your journey.</li><li>Customize your playstyle with the inspiration system.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Consoles Launch Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Kingdom Shell ► Console Release Trailer At Top Hat Studios Tokyo Game Show Showcase" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/74BWfTM4DrQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/09/kingdom-shell-now-available-for-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-xbox-one-and-switch]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Islets now available for PS5, PS4]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/09/islets-now-available-for-ps5-ps4</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/islets-now-available-for-ps5-ps4.1305639/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Previously released for Xbox Series, Xbox One, Switch, and PC.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Top Hat Studios [42 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/top-hat-studios">Top Hat Studios</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Kyle Thompson [8 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/kyle-thompson">Kyle Thompson</a> have released <a title="Genres > Metroidvania [235 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/metroidvania">Metroidvania game</a> <em><a title="Games > Islets [4 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/islets">Islets</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [10,422 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a> and <a title="Platforms > PS4 [28,367 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, the companies announced. <span id="more-994615"></span></p><p><em>Islets</em> first launched for Xbox Series, Xbox One, Switch, and PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1669420/Islets/" target="_blank">Steam</a> and <a href="https://www.gog.com/game/islets" target="_blank">GOG</a> on August 24, 2022.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Top Hat Studios:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Iko is an aspiring yet hopeful warrior exploring the land and sky to reunite a series of floating islands. With his rickety airship, he must travel from island to island in order to reignite each one’s magnetic core while fighting off the many adversaries standing in his way.</p><p><em>Islets</em> is a surprisingly wholesome Metroidvania about making connections with the people around you. By reuniting the islands and befriending a cast of charming characters, the world expands and reveals new parts of each area for Iko to explore. Scour every nook and cranny in order to collect the many upgrades hidden around this world and face its numerous hidden challenges!</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>There’s also a tour guide to show you around, but you should be careful. The guy’s got some really weird vibes…</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li>Connect the islands like a puzzle to discover new ways to explore previous areas and reunite the vast world around you.</li><li>Fight back against terrifying monsters and ruthless sky pirates in epic boss battles.</li><li>Discover upgrades to help you on your journey by completing challenges and uncover the islands’ many secrets.</li><li>Make friends with a wide cast of charming characters—including a pretentious warrior classmate, a suspiciously friendly frog, and so many others.</li><li>Become immersed in a visually stunning hand-painted world with lush, vivid environments for you to experience.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span><a title="Platforms > PlayStation [48,554 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation">PlayStation</a> Launch Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Islets ► PlayStation 5 &amp; 4 Launch Trailer At Top Hat Studios Tokyo Game Show Showcase" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/jNK5ZWEoayQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/09/islets-now-available-for-ps5-ps4]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Baldur's Gate 3 Hotfix Includes Steam Deck-Native Version Of The RPG]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/new-baldurs-gate-3-hotfix-includes-steam-deck-native-version-of-the-rpg/1100-6534954/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-baldurs-gate-3-hotfix-includes-steam-deck-native-version-of-the-rpg.1305636/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-main">

      
                    
  
              <header id="masthead"><nav></nav></header>      
                            <div id="site-wrapper" role="main">
          <div id="default-content">
        
          <p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p>
  
    <article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6534954">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">Baldur's Gate 3 is apparently even better to play on the go now, as Larian Studios has released a new native version of the RPG for Steam Deck as part of a hotfix update. The developer states that the game has "a more stable frame rate, lower loading times, and smoother gameplay" on the PC handheld. </p><p dir="ltr">Larian detailed what's included with hotfix 34 <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1086940/view/511843343389426278" rel="nofollow ">on Steam</a> in a set of patch notes, with the spotlight on the Steam Deck-native build. But the developer pointed out this new portable version of Baldur's Gate 3 has led to "overall improvements to the way game models are streamed on all platforms, which should reduce framerate spikes in busy areas, such as the Lower City in Act 3." Previously, the RPG utilized the "Proton compatibility layer, which requires extra CPU processing power," to run on Valve's handheld.</p><div data-embed-type="html"><blockquote data-bluesky-uri="at://did:plc:4bbrhyv7c6do5ppnm2x45erw/app.bsky.feed.post/3lzj7ot4hoc2u" data-bluesky-cid="bafyreigtsf7x2oyvsl6mggdtigbjrlrmo6gxjut3ypz3asjio5hfafv4ge" data-bluesky-embed-color-mode="system"><div><p>Hotfix #34 is now live! You'll no longer turn into a floating torso when talking with Ketheric’s dog, the Apostle of Myrkul will stop regaining hit points when you load a save mid-combat, and we've attempted to save you from some annoying crashes. Read all about it: larian.club/Hotfix34</p><p><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:4bbrhyv7c6do5ppnm2x45erw/post/3lzj7ot4hoc2u?ref_src=embed" rel="nofollow  ">[image or embed]</a></p></div>  — Larian Studios (<a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:4bbrhyv7c6do5ppnm2x45erw?ref_src=embed" rel="nofollow  ">@larianstudios.com</a>) <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:4bbrhyv7c6do5ppnm2x45erw/post/3lzj7ot4hoc2u?ref_src=embed" rel="nofollow  ">September 23, 2025 at 11:14 AM</a></blockquote>


  






  </div><p dir="ltr">Mods can carry over to the native Steam Deck build of Baldur's Gate 3. Larian stated that by logging "in to your Larian Account and hav[ing] it connected to mod.io" will lead to your mods downloading for the game. Meanwhile, hotfix 34 also addresses other issues for Baldur's Gate 3, like crashing instances on Xbox Series X|S.</p><p dir="ltr">Last month, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/larian-studios-shares-baldurs-gate-3-rare-choices-and-stats-for-2nd-anniversery/1100-6533679/">Baldur's Gate 3 celebrated its second anniversary</a> with a lot of fun player stats. For instance, there have been more than 265 million mod downloads for the game and 1.1 million players finished the RPG in Tactician mode. Earlier this year, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/baldurs-gate-3s-final-patch-introduces-cross-play-photo-mode-and-12-new-subclasses/1100-6530875/">Baldur's Gate 3 got a beefy update that introduced cross-play</a> and 12 new subclasses.</p><p dir="ltr">For more, check out GameSpot's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/baldurs-gate-3-review-let-freedom-reign/1900-6418131/">Baldur's Gate 3 review</a>. It was also GameSpot's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/baldurs-gate-3-is-gamespots-game-of-the-year-2023/1100-6519739/">Game of the Year in 2023</a>. The patch notes for hotfix 34 are below:</p><h3><b>FIXES</b></h3><p><b>Crashes and Performance</b></p><ul><li>Fixed a potential crash related to the Slow condition during combat.</li><li>Fixed a potential crash related to using the Find Familiar spell on Scratch and Boo during combat.</li></ul><p><b>Xbox</b></p><ul><li>Fixed a crash that could occur when suspending and then resuming the game mid-cinematic.</li><li>Fixed a crash when loading a save while playing an Honour Mode game.</li><li>Fixed an issue that could cause the game to hang and become unresponsive when exiting to the Main Menu from an Honour Mode game.</li><li>Selecting View Xbox Live Profile via the Larian Friends list will now correctly show the user's gamercard.</li><li>Fixed a Cross-Play issue where, if one player had their cross-network privileges blocked on Xbox and was then invited to a multiplayer session by a friend, they wouldn't get notified of the conflict in their settings telling them why they couldn't proceed to the lobby.</li><li>Fixed a bug where creating a new game in Honour Mode after having loaded a previous savegame would cause the game to get stuck at 33% or 83% loading.</li></ul><p><b>Gameplay</b></p><ul><li>Fixed the Hound of Ill Omen and the Accursed Spectre's HP being affected by difficulty modifiers for enemy characters.</li><li>Fixed a bug causing the Apostle of Myrkul to regain Hit Points every time you load a savegame mid-combat in Tactician and Honour Mode.</li></ul><p><b>Audio</b></p><ul><li>Fixed a bug causing the sounds that djinn summons make when they follow you to loop continuously, creating an uncharacteristic metallic thrum.</li><li>When you're on the ground floor of Felogyr's Fireworks, the smokepowder explosions going off on the floor above will no longer sound like they're happening right next to you.</li><li>Fixed the audio levels for a rat in the Lower City that you, tragically, couldn't hear squeak when it squoke.</li><li>Fixed missing SFX when preparing to cast Wind Walk.</li><li>Fixed an issue causing the SFX to play longer than they should when preparing to cast the Way of the Drunken Master's subclass-specific actions.</li><li>Fixed missing SFX when preparing to cast Booming Blade.</li><li>Fixed the SFX for preparing a Starry Form continuing to play if you cast the spell quickly after selecting it.</li><li>Fixed missing SFX when Astarion taps Woe on the ground during a cinematic.</li><li>Fixed missing SFX in the overhead dialogue between Minthara and the questioners in Moonrise Towers Prison.</li><li>Fixed a sound resource for Photo Mode not being generated correctly.</li><li>Fixed the rattling Moonlantern SFX continuing to play after you unequip it.</li><li>Recovered some missing SFX when casting Speak with Dead on the mind flayer in the Shattered Sanctum.</li><li>Reminded Halsin to actually yell when he gains barbarian Rage instead of silently miming it.</li><li>Fixed the SFX during Vlaakith's appearance at camp getting cut off prematurely.</li></ul><p><b>Cinematics</b></p><ul><li>Told one of the imps on the nautiloid to stop looking in the wrong direction.</li><li>Fixed a super-mega-ultra-close-up shot during the dialogue with Raphael at Last Light.</li><li>Removed a static pool of blood hovering mid-air in the cinematic with the gnolls on the Risen Road when playing as a short Dark Urge character.</li><li>Fixed Karlach's line about Gale being a hero getting cut off prematurely.</li><li>Fixed a bug causing party members to appear as floating torsos (or simply floating hair) when talking to Ketheric's dog, Squire.</li></ul>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article>

    
  

        <div>
	<p>
		Latest in
		Baldur's Gate 3
	</p>

	
</div>
  
</div>
                      <meta itemprop="seamless-content-list-items" data-list-items="[{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534884&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/x-men-blue-gold-mutant-genesis-omnibus-edition-preorder-guide\/1100-6534884\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534817&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/how-to-do-grab-tricks-and-combos-in-skate\/1100-6534817\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534819&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/the-quick-and-the-dead-30-anniversary-4k-blu-ray-preorder\/1100-6534819\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534825&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/skate-has-a-special-bonus-for-game-pass-members\/1100-6534825\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534827&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/assassins-creed-4-black-flag-remake-wont-have-modern-day-sections-report\/1100-6534827\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534826&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/heres-how-to-improve-borderlands-4s-performance-on-pc\/1100-6534826\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534829&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/vampire-the-masquerade-bloodlines-2-will-no-longer-paywall-any-launch-day-vampire-clans\/1100-6534829\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534800&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/you-can-play-little-nightmares-3-now-even-though-it-isnt-out-yet\/1100-6534800\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534801&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/mutant-football-league-2-eviscerates-the-endzone-on-december-10\/1100-6534801\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534798&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/randy-pitchford-remains-defiant-about-borderlands-4-pc-issues\/1100-6534798\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534807&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/report-finds-nearly-all-gamers-have-played-a-remaster-or-remake-in-last-year\/1100-6534807\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534806&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/skate-softlock-issue-ea-is-investigating-but-needs-your-help\/1100-6534806\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534799&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/indie-horror-game-no-im-not-a-human-is-blowing-up-on-twitch\/1100-6534799\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534834&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/new-rematch-patch-adds-cross-play-and-ranked-mode\/1100-6534834\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534838&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/splinter-cell-anime-needed-to-rip-the-spine-out-of-the-source-material-showrunner-says\/1100-6534838\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534810&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/magic-the-gatherings-next-secret-lair-drop-features-art-built-with-play-doh\/1100-6534810\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534805&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/dragon-quest-smash-grow-lets-you-smash-enemies-to-grow-your-character\/1100-6534805\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534809&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/canceled-xbox-game-perfect-dark-eulogized-by-top-boss-i-leave-with-nothing-but-pride\/1100-6534809\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534796&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/how-to-make-money-in-skate-and-get-free-rewards\/1100-6534796\/&quot;}]">
            </div>
              
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/new-baldurs-gate-3-hotfix-includes-steam-deck-native-version-of-the-rpg/1100-6534954/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>