<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 11:37:31 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lunar Remastered Collection Review]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/12/lunar-remastered-collection-review/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/lunar-remastered-collection-review.1186737/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/12/lunar-remastered-collection-review/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
			
			<p>The opening cutscene of Lunar Silver Star Story might be the most ‘90s introduction to any game I’ve ever played… and I was alive in the 90s. Presented here in glorious 4:3, and accompanied by Noriyuki Iwadare and Victor Ireland’s track ‘Wings’, it captures a moment in gaming and culture where anime was making inroads into the West, and Japanese developers could push the latest hardware to newfound heights, making this a golden age for JRPGs.</p>
<p>While Sony had sewn up huge franchises like Final Fantasy and Dragon Quest, SEGA still had plenty of clout, and the Saturn – one of my favourite consoles of all time – played host to some amazing JRPGs, with Lunar Silver Star Story sitting at the top of the pile. Admittedly, it later found its way to PlayStations around the world too, but Saturn had it first, alright?</p>
<p><iframe title="LUNAR Remastered Collection | Launch Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/sdhkD6g6NR4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>Lunar Silver Star Story Remastered Collection is, in essence, a remaster of a remake, with the very first Lunar appearing for the Mega CD/Sega CD in 1992, before being remade as Lunar Silver Star Story in 1996. GungHo have pulled together Lunar Silver Star Story and its sequel, and given them a buff and a scrub suitable for modern platforms, bumping the resolution, cleaning up the cutscenes and adding in some welcome quality of life changes that make the games easier to live with nearly two decades after their original release.</p>
<p>The first game follows the adventures of Alex, a young man who dreams of becoming the next Dragonmaster, and who, after encountering the White Dragon Quark, discovers that it might just become a reality. Set on this path, he finds himself facing off against the big-bad Ghaleon, a former hero whose outlook was corrupted after the Goddess Althena decided to give up her power, and become human. As with all the best baddies, he believes that he’s right, willing to turn the world upside down to prove a point.</p>

<p>Alex is initially accompanied on this quest by his cute cat/bird companion Nall, Ramus, a dumpy treasure-obsessed friend, and his lifelong companion, Luna, and you’ll meet various other characters and party members along the way who all cement the fact that Lunar Silver Stary Story is a genuine classic. That’s helped by energetic and committed performances from the entire cast, with the characters truly coming to life across the many hours you’ll spend with them.</p>

<p>Lunar 2: Eternal Blue sees you take on the role of Hiro, an adventurer who finds himself caught up with the mysterious Lucia, aiding her in her quest to meet the returning Goddess Althena. Both stories feel enjoyably old-school – timeless tales that still hold up in the modern age.</p>
<p>Whichever of the games you’re playing, the artwork helps to paint an even clearer picture, and Toshiyuki Kubooka’s character design absolutely shines here thanks to the enhanced resolution and widescreen aspect. I love this classic mid-90s look, and it’s reminiscent of artwork in other games and anime of the era like Guardian Heroes and Neon Genesis Evangelion.</p>
<p>Both games effectively mix animated cutscenes, pre-rendered backgrounds and pixel-art, and it’s just such an alluring combination. It’s not as spectacular perhaps as <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/11/13/dragon-quest-iii-hd-2d-remake-review/">Dragon Quest HD-2D</a>, or modern takes on the genre like <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2018/07/26/octopath-traveler-review/">Octopath Traveller</a>, but it’s great looking, and the visuals help carry the story along perfectly.</p>

<p>The main action is resolutely turn-based, but there are a few surprises to the way that combat plays out, not least the necessity to choose how your team is positioned, and which enemies they can attack based upon that. It adds a spot more thought to each action, and some surprises along the way when things don’t quite play out as you were expecting. There’s also an auto-battle mode, which would have been trendsetting at the time, and is still a real boon when you’re making your way through dungeons and facing off against low-level mobs.</p>
<p>The key new addition is the ability to alter the battle speed, and alongside the auto-battler function it makes grinding and exploring feel so much less of a chore than it can do in these old-school RPGs. I wish that all RPGs were so considerate of your time!</p>
<p>If you’re a purist who’s looking to play both of the games as they were originally intended, it’s great to find that both the original and the remastered versions have been included here. However, with the reduced resolution and bars either side of the screen, it feels like there’s little to no reason to do this, other than pure curiosity. It would have been nice to be able to switch between the two versions mid-game, but you have to start them separately from the main menu.</p>

<p>There are a few old-school foibles to deal with – whether its tricky route-finding through dungeons, having to work your way back through the same areas, or the constant ‘La La La Laaaaaaa’ of Luna’s magical healing song in the first game, but they’re minor annoyances that you can forgive given the age of the originals.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Virtua Fighter 5 REVO confirmed for console and it'll be "more than a simple port"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/virtua-fighter-5-revo-confirmed-for-console-and-itll-be-more-than-a-simple-port</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/virtua-fighter-5-revo-confirmed-for-console-and-itll-be-more-than-a-simple-port.1186731/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/virtua-fighter-5-revo-confirmed-for-console-and-itll-be-more-than-a-simple-port<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
<a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/virtua-fighter-5">Virtua Fighter 5</a> REVO, the latest edition of Sega's nearly 19-year-old fighting sequel, is heading to PS5, Xbox Series X/S, and <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/switch-2-nintendo-direct-everything-announced">Switch 2</a> following its <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/virtua-fighter-is-making-its-3d-pc-debut-this-winter-including-rollback-netcode">PC debut earlier this year</a>.
</p>
<p>
For those who haven't been following Virtua Fighter 5's convoluted journey over the last two decades, REVO is a remaster of <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/virtua-fighter-5-ultimate-showdown">Virtua Fighter 5 Ultimate Showdown</a>, which initially launched for PS4 in 2021. That, in turn, was a remaster of the game's supposedly final revision, Virtua Fighter 5 Final Showdown, which arrived on PS3 and Xbox 360 in 2012.
</p>
<p>
As to how Virtua Fighter 5 REVO differentiates itself from the series' most recent revision, the PC version introduced 4K graphics, high-res textures, rollback netcode support to optimise online play, and new online modes enabling competition with up to 16 other players.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Virtua Fighter 5 R.E.V.O | Launch Trailer" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wKDD80JCv_o?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Virtua Fighter 5 R.E.V.O | Launch Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wKDD80JCv_o?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/wKDD80JCv_o?autoplay=1" title="Virtua Fighter 5 R.E.V.O | Launch Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Here's how Virtua Fighter 5 REVO looked on PC.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wKDD80JCv_o" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
Presumably, Sega's newly announced console editions will be similarly enhanced, but the publisher is yet to provide specific details beyond the fact cross-play will be supported, and there's no word of a release window either. "We're going to include even more content to make this much more than a simple port," it adds, "which we'll tell you about in future updates."
</p>
<p>
News of Virtua Fighter 5 REVO's console release comes after last year's confirmation a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/sega-unveils-new-virtua-fighter-sonic-racing-and-like-a-dragon">brand-new entry in the much-loved fighting series is on the way</a>. That reveal was followed by <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/first-in-engine-look-at-next-virtua-fighter-game-revealed">first in-engine footage</a> back in January, and Sega has now released a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NnyE4tsQ3w8">similarly styled teaser</a> showcasing returning character Wolf Hawkfield. Sega's new <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/virtua-fighter">Virtua Fighter</a> project is part of the initiative announced in 2023, which will <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/sega-announces-flurry-of-projects-including-jet-set-radio-crazy-taxi">see it revisiting a number of its previously dormant classic properties</a>, including  <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/crazy-taxi">Crazy Taxi</a>, Jet Set Radio, Streets of Rage, and Shinobi.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Last of Us Part 2 online backlash prompted Naughty Dog's next star to get "bootcamp-ing" from Neil Druckmann]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/the-last-of-us-part-2-online-backlash-prompted-naughty-dogs-next-star-to-get-bootcamp-ing-from-neil-druckmann</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-last-of-us-part-2-online-backlash-prompted-naughty-dogs-next-star-to-get-bootcamp-ing-from-neil-druckmann.1186725/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/the-last-of-us-part-2-online-backlash-prompted-naughty-dogs-next-star-to-get-bootcamp-ing-from-neil-druckmann<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>"I got a lot of love, but there was a lot of hate."</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Naughty Dog</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>The star of <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/companies/naughty-dog">Naughty Dog</a>'s next game has said she's received preparation for the role - and specifically the online reaction to it - from studio boss Neil Druckmann, following the online abuse previously kicked up around The Last of Us Part 2.</p>
<p>Actress Tati Gabrielle will star as bounty hunter Jordan A Mun in Intergalactic: The Heretic Prophet, Naughty Dog's upcoming sci-fi project for PlayStation 5. While Gabrielle has worked close to video games before - on PlayStation's Uncharted film adaptation and as Nora in The Last of Us' TV series - this will be her first video game role.</p>
<p>In preparation, Gabrielle said she had been given mental "bootcamp-ing" by Druckmann, as she becomes the face of the game.</p>
<p><strong>Please be aware of spoilers for The Last of Us Part 2 below. </strong></p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="The Death of Console Exclusives Is Inevitable and I Don't Know How I Feel About It" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ipoW24t90fw?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>The Death of Console Exclusives Is Inevitable and I Don't Know How I Feel About It</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ipoW24t90fw?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/ipoW24t90fw?autoplay=1" title="The Death of Console Exclusives Is Inevitable and I Don't Know How I Feel About It">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>The Death of Console Exclusives Is Inevitable and I Don't Know How I Feel About It. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ipoW24t90fw" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>"Neil's been bootcamp-ing me. I know Troy [Baker]'s experience, I know Ashley [Johnson]'s experience..." Gabrielle told <a href="https://ew.com/tati-gabrielle-of-the-last-of-us-about-to-go-intergalactic-exclusive-11732492">EW</a>.</p>
<p>"I know Laura Bailey's experience," Gabrielle continued, referring to the backlash Bailey received for her turn as The Last of Us Part 2's Abby.</p>
<p>Prior to The Last of Us Part 2's release, Abby's role as the character that kills Joel was leaked, sparking a wave of online abuse and death threats aimed at Bailey and her son. "Every time I went online, that's all I saw," Bailey revealed previously as part of the game's <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-last-of-us-part-2s-abby-actor-reveals-online-abuse-didnt-just-threaten-her-life-but-her-baby-son-too">behind-the-scenes documentary, Grounded 2: Making The Last of Us Part 2</a>, which was released in February last year. "Death threats and threats of violence."</p>
<p>Gabrielle revealed that, like Bailey, she too has been the subject of backlash since it was announced she would star in Intergalactic: The Heretic Prophet. Already, she has had misogynistic and racist comments sent her way.</p>
<p>"I got a lot of love, but there was a lot of hate over me being a woman, me being a woman of colour, me having my head shaved, all these things that I didn't even actually initially see," Gabrielle said. "I'm out of the social media zeitgeist for that reason - but once I did, Neil [Druckmann] was like, 'Ignore it. No matter what, me and you, we're going to make something beautiful. We're going to make something that we're proud of'."</p>
<figure>

<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Naughty Dog</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>The actress also spoke more about the upcoming game's theme of faith. Back in March of this year, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/after-the-hate-directed-at-the-last-of-us-part-2-naughty-dog-boss-says-next-game-about-the-entirely-uncontroversial-topics-of-faith-and-religion">Druckmann explained how Intergalactic: The Heretic Prophet features a fictitious religion</a> which "becomes pretty prominent" in the game's alternate history.</p>
<p>"The question of faith is not black and white," Gabrielle elaborated. "When you initially think of faith, you think of religion, which is a part of it, but there's also faith in oneself. There's faith in your environment or your community. All that faith means is, What are your beliefs?</p>
<p>"What are the things that you hope for? Faith sounds flowery, but we all experience it day in and day out. What is your reason for waking up?"</p>
<p>Intergalactic: The Heretic Prophet is in development for PS5. Last year, Druckmann confirmed <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/naughty-dog-will-not-be-the-last-of-us-studio-forever-neil-druckmann-says">Naughty Dog had a number of games in the works</a>, including "multiple single-player projects", this being one of them.</p>
<p>Elsewhere in studio news, Naughty Dog and HBO have <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/theres-something-in-the-air-as-ellie-sees-red-in-the-last-of-us-season-2-episode-five">just aired the fifth episode of The Last of Us season two</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Oblivion Remastered Gets First Stunning 8K Texture Pack From the Creator of The Witcher 3 HD Reworked Project]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/oblivion-remastered-8k-texture-packs/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/oblivion-remastered-gets-first-stunning-8k-texture-pack-from-the-creator-of-the-witcher-3-hd-reworked-project.1186719/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/oblivion-remastered-8k-texture-packs/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The creator of the amazing <a href="https://wccftech.com/the-witcher-3-hd-reworked-project-nextgen-edition-is-finally-out-now/">The Witcher 3 HD Reworked Project</a>, which was so good even in its first few versions that it was officially implemented in the next-gen version, released some stunning texture packs for The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion Remastered.</p>
<p>The first of these packs created by Halk Hogan PL is the<a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/oblivionremastered/mods/1614?tab=images" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> Ultra Quality 8K Body Textures - Imperials</a> pack, which comes in different resolution options, including 8K diffuse with the best quality, improves body details and quality, makes skin color more natural, and is more suitable for all Imperial characters. The results are excellent, as highlighted in the comparison screenshots on <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/oblivionremastered/mods/1614?tab=images">Nexus Mods</a>.</p>
<p>As mentioned in the description of the texture pack above found on Nexus Mods, the Ultra Quality 8K Body Textures pack is best used with the <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/oblivionremastered/mods/1284">Realistic High Quality Skin pack</a>, which improves human skin and makes it more realistic for all the races found in Oblivion Remastered, except for Argonians and Khajiits. This texture pack also slightly improves face details.</p>
<p>The third Oblivion Remastered texture pack shared by Halk Hogan PL is the <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/oblivionremastered/mods/2522?tab=description">Smooth Beautiful Faces pack</a>, which introduces impressive face textures that are a significant improvement over the vanilla textures. Among the improvements the new textures bring are more detailed lips, high-quality eyebrows, and more. Despite the new textures working best for female characters with the youngest possible age of the character creator, they still improve the faces of characters of all ages.</p>
<p>The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion Remastered is now available on PC, PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X, and Xbox Series S worldwide. You can learn more about the remaster developed by Virtuos by checking out my<a href="https://wccftech.com/review/the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-remastered-back-in-cyrodiil-19-years-later/"> review.</a></p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tony Hawk's Underground remaster hopes increase as iconic skater says he'll "campaign all I can"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/tony-hawks-underground-remaster-hopes-increase-as-iconic-skater-says-hell-campaign-all-i-can</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/tony-hawks-underground-remaster-hopes-increase-as-iconic-skater-says-hell-campaign-all-i-can.1186716/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/tony-hawks-underground-remaster-hopes-increase-as-iconic-skater-says-hell-campaign-all-i-can<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Ahead of <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/tony-hawks-pro-skater-3-4">Tony Hawk's Pro Skater 3+4</a>, the skating icon has said he has "aspirations" for further remakes, including one for the popular <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/tony-hawks-underground">Tony Hawk's Underground</a>.
</p>
<p>
Speaking to <a href="https://screenrant.com/tony-hawks-underground-remake-campaign/">Screen Rant</a>, Hawk said the decision to continue remaking older games ultimately rested with the company he worked with - that'd be publisher Activision, and ultimately its owner Microsoft - but that he would "campaign all I can".
</p>
<p>
Still, Hawk's wishes appear to hold at least some sway - such as with the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/bam-margera-officially-returning-to-tony-hawks-pro-skater-3-4">seemingly last-minute restoration of skater Bam Margera to the roster of Tony Hawk's Pro Skater 3+4</a>.
</p>
<p>
"I always have aspirations," Hawk said on the possibility of Underground being remastered next. "It's not up to me generally. I'll campaign all I can, but I'm working with a much bigger company that's a lot smarter than me."
</p>
<p>
Asked if a decision on Underground was too early, before the launch of Pro Skater 3+4, Hawk added: "Yeah, we haven't even released this game."
</p>
<p>
Activision had looked ready not to continue the Tony Hawk's series at all, despite a positive reception to Pro Skater 1+2 when it arrived back in 2020. Its developer, Vicarious Visions, was later shuffled over to become part of Blizzard, and the future of Hawk's skating series put on ice. 
</p>
<p>
But teases from Hawk himself last year of talks between himself and Activision ultimately resulted in a reversal of fortunes. Earlier this year, Activision began teasing a Pro Skater 3+4 remake within Call of Duty, before making the project official on 4th March.
</p>
<p>
Tony Hawk's Pro Skater 3+4 will launch on 11th July for Nintendo Switch and <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/switch-2-nintendo-direct-everything-announced">Switch 2</a>, PC, PlayStation 4, PS5, Xbox One and Xbox Series X/S including through Game Pass Ultimate.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Grow a Garden Codes (May 2025)]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/grow-a-garden-codes-may-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/grow-a-garden-codes-may-2025.1186707/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/grow-a-garden-codes-may-2025<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">The Lunar Glow update for Grow a Garden finally saw the addition of a code redemption system, and the Roblox experience's first reward code was released. This big change means it's likely there will be more codes released in the future, so IGN will keep you covered with all your Grow a Garden code needs!</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Working Grow a Garden Codes</h2><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>LUNARGLOW10</strong> - 3 Basic Seed Packs <strong>(NEW)</strong></li></ul><h2 data-cy="title2">Expired Grow a Garden Codes</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Because codes were just added in the latest Lunar Glow update, there are <strong>no expired Grow a Garden codes</strong> for now! Be sure to make the most of the working codes, so you don't miss out on extra seed packs.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">How to Redeem Grow a Garden Codes</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/05/12/grow-a-garden-codes-1747041583655.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Now that there's a code redemption system in the Roblox experience, here are the steps you need to follow to use Grow a Garden codes:</p><ol data-cy="list"><li>Launch the Grow a Garden Roblox experience</li><li>Look in the<strong> top left corner to find the Settings cog </strong>next to the icon of the backpack</li><li>Click settings and scroll down to the bottom</li><li>Copy and paste codes from this article into the Redeem Codes box</li><li>Press claim and enjoy your goodies!</li></ol><h2 data-cy="title2">Why Isn't My Grow a Garden Code Working?</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">There are usually two reasons why a code isn't working. It's either because:</p><ul data-cy="list"><li>The code is expired</li><li>The code has been entered incorrectly</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph">If a code has been entered incorrectly or is expired, it will say the "code is invalid." To stop this from happening, we'd recommend <strong>copying and pasting the code directly from this article</strong>. We check and test each of the codes before we add them to our articles. However, when copying them, you can sometimes accidentally include an extra space somwhere, so always double check there's no additional spaces!</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Where to Find More Grow a Garden Codes</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">If new codes are added to the game, we'll update this article, so you can always check back here and keep up-to-date with the latest codes. Grow a Garden has its own <a href="https://discord.com/invite/gwQvzBS3Ea" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">dedicated Discord server</a> where codes will be announced, as well as game updates.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">What is Grow a Garden in Roblox?</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Grow a Garden is a new Roblox experience that's becoming incredibly popular since it launched. The gardening simulator allows players to show off their green fingers, as you buy seeds and plant a variety of crops from basic carrots to exotic dragon fruit trees.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As fruit and vegetables finally sprout, you'll be able to harvest them to sell for Sheckles. To go from a beginner gardener to a pro worthy of awards, you'll want your crops to experience mutations that increase their value. This can happen randomly, with Gold and Big mutations being down to chance, while weather events like snow can increase your luck of a Frozen mutation. There's also gear, and even pets now, that can affect how fast your crops grow, their value, and more. </p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Lauren Harper is an Associate Guides Editor. She loves a variety of games but is especially fond of puzzles, horrors, and point-and-click adventures.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine 2 Dev Opens Game Up to Modders, Who Now Plan to Add Tau and Necrons and a Whole Lot More — but first... a Fishing Mini-]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/warhammer-40000-space-marine-2-dev-opens-game-up-to-modders-who-now-plan-to-add-tau-and-necrons-and-a-whole-lot-more-but-first-a-fishing-mini-game</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/warhammer-40-000-space-marine-2-dev-opens-game-up-to-modders-who-now-plan-to-add-tau-and-necrons-and-a-whole-lot-more-%E2%80%94-but-first-a-fishing-mini.1186704/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/warhammer-40000-space-marine-2-dev-opens-game-up-to-modders-who-now-plan-to-add-tau-and-necrons-and-a-whole-lot-more-but-first-a-fishing-mini-game<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Warped expectations.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/warhammer-40000-space-marine-ii">Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine 2</a> fans are rejoicing after the developer handed modders the keys to its internal editor, sparking hope it could ‘do a Skyrim’ and last for years with user-generated content.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Game director Dmitry Grigorenko took to the Space Marine 2 modding Discord to announce what he described as “our biggest milestone yet in supporting the modding community.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Developer Saber Interactive has released the official Integration Studio for public use. This is the same editor the developers use internally for all gameplay development. This first release lets modders work with everything from level scenarios to game modes, tinker with AI behavior, abilities and melee combo logic, user interface and HUD elements, and make much of the general modding work with Space Marine 2 faster and easier.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Not long ago, I promised we would support the modding scene — and we meant it,” Grigorenko said. “Watching this community grow, push boundaries, and create incredible experiences has been both inspiring and humbling. We’re excited to see what you build next — whether it’s a cinematic campaign, wild new game mode, or something we never saw coming.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">To get the ball rolling, Grigorenko released jokey concept art for a "Fishing With Daddy Calgar" mini-game, below, which is technically possible now with these tools. Calgar is Marneus Calgar, the leader of the Ultramarines chapter of Space Marines.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/05/11/fishing-1746999241862.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">The race is on to create Space Marine 2's first fishing mini-game mod. Image credit: Saber Interactive / Discord.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">To find out what the Space Marine 2 modding community plans to do with this editor, I had a quick chat with Tom, aka <a href="https://ko-fi.com/warhammerworkshop" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Warhammer Workshop</u></a>, the modder behind <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/massive-warhammer-40000-space-marine-2-mod-adds-lore-accurate-classes-a-weapon-previously-locked-to-campaign-and-even-new-operations"><u>Space Marine 2’s excellent Astartes Overhaul</u></a>. Fresh from releasing <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/warhammer-40000-space-marine-2-modders-create-12-player-co-op-with-the-developers-blessing-and-now-theyre-working-on-raid-style-missions-with-bosses-that-hit-like-trucks">a mod that enables 12-player co-op in Space Marine 2</a>, Tom told me that he now has access to all the scripting tools that control what happens in any particular mission, as well as for all the different game components like weapons and abilities.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">This means modders could, for example, create a Space Marine 2 roguelite mode where modders spawn in one of the swarm sequences from the campaign with nothing but a combat knife, and progressively spawn bigger and tougher enemies, with percentage chances to spawn weapons, ammo, and health on death. “Killing a Carnifex might grant you a Heavy Bolter,” Tom suggested.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As for a brand new cinematic campaign, Tom said that while a Chaos campaign would “definitely” be doable, cutscenes are trickier because modders so far do not have access to the animation tools necessary.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">However, Tom is currently planning on adding new factions to Space Marine 2, including the Tau and Necrons, as the modders have the rigs that will fit those. Meanwhile, the Space Marine 2 modding community is racing to actually make the Fishing With Daddy Calgar mini-game mod Grigorenko challenged them to.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Reaction from Space Marine 2 fans is hugely positive, and with good reason. While Space Marine 2 is well-received and has gone down as one of the best-selling Warhammer video games of all time, it is relatively limited in terms of its official offering. That is to say, it contains three factions only: Space Marines, Chaos (a mix of Chaos Marines and some Tzeentch Daemons), and the Tyrannids. Players had hoped for DLC that might extend the faction roster (the Space Marine 2 campaign teased the Necrons), but can now take matters into their own hands.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“This is how you keep a game alive for years like Skyrim,” <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Spacemarine/comments/1kjgnix/comment/mrn2sq9/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">said redditor Mortwight</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s a particularly interesting development in the context of Saber and publisher Focus Entertainment’s announcement that <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/warhammer-40000-space-marine-3-announced-development-officially-begins-at-saber-interactive">Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine 3 is in development</a>. Some Space Marine 2 fans have expressed concern about what this means for potential DLC, although <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/warhammer-40000-space-marine-2-dev-moves-to-set-the-record-straight-insists-its-not-abandoning-the-game-following-space-marine-3-announcement">both Saber and Focus have insisted they’re not abandoning the game</a>. Still, Space Marine 2 is in a much better position now modders have the editor in hand.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Grand Theft Auto 6 delay is causing emergency meetings at other studios]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/grand-theft-auto-6-delay-is-causing-emergency-meetings-at-other-studios</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/grand-theft-auto-6-delay-is-causing-emergency-meetings-at-other-studios.1186701/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/grand-theft-auto-6-delay-is-causing-emergency-meetings-at-other-studios<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Take-Two Interactive</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>I want <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/grand-theft-auto-vi">Grand Theft Auto 6</a> to be good, and if I had to bet money on it, I'd guess it likely will be. The world is weird right now, and I want both you and me to enjoy driving a car into a man. It very much sounds like it's got Stephen Root from Barry in it! I love Stephen Root from Barry!</p>
<p>But, god, am I feeling some kind of way about it constantly sucking all the air out of the room. It feels less like we're looking forward to a game, more that we're in thrall to a captor that knows it can command attention whether it earns it or not. ( I do not believe <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/red-dead-redemption-2">Red Dead Redemption 2</a>'s excellence earns uncritical hype for all future projects, lest we forget Cyberpunk). There's plenty that <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-anti-heroes-of-grand-theft-auto-6-look-sexy-and-dull">can be said about the recent trailer</a>, but if I had to sum up my own misgivings with it, it's that it has an air less of "look at this cool thing we made, we can't wait to share it with you", more dick-swinging swagger, a cocksure sense of, well, you're going to buy this anyway, here's some absurdly good-looking beer to tide you piggies over.</p>
<!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Grand Theft Auto VI Trailer 2" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/VQRLujxTm3c?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Grand Theft Auto VI Trailer 2</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/VQRLujxTm3c?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/VQRLujxTm3c?autoplay=1" title="Grand Theft Auto VI Trailer 2">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VQRLujxTm3c" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>Anyway, the latest news - via a <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/newsletters/2025-05-09/-grand-theft-auto-vi-delay-is-impacting-every-game-company">Bloomberg report</a> entitled ‘<a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/grand-theft-auto">Grand Theft Auto</a> VI delay impacts every game company' - is that after already having caused various studios to scramble to change release dates, the fresh delay has now caused another round of lighting the panic beacons, and studios are now holding emergency meetings. Here's Bloomberg on a developer that had already delayed their game once to get out of GTA 6's drive-by firing line:</p>
<blockquote><p>"Now they’re caught in a vise. Delaying their game a second time would be an expensive endeavor, ratcheting up the stakes for the eventual release. Then again, trying to come out alongside GTA VI could be catastrophic. But…what if they delay again and then GTA VI slips along with them? There’s no guarantee that May 2026 is a sure thing. The best hope might be to release in March, April or even early May, and hope it’s not disastrous."</p></blockquote>
<p>Bloomberg does suggest that big competition like GTA 6 might not actually have this smothering effect on smaller titles, but the example given is that a single game - the very good <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/clair-obscur-expedition-33">Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</a> - still sold a bunch of copies despite its release coinciding with the Oblivion Remaster. There's no mention of games like<a href="https://x.com/jantonsson2/status/1915115694641090749"> Post Trauma getting "buried"</a> in Oblivion's wake, to the point where the publisher feels <a href="https://x.com/RawFury/status/1915784451440681375">they need to re-release the game</a>. 

</p><p>Unlike Oblivion's shadow drop, Rockstar have at least given a solid date. These things happen. But I still feel strange about the amount of tumult this as all caused. I actually feel like series devotees are getting off on this cultural dominance, too - red meat eatin', survival-of-the-fittest, my dad can beat up all your dads style. The sports-team-ifaction of game enjoying is not a new phenomena, but it is one that feels like it's <a href="https://www.readergrev.com/p/marathon-switch-2-very-serious-business-analysis">reaching critical mass</a> to the point where unaffiliated commentators gloating over sales figures can seem more prevalent than actual thoughts about what an actual game is actually like to play. Glory by osmosis? I dunno.</p>
<p>A lot of popular things are popular because they're very bloody good! But there has to a happy medium somewhere, right? The place between stilted water cooler conversations with baffled acquaintances each siloed off into their own niches, and this sort of behemothic, inescapable monoculture? Even if you bloody love a bit of rampant, unchecked capitalism, surely that's built on the foundation that competition is good for creativity? But GTA 6 is so absurdly massive, its dominance so assured, that it leaves no room for competition from the bottom up. It can only terraform and crush would-be hopefuls to dust and drippings from the top down.</p>
<p>There's a decent glug of selfish umbrage in all this, of course. Any non-independent games website is all but forced to report on any new happenings with GTA 6 whether we find them interesting or not, assuming we value our own survival. It all leaves me reminded that any sense of Rockstar being in any way countercultural is surely an ancient, unfunny joke by this point. If it walks and talks and acts like the man, it's the man, and to quote Hatsune Miku, no one man should have all that power.</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Switch 2's mouse controls usable in the Home menu]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/switch-2s-mouse-controls-usable-in-the-home-menu</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/switch-2s-mouse-controls-usable-in-the-home-menu.1186683/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/switch-2s-mouse-controls-usable-in-the-home-menu<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/switch-2-nintendo-direct-everything-announced">Switch 2</a>'s mouse controls will be usable in the console's Home menu.</p>
<p>As shared in the Nintendo Today app, mouse controls won't just be for in-game but for navigating menus - there's a video of it in action too.</p>
<p>What's more, just like in <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/metroid-prime-4">Metroid Prime 4</a>, users simply place the Joy-Con 2 sideways on any surface to switch to mouse mode, then pick it up again to revert to the control sticks.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Nintendo Switch 2 Hands-On Preview: Mario Kart World Impressions &amp; More!" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9CF8nQGolWY?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Nintendo Switch 2 Hands-On Preview: Mario Kart World Impressions &amp; More!</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9CF8nQGolWY?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/9CF8nQGolWY?autoplay=1" title="Nintendo Switch 2 Hands-On Preview: Mario Kart World Impressions &amp; More!">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Nintendo Switch 2 Hands-On Preview: Mario Kart World Impressions &amp; More!<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9CF8nQGolWY" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>The video in the app shows the Home menu will be the same as the original Switch, now with options selectable via cursor.</p>
<p>You can see the video below:</p>
<div>

<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>

<p>Mouse controls are one of the Switch 2's new innovative features, allowing both Joy-Con 2 to be flipped and moved along any surface - be that your coffee table, your desk, or your thighs.</p>
<p>Nintendo is even releasing a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/switch-2s-first-dual-mouse-mode-game-is-wheelchair-basketball-drag-x-drive">dual-mouse mode game in Drag x Drive</a> - it's 3 v 3 wheelchair basketball, though with its awkward controls it feels like more of a tech demo.</p>
<figure>

<figcaption>Nintendo Today | <span>Image credit: <cite>Nintendo</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Instead, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/metroid-prime-4-is-the-best-example-of-switch-2s-varied-control-capabilities-but-you-might-want-to-work-on-your-thighs">Metroid Prime 4: Beyond feels like the best example of the varied control schemes of the Switch 2</a>.</p>
<p>The first-person adventure will allow players to either use traditional stick controls, motion controls, or mouse controls. I tested this out at the Switch 2 reveal event and found the mouse controls surprisingly responsive, though I'm not convinced it will be the best way to play - it depends on the surface area of your thighs.</p>
<p>The <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-switch-2-edition-upgrade-prices-for-kirby-and-mario-party-cost-more-than-zelda">expanded Mario Party Jamboree on Switch 2</a> will also include new minigames to show off the mouse functionality.</p>
<p>Nintendo's Switch 2 will launch on 5th June, with <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/mario-kart-world-reinvents-the-series-and-feels-like-switch-2s-killer-app-after-an-hour-of-hands-on-play">Mario Kart World as its big launch game</a>. Nintendo recently <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-responds-to-suggestion-that-ai-generated-images-used-in-mario-kart-world">confirmed it does not include AI art</a>.</p>
<p>Last week, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-reserves-the-right-to-brick-your-console-following-unauthorised-use-in-bid-to-prevent-piracy">Nintendo updated its Account Agreement with a severe warning against "unauthorised use"</a> to prevent piracy.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Death Stranding 2 Could Last Nearly Twice as Much as the Original, Has More Combat Because People Ask Kojima for MGS]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/death-stranding-2-could-last-nearly-twice-as-much-as-the-original-has-more-combat-because-people-ask-kojima-for-mgs/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/death-stranding-2-could-last-nearly-twice-as-much-as-the-original-has-more-combat-because-people-ask-kojima-for-mgs.1186677/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/death-stranding-2-could-last-nearly-twice-as-much-as-the-original-has-more-combat-because-people-ask-kojima-for-mgs/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Death Stranding 2: On the Beach will be a much larger game than the original. The news came <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-big-death-stranding-2-preview-how-a-big-dollop-of-metal-gear-is-expanding-kojimas-bizarre-epic" target="_blank" rel="noopener">from Eurogamer</a>, which recently had the chance to play around 30 hours of the game at Kojima Productions headquarters and relayed the info that this constitutes roughly 40% of the story. This means the game could last as much as 75 hours, nearly double the average playtime of the previous installment (40 hours).</p>
<p>It's not too surprising when you consider that the first game was the debut project of a brand new studio. While it had Sony's support, it was still a new IP from a new team, albeit led by a world-famous game designer. Following the <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/death-stranding-directors-cut-ill-keep-coming/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">first game's successful release</a> (Kojima Productions revealed last month that the game had reached 20 million players to date, although that counts players who checked out the game via their subscription services), Death Stranding 2: On the Beach is going the classic way of bigger and better, albeit still with Kojima's unique twist.</p>
<p>One of the changes from the original will be the increased combat options. Kojima said that this was partly because of people asking him to make another Metal Gear title:</p>
<p><em>There are so many people all over the world asking me to make another Metal Gear, so I added more options for combat. When I was working out those mechanics, I was a little worried because many of the staff that worked with me on Metal Gear still work here, and we kept saying to each other, 'Does this feel too much like Metal Gear?' It wasn't on purpose.</em></p>
<p>As a side note, the sequel will include some unreleased songs by the late Ryan Karazija, founder and lead vocalist of Low Roar. Kojima said he was contacted by Karazija's family, who told him that the singer wished for these songs to be included in the new game (his work was heavily featured in the previous Death Stranding).</p>
<p>Death Stranding 2: On the Beach will be released <a href="https://wccftech.com/death-stranding-2-on-the-beach-launches-on-june-26-pre-orders-begin-soon/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">on June 26</a>, along with a new <a href="https://wccftech.com/death-stranding-2-provides-players-with-more-choices-and-freedom-says-kojima-limited-edition-dualsense-controller-announced/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">limited-edition DualSense controller</a>. The game will initially be available for Sony's PlayStation 5; however, given that Kojima Productions has purchased back the publishing rights from Sony, it's fair to expect the game to launch on PC and Xbox (like the original) in the not-too-distant future.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ori Developer Moon Studios Is Not Actually in Immediate Trouble, Says CEO]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/ori-developer-moon-studios-is-not-actually-in-immediate-trouble-says-ceo/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ori-developer-moon-studios-is-not-actually-in-immediate-trouble-says-ceo.1186671/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/ori-developer-moon-studios-is-not-actually-in-immediate-trouble-says-ceo/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Vienna-based Ori developer Moon Studios is not actually in trouble, <a href="https://x.com/thomasmahler/status/1921646282726138116" target="_blank" rel="noopener">according to its own founder and CEO, Thomas Mahler</a>.</p>
<p>On the developer's Discord, Mahler had told fans in no uncertain terms that they need their help to survive and complete No Rest for the Wicked. The studio's latest game, a top-down action RPG, debuted around a year ago on Steam Early Access and just <a href="https://wccftech.com/no-rest-for-the-wicked-breach-update-adds-nvidia-dlss-4-and-lots-of-content/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">received</a> a large update. However, the player numbers aren't that great, and neither are the user reviews (72% for the recent ones, 74% overall), with the latter leading to the former. Mahler claimed (as first <a href="https://www.gamereactor.eu/ori-studio-in-crisis-no-rest-for-the-wicked-could-be-their-final-game-1541163/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reported</a> by Gamereactor) that Moon Studios is the victim of 'review bombing' and asked true fans to help counterbalance the phenomenon with their own reviews of No Rest for the Wicked.</p>
<p><em>I think people think I'm joking when I'm asking for positive reviews cause in people's mind there's always some big publisher in the background who'll cover costs...</em></p>
<p><em>Folks, if you're writing here and are enjoying Wicked and are excited for future updates, but haven't left a positive review, it's entirely possible that we won't be around in a couple of months to do anything anymore simply because we got review bombed which leads to people not buying the game. Which means we're not making any money and will have to shut down.</em></p>
<p><em>I wouldn't ask if our business wouldn't be dependent on it. I also never write reviews on anything, but if you want to see us actually finish Wicked, it's detrimental that we get that review score back up.</em></p>
<p>Indeed, Mahler is absolutely correct that they do not have a publisher's backing anymore. While Private Division originally published No Rest for the Wicked, Moon Studios <a href="https://wccftech.com/no-rest-for-the-wicked-gets-new-major-update-moon-studios-purchases-publishing-rights-back/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">repurchased the rights a couple of months ago</a>. As you might recall, Take-Two <a href="https://wccftech.com/former-annapurna-staff-form-new-company-to-inherit-private-division-franchises/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">sold Private Division</a> to a new company managed by former Annapurna Interactive staff members.</p>
<p>However, a few hours ago, Mahler suggested that the press had misinterpreted his original statement. Here's what he wrote on X:</p>
<p><em>Overall, pretty much everyone who’s tried Wicked after the last few hotfixes is extremely positive. The reason I left the post on Discord up was simply to push back against some of the bullshit reviews. I have no issue telling active players who love Wicked that they should go ahead and leave a positive review on Steam. After all, it’s allowed on Steam to buy a game, leave a negative review that doesn’t even talk about the game at all (there are negative Wicked reviews that literally just say '.'), and then instantly refund it… and the negative review still counts.</em></p>
<p><em>If that’s allowed, then it should also be allowed for a developer to encourage their players to share their real experiences. And no, we’re not in immediate financial danger—but from time to time, I think I’m allowed to speak up about issues within our industry I personally find unbecoming.</em></p>
<p><em>We are continuing as always—our goal is for every game Moon Studios creates to be an absolute masterpiece, and with Wicked we’re already on the way.</em></p>
<p>It would be a shame to see Moon Studios close down, that's for sure. The Ori games were stellar, and No Rest for the Wicked also has 'extreme' potential, as noted by Francesco De Meo <a href="https://wccftech.com/no-rest-for-the-wicked-early-access-hands-on-extreme-potential/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">in our early access preview</a>.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Please start making special editions like the Hitchhiker's Guide To The Galaxy again]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/please-start-making-special-editions-like-the-hitchhikers-guide-to-the-galaxy-again</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/please-start-making-special-editions-like-the-hitchhikers-guide-to-the-galaxy-again.1186668/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/please-start-making-special-editions-like-the-hitchhikers-guide-to-the-galaxy-again<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Drink up, the world's about to end</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>filfre.net</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>I started writing this piece as a sort of "oh, this was cool!" bit of game archaeology after seeing a post from Scott Krol - who shares consistently fascinating bits of ephemera on video and tabletop games - on the physical bits that came with 1984's The Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy adventure game.</p>
<p>"Infocom, known for their brilliant text adventures, was the first company to put physical items in with their games," <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/scottrkrol_limited-run-games-just-announced-a-physical-activity-7318076800683708416-wel_">writes Scott</a>. "In fact, Infocom were attributed as the first to coin the term “feelies” for physical goodies that came with the game".</p>
<!--more-->
<p>That's two great facts for the price of none, that is. The actual bits were excellent too: I'm still not tired of packets that contain absolutely nothing but a label saying there's something invisible or imperceivable inside. If there's more fun you can have with the contents of a cheap plastic baggy I don't want to know about it. You can read more about <a href="https://www.filfre.net/2013/11/hitchhiking-the-galaxy-infocom-style/">them here</a>.</p>
<p>I say I <em>started </em>writing this piece as that, because I actually found something better along the way, hanging in RPS archives in much the way that bricks don't. <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/hitchhikers-guide-text-adventure-review">Victoria Regan's edition of 'gaming made me'</a> on Infocom's Hitchhiker's Guide adventure game. It's a beautiful piece for many reasons, but two stood out to me especially.</p>
<p>First, Regan's characterisation of human dressing gown Arthur Dent made me appreciate the story's cosmically put-upon protagonist in ways I'm not sure I have before. "His willingness to lie down in the path of an oncoming bulldozer showed courage in the face of randomness," Regan writes, admiring his "stoical response to a sea of surprising events". I wouldn't have used the word stoic or even courageous because I've had the Simon Jones television portrayal of Dent stuck in my head for most of my memory-having life, screaming about jumping up and down on boiled bits of councilmen and threatening to lose his lunch every twenty minutes.</p>
<p>But you know what? I'll buy it. Given Arthur's circumstances, anything north of not just laying on the floor shaking is effectively heroism. I actually really like this framing of the entire story as a battle between Dent's sense of himself as respectable Englishman vs. all the incomprehensible nonsense a vast and futile universe can throw at him.</p>
<p>But my favourite part of Regan's piece is her description of her and her brother's motivation to keep struggling through a famously obtuse adventure game as "the urge to find out what was hidden", a vanishingly precious feeling in an age of games that are not only laid bare moments after release,but also pre-mythologised - by advertising hype campaigns, and also the contemporary incarnation of these same goody-laden game editions - to the point where our own unique personal experiences are all but denied to us, smothered by expectation and iconography (I am not allowed to decide who the Doom Slayer is, this £200 statue has done my thinking for me.)</p>
<p>Most tat is equally impractical, but there's something about these old Infocom feelies that feels less grossly insistent on their value or power. They're humble, almost sarcastic about their own existence. Beautifully useless objects, but also wonderfully un-standard. The standardisation of video game collectibles feels like a natural state for an industry that postures rivalry but actually feeds into itself more often than not: collecting ephemera is vast and messy, collecting statues feels like the sort of thing a bankable demographic might well do. Thus, statues for all. Give me more proud uselessness, I say. More tat that knows what it is.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Virtua Fighter 5 R.E.V.O. Is Coming to PS5, Xbox Series and Nintendo Switch 2 with Crossplay]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/virtua-fighter-5-r-e-v-o-is-coming-to-ps5-xbox-series-and-nintendo-switch-2-with-crossplay/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/virtua-fighter-5-r-e-v-o-is-coming-to-ps5-xbox-series-and-nintendo-switch-2-with-crossplay.1186644/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/virtua-fighter-5-r-e-v-o-is-coming-to-ps5-xbox-series-and-nintendo-switch-2-with-crossplay/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Yesterday, SEGA and Ryu Ga Gotoku Studio announced that Virtua Fighter 5 R.E.V.O. is coming to all the main consoles (PlayStation 5, Xbox Series S and X, and Nintendo Switch 2) following <a href="https://wccftech.com/virtua-fighter-5-r-e-v-o-available-on-steam-new-launch-trailer-released/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">its debut on PC on January 28</a>.</p>
<p>The news was shared <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ivwjAPp-w6Q" target="_blank" rel="noopener">during Virtua Fighter Direct 2025 Spring</a> by legacy Virtua Fighter project producer Seiji Aoki, who stated:</p>
<p><em>I know we’ve kept you waiting, but our Steam release Virtua Fighter 5 R.E.V.O. is finally coming to PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X|S, and Nintendo Switch 2. Since Virtua Fighter 5 R.E.V.O.'s launch, we’ve heard your requests for multiplatform support via the official Virtua Fighter Discord and other channels. We on the development team want to give users on all platforms the opportunity to enjoy Virtua Fighter 5 R.E.V.O., so we are happy to bring you this announcement.&nbsp;</em></p>
<p><em>Also, in bringing this title to multiple platforms, we’re planning to include cross-play support. And to make your cross-play experience even smoother, the rollback functionality used in the Steam version will be supported on all platforms. We’re going to include even more content to make this much more than a simple port, which we’ll tell you about in future updates.</em></p>
<p><iframe title="Virtua Fighter 5 R.E.V.O. - Multiplatform Release Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Q4EEo8qyubs?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>During the dedicated live stream, the developers also provided an update on the New Virtua Fighter Project. Wolf Hawkfield, a returning character, will be featured in the upcoming new franchise installment. As part of the announcement, it was also explained that each character's motivations behind their decision to join the fighting tournament would be made much clearer to players this time around. Producer Riichiro Yamada said:</p>
<p><em>In previous Virtua Fighter games, the backstories and motivations of the characters weren't well known. This is one of the major differences between the previous games and our new game. Playing the new game will give you a much better sense of who the characters are, including their backstories and personalities.</em></p>
<p><em>This includes characters from the previous games, too. Legacy characters have been refined for the modern age but remain authentic at their core. </em><em>Wolf's motivation this time is his love for wrestling. What's happened to Wolf since the last game? Why does he fight?</em></p>
<p><iframe title="New VIRTUA FIGHTER Project - Wolf Hawkfield Teaser Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NnyE4tsQ3w8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>The new Project does not currently have a release window, but we'll keep you updated on any rumors and news about it.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Telenet Shooting Collection II announced for Switch]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/05/telenet-shooting-collection-ii-announced-for-switch</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/telenet-shooting-collection-ii-announced-for-switch.1186623/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/05/telenet-shooting-collection-ii-announced-for-switch<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Due out on August 28 in Japan.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Edia [31 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/edia">Edia</a> has <a href="https://prtimes.jp/main/html/rd/p/000000907.000021592.html" target="_blank">announced</a> <em><a title="Games > Telenet Shooting Collection II [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/telenet-shooting-collection-ii">Telenet Shooting Collection II</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > Switch [17,071 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>, which will include ports of four <a title="Genres > Shoot 'Em Up [783 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/shoot-em-up">shoot ’em up games</a> originally developed and released by Telenet Japan. It will launch on August 28 in Japan for 7,480 yen. <span id="more-964526"></span></p><p>The collection will feature the following four titles:</p><ul><li><em>Kiaidan 00</em> (1992, PC Engine)</li><li><em><a title="Games > Final Zone [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/final-zone">Final Zone</a> II</em> (1990, PC Engine)</li><li><em>Browning</em> (1992, PC Engine)</li><li><em>Legion</em> (1990, PC Engine)</li></ul><p>In addition to the standard edition, a limited edition will also be available for 14,080 yen, which includes the two-disc soundtrack CD and the official fan book “Telenet Shooting FAN mini” (B6-size, page count to be announced).</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/Telenet-Shooting-Collection-II-Ann_05-12-25_002.jpg"></a></figure><p>Watch the announcement trailer below. Visit the official website <a href="https://www.telenet-revive.com/tsc2-info" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here</a>.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <h2><span>Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="『テレネット シューティング コレクション II』トレーラー" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/L-zOs87NEu8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hannah’s Day coming to PS5, Xbox Series, PS4, Xbox One, and Switch on May 17]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/05/hannahs-day-coming-to-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-xbox-one-and-switch-on-may-17</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hannah%E2%80%99s-day-coming-to-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-xbox-one-and-switch-on-may-17.1186620/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/05/hannahs-day-coming-to-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-xbox-one-and-switch-on-may-17<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><a title="Companies > Watt Games" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/watt-games">Watt Games</a> will release puzzle <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,264 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure game</a> <em><a title="Games > Hannah's Day" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/hannahs-day">Hannah’s Day</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [9,449 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [7,182 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,990 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox One [13,964 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a>, and <a title="Platforms > Switch [17,071 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a> on May 17, the developer announced. <span id="more-962538"></span></p><p><em>Hannah’s Day</em> first launched for PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2851020/Hannahs_Day/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> on July 25, 2024.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Watt Games:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><a title="Games > Hannah" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/hannah">Hannah</a> loves three things more than anything—singing, friends, and her skateboard. But her parents are not supportive of Hannah’s decision to tie her life to music.</p><p>None of this matters. Music and imagination will get Hannah through the challenges!</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Overcome the obstacles, reunite with Hannah’s friends, and set the stage on fire! And beware, fears, and doubts can poison even the brightest dreams…</p><p><b>Key Features</b></p><ul><li>A visual adventure inspired by supermatism and the avant-garde.</li><li>An elaborate world full of quests and Easter egg.</li><li>A full voice cast of main characters.</li><li>An inspiring story about choosing your path and striving for your goal.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Consoles Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="🚀 Hannah’s Day Gameplay – Skateboarding, Music &amp; Adventure! 🎸🛹" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_MYRDpNXAG0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Suikoden Live broadcast set for May 15]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/05/suikoden-live-broadcast-set-for-may-15</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/suikoden-live-broadcast-set-for-may-15.1186617/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/05/suikoden-live-broadcast-set-for-may-15<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div role="main">
  
  <article>

    
<header>

  <div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/mobile/smartphone">Smartphone</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch-2">Switch 2</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Featuring Suikoden I &amp; II HD Remaster and Suikoden STAR LEAP.</span>
      </p></div>

  

</header>  

<!-- Moved from templates/posts/default.php -->

    <div><p><a title="Companies > Konami Digital Entertainment [1,116 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/konami">Konami</a> will host its second <em>Suikoden</em> Live broadcast on <a href="https://www.timeanddate.com/worldclock/fixedtime.html?iso=20250515T1400" target="_blank">May 15 at 7:00 a.m. PT / 10:00 a.m. ET / 23:00 JST</a>, the company <a href="https://x.com/Suikoden/status/1921732095329665309" target="_blank">announced</a>. You will be able to watch it on <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@KONAMI573ch" target="_blank">YouTube</a>. <span id="more-964519"></span></p><p>The broadcast will cover <em><a title="Games > Suikoden I &amp; II HD Remaster: Gate Rune and Dunan Unification Wars [9 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/suikoden-i-ii-hd-remaster-gate-rune-and-dunan-unification-wars">Suikoden I &amp; II HD Remaster: Gate Rune and Dunan Unification Wars</a></em>, <em><a title="Games > Suikoden STAR LEAP [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/suikoden-star-leap">Suikoden STAR LEAP</a></em>, and feature a new series introduction segment called “First Time in <em>Suikoden</em>.”</p><p><em>Suikoden I &amp; II HD Remaster: Gate Rune and Dunan Unification Wars</em> launched for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [9,449 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [7,182 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,990 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox One [13,964 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch [17,071 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [23,113 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1932640/Suikoden_III_HD_Remaster_Gate_Rune_and_Dunan_Unification_Wars/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a>, <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/p/suikoden-i-and-ii-hd-remaster-76426f" target="_blank">Epic Games Store</a>, and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-us/games/store/suikoden-i-ii-hd-remaster-gate-rune-and-dunan-unification-wars-pre-order-bonus/9p9fm62wzxr2" target="_blank">Microsoft Store</a> on March 6, and is coming to <a title="Platforms > Switch 2 [134 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch-2">Switch 2</a> on June 5. <em>Suikoden STAR LEAP</em> is in development for iOS and Android.</p></div>

        
    
  </article>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Last Of Us Season Two, Episode Five Recap: Seeing Red]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/last-us-season-2-episode-5-recap-ellie-nora-joel-alive-1851780135</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-last-of-us-season-two-episode-five-recap-seeing-red.1186605/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/last-us-season-2-episode-5-recap-ellie-nora-joel-alive-1851780135<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Ellie finally got a little bit of revenge this week. How are we feeling? Not as cathartic as you thought it was gonna be, huh? HBO’s take on <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/last-of-us-season-2-hbo-max-show-review-joel-ellie-abby-1851774661&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/last-of-us-season-2-hbo-max-show-review-joel-ellie-abby-1851774661"><em>The Last of Us</em></a></span><em> </em>is finally back in the trenches after a <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/last-us-dina-ellie-romance-sex-scene-pregnant-episode-4-1851779166&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/last-us-dina-ellie-romance-sex-scene-pregnant-episode-4-1851779166">few weeks of levity</a></span>, or at the very least with its grisly revenge plot out of sight and mostly out of mind. It’s been interesting watching newcomers react to the show, roaring and ready for Ellie to exact her pound of flesh. But, unlike the game, the first taste the show gives us of her revenge tour starts with something just as disturbing as <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/last-of-us-hbo-max-season-2-episode-2-joel-abby-death-1851776976&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/last-of-us-hbo-max-season-2-episode-2-joel-abby-death-1851776976">Joel’s death three episodes ago</a></span>. It’s a complicated scene to unpack for several reasons, but we have a fair bit of television to get through before we get there.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="197562" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="THPS 3+4 Does Away With The OG 4's Career Mode, Here's Why" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="118" data-playlist="197562,197559,197556" data-current="197562"><div><p>THPS 3+4 Does Away With The OG 4's Career Mode, Here's Why</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197562/197562_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197562/197562_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197562/197562_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/23086.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><h2 id="h171992"><a id=""></a><strong>Something in the air</strong></h2><p>This episode starts in a Washington Liberation Front base. We see Hanrahan, whom we briefly saw Isaac (Jeffrey Wright) meeting <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/last-us-season-2-episode-4-dina-ellie-isaac-seraphite-1851779062&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/last-us-season-2-episode-4-dina-ellie-isaac-seraphite-1851779062">in the opening flashback last week</a></span>, walking through one of the group’s bases with dozens of troops looking at her with concern. Whatever she’s there to do must be important because the tension is palpable. She enters a room where a lone woman named Sergeant Park sits at a table with a cigarette in her hand. Hanrahan tells her that her soldiers are clearly very loyal to her, but Park thinks their worry might be misplaced, since if she were getting executed, she imagines Isaac would have come to pull the trigger himself. Hanrahan says Isaac is off dealing with more important matters, like fighting the Seraphite forces elsewhere in Seattle. This woman apparently killed several W.L.F. soldiers; however. So, despite her confidence based on Isaac’s absence, the jury’s still out on whether she’ll be executed.</p><p>Park, we learn, was in charge of securing a hospital, and when her squad cleared the ground floor of infected, they headed to the basement where the original cordyceps patients were supposedly brought back when the outbreak began over 20 years prior. However, aside from the fungus that had grown onto the walls as it does anywhere the infected proliferate, they found no sign of infected. But as the squads investigated the basement floors, they started to exhibit respiratory symptoms along with the early signs of infection. There’s only one possibility: The infection is in the air. The squads above the basement floors hadn’t gotten sick, so they sealed the basements shut with their less fortunate comrades inside and fell back to the base. After Park recounts her tragic tale, Hanrahan says that as far as the W.L.F. is concerned, her actions were heroic and ensured the longevity of the group’s operations. She’s exonerated and left to mourn her squad, her son included.</p><p>When season one aired, <em>The Last of Us </em>showrunner Craig Mazin <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/the-last-of-us-hbo-lore-changes-tendrils-mycology-tess-1850019712&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/the-last-of-us-hbo-lore-changes-tendrils-mycology-tess-1850019712">made a big hoopla</a></span> of changing how the cordyceps infection spreads. In the games, it’s an airborne illness, spread via spores that hang visibly in the air in environments where the fungus grows, but the show did away with this. Mazin admits that was done in part so that Pedro Pascal’s face wouldn’t be obscured by a gas mask every other episode. But now that we’re coming up on a scene that relies on the use of the original airborne virus, this seems like the show’s way of weaving it back into the world. Right now, only the W.L.F. seems to know about this, and it seems to only really be a danger in long-incubated spaces like the hospital basement Park’s squad was inspecting, so I doubt we’ll see Ellie and Dina putting gas masks on anytime soon.</p><h2 id="h171993"><a id=""></a><strong>The boys are back in town</strong></h2><p>Back at the theater, Dina is still on radio duty, listening to the W.L.F. chatter and marking up a map of the city. Ellie has managed to get the power running in the old building, but still wants to help Dina with whatever she can. Dina gives Ellie light shit for not being “school oriented” as she triangulates the probable location of their targets based on what she hears on the radio. When it becomes clear that Ellie’s out of her depth, she leaves Dina to figure it out. As she leaves, Dina calls out to her and just silently smiles at her when she turns around. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xNvdcu9Uh88&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xNvdcu9Uh88" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">“I just wanted to take another look at you.”</a></span></p><p>Ellie explores the theater a bit more and finds the remains of a musical outfit that was performing on the stage some time before the outbreak. The show does a good job of pulling from the games’ soundtracks at exactly the right moments, like here, when it uses the gorgeous <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Wk5m1iMWJnM&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Wk5m1iMWJnM" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">“Vanishing Grace”</a></span> from the first game, which was most notably used when Joel and Ellie got a brief break from all the horrors to pet some giraffes in Salt Lake City. It gives this moment where Ellie looks at the empty theater a sense of cozy, nostalgic safety after the terrors of running away from infected and a crazed militia.</p><p>She finally stops when she finds a line of guitars just waiting to be played. She picks up an acoustic one and sits on a stool on the stage to start playing. The guitar is miraculously somewhat in tune, so she only has to turn a few knobs to get it where she needs it to be. Then, she finally starts picking away at the strings and plays a few measures of “Future Days” by Pearl Jam before putting the guitar down in a huff.</p><p>Any <em>Last of Us </em>game fan knows this song immediately, but this is the first time we’ve heard it performed on the show, even if it’s only for a few moments. The funny thing about the use of this Pearl Jam deep cut in the show is that there is no plausible reason for it to exist in the show’s timeline. For some reason, HBO’s series begins in 2003, rather than in 2013 as the games do. “Future Days” is from the grunge band’s 2013 album <em>Lightning Bolt</em>, which wasn’t even out by the time the outbreak began in the game’s timeline on September 26. Naughty Dog explained this by pointing out <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.gamespot.com/articles/heres-why-the-last-of-us-2-could-feature-that-pear/1100-6479066/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/heres-why-the-last-of-us-2-could-feature-that-pear/1100-6479066/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">the song had been performed live</a></span> and posted to YouTube months before the album was released, but that explanation doesn’t work for the show, since neither the song nor the video platform existed in 2003. Will the show have its own explanation for why a song that shouldn’t exist does? Or is it just too important to the story of <em>The Last of Us</em> to leave out, even if it makes no sense?</p><p>Dina has mapped out a way for Ellie to reach the hospital where Nora is stationed, but her plan does require them to go through a building that the W.L.F. seemingly avoids. The only reason they can think of is that it’s likely overrun with infected. How does she know this? The W.L.F. never shut up on the radio. Ellie points out this is stupid, considering they’re just giving away their positions to their enemies, but based on the fact that the “scars” they’re facing use archaic weaponry and seem to be some kind of religious cult, Dina hypothesizes that they may not use technology, and she wonders if they’re like the Amish. (Sidenote: Dina, you know who the Amish were, but not what a Pride Flag is? What are they teaching about the old world in these post-apocalypse schools?)</p><figure id="" data-id="cc23a78bc85c5ac0a69d2fec9c473e1e" data-recommend-id="image://cc23a78bc85c5ac0a69d2fec9c473e1e" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Dina looks at something off-screen while Ellie approaches her from behind." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Dina looks at something off-screen while Ellie approaches her from behind." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->HBO</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="cc23a78bc85c5ac0a69d2fec9c473e1e" data-recommend-id="image://cc23a78bc85c5ac0a69d2fec9c473e1e" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Dina looks at something off-screen while Ellie approaches her from behind." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>The two head out and kill some time talking about baby names for the bun in the oven. Dina jokes that if it’s a girl, she’ll name the baby “Ellie,” and if it’s a boy, “Elijah.” Before she can offer a more serious option, the two stumble upon the bodies of a group of massacred Seraphites, which makes Dina sick to her stomach. Ellie tries to get her to turn back for her and the baby’s safety, but Dina presses on, offering her own reason for why she intends to see this through with Ellie. She brings up how Ellie never asked about the first person she killed after she’d asked Ellie about hers on the way into the city, and she proceeds to tell the story now. Dina recounts how, when she was eight years old, she lived in a cabin north of Santa Fe and would get bored because she wasn’t allowed to go outside to play. Despite her homophobic mother’s protests, Dina went out one day to explore, but brought a gun with her for protection. But, as it turned out, she wasn’t the one who needed it; her mother and sister did back home.</p><p>A raider entered the cabin while Dina was gone and killed her family, and was still there when she ran back upon hearing the screams. Ellie didn’t kill her first human until she was a teenager, but Dina was half that age when she shot the raider for what he’d done to her family. Ellie apologizes for not asking before, but as she inquires about how she made it to Jackson, Dina says it doesn’t matter because it’s the past. What matters is right now. Joel didn’t deserve what happened to him any more than her mother and sister did, she says, and if the person who killed her family had gotten away, she would have hunted him down, too.</p><p><em>The Last of Us </em>has probably embellished Dina’s story more than any other this season, and with each passing episode, I’m more curious where her journey ends because it’s so starkly different from the source material. In <em>The Last of Us Part II</em>, Dina is devoted to Ellie’s cause because she’s being supportive of her girlfriend, whereas the show has gone out of its way to give her more personal stakes than before, and at times, she seems almost as consumed by the need for vengeance as Ellie. Maybe she still ends up in the same place as she does in <em>Part II</em>, but the more the show changes her, the more I wonder. The show’s given me zero reason to have any confidence in its vision of this story, but I guess I’ll take cautious intrigue over being bored and annoyed the whole time.</p><p>Ellie decides to let Dina stay with her, and they finally reach this mystery building the W.L.F. refuses to enter. Inside is an office that seems empty at first glance, but the militia is still keeping an eye on it with a searchlight. At least, they’re looking at the perimeter around it. Dina notes that they haven’t positioned searchlights to see inside the building itself, which means the girls should be able to move freely throughout without worrying about the wolves. She offers to scout out the next room before Ellie says she should be the one taking point, since she can’t get infected. Now that the facade is over, the team can be a little more tactical. Ellie doesn’t see any infected, and Dina surmises that there are probably, at most, a few strays somewhere in the building rather than a full-blown horde. The two get into a little lovers’ spat when Dina accuses Ellie of being a loose cannon with her firearms, but says that her “crazy” side is exciting and one of the reasons she loves her. When she says the L-word (Lesbians), Ellie is a little starstruck and nearly says it back before Dina interrupts and says, “Oh, I know.”</p><p>I am glad to see some of this confidence Dina exudes redirected at Ellie now that the relationship is official. But damn, these girls are slamming their feet on the gas like the most stereotypical U-haul lesbians. I keep getting pulled back and forth between how much I enjoy Merced’s performance and how the pacing of this relationship has been thrown all out of whack by Mazin’s timeline. Yeah, Dina has pretty much always loved Ellie, so dropping this less than 24 hours after they confessed their feelings and decided to raise a child together isn’t entirely out of the question. But damn, it sure feels like this relationship is being fast-tracked without taking a breath to accommodate the TV show format.</p><p>The two move through the building and it’s unnervingly quiet, until they reach a boiler room and find the mangled remains of a wolf caught by an infected. Not just any infected, though; it’s another stalker.</p><p>But it’s just one of them, right? If they coordinate, they can probably take it out, no problem. But unfortunately it’s not going to be that simple, because an entire pack of stalkers starts to circle the two. Dina starts to panic, and Ellie tells her to take shelter in a gated area while she lures them away. Dina’s not about this plan, but Ellie reminds her that she can get bitten as many times as she has to without getting infected. There’s no other choice right now. She sends Dina off with a kiss, and the girls get to work. Dina reaches the gated area and is able to seal herself inside, but the stalkers immediately start to tear through the rusted metal. Meanwhile, Ellie is quickly overpowered by them, and for just a moment it seems like this might be the end for our girls. Just then, however, gunfire starts ringing through the room. The infected collapse one by one as the mystery gunman takes them out with a trained and precise hand. As he reaches out to Ellie to help her off the ground, we see it’s Jesse, who has finally reached the city after leaving Jackson shortly after the girls.</p><p>He asks if Ellie got bitten in the scrap, and seems a little unconvinced when she insists she wasn’t. But they don’t have time for a full body check, they gotta get moving before more infected show up. The trio books it out of the building and narrowly escapes a wolf squad by running into a park that the soldiers won’t enter. They assume that means the infected are lurking, so they’re still on guard. Ellie immediately starts bombarding Jesse with questions about how he found them, and he says he tracked them to the theater and found the map Dina had been marking up. Finally, after Ellie asks one too many questions, Jesse snaps and asks, “Do I look like I want to fucking talk to you right now?”</p><p>Okay, mean ass. It feels like Jesse is taking on the role of “unlikeable hero” in the show now that HBO has siphoned all of Ellie’s irritability out of her to make her a loving mother-to-be. <em>The Last Of Us</em> (Craig Mazin’s Version) and all its creative liberties have felt fundamentally at odds with the story of self-destructive revenge that it’s based on in a seeming effort to make it more palatable, and one of the many casualties of this approach is that the golden retriever of the group has now become an angsty rottweiler so Ellie doesn’t have to be one. I sometimes worry too much of my criticism of this show reads like a jilted game fan mad that the show isn’t following the original script to the letter, but nearly every change the show makes is either undermining the actual point of the story, or is replacing the dynamics the characters once had with new ones that are not as interesting. The Bill and Frank episode in season one, a notable exception, is still one of the most drastic shifts away from the source material that the show has done, but it lifted up the larger themes of the story. This season, it seems like every effort is being made to ensure Ellie is still the hero of her own story, even if that means making the people who were originally there to ground her read more like scolding family members.</p><figure id="" data-id="0df64fa6d398858ed91bc6165ba97405" data-recommend-id="image://0df64fa6d398858ed91bc6165ba97405" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A group of Seraphites walk through a forest with lit torches." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A group of Seraphites walk through a forest with lit torches." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->HBO</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="0df64fa6d398858ed91bc6165ba97405" data-recommend-id="image://0df64fa6d398858ed91bc6165ba97405" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A group of Seraphites walk through a forest with lit torches." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Jesse reveals that he and Tommy both left Jackson the day after Ellie and Dina snuck out, but they’re not here to help with the girls’ crusade; they’re just here to collect them and get them back to Wyoming. Ellie protests, but their argument is interrupted by the shrill whistles of the Seraphites. A group of cultists gathers in the middle of the park with a W.L.F. prisoner, who begs for his life as they tie a noose around his neck. The Scar leader says they have no interest in any secrets he can offer about Isaac’s plan, and then disembowels him with a scythe. The Jackson trio watches in horror before one of the cultists sees them and fires an arrow into Dina’s leg. Ellie tells Jesse to carry her out of there and back to the theater while she diverts their attention. The darkness of the night works to her advantage, and she’s able to disappear into the woods as Jesse and Dina escape. But even as the Scars give up on the chase, Ellie’s not retreating to the theater where her injured girlfriend waits for her just yet.</p><h2 id="h171994"><a id=""></a><strong>“...I’d surely lose myself”</strong></h2><p>Instead, Ellie heads for her original target: Nora. After evading the guards positioned outside the hospital, Ellie sneaks into the building through a hole in the wall too small for the average person to crawl through. Even as the W.L.F. guard dogs bark at the opening, their human owners hold them back, assuming some kind of animal must have set them off. They’re not entirely wrong, I suppose.</p><p>We then see Nora working in the hospital’s sick bay and caring for the injured. As she leaves to put away some supplies, she’s greeted by none other than the girl she thought she’d left behind in Jackson. Ellie tells her to put her hands up and turn around to face her. She asks if Nora remembers her. She doesn’t answer, but her expression reveals she certainly does. Nora asks what Ellie wants, and she asks where Abby is. Nora claims she doesn’t know, but Ellie doesn’t believe her. If Ellie shoots Nora, her quarry points out, the gunfire will have every wolf in the building scrambling to her location. “You’ll still be dead,” Ellie replies.</p><p>Nora tries to appeal to Ellie’s sense of mercy, pointing out that they could have killed her in Jackson, but they only came to Wyoming with one target in mind. Ellie says that was a mistake, and once again asks where Abby is. For a moment, it seems like Nora is about to confide in Ellie that she regrets what happened to Joel. She says she still hears the screams he let out as Abby tortured him at night, and she’s sorry that Ellie had to see it happen. But then, just as Ellie slightly lets her guard down, Nora’s tune changes: “Yeah, that little bitch got what he deserved.” Ellie is stunned just long enough for Nora to throw a bucket of water and supplies at her and give herself a window to run. Then Ellie gives chase. As Nora runs through the hospital she screams for her fellow soldiers to fire at the intruder, but then she reaches a dead end with her only way out a sealed elevator leading to the basement floors. You know, the ones where the infection is in the air. This scene is probably why the show had to bring spores into the fold. Short of a complete rewrite, the clash between Ellie and Nora requires the cordyceps infection to be an airborne illness to work. The difference this time around is that there’s a dramatic irony as Nora heads into the basement floors to escape Ellie’s wrath, only for us as viewers to know that a different danger entirely awaits.</p><figure id="" data-id="e6c8afefed11782715c68975f5e5d9db" data-recommend-id="image://e6c8afefed11782715c68975f5e5d9db" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Nora raises her hands and looks at something off-screen." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Nora raises her hands and looks at something off-screen." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->HBO</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="e6c8afefed11782715c68975f5e5d9db" data-recommend-id="image://e6c8afefed11782715c68975f5e5d9db" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Nora raises her hands and looks at something off-screen." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Ellie gives chase and finds the overgrown fungus covering the walls. A few still-breathing infected are trapped within the structure, breathing out bits of infection with each wheezing gasp. Hearing the labored breathing of someone else in the next hallway over, she turns on the oppressive red emergency lighting in the electrical room, only to find Nora leaning against a wall, choking on the spores in her lungs. She hacks up a curse in Ellie’s direction and says that she’s “killed [them] both” by driving them to this sealed basement. But when she realizes Ellie isn’t struggling to breathe, she realizes the reports of an immune girl in Salt Lake City were real. Ellie confirms that she is, in fact, that girl, and asks, once again, where Abby is.</p><p>Nora tries to appeal to Ellie’s humanity, telling her about all the people Joel killed, including Abby’s father and with him, any hope the world had of being rid of this infection. Then, to her surprise, Ellie says that she already knows and again asks where Abby is. Nora collapses on the ground and stays silent. Then Ellie looks around and, finding a pipe, holds it over Nora and asks her question one more time. Nora flatly says “no,” and Ellie starts to let loose, bringing the pipe down on Nora’s legs, repeatedly asking where Abby is until the screen cuts to black.</p><p>Okay. There’s a lot to unpack here. This is arguably one of the most controversial scenes in <em>The Last of Us Part II</em>, and for good reason. But before we get into the uncomfortable optics, I do have to point out that part of what made this section effective in the game was that this originally served as the big reveal that Abby and company were once Fireflies, but the show instead told us that right off the bat. The game used this scene as a one-two punch to reveal both that truth bomb <em>and </em>the fact that Ellie was already well aware of what Joel had done by the time Abby had made her way to Jackson. So much of <em>The Last of Us Part II</em>’s excellent narrative tension comes from its calculated silence. The game tells you almost nothing about what Ellie is feeling, outside of her journal entries which conveniently write around the specifics of what she already knows. This exchange between Ellie and Nora is a moment of realization for both of them, as Nora realizes that Ellie is the immune girl Joel killed dozens of people to save, and Ellie discovers that this entire crusade against her surrogate father was carried out by people who suffered for her survival. All of these things could have been inferred by the player, but the game hadn’t said them outright by this point, and the sparse script and unnerving performances by game actors Ashley Johnson and Chelsea Tavares really sell the weight of that moment before any blood has been shed.</p><p>Looking back at the original scene and how its dialogue elegantly reveals so much without having to beat you over the head with the most literal expository writing makes the show look like an amateurish rewrite by someone who thought that scene was a little too subtle. Plus, Ellie already told Jesse, and by extension, the audience, that she and Joel were getting past whatever conflict they had in his final days, so the reveal that she already knew about the Salt Lake City massacre isn’t really a surprise this time around. But that’s not really new for the show, as I’ve pointed out several times over the course of the season. Every time we get to what was a huge “oh shit” moment in the game, it feels like the show just goes through the motions of recounting it while cushioning uncomfortable moments like Joel’s death with quippy dialogue, or Nora’s interrogation with overexposition.</p><p>In the end, neither of those reveals change anything. Ellie is still dead set on killing Abby, even if she has to torture her friend to do it. Which means it’s time to get into one of the more questionable moments in the entire <em>Last of Us </em>franchise. In <em>Part II</em>, Nora’s death was notable for a few reasons. On top of it being the first kill that really solidified Ellie’s revenge tour demanded more of her than she bargained for, it is framed much differently from any other in the game. Prior to this, Ellie had killed Abby’s hotheaded friend Jordan who wasn’t included in the show (Manny seems to have been made into a composite of himself and Jordan for the series), and that fight is a bit more cathartic because that dude was a shithead who taunted Ellie and didn’t spend his final moments begging for his life. Nora, meanwhile, is tortured for information, and the interrogation leaves Ellie absolutely shattered at what she had done. This is all in-line with the story <em>The Last of Us Part II</em> tells, in which Ellie goes down this violent path but is unable to stomach the reality. However, the difference is that when the player kills Nora, the woman herself isn’t even given the dignity of an on-screen death. The camera lingers on Ellie as the player is forced to press a button to strike her off-screen. It’s supposed to be a transformative moment in which the player is forced to look upon Ellie in her darkest hour and understand what this crusade is doing to her. But when you have a white woman beating the lone named Black woman in the game for information and you can’t so much as show her as it’s happening, it is the most damning example of a trend of <em>The Last of Us </em><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://uppercutcrit.com/the-world-of-the-last-of-us-leaves-black-trauma-behind/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://uppercutcrit.com/the-world-of-the-last-of-us-leaves-black-trauma-behind/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">subjecting Black characters to the worst fates</a></span> it can imagine in its post-apocalyptic world.</p><p>HBO’s take on the series has only slightly mitigated this by casting more actors of color, including Rutina Wesley as Jackson’s leader, Maria. But even so, Nora’s death still has an optics problem that the show can’t shake. If there had ever been a time for the show to reconsider the source material and make thoughtful, intentional changes, this was probably it. But here we are, watching Ellie torture Nora for information on Abby’s whereabouts. If nothing else, it’s still just as effective at communicating Ellie’s fall from grace.</p><p>We end this episode with something a little more pleasant: a flashback. The sun shines through the window in Ellie’s old room in Joel’s Jackson house. She stirs awake as Joel enters the room with his signature “Hey, kiddo.” Ellie says “hi” as the credits roll. Rejoice, Pedro fans. Daddy’s back next week.</p><hr><p>New episodes of <em>The Last of Us </em>air on Sundays at 9 p.m. Eastern on Max.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Some retailers have broken Doom: The Dark Ages' street date, and huge spoilers are already out there]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/some-retailers-have-broken-doom-the-dark-ages-street-date-and-huge-spoilers-are-already-out-there</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/some-retailers-have-broken-doom-the-dark-ages-street-date-and-huge-spoilers-are-already-out-there.1186524/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/some-retailers-have-broken-doom-the-dark-ages-street-date-and-huge-spoilers-are-already-out-there<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Careful, Doom fans - details of <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/doom-the-dark-ages">Doom: The Dark Ages</a> have leaked ahead of its release next week.</p>
<p>As posted to the <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GamingLeaksAndRumours/comments/1kiyzhc/doom_the_dark_ages_screenshot_leak/">Gaming Leaks and Rumours subreddit</a>, some players have received their discs ahead of the 15th May street date, which means details are popping up all over the place now, including information about the plot, menus, combat, weapons, beastiary, and more.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Introducing the DOOM: The Dark Ages Limited Edition Collection" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ypuJdFAFSsc?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Introducing the DOOM: The Dark Ages Limited Edition Collection</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ypuJdFAFSsc?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/ypuJdFAFSsc?autoplay=1" title="Introducing the DOOM: The Dark Ages Limited Edition Collection">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Here's a trailer showing off Xbox's Doom: The Dark Ages accessories.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ypuJdFAFSsc" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>"Hey dudes, I got lucky and got the [Collector's Edition on] the 8th and just finished this amazing game, what a trip. This will have spoilers, so it's up to you if you want to get spoiled," one player wrote, before individually linking dozens and dozens of screenshots with spoilers a-plenty.</p>
<p>The early shipping has also identified something else, too; it seems as though even with a physical disc, <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GamingLeaksAndRumours/comments/1kighkz/doom_the_dark_ages_the_entire_game_in_the/">PS5 players have to be connected to the internet and download the entire game to their consoles</a> before they can play.</p>
<p>As reportedly verified by <a href="https://www.ppe.pl/news/369411/doom-the-dark-ages-z-haczykiem-w-wersji-pudelkowej-na-ps5-uzytkownik-ppe-pl-zdradza-istotny-szczegol.html">ppe.pl</a>, "the disc for Doom: The Dark Ages contains nothing but the data necessary to trigger a download of the game from the internet. This means PS5 owners hoping to step into the Doom Slayer’s boots should be prepared to download over 80 GB - the full size of the game."</p>
<p>"Literal waste of materials," <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GamingLeaksAndRumours/comments/1kighkz/comment/mrelxmr/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button">responded</a> one commenter. "This is just profoundly stupid."</p>
<p>In <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/doom-the-dark-ages-review">Eurogamer's Doom: the Dark Ages review</a>, Chris D. awarded it four stars out of five, writing: "It's all so simple, so joyously, generously straight ahead. You're a powerful goody, you're surrounded by powerful baddies, and you have to finish them all off. Everyone knows where they stand, and they all seem pretty happy with the roles they're playing. And it's kind of lovely."</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The First Descendant Season 3 update and NieR: Automata collaboration announced]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/05/the-first-descendant-season-3-update-and-nier-automata-collaboration-announced</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-first-descendant-season-3-update-and-nier-automata-collaboration-announced.1186515/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/05/the-first-descendant-season-3-update-and-nier-automata-collaboration-announced<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>2B and A2 outfits incoming.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Nexon [130 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/nexon">Nexon</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Nexon Games [11 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/nexon/nexon-games">Nexon Games</a> announced have announced the Season 3 update for <a title="Genres > Free-to-Play [387 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/free-to-play">free-to-play</a> <a title="Genres > Co-Op [262 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer/co-op">cooperative</a> looter <a title="Genres > Shooter [4,106 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/shooter">shooter</a> <em><a title="Games > The First Descendant [10 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/the-first-descendant">The First Descendant</a></em>, which includes a new battlefield, Hover Bike, Colossus Field Raid, the introduction of the “Lounge,” a new Descendant, and more. It will launch this summer. A collaboration with <a title="Companies > Square Enix [5,344 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/square-enix">Square Enix</a>‘s <em><a title="Games > NieR: Automata [117 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/nier-automata">NieR: Automata</a></em>, focused on cosmetics, was also revealed. <span id="more-964497"></span></p><p>“Unfortunately, the collaboration will focus on decorations, as we are in the process of solidifying the substance of our game, we decided to invest more in the content of Season 3 rather than other content related to the <em>NieR: Automata</em> collaboration,” <em>The First Descendant</em> producer Beomjun Lee said during a panel at PAX East 2025. “However, in addition to the A2 and 2B outfits, we have prepared a damaged version of 2B with no skirt, with other motions and decorations as well.”</p><p>Here are the details:</p><blockquote><p><strong>Season 3 “Breakthrough” Sneak-Peek</strong></p><ul><li><strong>New <a title="Companies > Mas" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/mas">Mas</a>sive Field: Axion Plains</strong><ul><li>A brand-new, enormous battlefield once a promising outpost site, now devastated by a Void Storm and overrun by Colossus.</li><li>Faces a new threat from both artificial creatures and mutated beasts, making it more dangerous than ever.</li></ul><!-- AD: content -->
        </li><li><strong>New Vehicle: Hover Bike</strong><ul><li>A new vehicle system designed for high-speed travel across a massive field, giving players a thrilling sense of speed.</li><li>Players can obtain a standard Hover Bike just by logging in during Season 3, and can collect enhanced ‘Accelerated’ and ‘Boosted’ models by exploring the Axion Plains.</li><li>Each Hover Bike can be upgraded, allowing players to traverse the battlefield with dynamic movement using boost and jump abilities.</li></ul></li><li><strong>New Content: Colossus Field Raid</strong><ul><li>Eight-player raid content</li><li>First-ever reveal of the new and overwhelming colossus “Wall Crasher”</li><li>Massive scale designed to match the size of Axion</li><li>Players are able to ride their Hover Bike along the vast field, then engage in combat against the Colossus.</li></ul></li><li><strong>New Feature: Lounge</strong><ul><li>A dedicated social space where players can interact with their Descendants and take a break.</li><li>A personalized space where players can display and interact with their Descendants.</li><li>Players can place their Descendants throughout the space, customize their appearances with skins, and interact with furniture.</li><li>Collectibles like Colotoys can be placed inside, with lounge-exclusive items to be added in the future.</li><li>Designed to deliver a deeper, more immersive experience within the world of The First Descendant beyond just combat.</li></ul></li></ul></blockquote><div id="carousel_964498"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div><blockquote><ul><li><strong>Season 3: Breakthrough – Story</strong><ul><li>The reappearance of “Karel,” a key character in the story.</li><li>Season 3 story marks a big turning point for the narrative of The First Descendant.</li><li>Focusing on Enzo and Nell’s romance would be one of the highlights of Season 3</li></ul></li><li><strong>New Descendant: Nell</strong><ul><li>Former NPC Nell joins the roster as a playable character with a brand-new look and unique abilities.</li><li>Nell utilizes arche like telekinesis, throwing spheres which form debuffs and also pulls nearby enemies.</li><li>Capable of changing all her gunshots into weak point strikes, making her a perfect fit for aggressive, <a title="Genres > Run-and-Gun [10 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/shoot-em-up/run-and-gun">run-and-gun</a> playstyles.</li><li>Nell will be officially added in the upcoming summer update.</li></ul></li><li><strong>New Ultimate: Ultimate <a title="Platforms > Luna [60 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/cloud/luna">Luna</a></strong><ul><li>Two new Transcendent Modules are being prepared for the release of Ultimate Luna. One shifts her playstyle to focus on firearms, while the other enhances her rhythm-based abilities and debuffing potential.</li><li>As Season 3 will be divided into multiple episodes, Ultimate Yujin is expected to arrive in Season 3 Episode 2, following Ultimate Luna.</li></ul></li><li><strong>New Weapon: Sword (Three Types)</strong><ul><li>Swords are finally being added to the game and can be equipped in the same weapon slot as firearms, with performance enhanced through specialized modules.</li><li>Players can perform both normal and special attacks with swords. The first type, the “Shadow” Blade, features a charged iaijutsu-style dash attack as its special move.</li><li>The Blade and a new dungeon featuring a boss that utilizes sword mechanics will be introduced in Season 3 – Episode 1.</li><li>Additional sword types, including a two-handed greatsword and a lightsaber-style weapon, will be added in Season 3 – Episode 2.</li></ul></li><li><strong>First-Ever Official Crossover with <em>NieR: Automata</em></strong><ul><li>The First Descendant’s first official crossover features the fan-favorite <em>NieR: Automata</em>.</li><li>A full trailer will be released soon, following the reveal of key visuals during [today’s panel at PAX East 2025].</li><li>More intellectual property collaborations are also in the works.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Additional Announcements</strong><ul><li>New “Gilded Death Blossom” skin to be released on May 22.</li><li>Announcement of “TFD Fest” for 1st Anniversary in July, featuring: showcase, in-game events, skin design contest and more.</li></ul></li></ul></blockquote><p><em>The First Descendant</em> is available now for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [9,449 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [7,182 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,990 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox One [13,964 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [23,113 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2074920/The_First_Descendant/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a>.</p><p>Watch a teaser trailer and the PAX East 2025 panel archive below. View a new set of screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/the-first-descendant/may-11-2025/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>Hover Bike Teaser Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="The First Descendant: Breakthrough | Hover Bike Teaser" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/FqEbWCKYKT8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><span>PAX East 2025 Panel</span></h2><p><iframe title="The First Descendant | PAX East 2025 | Dev Livestream" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/tNdje4dwrD0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fallout show could run for "five, six" seasons, says actor]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/fallout-show-could-run-for-five-six-seasons-says-actor</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fallout-show-could-run-for-five-six-seasons-says-actor.1186512/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/fallout-show-could-run-for-five-six-seasons-says-actor<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>"When I signed on to do the series, they gave me the endpoint."</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Amazon</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Amazon's hit Fallout show will run for five or six seasons.</p>
<p>That's according to actor Aaron Moten, who revealed in an interview at Comic Con Liverpool that when he signed on for the role of Maximus, he was told to expect the show to run for "five, six" seasons in total.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="How To Build Lucy, The Ghoul, and Maximus in Fallout 4" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/kbvXnjr14c8?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>How To Build Lucy, The Ghoul, and Maximus in Fallout 4</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/kbvXnjr14c8?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/kbvXnjr14c8?autoplay=1" title="How To Build Lucy, The Ghoul, and Maximus in Fallout 4">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>How To Build Lucy, The Ghoul, and Maximus in Fallout 4.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kbvXnjr14c8" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>"When I signed on to do the series, we would have a starting point, and they gave me the end point," Moten explained (thanks, <a href="https://www.thegamer.com/fallout-tv-show-six-five-seasons-of-story-planned/">TheGamer</a>).</p>
<p>"That endpoint hasn't changed, but it is season five, season six, type of endpoint. We've always known that we're going to take our time with the development of the characters."</p>
<p>Given Fallout's rich lore across several games, this may not be a complete surprise, but it's good news nonetheless, as it assures Fallout fans that the show was created with longevity in mind.</p>
<blockquote data-embed-height="740"><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Fotv/comments/1kjjf1y/fallout_tv_series_is_planned_by_showrunners_for_5/">Fallout TV series is planned by showrunners for 5 or 6 seasons said actor Aaron Moten</a><br> by<a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/TOZAR_N7/">u/TOZAR_N7</a> in<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Fotv/">Fotv</a></blockquote><p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span></p><p>"Excellent sign!" <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Fotv/comments/1kjjf1y/comment/mro0crc/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button">said one happy fan</a>. "Too many stories fall apart suddenly when the writers don't have a solid plan."</p>
<p>Production on Fallout season two wrapped this week, and <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/walton-goggins-celebrates-wrapping-fallout-season-two-by-peeling-off-his-skin">actor Walton Goggins shared the news by ripping off his prosthetics</a>. Fallout's first season was a huge hit for Amazon, and was <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/amazons-fallout-show-officially-renewed-for-second-season">quickly picked up for a second season</a>. Jonathan Nolan and Lisa Joy - who executive produce the show via Kilter Films - said they couldn't "wait to blow up the world all over again", although production shut down during <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/devastating-los-angeles-fires-shut-down-fallout-season-2">the filming of Fallout season 2</a> following the devastating wildfires.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/leaked-fallout-set-photo-teases-a-familiar-new-vegas-face-of-jurassic-proportions">There have been several set leaks</a>, giving us a closer look at some <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/fallout-season-two-leaks-give-first-look-at-new-vegas">iconic locales and faces from the Fallout video games</a>, and <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/fallout-season-two-will-blow-the-first-out-of-the-water-star-walton-goggins-says">Goggins has assured fans it will blow the first season out of the water</a>. New cast members reported to be joining Goggins and co. include <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/fallout-season-2-reportedly-adds-marvel-actor-kumail-nanjiani-to-its-cast">Kumail Nanjiani as "a high-ranking official within the Brotherhood of Steel"</a> and <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/fallout-tv-series-second-season-lands-home-alone-star">Macaulay Culkin as "a crazy genius-type character"</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>