<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 11:46:58 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch 2 May Use Same Tools and ROM Format as Current Console, Potentially Making It Easy to Emulate]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-rom-emulate/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-switch-2-may-use-same-tools-and-rom-format-as-current-console-potentially-making-it-easy-to-emulate.1011936/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-rom-emulate/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Nintendo shutting down emulators like <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-emulator-yuzu-shut-down-nintendo-gets-paid-2-4-million/">Yuzu</a> and <a href="https://wccftech.com/ryujinx-switch-emulator-is-dead-too-taken-down-by-nintendo-like-yuzu/">Ryujinx</a> years after their first release may have to do with the Nintendo Switch 2, as the system may end up being easier to emulate near launch than the vast majority of gaming consoles.</p>
<p>Thanks to the recent massive <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-pokemon-mmo/">Game Freak leak</a>, which confirmed the Ounce codename for the next Nintendo console, among other things, as reported by<a href="https://x.com/CentroLeaks" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> Centro LEAKS</a>, the system seems to use the same tools and ROM format that is being used for the current Switch, but with new encryption keys only known to Nintendo. This would make the system far easier to emulate than every other gaming system at launch and may explain why the Japanese company shut down emulators like Ryujinx and Yuzu after they had been widely available for years.</p>
<blockquote>
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Ounce (Switch 2) seems to use the same tools and ROM format Nintendo currently uses for Switch 1 (ROMs are still NSPs), but obviously they have new encryption keys that only Nintendo has</p>
<p>— Centro LEAKS (@CentroLeaks) <a href="https://twitter.com/CentroLeaks/status/1846709024160420043?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 17, 2024</a></p></blockquote>

<p>Very little is currently known about the Nintendo Switch 2 other than that it has been in the works for a while. Production seems to have started ramping up recently, and a first look at what is supposed to be an early prototype was shared online <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-new-video-design/">last month</a>. Unfortunately, it's still not clear when the system will be formally announced and when precisely it will be released, although recent reports suggest that the console could be ready for a <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-rumored-to-be-ready-for-march-april-2025-launch/">March-April 2025 release.</a></p>
<p>The Nintendo Switch 2 has yet to be officially revealed. We will keep you updated on the system as soon as possible, so stay tuned for all the latest news.</p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Oh, WoW]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/c/24235606/world-of-warcraft-legacy-mmorpg-blizzard-2004</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/oh-wow.1011933/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/c/24235606/world-of-warcraft-legacy-mmorpg-blizzard-2004<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
	
	

	<div>
	
		
				<div>
					
					
								<p><em>World of Warcraft</em>, or <em>WoW</em>, is like the Red Hot Chili Peppers of the massively multiplayer online roleplaying genre: not only <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Red_Hot_Chili_Peppers_2022%E2%80%932024_Global_Stadium_Tour">is it still going strong</a> but it’s also somehow even bigger than you thought. <em>World of Warcraft</em>’s current numbers aren’t public, but <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OHDFgZAuJHU">one recent educated guess</a> came in at 7 million paying subscribers, which, at $15 / month, would make the game a billion-dollar earner by itself. Its developer, Blizzard, merged with Activision in 2008, and Microsoft gobbled up both companies in 2022, but <em>World of Warcraft </em>remains a load-bearing spine of the newly formed corporate turducken. The game that redefined gold mining for the 21st century is still a 19th-century gold mine for its landlords.&nbsp;</p>

								<p>It’s also thriving in a subscription ecosystem that it helped to legitimize. <em>World of Warcraft</em> debuted in 2004, during an era when you still had to buy games in boxes from stores. The runaway success of Blizzard’s always-on portal to Azeroth proved that, for the right product, studios could charge a recurring fee beyond the initial cost of the core game’s (at the time) formidable five installation CDs. Here, in the enshittified 2020s, we’ve all grown used to renting our culture by the month, but it was genuinely pathbreaking for <em>World of Warcraft</em> to have 12 million subscribers at its peak in 2010. It didn’t invent the monthly model, which had already gained traction in games like <em>Ultima Online</em> and <em>EverQuest</em> during the dawn of the massively multiplayer online roleplaying game (MMORPG) genre. But <em>World of Warcraft</em>’s success took that recurring charge mainstream and helped popularize the unassailable business logic that having your customers pay you once was worse than having them pay you until they decided or remembered to stop.&nbsp;</p>

								<p>As <em>World of Warcraft </em>turns 20,<em> </em>its enduring financial success arguably pales in comparison to its cultural significance. I asked Angela Washko, a new-media artist who staged several notable performance pieces inside the game world, what she considered <em>World of Warcraft</em>’s biggest contribution, for better or worse. “<em>World of Warcraft</em> expanded the notion of what public space was,” she told me. “I saw the bonds created amongst members of my guilds moving beyond the game space, as players flew across the country to meet each other.” Everyone I talked to about <em>World of Warcraft</em>’s legacy seemed to mention someone or other getting married, either in the game itself or here in reality after meeting in the game. “I think the degree of immersion and dissolving of the boundary between ‘real life’ and ‘fantasy’ within <em>World of Warcraft</em> was really a turning point in computing culture,” Washko said, adding that <em>World of Warcraft </em>“changed the conversation around video games from being something that was ‘an escape from everyday life’ to something that was an extension of one’s social life and happened to take place in a virtual environment.”&nbsp;</p>

								<p>Through her own work, Washko also explored the less savory side of a fantasy game populated by real people; her <a href="https://angelawashko.com/section/300206-The%20Council%20on%20Gender%20Sensitivity%20and%20Behavioral%20Awareness%20in%20World%20of%20Warcraft.html">Council on Gender Sensitivity and Behavioral Awareness in <em>World of Warcraft</em></a> involved traveling from town to town to educate passersby about feminism and discuss how the game’s dominant culture often created a hostile environment for its marginalized players. I recalled my own playing days, when you could be flying into a town on your hippogryph, minding your own business, only to be deluged by a wave of sewer-grade hate speech on a public text channel. We now take it for granted that online spaces reflect the social dynamics of the people who occupy them, including and especially the problematic ones, but in many ways, <em>World of Warcraft</em> was the kobold in this particular coal mine.</p>

				</div>
		
				<div>
					
					
								<p>I first encountered the <em>Warcraft</em> universe like many ’90s computer kids: as a series of top-down, real-time strategy games about economic management and cartoon fantasy violence. The world (lowercase) of <em>Warcraft</em> pitted the seemingly noble Alliance (humans, elves, dwarves, your Tolkienesque usual suspects) against the villainized Horde (orcs, trolls, and other stock monster-humanoids from the trope factory) in a vicious-with-a-touch-of-slapstick conflict spanning three main titles and numerous expansions between 1994 and 2003. If no one was using the phone, you could play against your friends over a modem. The series had a rich and goofy aesthetic of exaggerated proportions, saturated colors, and sarcastic jokes. The units that ran your economy were literal simpering peons, which gave everything a barrel-shaped, vaguely comedic flavor that played well against the high-gloss cinematic interludes that would become Blizzard’s calling card.</p>

								<p>Flush with revenues from its flagship series, Blizzard began exploring how it might expand <em>Warcraft</em>’s popular lore into other types of games. First, a point-and-click game called <em>Warcraft Adventures</em> — a late-1990s attempt at LucasArts-style vintage puzzle-solving in a cel-shaded take on the<em> </em>mythos — was infamously canceled for not meeting Blizzard’s internal release standards. (It also leaked, fully playable, not too long ago. Based on what I’ve seen, Blizzard was right.) Then, starting in 2001, an experimental team of a few dozen people got busy building a whole new engine that would bring Azeroth into 3D for the first time and let players meet, socialize, and slaughter skeletons together. It was a primordial example of the modern phenomenon where a corporation exploits its intellectual property by jumping genres and colonizing a new medium. It was also how they’d get me.</p>

								<p>There are plenty of humbling ways to use Gmail’s internal search function, especially if you’ve had your account for roughly as long as <em>World of Warcraft </em>has existed. For one example, consider my collected personal correspondence surrounding <em>World of Warcraft</em>, from the peak years of its involvement in my life. When I queried “Warcraft before:2007/1/1,” it yielded about two dozen results, and together, they trace a blunt biography of that moment: landing a big new job; getting hella dumped; and “spending two months as an antisocial hermit,” as I told a friend in a Gchat in early 2006. (And how about <em>World of Warcraft </em>outliving Gchat?)&nbsp;</p>

								<p>Reviewing the private record, it’s clear <em>World of Warcraft </em>tore through my life like an experienced raiding party of max-level grinders through the Deadmines. Admittedly, it was the kind of nymph-stage young adult life that was conceptually made of crepe paper and easily shredded by a video game. But something about the predictable rhythm of ordering junk food delivery after an exhausting workday, logging onto <em>World of Warcraft,</em> and hopping through some lush environment searching for herbs to make into sellable virtual potions just drew me in, one night after another.</p>

								<p>This aspect of <em>World of Warcraft</em> — its knack for blurring the line between work and fun until the casual observer might not quite recognize it as either — often came up when I spoke to others about their experiences. “One thing <em>WoW</em> proved on a large scale is that people will turn a game into a job at the slightest provocation,” said Cory O’Brien, now a narrative and level designer for games like <em>Redfall </em>and <em>HoloVista</em>. <em>“</em>I remember spending hours and hours and hours grinding for dust so that I could enchant magic items. I remember smelting tin and copper to make bronze.” The elaborate crafting system in <em>World of Warcraft</em>, which often required materials gained through repetitive in-game labor, represented an explosion in the popularity of the now-ubiquitous mechanic where you, as a player, find some stuff and turn it into something else. “I still play all these more recent games like <em>Minecraft,</em> <em>Project Zomboid,</em> and <em>Valheim</em> that are literally just that crafting part,” O’Brien told me. “I spend so much time doing monotonous, repetitive tasks, for free, because somehow we have discovered that that’s fun.” Here, in 2024, it’s hard not to feel a vaguely sinister undertone to all of this as the rising tides of capitalistic overreach gamify the gig economy and hijack the natural human affinity for rewards for their own extractive purposes. But to Washko’s point about an expanded social life, one reason this all worked is that you were often helping out real people, with “legitimate needs” in the scope of the game. You were rarely just doing these things for yourself.</p>

								<p>It wasn’t always exactly a waste, either. Andrew Simone, now a project manager in tech, attributes a large swath of his professional tool kit to skills he gained as a guild leader in <em>World of Warcraft. </em>“I actually stopped playing <em>WoW</em> largely because I felt like I was managing my guild more than my actual professional jobs,” he told me, proceeding to outline a frightening slate of workplace-flavored tasks that included interviewing prospective guild candidates, analyzing performance metrics from the game’s multiuser boss fights, dealing with in-guild sexual harassment, managing schedules across the world to hold meetings about all these things, writing guides for new members, and even “cultivating a kind of guild culture so people <em>enjoyed</em> being there,” which is an incredible thing to say about something that is already ostensibly a game. I know there are countless former guild leaders reading this and nodding along because their current workday docket has nothing on mediating a 10-way raiding party dispute over who should get the legendary enchanted pauldrons that just dropped.&nbsp;</p>

								<p>On the other hand: plenty of it <em>was</em> a giant waste. I can’t tell you, back in the day, how many hours I was technically playing <em>World of Warcraft </em>but<em> </em>ignoring the game itself while I sifted through, rearranged, and tested various custom add-ons for its labyrinthine, fintech-ass user interface. <em>World of Warcraft </em>is a persistent software ecosystem with clients and servers and all kinds of data flying between them at all times — it’s just not necessarily exposed to every player in full. An entire cottage industry of user-created UI mods sprung up to assign repeatable actions to shortcut keys, or process advanced analytics from game logs like Simone would do for his guild, or implement an “<a href="https://www.wowinterface.com/downloads/info23151-AGT-AutomaticGoblinTherapist.html">automatic goblin therapist</a>” who answers any incoming whispers to your character with an in-game implementation of the classic ELIZA protocol. Letting players scratch their own itches for how the game felt to play was also a clever way to limit complaints about the parts of it that weren’t as polished. I never got much into the game’s advanced content myself, but for those who did, pretty much the only way to follow the expected meta of guild raids was to use externally designed UI add-ons. <em>World of Warcraft </em>had the audacity to make players create their own custom cockpits for the game and ended up creating a kind of recursive procrastination where you could even distract yourself from your intended leisure activity. Anyone who’s ever rearranged the app icons on their phone knows just how ubiquitous this kind of time-consuming “metawork” has become.</p>

								<p>Recently, I engaged in a more contemporary form of networked social entertainment — sitting around a big TV with friends, watching four strangers play a game together on Twitch. Just as things were picking up, the stream cut out, and an algorithmically inserted video ad began to play: it was for <em>World of Warcraft</em>. This was a group of mostly game designers, and before I had a chance to say anything, someone <em>else</em> piped in to mention <em>World of Warcraft</em> was 20 years old now — and formally impactful enough that working game makers still know its birthday.</p>

								<p>Seeing that ad, writing this piece, none of it was enough to get me to reinstall <em>World of Warcraft</em>. (It’s a good thing the game never stooped to making you feed your in-game pets.) I didn’t really feel I had to replay the game to measure its influence because its influence is everywhere. Every monthly subscription, in-game economy, or digital “third place” where lives bleed into online connections owes it some spiritual recognition as prior art; those things have all become inescapable. Twenty years later, we are all living in the <em>World of Warcraft.</em></p>

				</div>
</div>
</article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 will not release in Kuwait, pre-orders cancelled and refunded]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-will-not-release-in-kuwait-pre-orders-cancelled-and-refunded</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-will-not-release-in-kuwait-pre-orders-cancelled-and-refunded.1011927/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-will-not-release-in-kuwait-pre-orders-cancelled-and-refunded<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>"We remain hopeful that local authorities will reconsider."</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Call-of-Duty-Black-Ops-6-screenshot-from-trailer.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Activision</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p><a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/call-of-duty-2024">Call of Duty: Black Ops 6</a> is set to release in just over a week, however it will not launch in Kuwait.</p>
<p>In a statement shared with Eurogamer, Activison said this year's Call of Duty had "not been approved for release" in the country.</p>
<figure>
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<figcaption>Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 live action trailer. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ovxYvuEYaE0" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>"At this time, the title will not be available for release in the region. As a result, all pre-orders in Kuwait will be cancelled and refunded to the original point of purchase," Activision told us. "We remain hopeful that local authorities will reconsider, and allow players in Kuwait to enjoy this all-new experience in the Black Ops series."</p><p>While Activision did not go into further detail as to why Black Ops 6 had not been approved for sale in Kuwait, it is fair to assume the game's Gulf War themes are a key factor for this decision. Iraq invaded Kuwait in the early 90s, which triggered the start of the first Gulf War.</p>
<p>Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 is set to release later this month, on 25th October. When it arrives, it <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/heres-the-next-batch-of-xbox-game-pass-titles-for-october-and-into-november">will also be available on Game Pass</a> via the service's Ultimate and PC Game Pass membership tiers. This will mark a significant milestone for Microsoft, which acquired <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/its-been-12-months-since-microsoft-purchased-activision-blizzard-so-whats-changed">Call of Duty maker Activision last October</a>, after almost two years of legal dealings and negotiations.</p>
<p>For more, you can read about this year's Call of Duty release in <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/forget-levolution-and-drivatars-call-of-duty-black-ops-6-now-has-omnimovement">Eurogamer's Black Ops 6 preview here</a>, where our Chris talks to Treyarch's senior director of production Yale Miller.</p>
<p>Yesterday, Microsoft unveiled its <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/microsoft-unveils-customisable-call-of-duty-blacks-ops-6-controllers-and-matching-xbox-series-x-wrap">customisable Call of Duty: Blacks Ops 6 controllers</a> and a matching wrap for Xbox Series X consoles, if you want to bedeck your kit ahead of the game's release.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Analogue's new console is a 4K N64 machine that uses original cartridges]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/analogues-new-console-is-a-4k-n64-machine-that-uses-original-cartridges</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/analogues-new-console-is-a-4k-n64-machine-that-uses-original-cartridges.1011924/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/analogues-new-console-is-a-4k-n64-machine-that-uses-original-cartridges<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>



            <p>Analogue has unveiled its next console, the Analogue 3D, that allows users to play original N64 cartridges in 4K.</p>
<p>The console follows Analogue's successful Analogue Pocket device that plays original Game Boy cartridges.</p>
<p>"Analogue 3D represents a milestone in video game preservation: it's not only the world's first reimagining of an N64 - but the world's first 100 percent-compatible recreation of an N64," reads the <a href="https://www.analogue.co/3D">company's website</a>.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Erogamer Newscast: New Nintendo Hardware, don't be alarmed it's not Switch 2." data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/GdNKD3U-4AY?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Erogamer Newscast: New Nintendo Hardware, don't be alarmed it's not Switch 2.</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/GdNKD3U-4AY?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/GdNKD3U-4AY?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Nintendo has announced new hardware, but it's not Switch 2 - so what's the point of Alarmo?<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GdNKD3U-4AY" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>"No more incompatibilities found in software emulation like input lag, graphic/audio inaccuracies, timing/frame rate issues and more. For the first time, you can re-experience the N64 exactly as it was meant to be, without compromise."</p>
<p>In addition, the console is region free, includes both bluetooth and wi-fi, and features four original-style controller ports.</p>
<p>Further, Analogue has created a new wireless controller with 8BitDo, though its modern design loses the iconic three prongs of Nintendo's original. It's sold separately for $39.99.</p> <div>
<div data-domain="twitter.com"><blockquote><div dir="ltr" lang="en"><p>Introducing Analogue 3D. A reimagining of the N64. </p><p>In 4K resolution. Perhaps the greatest multiplayer system of all time. Analogue 3D is the worlds first 100% compatible with every original N64 game ever made. Region Free. Bluetooth LE. Dual-band Wifi. Four original-style… <a href="https://t.co/7WM3ByIU6C">pic.twitter.com/7WM3ByIU6C</a></p></div>— Analogue (@analogue) <a href="https://twitter.com/analogue/status/1846567133788147838?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 16, 2024</a></blockquote></div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>The console itself comes in black or white and is available for $249.99 (about £192). Pre-orders will open on 21st October directly from the <a href="https://store.analogue.co/">Analogue store</a>, with shipping expected in the first quarter of 2025 (according to <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2024/10/250-analogue-3d-will-play-all-your-n64-cartridges-in-4k-early-next-year">ArsTechnica</a>).</p>
<p>On the product website, Analogue details the "unmistakable essence" of CRT to the look and feel of N64 games. As such, the console features original display modes to meticulously reproduce CRT displays. "Capturing the warmth, depth, and texture in every frame. The soft glow of phosphor and vibrant colours unite with immersive scanlines and shadow masks. This isn't just upscaling - it's an unprecedented transformation."</p><p>It certainly looks like a beautiful machine - especially if the Analogue Pocket is anything to go by. Of course, if you own a Nintendo Switch, you can play plenty of N64 games if you have a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/all-nintendo-switch-online-games-available-to-play-right-now">Switch Online Expansion Pack</a> membership.</p>
<p>Still, the Analogue 3D uses original cartridges, meaning the whole catalogue of games will be playable beyond the obvious Mario and Zelda favourites.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fallout Day Broadcast Announced For October 23rd]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/fallout-day-broadcast-announced-for-october-23rd/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fallout-day-broadcast-announced-for-october-23rd.1011921/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/fallout-day-broadcast-announced-for-october-23rd/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>This year's Fallout Day will be celebrated in style, with a broadcast that will give players a glimpse at the future of Fallout 76, the latest entry in the series.</p>
<p>As confirmed by Bethesda, Jon Rush and Bill Lacoste, Creative Director and Lead Producer of the latest entry in the series, will provide a new look at what the team is working on during the first-ever Fallout Day broadcast, which will air on October 23rd at 9:00 PM CEST/ 3:00 PM EST / 12:00 PM PST. FalloutforHope, a community-run charity initiative, will also be part of the festivities, as confirmed by a video message shared on the official X profile.</p>
<blockquote>
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Fallout Day is coming on October 23 where we will be hosting our first ever <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/FalloutDay?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#FalloutDay</a> Broadcast. Join Jon Rush and Bill LaCoste as they give you a glimpse at what we've been working on in Fallout 76.</p>
<p>The party keeps going from there with our friends <a href="https://twitter.com/FalloutForHope?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@FalloutforHope</a> for their… <a href="https://t.co/cLfkUGvlt8">pic.twitter.com/cLfkUGvlt8</a></p>
<p>— Bethesda Game Studios (@BethesdaStudios) <a href="https://twitter.com/BethesdaStudios/status/1846567782223106259?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 16, 2024</a></p></blockquote>

<blockquote>
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">A message from our friends <a href="https://twitter.com/FalloutForHope?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@FalloutforHope</a>. Come celebrate <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/FalloutDay?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#FalloutDay</a> with us on October 23! <a href="https://t.co/R54X9JKujl">pic.twitter.com/R54X9JKujl</a></p>
<p>— Fallout (@Fallout) <a href="https://twitter.com/Fallout/status/1846599662343475516?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 16, 2024</a></p></blockquote>

<p>While only Fallout 76 has been mentioned to be part of the broadcast, it would definitely make sense for Bethesda to take advantage of the occasion to speak more about what's in store for the future of the popular series, especially now that its popularity is at an all-time high thanks to the successful TV show by Amazon which has registered <a href="https://wccftech.com/the-fallout-tv-show-has-registered-100-million-viewers-to-date/">100 million viewers</a> to date. Even without Bethesda's involvement, however, fans of the series are still able to experience more Fallout in existing games thanks to high-quality fan-made mods, such as the incredible <a href="https://wccftech.com/fallout-london-is-now-available-for-download/">Fallout: London mod</a>, which finally brings the post-apocalyptic series outside the United States for the first time.</p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bohemia Used a Live Concert to Announce Arma 4 Coming in 2027]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/bohemia-used-a-live-concert-to-announce-arma-4-coming-in-2027</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/bohemia-used-a-live-concert-to-announce-arma-4-coming-in-2027.1011915/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/bohemia-used-a-live-concert-to-announce-arma-4-coming-in-2027<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>Bohemia Interactive chose an unusual venue to announce its next big game: a concert.</p><p>To celebrate its 25th anniversary, Czech studio Bohemia Interactive put together <a href="https://www.youtube.com/live/cC-uT5rc9HQ?feature=shared" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">a concert of video game music</a> performed by the Czech National Symphony Orchestra. The concert included songs from its Arma series, as well as DayZ, Ylands, and Vigor.</p><p>But the big surprise of the night was a blink and you’ll miss it announcement that <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/arma-iv">Arma 4</a> is due out in 2027. At the end of the final piece of the night, the game’s logo and release window flashed on the big screen that was propped up behind the orchestra for little more than a second, but it was long enough to catch the attention of the live audience as well as the livestream chat.</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/10/17/screenshot-2024-10-17-093220-1729154703401.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p>Arma is Bohemia’s hugely successful PC military shooter that first launched back in 2006. <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/arma-3">Arma 3</a> launched in 2013, with the latest release, the standalone <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/arma-reforger">Arma Reforger</a>, launching in 2022 in early access form before a 1.0 launch last year.</p><p>Reforger was designed as a “bridge” to Arma 4, which is intended for PC and consoles. Reforger was the first game in the Arma series to launch on console (Xbox Series X and S), and has helped Bohemia learn how best to take the PC-focused series multiplatform in a big way with Arma 4.</p><p>2027 is of course three years away, and it’s fair to say Arma fans had hoped to see Arma 4 come out before then. Already the memes about GTA 6 coming out before Arma 4 are flooding in, and we haven’t even suggested Arma 4 might be delayed. The question is, which consoles will Arma 4 launch on when it comes out in 2027?</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3>The Best PC Games</h3></div></output><p>At the time of this article’s publication, Bohemia had yet to make an official announcement about Arma 4 coming in 2027, release any notes to press or screenshots or trailers. Using a live concert for such a significant announcement is certainly novel, but hopefully the developer will follow it up with something more tangible sooner rather than later.</p><p><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Silent Hill 2 remake tops one million copies sold in less than a week]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/silent-hill-2-remake-tops-one-million-copies-sold-in-less-than-a-week</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/silent-hill-2-remake-tops-one-million-copies-sold-in-less-than-a-week.1011909/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/silent-hill-2-remake-tops-one-million-copies-sold-in-less-than-a-week<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>



            <p><a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/companies/bloober-team">Bloober Team</a>'s <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/silent-hill-2">Silent Hill 2</a> remake, which released earlier this month, has already managed to shift an impressive number of copies.</p>
<p>As shared by publisher Konami, the remake, which puts players back into the grief-riddled shoes of James Sunderland, has already sold a total of 1m copies (that's across both physical and digital media) since its global launch on 8th October.</p>
<p>In fact, Konami said the remake reached this sales milestone in less than a week, citing sales figures from 11th October. So, that's actually a whopping 1m copies in just three days.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Silent Hill 2 Review" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/vOv1JTfPnuQ?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Silent Hill 2 Review</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/vOv1JTfPnuQ?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/vOv1JTfPnuQ?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Here's Eurogamer's review for Silent Hill 2 remake in video form. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vOv1JTfPnuQ" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>As noted by industry insider DuskGolem, this rather zippy timeframe makes <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/silent-hill-2-remake">Silent Hill 2 Remake</a> the fastest-selling entry in the series to date.</p>
<p>What's more, while Bloober hasn't published sales of its previous games, this so far appears to be the company's biggest critical and commercial success to date.</p>
<p>As a slight aside (considering the two series were traditionally in competition on PlayStation), <a href="https://x.com/dev1_official/status/1846479698232324198">Capcom</a> also announced today its <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/resident-evil-4">Resident Evil 4</a> remake has now welcomed "eight million-plus agents" since its debut.</p>
<div>
<div data-domain="twitter.com"><blockquote><div dir="ltr" lang="en"><p>Silent Hill 2 Remake has surpassed 1 million units sold in less than a week (via Konami's press release, reached 1 million sales on October 11th).</p><p>Makes it the fastest selling Silent Hill game by far, &amp; certainly not bad for a PS5/PC exclusive releasing for a long dormant IP. <a href="https://t.co/OqpYs5kbI5">https://t.co/OqpYs5kbI5</a></p></div>— AestheticGamer aka Dusk Golem (@AestheticGamer1) <a href="https://twitter.com/AestheticGamer1/status/1846770601027162471?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 17, 2024</a></blockquote></div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>

<p>But, back to Silent Hill 2. It is fair to say today's sales milestone is well deserved for Bloober. The game has been met with widespread acclaim from critics and fans, who have praised the developer for its brillaint remake. </p><p>"Against the odds, Bloober Team has delivered a remake that both expands Silent Hill 2 in just the right places, and gives careful attention to what it preserves," our Vikki wrote in <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/silent-hill-2-remake-review">Eurogamer Silent Hill 2 Remake review</a>, awarding the game an impressive five out of five stars in the process.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hades 2 adds a boss fight against Prometheus and a lot more in a chunky update]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/hades-2-adds-a-boss-fight-against-prometheus-and-a-lot-more-in-a-chunky-update</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hades-2-adds-a-boss-fight-against-prometheus-and-a-lot-more-in-a-chunky-update.1011903/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/hades-2-adds-a-boss-fight-against-prometheus-and-a-lot-more-in-a-chunky-update<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
  

        <p>An unexplored region, new pets, and a shiny weapon</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/hades-2-prometheus-boss-olympian-update-1.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Supergiant Games</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>Praise the gods, it's <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/hades-2">Hades 2</a> update day, and developers Supergiant are not mucking about. They have bolstered the nippy roguelike with a heap of shiny new things in this "Olympian Update", including a new weapon with homing attacks, a liver-pecking boss fight, two new animal familiars, and the home region of the Gods - mount Olympus. It's probably the biggest update they've made yet in terms of fresh sights. And by "fresh sights", I mean Dionysus sporting a leopard-print thong. Yikes.</p>
<!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Hades II - The Olympic Update Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/WH3jT53hIYM?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Hades II - The Olympic Update Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/WH3jT53hIYM?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/WH3jT53hIYM?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WH3jT53hIYM" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>Chief among the changes is the new region, Olympus, which looks suitably full of marble statues and ionic columns, if suspiciously gloomy. The new weapon is called the Black Coat, which can launch a bunch of missile-like orbs at enemies or be used to perform damage-blocking counterattacks. Your two new animal familiars will be Raki the raven and Hecuba the hound, who can dig holes for you in place of the usual shovel, it seems. Yes, you can pet the dog. Don't make Frinos the frog jealous, now.</p>
<p>If you're wondering how much this update advances the story, we're told that there are now 2500 new voice lines,  plus "expanded subplots" for certain characters like Arachne the spider gal and Dora the friendly ghost. But the big new development in this regard is probably the appearance of Prometheus, the Titan that made humans from clay and then stole fire from the gods to give to humanity. You'll be fighting him as a boss, and likely learning a bit about his motivations. The eagle who chows on his liver every day also seeks extra protein from your face.</p><p>Like I say, it's an absolutely stacked update. You'll be able to decorate your hub at the Crossroads. Many hexes and keepsakes have been tweaked. There's new portrait art for Charon, Medea, and Hades, among others. And while Olympus is the big new hot spot, existing regions also have some new locales, we're told. I'm not even going to try to summarise the many, many changes to boons and blessings. Just know that there are some new boons, while others have been altered, and a few have been removed. </p>
<p>All the highlights are mentioned in <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1145350/view/7057794870232159705">this Steam post</a> but you can get into the nitty gritty of <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1145350/view/7057794870234137716">the full patch notes</a> if you like. Supergiant has even recorded <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PQtih_yy6IA">a 26-minute long "dramatic reading"</a> of the changes, featuring Logan Cunningham, voice actor of Homer and vocal calling card of the studio. This sounds like the most niche bedtime listening.</p>
<p>I found the fast pace and quippy conversatin' of Hades 2 a lot of fun in our <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/hades-2-early-access-review">early access review</a>. But I haven't been back to it much. Maybe this update will convince me to go check on my favourite rival, Nemesis. According to these patch notes, "she is less quick about gruffly running through exits; she is less quick to purchase items from Charon." Aw, I always <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/hades-2s-best-girl-is-nemesis-because-she-messes-up-your-run">liked that about her</a>. </p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Former PlayStation exec says there's a "collapse of creativity" in the industry]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/former-playstation-exec-says-theres-a-collapse-of-creativity-in-the-industry</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/former-playstation-exec-says-theres-a-collapse-of-creativity-in-the-industry.1011894/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/former-playstation-exec-says-theres-a-collapse-of-creativity-in-the-industry<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>Relying on blockbusters is "a death sentence".</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/shawnlayden-sony.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Sony</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>Former PlayStation exec Shawn Layden has discussed the state of the games industry, stating there's a "collapse of creativity" and that relying on blockbusters is "a death sentence".</p>
<p>Layden took to the stage at <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/everything-announced-at-gamescom-opening-night-live-2024">Gamescom</a> Asia alongside Raw Fury co-founder and chief publishing officer Gordon Van Dyke (thanks <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/shawn-layden-aa-is-gone-and-thats-a-threat-to-the-ecosystem-going-forward">GI.Biz</a>), where the pair discussed the disappearance of AA studios.</p>
<p>In the past, said Layden, studios focused simply on whether a game was fun rather than monetisation schemes, though admitted "risk tolerance was fairly high".</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Erogamer Newscast: New Nintendo Hardware, don't be alarmed it's not Switch 2." data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/GdNKD3U-4AY?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Erogamer Newscast: New Nintendo Hardware, don't be alarmed it's not Switch 2.</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/GdNKD3U-4AY?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/GdNKD3U-4AY?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Nintendo has announced new hardware, but it's not Switch 2 - so what's the point of Alarmo?<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GdNKD3U-4AY" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>"Today, the entry costs for making a AAA game is in triple digit millions now," he continued. "I think naturally, risk tolerance drops. And you're [looking] at sequels, you're looking at copycats, because the finance guys who draw the line say, 'Well, if <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/fortnite">Fortnite</a> made this much money in this amount of time, my Fortnite knockoff can make this in that amount of time.' We're seeing a collapse of creativity in games today [with] studio consolidation and the high cost of production."</p>
<p>Further, Layden stated "AA is gone", which he described as "a threat to the ecosystem".</p>
<p>Noting the general standard of games, including indie titles, is much higher thanks to advancements in tools, he continued: "Now if we can just get a bit more interest and excitement and exposure for these lower budget, but super creative and super unusual [type] of games... I'd like to see more of that. Because if we're just going to rely on the blockbusters to get us through, I think that's a death sentence."</p>
<p>AA games can bring "the new thing" and can be developed far quicker than AAA games, said Layden. Most importantly, though, they must seek unique ideas not monetisation.</p>
<p>"If you're going to pitch me your AA game, and in the first two pages of your deck is your monetisation and revenue, subscription scheme, I'm out. Your first page has to be 'This game needs to be made and here's why'," he said.</p>
<p>"I want to see that fire, I don't want to see 'here's the chief accountant on the team that's going to explain to you the [game's monetisation]'."</p>
<p>Layden also commented on current trends around <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/how-ai-is-changing-video-game-development-forever">AI in game development</a>, stating it's "not a saviour".</p>
<p>"Artificial intelligence has been in gaming since almost the first or second games ever made," he said. "So all this excitement about gen AI, I find kind of humorous. I do see its applications in certain places for certain things. But it's just a tool, it's not a saviour. It's a tool in the way that Excel is a tool. It just helps speed you along your tasks."</p>
<p>Layden began working for Sony in 1987, eventually serving as chairman of SIE Worldwide Studios from 2014 - 2019. He's worked as a strategic advisor at <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/companies/tencent">Tencent</a> since September 2022.</p>
<p>His comments are perhaps best reflected in games like <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/hi-fi-rush">Hi-Fi Rush</a>, a unique and creative concept that was certainly a risk for Tango Gameworks.</p>
<p>That studio was closed by Microsoft, but <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/tango-gameworks-and-hi-fi-rush-acquired-by-pubgs-krafton-following-microsofts-studio-closure-in-may">subsequently acquired by Krafton</a>. And Krafton boss Changhan 'CH' Kim has made comments that parallel those of Layden - specifically the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/krafton-acquired-tango-gameworks-to-maintain-its-legacy-rather-than-cash-in">studio acquisition was motivated by the desire to maintain its legacy rather than make money</a>.</p>
<p>"We wanted to maintain their legacy," said Kim. "Although they did not have a big success in their games, we saw many creatives worth pursuing. That's why we wanted to work with that organisation."</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Leadership at Don’t Nod are "creating an atmosphere of extreme violence” with planned layoffs, says French game workers union]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/leadership-at-dont-nod-are-creating-an-atmosphere-of-extreme-violence-with-planned-layoffs-says-french-game-workers-union</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/leadership-at-don%E2%80%99t-nod-are-creating-an-atmosphere-of-extreme-violence%E2%80%9D-with-planned-layoffs-says-french-game-workers-union.1011867/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/leadership-at-dont-nod-are-creating-an-atmosphere-of-extreme-violence-with-planned-layoffs-says-french-game-workers-union<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
  

        <p>The STJV "cannot tolerate the company rejecting the responsibilities of its own failures"</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/jusant-review-1.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>RPS/Don't Nod</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>Leadership at Don’t Nod yesterday “presented a reorganisation project to the employee representative bodies,” via <a href="https://www.dontnod-bourse.com/en/financial-information/press-releases?ID=ACTUS-0-88278">financials report</a>, in response to "a balance sheet that highlights the need to secure the company's resources" following the underperformance of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/jusant">Jusant</a> and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/banishers-ghosts-of-new-eden">Banishers: Ghosts of new Eden</a>.</p>
<p>In plain terms, this means that up to 69 workers at the French company are at risk of layoffs due to an 11% year-on-year decline in operating revenue, <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/dont-nod-announces-layoffs-that-could-impact-up-to-69-workers">via IGN</a>. The number represents "29% of the Paris studio workforce", say the STJV.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>"Our half-year results for 2024 reflect the economic underperformance of our latest release, despite solid ratings on Metacritic, as well as the accounting impact of the decisions we had to take," said Don’t Nod’s CEO and Chairman Oskar Guilbert. "The initial performance support measures announced last spring no longer seem sufficient to maintain the company's competitiveness.</p>
<p>"As a result," the statement continued, "today we presented a reorganisation project to the employee representative bodies, which could set DON'T NOD on a new development trajectory. I am fully conscious of the impact this project may have on all our employees. Securing our company's resources and restoring its ability to perform more in an increasingly competitive and selective industry is extremely necessary."</p>
<p>In late September, Don’t Nod <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dont-nod-pause-two-game-projects-and-refocus-others-following-jusant-and-banishers-sales-disappointment">announced that they’d paused development</a> on two upcoming projects, and that development on others had been "refocused to reach a wider audience", again citing the underperformance of Jusant and Banishers.</p>
<p>Back in early September, French Video Game Workers Union (STJV) put out a press release titled <a href="https://www.stjv.fr/en/2024/02/dont-nod-ascension-or-free-fall/">"DON’T NOD: Ascension or free fall?"</a>. "We’re sounding the alarm on the situation of Don’t Nod employees," they wrote, alleging "erratic" and "tumultuous" project management and citing concern over "the psychosocial hazards Don’t Nod’s workers are facing, in view of the significant number of reports of ill-being and sick leaves." The press release also describes a situation in which "Jusant’s developers were left in the dark about their future, many without any work to do, for over 2 months" following that game’s release.</p>
<p>Coinciding with Don’t Nod’s financial report yesterday, the STJV put out <a href="https://www.stjv.fr/en/2024/10/at-dont-nod-the-only-plans-for-the-future-are-layoffs/">another statement </a>entitled "At Don’t Nod, the only plans for the future are layoffs", calling the layoff plans "the climax of a series of catastrophic decisions".</p>
<p>"Today’s meeting, after 2 weeks of waiting in anguish, was revealed as the starting point of a layoff plan," write the STJV. "Workers’ representatives were not told in advance about the meeting’s topic, and were not provided with any documents and information before the it, which goes against the law."</p><p>"The Don’t Nod union section, as well the whole of the STJV, cannot tolerate the company rejecting the responsibilities of its own failures on its workers," they continue. "We warned them long ago, but they ignored us and accused us of being too aggressive to speak with. With this layoffs plan, they are creating an atmosphere of extreme violece [sic]. We are calling on all workers at Don’t Nod to mobilise to save their jobs and working conditions".</p>
<p>Alice Bell (RPS in peace) awarded both <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/banishers-ghosts-of-new-eden-review">Banishers: Ghosts of new Eden</a> and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/jusant-review">Jusant</a> a Bestest Best, and Jusant was a personal favourite of mine from last year. Best of luck to the workers who helped make such wonderful games.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The demo for Streets Of Rogue 2 lets you roleplay as the world's most violent chef]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-demo-for-streets-of-rogue-2-lets-you-roleplay-as-the-worlds-most-violent-chef</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-demo-for-streets-of-rogue-2-lets-you-roleplay-as-the-worlds-most-violent-chef.1011861/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-demo-for-streets-of-rogue-2-lets-you-roleplay-as-the-worlds-most-violent-chef<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>



            
<p>I punched a cultist in the face in <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/streets-of-rogue-2">Streets Of Rogue 2</a>, just because. He started running away - something I would not allow. When another robed cultist spotted what was happening, he tried to intervene, and a kind of Benny Hill pursuit chain began. We ran across a beach, through public toilets, and into the surf. In the end I had to knock them both out. As they lay unconscious, I worried they might soon wake and tell someone what I had done. This can't happen, I hate accountability. I punched their unawake bodies toward the sea in an effort to float the evidence away. But after a few punches the first man exploded into chunks of flesh. I am a murderer now. I was supposed to be a chef.</p>
<p>Streets Of Rogue 2 <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2165810/Streets_of_Rogue_2/">has a demo</a> out for Steam Next Fest, and while a lot of features are locked up behind the word "UNAVAILABLE" in red font, there's still quite a lot of mischief for you to get up to.</p>
<!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Streets of Rogue 2 - Official Reveal Trailer | gamescom 2023" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6f43pVHhGR0?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Streets of Rogue 2 - Official Reveal Trailer | gamescom 2023</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6f43pVHhGR0?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/6f43pVHhGR0?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6f43pVHhGR0" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>If you missed the first <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/streets-of-rogue">Streets Of Rogue</a>, it was a small but mighty indie immersive sim of sorts, with random roguelike elements thrown in to create a <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/streets-of-rogue-review">funny, chaotic sandbox of silliness</a>. You're supposed to be climbing floor after floor in an effort to find and dethrone the city mayor. But more often you end up freeing a troop of gorillas and watching as they run amok, or hacking all the ATMs while a co-op friend injects themselves with a syringe of gigantism. </p><p>The sequel is following suit, with a <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/streets-of-rogue-2-goes-open-world-and-you-can-drive-a-truck-through-a-barn">load of extra stuff thrown in</a>. Even something as simple as gathering chicken to craft a sandwich can take a comic turn for the worse. At first, I figured I'd simply buy some chicken fillets in the shop. But the only store in town was closed. What does that matter? I smashed the window and cut myself on broken glass clambering inside, only to find neither chicken in the freezer nor money in the cash register. </p>
<p>I washed my face in the staff bathroom, again because I can. This normally removes status effects. But my status was merely chickenless. I had to leave town and source my meat from the wilderness on the outskirts, where a gang of live chickens were frolicking happily in a pond. "I'll just kill a hen and watch the others run away in terror," I thought, getting out my trusty chef's pocket knife. But as soon as I stuck one chicken, four others immediately turned on me, pecking my poor body to pieces. </p>
<p>I barely managed to fend them off. And I had to go back to the shop to buy bread from the shopkeeper anyway, who had finally opened for business. I eyed the broken glass innocently. Shopkeepers in Streets Of Rogue 2 carry shotguns, just like the cranky hawkers of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/spelunky-2">Spelunky 2</a>. </p>
<p>There's a lot missing, this being a demo. But it does grant you a sneak peek at the possibilities. I created a vanilla world during the world generation process. But an encouraging amount of world modifiers are teased in the menu. You'll be able to make every animal invincible, it seems, or adjust a "cop leniency" meter. One modifier turns the game into "Water World", another reads "Zombies Ate My Game Balance", which suggests a means of transforming the game into a zombie apocalypse playground. </p><p>As for personal stats and quirks, these can include being computer illiterate, or being addicted to all drugs. You may need to kill at least once per day, or be unable to speak to people at all. One quirk makes you small enough to flush yourself down a toilet, like the shapeshifter of the previous game. Probably handy in a bind.</p>
<p>As part of the tutorial, I was sent to kill the mayor in a larger neighbouring town, which I did. But only after driving a car at questionable speeds and hitting many pedestrians along the way. The cars (a new addition) handle very nicely, drifting and sliding along with the smooth sensation of an old-school Grand Theft Auto. I parked neatly in the carpark of city hall, denting perhaps only five other vehicles, and got to work sneaking around inside the building, knife at the ready. I was discovered by goons and office workers multiple times. It was perhaps inadvisable to plant so many landmines in the hallways. Many people died. </p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/streets-of-rogue-2-wishlisted-3.jpg?width=1200&amp;height=1200&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Rock Paper Shotgun / TinyBuild</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Including the mayor himself. You're meant to be able to wear the mayor's hat after killing him, and give a speech at the podium to inherit his municipal throne. But at this point the tutorial bugged out and wouldn't detect that I wore the headwear. That's fine, demos gonna demo. It was nice just to kill the head honcho for once. I don't think I ever made it to the mayor in the first game, yet here I have smeared his internal organs all over his dining room in just over an hour. A satisfying result by itself. What? Why are you looking at me like that? It's not like there's going to be a "pacifist" mode in this ga-- oh, there is.</p><p>At this point I could wander out and explore the city streets, take some career quests as a chef, or restart things as a (probably much shootier) soldier or cop. But my "let this simmer" sense is tingling. I was already willing to trust this sequel on the playful strengths of its predecessor (it's one of our <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-roguelike-games-pc">best roguelikes</a>). But seeing firsthand that much of the wackiness and freedom of the original Streets Of Rogue remains intact is doubly reassuring. You can play the demo yourself on Steam, should you too wish to bash a bodyguard through the wall and inject yourself with a bunch of syringes marked: "???"</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[IO Interactive Wants to Create a 007 Gaming Franchise, Will Publish MindsEye from Rocket Boy]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/io-interactive-wants-to-create-a-007-gaming-franchise-will-publish-mindseye-from-rocket-boy/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/io-interactive-wants-to-create-a-007-gaming-franchise-will-publish-mindseye-from-rocket-boy.1011852/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/io-interactive-wants-to-create-a-007-gaming-franchise-will-publish-mindseye-from-rocket-boy/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>IO Interactive CEO Hakan Abrak has discussed the upcoming Project 007 game again. <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/project-007-io-interactive-young-bond-for-gamers-trilogy" target="_blank" rel="noopener">In an interview with IGN</a>, he openly said the goal is to make it a gaming franchise rather than a one-off project.</p>
<p><em>What's exciting about that project is that we actually got to do an original story. So, it's not a gamification of a movie. It's completely beginning and becoming a story, hopefully for a big trilogy out there in the future. And equally important and exciting, it's a new Bond. It's a Bond we built from the ground up for gamers. It's extremely exciting with all the tradition and all the history there is there together to work on this together with the family of creating a young Bond for gamers; a Bond that the gamers can call their own and grow with.</em></p>
<p><em>I don't want to speak too big about it, but I just hope we'll do a thing that will define James Bond in gaming for years to come. And that is not only one game, but that we create a universe for gamers to own for many years to come that we can grow with that next to the Bond on the movies.</em></p>
<p>Abrak also provided an update on development, saying that production at IO Interactive is going 'amazingly well.' That doesn't tell us when we can expect to learn more, but it's been nearly four years since the <a href="https://wccftech.com/project-007-announced/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Project 007 announcement</a>, and it might not be much longer until we get a proper trailer.</p>
<figure>
<div>

<div>
		
		
		<p><span>2 of 9</span>
	</p></div></div>
</figure>


<p>Meanwhile, IO Interactive has just signed an agreement with Build a Rocket Boy to publish <a href="https://wccftech.com/mindseye-everywhere-gta-producer-leslie-benzies-teaser-new-details/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">MindsEye</a>, the triple-A single player story-driven action/adventure game created with Everywhere's engine. Abrak said:</p>
<p><em>We are honored to be the global publishing partner working with Build A Rocket Boy’s exceptionally talented team and to bring our community an exciting new IP. IO Interactive and Build A Rocket Boy are like-minded in how we aim to create a bond and a long-term relationship with our communities, which perfectly aligns with our commitment to delivering high-quality, immersive experiences to players worldwide. As our first publishing partnership, this marks a significant milestone for IO Interactive, and we could not be prouder of this collaboration.</em></p>
<p>Game Director Leslie Benzies, who produced GTA games from III to V at Rockstar, added:</p>
<p><em>From day one, Build A Rocket Boy Studios has been focused on creating the next generation of compelling gaming and quality entertainment experiences. We can’t wait to share our first AAA premium game and ever-evolving universe, MindsEye, with the world. There is no finer partner than IO Interactive to publish our first title, with their strong understanding of community culture, premium action-adventure games, and a best-in-class publishing team, we really look forward to partnering with them on our new blockbuster journey.</em></p>
<p>In MindsEye, players will become Jacob Diaz, a former soldier with a mysterious neural implant who suffers from memory loss and flashbacks. They will embark on a series of dangerous covert missions to unravel the secrets of Jacob's past in a world filled with the constant threat of artificial intelligence, high-tech experimentation, corporate espionage, political corruption, and an unchecked military. According to the developer, they can expect complex narrative, rich environments, groundbreaking combat, futuristic technology, and high-speed chases. There's no release date yet, but you can add it to your <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3265250/MindsEye/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> wishlist.</p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Silent Hill 2 Remake Becomes Million Seller]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/silent-hill-2-remake-becomes-million-seller/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/silent-hill-2-remake-becomes-million-seller.1011849/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/silent-hill-2-remake-becomes-million-seller/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Today, KONAMI proudly announced that the Silent Hill 2 remake has sold over a million units globally across PC and PlayStation 5 as of October 11, according to the publisher's internal tracking. That's pretty impressive, given that the game only launched on October 8. It's another indicator of the game's great reception from critics and users alike. On Steam, the Silent Hill 2 remake didn't reach a massive peak, stopping at 23.6K concurrent users. However, user reviews are extremely positive, with 92.5% of the players leaving a favorable review. That's similar to the assessment provided by Chris Wray <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/silent-hill-2-restless-dreams-town/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">in Wccftech's review</a>, where he scored the game 9 out of 10.</p>
<p><em>Silent Hill 2 is the best game Bloober Team has made. A faithful reimagining of the original, bringing it to the modern day without losing what made the original the best horror game ever, using modern game mechanics to improve where they could, and expanding on what was already an engrossing world. Without any shadow of a doubt, a resounding success, one that will likely come as a surprise to many.</em></p>
<p>Unfortunately, the game <a href="https://wccftech.com/silent-hill-2-remake-pc-is-yet-another-unreal-engine-case-of-stutter-struggle/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">does have some technical shortcomings on PC</a>, mainly traversal stuttering, as in most recent Unreal Engine games. However, several mods attempt to improve the situation by adding certain lacking features, such as<a href="https://wccftech.com/silent-hill-2-remake-fsr-3-frame-generation-nvidia-dlss-ray-reconstruction-mod/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> AMD Frame Generation and NVIDIA DLSS Ray Reconstruction</a>. Another mod aims to enhance overall performance while minimizing the visual downgrade. Still, the only real fixes for the PC version's stuttering can come from Bloober Team via patches.</p>
<p>By the way, the Polish team has heavily <a href="https://wccftech.com/you-can-expect-this-isnt-end-of-adventure-with-konami-bloober-team-silent-hill-2/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">hinted</a> that the Silent Hill 2 remake won't be the end of their collaboration with KONAMI. Franchise fans are already wondering which of the other installments should be remade first. In any case, it will inevitably take several years; it's best to enjoy this remake and then move on until there's something concrete to announce.</p>

				

			
	<div>
		<h2>Products mentioned in this post</h2>
		
		<!--<p class="story-notice text-center">The links above are affiliate links. As an Amazon Associate, Wccftech.com may earn from qualifying purchases.</p>-->
	</div>

			
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon's New Full-Color Kindle Could Be A Game Changer For Comic Books]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/amazon-kindle-colorsoft-e-ink-color-ereader-comic-books-new-kindle-models-2024/1100-6527202/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/amazons-new-full-color-kindle-could-be-a-game-changer-for-comic-books.1011810/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/amazon-kindle-colorsoft-e-ink-color-ereader-comic-books-new-kindle-models-2024/1100-6527202/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="default-content">
        
          <p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p>
  
    <article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6527202">

            
            
    


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Amazon has revealed<i> </i><em>five </em>new Kindles, including its first full-color e-ink tablet. The <strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CN3XR57P?tag=gamespot-preorders-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Kindle Colorsoft</a></strong> is a brand-new addition to the lineup, and it's a potential game changer for fans of comic books and graphic novels. You can already read digital comics on any Kindle reader, but unless it has black-and-white illustrations, you lose a key component of the story. If the Kindle Colorsoft works well, you will be able to read all of your favorite full-color comics, graphic novels, and manga as intended, with the inherit benefits of an e-ink display. It releases October 30 and is available to <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CN3XR57P?tag=gamespot-preorders-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">preorder now for $280</a>.</p><p>The Kindle Colorsoft sounds even more appealing when you consider Amazon's <strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/kindle-dbs/cu/signup?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Comixology Unlimited subscription service</a></strong>. Comixology Unlimited offers over 45,000 comics, graphic novels, and manga for $10 per month (after a free 30-day trial). The catalog includes comics and graphic novels published by Marvel, DC, Dark Horse, Image, and other leaders in the visual storytelling medium. <strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/kindle-dbs/hz/subscribe/ku?tag=gamespot-promos-20&amp;tag=gamespot-buybutton-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Kindle Unlimited</a></strong> also has graphic novels and manga, but Amazon's $12/month flagship reading subscription service has a much larger focus on novels.</p><p>The Kindle Colorsoft releases <strong>October 30</strong> and is available to <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CN3XR57P?tag=gamespot-preorders-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">preorder now for $280</a>. We've rounded up all five of the new Kindles below, including the updated <strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CZ9VFQ2P?tag=gamespot-preorders-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Kindle Scribe</a></strong> with improved note-taking features, a faster version of the ever-popular <strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CFPJYX7P?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Kindle Paperwhite</a></strong> in models geared for adults and kids, and an <strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CNV9F72P?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">upgraded entry-level Kindle</a></strong>.</p><p><strong>Quick look: Amazon's All-New Kindles</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Preorder Now</strong><ul><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CN3XR57P?tag=gamespot-preorders-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Kindle Colorsoft</a> -- $280 | Releases October 30</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CZ9VFQ2P?tag=gamespot-preorders-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Kindle Scribe</a> -- Starting at $400 | Releases December 4</li></ul></li><li><strong>Available Now</strong><ul><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CFPJYX7P?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Kindle Paperwhite</a> -- Starting at $160 | Available Now</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CFPS7ZY9?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Kindle Paperwhite Kids</a> -- Starting at $180</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CFPS7ZY9?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Kindle</a> -- $110</li></ul></li></ul><div title="[Various] Kindle Colorsoft" data-embed-type="buylink" data-ref-id="2751" data-template="4" data-size="buylink__listicle" data-title="[Various] Kindle Colorsoft" data-collection="">             <h2>                    <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CN3XR57P?tag=gamespot-preorders-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/dp\/B0CN3XR57P?tag=gamespot-preorders-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CN3XR57P?tag=gamespot-preorders-20">Kindle Colorsoft</a>       </h2>                                   <h3>                      <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CN3XR57P?tag=gamespot-preorders-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/dp\/B0CN3XR57P?tag=gamespot-preorders-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CN3XR57P?tag=gamespot-preorders-20">$280 | Save 20% with Eligible Trade-In | Releases October 30</a>         </h3>                                                                                                                      <div><p>The Kindle Colorsoft has a 7-inch full-color display that lasts up to eight weeks on a full charge, which is pretty remarkable for a color e-ink tablet. Designed to be used anywhere, the Colorsoft's front light will automatically adjust to your surroundings. The high-contrast screen has built-in anti-glare technology to help create the Kindle's signature paper-like reading experience, just with a full color palette this time around. While reading, you can highlight passages in color, which sounds like a nice little benefit for those who regularly like to revisit to share their favorite sentences.</p><p>Amazon has labeled the launch-model Colorsoft a "Signature Edition." This may sound a bit confusing since it's the only model available at launch, but Kindle Signature Editions offer a handful of upgrades versus lower-priced models: support for wireless charging, auto-adjusting front light, no ads, and 32GB of storage. Signature Editions also have metallic chassises. The Metallic Black Colorsoft checks all of the Signature Edition boxes.</p><p>Amazon says it's totally safe to read in the bathtub or the pool, as the Colorsoft has an <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/browse.html?node=18116670011&amp;ref=ods_me_waterproof&amp;tag=gamespot-preorders-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">IPX8 water resistance rating</a>. In lab tests, the Colorsoft still functioned after being immersed in 6.5 feet (2 meters) of fresh water for up to 60 minutes. You probably won't want to bring the Kindle with you in ocean, though, as it's only graded for three minutes of immersion at less than 0.8 feet (0.25 meters) of depth.</p><p>As mentioned, the Colorsoft is especially exciting for fans of comic books, graphic novels, and manga. Being able to read your favorite graphic novels in color on a paper-like display could bring those who have wanted to switch to digital but weren't keen on the idea of looking at black-and-white illustrations into the ereader community.</p><p>At $280, the Colorsoft is cheaper than the Scribe but a good bit pricier than the Paperwhite. Amazon is running one of its generous trade-in promotions for existing Amazon device owners that can save you some serious cash. Trade-in values for your old devices vary, but what doesn't change is the 20% discount on the Colorsoft. You'll automatically save $56 plus however much you get for your old device. Click the "Save 20% with Trade-in" banner below the price to instantly see trade-in values for eligible devices. It doesn't even need to be a Kindle. Other devices, including cheap Fire TV Sticks, can get you the 20%-off deal.</p><p>Amazon is also offering a deal on the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Introducing-Amazon-Essentials-Plant-Based-Cover-Black/dp/B0DJ3RRNQX?tag=gamespot-preorders-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Kindle Colorsoft Essentials Bundle</a>, which comes with a plant-based leather cover and a wireless charging dock/stand for $328. You're saving $35 by purchasing the bundle compared to buying the Colorsoft and both accessories separately. Cases are available to purchase separately, too. Amazon has <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Amazon-Paperwhite-Lightweight-Water-Safe-Protective/dp/B0DGNVSYR5?tag=gamespot-preorders-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">fabric protective covers</a> in three color options for $37, while the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Introducing-Amazon-Plant-Based-Lightweight-Sustainability/dp/B0DGNSVTFK?tag=gamespot-preorders-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">leatherette covers</a> are $43. That means you'd spend $317 or $323 for the Colorsoft and one of the cases. The Kindle Colorsoft Essentials Bundle is probably the way to go here, as you'll only spend $5-$11 more to get the charging stand thrown in, too.</p></div>                      </div><p>Color e-ink has become a trend over the past year. Kobo, Amazon's biggest competitor, released its own full-color e-ink reader in April. The <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Kobo-Glare-Free-KaleidoTM-Audiobooks-Waterproof/dp/B0CZXX465Z?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Kobo Libra Colour</a> has a 7-inch full-color display and 32GB of storage for $220. But switching between brands after years of use is tough, as Amazon and Kobo have unique digital storefronts and file formats. You can't read Kindle ebooks on Kobo devices and vice-versa.</p><p>Most of the color e-ink tablets available now are more comparable to the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CZ9VFQ2P?tag=gamespot-preorders-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Kindle Scribe</a> as hybrid readers, note-taking, and productivity devices. For instance, Android e-ink tablet manufacturer Boox has released a few different full-color options, including the 7.8-inch <a href="https://www.amazon.com/BOOX-Tablet-Tab-Mini-ePaper/dp/B0CCJCXN25?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Boox Tab Mini C</a> for $400, the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/BOOX-Tablet-Note-Air-ePaper/dp/B0CHF423CP?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">10.3-inch Note Air 3 C</a>, and the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/BOOX-Tab-Ultra-Pro-Digital/dp/B0CHM54YZK?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">10.3-inch Tab Ultra C Pro</a> for productivity for $650.</p><p>And then there's reMarkable, the manufacturer behind the most popular note-taking e-ink tablet not made by Amazon, released its own full-color tablet in September. The $629 <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fshop-links.co%2F1856639036910958843%3Fu1%3Dsubid_value&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Famazon-kindle-colorsoft-e-ink-color-ereader-comic-books-new-kindle-models-2024%2F1100-6527202%2F%3Fftag%3DCAD-01-10abi2f%26utm_source%3Dgamefaqs%26utm_medium%3Dpartner%26utm_content%3Dnews_module%26utm_campaign%3Dhomepage&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">reMarkable Paper Pro</a> has an 11.8-inch display and is designed to replicate the experience of writing in a notebook.</p><p>Perhaps the next iteration of the Kindle Scribe will join the color e-ink party, too. For now, here's what's new with the Kindle Scribe and Amazon's other black-and-white ereaders.</p><p>All of the new Kindles are eligible for Amazon's 20%-off trade-in promotion.</p><div title="6527202 - Kindle Preorders" data-embed-type="buylink" data-ref-id="2750" data-template="4" data-size="buylink__listicle" data-title="6527202 - Kindle Preorders" data-collection="">                                                                     <div>             <h2>                    <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CZ9VFQ2P?tag=gamespot-preorders-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/dp\/B0CZ9VFQ2P?tag=gamespot-preorders-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CZ9VFQ2P?tag=gamespot-preorders-20">Kindle Scribe (2024)</a>       </h2>                                   <h3>                      <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CZ9VFQ2P?tag=gamespot-preorders-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/dp\/B0CZ9VFQ2P?tag=gamespot-preorders-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CZ9VFQ2P?tag=gamespot-preorders-20">Starting at $400 | Releases December 4</a>         </h3>                                                                                                                      <div><p>The updated Kindle Scribe now features new white borders, an updated screen with a paper-like texture for an improved writing experience, and a new Active Canvas feature that lets you write notes directly in your books. It comes bundled with the Premium Pen so you can draw, doodle, or jot down reminders during a meeting. It’s large 10.2-inch display is a good size for both reading or writing, and you can even share your files via email if you want to access them off your tablet.</p><p>The Kindle Scribe starts at $400 and is available in three different storage configurations: 16GB, 32GB, and 64GB. All three capacities can be purchased with a Tungsten chassis, and the 64GB is also available in Metallic Jade.</p><p>Multiple <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Amazon-Kindle-Scribe-Essentials-including/dp/B0DB2SP9VV?tag=gamespot-preorders-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Kindle Scribe Essential Bundles</a> are eligible for preorder discounts. For the 16GB model, the Essentials Bundle with a plant-based leather folio and AC adapter costs $435. Official Kindle Scribe cases cost more than $35, so if you preorder this one, it'd be a good idea to opt for one of the bundles. You can also <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Amazon-Kindle-Scribe-Essentials-including/dp/B0DB2RY4S5?tag=gamespot-preorders-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">get a bundle with a premium, natural leather folio</a> starting at $460.</p></div>                      </div>                                                                     <div>             <h2>                    <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CFPJYX7P?tag=gamespot-promos-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/dp\/B0CFPJYX7P?tag=gamespot-promos-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CFPJYX7P?tag=gamespot-promos-20">Kindle Paperwhite (2024)</a>       </h2>                                   <h3>                      <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CFPJYX7P?tag=gamespot-promos-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/dp\/B0CFPJYX7P?tag=gamespot-promos-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CFPJYX7P?tag=gamespot-promos-20">Starting at $160 | Available Now</a>         </h3>                                                                                                                      <div><p>This is the speediest Kindle on the market, as Amazon says it’ll get you 25% faster page turns than the previous generation. It also benefits from the highest contrast ratio in the Kindle lineup, which should result in crisper images and text. You’ll get a 7-inch display, 16GB storage, and up to three months of battery life, so you won’t have to worry about forgetting your charger when going on vacation.</p><p>It’s sold in three different colors and is available now. Prices start at $160 for the model with ads on the lockscreen. You can purchase the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Kindle-Paperwhite-Essentials-including-All-new/dp/B0DGRTBPKT?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Kindle Paperwhite Essentials Bundle</a> with a fabric cover and power adapter for $197. For $202, the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Kindle-Paperwhite-Essentials-including-All-new/dp/B0DGRLSRR7?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Paperwhite Essentials Bundle</a> comes with the leatherette case. </p><p>The new Kindle Paperwhite has the same form factor as the Colorsoft, so the two case options are the same: <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Amazon-Paperwhite-Lightweight-Water-Safe-Protective/dp/B0DGNVSYR5?tag=gamespot-preorders-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">fabric</a> for $37, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Introducing-Amazon-Plant-Based-Lightweight-Sustainability/dp/B0DGNSVTFK?tag=gamespot-preorders-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">leatherette</a> for $43.</p></div>                      </div>                                                                     <div>             <h2>                    <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CNV9F72P?tag=gamespot-promos-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/dp\/B0CNV9F72P?tag=gamespot-promos-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CNV9F72P?tag=gamespot-promos-20">Kindle (2024)</a>       </h2>                                   <h3>                      <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CNV9F72P?tag=gamespot-promos-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/dp\/B0CNV9F72P?tag=gamespot-promos-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CNV9F72P?tag=gamespot-promos-20">$110 | Available Now</a>         </h3>                                                                                                                      <p>The standard Kindle has also been upgraded, and it’s the most compact Kindle yet. It clocks at just 158 grams, and its 6-inch screen should make it easy to slip into a backpack or purse without taking up much space. It also benefits from a brighter front light, up to six weeks of battery life, and 16GB storage space. </p>                      </div>                                                                     <div>             <h2>                    <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CFPS7ZY9?tag=gamespot-promos-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/dp\/B0CFPS7ZY9?tag=gamespot-promos-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CFPS7ZY9?tag=gamespot-promos-20">Kindle Paperwhite Kids (2024)</a>       </h2>                                   <h3>                      <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CFPS7ZY9?tag=gamespot-promos-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/dp\/B0CFPS7ZY9?tag=gamespot-promos-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CFPS7ZY9?tag=gamespot-promos-20">$180 | Available Now</a>         </h3>                                                                                                                      <p>This version of the new Paperwhite comes with a durable cover to help protect it from the inevitable drops and scratches it’ll endure when placed in the hands of a young reader. You’ll also get a two-year worry-free guarantee and six months of Amazon Kids+ ($36 value), unlocking thousands of children’s books. Coupled with the included case, the new Paperwhite Kids reader is valued at $242.</p>                      </div>   </div><div data-embed-type="pinbox" data-ref-id="4304">  <ul>                              <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/amazon-kindle-colorsoft-e-ink-color-ereader-comic-books-new-kindle-models-2024/1100-6527202/">Amazon's New Full-Color Kindle Could Be A Game Changer For Comic Books</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-preorder-guide/1100-6524005/">Call Of Duty: Black Ops 6 Preorders - Bonuses, Game Pass Deals, Branded Gear, And More</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-this-75-bundle-has-all-you-need-to-play-no-console-or-pc-required/1100-6527064/">Call Of Duty: Black Ops 6 - This $75 Bundle Has All You Need To Play, No Console Or PC Required</a></li>                          <li>         <span>+ Show More More Gaming, Tech, and Entertainment Deals &amp; Preorders Links (5)</span>       </li>          <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/black-ops-6-gets-official-corsair-gear-call-of-duty-themed-gaming-pc-keyboard-mouse-and-more/1100-6526620/">Black Ops 6 Gets Official Corsair Gear - Call Of Duty-Themed Gaming PC, Keyboard, Mouse, And More</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/lego-nes-is-on-sale-for-20-off-this-week-save-54-while-supplies-last/1100-6526872/">Lego NES Is On Sale For 20% Off This Week - Save $54 While Supplies Last</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-legend-of-zelda-echoes-of-wisdom-is-already-discounted-but-not-for-long/1100-6527148/">The Legend Of Zelda: Echoes Of Wisdom Is Already Discounted, But Not For Long</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ps5-pro-preorders-live-at-amazon-walmart-and-best-buy/1100-6526406/">PS5 Pro Preorders Live At Amazon, Walmart, And Best Buy</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-xbox-elite-series-2-is-down-to-its-best-price-of-the-year/1100-6527087/">The Xbox Elite Series 2 Is Down To Its Best Price Of The Year At Amazon</a></li>   </ul> </div>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          

                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article>

    
  

</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[All Fortnite Ranks in Order]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/all-fortnite-ranks-in-order/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/all-fortnite-ranks-in-order.1011795/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/all-fortnite-ranks-in-order/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Venturing down the road of competitive Fortnite, but not sure exactly how many ranks there are in competitive? The popular game mode is full of some of the best sweats in the game, making it a hefty challenge to move up. Here is a list of all the Fortnite ranks in order from worst to best.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-fortnite-ranks">Fortnite Ranks</h2>



<p>The ranking system in Fortnite is similar to many other games as it starts with Bronze and then moves up. However, higher up in the ranking system is where the game differs from others.</p>



<p><strong>Here are all the Fortnite ranks in order:</strong></p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Bronze (I, II, III)</strong></li>



<li><strong>Silver (I, II, III)</strong></li>



<li><strong>Gold (I, II, III)</strong></li>



<li><strong>Platinum (I, II, III)</strong></li>



<li><strong>Diamond (I, II, III)</strong></li>



<li><strong>Elite</strong></li>



<li><strong>Champion</strong></li>



<li><strong>Unreal</strong></li>
</ul>



<p>After Diamond, each ranking is no longer split up into threes. Elite, Champion and Unreal are all their own ranking.</p>



<h6 id="h-ranked-esports-events-calendar-2024-every-tournament-you-need-to-see">Ranked:<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/esports-events-calendar-2024/"> Esports Events Calendar 2024 | Every Tournament You Need to See</a></h6>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-fortnite-s-old-system">Fortnite’s Old System</h2>



<p>Did you know that Fortnite used to have a completely different system for Ranked? In fact, it was not even called Ranked, instead, it was titled “Arena.”</p>



<p>Arena first left the game back in 2023, when Ranked officially replaced it. So, what was Arena? Well, the game mode went off of points and not rankings. </p>



<p>There were three different divisions, Open, Contender and Champion. Players who wanted to compete in FNCS had to be in Champion League. Fortnite often played around with how many points players needed to reach Champion League, but it was usually around 6,500. </p>



<p>In some seasons, once you reached a specific division, you would not fall back below that division even if your points dropped below. This ended up changing later on until Fortnite officially released Ranked.</p>



<p>Would you like to see Arena return?</p>



<p>Stay tuned to Insider Gaming for more <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/category/esports/">esports news</a>.</p>



<hr>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Werewolf game-style social deduction adventure game Yokai Landlord: Monster Mystery! announced for PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/10/werewolf-game-style-social-deduction-adventure-game-yokai-landlord-monster-mystery-announced-for-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/werewolf-game-style-social-deduction-adventure-game-yokai-landlord-monster-mystery-announced-for-pc.1011789/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/10/werewolf-game-style-social-deduction-adventure-game-yokai-landlord-monster-mystery-announced-for-pc<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Publisher FINE and developer <a title="Companies > Shadow Glove [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/shadow-glove">Shadow Glove</a> has announced <em><a title="Games > Yokai Landlord: Monster Mystery! [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/yokai-landlord-monster-mystery">Yokai Landlord: Monster Mystery!</a></em>, a Werewolf game-style social deduction <a title="Genres > Adventure [1,823 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure game</a> for <a title="Platforms > PC [21,485 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> (<a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3193560/_/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a>). It will launch in 2025 with English, Japanese, and Simplified Chinese language support. <span id="more-921811"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3193560/_/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam page</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>A Werewolf game-style social deduction adventure where you play as the landlord of an apartment and try to uncover the Yokai hiding among your residents. Not just a mystery adventure, this is a heart-warming tale of character growth.</p><p><strong>Story</strong></p><p>You are left all alone in the world after losing your last remaining relative, with only the apartment inherited from your late father.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Suddenly, a man appears and gives you—the new landlord—a warning.</p><p>“There are Yokai living among the residents in your apartment building.”</p><p>Your time spent sleuthing out the cleverly disguised Yokai began from that moment.</p><p><strong>Overview</strong></p><p>In this social deduction adventure game, the player uses the information they gather to find the Yokai who have attempted to blend in with the residents of the apartment building they manage.</p><p>But Yokai aren’t so easy to find. You will need to talk with residents, check the security cameras, and use the detailed information in the residents’ directory to gradually uncover the truth.</p><p>However, the Yokai may set traps in order to conceal their existence, causing the residents to become suspicious of one another. Just like in a Werewolf game, every word and action can sow the seeds of doubt.</p><p>As the landlord, it’s your duty to keep your residents safe, calmly gather information, and root out the true Yokai amongst the chaos.</p><p>And while you do, you’ll also unravel the true intentions behind the mysterious man who warned you about the Yokai…</p><p>Not just a mystery adventure! A heart-warming tale of character growth awaits you.</p></blockquote><div id="carousel_921816"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div><blockquote><p><strong>Gameplay</strong></p><p>Gather information from the residents to uncover the Yokai who are hiding among your apartment’s residents.</p><p>The residents will come to the player, as the new landlord, with complaints and requests, or just to have a chat.</p><p>This will give you the information you need to root out all of the Yokai.</p><p>If you notice anything in their conversations that feels out of place, that may be a clue to the Yokai’s identity. Note down anything important that you hear.</p><p><strong>Check the Apartment’s Security Cameras</strong></p><p>Yokai are cunning. Even with security cameras installed, that doesn’t mean they will reveal themselves so easily.</p><p>But you might be able to catch them dong something that’s not quite human-like when they think no one’s looking, or something they normally wouldn’t do when in their human forms.</p><p>Behavior that appears ordinary at first glance could be a hint. Keep no stone unturned, and root out the Yokai.</p><p><strong>Evict the Yokai Upon Discovery</strong></p><p>Evict the resident after you have gathered enough evidence and identified them as a Yokai.</p><p>But be careful, if you mistake a real human for a Yokai and evict them, the remaining residents will become even more suspicious of each other, which is exactly what the Yokai want.</p><p>Stay calm during your investigations and keep the residents safe until the day of the new <a title="Games > moon [8 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/moon">moon</a>, when the Yokai will reveal their true forms.</p><p><strong>If You Don’t Evict Them in Time…</strong></p><p>On the night of the new moon, the Yokai will display their true power.</p><p>When that happens, there will be nothing that we powerless humans can do.</p><p><strong>Future Plans</strong></p><p>We will also continue to make the interface compatible with translations.</p></blockquote><p>Watch the announcement teaser trailer below. View the first screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/yokai-landlord-monster-mystery/october-16-2024/">at the gallery</a>. Visit the official website <a href="https://oyaoya-ooya3.com/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">here</a>.</p><h2><span>Announce Teaser Trailer</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><p><iframe title="Yokai Landlord: Monster Mystery! - Teaser trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/p2lsan_V99Y?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe title="『おやおや？大家さん！』ティーザー予告" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZTLabAb7NBs?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Simplified Chinese</strong></p><p><iframe title="《哎呀哎呀？房东呀！》首發PV" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/TyV66qpBqAs?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[RPG Maker WITH for PS5, PS4 launches January 30, 2025 in Japan]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/10/rpg-maker-with-for-ps5-ps4-launches-january-30-2025-in-japan</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/rpg-maker-with-for-ps5-ps4-launches-january-30-2025-in-japan.1011774/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/10/rpg-maker-with-for-ps5-ps4-launches-january-30-2025-in-japan<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Currently available for Switch.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>The <a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,179 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a> and <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,331 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a> versions of <em><a title="Games > RPG Maker WITH [7 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/rpg-maker-with">RPG Maker WITH</a></em> will launch on January 30, 2025 in Japan for 8,580 yen, developer <a title="Companies > Gotcha Gotcha Games [27 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/kadokawa-corporation/gotcha-gotcha-games">Gotcha Gotcha Games</a> <a href="https://prtimes.jp/main/html/rd/p/000015658.000007006.html" rel="noopener" target="_blank">announced</a>. Pre-orders are available now at retailers such as <a href="https://www.amazon.co.jp/s?k=B0DK5NSMCN%7CB0DK5PDZV7%7CB0DK5M16GY%7CB0DK5L32VT" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Amazon Japan</a> and <a href="https://www.biccamera.com/bc/category/?q=RPG+MAKER+WITH&amp;entr_nm=Gotcha+Gotcha+Games" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Biccamera</a>. <span id="more-921802"></span></p><p><em>RPG Maker WITH</em> first launched for Switch on April 11 in Japan and October 11 in the west. The PlayStation 5 and PlayStation 4 versions are due out in 2025 in the west.</p><p>When the PlayStation 5 and PlayStation 4 versions launch, <em>RPG Maker WITH</em>‘s “Maker Plaza,” where users can publish created games and assets for others to download, will support cross-platform sharing across PlayStation 5, PlayStation 4, and Switch.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via western publisher <a title="Companies > NIS America [157 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/nippon-ichi-software/nis-america">NIS America</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>As the latest installment in the <em><a title="Genres > RPG [16,716 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg">RPG</a> Maker</em> series, <em>RPG Maker WITH</em> features more tools and greater accessibility than ever before. The user-friendly interface and intuitive controls make it easy to choose between creating simple or complex assets and functions, so you can dive right in, regardless of skill level. Not sure what to make? Head online to play other creators’ games and get inspired, then inspire others by sharing your own. And, for the first time ever in a console <em>RPG Maker</em> title, you can even share your assets and unfinished projects.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Create Your Way</strong> – Making your own game has never been easier! Whether you’ve never made a game or are a seasoned professional, user-friendly controls and options for simple to complex creations make it easy to dive right in.</li><li><strong>Share with Others</strong> – Share custom assets and unfinished projects! Post your creations online and play other creators’ games to gain inspiration, feedback, and inspire others.</li><li><strong>Oodles of Assets</strong> – Utilize premade sample games and tons of assets to help you get started working on your ultimate RPG! Then, flex your creativity even further by <a title="Genres > Crafting [21 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/crafting">crafting</a> your own assets from scratch once you’ve become familiar with all the tools <em>RPG Maker WITH</em> has to offer.</li></ul></blockquote></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Itch’s Domain Name Is Under Threat Because Of *Checks Notes* The…Decline Of The British Empire?]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/itch-indie-games-chagos-islands-rule-britannia</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/itch%E2%80%99s-domain-name-is-under-threat-because-of-checks-notes-the%E2%80%A6decline-of-the-british-empire.1011771/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://aftermath.site/itch-indie-games-chagos-islands-rule-britannia<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><a href="https://itch.io/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Itch.io</a>, if you don't already know it, is a wonderland of game ideas, rough sketches, works in progress and little indie surprises. You can't exist in game development, or love indie games, without having come into contact with it at <em>some</em> point.</p><p>The weird thing about Itch, though, is that the site isn't just known as Itch. You'll usually see it written about in full, domain extension and all, as Itch.io, in ways people would never do for, say, github.com. Even weirder is that,<a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/could-a-surprise-uk-territory-handover-spell-the-end-for-itch-io-" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> as Game Developer report</a>, the .io part of that name is now under threat for the most unlikely of reasons.</p><p>I'll be honest and say that, until this week, I had no idea what the .io even meant. Aftermath.site, that makes sense, we're a site! Ebay.com.au also makes sense, we all know .com is a business, and .au is Australia. But .io? I've just taken it for granted all these years, figuring it was some tech thing or coder thing or something I just didn't understand and had never bothered to learn.But no! Turns out .io is a <em>place</em>! And that place is the Chagos Islands, a tiny series of atolls in the Indian Ocean <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chagos_Archipelago" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">whose history is, well...</a></p><blockquote><p>The Chagos Islands had been home to the Chagossians from the 1700s brought as slaves by the French from Africa and India, a Bourbonnais Creole-speaking people, until the United Kingdom expelled them from the archipelago at the request of the United States between 1967 and 1973 to allow the United States to build Naval Support Facility Diego Garcia, a military base on Diego Garcia, on land leased from the UK military in the British Indian Ocean Territories. Since 1971, only the atoll of Diego Garcia has been inhabited, and only by employees of the US military, including American civilian contracted personnel. Since being expelled, Chagossians, like all others not permitted by the UK or US governments, have been prevented from entering the islands.</p><span><blockquote></blockquote></span></blockquote><p>It's essentially some rocks, with very nice beaches, that are outposts for the US military, built on land leased from the United Kingdom, which acquired the islands in 1814 as part of the treaty governing Napoleon's original surrender. Not the kind of scenario you associate with experimental indie game development, but it is what it is. It's .io specifically because, at the time of the creation of international domain extensions, the islands were listed as the British <strong>I</strong>ndian <strong>O</strong>cean Territory.</p><p>Those islands, despite being presently leased to the US, are actually one of the few remaining overseas possessions of the United Kingdom, and that's about to change because they're about to be handed over to Mauritius as part of an overdrawn (and overdue) exchange. And with that handover comes the risk of the .io domain extension no longer existing, since the Chagos will be folded into Mauritius (whose own extension is .mu, if you were wondering).</p><p>Itch's Leaf Corcoran<a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/could-a-surprise-uk-territory-handover-spell-the-end-for-itch-io-" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> tells Game Developer</a> that the site itself is obviously not going anywhere, but that they might in a worst-case scenario have to change domain extension, which sounds like an enormous pain both in terms of branding but also in policing external links and backlinks. Hopefully the internet's authorities can just leave .io up. If not, Ireland's domain extension (.ie) is probably the closest replacement, and would also be much funnier to read out loud.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Silent Hill 2 remake shipments and digital sales top one million]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/10/silent-hill-2-remake-shipments-and-digital-sales-top-one-million</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/silent-hill-2-remake-shipments-and-digital-sales-top-one-million.1011744/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/10/silent-hill-2-remake-shipments-and-digital-sales-top-one-million<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Milestone achieved three days after launch.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Total worldwide shipments and digital sales for the remake of <a title="Genres > Survival [332 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/survival">survival</a> <a title="Genres > Horror [508 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/horror">horror game</a> <em><a title="Games > Silent Hill 2 (2024) [8 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/silent-hill-2-2024">Silent Hill 2</a></em> have surpassed one million units worldwide as of October 11, publisher <a title="Companies > Konami Digital Entertainment [1,088 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/konami">Konami</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Bloober Team [86 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/bloober-team">Bloober Team</a> <a href="https://prtimes.jp/main/html/rd/p/000001019.000050711.html" rel="noopener" target="_blank">announced</a>. <span id="more-921789"></span></p><p><em>Silent Hill 2</em> launched for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,179 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a> and <a title="Platforms > PC [21,485 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2124490/SILENT_HILL_2/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> on October 8.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Konami:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Having received a letter from his deceased wife, James heads to where they shared so many memories, in the hope of seeing her one more time: <a title="Companies > Sile" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sile">Sile</a>nt Hill. There, by the lake, he finds a woman eerily similar to her…</p><p>“My name…is Maria,” the woman smiles. Her face, her voice… She’s just like her.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><a title="Companies > Experience [210 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/experience">Experience</a> a master-class in psychological survival horror—lauded as the best in the series—on the latest hardware with chilling visuals and visceral sounds.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>High-end Graphics and Sound</strong> – With ray tracing and other cutting-edge technical enhancements, the world of <em>Silent Hill</em> and its unsettling ambiance is even realer than before. And with the inclusion of new, immersive soundscapes, you’ll feel like you’re standing in the thick of it.</li><li><strong>Larger Environments</strong> – Explore locations and buildings that were once inaccessible, or are newly added in the remake.<br>Enjoy the same acclaimed story, even while you experience the town of Silent Hill with fresh eyes across an expanded map.</li><li><strong>Over-the-Shoulder Camera</strong> – The remake moves from the original’s fixed-camera viewpoints to an over-the-shoulder perspective, putting you closer to what James sees, for a more thrilling, more immersive experience as you explore the town and come face-to-face with monsters.</li><li><strong>Evolved Combat Gameplay</strong> – Familiar weapons like the steel pipe and handgun make their return, but now with an updated combat system. Avoid attacks with carefully timed dodges, aim down sights, and more, making monster encounters more engaging and nerve-wracking then ever.</li></ul></blockquote></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hades 2 gets new region, weapon, familiars, and more in first major early access content update]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/hades-2-gets-new-region-weapon-familiars-and-more-in-first-major-early-access-update</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hades-2-gets-new-region-weapon-familiars-and-more-in-first-major-early-access-content-update.1011711/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/hades-2-gets-new-region-weapon-familiars-and-more-in-first-major-early-access-update<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/hades-2-art.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Supergiant Games</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
Five months after bursting into PC early access, Hades 2 - the sequel to Supergiant Games' much-loved 2020 roguelike action-adventure - has just received its first major content update, adding a new region, weapon, and so much else its patch notes weigh in at over 3,500 words.
</p>
<p>
Hades 2's Olympic Update ("practically mountain-sized!", exclaims Supergiant) starts with the addition of a brand-new region - one you'll probably already have guess based on the name of today's release. If it's concrete information you want, though, we'll need to delve into spoiler territory - so <strong>turn back right now</strong> if you're sensitive to that kind of thing, otherwise I'll just get on and confirm Hades 2 players can now explore Olympus, the mountain of the gods.
</p>
<p>
Olympus consists of multiple new locations, and Supergiant notes today's update also adds new locations to several other existing regions. That's alongside an "otherworldly" new weapon - Xinth's Black Coat, to be more specific - plus two new allies with unique Keepsakes, and two new Animal Familiars (Raki the Raven and Hecuba the Hound) to find.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Hades II - The Olympic Update Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/WH3jT53hIYM?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Hades II - The Olympic Update Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/WH3jT53hIYM?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/WH3jT53hIYM?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Hades 2's Olympic Update trailer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WH3jT53hIYM" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
Elsewhere in Hades 2's Olympic Update, those looking to spruce up the Crossroads a little now have access to "dozens" of new cosmetic items, while Supergiant also promises "hours" of new dialogue (spanning 2,500 new voice lines) as the game's plot picks up the pace thanks to the arrival of Olympus and its denizens. Other key additions include a new world map that appears as protagonist Melinoë moves between regions, plus native support for Apple's M1 Macs.
</p><p>
Supergiant's full patch notes are appropriately supergiant in nature, so I won't be appending the whole thing to the bottom of this page. Instead, you'll find <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1145350/view/7057794870234137716?l=english">all 3,500+ words covering Hades 2's latest additions</a> over on Steam; alternatively, Supermassive has brilliantly released a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PQtih_yy6IA">nearly 27-minute long dramatic reading</a> of the whole thing.
</p>
<p>
Hades 2 is currently expected to leave early access next year, and a release for unspecified consoles is also on the cards. Already, though, it's a bit of a treat, with Eurogamer contributor Christian Donlan <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/hades-2-early-access-review">calling it</a> "comfortable and familiar" and armed with the "power of surprise".
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Disney World's New Line-Skipping Pass Costs Up To $450 A Day Per Person]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/disney-lightning-pass-premier-costs-disneyland-world-1851674534</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/disney-worlds-new-line-skipping-pass-costs-up-to-450-a-day-per-person.1011705/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/disney-lightning-pass-premier-costs-disneyland-world-1851674534<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Disney has announced a new way to skip the lines at its parks. But depending on where you go and when, you might have to spend over $400 a day per person to take advantage of the new Lightning Lane Premier Pass.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="194664" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Disney's New Post-Apocalyptic Anime Proves The Mouse Has Good Taste" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="162" data-playlist="194664,193897,196115" data-current="194664"><div><p>Disney's New Post-Apocalyptic Anime Proves The Mouse Has Good Taste</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/194664/194664_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/194664/194664_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/194664/194664_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/194664/194664_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/20130.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>On Wednesday, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://apnews.com/article/disney-lightning-premier-disneyland-84d74db76e8222845bfd4ef9b152c810&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://apnews.com/article/disney-lightning-premier-disneyland-84d74db76e8222845bfd4ef9b152c810" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Disney announced</a></span> its plans to roll out a new tier of Lightning Lane, a pre-existing program that lets visitors pay extra to skip the lines for certain rides in Disney World and Disneyland. Previously, Lightning Lane Multi Passes, which let you skip the line on multiple rides, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://disneyland.disney.go.com/lightning-lane-passes/#faqItem2&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://disneyland.disney.go.com/lightning-lane-passes/#faqItem2" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">cost $32 a day</a></span> per person, though the price could increase for various reasons. These passes forced guests to select a time to arrive for their “line skip,” which could cause problems if you were late. This newly announced tier of line skipping, Premier Pass, does away with that restriction, but at a steep cost. </p><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.gamespot.com/articles/disney-worlds-new-line-skipping-service-charges-up-to-450-per-day/1100-6527195/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/disney-worlds-new-line-skipping-service-charges-up-to-450-per-day/1100-6527195/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">As spotted by <em>GameSpot</em></a></span>, the new “Premier” pass—which will be available later this month—<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://disneyworld.disney.go.com/lightning-lane-passes/lightning-lane-premier/#faqItem1&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://disneyworld.disney.go.com/lightning-lane-passes/lightning-lane-premier/#faqItem1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">will cost up to $450 a day per person at Disney World</a></span>. The price varies depending on the park and when you go, with Disney saying that the highest prices will be found on a “limited number of days over peak travel periods.” </p><p>Here are the prices for each park, but keep in mind that you still need to buy a ticket to the park, and at Disney World, only folks staying in Disney World hotels on property will be eligible to buy these new, limited passes. </p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li>Disney’s Animal Kingdom: $129 to $199</li><li>EPCOT: $169 to $249</li><li>Disney’s Hollywood Studios: $269 to $349</li><li>Magic Kingdom: $329 to $449</li></ul><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://people.com/disney-lightning-lane-premier-pass-costs-449-how-to-buy-8729064#:~:text=Disney%20World's%20New%20'Premier%20Pass,on%20Top%20of%20Park%20Ticket&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://people.com/disney-lightning-lane-premier-pass-costs-449-how-to-buy-8729064#:~:text=Disney%20World's%20New%20'Premier%20Pass,on%20Top%20of%20Park%20Ticket" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Meanwhile, at Disneyland</a></span>, the Premier pass will cost $400 per person until December 31. In 2025, the pass will drop to $300 to $400 a day per person, based on what dates you visit. </p><p>In 2023, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://blogmickey.com/2023/03/bob-iger-reiterates-the-need-to-make-the-price-of-a-disney-vacation-more-accessible/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://blogmickey.com/2023/03/bob-iger-reiterates-the-need-to-make-the-price-of-a-disney-vacation-more-accessible/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Disney CEO Bob Iger said</a></span> that the massive company had been “too aggressive” about increasing prices at the parks and wanted to make them more “accessible.” This, uh, doesn’t seem like a good way to do that. And sure, you can argue that people don’t <em>need</em> to buy these passes, that they can just wait in line, but ride queues can get quite long and waiting sucks. Besides, the big appeal of Disney World and Disneyland is the rides! And making it more expensive to actually enjoy them seems like the opposite of making your parks more accessible to more people.</p><p> .<br></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Magic: The Gathering Pixel Perfect Secret Lair Brings Retro Vibes to the Table]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/magic-gathering-pixel-perfect-secret-lair-brings-retro-vibes-to-table</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-magic-the-gathering-pixel-perfect-secret-lair-brings-retro-vibes-to-the-table.1011687/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/magic-gathering-pixel-perfect-secret-lair-brings-retro-vibes-to-table<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Wizards of the Coast has announced a new <a href="https://techraptor.net/games/magic-the-gathering" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><em>Magic: The Gathering</em></a> <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/new-magic-gathering-camp-totally-safe-secret-lair-brings-tricks-and-treats" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Secret Lair</a>. The aptly named Pixel Perfect Secret Lair contains card artwork inspired by 16-bit pixel art games. Furthermore, proceeds from the drop will go to Extra Life.</p>

<p>The Pixel Perfect Secret Lair was announced <a href="https://secretlair.wizards.com/us/extralife2024#filter-product-1018598|sort-availability_wotc,featured">via blog post</a> on the <em>Magic: The Gathering</em> website. It is a limited time drop available in both foil (MSRP $49.99) and non-foil (MSRP $39.99). According to the drop's description, 50% of the drop's sales will go to the fundraising program Extra Life.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/magic-the-gathering-pixel-perfect-secret-lair-card-artwork.jpg?itok=oq6DhWOE 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/magic-the-gathering-pixel-perfect-secret-lair-card-artwork.jpg?itok=SLE8kTRO 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>For that price, you'll get four cards in the Pixel Perfect Secret Lair. The cards in the drop are <em>Mana Geyser</em>, <em>Lightning Bolt</em>, <em>Fierce Guardianship</em>, and <em>Delayed Blast Fireball. </em>Each of these four cards contains pixel art by Mike Burns. That artwork depicts the Fbithp braving a lava-filled dungeon to do battle with the powerful dragon planeswalker Nico Bolas.</p>
<p>The pixel art is packed with small but important details. Background details like Nico Bolas' symbol. Fbithp having a heart gauge in the upper left corner. Nico Bolas having a large boss health bar. The card descriptions depicted as textboxes by planeswalker Ajani. It all comes together to sell the retro sidescroller aesthetic.</p>
<p>Extra Life was founded in 2008 as a fundraising program of Children's Miracle Network hospitals led by the gaming community. Since its inception, the program has raised $120 million for critical pediatric needs at local hospitals across the United States and Canada.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Wizards of the Coast has helped donate money to their cause in the past through similar <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/wizards-of-coast-partners-with-extra-life-2022" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Secret Lair</a> events. Specifically, their proceeds go to support the Seattle Children's Autism Center.</p>
<p>The Pixel Perfect Secret Lair is available for pre-order right now. The Secret Lair will be available until November 18, 2024.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Ever since he was small, Tyler Chancey has had a deep, abiding love for video games and a tendency to think and overanalyze everything he enjoyed. This… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/tyler-chancey">More about Tyler</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Matthew McConaughey Saying Cool Sci-Fi Nonsense Over Pretty Concept Art Is Peak Video Game Trailer]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/exodus-trailer-scifi-rpg-matthew-mcconaughey-1851674488</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/matthew-mcconaughey-saying-cool-sci-fi-nonsense-over-pretty-concept-art-is-peak-video-game-trailer.1011684/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/exodus-trailer-scifi-rpg-matthew-mcconaughey-1851674488<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>A space ship flying through a beautiful but menacing nebula. Cosmic horrors that feast on dreams and memories. That’s our latest look at <em>Exodus</em>, the sci-fi action RPG helmed by two ex-BioWare devs <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/matthew-mcconaughey-exodus-space-game-awards-trailer-1851082938&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/matthew-mcconaughey-exodus-space-game-awards-trailer-1851082938">starring Matthew McConaughey</a></span>, and it could very well be the most alluring and exciting this game is.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196307" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="10 Minutes From The Last Of Us Part II’s Roguelike Mode " data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="657" data-playlist="196307,196909,195891" data-current="196307"><div><p>10 Minutes From The Last Of Us Part II’s Roguelike Mode </p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196307/196307_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196307/196307_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196307/196307_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196307/196307_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21857.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p><em>Exodus</em> was revealed at last year’s Game Awards and the studio behind it, Archetype Entertainment, is building up to a proper gameplay reveal via additional cinematic trailers and Q&amp;As with the studio founders, James Ohlen (<em>Dragon Age: Origins</em>) and Chad Robertson (<em>Anthem</em>). Maybe it’s all leading up to another big trailer at the next Game Awards this December. In the meantime we have 90 seconds of McConaughey reprising his energy from <em>True Detective</em> season 1 to describe the game’s main villains, The Mara Yama.</p><p>“Do you know what fear is?” the <em>Interstellar</em> astronaut asks. “The Mara Yama do. They thrive on it. These monstrous celestials haunt the darkest corners of the cluster hunting for isolated targets, and, unfortunately for their victims, the Mara Yama are interested in stealing more than just cargo. They want minds. Memories. Emotions. The more twisted and tortured, the better.”</p><p> <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=A8x73UW8Hjk&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=A8x73UW8Hjk" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Smell the psychosphere much</a></span>?</p><p>  <em>Exodus</em>, which is promising to let players engage with the consequences of their actions between the past and future through a unique time dilation mechanic, might end up being the next <em>Mass Effect</em> or <em>Destiny</em>. Or it could be another interesting but flawed AAA experiment from a new studio still finding its footing amid a grim video game industry landscape. Either way, I’m willing to bet that it never feels as full of violent, weird, and imaginative possibility as it does in this trailer. </p><p>Real games, the ones that survive a brutal series of trade-offs, compromises, and unexpected pitfalls to come out the other end a finished product on a store shelf or download queue, are almost never as good <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/the-god-of-war-weve-already-been-playing-in-our-heads-1824356326&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/the-god-of-war-weve-already-been-playing-in-our-heads-1824356326">as the versions of them we dream up</a></span> while we’re waiting for them to arrive. I don’t expect it to be any different with <em>Exodus</em>, which is coming to PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X/S, and PC, but still doesn’t have any kind of release window. At least we’ll always have this incredible teaser. </p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kingdom Hearts Fans Have Another Chance To Get Nintendo's Sora Amiibo]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/kingdom-hearts-fans-have-another-chance-to-get-nintendos-sora-amiibo/1100-6519863/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/kingdom-hearts-fans-have-another-chance-to-get-nintendos-sora-amiibo.1011681/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/kingdom-hearts-fans-have-another-chance-to-get-nintendos-sora-amiibo/1100-6519863/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="default-content">
        
          <p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p>
  
    <article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6519863">

            
            
    


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>One of the most elusive and sought-after <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/amiibo-nintendo-switch-restocks-reprints-2024/2900-5671/" data-ref-id="2900-5671">Nintendo Switch Amiibo figures</a> is receiving a reprint: Sora from Kingdom Hearts. The Keyblade wielder has been hard to find for a reasonable price since launching in February, but now it's the latest popular figure scheduled for a re-release. The Sora Amiibo reprint releases <strong>November 7</strong> and is available to <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fclick.linksynergy.com%2Fdeeplink%3Fid%3DVZfI20jEa0c%26mid%3D24348%26u1%3Dsubid_value%26murl%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Fconsoles-hardware%2Fnintendo-switch%2Fnintendo-switch-amiibo%2Fproducts%2Fsuper-smash-bros.-series-sora-kingdom-hearts-amiibo%2F403500.html&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fkingdom-hearts-fans-have-another-chance-to-get-nintendos-sora-amiibo%2F1100-6519863%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">preorder for $16 at GameStop</a> and <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fshop-links.co%2F1827843303217347672%3Fu1%3Dsubid_value&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fkingdom-hearts-fans-have-another-chance-to-get-nintendos-sora-amiibo%2F1100-6519863%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Best Buy</a>.</p><p><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fclick.linksynergy.com%2Fdeeplink%3Fid%3DVZfI20jEa0c%26mid%3D24348%26u1%3Dsubid_value%26murl%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Fsearch%2F%3Fq%3Damiibo%26lang%3Ddefault%26start%3D0%26sz%3D20&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fkingdom-hearts-fans-have-another-chance-to-get-nintendos-sora-amiibo%2F1100-6519863%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">GameStop actually has a bunch of Amiibo figures</a> that were previously sold out, so make sure to take a look at other figures, especially since GameStop requires customers to spend over $79 to get free shipping. Some of the highlights include the <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fclick.linksynergy.com%2Fdeeplink%3Fid%3DVZfI20jEa0c%26mid%3D24348%26u1%3Dsubid_value%26murl%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Fconsoles-hardware%2Fnintendo-switch%2Fnintendo-switch-amiibo%2Fproducts%2Fsuper-smash-bros.-series-steve-and-alex-amiibo-2-pack%2F348042.html&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fkingdom-hearts-fans-have-another-chance-to-get-nintendos-sora-amiibo%2F1100-6519863%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Minecraft Steve and Alex combo pack</a>, <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fclick.linksynergy.com%2Fdeeplink%3Fid%3DVZfI20jEa0c%26mid%3D24348%26u1%3Dsubid_value%26murl%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Fconsoles-hardware%2Fnintendo-switch%2Fnintendo-switch-amiibo%2Fproducts%2Fsuper-smash-bros.-ness-amiibo-gamestop-exclusive%2F111544.html&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fkingdom-hearts-fans-have-another-chance-to-get-nintendos-sora-amiibo%2F1100-6519863%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Ness</a> from Smash Bros. (and Earthbound/Mother), <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fclick.linksynergy.com%2Fdeeplink%3Fid%3DVZfI20jEa0c%26mid%3D24348%26u1%3Dsubid_value%26murl%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Fconsoles-hardware%2Fnintendo-switch%2Fnintendo-switch-amiibo%2Fproducts%2Fsuper-smash-bros.-mr.-game-and-watch-amiibo-gamestop-exclusive%2F409892.html&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fkingdom-hearts-fans-have-another-chance-to-get-nintendos-sora-amiibo%2F1100-6519863%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Mr. Game &amp; Watch</a>, <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fclick.linksynergy.com%2Fdeeplink%3Fid%3DVZfI20jEa0c%26mid%3D24348%26u1%3Dsubid_value%26murl%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Fconsoles-hardware%2Fnintendo-switch%2Fnintendo-switch-amiibo%2Fproducts%2Fsuper-smash-bros.-duck-hunt---duck-hunt-amiibo%2F406393.html&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fkingdom-hearts-fans-have-another-chance-to-get-nintendos-sora-amiibo%2F1100-6519863%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Duck Hunt</a>, the original Nintendo robot accessory <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fclick.linksynergy.com%2Fdeeplink%3Fid%3DVZfI20jEa0c%26mid%3D24348%26u1%3Dsubid_value%26murl%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Fconsoles-hardware%2Fnintendo-switch%2Fnintendo-switch-amiibo%2Fproducts%2Fsuper-smash-bros.-r.o.b.-amiibo%2F406391.html&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fkingdom-hearts-fans-have-another-chance-to-get-nintendos-sora-amiibo%2F1100-6519863%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">R.O.B.</a></p><p><strong>GameStop Amiibo Restock (October 2024)</strong></p><ul><li><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fclick.linksynergy.com%2Fdeeplink%3Fid%3DVZfI20jEa0c%26mid%3D24348%26u1%3Dsubid_value%26murl%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Fconsoles-hardware%2Fnintendo-switch%2Fnintendo-switch-amiibo%2Fproducts%2Fsuper-smash-bros.-series-sora-kingdom-hearts-amiibo%2F403500.html&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fkingdom-hearts-fans-have-another-chance-to-get-nintendos-sora-amiibo%2F1100-6519863%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Sora</a> -- $16 | Releases November 7</li><li><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fclick.linksynergy.com%2Fdeeplink%3Fid%3DVZfI20jEa0c%26mid%3D24348%26u1%3Dsubid_value%26murl%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Fconsoles-hardware%2Fnintendo-switch%2Fnintendo-switch-amiibo%2Fproducts%2Fsuper-smash-bros.-series-steve-and-alex-amiibo-2-pack%2F348042.html&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fkingdom-hearts-fans-have-another-chance-to-get-nintendos-sora-amiibo%2F1100-6519863%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Minecraft Steve and Alex 2-Pack</a> -- $30</li><li><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fclick.linksynergy.com%2Fdeeplink%3Fid%3DVZfI20jEa0c%26mid%3D24348%26u1%3Dsubid_value%26murl%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Fconsoles-hardware%2Fnintendo-switch%2Fnintendo-switch-amiibo%2Fproducts%2Fsuper-smash-bros.-ness-amiibo-gamestop-exclusive%2F111544.html&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fkingdom-hearts-fans-have-another-chance-to-get-nintendos-sora-amiibo%2F1100-6519863%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Ness (Exclusive)</a> -- $16</li><li><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fclick.linksynergy.com%2Fdeeplink%3Fid%3DVZfI20jEa0c%26mid%3D24348%26u1%3Dsubid_value%26murl%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Fconsoles-hardware%2Fnintendo-switch%2Fnintendo-switch-amiibo%2Fproducts%2Fxenoblade-noah-amiibo%2F414530.html&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fkingdom-hearts-fans-have-another-chance-to-get-nintendos-sora-amiibo%2F1100-6519863%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Noah from Xenoblade Chronicles (Preowned)</a> -- $20</li><li><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fclick.linksynergy.com%2Fdeeplink%3Fid%3DVZfI20jEa0c%26mid%3D24348%26u1%3Dsubid_value%26murl%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Fconsoles-hardware%2Fnintendo-switch%2Fnintendo-switch-amiibo%2Fproducts%2Fsuper-smash-bros.-terry-amiibo%2F234564.html&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fkingdom-hearts-fans-have-another-chance-to-get-nintendos-sora-amiibo%2F1100-6519863%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Terry Bogard from Fatal Fury/King of Fighters</a> -- $16</li><li><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fclick.linksynergy.com%2Fdeeplink%3Fid%3DVZfI20jEa0c%26mid%3D24348%26u1%3Dsubid_value%26murl%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Fconsoles-hardware%2Fnintendo-switch%2Fnintendo-switch-amiibo%2Fproducts%2Fsuper-smash-bros.-r.o.b.-amiibo%2F406391.html&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fkingdom-hearts-fans-have-another-chance-to-get-nintendos-sora-amiibo%2F1100-6519863%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">R.O.B.</a> -- $16</li><li><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fclick.linksynergy.com%2Fdeeplink%3Fid%3DVZfI20jEa0c%26mid%3D24348%26u1%3Dsubid_value%26murl%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Fconsoles-hardware%2Fnintendo-switch%2Fnintendo-switch-amiibo%2Fproducts%2Fsuper-smash-bros.-duck-hunt---duck-hunt-amiibo%2F406393.html&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fkingdom-hearts-fans-have-another-chance-to-get-nintendos-sora-amiibo%2F1100-6519863%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Duck Hunt</a> -- $16</li><li><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fclick.linksynergy.com%2Fdeeplink%3Fid%3DVZfI20jEa0c%26mid%3D24348%26u1%3Dsubid_value%26murl%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Fconsoles-hardware%2Fnintendo-switch%2Fnintendo-switch-amiibo%2Fproducts%2Fsuper-smash-bros.-mr.-game-and-watch-amiibo-gamestop-exclusive%2F409892.html&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fkingdom-hearts-fans-have-another-chance-to-get-nintendos-sora-amiibo%2F1100-6519863%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Mr. Game &amp; Watch</a> -- $16</li><li><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fclick.linksynergy.com%2Fdeeplink%3Fid%3DVZfI20jEa0c%26mid%3D24348%26u1%3Dsubid_value%26murl%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Fconsoles-hardware%2Fnintendo-switch%2Fnintendo-switch-amiibo%2Fproducts%2Fsuper-smash-bros.-pokemon-pikachu-amiibo%2F406394.html&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fkingdom-hearts-fans-have-another-chance-to-get-nintendos-sora-amiibo%2F1100-6519863%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Pikachu</a> -- $16</li><li><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fclick.linksynergy.com%2Fdeeplink%3Fid%3DVZfI20jEa0c%26mid%3D24348%26u1%3Dsubid_value%26murl%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Fconsoles-hardware%2Fnintendo-switch%2Fnintendo-switch-amiibo%2Fproducts%2Fsuper-smash-bros.-pokemon-charizard-amiibo%2F406392.html&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fkingdom-hearts-fans-have-another-chance-to-get-nintendos-sora-amiibo%2F1100-6519863%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Charizard</a> -- $16</li><li><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fclick.linksynergy.com%2Fdeeplink%3Fid%3DVZfI20jEa0c%26mid%3D24348%26u1%3Dsubid_value%26murl%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Fconsoles-hardware%2Fnintendo-switch%2Fnintendo-switch-amiibo%2Fproducts%2Fmonster-hunter-rise-palamute-amiibo%2F225482.html&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fkingdom-hearts-fans-have-another-chance-to-get-nintendos-sora-amiibo%2F1100-6519863%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Monster Hunter Rise Palamute</a> -- $20</li><li><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fclick.linksynergy.com%2Fdeeplink%3Fid%3DVZfI20jEa0c%26mid%3D24348%26u1%3Dsubid_value%26murl%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Fconsoles-hardware%2Fnintendo-switch%2Fnintendo-switch-amiibo%2Fproducts%2Fmonster-hunter-rise-palico-amiibo%2F225476.html&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fkingdom-hearts-fans-have-another-chance-to-get-nintendos-sora-amiibo%2F1100-6519863%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Monster Hunter Palico</a> -- $20</li><li><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fclick.linksynergy.com%2Fdeeplink%3Fid%3DVZfI20jEa0c%26mid%3D24348%26u1%3Dsubid_value%26murl%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Fconsoles-hardware%2Fnintendo-switch%2Fnintendo-switch-amiibo%2Fproducts%2Fmonster-hunter-rise-sunbreak-palico-felyne-malzeno-amiibo-gamestop-exclusive%2F342691.html&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fkingdom-hearts-fans-have-another-chance-to-get-nintendos-sora-amiibo%2F1100-6519863%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Monster Hunter Rise: Sunbreak Palico</a> -- $22</li><li><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fclick.linksynergy.com%2Fdeeplink%3Fid%3DVZfI20jEa0c%26mid%3D24348%26u1%3Dsubid_value%26murl%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Fconsoles-hardware%2Fnintendo-switch%2Fnintendo-switch-amiibo%2Fproducts%2Fmonster-hunter-rise-sunbreak-palamute-canye-malzeno-amiibo-gamestop-exclusive%2F342690.html&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fkingdom-hearts-fans-have-another-chance-to-get-nintendos-sora-amiibo%2F1100-6519863%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Monster Hunter Rise: Sunbreak Palamute</a> -- $22</li><li><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fclick.linksynergy.com%2Fdeeplink%3Fid%3DVZfI20jEa0c%26mid%3D24348%26u1%3Dsubid_value%26murl%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Fconsoles-hardware%2Fnintendo-switch%2Fnintendo-switch-amiibo%2Fproducts%2Fsuper-smash-bros.-banjo-and-kazooie-amiibo%2F234560.html&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fkingdom-hearts-fans-have-another-chance-to-get-nintendos-sora-amiibo%2F1100-6519863%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Banjo &amp; Kazooie</a> -- $16</li><li><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fclick.linksynergy.com%2Fdeeplink%3Fid%3DVZfI20jEa0c%26mid%3D24348%26u1%3Dsubid_value%26murl%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Fconsoles-hardware%2Fnintendo-switch%2Fnintendo-switch-amiibo%2Fproducts%2Fthe-legend-of-zelda-links-awakening-link-amiibo%2F202844.html&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fkingdom-hearts-fans-have-another-chance-to-get-nintendos-sora-amiibo%2F1100-6519863%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Link's Awakening Link</a> -- $16</li><li><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fclick.linksynergy.com%2Fdeeplink%3Fid%3DVZfI20jEa0c%26mid%3D24348%26u1%3Dsubid_value%26murl%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Fconsoles-hardware%2Fnintendo-switch%2Fnintendo-switch-amiibo%2Fproducts%2Fthe-legend-of-zelda-wind-waker-series-zelda-amiibo%2F414780.html&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fkingdom-hearts-fans-have-another-chance-to-get-nintendos-sora-amiibo%2F1100-6519863%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Toon Zelda from The Wind Waker</a> -- $16</li></ul><p>The Sora Amiibo features the star of Kingdom Hearts with his signature Keyblade. Sora originally joined the small list of non-Nintendo characters who have appeared in Super Smash Bros. and received the Amiibo treatment on February 16. Other notable non-Nintendo characters with Amiibo figures include <strong><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fclick.linksynergy.com%2Fdeeplink%3Fid%3DVZfI20jEa0c%26mid%3D24348%26u1%3Dsubid_value%26murl%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Fconsoles-hardware%2Fnintendo-switch%2Fnintendo-switch-amiibo%2Fproducts%2Fsuper-smash-bros.-banjo-and-kazooie-amiibo%2F234560.html&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fkingdom-hearts-fans-have-another-chance-to-get-nintendos-sora-amiibo%2F1100-6519863%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Banjo &amp; Kazooie</a></strong> from Rare's classic platformer series and <strong><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fclick.linksynergy.com%2Fdeeplink%3Fid%3DVZfI20jEa0c%26mid%3D24348%26u1%3Dsubid_value%26murl%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Fconsoles-hardware%2Fnintendo-switch%2Fnintendo-switch-amiibo%2Fproducts%2Fsuper-smash-bros.-terry-amiibo%2F234564.html&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fkingdom-hearts-fans-have-another-chance-to-get-nintendos-sora-amiibo%2F1100-6519863%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Terry Bogard</a></strong> of Fatal Fury and King of Fighters fame.</p><p>Sora is just the latest Amiibo figure to receive a reprint this year. Numerous The Legend of Zelda Amiibo figures were reissued ahead of Echoes of Wisdom's release, including the adorable doll-like <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fclick.linksynergy.com%2Fdeeplink%3Fid%3DVZfI20jEa0c%26mid%3D24348%26u1%3Dsubid_value%26murl%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Fconsoles-hardware%2Fnintendo-switch%2Fnintendo-switch-amiibo%2Fproducts%2Fthe-legend-of-zelda-links-awakening-link-amiibo%2F202844.html&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fkingdom-hearts-fans-have-another-chance-to-get-nintendos-sora-amiibo%2F1100-6519863%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Link from Link's Awakening (and Echoes of Wisdom)</a> and <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fclick.linksynergy.com%2Fdeeplink%3Fid%3DVZfI20jEa0c%26mid%3D24348%26u1%3Dsubid_value%26murl%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Fconsoles-hardware%2Fnintendo-switch%2Fnintendo-switch-amiibo%2Fproducts%2Fthe-legend-of-zelda-wind-waker-series-zelda-amiibo%2F414780.html&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fkingdom-hearts-fans-have-another-chance-to-get-nintendos-sora-amiibo%2F1100-6519863%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Toon Zelda from The Wind Waker</a>.</p><div data-embed-type="pinbox" data-ref-id="4304">  <ul>                              <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/amazon-kindle-colorsoft-e-ink-color-ereader-comic-books-new-kindle-models-2024/1100-6527202/">Amazon's New Full-Color Kindle Could Be A Game Changer For Comic Books</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-preorder-guide/1100-6524005/">Call Of Duty: Black Ops 6 Preorders - Bonuses, Game Pass Deals, Branded Gear, And More</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-this-75-bundle-has-all-you-need-to-play-no-console-or-pc-required/1100-6527064/">Call Of Duty: Black Ops 6 - This $75 Bundle Has All You Need To Play, No Console Or PC Required</a></li>                          <li>         <span>+ Show More More Gaming, Tech, and Entertainment Deals &amp; Preorders Links (5)</span>       </li>          <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/black-ops-6-gets-official-corsair-gear-call-of-duty-themed-gaming-pc-keyboard-mouse-and-more/1100-6526620/">Black Ops 6 Gets Official Corsair Gear - Call Of Duty-Themed Gaming PC, Keyboard, Mouse, And More</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/lego-nes-is-on-sale-for-20-off-this-week-save-54-while-supplies-last/1100-6526872/">Lego NES Is On Sale For 20% Off This Week - Save $54 While Supplies Last</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-legend-of-zelda-echoes-of-wisdom-is-already-discounted-but-not-for-long/1100-6527148/">The Legend Of Zelda: Echoes Of Wisdom Is Already Discounted, But Not For Long</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ps5-pro-preorders-live-at-amazon-walmart-and-best-buy/1100-6526406/">PS5 Pro Preorders Live At Amazon, Walmart, And Best Buy</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-xbox-elite-series-2-is-down-to-its-best-price-of-the-year/1100-6527087/">The Xbox Elite Series 2 Is Down To Its Best Price Of The Year At Amazon</a></li>   </ul> </div>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          

                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article>

    
  

</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jusant, Lost Records studio Don't Nod says 69 jobs at risk as part of "reorganisation project"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/jusant-lost-records-studio-dont-nod-says-69-jobs-at-risk-as-part-of-reorganisation-project</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/jusant-lost-records-studio-dont-nod-says-69-jobs-at-risk-as-part-of-reorganisation-project.1011678/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/jusant-lost-records-studio-dont-nod-says-69-jobs-at-risk-as-part-of-reorganisation-project<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>Amid "deteriorating" financial results.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Lost-records_sMM3ZtD.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Don't Nod</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
Don't Nod - the studio behind the likes of Jusant, <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/life-is-strange">Life is Strange</a> 1 &amp; 2, and the upcoming Lost Records: Bloom &amp; Rage - has announced 69 jobs are at risk as it initiates a "reorganisation project to ensure the company's long-term future" amid "deteriorating" financial results.
</p>
<p>
Signs the studio was facing difficulties <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/dont-nod-bets-on-lost-records-bloom-rage-as-multiple-projects-fail-to-meet-expectations">emerged earlier this year</a> when it announced it would be partially writing down €24m following the underperformance of Jusant and Banishers: Ghost of New Eden. It also confirmed it would be cancelling the development of one unannounced project, codenamed P10, while two additional Paris-developed projects (codenamed P12 and P13) had been temporarily put on hold in order to "prioritise resources and maximise the chances of success for the most promising titles at present." Despite all this, it remained upbeat regarding the prospects of Lost Records: Bloom &amp; Rage, and noted it had two additional in-house projects in the works, both scheduled to release by the end of 2027. 
</p>
<p>
But in its newly released <a href="https://www.dontnod-bourse.com/en/financial-information/press-releases?ID=ACTUS-0-88278">2024 half-year results update</a>, Don't Nod has acknowledged "strongly negative results despite [these] performance-enhancing measures", and has announced a "reorganisation project to safeguard its competitiveness in an increasingly demanding and competitive ecosystem" that may affect up to 69 jobs. "An initial exchange took place today with the employee representative bodies," it noted, "and an information-consultation process with these same bodies will subsequently be initiated regarding this project."
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Lost Records: Bloom &amp; Rage | Lo-fi Summer Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/A2aNUtMUvIM?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Lost Records: Bloom &amp; Rage | Lo-fi Summer Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/A2aNUtMUvIM?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/A2aNUtMUvIM?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Don't Nod's next game, Lost Records: Bloom &amp; Rage, arrives next year.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=A2aNUtMUvIM" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
In a statement accompany today's news, Don't Nod CEO Oskar Guilbert wrote, "Our half-year results for 2024 reflect the economic underperformance of our latest release, despite solid ratings on Metacritic, as well as the accounting impact of the decisions we had to take. The initial performance support measures announced last spring no longer seem sufficient to maintain the company's competitiveness. As a result, today we presented a reorganisation project to the employee representative bodies, which could set Don't Nod on a new development trajectory. I am fully conscious of the impact this project may have on all our employees. Securing our company's resources and restoring its ability to perform more in an increasingly competitive and selective industry is extremely necessary."
</p><p>
In addition to its in-house projects, Don't Nod is providing support for two external publishing projects due for release in 2025, but Lost Records: Bloom &amp; Rage will be the company's next major own release when it launches for PC, PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X/S next year - the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/life-is-strange-creators-lost-records-launches-in-two-parts">first part arriving on 18th February</a> and its concluding half releasing a month later on 18th March.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>