<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 20:21:58 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hyper Light Breaker heads into Steam Early Access in January]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/12/11/hyper-light-breaker-early-access-release-date-january-2025/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hyper-light-breaker-heads-into-steam-early-access-in-january.1058403/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/12/11/hyper-light-breaker-early-access-release-date-january-2025/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>The narrative prequel to <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/hyper-light-drifter">Hyper Light Drifter,</a> <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/hyper-light-breaker">Hyper Light Breaker</a> is set to launch into Steam Early Access on 14th January 2025.</p>
<p><iframe title="Hyper Light Breaker | Early Access Date Reveal Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/njIYX84JetA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>Set decades before the acclaimed action adventure RPG, Hyper Light Breaker is making a pretty clean break(er) in terms of genre, even if it retains a lot of the visual traits of the original. This is now a 3D co-op roguelite where players will head into the Overgrowth and explore its procedurally generated worlds and challenges, looking to uncover the truth of the Crowns, the Abyss King and the eerie landscape in general.</p>
<p>Of course, this isn’t going to be the full game, with developer Heart Machine having plenty planned for the journey through Early Access. There will be new Breakers characters, Crowns bosses, gear, and more on the to-do list. They will also naturally be listening to the community feedback to help balance the experience and shape certain parts of it as it heads toward a 1.0 launch.</p>
<h2><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2018/10/08/hyper-light-drifter-special-edition-review/">Hyper Light Drifter – Special Edition Review</a></h2>
<p>In our Hyper Light Drifter review, Miguel wrote, <em>“Hyper Light Drifter is a jaw-dropping experience no matter the platform you play it on. What started as an engaging masterpiece in 2016 continues to be just as rewarding and worthwhile of a video game in 2018. With the Nintendo Switch you get the valuable bonus of being able to take this journey with you anywhere you want and believe me when I say this is a journey you will not want to step away from once you start it.”</em></p>



<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Harley Quinn Season 5 Trailer Is The Batman/Superman Mash-Up We Needed]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/harley-quinn-max-superman-batman-1851718833</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/harley-quinn-season-5-trailer-is-the-batman-superman-mash-up-we-needed.1058394/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/harley-quinn-max-superman-batman-1851718833<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="cafb53b942cfd71d9ddea016a1c09d5c" data-recommend-id="image://cafb53b942cfd71d9ddea016a1c09d5c" data-format="png" data-width="2157" data-height="1444" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Harley Quinn is shocked at what she sees" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Harley Quinn is shocked at what she sees" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Warner Bros</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="cafb53b942cfd71d9ddea016a1c09d5c" data-recommend-id="image://cafb53b942cfd71d9ddea016a1c09d5c" data-format="png" data-width="2157" data-height="1444" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Harley Quinn is shocked at what she sees" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>Gotham’s biggest problem is now going to be giving Superman mallet-sized headaches. In the first trailer for the fifth season of Max Original <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/new-harley-quinn-clobbers-comic-industry-ableism-1847850470?_gl=1*5kef07*_ga*MzQzNjkwNDM2LjE2NDY2NjQ1NzQ.*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczMzk0NTU5NC4xMTMuMC4xNzMzOTQ1NTk3LjU3LjAuMA..&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/new-harley-quinn-clobbers-comic-industry-ableism-1847850470?_gl=1*5kef07*_ga*MzQzNjkwNDM2LjE2NDY2NjQ1NzQ.*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczMzk0NTU5NC4xMTMuMC4xNzMzOTQ1NTk3LjU3LjAuMA.."><em>Harley Quinn</em></a></span>, the titular queen of mischief (Kaley Cuoco) and Poison Ivy (Lake Bell) have left the grimy streets of Gotham and make their way to Metropolis in a Batman<em>/</em>Superman mashup that’s perfect for kicking off 2025.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="197298" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Live Forever in the Universe of 'New World: Aeternum'" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="108" data-playlist="197298,197284,197260" data-current="197298"><div><p>Live Forever in the Universe of 'New World: Aeternum'</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"></video></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>In the trailer, the worlds of the greatest detective and Krypton’s greatest orphan merge with Quinn at the center of it all. Joker (Alan Tudyk) asks <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/superman-legion-vfx-james-gunn-costumes-leaks-1851626258?_gl=1*gmzctl*_ga*MzQzNjkwNDM2LjE2NDY2NjQ1NzQ.*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczMzk0NTU5NC4xMTMuMC4xNzMzOTQ1NTk3LjU3LjAuMA..&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/superman-legion-vfx-james-gunn-costumes-leaks-1851626258?_gl=1*gmzctl*_ga*MzQzNjkwNDM2LjE2NDY2NjQ1NzQ.*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczMzk0NTU5NC4xMTMuMC4xNzMzOTQ1NTk3LjU3LjAuMA..">Superman</a></span> to save the day, Bane (James Adomian) wars against AI robots in Metropolis, and all of them are in the way of whatever evil plan Superman villain Brainiac (Stephen Fry) has cooked up. According to Max’s synopsis of the season, “Harley and Ivy discover that something sinister is at play” in Metropolis when they arrive, and they can count Lex Luthor (Giancarlo Esposito) and his sister Lena Luthor (Aisha Tyler) as threats, along with Brainiac. </p><p>This season is set to premiere on January 16, 2025, and comes after Harley Quinn’s pocket of the DC animated universe expanded this year with its first spin-off series, <em>Kite Man: Hell Yeah!</em> The show features the comedic, endearingly ill-fortuned character who, on <em>Harley Quinn</em>, was the title character’s ex-fiance and is voiced by <em>Fresh Off The Boat</em>’s Matt Oberg.<em>&nbsp;</em>In a November interview with <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://screenrant.com/creature-commandos-season-1-showrunner-dean-lorey-interview/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://screenrant.com/creature-commandos-season-1-showrunner-dean-lorey-interview/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>ScreenRant</em></a></span><em>, </em>executive producer and writer Dean Lorey hinted at another possible spin-off from what he calls the Harleyverse:</p><p>“Well, I’m all in on the Harleyverse. There’s a show that I am hoping to be able to announce somewhat soon, that is in the Harleyverse that I’m very excited about.”</p><p>I honestly wouldn’t mind seeing King Shark (Ron Funches) be a lovable giant getting himself out of trouble by hacking into anything with a computer chip, and maybe assuming the royal duties of his underwater kingdom. Or, we could wash away the stain <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/joker-folie-a-deux-hbo-max-release-date-1851715983&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/joker-folie-a-deux-hbo-max-release-date-1851715983"><em>Joker: Folie à Deux</em></a></span><em> </em>left in our eyes by letting Alan Tudyk have his own show as the homicidal trickster. Whether these spin-offs happen or not, it’s good to know we won’t have to wait long for the center of the Harleyverse to return and get back to serving us murder with a smile.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hyper Light Breaker is Launching in Steam Early Access on January 15, 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/hyper-light-breaker-announcement/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hyper-light-breaker-is-launching-in-steam-early-access-on-january-15-2025.1058391/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/hyper-light-breaker-announcement/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Heart Machine and Arc Games have announced that Hyper Light Breaker will be launching in Steam Early Access on January 15, 2025.</p>



<p>The announcement was made on the Hyper Light Breaker X (formerly Twitter) <a href="https://x.com/HLBreaker/status/1866909571429830937" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">account</a>, where the developers announced, “<a href="https://x.com/hashtag/HyperLightBreaker?src=hashtag_click">#HyperLightBreaker</a>, the highly-anticipated open world co-op rogue-lite set in a new realm in the Hyper Light universe, launches in Steam Early Access on January 14, 2025!”</p>



<p>The game description reads, </p>



<p>Enter the Overgrowth, a new realm in the world of Hyper Light. Play alone or with friends to explore open worlds, create new builds, rip through hordes and overcome the Crowns and the Abyss King. </p>



<p>Breaker is a brand new entry in the Hyper Light franchise, with a unique story fully realized in 3D for the first time.</p>



<h2 id="h-ever-changing-worlds-to-explore">EVER-CHANGING WORLDS TO EXPLORE</h2>



<ul>
<li>A world in disarray, with mysteries to solve, vicious enemies to fight, and fully 3D environments to explore.</li>



<li>A vast, ever-changing world awaits with large scale open biomes and deep labyrinths.</li>



<li>Worlds are procedurally generated with unique layouts, enemies, loot and rewards leading to multiple playthroughs.</li>



<li>Traverse landscapes with incredible freedom with a variety of abilities; wall-dashing, hoverboard, glider and more.</li>
</ul>



<h2>JOIN THE BREAKERS</h2>



<ul>
<li>Battle through the Overgrowth alone or as a team in online co-operative play.</li>



<li>Face hordes of enemies and brutal bosses in frenetic third-person combat.</li>



<li>Rise to the increasing challenges stacking through every run.</li>
</ul>



<h2>EXPLORE, COLLECT AND DESTROY</h2>



<ul>
<li>Discover and unlock a wide arsenal of weapons, items and upgrades to create the ideal build for new runs.</li>



<li>Learn more about the Overgrowth from the fragmented memories of its mysterious defenders, the Crowns.</li>



<li>Bring back resources to help the settlement flourish over the course of your journey.</li>
</ul>



<p>Minimum and recommend PC specs are yet to be announced.</p>



<p>The game is available to <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1534840/Hyper_Light_Breaker/">wishlist on </a><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1534840/Hyper_Light_Breaker/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Steam </a><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1534840/Hyper_Light_Breaker/">now</a>.</p>



<p>Will you be wish listing the game? Let us know on the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/kick-streamer-performance-report-2024/">Kick has skyrocketed in 2024</a></p>




    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Day of the Devs: The Game Awards Edition 2024 - Everything Announced]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/day-of-the-devs-the-game-awards-edition-2024-everything-announced</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/day-of-the-devs-the-game-awards-edition-2024-everything-announced.1058388/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/day-of-the-devs-the-game-awards-edition-2024-everything-announced<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Once again, non-profit Day of the Devs officially returned Wednesday with an indie showcase featuring nearly 20 independent games across multiple genres, platforms, studios, and styles as part of the run-up to The Game Awards. The show featured everything from a stop-motion game that’s entirely made of felt, a game where you engage in medieval warfare with modern guns, the return of an unreleased puzzle game first announced over a decade ago, and something to do with changing channels on a one-bit TV.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">You should really go back and watch the whole thing, but if you’re skimming the highlights, here’s a rundown of everything we just saw at Day of the Devs:</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><h3 data-cy="title3">Faraway</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">The presentation opened with Faraway – a single-player, one-button, procedurally generated arcade game about drawing constellations in the night sky. Faraway has been a hot rumor for a long time, having been shown around at indie showcases all the way back in 2011 and initially billed as an iPad game. But it missed its planned release date then, and disappeared for years. Faraway is developed by Steph Thirion of Little Eyes studio, and is being published by Annapurna on PC in 2025.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><h3 data-cy="title3">Ultimate Sheep Raccoon</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">Ultimate Sheep Raccoon is exactly what it says on the tin. A spiritual successor to Ultimate Chicken Horse from the same team, Clever Endeavor Games, it is a multiplayer competitive platformer where players build wild platforming courses and race through them with friends. This time, everyone’s on bikes. No release date yet, but it’s planned for Steam.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Sleight of Hand</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">We’ve seen Sleight of Hand, from Riffraff Games, at an <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/framed-developer-unveils-occult-noir-stealth-game-sleight-of-hand-xbox-partner-preview"><u>Xbox Partner Preview</u></a> event earlier this year. In it, you play as Lady Luck, a witch detective working to take down her former coven using dark magic via a cursed deck of cards. In Day of the Devs today, we watched a sample of how a gameplay scenario might go, with Lady Luck using a drawn hand of cards to hide, lure her enemies, and ultimately trap them so she can pass by unseen. Sleight of Hand is coming to PC and Xbox at a later date.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><h3 data-cy="title3">Demon Tides</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">By studio Fabraz, Demon Tides is an open world 3D platformer that gives off “Wind Waker but hip and stylish” vibes. We got a look today at some of the platforming and the player’s ability to customize not just their character’s appearance, but also their abilities, giving them a number of different options for how to cross the same gaps. Demon Tides is planned for release in 2025 on Steam.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Kingmakers</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">Developers Redemption Road, makers of, uh, Road Redemption, appeared in Day of the Devs to show off Kingmakers, a game we’re <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/kingmakers-combines-back-to-the-future-with-army-of-darkness-and-its-blowing-up-right-now-ign-next"><u>already pretty stoked about here at IGN</u></a>. It’s a game with a concept that’s…kind of delightful? You play as part of a team of fighters with modern weapons – guns, bombs, tanks, and so forth – who go back to medieval England to change the course of history. So you’re fighting in medieval times…but with guns. Kingmakers mixes city simulator elements with first and third-person shooter mechanics and massive, destructible environments. You can blow up anything you can see, or stage a fight on top of it, or drive a car through it. The whole thing looks kind of nuts, and you can play the entire campaign solo or with up to three friends. Kingmakers is coming to early access on Steam and the Epic Games Store next year.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Recur</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">Recur is a puzzle game from developer kaleidoscube where you play as an unassuming postman who suddenly finds himself with the ability to pause, rewind, and fast forward time itself. From what we saw, it looks like you’ll be working your way through levels where the postman has to use his time powers to avoid obstacles and danger, such as collapsing platforms, a moving train, attacking dogs, or even a whole car nearly smashing into him. Recur is planned for release on Steam.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Blue Prince</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">Blue Prince (Get it, like Blueprints?) looks gorgeous and mysterious, an atmospheric "architectural adventure” where you’re exploring an “ever-changing house of shifting rooms.” There seems to be some kind of mystery to solve, where you’re hunting for “Room 46” in a 45-room house, and you’re using the house’s blueprints to shape your exploration and build the structure as you go, day by day. The vibes are kind of like Edith Finch meets Mist, and the whole thing is coming out on PC in spring of 2025 from developer Dogubomb.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Incolatus: Don’t Stop, Girlypop!</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s right there in the title: don’t stop. Incolatus is a Y2K-style girly-pop movement shooter where you literally cannot stop moving. The more you move and the faster you go, the more damage you do and the more you heal yourself, so you just have to keep going. It’s a first-person arena shooter, where you’re shooting elaborate, colorful, and sometimes massive guns that blast cutesy girly hearts and stars at enemies (an evil mining corporation destroying the environment) to a boppin’ soundtrack. The guns get bigger the faster you go. More scope. More damage. More movement. Oh, and there’s a dress-up megagame where you can dress up your arms and customize your guns. Incolatus: Don’t Stop, Girlypop! is coming to Steam “soon”.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><h3 data-cy="title3">Lok Digital</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">Lok Digital was born of a fascinating collaboration between a puzzle designer who made a clever physical puzzle book, and a game developer who wanted to digitize it in video game form. The result, Lok Digital, is a puzzle game where you slowly solve world puzzles in the fictional language of Lok, which you learn as you work your way through the puzzles. You start with the word “Lok”, and from there will discover other words, other puzzle rules, and the language of the little Lok creatures the game is named after. If that sounds intriguing, great news, you don’t have to wait. Lok Digital is out today on PC, and it’s coming to mobile next year.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><h3 data-cy="title3">Neon Abyss 2</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">We didn’t get a ton of info today about Neon Abyss 2, but it’s safe to say it’s a sequel to Neon Abyss from Veoowo Games. A 2D, pixelated, run-and-gun roguelike, Neon Abyss 2 looks to bring back the bright colors, flashy lasers, and bullet hell intensity of the first game for another round. It’s coming in 2025 to Steam, and looks like it will incorporate multiplayer, too.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Crescent County</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">A sci-fi fantasy motorbike game, Crescent County styles itself as “roller derby but with gay witches” or “Studio Ghibli but with considerably more crop jackets”. You’re a witch, you ride a broom motorbike, and through the day you make deliveries and do other important witch tasks on your broom, earning parts that will make your broom faster, cooler, and more powerful. Then, at night, you go out for broom races. In between it all, there’s plenty of flirting and smooching, as witches do. Crescent County is still fairly early in development, but there’s an early playtest happening now on Steam and itch.io.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><h3 data-cy="title3">PBJ - The Musical</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">I briefly thought I was looking at a Marcel the Shell short when I glanced at my screen and saw this one, but maybe that was just the googly eye. PBJ - The Musical is…well, a musical, telling a romance story of a berry and a peanut, sweet and salty, and their ultimate creation of the peanut butter and jelly sandwich. Through the musical acts, you’ll be guiding these two characters through paper stop motion cut out from vintage cookbooks and retelling the story of Romeo and Juliet…in sandwich form. All the music is written by Britain’s Got Talent’s Lorraine Bowen. Sadly, no word on when or where this hungry adventure is dropping for now.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Curiosmos</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">Curiosmos is a cute little space game where you slowly create a solar system, at first by bashing asteroids into one another to create a planet. Once the planet’s created, you can experiment with sunlight, terrain, water, weather, and other elements to see what happens…including whether or not life blossoms and evolves. It seems like a fairly peaceful experience…until a giant black hole starts flying at you and your planets, potentially causing a catastrophe you’ll have to try and avert before it arrives. Curiosmos doesn’t have a release date yet.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><h3 data-cy="title3">Bionic Bay</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">In the platformer Bionic Bay, you’ll be thinking a lot about gravity, speed, and momentum. You’re a scientist with strange powers over time and space, allowing you to teleport, manipulate time, and flip the environment on its head. Using these abilities, you’ll flip and launch yourself across sci-fi themed environments with realistic physics. Bionic Bay is planned for release on Steam and PS5 in 2025.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">inKonbini</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">I <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-amazing-upcoming-games-that-make-xbox-playstation-and-nintendos-2024-so-much-more-interesting"><u>wrote about inKonbini earlier this year</u></a> after playing it at an Xbox showcase adjacent to the Game Developers Conference. It’s a soothing organizational game about working in a convenience store, stocking the shelves, and interacting with customers who come in and share tidbits from their lives. I found the concept appealing and the execution incredibly relaxing, especially the sound effects of bags and boxes hitting the shelves and the satisfying way everything fell neatly into place on the display. InKonbini is planned for launch on Xbox, PS5, Switch, and Steam sometime in the future.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><h3 data-cy="title3">Feltopia</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">Feltopia is a stop-motion game that is entirely hand-felted. Every piece of the environment, character, enemy, everything is made by hand, out of felt, recorded, and animated. And the effect is adorable, with fuzzy unicorns, sheep, butterflies, clouds, and more all puffing up out of the world soft as can be. The game itself is a sidescrolling shmup where you ride a unicorn and shoot rainbow beams at shadowy creatures that will transform them back into their true forms. Feltopia is planned for release on Steam in 2026.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><h3 data-cy="title3">Blippo+</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">I’m not sure what I just watched, but I guess it’s Blippo+. This looks like some sort of game around changing the channel on a one-bit TV and watching all the different, weird programs? Whatever it is, Panic (the Untitled Goose Game and Thank Goodness You’re Here) publisher, so that might convey the vibe. No idea when this is coming out, where, or how. Stay tuned for more Blippo?</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><h3 data-cy="title3">Hyper Light Breaker</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">We’ve already seen a lot of Hyper Light Breaker from Heart Machine, so I won’t belabor it (you can <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/hyper-light-breaker-exclusive-first-hands-on-gameplay-preview-dreaming-a-tangerine-dream"><u>read my preview from earlier this year here</u></a>), but today the team showed up at Day of the Devs to announce an early access release on Steam on January 14, 2025.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><h3 data-cy="title3">Tankhead</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">Finally, Day of the Devs closed with Tankhead from Alpha Channel. It’s a sci-fi vehicular adventure where you play as a “sleepwalker” or a person who uploads their consciousness into a machine to explore a dangerous world. Basically, you’re a literal tank (or sometimes a smaller robot) exploring a ruined world, able to travel over tough terrain, shoot stuff, and move fast when you need to. The tank’s customizable, and yes, you drive using tank controls. Tankhead, delightfully, is out today on the Epic Games Store.<br>
</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Rebekah Valentine is a senior reporter for IGN. You can find her posting on Bluesky @duckvalentine.bsky.social. Got a story tip? Send it to rvalentine@ign.com.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sonic x Shadow Generations Collector's Edition Now Available at Amazon, Includes Dreamcast Statue, Chao Figurines and More]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/sonic-x-shadow-generations-collectors-edition-where-to-buy</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sonic-x-shadow-generations-collectors-edition-now-available-at-amazon-includes-dreamcast-statue-chao-figurines-and-more.1058385/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/sonic-x-shadow-generations-collectors-edition-where-to-buy<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Previously limited, pun intended, to Limited Run, and completely sold out, the Sonic X Shadow Generations Collector's Edition is now available to <a href="https://zdcs.link/avxgy7?object_uuid=00001f29-6d23-4dce-a725-036bb0f0287f&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">preorder at Amazon</a>. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Shipping by July 31, 2025, it might be late, but it's a good opportunity for anyone who missed the previous preorder window. It's available for PS5, Switch, and Xbox, and priced at $249.99, it includes an overload of nostalgia.</p><div catalogid="5f751717-1471-4d59-8ca7-149a34a84023" id="213340"><div id="213340" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Sonic X Shadow Generations: Collector's Edition</h3></p></div><ul data-cy="list"><li><a href="https://zdcs.link/9lwWyN?object_uuid=00001f29-6d23-4dce-a725-036bb0f0287f&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" data-aps-asin="B0DPXVY8GM" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Get it for PS5/PS4</a> - $249.99</li><li><a href="https://zdcs.link/aMvkMm?object_uuid=00001f29-6d23-4dce-a725-036bb0f0287f&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" data-aps-asin="B0DPXTXPQK" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Get it for Switch</a> - $249.99</li><li><a href="https://zdcs.link/9g34yq?object_uuid=00001f29-6d23-4dce-a725-036bb0f0287f&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" data-aps-asin="B0DPXTS3MZ" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Get it for Xbox</a> - $249.99</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph">The Collector’s Edition adds a range of exciting extras, with the main attraction being the stunning statue featuring Sonic and Shadow standing atop a model of SEGA's final console, the Dreamcast, where Shadow debuted in Sonic Adventure 2. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Other highlights include <em>The Art of Sonic X Shadow Generations</em> art book, the official soundtrack, a commemorative Dreamcast jewel case (a great nostalgic touch), a SteelBook, Chao figurines, and a keychain featuring Sonic, Shadow, and Classic Sonic’s shoes—an accessory we can’t help but love. Check out our full <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/sonic-shadow-generations-preorder-guide">Generations Buying Guide</a> here for more info.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Here's bullet point breakdown as well:</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Sonic &amp; Shadow Dreamcast Statue</li><li>Full game in physical form</li><li>Reversible Cover, Legacy Skin for Modern Sonic (Pre-order Bonus), </li><li>Gerald Robotnik's Journal - a 28-page logbook chronicling Gerald's innermost thoughts and drawings while he created Shadow the Hedgehog and the Ark Space Station</li><li>The Art of Sonic x Shadow Generations Art Book</li><li>Official Soundtrack</li><li>Commemorative Dreamcast Jewel Case</li><li>SteelBook</li><li>Chao Figurines</li><li>Sonic, Shadow, &amp; Classic Sonic Shoes Keychain</li><li>Individually Numbered Certificate of Authenticity (Digital Content Codes are region locked to North America)</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph">As mentioned, this might be a late release, but it's still extremely exciting for any Sonic fans who weren't able to grab the Collector's Edition from Limited Run earlier in the year. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">IGN's Jada Griffin had high praise for <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/sonic-x-shadow-generations-review">Sonic X Shadow Generations in her review</a>, giving it a of 9/10. In it, she says that, "Sonic X Shadow Generations takes an already excellent game and spring jumps it to new heights at a blistering pace by doubling up the campaign length with creative level design, fantastic bosses, plenty of collectibles, and an appreciable graphical upgrade."</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Why Should You Trust IGN's Deals Team?</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">IGN's deals team has a combined 30+ years of experience finding the best discounts in gaming, tech, and just about every other category. We don't try to trick our readers into buying things they don't need at prices that aren't worth buying something at. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Our ultimate goal is to surface the best possible deals from brands we trust and our editorial team has personal experience with. You can check out <a href="https://corp.ign.com/ign-deals-standards-and-practices" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">our deals standards here</a> for more information on our process, or keep up with the latest deals we find on <a href="https://x.com/IGNDeals" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">IGN's Deals account on Twitter</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Robert Anderson is a deals expert and Commerce Editor for IGN. You can follow him <a href="https://twitter.com/robertliam21" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@robertliam21</a> on Twitter.</p></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Dec 11, 2024 5:43 pm</p></div></div><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PlayStation Launches 2024 Wrap-Up, But the Site Is Already Down]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/playstation-launches-2024-wrap-up-but-the-site-is-already-down</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/playstation-launches-2024-wrap-up-but-the-site-is-already-down.1058382/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/playstation-launches-2024-wrap-up-but-the-site-is-already-down<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">PlayStation has now launched its yearly Wrap-Up that lets players see their gaming stats from the year gone by — at least it would if the site wasn't down.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">A <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2024/12/10/celebrate-30-years-of-playstation-with-playstation-2024-wrap-up-launching-today/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">PlayStation Blog</a> post revealed the release of Wrap-Up, a feature which gained traction first through the likes of music app Spotify before gaming brands PlayStation and Xbox got on board. Those who want to check out their year in review, and for the first time a personal PlayStation history, will need to wait, however.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Though officially released on December 10, the <a href="https://wrapup.playstation.com/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">PlayStation Wrap-Up</a> website currently displays an non-interactive screen branded with the sacred symbols and 2024 Wrap-Up logo before a sobering message below simply reads: "We'll be back soon."</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/12/11/screenshot-2024-12-11-173412-1733938852754.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Image Credit: PlayStation</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">When PlayStation does get it working again, players will be able to see a summary of their 2024 in gaming, with stats displaying information such as the number of games played, number of Trophies gained, total hours played, and time spent in multiplayer.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">New this year, however, are "personalized historical statistics." These dig deep into a player's PlayStation legacy, revealing the total number of games played since creating their PlayStation Network account and even looking back on Trophy milestones.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Only those who've consented to have their full data collected by PlayStation will be unable to view the 2024 Wrap-Up when it's working again.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As mentioned, Xbox has made a similar move but actually has its website working. The <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-GB/year-in-review" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">2024 Year in Review</a> shows similar stats from throughout 2024 including a player's top played games. It even has "a special shout-out from [Xbox boss Phil Spencer] to you."</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Ryan Dinsdale is an IGN freelance reporter. He'll talk about The Witcher all day.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Death Match Love Comedy! coming west in 2025 for PS5, Xbox Series, PS4, Xbox One, Switch, and PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/12/death-match-love-comedy-coming-west-in-2025-for-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-xbox-one-switch-and-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/death-match-love-comedy-coming-west-in-2025-for-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-xbox-one-switch-and-pc.1058379/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/12/death-match-love-comedy-coming-west-in-2025-for-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-xbox-one-switch-and-pc<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Heartfelt confessions with explosive consequences.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > PQube [365 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/pqube">PQube</a> will release <a title="Companies > Kemco [68 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/kemco">Kemco</a>-developed <a title="Genres > Visual Novel [497 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/visual-novel">visual novel</a> <em>Death Match Love Comedy!</em> for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,511 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [6,462 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,520 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox One [13,669 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch [16,417 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [21,926 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1265570/DMLC/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> in 2025 in the west, the publisher announced. <span id="more-932597"></span></p><p>A remake of the iOS and Android game <em>D.M.L.C.: Death Match Love Comedy</em>, <em>Death Match Love Comedy!</em> first launched for PlayStation 4, Switch, and PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1265570/DMLC/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> on June 25, 2020 in Japan.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via PQube:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Heartfelt confessions—explosive consequences!</p><p>From the creators of <em><a title="Games > Raging Loop [4 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/raging-loop">Raging Loop</a></em> comes a wild-ride of a visual novel, full of slapstick comedy, occult experiences, and romance!</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>First year Kei Yagi is about to receive a love confession from not one, but two classmates, when he suddenly explodes! Although this initial incident was an illusion, he discovers that due to a mysterious curse put upon him, the next time he receives a confession of love he will truly explode and die!</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Map It All Out</strong> – Multiple routes and endings can be navigated easily through the chart system which allows you to pick up from various points along any route you’ve travelled.</li><li><strong>Confession Time</strong> – A special confession warning light appears when the time for love confessions looms near, helping you avoid destruction (or accept it to collect all the bad endings!).</li><li><strong>The Popular Kid</strong> – with all sorts of strange happenings and encounters with curious characters, at least Kei isn’t alone in this rollercoaster ride. From girls fighting over him, to classmates fighting alongside him, Kei’s making some unforgettable high school memories.</li><li><strong>Sister Universe</strong> – Loved <em>Raging Loop</em>? Then you’ll love this. At first glance it may seem like completely different work, but these visual novels are deeply connected sister works by scenario writer amphibian.</li></ul><p>Enjoy your time in this hybrid, high school fantasy / romantic slapstick comedy visual novel, where you need to push away the affection thrown your way, lest you instantly explode all the while trying to break the strange curse put upon you.</p></blockquote><p>Watch the announcement trailer below.</p><h2><span>Announce Trailer</span></h2><p>Trailer coming soon. Check back shortly.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Class of Heroes 3: Remaster announced for PS5, Switch, and PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/12/class-of-heroes-3-remaster-announced-for-ps5-switch-and-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/class-of-heroes-3-remaster-announced-for-ps5-switch-and-pc.1058373/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/12/class-of-heroes-3-remaster-announced-for-ps5-switch-and-pc<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Due out in 2025.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > PQube [365 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/pqube">PQube</a> and developer <a title="Companies > ACQUIRE [339 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/kadokawa-corporation/acquire">ACQUIRE</a> have announced <em><a title="Games > Class of Heroes 3: Remaster" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/class-of-heroes-3-remaster">Class of Heroes 3: Remaster</a></em>, a remastered version of <a title="Genres > Dungeon RPG [65 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg/dungeon-rpg">dungeon RPG</a> <em>Class of Heroes 3</em> for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,511 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch [16,417 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [21,926 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> (<a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3301820/Class_of_Heroes_3_Remaster/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a>). It will launch in 2025. <span id="more-932492"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via PQube:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Class is back in session! After a 15 year wait, <em>Class of Heroes 3 Remaster</em>, the revered school-themed dungeon RPG series, is finally here! Enroll in one of three distinct schools and join your fellow students on an epic dungeon crawling <a title="Genres > Adventure [1,936 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a>.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Delve Into Dungeons!</strong> – <em>Class of Heroes 3 Remaster</em> takes 3D dungeon-crawling <a title="Genres > RPG [16,862 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg">RPGs</a> to a new level—with more characters and bigger dungeons than ever before!</li><li><strong>Back to School</strong> – Choose from one of three distinct schools – each will change your uniform, difficulty and story!</li><li><strong>Make New Friends</strong> – The expanded relationship system lets you forge (or break!) bonds with the fellow students in your party. The stronger the bond, the greater the benefit!</li><li><strong>Let’s <a title="Genres > Party [81 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/party">Party</a>!</strong> – Team up with fellow students from a huge range of races and classes to build the best possible party of heroes to explore dungeons with.</li><li><strong>Plunder the Dungeons!</strong> – Take your party into colossal, labyrinthine dungeons—fight off enemies and plunder the loot to make yourself stronger on each run!</li><li><strong>Build It Your Way</strong> – With hundreds of weapons, armor and items—along with even more combinations of races and classes. Customize your team to suit your playing style!</li><li><strong>New and Improved</strong> – As the third iteration in the series, every aspect of the original games has been enhanced and improved to make this the most enjoyable in the series yet!</li></ul><!-- AD: content -->
        </blockquote><p>Watch the announcement trailer below. View the first screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/class-of-heroes-3-remaster/december-11-2024/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>Announce Trailer</span></h2><p>Trailer coming soon. Check back shortly!</p><h2><span>Screenshots</span></h2><!-- zp_shiv error: no images in gallery! --></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Balatro, Thank Goodness You're Here win at Apple's 2024 App Store Awards]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/balatro-thank-goodness-you-re-here-win-at-apple-s-2024-app-store-awards</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/balatro-thank-goodness-youre-here-win-at-apples-2024-app-store-awards.1058367/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/balatro-thank-goodness-you-re-here-win-at-apple-s-2024-app-store-awards<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The end of the year means awards season, and Apple has revealed the winners for its </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2024/12/apple-honors-2024-app-store-award-winners/">2024 App Store Awards</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. In its announcement, the tech company said the recipients "highlight the endless opportunities across the App Store and the Apple ecosystem."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">For its game categories, Farlight Games' </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>AFK Journey </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">won Best iPhone Game, and Supercell's </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Squad Busters </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">for Best iPad Game. The former also won Game of the Year for </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/afk-journey-and-clash-of-clans-lead-google-play-s-top-games-of-2024">Google Play's awards</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> in November, and the latter for Best Multiplayer.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Panic Inc's </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/-humor-is-all-we-ve-really-got-championing-absurdity-in-thank-goodness-you-re-here-">Thank Goodness You're Here!</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"><span> </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">was deemed the year's best Mac game, and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Thrasher: Arcade Odyssey </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">was the inaugural winner for the Apple Vision Pro. Finally, LocalThunk's </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/balatro-creator-says-he-will-never-let-it-be-licensed-for-gambling-even-after-death">Balatro</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"><span> </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">took the Best Apple Arcade award. The roguelike deckbuilder is nominated for several industry awards this year, including "Best Game Direction" and "Game of the Year" at tomorrow's </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/astro-bot-and-balatro-headline-game-awards-2024-nominees">Game Awards</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Apple also recognized the </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/new-york-times-staff-ask-readers-to-not-play-its-games-as-union-strikes">New York Times' games division</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, Pixel Hunt's </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>The Wreck, </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">and Gamtrophy's </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Do You Really Want to Know 2 </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">as part of its "Cultural Impact" winners. The category highlights games and apps that have made a "lasting impact" on players' lives and communities.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Do You Really Want to Know 2</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, for example, is a text adventure game chosen for "exploring the nuances of living with HIV, offering users local resources and educational materials to navigate conversations with family and friends." NYT Games was selected for "connecting family and friends across generations with a variety of fun and simple daily games."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The full list of App Store Award winners can be read </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2024/12/apple-honors-2024-app-store-award-winners/">here</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Contributing Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">A Kansas City, MO native, Justin Carter has written for numerous sites including IGN, Polygon, and SyFy Wire. In addition to Game Developer, his writing can be found at io9 over on Gizmodo. Don't ask him about how much gum he's had, because the answer will be more than he's willing to admit.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Arcs Expansions Review - The Blighted Reach and Leaders and Lore]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/arcs-expansions-review-blighted-reach-and-leaders-and-lore</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/arcs-expansions-review-the-blighted-reach-and-leaders-and-lore.1058340/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/arcs-expansions-review-blighted-reach-and-leaders-and-lore<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>The deep strategy of the sci-fi board game <em>Arcs</em> wasn't enough for you by itself? Even with its huge amount of replayability? You want more? Luckily, Leder Games have got you, with 2 expansions that add to the base <em>Arcs</em> game. In this article, we'll look at the huge box The Blighted Reach Expansion and the small card pack Leaders and Lore and see what they add to games.</p>

<p><em>Arcs</em> is a sci-fi strategy board game by Cole Wehrle and Leder Games, and you can read our review of it <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/arcs-review-fun-unbridled-space-chaos" rel="nofollow">here</a>, which is recommended before you read this review of the expansions.</p>



<p>The 2 <em>Arcs</em> expansions, The Blighted Reach and Leaders and Lore are supplementary expansions to the core <em>Arcs </em>game. One adds a new campaign element and the other supplements the Leaders and Lore add-on that was introduced in the base game. We look at both in detail below.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/arcs-the-blighted-reach-4.jpg?itok=_nV3xZ1L 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/arcs-the-blighted-reach-4.jpg?itok=oaDzzQ7A 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>The <em>Arcs</em>&nbsp;The Blighted Reach box is huge, adding in more components than the core game, but having a box that can contain all of it.</figcaption></figure><h2>What Does The Arcs The Blighted Reach Expansion Add To Games?</h2>

<p><em>Arcs</em> The Blighted Reach Expansion adds a whole campaign to the&nbsp;<em>Arcs</em>&nbsp;base game and includes more components than the original box. The Blighted Reach box is also designed so that you can also store your base <em>Arcs</em> game inside, so everything is combined in a single place.</p>

<p>The Blighted Reach Expansion contains a 3 arc campaign, that starts with players selecting a character, known as a Fate to play. These are randomly drawn from the 8 available in the first act. Each fate has its own objective, and if you complete your objective, you can continue to play your fate in the next act (drawing 1 new fate to see if you wish to change). If you fail your objective, your current fate is discarded, and you draw 2 new ones. There are 24 fates in total, 8 in each of the 3 acts, so every game you play will offer a different combination of paths and objectives to seek.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/arcs-the-blighted-reach-2.jpg?itok=SJp-D8jQ 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/arcs-the-blighted-reach-2.jpg?itok=zRA5Q0hC 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Each of the 24 fates in <em>Arcs</em>&nbsp;The Blighted Reach Expansion includes a fate card, and 3 acts worth of new content.</figcaption></figure><p>Each fate also has its own fate deck, which gives you cards, and also adds cards to the court deck, and other rules as the game progresses, this means that the fates that the other players are playing will also add elements to the game, impacting your own depending on their fates.</p>

<p>The whole campaign adds an overarching element of the Empire and an Imperial Council that does add a lot of rules and complexity to the base game. There are some extremely crazy abilities to unlock, and it can really shake the balance of the game. It also changes the game entirely from the base <em>Arcs</em> game, giving it much more of an unbalanced narrative element than a strategy game. It is a lot of fun, and exploring the different fates is extremely rewarding, but just because you like the base <em>Arcs</em> game, doesn't mean you will like this, and also some that didn't love the base game, will love this instead. It is highly recommended that you play the base game a few times before taking on the campaign, because the complexity added here is high, and not having a core understanding of the base rules will make you miss the joy of exploring The Blighted Reach</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/arcs-the-blighted-reach-3.jpg?itok=jEffnrhS 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/arcs-the-blighted-reach-3.jpg?itok=6iDfoqKa 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>The <em>Arcs</em> Leaders and Lore Pack adds 8 new leaders and 14 new lore cards to those included in the base game.</figcaption></figure><h2>What Does The Arcs Leaders and Lore Pack Add To Games?</h2>

<p>The Arcs Leaders and Lore Pack adds a further 8 Leader and 14 Lore cards, to those already already available in the core <em>Arcs</em> game. The Leaders and Lore game mode adds a random element to games, stepping away from the core strategy of the base game, and sits nicely between the base game, and the Blighted Reach expansion. The leader card details the abilities and setup for that leader, and the lore card adds another unique ability.</p>

<p>The Leaders and Lore Packs adds more variety to those already included in the base game, improving replayability and adding in some great leader/lore combinations. It feels odd that a pack of 22 cards wasn't just added into the core game, or that the 22 leaders and lore cards weren't removed from the core game into a larger Leaders and Lore pack. It seems strange to include half in the core game with an extra purchase for the extra variety when it could all just be included together for a very minor 22-card price bump on the core game, or make it a completely separate purchase for those who want the asymmetrical abilities variety in <em>Arcs</em> gameplay.</p>

<h2>What Are Our Final Thoughts On The Arcs Expansions?</h2>

<p>The Leaders and Lore Pack adds the same fun variety to games of <em>Arcs</em> that's already included in the cards in the base game, it just increases the number of options and randomness of drawing, thus increasing replayability. Between the 16 leaders and 28 lore cards, that's a lot of combinations. It feels very weird that it's split in half and either not all in an expansion, or all in the base game for such a low amount of cards. Leaders and Lore sits nicely between the base strategy of the core game, and the Blighted Reach Expansion, adding in variety, but not the complexity of the full campaign.</p>

<p>The Blighted Reach Expansion completely changes the <em>Arcs'</em> experience. It moves from a strategy game to a narrative experience, simply using the base game mechanics to move the story along. I love both games, but they are completely different, and may not be for everyone, especially as to get the full experience, you need to play through all 3 acts.</p>

<h2>Should I Buy The Arcs Expansions?</h2>

<p>If you liked <em>Arcs</em> with the Leaders and Lore experience from the core set, then the Leaders and Lore Pack adds more of that to keep things fresh.</p>

<p>If you want an incredible narrative experience, and enjoy the core mechanic of <em>Arcs</em>, then The Blighted Reach is a lot of fun, with a huge amount of replability. If you're looking for a balanced experience, focusing on the core strategy of <em>Arcs</em>, then the Blighted Reach isn't for you, as it just uses the mechanics to progress the narrative. That also works on the flipside, and if you didn't like <em>Arcs</em>, but want an enjoyable narrative experience, then you might love the Blighted Reach, where you didn't love the strategy of the base game.</p>

<hr><p><em>The copy of&nbsp;</em><strong>Arcs The Blight Reach and Leaders and Lore Expansions&nbsp;</strong><em>used to produce this review were provided by Asmodee UK.</em></p>


</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Adam is a Tabletop Specialist for TechRaptor. He started writing for TechRaptor in 2017 and took over as Tabletop Editor in 2019 and has since stood down… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/adam-potts">More about Adam</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Arcs Review - Fun Unbridled Space Chaos]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/arcs-review-fun-unbridled-space-chaos</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/arcs-review-fun-unbridled-space-chaos.1058337/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/arcs-review-fun-unbridled-space-chaos<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>You're there. You're nearly there. Your push for power has nearly brought you glory. You hold the resources, and no one can stop you. But something changes. Something shifts and that material wealth will no longer see you at the peak of power. So you shift. You pivot. Your now worthless materials are pushed into production, and your vast fleet emerges into the stars. You burn the fuel you have stockpiled and you prepare to release hell on those that oppose you. The hand you were dealt has forced this, it is not what you sort when you first started, but fate has decreed you become a monster. Welcome to <em>Arcs</em>.</p>

<p><em>Arcs</em> is a sci-fi strategy board game by Cole Wehrle and Leder Games. Most will know their work from the popular <em>Root </em>and <em>Oath</em>&nbsp;board games. <em>Arcs</em> has seen the tabletop industry divided, is it complicated and random, or is this 2024's game of the year? In this review, we'll look at how to play, and how it feels to play.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/arcs-3.jpg?itok=U5BBXDZt 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/arcs-3.jpg?itok=Iw48XPky 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Arcs</em> takes place on a galaxy map that cacn change with the set up cards each game.</figcaption></figure><h2>How Do You Play Arcs?</h2>

<p>You will see <em>Arcs</em> described as a trick-taking game and in essence, this means that players play cards with a suit and a value, and the card the first player plays, sets the standard for those played after. In <em>Arcs</em>, there are 4 types of cards, Administration, Aggression, Construction, and Mobilization. Each of those cards has values 1 through 7. The first player to play a card can play any of their choice. The suit of the card details the actions that they can take, and all cards also have a number of pips (the higher the card value, the fewer pips it has), which details the number of those actions they can do. A 4 pip aggression card means you can take any combination of 4 move, battle, or secure actions.</p>

<p>The actions players can take in <em>Arcs</em> see them doing a mixture of building cities and shipyards, building ships and hiring agents, moving ships to locations to build on, taxing cities they own, or control by having the most ships in an area for resources, or battle with your ships against enemy ships and cities. You can also secure cards, known as the court, where hired agents go onto. If you have the most agents there, you get the card and its ability, and you also capture any enemy agents on that card.&nbsp;</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/arcs-4.jpg?itok=QKXJCU4I 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/arcs-4.jpg?itok=OZMbM43y 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Each of the 4 <em>Arcs </em>card suits dictate the type and number of actions you can take, the amibtion (if any) you can declare and the value that sets the standard if played by the first player.</figcaption></figure><p>The next player then has a choice when they play their card. They can play the same suit, but a higher value, known as surpassing, and they get actions equal to the number of pips on their card. They can play any card face down, known as copying, and take 1 action on the card that was already played. Or the player can play a card face up, and take one action from their card.</p>

<p>When the lead player plays their card, they can also declare an ambition, of which there are 5 to choose from, but they can only choose the one shown on the card they play. In each chapter, only 3 ambitions can be declared, and once declared, anyone can win them, not just the player who declared the ambition. The 5 ambitions are:</p>

<ul><li>Tycoon - won by having the most fuel and material</li>
	<li>Tyrant - won by having the most captives</li>
	<li>Warlord - won by having the most trophies</li>
	<li>Keeper - won by having the most relics</li>
	<li>Empath - won by having the most psionics</li>
</ul><figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/arcs-5.jpg?itok=9Ys-pcxz 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/arcs-5.jpg?itok=vXpSGUY7 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Arcs</em> guild cards can be scored with agents, but if another player scores them, they capture any agents you had on them.</figcaption></figure><h2>Is There A Lot Of Strategy In Arcs?</h2>

<p>The hand you draw each turn in<i> Arcs</i> sets the tone for your turn. Don't have a lot of aggression cards? You're not going to be doing a lot of Warlord or Tyanting. Even if you've been working towards that for the last few chapters, you're going to need to adapt each chapter based on the cards you draw. That might not be appealing to some players, I certainly found it frustrating as I built up my forces and focused the first few chapters on smashing as many of my opponent's ships and cities as possible in my first game, but the more you play <em>Arcs</em>, the more aware you become of the options you have. If you have a huge armada, it still stops your opponent from taxing their own cities and allows you to focus on other areas. If you have a huge amount of stockpiled resources, you can use them for bonus actions that turn, like moving and attacking, outside of the actions from the card you play to watch the galaxy burn.</p>

<p>The timing of declaring an ambition is also extremely strategic as it indicates what you're aiming for. You can only declare an ambition if you play the first card by holding the initiative during each turn in each chapter, and only 3 out of the 5 can be declared, which means that if you spend the entire chapter gaining relics, but the other players all declare 3 different ambitions, you won't score for having them this chapter. Declaring too early pushes other players to compete towards that ambition too, although it's usually pretty obvious what you're aiming for, knowing how and when to pivot your game is a huge part of the strategy.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/arcs-2.jpg?itok=ezfKJFnZ 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/arcs-2.jpg?itok=I5IlHR53 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Battles in <em>Arcs</em> take place using custom dice, with low risk low reward blue dice, high risk high reward red dice, and raid dice to capture resources.</figcaption></figure><h2>How Long Does A Game Of Arcs Take?</h2>

<p>The<i> Arcs'&nbsp;</i>box says 60-120 mins for a game, and that feels about right. Games are rarely super quick, but that's part of the charm. It's not about fast strategy, it's about the slow domination of an area of the game, and the ability to slowly win back other areas if required. You really want to consider your options as you play, and you need to give the other players a chance to do the same. Everything from the card you play to the actions and sequencing of those actions is key, and shouldn't be rushed.</p>

<p>One thing to note is that the setup is pretty fast. There's a deck of cards to shuffle for actions, the components for each player to collect, and the guild deck to shuffle and draw a couple of cards from. The most complex, which isn't that complex, is setting up the map. There are a few set-up card options for each player count, and this details which areas of the map aren't used, and where to set up your pieces. Once that's done, you're ready to go.</p>

<h2>What Are Our Final Thoughts On Arcs?</h2>

<p>I was blown away by <em>Arcs</em> in my first game. I went at it as I usually do in my first play of almost any game, and led with violence over strategy, building up a mighty empire with which to empty the stars of my enemies in later turns. But the cards weren't to be, and I was forced to rethink, which was initially frustrating, why couldn't I play the game I wanted? But actually, no one was playing the game they wanted. Had I pushed forward aggressively, everyone else would have been forced to react and play my game, which they started preparing for, completely setting them off when I forcibly pivoted into gaining resources and using my fleet to protect myself. And it feels like that's what <em>Arcs</em> is about. There's a little bit of chaos with the random card draw, but you can absolutely ride that, and turn it into your strategy, as every other player will be, whilst trying to second-guess your strategy (it's not difficult when playing me, ships, all the ships) and either beat you to it, or offset it with their own.</p>

<h2>Should I Buy Arcs?</h2>

<p>I think <em>Arcs</em> is an awesome game, but is it for everyone? No, it's not. If you don't like longer games, then <em>Arcs</em> is definitely a slow and steady game. It's not a 4-hour slog, but it's at least a couple of hours. There are multiple paths to victory, but they're not all available to you, and the mercy of the card draws may upset some. If you've played&nbsp;Cole Wehrle's other games (<em>Root</em> and <em>Oath</em>), then you'll know what you're getting into and will probably love it. If you're not looking for deep strategy or especially reactive strategy, then this won't be for you. But if the above review sounds like something you and your group will enjoy, then it's definitely a game that gets better the more you play it, and a regular group will find a huge amount of replayability here.</p>

<hr><p><em>The copy of&nbsp;</em><strong>Arcs&nbsp;</strong><em>used to produce this review was provided by Asmodee UK.</em></p>


</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Adam is a Tabletop Specialist for TechRaptor. He started writing for TechRaptor in 2017 and took over as Tabletop Editor in 2019 and has since stood down… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/adam-potts">More about Adam</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Just In Time For The Holidays, PlayStation Plus Gets Sonic, Star Wars, And Jurassic World Games]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/ps-plus-free-games-december-2024-list-sonic-ps5-ps4-1851718879</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/just-in-time-for-the-holidays-playstation-plus-gets-sonic-star-wars-and-jurassic-world-games.1058328/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/ps-plus-free-games-december-2024-list-sonic-ps5-ps4-1851718879<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="481f7eb5a1614b0c9b8fe8c04bc66299" data-recommend-id="image://481f7eb5a1614b0c9b8fe8c04bc66299" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="An image shows Sonic, C-3PO, and a dinosaur. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="An image shows Sonic, C-3PO, and a dinosaur. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Sega / Lucasfilm / Universal / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="481f7eb5a1614b0c9b8fe8c04bc66299" data-recommend-id="image://481f7eb5a1614b0c9b8fe8c04bc66299" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="An image shows Sonic, C-3PO, and a dinosaur. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>This month Sony is adding a recent <em>Sonic</em> game, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/games/jurassic-world-evolution-2&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/games/jurassic-world-evolution-2"><em>Jurassic World Evolution 2</em></a></span>, the divisive <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/forspoken-review-dialogue-rpg-square-frey-open-world-1850048781&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/forspoken-review-dialogue-rpg-square-frey-open-world-1850048781"><em>Forspoken</em></a></span>, and a<em> Star Wars </em>VR experience to its large PlayStation Plus Game Catalog. All these games arrive just in time for being stuck indoors due to snow and family gatherings. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196181" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="The Best Reveals From The Game Awards 2023" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="180" data-playlist="196181,196230,196123" data-current="196181"><div><p>The Best Reveals From The Game Awards 2023</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196181/196181_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196181/196181_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196181/196181_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196181/196181_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21718.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p> <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://blog.playstation.com/2024/12/11/playstation-plus-game-catalog-for-december-sonic-frontiers-forspoken-rabbids-party-of-legends-wrc-generations-and-more/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://blog.playstation.com/2024/12/11/playstation-plus-game-catalog-for-december-sonic-frontiers-forspoken-rabbids-party-of-legends-wrc-generations-and-more/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">On December 11, PlayStation officially announced</a></span> the next round of PS Plus Extra and Premium games that will be added to the service’s game catalog. These new games will be available starting on December 17. </p><p>Sony previously revealed in November that some PS2 classics,<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/ps-plus-games-december-2024-classics-ps2-sly-cooper-jak-1851709425&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/ps-plus-games-december-2024-classics-ps2-sly-cooper-jak-1851709425" target="_blank"> including<em> Sly 2</em> and <em>Sly 3</em></a></span>, would be added to PS Plus this month, and we’ve included those titles (as well as the free monthly games) in this list. </p><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/sonic-hedgehog-3-movie-early-reviews-premiere-keanu-1851718562&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/sonic-hedgehog-3-movie-early-reviews-premiere-keanu-1851718562"><em>Sonic the Hedgehog 3</em> is headed to theaters this Christmas</a></span>, so it’s only fitting that one of his latest games, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/sonic-frontiers-review-open-world-breath-of-the-wild-1849764736&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/sonic-frontiers-review-open-world-breath-of-the-wild-1849764736">2022's <em>Sonic Frontiers</em></a></span>, is arriving on PS Plus this month. <em>Frontiers</em> is nothing like the new movies or classic 2D games from the franchise’s past. Instead, it’s a lonely mess of a game that looks and feels a lot like <em>Death Stranding</em>. It’s an odd one for sure, but strangely compelling, too.</p><hr><p>Anyway, here’s the full list of games being added to PS Plus and its various tiers next week:</p><h2 id="h114865"><a id=""></a><strong>PlayStation Plus Extra and Premium</strong></h2><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li><em>Sonic Frontiers</em> | PS4, PS5</li><li><em>Forspoken </em>| PS5</li><li><em>Rabbids: Party of Legends</em>| PS4</li><li><em>WRC Generations </em>| PS4, PS5</li><li><em>F.I.S.T.: Forged In Shadow Torch</em> | PS4, PS5</li><li><em>Jurassic World Evolution 2</em> | PS4, PS5</li><li><em>Coffee Talk </em>| PS4, PS5</li><li><em>Coffee Talk Episode 2: Hibiscus &amp; Butterfly</em> | PS4, PS5</li><li><em>A Space for the Unbound</em> | PS4, PS5</li><li><em>Phogs</em> | PS4</li><li><em>Biped </em>| PS4, PS5</li></ul><h2 id="h114866"><a id=""></a><strong>PlayStation Plus Premium</strong></h2><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li><em>Star Wars: Tales from the Galaxy’s Edge</em> | PS VR2</li><li>  <em>Sly 2: Band of Thieves</em> | PS4, PS5</li><li>  <em>Sly 3: Honor Among Thieves </em>| PS4, PS5</li><li><em>Jak and Daxter: The Precursor Legacy</em> | PS4, PS5</li></ul><p>And, as announced last month, these are the three games available to all PS Plus subscribers to download until January 6: </p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li>  <em>It Takes Two</em> | PS4, PS5</li><li><em>Aliens: Dark Descent </em>| PS4, PS5</li><li><em>Temtem </em>| PS5</li></ul><p>Remember, to access, download, and play these games you’ll need to be an active PS Plus Extra or Premium tier subscriber. And if your subscription runs out in the future, you’ll no longer be able to play these games.</p><p> .<br></p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Google Is Testing AI That "Helps" You Play Video Games]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/google-is-testing-ai-that-helps-you-play-video-games/1100-6528391/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/google-is-testing-ai-that-helps-you-play-video-games.1058322/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/google-is-testing-ai-that-helps-you-play-video-games/1100-6528391/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6528391">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>AI is already being used by some companies in the production of video games, but now there's an AI that may be able to help people play games. Google is currently testing AI that it says can process the information on screen in real-time and offer advice to players about how to proceed.</p><p>Google revealed this information while touting <a href="https://blog.google/technology/google-deepmind/google-gemini-ai-update-december-2024/#ceo-message" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">the benefits of its Gemini 2.0 AI model</a>. AI agents created by Gemini 2.0 are using Supercell games like Clash of Clans and Hay Day to test the technology's ability to learn and decipher the "rules and challenges across a diverse range of games." The idea is that these agents can engage players in conversation with hints and strategies, in addition to using Google Search to look up any relevant info.</p><p>Setting aside the matter of whether this actually works, the real question is whether an AI game buddy is something that players really want or need. Adding AI in this fashion may be more distracting than helpful, especially if it breaks the narrative flow of a game. Additionally, the titles cited as test subjects are fairly simple compared to AAA console and computer games. Even if this new AI works as intended, it may be years away from being useful with more-complex titles.</p><p>Earlier this month, PlayStation boss Hermen Hulst shared his belief that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/playstation-boss-says-ai-can-revolutionize-gaming-but-the-human-element-remains-vital/1100-6528197/" data-ref-id="1100-6528197">AI can revolutionize game development</a>, but he also stressed the importance of the human element. Amazon's Christoph Hartmann of Amazon said that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ai-can-help-solve-game-industrys-problems-or-at-least-some-of-them-amazon-boss-says/1100-6526061/" data-ref-id="1100-6526061">AI could replace "boring" parts of game development</a> rather than the creative aspects. But so far, some of these projected AI capabilities appear to be theoretical until the technology significantly improves.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox Game Pass Adds A Nice New Feature, But Only For Testers Right Now]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/xbox-game-pass-adds-a-nice-new-feature-but-only-for-testers-right-now/1100-6528390/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/xbox-game-pass-adds-a-nice-new-feature-but-only-for-testers-right-now.1058319/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/xbox-game-pass-adds-a-nice-new-feature-but-only-for-testers-right-now/1100-6528390/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6528390">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Microsoft has announced that Xbox Game Pass Ultimate members can now stream some games they own on Xbox consoles as part of a pilot program, with the expectation for the feature to roll out for everyone in 2025. In a <a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2024/12/11/xbox-insiders-with-game-pass-ultimate-stream-your-own-game-on-xbox-consoles/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">blog post</a>, Microsoft said Xbox Insiders who are in the Alpha Skip-Ahead and Alpha rings can test out this feature right now. The Xbox Insider program is <a href="https://support.xbox.com/en-US/help/account-profile/manage-account/xbox-insider-program" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">free and open to everyone. </a></p><p>In November, Microsoft <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/game-pass-ultimate-will-now-let-you-stream-non-game-pass-games-including-baldurs-gate-3/1100-6527893/" data-ref-id="1100-6527893">announced</a> that Game Pass Ultimate members could stream select non-Game Pass games they own on a smartphone, PC, or tablet in 28 supported countries. Now, however, this is being extended to consoles.</p><p>This new feature is called "Stream your own game," and it allows players to stream games they own that are outside of the Game Pass catalog--the list of supported titles can be seen <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/game-pass-ultimate-will-now-let-you-stream-non-game-pass-games-including-baldurs-gate-3/1100-6527893/" data-ref-id="1100-6527893">here</a>. It includes games like Assassin's Creed Mirage, Baldur's Gate 3, Cyberpunk 2077, Hogwarts Legacy, and NBA 2K25.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4414063-screenshot2024-12-11at2.03.38pm.png" data-ref-id="1300-4414063" data-ratio="0.55764304013664" data-width="2342" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4414063-screenshot2024-12-11at2.03.38pm.png" data-ref-id="1300-4414063"></a><figcaption>The cloud badge lets you know if a game can be streamed or not</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4414063-screenshot2024-12-11at2.03.38pm.png"></figure><p>Microsoft says the big benefit here is that players do not need to download anything locally because the games themselves are being streamed over the internet from a Microsoft data center. With file sizes growing, this might be an attractive option for some people. Of course, players need a stable and powerful internet connection for the best experience. Players should also be mindful about any data caps their internet service provider might have, as streaming games would quickly eat into that.</p><p>Players can navigate to My games &amp; apps &gt; Full library &gt; Owned games to get started. From there, players will see a new "cloud badge" that lets them know if a game can be streamed. Users can also use the filter settings to see only the games that support cloud gaming. In the future, Microsoft said it plans build out the feature even more with things like support for launching directly from the Store app and streaming in the Xbox app on Windows PC.</p><p>The ability to stream non-Game Pass games could be quite handy in the event that one of your favorite games leaves the Game Pass library. Provided that game continues to offer cloud streaming, players could continue to be able to stream a game by purchasing it and then using this feature to stream it.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[10 Years Later, Alien: Isolation Still Benefits From One Vital Design Decision]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/10-years-later-alien-isolation-still-benefits-from-one-vital-design-decision/1100-6528385/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/10-years-later-alien-isolation-still-benefits-from-one-vital-design-decision.1058298/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/10-years-later-alien-isolation-still-benefits-from-one-vital-design-decision/1100-6528385/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6528385">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">Even a decade after its release, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/alien-isolation/" data-ref-id="5000-232868">Alien: Isolation</a> remains a standout experience.</p><p dir="ltr">It's a monumental example of adaptation in video games, thanks to the fact that developer Creative Assembly was packed with fans of Ridley Scott's 1979 film, Alien, and an incredibly tight, detailed focus on the fidelity of the movie's setting. It also set a bar in horror game design, with the alien operating on a set of reactive artificial intelligence rules that made it terrifyingly unpredictable and unstoppably lethal.</p><p dir="ltr">It also stands apart from other games based on the Alien franchise, which tend to ignore Scott's original film in favor of iterations on Aliens, James Cameron's sequel, which moves away from straight horror to feature more action--and a bunch of well-outfitted, smack-talking Marines. Creative Assembly instead pitched an <em>Alien</em> game, not an <em>Aliens</em> game, one that would focus on making the creature feel like an unstoppable, unknowable predator instead of a horde of animals players would mow down with pulse rifles.</p><p dir="ltr">"The goal was to transport you back to that time and place, that 1970s view of the future, the kind of lo-fi sci-fi aesthetic of that first movie, allowing you to encounter and try and survive against that original alien--where just one alien could be terrifying, which is really different in terms of video games," director Al Hope told me in a recent interview. "The fact that you can play it today and get that experience, get that feeling--as part of the team that made it, that's so rewarding."</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1197/11970954/2699099-alienisolationdlc_001.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-2699099" data-ratio="0.54895833333333" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1197/11970954/2699099-alienisolationdlc_001.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-2699099"></a><figcaption>Alien: Isolation focused on capturing the horror intrinsic in the original 1979 film, specifically to make the alien terrifying again.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1197/11970954/2699099-alienisolationdlc_001.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">Alien: Isolation recently celebrated its 10-year anniversary, and rather than fade into obscurity as time marched on and new game releases took attention away, it instead seems to have grown in popularity over the years since its release. Streamers and content creators seem to keep finding the game, and new ports have been released on Nintendo Switch, iOS, and Android. The Switch version also got a fairly expansive physical collector's edition release from Limited Run Games last year--fully nine years after Alien: Isolation first came out.</p><p dir="ltr">It seems that there's not just a fanbase for Alien: Isolation, but a growing demand for it. On the anniversary, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/alien-isolation-2-is-in-early-development-with-original-director-returning/1100-6526951/">Creative Assembly announced it has started work on an Alien: Isolation sequel</a>, with Hope returning as its director.</p><p dir="ltr">"What's really incredible is that it seems to have grown and snowballed over time, over the last decade, as more people have found it and people talk about it," Hope said. "It's still in the conversation around the scariest games and best Alien game, or whatever. One of the really rewarding things is people are still finding it for the first time today, and having a really fantastic experience. And, you know, considering it's a relatively old game now, or could be considered a relatively old game. And, yeah, I think that's just a testament to the fantastic work that the team did, because it was a labor of love. But, yeah, it's just immensely rewarding that people are still playing and talking about it today."</p><p dir="ltr">What makes Alien: Isolation so frightening is how much the game reacts to the player's actions, beginning with the impressive AI running its alien. The creature is designed to seek players out using its senses, and when it can't find you, to search the station in a fairly systematic way. Another AI, an underlying director, will sometimes direct the alien in your direction if you've gone too long without an encounter, or away from you if the tension has been high for a long time.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/536/5360430/2563858-01_1402071153.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-2563858" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/536/5360430/2563858-01_1402071153.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-2563858"></a><figcaption>Artificial intelligence systems at work in Alien: Isolation provide a sense that the creature is always hunting you, and being careful and aware are the only things that can save your life.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/536/5360430/2563858-01_1402071153.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">Other systems also work dynamically to increase the tension and fear when things get intense. Sound design is a huge part of what makes Alien: Isolation so effective, and it's full of reactive elements to ratchet up the fear--including ramping up the music as the situation with the alien gets more and more harrowing.</p><p dir="ltr">"It was interesting for us because we had this idea that the creature wasn't going to be choreographed and scripted, which is what typically occurs in this kind of game," Hope explained. "And I seem to remember this kind of penny drop moment where we realized, well, we can't just ask the composers to create a wav file that we'll just hit play on and it will play out, because it will completely disconnect with what's happening. Because the creature and the drama and the action is completely dynamic and unpredictable, we're gonna have to do something completely different, and that felt like, wow, okay, this has a really big impact on everything, and especially the music, because the music needs to be able to support tension, anticipation, action, and we don't know what's going to happen."</p><blockquote data-size="medium" data-align="right"><p dir="ltr">We kept getting, 'We need more deaths. Everyone's dying all the time. We need more deaths.' Like 90 different death cues."</p></blockquote><p dir="ltr">"So much is going on under the hood with the music, to get on with the mixing of all the ambient sounds and local sounds," he continued. "We're doing some really fun and pretty clever things, where, when the alien is getting close, we might push the music so we have this emotional content that's kind of being more present than what the player's receiving. But, say there's an alarm going on in the room, we'll actually duck that down, so it's almost like we're replicating the player's focus on the alien so everything else doesn't matter. It's doing really quite brilliant, interesting things to really enhance the experience. And so what you're receiving is this constant, ever-fluctuating soundscape that's being remixed in real time."</p><p dir="ltr">In keeping with the heightened demand for Alien: Isolation, the 10th anniversary also saw another long-awaited release: the game's soundtrack. It's now available on streaming services, and a vinyl and cassette edition are available for preorder from <a href="https://www.iam8bit.com/products/alien-isolation-vinyl-soundtrack" rel="nofollow ">iam8bit</a>.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1581/15811374/4413977-alienisolationsoundtrack.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4413977" data-ratio="1" data-width="1000" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1581/15811374/4413977-alienisolationsoundtrack.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4413977"></a><figcaption>True to the game's analog tech nature, the iam8bit release of Alien: Isolation's soundtrack is available on vinyl or on cassette tape.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1581/15811374/4413977-alienisolationsoundtrack.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">Creating music that could work dynamically with those systems was a challenge unto itself, as composers Joe Henson and Alexis Smith, who together make up English duo The Flight, told me. Alien: Isolation wasn't the duo's first game--they'd previously worked on Assassin's Creed IV: Black Flag and LittleBigPlanet. But on previous games, the pair was learning how music in games worked. Isolation was the first big game where they were able to do exactly what they wanted, Henson said, and they were drawn to its low-fi, '70s-inspired aesthetic.</p><p dir="ltr">While Alien: Isolation's approach to music <em>seemed</em> like a complex problem to solve at the time, the pair said, it didn't actually end up being that difficult to write music that could be used dynamically. It mostly required creating different layers of tracks for each level: an exploration layer for when the player wasn't under threat, a more intense layer for when the alien was present but not hunting you, and a "you're about to die" layer, Henson said.</p><p dir="ltr">"What I remember mostly is making this third layer, which was the 'you're about to die' layer, and it's all very well, making a five-minute ambient exploration piece," he explained. "In order for it to be able to go into this 'you're about to die' at any point, we had to make a five-minute 'you're about to die' layer. We were young and green and really wanting to put our mark on the first game we were going to be proud of, so we did these completely bespoke five minutes. We didn't copy bits. We did ups and downs and going with what was happening in the music. And it works really well. But they were exhausting [to write]."</p><p dir="ltr">"And loads of deaths," Smith chimed in, laughing. "We kept getting, 'We need more deaths. Everyone's dying all the time. We need more deaths.' Like 90 different death cues."</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/536/5360430/2563863-06_1402071176.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-2563863" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/536/5360430/2563863-06_1402071176.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-2563863"></a><figcaption>Creative Assembly made sure the alien was a formidable opponent--you can never kill it, only drive it away, but your defenses become less effective the more you use them.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/536/5360430/2563863-06_1402071176.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">The music in Alien: Isolation is a big way in which the game links to the movie and works to convey its tone. Isolation's music uses portions of composer Jerry Goldsmith's score from the movie, but as The Flight have noted in the past, there's not actually that much music in Alien, period.</p><p dir="ltr">Isolation separates itself by using some elements of Goldsmith's original score, "threading that DNA" of Alien throughout the game, as Hope put it, while also adding its own sound with the use of other period-appropriate instruments, like synthesizers and electronic elements.</p><p dir="ltr">"That was an interesting discovery actually, while we're working on it, where, when we felt we were losing the Alien sound, we could just drop pepper in those--there are such strong sounds, not just motifs, just <em>sounds </em>from Alien from the score, that we could very easily kind of bring in and bring us back," Smith said.</p><blockquote data-size="medium" data-align="right"><p dir="ltr">We never thought about trying to compromise."</p></blockquote><p dir="ltr">"It's not like a theme song; it doesn't, like, repeat," Henson said, to which Smith added that the memorable musical elements of Alien are more like "little bits" and small musical phrases. Other elements of the score, like clicking sounds and different noises, as well as analog elements from the equipment and instruments used to create those sounds, ended up being very useful in keeping Isolation's soundscape feeling like Alien.</p><p dir="ltr">"We kind of saw them as almost like samples that we could throw in with other stuff," Henson continued. "And because we love that film so much, and we love that score and everything, that's the way we kind of treated it. Not with too much reverence that we wouldn't do anything to it or change anything, but we knew how to--you know, as long as the electronics we were adding, as long as the stuff we were adding was as crusty as the computers on the space station, then we thought it would work."</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1365/13658182/2589188-alienisolation2_1404833866.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-2589188" data-ratio="0.56475" data-width="4000" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1365/13658182/2589188-alienisolation2_1404833866.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-2589188"></a><figcaption>20th Century Fox gave Creative Assembly access to a huge amount of archival information from Alien, which the studio used to faithfully recreate the look and sound of the film.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1365/13658182/2589188-alienisolation2_1404833866.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">Getting that soundtrack released "has been an epic struggle," Hope said. A version has been ready to go for the last 10 years--Henson and Smith created a listening version akin to a film score back when Alien: Isolation was in production--but the complex web of stakeholders, copyright holders, and contracts held it back.</p><p dir="ltr">The situation around game soundtracks has changed during that period as well, Smith said. The business of selling game soundtracks has grown significantly, which increased the incentives to finally make Isolation's available.</p><p dir="ltr">For The Flight, the release is a big one. Of all the games they've worked on, Smith said, Alien: Isolation is the one the duo gets asked about most often.</p><p dir="ltr">"We've got a 1 million sales thing here [for Alien: Isolation]," Henson said. "I don't know what the sales have got to, but it doesn't touch some of the games we've done. But for fan adoration and respect, from our peers, as well, it's the one."</p><p dir="ltr">"The big thing about this game is, this kind of launched us," Smith said. "So it's a really special soundtrack for us. I still go back and play the game with people I know. I've just actually given it to a friend of mine whose kids have just got into Alien. They're like 18, 19, and one of my friend's kids is absolutely obsessed with it. And now the calls I've been getting are brilliant. The whole family are terrified."</p><p dir="ltr">"I finally played the game with my eldest son last year, but he couldn't. He wouldn't," Henson added. "He plays games all the time. He wouldn't play it on his own. He refused to play on his own when it was dark, because I turn out all the lights. He was shit scared. I feel like there are a lot of people like that."</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1197/11970954/2423662-0004.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-2423662" data-ratio="0.56475" data-width="4000" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1197/11970954/2423662-0004.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-2423662"></a><figcaption>The intense attention to detail in visuals and sound makes Alien: Isolation one of the best film adaptations ever in video games.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1197/11970954/2423662-0004.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">Replaying Alien: Isolation today, it absolutely holds up--the game is still as unpredictable and frightening as it was in 2014. But while it seems to continue to find its audience, there was a point at release that it seemed to struggle. Review aggregator Metacritic puts Alien: Isolation at an average score of 79, but there are scores that run the gamut, from several 10 out of 10s and 9 out of 10s, to a few that fall significantly lower. At the time, GameSpot gave Alien: Isolation a 6.5 out of 10. IGN reviewed it at a 6 out of 10. Reviewers lauded the game's fidelity in bringing players into its world, but some struggled with the difficulty and dealing with the alien itself.</p><p dir="ltr">I asked Hope if, looking back, there was anything he wished he and the team had done differently. His answer was short: "Ultimately, on balance, no."</p><blockquote data-size="medium" data-align="right"><p dir="ltr">I finally played the game with my eldest son last year, but he couldn't. He wouldn't. He was shit scared. I feel like there are a lot of people like that."</p></blockquote><p dir="ltr">"I think we knew, by its nature, we weren't trying to please everybody, you know?" he said. "Some players might think it's too hard. So do we then make it much easier? But then the people who want something more of a challenge will be disappointed. So that's not even really a discussion we had, because we wanted to create this Alien experience which presented a certain level of intrinsic challenge if we were going to take it the approach that we did. ...We never thought about trying to compromise."</p><p dir="ltr">The uncompromising vision was, ultimately, the correct call. It didn't happen all at once, but Alien: Isolation has left its mark both on the extended Alien universe and on the horror game landscape at large. Fede Alvarez, the director of the newest Alien movie, Alien: Romulus, has cited Isolation as an inspiration for the kind of horror he wanted to conjure up with the movie, and he even included the <a href="https://www.bing.com/ck/a?!&amp;&amp;p=27c6b2fb3ffa3b0bac2c0e649fbf149cb95e9e320d2907667ef3c3ad2b6448a6JmltdHM9MTczMzcwMjQwMA&amp;ptn=3&amp;ver=2&amp;hsh=4&amp;fclid=05d40eb0-41a0-65da-0c4b-1d16404e64d2&amp;psq=alien+romulus+alien+isolation+influence+gamespot.com&amp;u=a1aHR0cHM6Ly93d3cuZ2FtZXNwb3QuY29tL2FydGljbGVzL2FsaWVuLXJvbXVsdXMtaW5jbHVkZXMtYW4tZWFzdGVyLWVnZy1mb3ItdGhpcy1wb3B1bGFyLXZpZGVvLWdhbWUvMTEwMC02NTI1NzUwLw&amp;ntb=1">iconic emergency phone save points from Isolation</a> as Easter eggs in the film. Amanda Ripley, Isolation's protagonist, has also become a recurring character in ongoing Alien comics and other media.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1365/13658182/2677748-alienisolation_ai_launch_screen004_1411636900_result.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-2677748" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1365/13658182/2677748-alienisolation_ai_launch_screen004_1411636900_result.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-2677748"></a><figcaption>The story of Alien: Isolation has continued to influence other Alien media, with Amanda Ripley showing up in more stories in the wider canon.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1365/13658182/2677748-alienisolation_ai_launch_screen004_1411636900_result.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">Other horror developers have started to take pages from Creative Assembly's approach to its creature, too, leading to some terrifying new experiences. Games such as <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/amnesia-the-bunker/" data-ref-id="5000-577134">Amnesia: The Bunker</a> and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/the-outlast-trials/" data-ref-id="5000-505577">The Outlast Trials</a> feel like different riffs on the idea, putting players in the same kinds of tense situations with unpredictable, unkillable antagonists.</p><p dir="ltr">The Switch and mobile ports, the collector's edition, and the soundtrack release all suggest a demand for Alien: Isolation that's been building, not receding. That goes for the sequel, too--Hope wouldn't talk about it, but said a continual call of a sequel is something Creative Assembly has received every day since the game's release.</p><p dir="ltr">Hope said he and the Alien: Isolation team are "immensely proud" of what they achieved with the game.</p><p>"The team did what we set out to achieve, which was to create that authentic experience that felt like it had never been available before--and we were just <em>desperate </em>to experience that and play it ourselves," he said. "Ten years later, people are still picking up, for the first time, having an amazing experience and talking about wanting more. So, you know, we're really fortunate for the people out there. They've really connected with what we did."</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Operations Manager Is Actually A Very Cool Video Game Job, But So Is Being A Hades Voice Actor]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/operations-manager-hades-supergiant</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/operations-manager-is-actually-a-very-cool-video-game-job-but-so-is-being-a-hades-voice-actor.1058280/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://aftermath.site/operations-manager-hades-supergiant<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>It's been a while since we ran a<a href="https://aftermath.site/category/what-i-do" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> 'What I Do' feature</a>, so let's rectify that!</p><p>This week's instalment is a <em>very </em>fun one. The main reason I started the column was to help shed a light on <em>every </em>corner of games development, from the most obvious job descriptions to the most obscure. And I don't think there are many more obscure than 'Operations Manager'.</p><p>Do you know what an Operations Manager does? Aside from...managing operations? Probably not! But it's an incredibly important job, often serving as the glue that can help hold an entire project--and studio--together. To help me (and you!) better understand the role and what it involves, I spoke with <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/michael-ailshie-b85b785a/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Michael Ailshie</a> about operational health, keeping the lights on and...being a voice actor for <em>Hades</em>.</p><p><strong>Luke Plunkett</strong>: <em><strong>Hello, Michael! Tell us a little about yourself! </strong></em></p><p><strong>Michael Ailshie</strong>: Hello! I’m a California native who grew up about 15 minutes from Disneyland - where I also landed my first job as a canoe guide! After high school, I escaped the tropical Mediterranean climate of Orange County for the colder Mediterranean climate of the San Francisco Bay Area, where I studied English Literature at U.C. Berkeley. I graduated from college in the fortuitous year of 2008 (with an English degree, no less), and ended up managing front-of-house operations at Whole Foods in Oakland before responding to a Craigslist post from an anonymous San Francisco video game developer in 2011. That anonymous developer turned out to be Supergiant Games, with whom I would end up working for nearly a decade. I currently live in Hollywood with my wife, a voice actor and improviser who’s been involved with UCB, Second City, and the Groundlings (our pup, Chili Cheese, and our elderly cat, Craig). </p><figure><figcaption>Chili Cheese (L) &amp; Craig (R)</figcaption></figure><p><strong>LP</strong>: <em><strong>Can you tell us a little about your career in the video game industry? What's your current role, and what are some of your other recent positions?</strong></em></p><p><strong>MA</strong>: I’m currently the General Manager at Null Games, a new indie games publisher founded on the notion that developers don’t need to sign away their life’s work and their ability to earn a living to acquire funding and support for their games. We offer generous, equitable terms that enable our developers to focus on making great games. As with most of my jobs in the industry, I wear a lot of hats in this role: finance manager, HR administrator, legalese analyst, strategist, business developer, and guy who worries a lot. Prior to this role, I was the Senior Operations Manager at Night School Studio, Lead External Development Manager at Epic Games, and Operations Manager at Supergiant Games. Prior to the pandemic, I also moonlit as the head of merchandise operations for The Last Podcast on the Left.&nbsp;</p><p><strong>LP</strong>: <em><strong>That's...a lot of hats. So to stick to your most-worn hat, what does a job managing people and systems actually look like? Like, what does an average day or week entail? </strong></em></p><p><strong>MA</strong>: Operations is sort of an invisible discipline in games. If you’re doing the job of an Operations Manager well, your day-to-day is relatively incognito. Sometimes, though, things will go wrong and you’ll become acutely aware of what Operations teams are responsible for. If you’ve ever had an issue with onboarding, payroll, benefits, contracts, government agencies, payments, software licenses, hardware, or just having a functional, organized place to work and the means to do that work effectively, it’s likely something was rotten in the state of Operations. As my old colleague Greg Kasavin used to say, “Michael keeps the lights on around here.” While that might sound a bit reductive, I always wore that as a badge of honor because, frankly, it takes a lot of work to keep the lights on for a successful video game studio.&nbsp;</p><p>As the Operations Manager for Supergiant Games, there often wasn’t an “average” day-to-day since there was always some new and exciting challenge on the horizon, but on a given day, you could expect to find me vetting and negotiating contracts, maintaining the company’s financial records, filing taxes, literally paying the bills, building workstations, administering the studio’s benefits offerings, running the studio’s official merchandise store, planning the studio’s live event activations, and managing partnerships with any number of external mercenaries adjacent to those projects. During my time there, I built dozens of highly-themed event booths, packaged and shipped thousands of vinyl records, pestered people for countless receipts, scouted voice acting talent, and even navigated the treacherous waters of San Francisco commercial real estate.&nbsp;</p><p>While at Night School (which was acquired by Netflix), a fair amount of the Operations work mentioned above fell to dedicated teams like Finance, Facilities, HR, and so on. Some of the benefits of working with a large company! With much of that tactical work handled by better, faster, stronger colleagues, my day-to-day was more focused on the long-term operational health of the studio. When not moonlighting as a game producer, I wrote the studio’s employee handbook, built budget and team growth projections, managed new team member onboarding, organized and moderated the studio’s regular all-hands meetings, organized team-building events, constructed a centralized database that allowed our production and development teams to track all of our projects, negotiated contracts with external parties, and ran budgeting and forecasting exercises that tried to peer into the distant future.&nbsp;</p><p><strong>LP: </strong><em><strong>What is it about the job that you love? What keeps you coming into work every day, and doing what you do?&nbsp;</strong></em></p><p><strong>MA</strong>: It might sound strange, but I love it when my work removes worry and occupational stress from the equation for creative game developers. I hear so many horror stories from small development teams about losing creative development time to competing (and critically important) priorities like recruiting, negotiating, taxes, accounting, payroll, benefits, contracts, and generally “keeping the lights on,” and I love getting the chance to tank those problems. I firmly believe that when creative, passionate game developers are shielded from the anxieties that come with running and maintaining a business by someone with the aptitude to manage that work, they tend to make really good video games. Beyond that, I love figuring out how to solve problems that have no template to follow. For example, I had no playbook when it came to organizing an orchestra concert, but it was a blast to figure out and pull off.&nbsp;</p><p><strong>LP</strong>: <strong><em>Putting everything you love and work hard on aside, is there anything you </em>don't<em> enjoy about the job? And is there anything the wider games industry could do to make it better or easier for anyone doing a role like yours?</em></strong></p><p><strong>MA</strong>: I’ll never forget an interaction I had with a PAX attendee a few years into my tenure at Supergiant. When this person asked what I did at the studio, I let them know I was the Operations Manager and told them a bit about that role. Their response? “Ok. Can I talk to somebody relevant to the game?” Ouch! While I take it in stride and feel confident in my contributions today, I do think that many people both in and out of the industry consider folks who aren’t actively making video game assets as tangential at best and superfluous at worst, when that couldn’t be further from the truth. I’ll always appreciate Supergiant co-founder Amir Rao for insisting that everyone on the team, regardless of their title, was a “developer.” Just like any narrative designer, artist, or engineer, I got into this business to make incredible video games and am happy I get to do that in an unconventional way.&nbsp;</p><p><strong>LP</strong>: <strong><em>Before we go, I saw a </em>Hades<em> voice actor credit on your bio and it would be remiss if I didn't also ask how the hell that came to be and what it was like.</em></strong></p><p><strong>MA</strong>: I worked with Greg and Darren to track down some vocal talent for both <em>Pyre</em> and <em>Hades</em> via the SF Bay Area and LA improv communities (including my wife, Courtney Vineys, who voiced Ti’Zo in <em>Pyre</em>, and both Aphrodite and Dusa in <em>Hades</em>). I really enjoyed the casting process and loved finding uniquely talented actors that could bring their characters to life. Like a number of Supergiant’s core creative team members (including composer Darren Korb and voice actor Logan Cunningham), I was a high school theater kid and have never lost my passion for the DRAMATIC ARTS (aka playing make-em-ups and doing funny voices). At the tail end of casting for <em>Hades</em>, Greg and Darren actually asked me if I wanted to audition for the role of Orpheus. Of course, I said yes. Luckily, it wasn’t a stretch for me to pull off the disaffected, malaise-stricken vocal stylings of <em>Hades</em>’ resident bard, and I got the part. However, I left the singing work to Darren (trust me, you don’t want to hear my version of “Lament of Orpheus”).&nbsp;&nbsp;</p></div><div><h2>Stay in touch</h2><p>Sign up for our free newsletter</p></div><div><h2><span>More from Aftermath</span></h2><div><a target="" rel="" tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/moxie-robot-ai-dying-llm-embodied"><h3>AI Company That Made Robots For Children Went Bust And Now The Robots Are Dying</h3></a><p>Embodied, maker of the AI robot called Moxie, is shuttering. With their closing, parents have to explain to their kids that Moxie is dead.</p></div><a target="" rel="" tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/all">See all posts<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="#000" stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round"><path d="M5 12h13m-6-7 7 7-7 7"></path></svg></a></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[TankHead is out today!]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/12/11/tankhead-is-out-today/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/tankhead-is-out-today.1058265/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/12/11/tankhead-is-out-today/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>TankHead has a release date and that release date is… today! That’s right, the thoroughly unusual tank combat, survival and scavenging game TankHead is out now, exclusively on the Epic Games Store.</p>
<p><iframe title="TankHead - Launch Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fyZo9AC0bsM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>TankHead takes place in an apocalyptic setting where the war-torn world of ECA has become almost entirely uninhabitable. It’s because of this that Whitaker needs to tele-project his consciousness into a Needle drone that can survive the harsh environment. Also pilot a tank. That’s also quite important.</p>
<p>Heading into the wasteland, you’ll need a tank, but you’ll have to scavenge and cobble it together from parts. collecting new weapons, wheels, armour, spare parts, engines and more to improve your vehicle.</p>
<p>Because of the scrappily put together tanks you have, you’ll need a tactical approach to combatting the enemy tanks you face, always trying to present your strongest side – you have separate control of the tank’s direction and the turret – evade incoming fire as much as possible and chip away at their armour to reveal weak points to target.</p>

<p>The better and cleaner the vicoty, the more valuable the loot you can recover from the burning carcass of your fallen foes, grabbing replacement parts and upgrades for your tank.</p>
<p>It all culminates in battles against truly bizarre boss tanks, which in the trailer seems to include a very angry walking hotel or river boat?</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Neon Abyss 2 brings more run ‘n gun roguelike action to Early Access in 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/12/11/neon-abyss-2-brings-more-run-n-gun-roguelike-action-to-early-access-in-2025/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/neon-abyss-2-brings-more-run-%E2%80%98n-gun-roguelike-action-to-early-access-in-2025.1058262/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/12/11/neon-abyss-2-brings-more-run-n-gun-roguelike-action-to-early-access-in-2025/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Veewo Games has revealed Neon Abyss 2, a sequel to their hit run ‘n’ gun roguelike from 2020. Neon Abyss 2 is heading to Steam Early Access in 2025.</p>
<p><iframe title="Neon Abyss 2 | Reveal Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/A86PCFApasQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>Neon Abyss 2 aims to take everything that was great about the original and amp it up to 11. There’s a wild range of weapons, from deadly plants to dragon-like creatures, all of which will shift your combat style in tandem with synergistic power-ups that you will combine and evolve through each run. You can also still hatch and train new companions, evolving them into allies that will fight alongside you.</p>
<p>And there’s now a Faith system that can be used to power up, recruit allies, or gamble away.</p>
<p>Oh, and of course there’s still minigames, with the trailer wrapping up with a little bit of basketball.</p>



<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[5 Things I Love And 4 Things I Loathe About Indiana Jones And The Great Circle]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/indiana-jones-great-circle-bethesda-locks-doors-breath-1851718447</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/5-things-i-love-and-4-things-i-loathe-about-indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle.1058250/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/indiana-jones-great-circle-bethesda-locks-doors-breath-1851718447<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><figure id="" data-id="d4ec66d11f80dd94e286766189728cff" data-recommend-id="image://d4ec66d11f80dd94e286766189728cff" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Indiana Jones in his trademark hat looks absolutely horrified, his mouth open, his eyes wide." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Indiana Jones in his trademark hat looks absolutely horrified, his mouth open, his eyes wide." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Bethesda / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="d4ec66d11f80dd94e286766189728cff" data-recommend-id="image://d4ec66d11f80dd94e286766189728cff" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Indiana Jones in his trademark hat looks absolutely horrified, his mouth open, his eyes wide." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>I’m having such a good time with <em>Indy</em> and his splendid circle. My hopes for the game were incredibly raised when I saw <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/indiana-jones-great-circle-bethesda-footage-1851628386&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/indiana-jones-great-circle-bethesda-footage-1851628386">the first in-game footage at Gamescom this year</a></span>, but even that didn’t properly convey that this was going to be a full-fledged immersive sim adventure. It’s tremendous fun, and a big part of that is the many title details that really shine. Oh, and then there’s the shit bits too.</p><p>Overall, I’m deeply impressed with <em>The Great Circle</em>, so this article isn’t some bizarre attempt to weigh bad against good. Given how much it’s occupying my time, how it’s making me happy in a way a video game hasn’t since <em>Prey</em>, in my experience the good enormously outweighs the bad. I have so many things to celebrate about it! However, as a committed curmudgeon, that doesn’t stop me from being <em>infuriated</em> every time I read the words “Opens from other side” or not being able to swim underwater for more than five seconds. </p><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/indiana-jones-great-circle-review-is-it-good-pc-xbox-1851717174&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/indiana-jones-great-circle-review-is-it-good-pc-xbox-1851717174">Zack already did a brilliant job reviewing the game</a></span>, so again, this isn’t that. This is me picking out some teeny details and all-encompassing aspects that make me feel joy, then moaning like a bastard about equally small or ethereal annoyances. Let’s start with the loving (and the hating).</p></div></div><div><figure id="" data-id="740017ab2e79031e645bb43536ca208a" data-recommend-id="image://740017ab2e79031e645bb43536ca208a" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Indy rolling a safe's code wheels with his thumb." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Indy rolling a safe's code wheels with his thumb." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Bethesda / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="740017ab2e79031e645bb43536ca208a" data-recommend-id="image://740017ab2e79031e645bb43536ca208a" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Indy rolling a safe's code wheels with his thumb." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>I know this seems like the most ridiculous way to start, something so incredibly minor in the scheme of the game, but I cannot get over how much I love this about <em>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle</em>. Every time I see a suitcase with a four-digit code lock, or a safe with five, I’m totally thrilled, not for the puzzle solving that’s to come (although that makes me happy), but for the sheer visceral pleasure of rolling the dials with Indy’s sausage fingers.</p><p>Those sorts of code locks are fun to fiddle with in real life, too, of course. There’s a reason those <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.amazon.co.uk/fidget-cube/s?k=fidget+cube&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.amazon.co.uk/fidget-cube/s?k=fidget+cube" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">fidget cubes</a></span> have an approximation of them on one of the surfaces. But there’s something just so astonishingly perfect about how they’re rendered here, how perfectly they roll and click, and the incredibly tactile nature of scrolling them around with Indy’s thumb.</p><p>It’s a perfect piece of gaming interaction, and it deserves to be celebrated. I expect a special new category to be announced at The Game Awards.</p></div></div><div><figure id="" data-id="967ac797b05c2ccdda28b71bb2ceda8c" data-recommend-id="image://967ac797b05c2ccdda28b71bb2ceda8c" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A locked door with the words &quot;Opens from Other Side.&quot;" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A locked door with the words &quot;Opens from Other Side.&quot;" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Bethesda / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="967ac797b05c2ccdda28b71bb2ceda8c" data-recommend-id="image://967ac797b05c2ccdda28b71bb2ceda8c" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A locked door with the words &quot;Opens from Other Side.&quot;" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>Locked doors have been a tedious issue in video games for as long as games have had doors. We all learned the unspoken video game language of nonfunctional doors that look painted into the scenery versus those with which we can interact, and as infuriating as it is that there’s never any narrative rationale for this bizarre design, we roll with it. But <em>The Great Circle</em> takes it a stage further, with clearly interactive doors that are locked on the other side, <em>everywhere</em>.</p><p>It’s obviously just gating the levels, all such doors marking routes you’ll use on your return, rather than having to trace back along the ledges and windows and drops and climbs and so on you are intended to traverse on your way there. But when where you want to be is <em>there</em>, on the other side of this flimsy door with glass panels, and you’re holding a sledgehammer that’s capable of knocking through walls, it’s pretty annoying stuff. The phrase “Opens from Other Side” appears so, so often in the game’s enormous first third, and I began to greet it with an exasperated growl.</p><p>It’s also weird that it capitalizes “Other Side,” rather suggesting these doors are opened from the afterlife.</p></div></div><div><figure id="" data-id="5c2ed28d0b1bd2adeb2d2e05f1eb800b" data-recommend-id="image://5c2ed28d0b1bd2adeb2d2e05f1eb800b" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1041" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Admittedly this isn't a screenshot of an experiment working, but is instead a picture of Indy holding aloft a toilet brush as he approaches a Nazi guard. That counts, right?" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Admittedly this isn't a screenshot of an experiment working, but is instead a picture of Indy holding aloft a toilet brush as he approaches a Nazi guard. That counts, right?" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Bethesda / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="5c2ed28d0b1bd2adeb2d2e05f1eb800b" data-recommend-id="image://5c2ed28d0b1bd2adeb2d2e05f1eb800b" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1041" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Admittedly this isn't a screenshot of an experiment working, but is instead a picture of Indy holding aloft a toilet brush as he approaches a Nazi guard. That counts, right?" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>Big-budget video games don’t often encourage experimentation. Every aspect of every moment is so expensive that it’s often unfeasible to offer anything that isn’t heavily telegraphed. <em>The Great Circle</em> eschews all that with alacrity, happily letting players miss entire sections and sequences without desperately fussing about it. So much so that a friend shared a clip of a funny cutscene from the Vatican that I’d never encountered in all my time there. Because, this is a game where there are huge rewards for just seeing if something might work.</p><p>My first experience of this was noticing a pedestal in a dingy stone corridor, the first of them I’d seen in the game, and remembering that quite a while back I’d seen a stone bust on the floor in a distant room. “I wonder,” I thought, assuming I’d be about to waste my time. But I ran all the way back, then lugged the heavy object back down the stairs and through the tunnels, and saw the “X” appear on the pedestal. “Surely not?” I said, and then delighted as it let out a resounding click, followed by the grinding sound of a nearby door opening. I’d found a secret area!</p><p>The game keeps on doing this. Find a note in some room far off the path of any of the main missions, and it’ll unlock a little storyline or offer a mystery to solve, or even cause conversation later in the area to change. Notice a pattern in a bunch of the ancient art on the walls, and then realize the number of unmentioned statues in this one room matches the number of images, and what if you just... I love that it respects the player enough to leave these things hanging loosely.</p></div></div><div><figure id="" data-id="247e508aa4d1f9f56d860f4f2b7c3761" data-recommend-id="image://247e508aa4d1f9f56d860f4f2b7c3761" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Indy has a hand on a door handle, another putting a key into the lock." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Indy has a hand on a door handle, another putting a key into the lock." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Bethesda / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="247e508aa4d1f9f56d860f4f2b7c3761" data-recommend-id="image://247e508aa4d1f9f56d860f4f2b7c3761" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Indy has a hand on a door handle, another putting a key into the lock." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>And that’s just the start of the issue. I don’t mean that I have an issue with either action in games, obviously—that would be weird. But rather I really hate how <em>The Great Circle</em> requires such things be done.</p><p>One of my favorite gaming moments was playing the <em>Amnesia</em> developers’ earlier game, <em>Penumbra</em>,<em>&nbsp;</em>for the first time, and interacting with the moveable objects. Doors and drawers moved in a whole new way: you’d reach out to them, and then push or pull with the mouse in the most tactile way, and it felt so much more involving as a result. It feels like <em>Indy </em>has tried for something similar, but entirely misunderstood how to get it right.</p><p>Here, you reach out to a locked door, and rather than just pressing the button to unlock and open it as would be normal, instead you interact with it, but then have to move the left analogue stick in an often arbitrary direction to complete the move. That’s <em>always</em> to the right when unlocking a door, even when the lock is on right side of the door, and it’s so unintuitive! If the game were aiming for the full-on interactivity of <em>Penumbra </em>(and more games should!), it’d be one thing, but this half-way point just makes for irritating interactions, when just pressing X and being done with it would be a much more rewarding experience.</p></div></div><div><figure id="" data-id="56281b6387daefd463407be1c1ab5df8" data-recommend-id="image://56281b6387daefd463407be1c1ab5df8" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Indy holds a lit torch in front of a pile of unconscious bodies." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Indy holds a lit torch in front of a pile of unconscious bodies." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Bethesda / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="56281b6387daefd463407be1c1ab5df8" data-recommend-id="image://56281b6387daefd463407be1c1ab5df8" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Indy holds a lit torch in front of a pile of unconscious bodies." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>What <em>Indiana Jones And The Great Circle</em> gets right better than anything I could have expected is that thrilling sensation of exploration. Combining its musical score, its lighting, and the way Indy moves, makes for this absolutely sensational experience whenever I enter a new cavern or catacomb or mysterious tunnel for the first time.</p><p>Indy stoops through doorways, and you can hold your torch aloft to light the way, as beasties scurry away and you semi-automatically reach the torch out to light a nearby lamp. There’s an incredible sense of being the first person to enter this location in a thousand years, of having everything laid out in front of you as <em>yours</em>, your discovery, and most of the time, without that being spoilt by impossibly located enemies.</p><p>This might be a me-thing, but one of my pet peeves in movies and games is when the adventurers find the lost, hidden temple, and then somehow the baddies are already inside! <em>Tomb Raider</em> has always been the worst for this, as Lara completes near-impossible obstacle courses through the jungle to find the Mayan ruin, and then guns down the seven people hanging out outside. No!</p><p>But not here. Here, unless there’s a narrative justification (like enemies crashing a tractor through the rocky ceiling due to their wild incompetence), Indy (and sometimes a chum) have the place to themselves. The threat comes in the form of ancient traps, tricksy obstacles, and those ghastly scorpions and the like. It’s <em>so</em> much better for it.</p></div></div><div><figure id="" data-id="200bf5008988d118a418af892b875afd" data-recommend-id="image://200bf5008988d118a418af892b875afd" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1038" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A shot Indy looking surprised, in front of golden decor." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A shot Indy looking surprised, in front of golden decor." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshots of not breathing are tough, so here’s a shot of breathing instead.</figcaption><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Bethesda / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="200bf5008988d118a418af892b875afd" data-recommend-id="image://200bf5008988d118a418af892b875afd" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1038" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A shot Indy looking surprised, in front of golden decor." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>I am not a very fit man. I’m trying to improve that, making some progress, but even at my most wheezingly incapable, I could hold my breath underwater for more than three seconds.</p><p>I don’t know if Indy is secretly smoking 120 a day, or if he was born with a serious lung disorder, but my goodness me, he needs to see a doctor, sharpish. Sure, I’m used to games having super-buff protagonists who can only sprint for five seconds before collapsing into breathless piles (and there I can identify), but I’ve never known anyone run out of air and start drowning as quickly as Dr Jones.</p><p>It’s literally three seconds of underwater swimming before he’s panicking, making desperate gasping noises, and the blackness of death starts creeping in around his vision. If someone did a nasty fart near him, he’d die.</p></div></div><div><figure id="" data-id="25a1637819046de1307d5a98505a9343" data-recommend-id="image://25a1637819046de1307d5a98505a9343" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A wall with alcoves that cause it to look like an aghast face." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A wall with alcoves that cause it to look like an aghast face." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>I’m afraid I don’t have a shot of the dynamite exploding, so share your disgust with this wall.</figcaption><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Bethesda / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="25a1637819046de1307d5a98505a9343" data-recommend-id="image://25a1637819046de1307d5a98505a9343" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A wall with alcoves that cause it to look like an aghast face." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>While <em>The Great Circle</em> isn’t aiming to be some sort of real-world simulator with “spreading fire” or whatever thing no game has ever actually properly delivered, it does adhere to a few basic laws of physics. And, given how few games do, these moments can really take you by surprise.</p><p>A few of us at<em> Kotaku</em> have experienced that moment when you’re sneaking up on a Nazi, holding a glass bottle, and then spot something better to use for bonking them on the head. “Ooh, a hammer!” you think, and then press to grab that, forgetting that dropping a thing made of glass tends to have consequences. Then comes the smash on the ground, and the guard, hearing it, spins around and spots you—a doofus holding a hammer—right away.<br></p><p>I took this to another level when the thought was “Ooh, some dynamite,” and I was holding not a bottle but a fiery torch. As you might have guessed, when I dropped the open flame onto the sticks of explosives, the fuses immediately started fizzing, and I realized the situation I’d created for myself in one big rush. It was “Oh, this game is realistic like that!” combined with “Shit! I need to get away!” And this led to my incompetently fumbling the controls, tripping over a fallen pillar that was immediately behind me, and eventually gathering my wits enough to scramble into an opposite corner as the whole lot spectacularly blew up.</p><p>Sure, this is a tale about what a twit I am, but at the same time, it’s a wonderful demonstration of the emergent moments that this lovely game can offer.</p></div></div><div><figure id="" data-id="0be33f70dc5c6e3dcf5a5cf153b4e65c" data-recommend-id="image://0be33f70dc5c6e3dcf5a5cf153b4e65c" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1052" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Indie and Gina sit in shadows." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Indie and Gina sit in shadows." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Bethesda / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="0be33f70dc5c6e3dcf5a5cf153b4e65c" data-recommend-id="image://0be33f70dc5c6e3dcf5a5cf153b4e65c" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1052" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Indie and Gina sit in shadows." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>Yes, I am absolutely scraping the barrel for complaints at this point, but it’s still something that really grates with me. While this is certainly exacerbated by my desire to be able to screenshot the game for articles, I do think it remains a thing that could be improved upon, in any number of games.</p><p>For some reason, so many of the cutscenes in <em>The Great Circle</em> are lit so that the characters are in shadow in the foreground, then the mid-ground with no features is floodlit, and the slightly more interesting backgrounds muted and out of focus. It’s so weird! It keeps doing it!</p><figure id="" data-id="eb86f43c36df67854c9f0e7a3c1680b6" data-recommend-id="image://eb86f43c36df67854c9f0e7a3c1680b6" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1081" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Voss and his driver drive in shadows." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Voss and his driver drive in shadows." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Bethesda / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="eb86f43c36df67854c9f0e7a3c1680b6" data-recommend-id="image://eb86f43c36df67854c9f0e7a3c1680b6" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1081" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Voss and his driver drive in shadows." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Over and over.</p><figure id="" data-id="11f860370d94ae4b9dcedd358a43ad0d" data-recommend-id="image://11f860370d94ae4b9dcedd358a43ad0d" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1054" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Indie and Gina sit in shadows again." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Indie and Gina sit in shadows again." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Bethesda / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="11f860370d94ae4b9dcedd358a43ad0d" data-recommend-id="image://11f860370d94ae4b9dcedd358a43ad0d" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1054" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Indie and Gina sit in shadows again." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Even outdoors.</p><figure id="" data-id="4a1660b546f48c82772017c3b708222f" data-recommend-id="image://4a1660b546f48c82772017c3b708222f" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1041" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Indie and Gina sit in shadows outdoors." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Indie and Gina sit in shadows outdoors." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Bethesda / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="4a1660b546f48c82772017c3b708222f" data-recommend-id="image://4a1660b546f48c82772017c3b708222f" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1041" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Indie and Gina sit in shadows outdoors." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Stop that.</p></div></div><div><figure id="" data-id="8e27f08fac5bcf19918183ad36d275f2" data-recommend-id="image://8e27f08fac5bcf19918183ad36d275f2" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="The game's main menu, in front of a lively scene in Egypt, in front of a pyramid." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="The game's main menu, in front of a lively scene in Egypt, in front of a pyramid." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Bethesda / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="8e27f08fac5bcf19918183ad36d275f2" data-recommend-id="image://8e27f08fac5bcf19918183ad36d275f2" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="The game's main menu, in front of a lively scene in Egypt, in front of a pyramid." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>Again, tiny detail, but it’s such a lovely one! <em>The Great Circle</em> makes the very reasonable assumption when you load it that you’re most likely going to want to continue playing where you last left off. So, it loads that already.</p><p>Doing this means the game’s main menu is the last checkpoint you reached, such that when you hit continue, but for a couple of moments, you quickly zoom from third-person to a first-person view from Indy’s eyes, and you’re just off! It’s so much more involving, removing all those “YOU’RE PLAYING A GAME!!!” messages that so like to break any elements of immersion.</p><p>Even better, that menu screen is alive! It’s packed with NPCs going through their animations, such that you might see Gina wander into shot, scratch her chin, then pootle off elsewhere, all while a group of workers hammer rocks amid patrolling Nazis. Yes, I’m describing what’s happening on the window behind the one I’m writing in—it’s the perfect example. And next time I play, it’ll be something completely different!</p><hr><p>There are a wealth of other things to sing about in <em>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle</em>, and likely a good few others to gripe on, but we’re all already tired.</p><p>The most important thing to know is this just isn’t what anyone was expecting, which I think it’s fair to say was a first-person action game in an Indiana Jones skin. Instead, this truly feels like a vivid part of the <em>Indiana Jones</em> universe, and is a far more involving, intricate and interesting game than I’d ever hoped for. I’m delighted!</p><p>.</p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Day Of The Devs 2024 Game Awards Edition: Every Game Shown]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/day-of-the-devs-2024-game-awards-edition-every-game-shown/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/day-of-the-devs-2024-game-awards-edition-every-game-shown.1058247/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/day-of-the-devs-2024-game-awards-edition-every-game-shown/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-73512">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>Day of the Devs: Game Awards Edition 2024 from Double Fine Productions was held on Wednesday, showcasing 19 upcoming indie games from studios like Heart Machine, Annapurna, and more.</p>



<p>The event featured a mix of premieres, trailers, and even release dates for games. To help you keep up on everything that was shown, Insider Gaming has put together the full list of every game shown during the event. If you want to watch the full show with walkthroughs and breakdowns of certain games, you <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WvxGulZT9Ig" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">can do so here</a>.</p>



<h6>RELATED: <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-game-awards-2024-all-nominees-announced/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The Game Awards 2024 – All Nominees Announced</a></h6>



<p>Check out the games from Day of the Devs below. And be sure to let us know what upcoming indie games you’re looking forward to the most down below and in the official Insider Gaming Forums.</p>



<h2 id="h-day-of-the-devs-game-awards-edition-2024-games">Day of the Devs: Game Awards Edition 2024 Games</h2>



<h3>Faraway – Coming to PC in 2025</h3>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="FARAWAY | Reveal Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/5LxbmaXQa-E?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<hr>



<h3 id="h-ultimate-sheep-racoon">Ultimate Sheep Racoon</h3>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Ultimate Sheep Raccoon Reveal Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/J4hC8GudgBU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<hr>



<h3 id="h-sleight-of-hand">Sleight of Hand</h3>



<p>TRAILER COMING SOON</p>



<hr>



<h3 id="h-demon-tides">Demon Tides</h3>



<figure><p>
<iframe loading="lazy" title="Demon Tides - Announcement Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/4g9hmjD_WTM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<hr>



<h3 id="h-kingmakers-coming-2025">Kingmakers – Coming 2025</h3>



<figure><p>
<iframe loading="lazy" title="Kingmakers | Winter Games Expo Trailer - Early Access Release in Q1 2025 AD" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZXujvsd9C58?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<hr>



<h3 id="h-recur">Recur</h3>



<figure><p>
<iframe loading="lazy" title="RECUR - Announcement Trailer | Time-Bending Puzzle Platformer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/P2TVqmdZYUc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<hr>



<h3 id="h-blue-prince-spring-2025">Blue Prince – Spring 2025</h3>



<figure><p>
<iframe loading="lazy" title="Blue Prince Release Window Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/SxT2jjn2yZ8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<hr>



<h3 id="h-incolatus">Incolatus</h3>



<p>TRAILER COMING SOON</p>



<hr>



<h3 id="h-lok-digital">LOK Digital</h3>



<figure><p>
<iframe loading="lazy" title="LOK Digital Launch Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ofCYQGRWcS4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<hr>



<h3 id="h-neon-abyss-2">Neon Abyss 2</h3>



<figure><p>
<iframe loading="lazy" title="Neon Abyss 2 | Reveal Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/A86PCFApasQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<hr>



<h3 id="h-crescent-county">Crescent County</h3>



<p>TRAILER COMING SOON</p>



<hr>



<h3 id="h-pbj-the-musical">PBJ – The Musical</h3>



<figure><p>
<iframe loading="lazy" title="PBJ – The Musical (Gameplay)" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/enk-553M3v4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<hr>



<h3 id="h-curiosmos">Curiosmos</h3>



<p>TRAILER COMING SOON</p>



<hr>



<h3 id="h-bionic-bay-march-13-2025">Bionic Bay – March 13, 2025</h3>



<figure><p>
<iframe loading="lazy" title="Bionic Bay - Release Date Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/XTqkn2vkcUY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<hr>



<h3>Inkonbini</h3>



<figure><p>
<iframe loading="lazy" title="POV: You've met inKONBINI developer in konbini in Tokyo" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/E37Ajl5C2vY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<hr>



<h3 id="h-feltopia">Feltopia</h3>



<figure><p>
<iframe loading="lazy" title="Feltopia Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/N5GOLZG20v4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<hr>



<h3 id="h-blippo">Blippo+</h3>



<figure><p>
<iframe loading="lazy" title="Blippo+ Reveal Teaser" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/KVIZjoZ8WWQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<hr>



<h3 id="h-hyper-light-breaker-early-access-on-january-14-2025">Hyper Light Breaker – Early Access on January 14, 2025</h3>



<figure><p>
<iframe loading="lazy" title="Hyper Light Breaker | Release Date Reveal Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/VijrcUbspqU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<hr>



<h3 id="h-tankhead">Tankhead</h3>



<figure><p>
<iframe loading="lazy" title="TankHead - Launch Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/KzYw01FIwUc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/delta-force-has-no-plans-for-battle-royale-mode/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/delta-force-has-no-plans-for-battle-royale-mode/">Delta Force Has “No Plans” For Battle Royale Mode</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>In a recent Q&amp;A, Delta Force game director Shadow Guo shut down the idea of a battle royale mode coming to the game soon.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/next-escape-from-tarkov-competitor-pioner/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/next-escape-from-tarkov-competitor-pioner/">Tarkov’s Next Competitor Can Now Be Wishlisted On Steam</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Escape from Tarkov’s next competitor (and STALKER’s, and Metro’s) has surfaced on Steam, and it’s ready to be wishlisted.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/playstation-plus-game-catalog-gets-15-new-games-in-december/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/playstation-plus-game-catalog-gets-15-new-games-in-december/">PlayStation Plus Game Catalog Gets 15 New Games In December</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Sony has announced that 15 new games are coming to the PlayStation Plus Game Catalog for Extra and Premium subscribers in December 2024.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/kick-streamer-performance-report-2024/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/kick-streamer-performance-report-2024/">Kick’s Streaming Performance Soared in 2024, Report Reveals</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Kick.com underwent massive growth through 2024, recent data has revealed. Check out Kick’s 2024 numbers here.</p>
                    </div>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Roguelite exploration and vehicle game TankHead announced for PC, now available]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/12/roguelite-exploration-and-vehicle-game-tankhead-announced-for-pc-now-available</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/roguelite-exploration-and-vehicle-game-tankhead-announced-for-pc-now-available.1058244/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/12/roguelite-exploration-and-vehicle-game-tankhead-announced-for-pc-now-available<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>A surprise release from Toronto-based studio Alpha Channel.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Toronto-based developer <a title="Companies > Alpha Channel" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/alpha-channel">Alpha Channel</a> has announced <em><a title="Games > TankHead" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/tankhead">TankHead</a></em>, a <a title="Genres > Roguelite [207 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/roguelite">roguelite game</a> built around exploration and vehicle gameplay. It is available now for <a title="Platforms > PC [21,926 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/p/tankhead-2f3b51" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Epic Games Store</a> at a 17 percent-off discount price of $24.89 until December 18, after which it will cost $29.99. <span id="more-933403"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/p/tankhead-2f3b51" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Epic Games Store</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Embark on a thrilling journey as Whitaker, piloting a drone-controlled tank through the desolate ECA. Battle fierce enemies, scavenge valuable parts, and fight to survive in this fast-paced science-fiction world, as you strive to reach the mysterious Highpoint.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Fight to Reach Highpoint</strong> – As Whitaker your goal is to fight to reach Highpoint, to do that you must traverse the ECA—an area where humans cannot survive. Whitaker must project his mind into a Needle, a robust drone capable of surviving in the harsh conditions of the ECA—and of piloting your Tank. Use your Needle and Tank to combat the vehicles and creatures of the ECA to reach Highpoint.</li><li><strong>Rich, Detailed <a title="Genres > Science-Fiction [71 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/science-fiction">Science-Fiction</a> World</strong> – Explore the ECA a world torn apart by war and a mysterious cataclysmic event that left it uninhabitable by humans. Where humans must “tele-project” their minds into drones in order to survive and pillage the remains of a once great society.</li><li><strong>Fast-Paced Tank Combat</strong> – Your vehicle of choice is a Light Tank; capable of moving quickly and delivering devastating damage to your enemies and the reactive world around you. Your tank can be equipped with various weapons, armor, wheels, motors and abilities to customize your gameplay.</li><li><strong>Dismantle and Destroy</strong> – Use a variety of weaponry to dismantle your enemies, blow off parts, to get a clear shot at their vulnerable weak points to deliver decisive blows. Defeated enemies leave behind their remaining parts for you to salvage or steal. Take what you need, scrap the rest. Use everything to survive.</li></ul><!-- AD: content -->
        </blockquote><p>Watch the launch trailer and a gameplay overview video below.</p><h2><span>Launch Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="TankHead - Launch Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/KzYw01FIwUc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><span>Game Overview and Tips</span></h2><p><iframe title="TankHead - Game Overview and Tips" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/uVJrBT1SB1M?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bionic Bay launches March 13, 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/12/bionic-bay-launches-march-13-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/bionic-bay-launches-march-13-2025.1058238/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/12/bionic-bay-launches-march-13-2025<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Physics-based action platformer dated.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Side-scrolling <a title="Genres > Action [2,357 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a> <a title="Genres > Platformer [583 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/platformer">platformer</a> <em>Bonic Bay</em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,511 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a> and <a title="Platforms > PC [21,926 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1928690/Bionic_Bay/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> and <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/p/bionic-bay-93dd7c" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Epic Games Store</a> on March 13, 2025, publisher <a title="Companies > Kepler Interactive [38 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/kepler-interactive">Kepler Interactive</a> and developers <a title="Companies > Mureena [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/mureena">Mureena</a> and <a title="Companies > Psychoflow [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/psychoflow">Psychoflow</a> announced. <span id="more-933397"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its store pages:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em><a title="Games > Bionic Bay [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/bionic-bay">Bionic Bay</a></em> is a unique physics-based platformer with action, creative game mechanics and a mysterious world crafted with exceptional detail.<br>It introduces a unique Swap mechanic, allowing players to interact with the physics-based world in new ways. The immersive gameplay is<br>completed by spectacular environments and creative level design.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li>Innovative swap mechanism offers players a new way of interacting with the environment. It can be used to move, defend or attack.</li><li>Stunning environments with an incredible attention to detail.</li><li>An extraordinary world with massive levels.</li><li>Extremely physics based gameplay. Tons of dynamic objects, particles and liquids with large variety of physical properties makes the gameplay exceptionally fun and unique.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Bionic Bay - Release Date Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/XTqkn2vkcUY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>