<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 14:29:38 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Arkane Founder Teases Ambitious New RPG As 'Fallout Meets Dishonored']]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/arkane-wolfeye-fallout-dishonored-prey-sci-fi-rpg-1851616440</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/arkane-founder-teases-ambitious-new-rpg-as-fallout-meets-dishonored.948000/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/arkane-wolfeye-fallout-dishonored-prey-sci-fi-rpg-1851616440<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="33682b8e6da14767d6e9ab09768ea2df" data-recommend-id="image://33682b8e6da14767d6e9ab09768ea2df" data-format="png" data-width="2000" data-height="1125" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A retro futurist robot takes alpha test signups. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A retro futurist robot takes alpha test signups. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->WolfEye Studios</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="33682b8e6da14767d6e9ab09768ea2df" data-recommend-id="image://33682b8e6da14767d6e9ab09768ea2df" data-format="png" data-width="2000" data-height="1125" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A retro futurist robot takes alpha test signups. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>WolfEye Studios’ <em>Weird West</em> was an excellent, though somewhat overlooked, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/weird-west-wolfeye-studio-arkane-dishonored-western-1848732026&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/weird-west-wolfeye-studio-arkane-dishonored-western-1848732026">2022 isometric RPG</a></span> that felt at times like an immersive sim stealth game. Now the team led by former Arkane staff are taking aim at something bigger: a first-person RPG that mixes elements of <em>Fallout</em> and <em>Dishonored </em>in a wrapper of  alt-history, sci-fi Americana. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196055" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="6 Things To Know Before Starting Persona 5 Tactica" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="227" data-playlist="196055,196599,194214" data-current="196055"><div><p>6 Things To Know Before Starting Persona 5 Tactica</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196055/196055_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196055/196055_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196055/196055_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196055/196055_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21584.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p> “We are so happy to be able to officially confirm that our next game is actively in production and that it is a First Person Action RPG,” WolfEye boss and Arkane founder Raphael Colantonio said in a press release. “Fans of the past games I have been involved with such as<em> Dishonored </em>and <em>Prey</em> will feel at home, as well as fans of RPGs in general.”</p><p>The game is still looking for a publisher, but has already wrapped up pre-production and is currently taking sign-ups for a “limited private Alpha” test in early 2025. Executive producer Julien Roby <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.eurogamer.net/arkane-founders-new-rpg-shoots-for-fallout-meets-dishonored-with-a-splash-of-obsidian-storytelling&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/arkane-founders-new-rpg-shoots-for-fallout-meets-dishonored-with-a-splash-of-obsidian-storytelling" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">told <em>Eurogamer</em></a></span> in an interview that the broad aim is for something along the lines of “<em>Fallout</em> meets <em>Dishonored</em>,” which could mean a ton of things but sound like magic words for longtime fans of Arkane-style games. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/WolfEyeGames/status/1821531821328499064&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/WolfEyeGames/status/1821531821328499064" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">One of the pieces of concept art shared</a></span> sure looks like cross between a steam punk contraption and atomic age robot. <br></p><p> Arkane Lyon, meanwhile, is currently working on <em>Marvel’s Blade</em>, an action game starring the comic book vampire hunter Eric Brooks. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/arkane-austin-dishonored-closure-harvey-smith-1851463271&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/arkane-austin-dishonored-closure-harvey-smith-1851463271" target="_blank">Microsoft’s recent decision to shutdown its sister-studio</a></span>, Arkane Austin, has  left a big hole in the immersive sim genre. It made the moody 2017 sci-fi stealth game <em>Prey</em>, which didn’t get the love it deserved at the time. No one can replace that studio, but it’s a minor consolation prize that WolfEye is in a position to build on some of that work and usher in its next evolution. </p><p>According to <em>Eurogamer</em>, the studio is still about 50 to 60 people, and not looking to grow much beyond that. So whatever the currently unnamed project ends up as, it won’t be some triple-A blockbuster open-world game. Hopefully, it’s something much more expressive and unique instead. </p><p> .</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[College Football 25 Gets First Major Title Update]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/college-football-25-gets-first-major-title-update/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/college-football-25-gets-first-major-title-update.947997/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/college-football-25-gets-first-major-title-update/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>Three weeks after its release, EA Sports College Football 25 has received its first major title update. The 4.2 GB update includes a number of fixes to the game’s simulation logic, gameplay, schools, and much more.</p>



<p>One of the bigger changes comes in the form of a fix to the “scheduling visit” bug with recruiting that wouldn’t allow you to schedule visits with recruits after they finalized their Top 5 schools. Also fixed is the sim logic and rankings that determine what schools make the Top 25 and College Football Playoffs. </p>



<p>One thing that didn’t appear to change with the College Football 25 title update is the ability to change player numbers for generated generic recruits. It’s something players have been vocal about being able to do across social media, but hasn’t been addressed just yet. There’s also no confirmation from EA on if they will address it at all.</p>



<p>Check out the full list of changes to the game from the College Football 25 title update below <a href="https://www.ea.com/games/ea-sports-college-football/college-football-25/news/college-football-25-campus-huddle-title-update-august-8th-2024" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">via EA Sports</a>. And be sure to let us know your thoughts on the update in the comments.</p>



<h6>RELATED: <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/college-football-25-had-over-5-million-players-in-its-first-week/">College Football 25 Had Over 5 Million Players In Its First Week</a></h6>







<h3>GAMEPLAY</h3>



<ul>
<li>Included 8 new shotgun formations to a total of 35 teams: Bunch Quads Open (Known as Diamond Quads; added to teams including Texas Tech, Western Michigan), Deuce Twins Over (Buffalo, Toledo), Slot F Wing (NC State, Liberty), Split Pro Far (NC State, Liberty), Split Pro Near (NC State), Tight Y Off Flex (Florida), Wing HB Wk Close (Indiana, Minnesota), Wing Slot Over (Texas A&amp;M, Kansas State)</li>



<li>Tuning and logic enhancements to pursuit angles.
<ul>
<li>Introduced new behavior that further differentiates players with high pursuit ratings vs lower pursuit ratings.&nbsp;</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>



<ul>
<li>Reduced frequency of broken tackles from trailing defenders.</li>



<li>Fixed various instances of rare broken play bugs.</li>



<li>Fixed issue where certain formations had offensive players align too wide when on the near or far hash.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where you could not use 4-2-5 or 3-3-5 formations in a custom playbook.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where singleback formations would be assigned the wrong name when creating a custom playbook.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where Spiking the Ball in online modes was not working as part of the Turbo Tempo system.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue so a Speed Option Running Back will follow the QB longer.</li>



<li>Adjusted AI QB behavior on shot plays to make more lob throws vs bullet passes.</li>



<li>Adjusted AI QB behavior to be less aggressive based on awareness rating.</li>



<li>Adjusted AI offensive line behavior resulting in less illegal man downfield penalties during RPO style plays.
<ul>
<li><em><strong>Dev Note:&nbsp;</strong>For best chances at success, make sure you press the icon of which receiver you want to throw to before the RB receives the ball.</em></li>
</ul>
</li>



<li>Adjusted the DB’s ability to more effectively shed blocks on the perimeter.</li>



<li>Increased the speed penalty for running out of stamina during play.</li>



<li>QB scrambles behind the line of scrimmage will lose stamina at a faster rate.</li>



<li>Fixed an exploit where players would leave a QB contain player unblocked and run around them.
<ul>
<li><em><strong>Dev Note:&nbsp;</strong>We will make further improvements to QB Contain in a future title update.</em></li>
</ul>
</li>



<li>Increased the reward players receive for shading inside or outside correctly in Man Coverage vs passing routes.</li>



<li>Adjusted False Start chances when you make preplay adjustments late in the play clock.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where run-fit defenders were not responding as effectively to Wildcat run plays.&nbsp;</li>



<li>Made an adjustment to the Wildcat Unbalanced Motion Zone play.</li>



<li>Reduced the effectiveness of multiple laterals in a single play.</li>



<li>Adjusted the thresholds required to receive the most effective Juke and Spin moves.&nbsp;</li>



<li>Adjusted press animations to be more of an effective counter to the Takeoff Ability.</li>



<li>Updated pass protection mechanic to only include the RB in the protection if they are already on a block or block and release assignment.</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Abilities&nbsp;</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Updated the coloring of Platinum tier Abilities to further distinct the look vs Silver Abilities.</li>



<li>Rebalanced the Gold and Platinum tiers of the Juke and Spin abilities like 360 and Side Step.&nbsp;</li>



<li>Rebalanced the Platinum tier of the extender ability which includes not firing on QB designed run plays.</li>



<li>Slightly rebalanced the effectiveness of the Gold and Platinum tiers of the Quick Jump Ability. Additionally we made adjustments to the tier levels found on the Texas Front 7.</li>
</ul>



<h3>DYNASTY</h3>



<ul>
<li>Fixed an issue where players were unable to have more than 20 created coaches at one time in an online Dynasty League.</li>



<li>Various fixes around score summaries and Box Scores.</li>



<li>Various fixes for News Stories.</li>



<li>Introduced a new Playoff Bracket Screen.</li>



<li>Updated Texas/Oklahoma Rivalry data.</li>



<li>Discovered that FCS SE, MW, and NW were secretly using professional players and passing them off as collegiate players. Gave them sanctions and ensured they are now using properly-rated players.
<ul>
<li><em><strong>Dev Note:</strong>&nbsp;For this change to go into effect, you will need to create a new Dynasty.</em></li>
</ul>
</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where Wear and Tear did not recover for FCS teams resulting in a high number of FCS team injuries during gameplay.</li>



<li>Reduced dynamic attendance penalties for playing FCS teams.</li>



<li>Increased dynamic attendance in rivalry games.</li>



<li>Retuned Toughest Places to Play formula to reduce the impact that large stadiums have on Toughest Places to Play and increase the value of filling the stadium and winning games at home historically.:
<ul>
<li>Reduced impact of raw crowd size.</li>



<li>Increased impact of historical win rate.</li>



<li>Increased impact of attendance rate.</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li>Updated Right hand panel in Stadium Atmosphere Grade on My School screen to accurately reflect the Toughest Places to Play at all times.</li>



<li>Increased the accumulation of Pride stickers, particularly for defensive players and offensive linemen.</li>



<li>Reduced the Chance to Transfer Penalty for players rated below 90 OVR.</li>



<li>Updated Coach Talents on Wyoming Offensive Coordinator.
<ul>
<li><em><strong>Dev Note:</strong>&nbsp;For this change to go into effect, you will need to create a new Dynasty.</em></li>
</ul>
</li>



<li>Defensive Schemes and Playbooks for the following teams have been updated.
<ul>
<li><em><strong>Dev Note:</strong>&nbsp;For this change to go into effect, you will need to create a new Dynasty.</em></li>



<li>USC</li>



<li>UCLA</li>



<li>Mississippi State</li>



<li>Texas Tech</li>



<li>UConn</li>



<li>Miami</li>



<li>Memphis</li>



<li>Nevada</li>



<li>North Carolina</li>



<li>Notre Dame</li>



<li>Oregon State</li>



<li>San Jose State</li>



<li>TCU</li>



<li>Texas A&amp;M</li>



<li>Troy</li>



<li>UMass</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li>Updating your coach’s playbook in the Schemes and Playbooks screen will now update your team’s scheme and should be reflected in Team Needs.&nbsp;</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where Offensive Linemen would appear in the Preseason Heisman Watch in future seasons.</li>



<li>Updated the Heisman Watch logic to reduce the value of receiving TDs.</li>



<li><strong>Recruiting</strong>
<ul>
<li><em><strong>Dev Note:</strong>&nbsp;Our primary goals for this update were to remove most of the recruiting strategies that were discovered during early access and to smooth out the pain points our players were reporting. Recruiting is a delicate balance as we want to try to make things as realistic as possible, while also allowing players to live out their football fantasies. With that in mind, we decided to introduce additional recruiting logic and balance changes:</em>
<ul>
<li>Fixed an issue where teams were pursuing too many quarterbacks in High School Recruiting.</li>



<li>Reduced the number of unrecruited 4 and 5 stars early in the season.</li>



<li>Increased the number of players that the AI will pursue at one time.
<ul>
<li><em><strong>Dev Note:</strong>&nbsp;The above changes strive to decrease the number of players that go unrecruited until late in the cycle, while also slightly reducing how aggressive the AI could be with those recruits once they start to recruit them. Our goal is to deliver a fun but balanced recruiting experience that feels rewarding to all players. We will monitor the impacts these changes have on the overall recruiting experience and continue to adjust as needed.&nbsp;</em></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li><strong>Visits</strong>
<ul>
<li>Fixed an issue where you could not schedule visits for recruits in certain situations.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where a visit remained scheduled even if a recruit was removed from a board.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where the allowed the number of visits scheduled for a week to exceed 4.</li>



<li>Tuned Visit Influence effects:
<ul>
<li>Removed initial influence when scheduling a visit.</li>



<li>Increased disparity between winning and losing a game during a visit.</li>



<li>Tuned the logic for game stakes to better account for ranked teams.</li>



<li>Increased the penalty for choosing a visit activity that the team does not have a high grade in or the player is not interested in.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li><strong>SuperSim</strong>
<ul>
<li>Increased hand off rate for simulated RPOs to increase the number of running plays across the country, especially for teams with a lot of RPOs in their playbook.</li>



<li>Various tuning fixes to increase the gap between good and bad teams/players.
<ul>
<li><em><strong>Dev Note:</strong>&nbsp;We are going to continue to monitor the simulation results to ensure that teams and players are performing within expected ranges, including reducing frequency of upsets, based on Pre-Season Projections and expected win totals.&nbsp;</em></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li><strong>Polls</strong>
<ul>
<li>Increased the loss penalty for schools with more than 1 loss.</li>



<li>Increased the weighing of Conference Prestige in the poll calculation.</li>



<li>Reduced variance in CFP poll logic vs Media/Coaches
<ul>
<li><em><strong>Dev Note:</strong>&nbsp;As with the other systems mentioned above, we will continue to monitor the Polls system to ensure that it strikes a balance between realism and reward for player success.</em></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li><strong>Custom Conferences/Custom Schedules</strong></li>



<li>Fixed an issue in Conference Rules where Divisions were changed to off, even if those Divisions were previously turned on.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where the Independents Tab disappeared when removing all teams from Independents
<ul>
<li><em><strong>Dev Note:</strong>&nbsp;This also fixes issues with tabs to the right of Independents having incorrect or missing data.</em></li>
</ul>
</li>



<li>Addressed UI issues around the Conference Title game for the CUSA and PAC-12</li>



<li>Addressed UI issues around Dynasty Team Select UI appropriately respecting Custom Conference moves</li>



<li>Updated text in the Team Header on the Custom Schedules Screen</li>
</ul>







<h3>ROAD TO GLORY</h3>



<ul>
<li>Added an additional scenario and NIL content.</li>



<li>Fixed rare issues where you’d get a scenario reward screen that did not align with your received bonuses.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where users were getting Skill Points maxed out after completing a practice.</li>



<li>Fixed a crash when quitting a Position Battle.</li>



<li>Reworked Wear and Tear UI to show position-appropriate ratings-impacts.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where you cannot equip a Mental Ability during the RTG Player creation flow if you enter a settings menu during creation.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where Meter Mental Progress is not tracked during Bye Weeks.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where it is impossible to lose Coach Trust once you reach max Coach Trust.</li>



<li>Fixed a UI issue related to the display of Coach Trust when a user is close to max Coach Trust.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where you cannot Upgrade your player during Bye Weeks.</li>



<li>Fixed a UI issue related to the display of Weekly Energy in the Meters Screen.</li>



<li>Fixed issues with Mental Goals not tracking correctly or reaching Platinum correctly.</li>



<li>Fixed UI issues around Text Messages.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where backing out of the Team Selection step in RTG Creation can soft lock the mode.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where a player can continue to work on Academics after graduating early.&nbsp;&nbsp;</li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-college-football-ultimate-team">COLLEGE FOOTBALL ULTIMATE TEAM</h3>



<ul>
<li>Generating ‘Best Lineup’ no longer changes your equipped visuals and playbook.</li>



<li>Player Portraits will no longer appear on non-player items after filtering or sorting.&nbsp;</li>



<li>Fixed a crash that occurred during kicking off at halftime when playing Champs.</li>



<li>Attributes on the front of Player Items should update correctly after a Player Item has been upgraded.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue that was occurring when highlighting the Rename Team tile on the UT Hub.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue with Squads 3v3 that prevented 2 users from being able to connect to the game.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue with the Orientation Pack that was preventing new users from being able to upgrade their lineup and progress through the Orientation Field Pass.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue on the Player Profile Screen that prevented users from being able to transition within the Profile selections.</li>



<li>Removed the Green Gavel icon that appeared on owned items placed on the Auction House.</li>



<li>Fixed a crash with House Rules: Touchdown Tango that triggered when the play clock reached 0.</li>



<li>Player Items displayed on the New Items Screen no longer appear transparent when not highlighted.</li>



<li>When viewing Challenge Details the yardage marker is now displayed within the Conditions.</li>



<li>On the Lineup Screen names of players in backup slots contributing to Chemistry should change in scale when highlighting a Chemistry boost.</li>



<li>Improved UI around Attributes that are receiving chemistry boosts when viewing the Attributes tab of the Item Detail screen.</li>



<li>Fixed issue that was causing long load transitions on the New Item Screen during the First Time User Experience.</li>



<li>The Difficulty star for Challenges now displays correctly when scrolling down the Play Co-op List.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue that was causing users to error out to the Main Hub when trying to access the Auction House.</li>



<li>Conference Filters in the Auction House now work correctly.</li>



<li>Fixed stability issues for users entering Ultimate Team for the first time.&nbsp;</li>
</ul>



<h3>PRESENTATION</h3>



<ul>
<li>Added new uniform pieces for Baylor, Oregon, Iowa State, Ole Miss, Vanderbilt, Bowling Green, Northwestern, UTEP, Boise State, New Mexico State, App State, Texas State, Louisiana, New Mexico, and South Alabama.</li>



<li>Adjusted uniform pieces for 2024 season: TCU, Arkansas, Missouri, Baylor</li>



<li>Various improvements made to teams’ uniform pieces for authenticity</li>



<li>Updates have been made to the following stadiums:
<ul>
<li>Holiday Bowl</li>



<li>Texas State</li>



<li>Kansas</li>



<li>Kennesaw State</li>



<li>Oklahoma State</li>



<li>Wake Forest</li>



<li>UL-Monroe</li>



<li>Nebraska&nbsp;</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li>Fixed an Issue where the USC Mascot would disappear during the opening ceremony.</li>



<li>Fixed an Issue where the incorrect mascot would appear during different situations.</li>



<li>Restored opening chants for Penn State, FSU, and Tennessee on Xbox Series S.</li>
</ul>



<h3>ROAD TO CFP</h3>



<ul>
<li>Tier Rebalancing and Reconstruction changing the format from 3 tiers to 5 tiers.</li>
</ul>



<hr>



<p>What do you think of all the changes to College Football 25 in this title update? For more Insider Gaming, check out what the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-borderlands-movie-is-absolutely-hated-by-everyone/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">reaction has been to the Borderlands movie</a> so far.</p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Borderlands Movie Is Absolutely Hated By Everyone]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/the-borderlands-movie-is-absolutely-hated-by-everyone/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-borderlands-movie-is-absolutely-hated-by-everyone.947991/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/the-borderlands-movie-is-absolutely-hated-by-everyone/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>The Borderlands movie hits theaters on Friday, August 9 but critics have already come out with their reviews of the movie, and it’s not good. In fact, it’s pretty much consensus at this point that everyone who’s watched the Borderlands movie hates it. </p>



<p>On <a href="https://www.rottentomatoes.com/m/borderlands" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Rotten Tomatoes</a>, the movie currently sits with a 0 rating. You read that right, 0 out of 100.</p>



<p>Based on 14 critic scores so far, Borderlands is being panned as being <a href="https://x.com/SmatthewAF/status/1821056580751913225" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">“uninspiring”</a>, “lifeless”, and even a <a href="https://x.com/AdriCaporusso/status/1821041077018882518" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">“disaster”</a>.</p>







<p>“Filled with every cliché you can ponder, this film swaps the mayhem and imagination of the games for a lifeless, unfunny, and visually repulsive dud with annoying characters and a cast with not one ounce of chemistry,” Adriano Caporusso of Bitesize Breakdown said.</p>



<p><a href="https://www.independent.co.uk/arts-entertainment/films/reviews/borderlands-movie-review-b2592670.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Clarisse Loughrey</a> of the Independent said that the movie has “dragged us back to a time when studios used to make these with all the grace and acuity of a drunk person attempting to place a 3am chicken nugget order.”</p>



<p>While there are certain to be some that do find the movie starring Cate Blanchett, Kevin Hart, Jamie Lee Curtis, and Jack Blatt funny or entertaining, it seems as though they’ll be in the minority. Earlier this year, Randy Pitchford said that the first movie was <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/borderlands-cinematic-universe-first-movie/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the “beginning” of the Borderlands cinematic universe</a>. If the movie struggles at the box office as much as it has with critics, there may not be a universe to explore.</p>



<p>Only time will tell what the future holds for the franchise.</p>



<hr>



<p>Are you going to see the Borderlands movie to see why people seem to hate it, or are you skipping it based on the reviews so far? For more Insider Gaming, read what <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/vampire-survivors-playstation-release/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">popular game is finally coming to PlayStation</a> later this month.</p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine II ‘Extended Multiplayer Gameplay’ trailer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/warhammer-40000-space-marine-ii-extended-multiplayer-gameplay-trailer</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/warhammer-40-000-space-marine-ii-%E2%80%98extended-multiplayer-gameplay%E2%80%99-trailer.947988/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/warhammer-40000-space-marine-ii-extended-multiplayer-gameplay-trailer<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>    

    <!-- AD: footer -->
           
            

    <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/" title="Gematsu"><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" width="302" height="39.731" viewBox="0 0 302 39.731"><g transform="translate(0 0)"><g transform="translate(0 0.001)"><path d="M39.49,10.82c.13,0,.2-.05.2-.17V.17c0-.1-.07-.15-.2-.17H4.28A4.28,4.28,0,0,0,0,4.28V35.4a4.29,4.29,0,0,0,4.28,4.29H39.49c.13,0,.2-.06.2-.17V14.75c0-.11-.07-.17-.2-.19H15.94c-.09,0-.15.06-.17.19v10.3a.17.17,0,0,0,.17.16H27.7v3.65H12v-18Z" fill="#ed1d3b"></path><path d="M43.69.17A.17.17,0,0,1,43.88,0H83.29a.15.15,0,0,1,.16.17V10.65c0,.12,0,.17-.16.17H55.7v3.65H83.29a.155.155,0,0,1,.16.17V25.13a.14.14,0,0,1-.16.16H55.7v3.57H83.29a.155.155,0,0,1,.16.17V39.52c0,.11,0,.17-.16.17H43.88c-.13,0-.19-.06-.19-.17Z" fill="#fff"></path><path d="M103.26,25.27V10.93H99.44V39.52a.15.15,0,0,1-.17.17H87.65c-.13,0-.2-.06-.2-.17V.17a.19.19,0,0,1,.2-.17H127a.158.158,0,0,1,.17.17V39.52a.15.15,0,0,1-.17.17H115.32c-.11,0-.16-.06-.16-.17V10.93h-3.91V25.27Z" fill="#fff"></path><path d="M170.63,0h-39.3a.18.18,0,0,0-.19.17V39.52c0,.11.06.17.19.17H143c.11,0,.16-.06.16-.17V25.29h15.72V39.52a.15.15,0,0,0,.17.17h11.62c.13,0,.19-.06.19-.17V.17A.229.229,0,0,0,170.63,0ZM158.84,14.47H143.12V10.82h15.72Z" fill="#fff"></path><path d="M188.3,11.1H175c-.13,0-.2-.06-.2-.17V.17A.19.19,0,0,1,175,0h39.41a.15.15,0,0,1,.16.17V10.93c0,.11-.05.17-.16.17H201V39.52c0,.11-.07.17-.2.17H188.49c-.12,0-.19-.06-.19-.17Z" fill="#fff"></path><path d="M258.08,0c.13,0,.2.07.2.17V10.65c0,.12-.07.17-.2.17H229.41v3.54h28.67a.189.189,0,0,1,.2.2v25c0,.11-.07.17-.2.17h-39.3c-.12,0-.19-.06-.19-.17V29a.18.18,0,0,1,.19-.17h28.68V25.29H218.78c-.12,0-.19-.05-.19-.16V.17a.18.18,0,0,1,.19-.17Z" fill="#fff"></path><path d="M301.77,0H290.14c-.09,0-.14.06-.16.17V28.75H274.26V.17c0-.1-.06-.15-.17-.17H262.47a.17.17,0,0,0-.19.17V39.52c0,.11.06.17.19.17h35.21A4.29,4.29,0,0,0,302,35.4V.17C302,.07,301.9,0,301.77,0Z" fill="#fff"></path></g></g></svg></a>

    <section>
      <nav>
        <div><ul id="menu-footer-menu-one"><li id="menu-item-691230"><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo">Nintendo</a></li>
<li id="menu-item-691231"><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation">PlayStation</a></li>
<li id="menu-item-691232"><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox">Xbox</a></li>
<li id="menu-item-691233"><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>
<li id="menu-item-691234"><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/c/industry">Industry</a></li>
</ul></div>      </nav>
      <nav>
        <div><ul id="menu-footer-menu-two"><li id="menu-item-691235"><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/about">About</a></li>
<li id="menu-item-691236"><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/about#contact">Contact Us</a></li>
<li id="menu-item-691237"><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/about#advertising">Advertising</a></li>
<li id="menu-item-691238"><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/about#staff">Staff</a></li>
<li id="menu-item-691239"><a rel="privacy-policy" href="https://www.gematsu.com/privacy">Privacy Policy</a></li>
</ul></div>      </nav>
    </section>

    <section>
      <ul>
        <li><a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://www.facebook.com/gematsucom"><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" width="24" height="24" viewBox="0 0 24 24"><path d="M9 8h-3v4h3v12h5v-12h3.642l.358-4h-4v-1.667c0-.955.192-1.333 1.115-1.333h2.885v-5h-3.808c-3.596 0-5.192 1.583-5.192 4.615v3.385z"></path></svg></a></li>
        <li><a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://twitter.com/gematsu"><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" width="24" height="24" viewBox="0 0 24 24"><path d="M24 4.557c-.883.392-1.832.656-2.828.775 1.017-.609 1.798-1.574 2.165-2.724-.951.564-2.005.974-3.127 1.195-.897-.957-2.178-1.555-3.594-1.555-3.179 0-5.515 2.966-4.797 6.045-4.091-.205-7.719-2.165-10.148-5.144-1.29 2.213-.669 5.108 1.523 6.574-.806-.026-1.566-.247-2.229-.616-.054 2.281 1.581 4.415 3.949 4.89-.693.188-1.452.232-2.224.084.626 1.956 2.444 3.379 4.6 3.419-2.07 1.623-4.678 2.348-7.29 2.04 2.179 1.397 4.768 2.212 7.548 2.212 9.142 0 14.307-7.721 13.995-14.646.962-.695 1.797-1.562 2.457-2.549z"></path></svg></a></li>
        <li><a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCcaswDIh-nrXYofcYQm6KTg"><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" width="24" height="24" viewBox="0 0 24 24"><path d="M9 15V8.26l6.48 3.38L9 15zm14.76-7.8a5.17 5.17 0 0 0-1-2.38 3.46 3.46 0 0 0-2.41-1C17 3.56 12 3.56 12 3.56s-5 0-8.4.24a3.46 3.46 0 0 0-2.41 1 5.17 5.17 0 0 0-.95 2.4A36.53 36.53 0 0 0 0 11.09v1.82a36.22 36.22 0 0 0 .24 3.88 5.17 5.17 0 0 0 1 2.38 4.08 4.08 0 0 0 2.65 1c1.92.18 8.16.24 8.16.24s5 0 8.4-.25a3.46 3.46 0 0 0 2.41-1 5.17 5.17 0 0 0 1-2.38 36.22 36.22 0 0 0 .14-3.87v-1.82a36.28 36.28 0 0 0-.24-3.89"></path></svg></a></li>
      </ul>
    </section>

    

    <section>
      <p>© Copyright Gematsu 2008 to 2023. All rights reserved.</p>
      <p>Reproduction in whole or in part in any form or medium without acknowledgment of Gematsu is prohibited. Use of this site is governed by all applicable laws.</p>
    </section>

    <section>
      <p>Website by <a title="44 Bytes Ltd - Intelligent Internet Services" href="https://www.44bytes.net/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">44 Bytes</a></p>
    </section>

  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hack-and-slash deckbuilder Spirit Mancer launches in November for PS5, Switch, and PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/hack-and-slash-deckbuilder-spirit-mancer-launches-in-november-for-ps5-switch-and-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hack-and-slash-deckbuilder-spirit-mancer-launches-in-november-for-ps5-switch-and-pc.947982/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/hack-and-slash-deckbuilder-spirit-mancer-launches-in-november-for-ps5-switch-and-pc<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>From Thai developer Sunny Syrup Studio.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Hack-and-slash and <a title="Genres > Deckbuilder [57 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/deckbuilder">deckbuilder</a> hybrid game <em><a title="Games > Spirit Mancer" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/spirit-mancer">Spirit Mancer</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [7,609 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch [15,755 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [20,823 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2172580/Spirit_Mancer/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> in November, newly revealed publisher Dear Villager and Thai developer <a title="Companies > Sunny Syrup Studio" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sunny-syrup-studio">Sunny Syrup Studio</a> announced. <span id="more-904280"></span></p><p>“We hope you all enjoy our game, <em>Spirit Mancer</em>,” Sunny Syrup Studio said in a press release. “We poured our heart and soul, and maybe a few too many crazy ideas, into this passion project. We had many good laughs and a lot of fun <a title="Genres > Crafting [17 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/crafting">crafting</a> this insane adventure. We hope you have as much fun playing it as we did creating it.”</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via <a title="Companies > Dear Villagers [75 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/plug-in-digital/dear-villagers">Dear Villagers</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>Spirit Mancer</em> is a 2D hack-and-slash adventure with deckbuilding mechanics. Inspired by classics like <em>Mega Man 5</em>, <em>JoJo’s Bizarre <a title="Genres > Adventure [1,654 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">Adventure</a></em>, and the first <em><a title="Series > Pokemon [44 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/series/pokemon">Pokemon</a></em> adventure, players are in the role of a modern-day demon hunter, they can go alone or also can join forces with a friend in local couch cooperative mode. Slash, shoot, and break hordes of demons from Ars Goetia and stop the evil queen with the power of the Spirit Mancer. Capture their spirits and summon them out into battle in the beautiful yet dangerous world of Inferno!</p></blockquote><div id="carousel_904290"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div><!-- AD: content -->
        <blockquote><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong><a title="Genres > Hack-and-Slash [38 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/hack-and-slash">Hack-and-Slash</a> <a title="Genres > Action [2,057 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">Action</a> Combines With Deckbuilding Elements</strong> – With a skill base card, you can summon demons to do your bidding and help you during combat.</li><li><strong>Local Cooperative Play Support</strong> – Like in the old <a title="Genres > Arcade [57 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/arcade">arcade</a> times, join forces with a friend and jump together for an epic battle into a colourful and vibrant inferno.</li><li><strong>Over 50 Unique Enemies You Can Fight and Capture</strong> – Huge variety of unique monsters and demons that you can fight and capture.</li><li><strong>Summon Captured Enemies to Battle as Spirit Cards</strong> – Capture any demons into spirit cards then summon them out into battle as your friends.</li><li><strong>Deckbuilding With Over 100 Spirit Cards</strong> – Build your deck with demon spirits that you want in your pocket.</li><li><strong>Over 40 Guns and Weapons to Be Used</strong> – Blast any foes with a large variety of weapons.</li><li><strong>Over Eight Levels for You to Explore</strong> – Beautiful beach, Volcanic fortress, Lush forest, and more adventure a huge fantasy world of inferno with over 20 biomes to explore.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below. View a new set of screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/spirit-mancer/august-8-2024/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>Publisher Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="SPIRIT MANCER - Announcement Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/yyiH2azmmjg?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Side-scrolling adventure platformer Dog Man: Mission Impawsible announced for PS5, Xbox Series, Switch, and PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/side-scrolling-adventure-platformer-dog-man-mission-impawsible-announced-for-ps5-xbox-series-switch-and-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/side-scrolling-adventure-platformer-dog-man-mission-impawsible-announced-for-ps5-xbox-series-switch-and-pc.947979/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/side-scrolling-adventure-platformer-dog-man-mission-impawsible-announced-for-ps5-xbox-series-switch-and-pc<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Based on the popular children's book series. Due out in 2024.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Mindscape [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/mindscape">Mindscape</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Floor 84 Studio" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/floor-84-studio">Floor 84 Studio</a> have announced <a title="Genres > Side-Scrolling [734 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/side-scrolling">side-scrolling</a> <a title="Genres > Adventure [1,654 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a> <a title="Genres > Platformer [500 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/platformer">platformer</a> <em><a title="Games > Dog Man: Mission Impawsible" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/dog-man-mission-impawsible">Dog Man: Mission Impawsible</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [7,609 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [5,797 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch [15,755 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [20,823 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> (<a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3112730/Dog_Man_Mission_Impawsible/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a>). It will launch both physically and digitally in 2024. <span id="more-904656"></span></p><p>“We are excited to partner with Mindscape to bring <em>Dog Man</em> to the gaming world,” said The Joester Loria Group senior licensing director Jackie DeMaio in a press release. “Mindscape’s experience and passion for delivering engaging, high-quality games makes them the perfect match for the <em>Dog Man</em> brand. The game joins the upcoming theatrical release from Dreamworks / Universal in providing fans another way to engage with the beloved <em>Dog Man</em> characters, stories and settings.”</p><p>Mindscape owner and CEO Mark Huijmans added, “<em>Dog Man</em> is a fantastic [intellectual property] with a huge following, and we are honored to have the opportunity to work with [The Joester Loria] Group to bring this beloved character to a video game. This game is not just a playthrough; it’s an adventure that expands the <em>Dog Man</em> universe, offering all fans a chance to play with their favorite characters in a dynamic and interactive way.”</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3112730/Dog_Man_Mission_Impawsible/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam page</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Join Dog Man and the Supa Buddies on an epic adventure!</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><em>Dog Man: Mission Impawsible</em> brings the beloved book series to life! Dive into this action-packed, humor-filled adventure. The key to the city has fallen into the hands of a supa bad guy, unlocking all the prison doors and releasing many evildoers. Help Dog Man and his friends chase down the supa bad guys in their most impawsible mission yet! Switch between Dog Man and his Supa Buddies, each with their own special abilities and gadgets such as Rockets Boots, Retractable Claws and Dirt Proof Pants. Together you can overcome challenging obstacles and defeat powerful bosses.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Exciting Levels</strong> – Explore iconic locations from the Dog Man universe, including the City Hall, Giant Marshmallow Factory, and the Police Station. Each location offers platforming and puzzle-solving challenges.</li><li><strong>Teamwork</strong> – Switch between Dog Man and his Supa Buddies, each with their own special abilities, to overcome obstacles and defeat bosses.<ul><li><strong>Dog Man</strong> – Digs underground and glides through the air.</li><li><strong>Li’l Petey</strong> – Hacks gadgets and fits into small spaces.</li><li><strong>80-HD</strong> – Pushes heavy objects and jumps long distances.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Fun Gadgets</strong> – Unlock new gadgets and abilities as you progress, like a grappling hook, rocket shoes and power gloves to navigate through the levels.</li><li><strong>Puzzles and Bosses</strong> – Use your brain to solve puzzles and defeat unique bosses. Each boss fight requires clever use of your team’s abilities.</li><li><strong>Humor and <a title="Genres > Action [2,057 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">Action</a></strong> – Enjoy funny dialogue, amusing interactions, and non-stop action that keeps you engaged in Dog Man’s world.</li><li><strong>Rewards and Collectibles</strong> – Revisit levels with new gadgets to find secret areas, and rescue the missing Comic Club members</li><li><strong>Art Style</strong> – Great animations inspired by the books, with comic-style sound effects that add a fun, cartoonish touch to the action.</li></ul></blockquote><p>View the first screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/dog-man-mission-impawsible/august-8-2024/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>Screenshots</span></h2><div id="carousel_904659"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Watch A D23 Presentation About Fortnite x Disney, Get A Free Wolverine-Themed Back Bling]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/watch-a-d23-presentation-about-fortnite-x-disney-get-a-free-wolverine-themed-back-bling/1100-6525630/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/watch-a-d23-presentation-about-fortnite-x-disney-get-a-free-wolverine-themed-back-bling.947973/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/watch-a-d23-presentation-about-fortnite-x-disney-get-a-free-wolverine-themed-back-bling/1100-6525630/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6525630">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Disney <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/disney-explains-why-it-invested-1-5-billion-into-fortnite-and-what-it-hopes-to-achieve/1100-6525584/" data-ref-id="1100-6525584">made an enormous investment</a> in Epic Games and Fortnite earlier this year, and while it's going to be some time before many aspects of this team-up bear fruit, we'll be getting some of our first peeks at what's in store for Disney x Fortnite at the D23 Expo in Anaheim this weekend. Even better: You'll be able to watch this panel on an exclusive livestream inside Fortnite, and doing so will net you the Peelverine Plushie back Bling for free. The only other way to watch is to actually be in the room in Anaheim.</p><p>The presentation is happening on Saturday night at 8:30 PM PT/11:30 PM ET-- and it's hosted by Josh D'Amaro, chairman of Disney Experiences, which is the portion of the corporation focused on parks, gaming, and other consumer products. The presentation is of interest for Fortnite fans because it will delve into some of the details about what kind of stuff Disney plans to do within Fortnite in the future.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1757/17577455/4347511-peelverinebackbling.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4347511" data-ratio="0.56253270538985" data-width="1911" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1757/17577455/4347511-peelverinebackbling.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4347511"></a><figcaption>A glimpse at the free Peelverine back bling.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1757/17577455/4347511-peelverinebackbling.jpg"></figure><p>The livestream will be viewable in the Disney Horizons Live from D23 creative island (island code: 7908-6413-2516), which will become available at 7:30 PM PT/10:30 PM ET on Saturday, an hour before the stream begins. After the presentation is over, it will play on a loop until August 16. All you have to do to earn the Peelverine back bling is hang out in the island for 10 minutes at any point during that span of time, so you don't even have to watch the whole thing if you don't want to.</p><p>We don't know anything at all for sure about what will be revealed, but the new Fortnite season begins next week and has long been <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/fortnite-chapter-5-season-4-start-date-leaks-and-rumors/2900-5569/" data-ref-id="2900-5569">rumored to be a new Marvel-focused one</a>--that's something that would make a lot of sense to announce during this presentation, particularly since they'll be looping the stream until the new season begins next Friday. So there's a very good chance that the D23 Horizons presentation actually is going to be very worth watching.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                        
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/112115755814061051052?rel=author">Phil Owen</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kingmakers Movie Announced Before the Game Is Even Out]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/kingmakers-movie-announced</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/kingmakers-movie-announced-before-the-game-is-even-out.947952/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/kingmakers-movie-announced<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Kingmakers&nbsp;</em>publisher tinyBuild has announced that the game is getting a live-action movie adaptation, and this announcement comes before a release date for the game has even been revealed.</p>
<p>Per <a href="https://venturebeat.com/games/story-kitchen-will-take-tinybuilds-time-travel-game-kingmakers-to-live-action-film/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">a report by VentureBeat</a> (endorsed <a href="https://x.com/tinyBuild/status/1821533320456384702" rel="noopener" target="_blank">by tinyBuild itself</a>), production company Story Kitchen has teamed up with both tinyBuild and&nbsp;<em>Kingmakers&nbsp;</em>developer Redemption Road in order to make the movie.</p>
<p>It'll be a collaborative project between the three studios, and according to VentureBeat's report, the movie will aim to "tell a unique story and establish the intellectual property" in a simultaneous fashion.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/kingmakers-movie-combat.jpg?itok=2tNfrhCY 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/kingmakers-movie-combat.jpg?itok=unaXrmZj 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Kingmakers&nbsp;</em>is getting a movie, even though it hasn't even technically got a game yet.</figcaption></figure><p>Story Kitchen cofounder Dimitri Johnson says that&nbsp;<em>Kingmakers</em>' "action, world-building, and intriguing sci-fi" make it the perfect choice for a "propulsive new franchise in Hollywood".</p>
<p>tinyBuild CEO Alex Nichiporchik, meanwhile (whose&nbsp;<em>James Bond</em>-style exploits during the outbreak of war in Ukraine <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/tinybuild-war-room-meeting-led-to-crazy-plans-to-extract-employees">you can read about here</a>), says he and his studio are "extremely pumped" to be teaming up with Story Kitchen. Nichiporchik describes the&nbsp;<em>Kingmakers&nbsp;</em>movie as a "time-bending spectacle".</p>
<p>Story Kitchen cofounder Mike Goldberg and Nichiporchik both think that&nbsp;<em>Kingmakers&nbsp;</em>has got rich enough lore behind it for a movie, and Nichiporchik further points to adaptations of&nbsp;<em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/sonic-hedgehog-3-movie-teaser">Sonic the Hedgehog</a>&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/features/fallout-season-one-review-welcome-to-apocalypse">Fallout</a>&nbsp;</em>as proof that video game movie adaptations can work.</p>
<p>Of course,&nbsp;<em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/kaitlyn-dever-last-of-us-season-2">The Last of Us</a>&nbsp;</em>doesn't get out of VentureBeat's article without a mention, either. tinyBuild and Story Kitchen seem to have all the right touchstones for a&nbsp;<em>Kingmakers&nbsp;</em>adaptation, but whether or not it works - or, indeed, even comes to fruition - remains to be seen.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/the-last-of-us-kingmakers-tv.jpg?itok=ok3PF3R1 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/the-last-of-us-kingmakers-tv.jpg?itok=XXfqHqD8 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>The Last of Us&nbsp;</em>is arguably the touchstone of quality for anyone wanting to make a video game-to-TV or movie adaptation.</figcaption></figure><p>Of course, it's unlikely that the&nbsp;<em>Kingmakers&nbsp;</em>adaptation will be quite so weighty as&nbsp;<em>The Last of Us</em>; any property in which assault rifle-wielding soldiers go up against medieval knights must surely be at least at a certain level of silly to proceed.</p>
<p>Still, we'll have to wait and see what Story Kitchen cooks up (ahem). The studio has a good pedigree; it's responsible for adaptations of properties like&nbsp;<em>Sonic</em>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<em>Tomb Raider</em>, and it's also behind the recently-announced <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/live-action-dredge-movie">live-action&nbsp;<em>Dredge&nbsp;</em>movie</a> that's currently in the works.</p>
<p>As for&nbsp;<em>Kingmakers&nbsp;</em>itself, no release date has yet been revealed for the game, and given that tinyBuild <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/tinybuild-financials-2023">made a pretty significant loss last year</a>, the publisher will likely be hoping for a date sooner rather than later.</p>
<p>Stay tuned for more, and in the meantime, if you want to wishlist&nbsp;<em>Kingmakers&nbsp;</em>on Steam, <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2109770/Kingmakers/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor">you can do so here</a>.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GeForce NOW Breaks 2,000 Games Milestone, Will Support Black Myth: Wukong at Launch]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/geforce-now-breaks-2000-games-milestone-will-support-black-myth-wukong-at-launch/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/geforce-now-breaks-2-000-games-milestone-will-support-black-myth-wukong-at-launch.947949/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/geforce-now-breaks-2000-games-milestone-will-support-black-myth-wukong-at-launch/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Today's GeForce NOW Thursday lineup is rather light, but it has just enough games to allow NVIDIA's cloud streaming platform to boast about having over two thousand compatible games.</p>
<p>As you might remember, GeForce NOW had a rather lengthy beta phase that began in October 2015 (although the free beta available for everyone came <a href="https://wccftech.com/geforce-now-free-beta-available-now-pc/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">out</a> in January 2018) and lasted until February 2020, when NVIDIA <a href="https://wccftech.com/nvidias-cloud-gaming-service-geforce-now-is-officially-out-of-beta/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced</a> the official release of the cloud streaming platform just as the world started grappling with the COVID-19 pandemic.&nbsp;Before the end of the launch month, NVIDIA already <a href="https://wccftech.com/nvidia-boasts-over-one-million-new-gamers-using-geforce-now-since-it-left-beta/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">boasted</a> GeForce NOW's one million user base despite several publishers (such as Activision Blizzard) leaving GFN after the beta.</p>
<p>As of two years ago, NVIDIA said that there were over 20 million GeForce NOW users. Of course, the cloud streaming platform has made big strides in its performance throughout these years. The <a href="https://wccftech.com/geforce-now-rtx-4080-superpod-rollout-begins-today-10-new-games-added/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Ultimate tier</a> is equipped with RTX 4080-class graphics cards, allowing gamers to play the latest PC titles at up to 4K resolution or 120 frames per second while also supporting NVIDIA DLSS 3.5, ray tracing, and Reflex.</p>
<p>One of those is Game Science's Black Myth: Wukong. The action RPG (which was shown once again today in a stunning new gameplay <a href="https://wccftech.com/black-myth-wukong-shows-its-stunning-game-world-in-final-gameplay-trailer/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">trailer</a>) will be available on GeForce NOW at launch. Overall, NVIDIA's cloud streaming platform popularity definitely benefited from Microsoft's decision to <a href="https://wccftech.com/microsoft-to-bring-all-its-xbox-pc-games-to-geforce-now-including-activision-blizzards-if-the-deal-passes/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">bring</a> all its games from the Xbox, Bethesda, and Activision Blizzard divisions to GFN as part of its bid to get the Activision Blizzard acquisition approved by regulators.</p>
<p>The full list of weekly GFN additions can be found below. As a reminder, the Summer Sale is still ongoing, albeit only for a little while longer. Moreover, Priority and Ultimate subscribers can grab an Elder Scrolls Online 'Noble Snack' emote for free starting today. Free members will get the opportunity starting tomorrow.</p>
<p><em>● Warhammer 40,000: Speed Freeks (New release on Steam, Aug. 6)</em><br>
<em>● Prince of Persia: The Lost Crown (New release on Steam, Aug. 8)</em><br>
<em>● Ratten Reich (New release on Steam, Aug. 9)</em><br>
<em>● Nine Sols (Steam)</em><br>
<em>● Visions of Mana Demo (Steam)</em></p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WolfEye Studios Reveals Images & Details for New Action RPG]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/wolfeye-studios-reveals-images-details-for-new-action-rpg/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/wolfeye-studios-reveals-images-details-for-new-action-rpg.947940/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/wolfeye-studios-reveals-images-details-for-new-action-rpg/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>In a new <a href="https://x.com/WolfEyeGames/status/1821531821328499064" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">post on X</a>, WolfEye Studios shared three first-look images of its anticipated action RPG, featuring different settings and characters.</p>



<p>The first image showcases a dusty landscape and base of some kind, while the other images create more of a steampunk look. Fans quickly praised the art design for its creativity, style, and worldbuilding.</p>



<p>In a <a href="https://x.com/WolfEyeGames/status/1821532563862687792" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">separate post</a> on X, WolfEye Studios offered another landscape shot. It also invited curious fans to sign up “for a chance at Private Alpha access.” This leads to another compelling visual, teasing “Candis Technologies” with the slogan “the future is bright.” </p>



<figure></figure>







<p>Just yesterday, Arkane co-founder Raphael Colantonio <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dishonored-and-prey-fans-should-watch-out-for-wolfeye-studios-next-game/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">teased WolfEye Studios’ next game</a>, adding that fans of Dishonored and Prey “will be happy.”</p>



<p>In an interview <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/arkane-co-founder-first-person-action-rpg-dishonored-prey" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener sponsored nofollow">with IGN</a> today, Colantonio also offered some new details about the nature of the project itself, though it remains untitled.  </p>



<p>They explained it’s “an ambitious new IP built upon the DNA of earlier Arkane games to deliver a rich and detailed world, freedom of how to play, and a deep RPG experience.” They added that it’s a first-person action RPG, and it is “actively in production.” </p>



<p>And although WolfEye Studios encouraged fans to sign up for the private alpha, Colantonio says there will be a “limited private Alpha in 2025.” So, players will have to wait some time before experiencing any gameplay.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more of the latest Insider Gaming news, you can read about a Sony briefing confirming new details about the company’s <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/sony-confirms-new-details-on-bungie-restructuring-plan/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Bungie restructuring plans</a>, and sign up to receive <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/newsletter/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">our official newsletter</a>.</p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vampire Survivors Coming to PlayStation Later This Month]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/vampire-survivors-playstation-release/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/vampire-survivors-coming-to-playstation-later-this-month.947937/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/vampire-survivors-playstation-release/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>It has just been revealed that the BAFTA Award-winning ‘bullet hell’ title, Vampire Survivors, is headed to PlayStation 4 and PlayStation 5 on August 29. This stellar title was released in 2021 and took audiences by storm, offering up a plethora of replayability stacked alongside rogue-lite mechanics and one of the most insane visual palettes I’ve ever seen in a game.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-can-t-put-it-down">Can’t Put It Down</h2>



<p>I’d never played a game like Vampire Survivors when I demoed it at WASD London, and as soon as I stood up after my 30 minutes in-game, I was hooked. I immediately purchased it on Steam and fell in love with it, spending hours looping the various maps and modes with a vast array of characters to play as and secrets to unravel.</p>



<p>This highly-reviewed, top-rated title is now making its way to PlayStation 4 and PlayStation 5, and it’ll be released digitally on August 29.</p>



<p>The base game will cost just $4.99, with various expansion packs and DLC bundles being offered at prices ranging from $1.99 to $2.49. It’s amazing that something with so much potential and so many hours of entertainment costs so little. I can’t recommend this game enough. </p>



<p>It’s particularly special if you’re a fan of retro gaming, thanks to the visual style employed by poncle, the game’s developer. </p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/sony-confirms-new-details-on-bungie-restructuring-plan/">Bungie is restructuring</a></p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vampire Survivors Is Finally Coming To PS5 And PS4 Later This Month]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/vampire-survivors-is-finally-coming-to-ps5-and-ps4-later-this-month/1100-6525631/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/vampire-survivors-is-finally-coming-to-ps5-and-ps4-later-this-month.947934/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/vampire-survivors-is-finally-coming-to-ps5-and-ps4-later-this-month/1100-6525631/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6525631">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/vampire-survivors/" data-ref-id="5000-544864">Vampire Survivors</a> has locked in an August 29 release date for PS5 and PS4 consoles. Developer Poncle made the announcement with a short trailer, showing off all of the action and 500,000 texture-mapped garlic balls, and emphasizing "at least" 13.5 hours of gameplay.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rcBhIhnXnO0" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/rcBhIhnXnO0" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>A Vampire Survivors PlayStation port was first revealed during <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/triple-i-initiative-showcase-games-announcements/2900-5250/" data-ref-id="2900-5250">the Triple-I Initiative showcase in April</a> alongside Contra DLC. One of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/gamespots-10-best-games-of-2022/2900-4517/" data-ref-id="2900-4517">GameSpot's best games of 2022</a>, Vampire Survivors has steadily grown since its full launch and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/vampire-survivors-is-crossing-over-with-among-us-to-bring-new-weapons-and-characters/1100-6519745/" data-ref-id="1100-6519745">even crossed over with Among Us</a>, adding new themed weapons and characters in December 2023.</p><p>"It's cheap. It's ugly. And it's easily one of the best games of 2022. Vampire Survivors is the clearest example of how compelling a simple concept and <em>fantastic</em> game feel can be," Tamoor Hussain wrote about the game, which is also being developed into a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/vampire-survivors-tv-series-in-the-works-from-john-wick-creators-studio/1100-6513691/" data-ref-id="1100-6513691">TV animated series</a>.</p><p>When Poncle wasn't adding other post-launch content like a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/vampire-survivors-adds-co-op-teases-adventures-mode-and-more/1100-6516980/" data-ref-id="1100-6516980">co-op mode</a> and a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/vampire-survivors-latest-update-makes-it-feel-a-lot-like-christmas/1100-6518553/" data-ref-id="1100-6518553">Christmas update</a>, it managed to find time to produce a shot-for-shot <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/vampire-survivors-trailer-recreates-classic-final-fantasy-7-teaser/1100-6521494/" data-ref-id="1100-6521494">remake of the classic Final Fantasy 7</a> original PlayStation trailer using Vampire Survivors assets.</p><p>If you don't have a PS5 or a PS4, Vampire Survivors is also currently available on PC, Xbox Series X|S, Xbox One, Nintendo Switch, and mobile platforms. If you'd like to get some insight into how the game came to be, the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XQVdR8mJrds" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">NoClip Vampire Survivors documentary</a> is insightful <em>and </em>it has a puppet show.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/108490194306897153177?rel=author">Darryn Bonthuys</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Order: 1886 and God of War Developer Ready at Dawn Reportedly Shut Down]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/ready-at-dawn-reportedly-shut-down</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-order-1886-and-god-of-war-developer-ready-at-dawn-reportedly-shut-down.947919/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/ready-at-dawn-reportedly-shut-down<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>The Order: 1886&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>God of War&nbsp;</em>developer Ready at Dawn has reportedly been closed down by parent company Meta, with employees apparently being encouraged to apply elsewhere in the company.</p>
<p>That's according to <a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/ready-at-dawn-studios-closing" rel="noopener" target="_blank">a report by Android Central</a>, which in turn cites an "internal memo sent to employees". Per the memo, which was apparently written by Meta's Oculus VP Gio Hunt, Meta's budget for its VR-based Reality Labs division is set to be slashed by 20% by 2026, and Ready at Dawn's closure is part of that initiative.</p>
<p>A Meta spokesperson subsequently told Android Central that rather than being made to "save money", these cuts were, in fact, part of ensuring that Oculus can make a "better long-term impact" in the world of VR gaming.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/ready-at-dawn-closure-lone-echo-2.jpg?itok=l2V8xCdy 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/ready-at-dawn-closure-lone-echo-2.jpg?itok=72e0ZWmK 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Since it was acquired by Oculus in 2020, Ready at Dawn has mostly focused on making VR games.</figcaption></figure><p>As Android Central points out, Meta's <a href="https://s21.q4cdn.com/399680738/files/doc_financials/2024/q2/Meta-06-30-2024-Exhibit-99-1_Final.pdf" rel="noopener" target="_blank">second-quarter earnings report</a>&nbsp;was released last week, and during an earnings call, the company said that its <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/meta-quest-3-review-mixed-reality-marvel">Quest 3 headset</a> was "exceeding...expectations" in sales terms, so Ready at Dawn's closure might seem like it's strangely-timed in relation to that announcement.</p>
<p>Still, the company's shuttering comes at a time when many studios are either being closed or are suffering heavy layoffs; recently, studios as diverse as <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/bungie-layoffs-200-employees">Bungie</a>, <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/ea-ceo-25-million-income-layoffs">EA</a>, and&nbsp;<em>Palia&nbsp;</em>developer <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/palia-developer-singularity-6-layoffs">Singularity 6</a> have all been hit by layoffs, while companies like&nbsp;<em>Elex&nbsp;</em>developer <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/piranha-bytes-shut-down-report">Piranha Bytes</a>&nbsp;(reportedly) have been shut down outright.</p>
<p>Ready at Dawn's is a long and storied history. The studio opened back in 2003, when it was founded by several former Naughty Dog employees. In that light, its first game, 2006's PSP platformer&nbsp;<em>Daxter</em>, makes a lot of sense, and the studio would go on to work on more games for Sony, including two&nbsp;<em>God of War&nbsp;</em>PSP titles.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/ready-at-dawn-closure-god-of-war.jpg?itok=k2P6Hxa2 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/ready-at-dawn-closure-god-of-war.jpg?itok=SlxyAMkD 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Ready at Dawn worked on two&nbsp;<em>God of War&nbsp;</em>games for the PSP.</figcaption></figure><p>Perhaps the studio's biggest project prior to being purchased by Oculus in 2020 was 2015's&nbsp;<em>The Order: 1886</em>, a third-person steampunk adventure for the PS4.</p>
<p>It was received with a certain ambivalence at launch, but there are many who believe the game is worth revisiting. If you want to read more about why some think&nbsp;<em>The Order: 1886&nbsp;</em>was misaligned, <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/features/is-order-1886-still-worth-playing">you can do so right here</a>.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WolfEye's new first-person RPG is "an evolution" of Prey and Dishonored featuring mechs, magnets and a continuous world]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/wolfeyes-new-first-person-rpg-is-an-evolution-of-prey-and-dishonored-featuring-mechs-magnets-and-a-continuous-world</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/wolfeyes-new-first-person-rpg-is-an-evolution-of-prey-and-dishonored-featuring-mechs-magnets-and-a-continuous-world.947916/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/wolfeyes-new-first-person-rpg-is-an-evolution-of-prey-and-dishonored-featuring-mechs-magnets-and-a-continuous-world<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
  

        <p>The Weird West devs on becoming the "alt-Arkane"</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Final_Workshop_8k(1).jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>WolfEye Studios</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
WolfEye's debut game <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/weird-west-review">Weird West</a> attempted to pack a little of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/dishonored">Dishonored</a>'s immersive sim sorcery into a top-down action-RPG. For the studio's next game, co-founders Raphaël Colantonio and Julien Roby are leaning into comparisons with their old endeavours at Arkane more earnestly. The new game - currently untitled and without a release date - is a first-person sci-fi RPG set in an alternate-1900s North America, which ostensibly combines the ingenuity and gadgetry of Dishonored and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/prey">Prey</a> with a "real RPG" experience redolent of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/the-elder-scrolls-v-skyrim">Skyrim</a> and modern-day <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/fallout-3">Fallout</a>.
</p>
<!--more-->
<p>
"The structure is very freeform, and you can explore whatever you want," Colantonio tells me over videocall. "But the mobility and the type of gameplay is very reminiscent of games that we've worked on in the past, like Prey or Dishonored. So you have this blend between an RPG, like an open experience, where you can go wherever you want, and level up, and there's branching etcetera, but at the same time, the physicality and the types of gadgets and powers that you've seen in games from Arkane before. So if you look at the continuum from Dishonored to Prey, and then we imagine, how would it be if it was even more open than that, even more RPG than Prey."
</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Final_Drone_8k.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>WolfEye</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>
Colantonio and Roby aren't saying much about the game's story right now, but the announcement screens give you a sense of the ambience and stakes: industrial brickwork, big smoky skies, automatons of delicately embossed steel. There are Gatling guns and water silos, canyons lined with rickety gantries, and workshops sliced into what seem like convenient shady hiding spots by the setting sun.
</p>
<p>
"It's a world where you can recognise the scenery, but then the types of technology are futuristic, even though in a style of fabrication that would have made sense in the 1900s," Colantonio says. "That's why you have this really unique look - it's not really steampunk, but some people will say it's steampunk. And part of the story is that at some point you will realise why this alternate timeline was created."
</p>
<p>
The developers aren't quite ready to talk about specific gadgets at your disposal, either. The project entered pre-production in 2022, and Wolfeye have only just finished the first vertical slice - that is, an internal demo which gives a sense of every aspect of the experience. But you can expect to get your grubby mitts on automatons of various kinds, together with firearms such as shotguns and one particular fancy traversal tool which sounds like it wants to be this game's Blink. 
</p>
<p>
"We have this thing that is a magnetic rope, so it sticks to any metal in a very systemic way," Colantonio says. "If there is any metal in the scene, like a bin or anything, it sticks to it and spawns a rope you can use to climb, for example." You'll also get abilities that appear more supernatural in nature, such as one that lets you "set a point that allows you to escape from the middle of combat later".
</p>
<p>
In general, Colantonio goes on, the game is about "going deeper into the space of possibilities" offered by his and Roby's previous projects at Arkane, while stirring in concepts and approaches from traditional role-players. "If you think about our games, I think they have, one, interesting worlds to explore that are very - I don't know if realistic is the word, but even though they are not real they are grounded, there's full coherence and lore that players will enjoy discovering. And the other aspect is play your way. There's a very sandboxy aspect to it, where you can customise your playstyle and the game responds to it as well as branching the story. If you did some things, there are consequences now and then - there are multiple ways to do things. 
</p>
<p>
"So we are doing this again, but I think putting this in an RPG structure gives even more possibilities. It's a little more free, in a way, and that's new for us and I think our players will enjoy it. Because our games have always been adjacent to RPGs, but this time we're going real RPG - so dialogue trees, level-ups and stats and other things that you can grow." Colantonio seems especially enthused about the addition of proper branching dialogue, noting that this is relatively unexplored territory for Wolfeye. "If you have [a high enough speech skill] or if you've done something specific, you can tell something to someone to access new options and possibilities."
</p>
<p>
The character stats, meanwhile, will be familiar to genre aficionadoes, though Colantonio again cautions me that everything is still WIP. "We've just finished a vertical slice, and the detail of the stats will change as we make progress in the game, because if you think about it, the stats are guiding all the underlying systems. They can change name, they can encompass more mechanics than one, so all of this is still very flexible. So it's too early right now to describe all of the stats. But yeah, it would be that kind of thing - maybe it's not "Strength" but "Fortitude". We're still trying different things and adapting, so that might change all the way until alpha." 
</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Final_Canyon_8k.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>WolfEye</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>
Is the game still recognisable as an immersive sim in the Arkane mold, given all these additions to the formula? "Definitely, people who are into our past games will enjoy that layer," Colantonio assures me. "So yes, it is on the page of an immersive sim, even though from a genre perspective, people will perceive it as an RPG."
</p>
<p>
He gives me a tentative example of an in-game scenario that brings abilities, gadgets and obstacles together into an open-ended, Dunwallian melange. "In the current vertical slice, it's the beginning of the game, and so there are different things you do to understand who you are and the story's inciting incident. But before that, one of the challenges is to go through a factory that's protected by automatons, and here there are, again, many ways you can do things, whether it's the more direct approach with dynamite you've found on the way, or shotguns and protective gear or protective drones - because you might have drones. Or you can be sneaky and find the security room and disable the automatons."
</p>
<p>
As to which RPGs have proven influential, there are some obvious big hitters. "I would definitely mention Fallout," Colantonio says. "I can tell you a list of RPGs that we've been very impressed with in general, but it doesn't mean that they are a direct comparison or inspiration for us. Skyrim has been a very good one, Baldur's Gate 3, of course, a really fantastic game, and the Fallout series, from when it was 2D and since it came to 3D with Fallout 3, New Vegas and Fallout 4. That kind of structure is really what we like." 
</p>
<p>
All of this comes with the caveat that Arkane aren't trying to make anything nearly as sprawling as an Elder Scrolls game. "The scope, the size - historically we've always created games that are more dense, higher density, and less about size," Colantonio says. "So that is something we always favour - more possibilities and more detail, more craft, over endless repetitive dungeons. We're not going for that - it's going to be more of a crafted world. It will land somewhere between Fallout, Prey and Dishonored, if you wanted to try to pinpoint it." 
</p>
<p>
The game's world won't have any discrete exploration, combat or town areas; it'll be a steadily unrolling sandbox that supports a multitude of methods, nice and nasty. Unlike Weird West, it won't have any loading transitions between areas. Definitely don't call it an open world, though. "It's not like Weird West, it's more of an evolution of Prey, if we were to look at the game structure," Colantonio notes. "Prey, technically it would be considered continuous, some people would say 'no, it's an open world'. The reason we don't want to say open world is that it comes with expectations that it's going to be gigantic - you know, it takes six months to ride a horse from A to B - which is not at all what we do. But technically, it's an open world in the sense that it's so continuous, you can go anywhere, there's no loading, etcetera." 
</p>
<p>
Colantonio and Roby's old outfit Arkane isn't in a great place, at present. Parent company Microsoft <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/microsoft-are-shutting-down-the-studios-that-made-redfall-and-hi-fi-rush">recently shut down Prey's original creators, Arkane Austin</a>, following a poor reception for the studio's vampire shooter Redfall (and more importantly, following Microsoft's $68.7 billion splurge on the acquisition of Activision Blizzard). Arkane Lyon have survived these "strategic repositionings", and are working on <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/arkane-release-new-marvels-blade-concept-artworks-hinting-at-missions-combat-and-levels#comments">a new immersive sim featuring Marvel's vampire hero Blade</a>. The future of the Dishonored series - which technically includes spy-fi extravaganza Deathloop, a game set in the same universe - remains ambiguous, though <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dishonored-3-is-the-only-exciting-thing-on-bethesdas-leaked-5-year-plan-and-im-worried">the words "Dishonored 3" appear on a leaked Microsoft planning document from 2020</a>.
</p>
<p>
Wolfeye have long traded on their Arkane associations for publicity. But in the wake of Microsoft's reductions, they increasingly resemble an Arkane rescue mission, clawing back that legacy of immersive sim design from Bethesda and Microsoft. According to Roby, the studio has "essentially doubled" in size since the release of Weird West, and they've hired a lot of former colleagues from Arkane Lyon and Austin, these being people "who know already the value of the kind of game we're doing from a design standpoint, and from a pure experience standpoint". 
</p>
<p>
Wolfeye has become the "alt-Arkane," suggests Colantonio in closing. "I think it's the spirit of Arkane, for sure, but Wolfeye is its own company. We do have so many people from Arkane at this point that it does feel like being at Arkane prior to being acquired. So yes, it's an unleashed Arkane. It's a free Arkane."</p>
<p><em>Look out for a limited private alpha test for WolfEye's new game next year.</em></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Roblox responds to platform ban in Türkiye]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/roblox-responds-to-platform-ban-in-turkiye</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/roblox-responds-to-platform-ban-in-t%C3%BCrkiye.947907/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/roblox-responds-to-platform-ban-in-turkiye<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>"We respect the laws and regulations in countries where we operate."</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/roblox-logo.png?width=1200&amp;height=1200&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Roblox</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
Roblox has responded to news the government of Türkiye has banned access to the platform in order to "ensure the protection of our children".
</p>
<p>
News of the ban was shared yesterday by the country's Minister of Justice Yılmaz Tunç in a lengthy statement on social media site X.
</p>
<p>
Tunç didn't provide a specific reason for the ban beyond it being "due to the content that could lead to the exploitation of children" and that the country is "obliged to take the necessary measures to ensure the protection of our children".
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="PlayStation live-service Concord won't sell you a battle pass - would it be better if it did?" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/1LcpqnUgV5E?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>PlayStation live-service Concord won't sell you a battle pass - would it be better if it did?</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/1LcpqnUgV5E?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/1LcpqnUgV5E?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>PlayStation live-service Concord won't sell you a battle pass - but would it be more successful if it did?<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1LcpqnUgV5E" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>

As <a href="https://www.turkiyetoday.com/turkiye/roblox-banned-in-turkiye-following-nationwide-instagram-block-37398/">Türkiye Today</a> reports, the ban was primarily motivated by reports of inappropriate sexual content on Roblox and exploitation of children.

</p>
<p>"We've spent almost 20 years making Roblox one of the safest online platforms for our users, particularly the youngest, and ensuring the safety of our users is at the core of everything we do," said a Roblox spokesperson in a statement to Eurogamer.</p>
<p>"We respect the laws and regulations in countries where we operate and share local lawmakers' commitment to children. We look forward to working together to ensure Roblox is back online in Türkiye as soon as possible."</p>
<p>
The ban arrives five days after Instagram was similarly banned, due to accusations from a senior aide to President Recep Tayyip Erdogan of censorship of posts related to the death of Hamas political chief Ismail Haniyeh. "We will continue to defend freedom of expression against platforms that serve global exploitation and injustice," said Fahrettin Altun, head of the Presidency's Directorate of Communications.
</p>
<p>
The banning of both platforms has fuelled debates on government control over online content.
</p>
<div>
<div data-domain="twitter.com"><blockquote><p dir="ltr" lang="tr">Çocukların istismarına neden olacak içerikler barındırması sebebiyle Roblox isimli oyun platformuna ve uygulama marketlerindeki linklerine, Adana Cumhuriyet Başsavcılığı tarafından yürütülen soruşturma kapsamında “İnternet Ortamında Yapılan Yayınların Düzenlenmesi ve Bu Yayınlar…</p>— Yılmaz TUNÇ (@yilmaztunc) <a href="https://twitter.com/yilmaztunc/status/1821259391087341579?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 7, 2024</a></blockquote></div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>

<p>
Back in 2021, a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/roblox-exploiting-young-game-developers-new-investigation-reports">report by People Make Games</a> accused Roblox of exploiting children as young game developers. 

</p>
<p>
Earlier this year, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/roblox-studio-boss-children-making-money-on-the-platform-isnt-exploitation-its-a-gift">Roblox Studio head Stefano Corazza discussed the platform with Eurogamer</a> and its reputation of being exploitative of young developers. In a follow-up statement, Roblox clarified the company does not hire minors.


</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Arkane founder's new RPG shoots for "Fallout meets Dishonored" with a splash of Obsidian storytelling]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/arkane-founders-new-rpg-shoots-for-fallout-meets-dishonored-with-a-splash-of-obsidian-storytelling</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/arkane-founders-new-rpg-shoots-for-fallout-meets-dishonored-with-a-splash-of-obsidian-storytelling.947904/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/arkane-founders-new-rpg-shoots-for-fallout-meets-dishonored-with-a-splash-of-obsidian-storytelling<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>One to keep a WolfEye on.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Wolfeye---Final_Workshop-1080.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>WolfEye Studios</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>As <a href="https://x.com/rafcolantonio/status/1820891833028727212">teased</a> earlier this week, Arkane founder Raphael Colantonio has today unveiled the first details of his next game at WolfEye Studios.</p>
<p>While the game's name is still under wraps, this new project is a first-person action <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/best-rpgs">RPG</a> that's set in an alternate America in the 1900s, marking a shift in time and perspective from the top-down, isometric sandbox towns of WolfEye's debut game, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/weird-west">Weird West</a>.</p>
<p>As the studio also <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/arkane-co-founder-teases-sci-fi-rpg-as-next-game">previously teased</a>, the new game's visuals will be grounded in a retro sci-fi aesthetic - and if the first three in-game screenshots didn't already give it away, Colantonio (who's creative director for this new game) and executive producer Julien Roby tell me over a video call that both its gameplay and art direction are intended to be "something like Fallout meets Dishonored".</p>
<figure>
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<figcaption></figcaption>
</figure><p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DOG4cSHXRws" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a>
<span data-position="1"></span></p><p>"That's where we want to be, we want to be in that space," Colantonio tells me. "If there is such a thing as a continuum between Fallout and Dishonored, I would say Prey is somewhere in the middle because it's already more RPG than Dishonored, and this new game is somewhere closer to Fallout, as far as the RPG-ness goes."</p>
<p>That means you can expect "a lot of [quest objectives] such as 'investigate about this thing, infiltrate that building'," Colantonio explains, "but with any approach you want." This can range from "very, very direct" approaches, perhaps utilizing the new weapon mods WolfEye are making for this game, or "more indirect" methods, such as talking your way in or out of a scenario with the game's speech options. All classic RPG fare, in other words, which Colantonio and Roby hope will "add even more layers of possibilities [to the game], which is really what we've always been about."</p>
<p>"I love personally RPGs that fall back on their feet when you shoot them between the eyes, for example," Colantonio says. "Games from Obsidian are pretty good at that, and that's that zone that we're hitting in this game."</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Wolfeye---Final_Canyon.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>WolfEye Studios</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>The world will be "continuous", too, allowing players to "go anywhere" and "kill anyone you want", Colantonio adds. He doesn't ever mention the words 'open world', mind, but I get the feeling it will at least be more connected than the discrete locations of Weird West, for example.</p>
<p>Alas, WolfEye isn't ready to reveal any details about the citing event that set this alternate timeline in motion yet either - only that "something happened in America," Colantonio says, "and the player is going to find this out as they play. It's going to be one of the reveals in the development of the plot."</p>
<p>As for what part of America the game will take place in, there are a couple of hints we can glean from those initial screenshots WolfEye has released. It still looks as though there will be a certain Wild West-ness about it, judging by the canyons and rocky landscapes, and when I put this to Colantonio, he confirms that, "Yes, of course, you can recognise the views and the vistas. It's in that area, and in that location."</p>
<p>Crucially, though, the game won't be drawing from traditional Western tropes. "I think the big distinction we're making here is, as far as genre literature goes, this is more like sci-fi literature than it is Wild West or whatever," he says. "I think the Western is a genre of literature that people associate with certain types of scenarios like revenge or duels in the streets. We don't have any of that."</p>
<p>Rather, it's more of a visual backdrop "where something so crazy has happened that there's not much left of it," he adds, though he does tease that at least some form of culture has managed to evolve in the intervening 20-30 years since that event in the game, "but it's already a different thing," he clarifies. "If you really wanted to pinpoint it, it would be like some sort of, I don't know, steampunk outtake 1900s."</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Wolfeye---Final_Drone.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>WolfEye Studios</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>It's an ambitious step-up for this entirely remote team, but throughout our conversation, Colantonio and Roby are both keen to emphasise how many former Arkane developers are now working at WolfEye - including Prey's lead visual designer and Dishonored level artist Emmanuel Petit, who's now the art director on this new project. They have also been able to hire a handful of Arkane Austin developers following that <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/former-blizzard-boss-mike-ybarra-defends-xboxs-phil-spencer-following-arkane-austin-tango-gameworks-closures">studio's closure</a> earlier in the year, though Colantonio states that "we had done most of our growth before" over the last couple of years. Still, working with so many former colleagues from across their respective careers "makes things a lot easier," says Roby, and Colantonio agrees. "It's the same formation of people [from Prey and Dishonored] who are now with us, so we already know what we're doing," he says.</p>
<p>That said, the studio's headcount still only numbers between 55-60 people, according to Roby, and the challenge will be "trying to keep the game within a scope that allows for the team to be that size and not too much beyond," he says. "Beyond that size is where things start to change the way you actually work, and we'd like to keep that sense of, 'Hey, everyone has a big impact on the game and a big enough say on what they're doing'."</p>
<p>As for when we might next hear more details about WolfEye's new game, it likely won't be until next year, when WolfEye are planning to run a private alpha for it (<a href="http://www.wolfeye-studios.com/signup">sign-ups for which are available now</a>).</p>
<p>"We're still discussing the details for it," Roby says, "but whatever we call it, we want to make sure that before we release the game, we get the community involved." The studio put on a similar test for Weird West, but Roby admits that they did it "way too late before release and we didn't really have time to act on the most major feedback". Hence the desire to bring in players earlier this time, so they can better act on any potential problems.</p>
<p>With pre-production now complete, WolfEye will now be moving into full production while they search for a publishing partner.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sony Confirms New Details on Bungie Restructuring Plan]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/sony-confirms-new-details-on-bungie-restructuring-plan/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sony-confirms-new-details-on-bungie-restructuring-plan.947895/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/sony-confirms-new-details-on-bungie-restructuring-plan/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>In a new <a href="https://www.irwebmeeting.com/sony/fast/20240807/sA7GHnQS/202503_1q_02_en/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">briefing video</a>, Sony President, COO and CFO Hiroki Totoki offered clarifying statements about its Bungie restructuring plans.</p>



<p>Totoki said that the purpose of the restructure is “cost restructure and portfolio optimization.” They also said that Bungie’s back office functions “should be integrated with the studio of SIE.”</p>



<p>Totoki further mentioned plans to concentrate Bungie’s head count and resources on Destiny 2 and live-service title Marathon. They said there would be “constant resources there.” However, “other title development” will instead move to PlayStation studios. </p>



<figure></figure>







<p>Rounding out the briefing’s mention of Bungie, Totoki broadly said that the organizational structure will also be changed. There are plans to “optimize the overall studio structure.”</p>



<p>The briefing follows Bungie’s extensive <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/bungie-announces-major-layoffs-and-restructuring/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">layoffs and restructuring</a>, which Bungie announced last week. It affected over 200 employees at Bungie, including about 17% of its workforce. Bungie also moved some of its employees to Sony as part of the restructuring.</p>



<p>Bungie CEO Pete Parsons cited “rising costs of development and industry shifts as well as enduring economic conditions.” They also called it a “difficult and painful day, especially for our departing colleagues.”</p>



<p>In June 2024, Bungie announced that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/bungie-announces-destiny-2-codename-frontiers-is-coming-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Destiny 2 Codename Frontiers</a> is coming in 2025, though there isn’t a concrete release date yet. It was accompanied by teasers for upcoming Year 10 episodes. These plans should remain unchanged, given Sony’s new briefing.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more of the latest gaming industry news, you can read about The Game Kitchen teasing some type of new Blasphemous content <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/blasphemous-devs-reveal-cryptic-teaser-for-fall-2024-content/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">coming in Fall 2024</a>, and sign up to receive the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/newsletter/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming newsletter</a>.</p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Verizon Announces Free High School Esports League]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/verizon-announces-free-high-school-esports-league/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/verizon-announces-free-high-school-esports-league.947892/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/verizon-announces-free-high-school-esports-league/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>Following the IOC’s announcement regarding esports joining the Olympics, Verizon has decided to provide access to competitive video games all across the US. The popular phone and data company has officially announced a high school esports league that will be free to all students.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-verizon-announces-first-ever-free-scholastic-high-school-esports-league">Verizon Announces First Ever Free Scholastic High School Esports League</h2>



<p>With esports growing at an alarming rate, many schools in the US have been scrambling to develop an esports program. What was originally just considered a LAN club, is now an actual program that could award kids with college scholarships, as collegiate esports continues to thrive.</p>



<p>Verizon has been focused on providing students with immersive learning content across the US. Now, though, the company is taking it one step further and providing kids with access to esports.</p>



<p>Schools that choose to participate will receive free coaching guidance from esports professionals to help prepare them for the yearly esports seasons.</p>



<figure></figure>







<p>The Verizon Innovative Learning Esports League officially opens for registration today (August 8). Schools can now sign up to hop on board with the program.</p>



<p>The league’s season will run from September 23, 2024, to December 13, 2024. The league is in partnership with the nonprofit, Games For Change, which is helping to provide the coaching guidance.</p>







<h3 id="h-about-verizon-innovative-learning">About Verizon Innovative Learning</h3>



<p>Verizon is not only dedicated to giving students access to free esports across the country but also looking to add new and immersive ways for kids to learn in the classroom. Their dedication ranges from kindergarten to seniors in high school, as they are constantly giving new tech-driven content to teachers.</p>



<p>Not only are they focusing on esports, but also pushing gaming and game designing into classrooms. This helps to further the notion that gaming is a great career.</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>Hopefully, Verizon’s mission will be successful and we see a new wave of gamers come into the spotlight from it.</p>



<p>Stay tuned to Insider Gaming for more esports news.</p>





									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[DEATHSPRINT 66 launches September 12]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/deathsprint-66-launches-september-12</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/deathsprint-66-launches-september-12.947889/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/deathsprint-66-launches-september-12<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Dedicated test sessions set for August 8 and 9.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Eight-player on-foot <a title="Genres > Racing [195 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/racing">racing</a> game <em><a title="Games > DEATHSPRINT 66 [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/deathsprint-66">DEATHSPRINT 66</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > PC [20,823 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1273560/DeathSprint_66/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> on September 12, publisher <a title="Companies > Secret Mode [30 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/secret-mode">Secret Mode</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Sumo Newcastle [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sumo-digital/sumo-newcastle">Sumo Newcastle</a> announced. <span id="more-904617"></span></p><p>Two dedicated test sessions are planned before the game’s release, the first being on August 8 from 10:00 a.m. PT / 1:00 p.m. ET to 2:00 p.m. PT / 5:00 p.m. ET, and the second on August 9 from 6:00 a.m. PT / 9:00 a.m. ET to 10:00 a.m. PT / 1:00 p.m. ET.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Secret Mode:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Welcome to The Deadliest Show on Earth.</p><p>In the year 2066, the Bachman Media Network is yet again, set to dominate the world of brutal entertainment with the latest series of their headline show. <em>DEATHSPRINT 66</em> sees challengers take on the role of a Clone Jockey with an endless supply of clones at their disposal to compete in the visceral velocity of DEATHSPRINT.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong>Race</strong></p><p>Take part in thrilling 8 player PvP on-foot races across extreme obstacle courses that push the boundaries of entertainment. Run, jump, drift and slide your way through a series of deadly tracks, chaining together traversals to enter a flow state and earn HYPE.</p><p>HYPE fuels a range of exiting and deadly abilities including Boost, Seekersaw, Mag-Shield, EMP Blasts and Proximity Mines. A well-deployed ability can be the difference between winning and losing, making those split-second strategic decisions vital to your race.</p><p><strong>Entertain</strong></p><p>Winning is not enough. Entertaining the audience on track leads to bigger rewards off it. Your FAME score is a measure of how attractive you are to sponsors, the higher the score, the more interested they’ll be, unlocking a greater variety of cosmetics for your runner.</p><p>Tracks are filled with deadly booby traps, thrilling traversals and opportunities to take out your rivals meaning that each race is an unpredictable, unique and gripping experience.</p><p><strong>Survive</strong></p><p>In the ruins of long-abandoned cities of the old world, the Bachman Media Network has built a series of deadly racetracks designed for one purpose – to keep their blood-thirsty viewers entertained.</p><p>Deadly traps and difficult traversals litter each track, but with an endless supply of human clones to race with, contestants must fight a bloody battle to the finish and claim victory.</p><p>Immersed in a gritty, dystopian world, <em>DEATHSPRINT 66</em> explores the societal consequences of extreme entertainment.</p></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="DEATHSPRINT 66 | Release Date Reveal Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/u126C1N1WQw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Famitsu Sales: 7/29/24 – 8/4/24]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/famitsu-sales-7-29-24-8-4-24</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/famitsu-sales-7-29-24-%E2%80%93-8-4-24.947886/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/famitsu-sales-7-29-24-8-4-24<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Powerful Pro Baseball 2024-2025 stays on top.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a href="https://www.famitsu.com/article/202408/13646" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Famitsu</a> has published its estimated physical game software data for Japan for the week of July 29, 2024 to August 4, 2024. <span id="more-904020"></span></p><p><em><a title="Games > Powerful Pro Baseball 2024-2025 [6 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/powerful-pro-baseball-2024-2025">Powerful Pro Baseball 2024-2025</a></em> remained the best selling game for the third straight week since its release, moving an additional 21,392 retail copies on <a title="Platforms > Switch [15,755 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>.</p><p>On the hardware side, the Switch family sold 57,757 units, the <a title="Platforms > PS5 [7,609 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a> family sold 25,793 units, the <a title="Platforms > Xbox [24,506 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox">Xbox</a> Series family sold 4,339 units, and the <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,029 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a> family sold 52 units.</p><p>Get the full sales charts below.</p><p><strong>Software Sales</strong> (followed by lifetime sales)</p><ol><li>[NSW] <em>Powerful Pro Baseball 2024-2025</em> (<a title="Companies > Konami Digital Entertainment [1,073 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/konami">Konami</a>, 07/18/24) – 21,392 (223,619)</li><li>[NSW] <em>Mario Kart 8 Deluxe</em> (<a title="Platforms > Nintendo [20,568 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo">Nintendo</a>, 04/28/17) – 10,694 (5,932,192)</li><li>[NSW] <em><a title="Games > Animal Crossing: New Horizons [39 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/animal-crossing-new-horizons">Animal Crossing: New Horizons</a></em> (Nintendo, 03/20/20) – 8,254 (7,858,430)</li><li>[NSW] <em><a title="Games > Luigi's Mansion 2 HD [8 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/luigis-mansion-2-hd">Luigi’s Mansion 2 HD</a></em> (Nintendo, 06/27/24) – 7,434 (166,364)</li><li>[NSW] <em>Minecraft</em> (Microsoft, 06/21/18) – 6,917 (3,585,175)</li><li>[NSW] <em><a title="Games > Nintendo Switch Sports [14 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/nintendo-switch-sports">Nintendo Switch Sports</a></em> (Nintendo, 04/29/22) – 6,469 (1,363,142)</li><li>[NSW] <em><a title="Games > Super Mario Bros. Wonder [12 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/super-mario-bros-wonder">Super Mario Bros. Wonder</a></em> (Nintendo, 10/20/23) – 5,035 (1,902,143)</li><li>[NSW] <em><a title="Games > Nintendo World Championships: NES Edition [5 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/nintendo-world-championships-nes-edition">Nintendo World Championships: NES Edition</a></em> (Nintendo, 07/18/24) – 4,989 (41,123)</li><li>[NSW] <em><a title="Games > One Piece Odyssey [17 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/one-piece-odyssey">One Piece Odyssey Deluxe Edition</a></em> (<a title="Companies > Bandai Namco Entertainment [6,542 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/bandai-namco-entertainment">Bandai Namco</a>, 07/25/24) – 4,806 (21,179)</li><li>[NSW] <em><a title="Games > Super Smash Bros. Ultimate [68 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/super-smash-bros-ultimate">Super Smash Bros. Ultimate</a></em> (Nintendo, 12/07/18) – 4,739 (5,553,891)</li></ol><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Rankings 11 to 30 will be announced on August 9.</p><ol><li>[PS4] <em>Powerful Pro Baseball 2024-2025</em> (Konami, 07/18/24) –</li><li>[NSW] <em><a title="Games > The Legend of Heroes: Trails through Daybreak II [26 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/the-legend-of-heroes-trails-through-daybreak-ii">The Legend of Heroes: Trails through Daybreak II</a></em> (<a title="Companies > Nihon Falcom [698 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/nihon-falcom">Falcom</a>, 07/25/24) –</li><li>[NSW]&nbsp;<em><a title="Games > It Takes Two [12 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/it-takes-two">It Takes Two</a></em> (<a title="Companies > Electronic Arts [1,748 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/electronic-arts">Electronic Arts</a>, 12/08/22) –</li><li>[NSW] <em><a title="Games > REYNATIS [10 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/reynatis">REYNATIS</a></em> (<a title="Companies > FuRyu [361 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/furyu">FuRyu</a>, 07/25/24) –</li><li>[NSW] <em><a title="Games > Momotaro Dentetsu World: Chikyuu wa Kibou de Mawatteru! [7 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/momotaro-dentetsu-world-chikyuu-wa-kibou-de-mawatteru">Momotaro Dentetsu World: Chikyuu wa Kibou de Mawatteru!</a></em> (Konami, 11/16/23) –</li><li>[PS5] <em>REYNATIS</em> (FuRyu, 07/25/24) –</li><li>[NSW] <em><a title="Games > Pokemon Scarlet and Violet [31 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/pokemon-scarlet-violet">Pokemon Scarlet</a></em> / <em><a title="Series > Pokemon [44 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/series/pokemon">Pokemon</a> Violet</em> (<a title="Companies > The Pokemon Company [399 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/the-pokemon-company">The Pokemon Company</a>, 11/18/22) –</li><li>[NSW] <em><a title="Games > Splatoon 3 [20 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/splatoon-3">Splatoon 3</a></em> (Nintendo, 09/09/22) –</li><li>[NSW]&nbsp;<em>Luigi’s Mansion 3</em> (Nintendo, 10/31/19) –</li><li>[NSW] <em><a title="Games > Paper Mario: The Thousand-Year Door (2024) [9 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/paper-mario-the-thousand-year-door-2024">Paper Mario: The Thousand-Year Door</a></em> (Nintendo, 05/23/24) –</li><li>[NSW] <em>Clubhouse Games: 51 Worldwide Classics</em> (Nintendo, 06/05/20) –</li><li>[NSW]&nbsp;<em>Super Mario <a title="Genres > Party [70 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/party">Party</a></em> (Nintendo, 10/05/18) –</li><li>[NSW]&nbsp;<em><a title="Games > Disgaea 7 Complete [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/disgaea-7-complete">Disgaea 7 Complete</a></em> (<a title="Companies > Nippon Ichi Software [1,075 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/nippon-ichi-software">Nippon Ichi Software</a>, 07/25/24) –</li><li>[NSW] <em>Ace Combat 7: Skies Unknown Deluxe Edition</em> (Bandai Namco 07/11/24) –</li><li>[NSW] <em>Super Mario Odyssey</em> (Nintendo, 10/27/17) –</li><li>[NSW] <em><a title="Games > Mario Party Superstars [5 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/mario-party-superstars">Mario Party Superstars</a></em> (Nintendo, 10/29/21) –</li><li>[NSW] <em>Natsuzora no Monologue: Another Memory</em> (<a title="Companies > Idea Factory [1,450 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/idea-factory">Idea Factory</a>, 07/25/24) –</li><li>[NSW] <em><a title="Games > Pikmin 4 [7 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/pikmin-4">Pikmin 4</a></em> (Nintendo, 07/21/23) –</li><li>[NSW] <em><a title="Games > Kirby and the Forgotten Land [8 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/kirby-and-the-forgotten-land">Kirby and the Forgotten Land</a></em> (Nintendo, 03/25/22) –</li><li>[NSW] <em><a title="Games > The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom [14 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/the-legend-of-zelda-tears-of-the-kingdom">The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom</a></em> (Nintendo, 05/12/23) –</li></ol><p><strong>Hardware Sales</strong> (followed by lifetime sales)</p><ol><li>Switch OLED Model – 35,104 (7,641,997)</li><li>PlayStation 5 – 20,472 (5,076,563)</li><li>Switch Lite – 13,280 (5,969,782)</li><li>Switch – 9,373 (19,852,343)</li><li>PlayStation 5 Digital Edition – 5,321 (828,671)</li><li><a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [5,797 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series X</a> – 4,264 (300,849)</li><li>Xbox Series S – 75 (317,111)</li><li>PlayStation 4 – 52 (7,928,186)</li></ol></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Wolfeye Studios shares first look at in-development retro sci-fi first-person action RPG]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/wolfeye-studios-shares-first-look-at-in-development-retro-sci-fi-first-person-action-rpg</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/wolfeye-studios-shares-first-look-at-in-development-retro-sci-fi-first-person-action-rpg.947880/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/wolfeye-studios-shares-first-look-at-in-development-retro-sci-fi-first-person-action-rpg<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
        </ul>

    
    <p><span>Limited private alpha test planned for 2025.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Wolfeye Studios [7 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/wolfeye-studios">Wolfeye Studios</a>, an independent development studio co-led by president Raphael Colantonio, who founded <a title="Companies > Arkane Studios [105 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/zenimax-media/arkane-studios">Arkane Studios</a> and co-created <em>Dishonored</em> and <em>Prey</em>, is currently developing an untitled first-person <a title="Genres > Action RPG [1,271 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg/action-rpg">action RPG</a> that just wrapped pre-production and is now in full production, the company announced. It is said to be an “ambitious new IP built upon the DNA of earlier Arkane [Studios] games” that will “deliver a rich and detailed world, freedom of how to play, and a deep RPG experience.” <span id="more-903948"></span></p><p>The announcement follows a tease at Game Developers Conference 2024 in March, where Wolfeye Studios shared an image of a whiteboard from its Austin office with the words “retro sci-fi” and “first-person” scribbled on it.</p><p>The following three screenshots were shared with the announcement:</p><blockquote><p><strong>Canyon</strong></p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Wolfeye-Studios-Game_08-08-24_Canyon.jpg"></a></figure><p><strong>Drone</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Wolfeye-Studios-Game_08-08-24_Drone.jpg"></a></figure><p><strong>Workshop</strong></p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Wolfeye-Studios-Game_08-08-24_Workshop.jpg"></a></figure></blockquote><p>Wolfeye Studios plans to hold a limited private alpha test in 2025, and is encouraging users to sign up via the <a href="https://www.wolfeye-studios.com/signup" target="_blank" rel="noopener">interest list</a> at the studio’s official website.</p><p>“We are so happy to be able to officially confirm that our next game is actively in production and that it is a first-person action RPG,” said president and creative director, Raphael Colantonio in a press release. “Fans of the past games I have been involved with such as <em>Dishonored</em> and <em>Prey</em> will feel at home, as well as fans of <a title="Genres > RPG [16,477 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg">RPGs</a> in general. While we look for the right publishing partner, our sights are firmly set on getting our community involved with the game’s development with a limited private alpha in 2025. We can not wait for fans to see what we are working on.”</p><p>Wolfeye Studios is made up primarily of staff who came from <a title="Companies > Arkane Studios Lyon [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/zenimax-media/arkane-studios/arkane-studios-lyon">Arkane Studios Lyon</a> and the <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2024/05/bethesda-softworks-to-close-arkane-austin-tango-gameworks-alpha-dog-games-and-roundhouse-studios">recently closed</a> <a title="Companies > Arkane Studios Austin [14 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/zenimax-media/arkane-studios/arkane-studios-austin">Arkane Studios Austin</a>. Colantonio is joined by CEO and executive producer Julien Roby, who is also a former Arkane Studios executive who worked on <em>Dishonored</em> and other Arkane Studios games.</p><p>The first release from Wolfeye Studios, <em><a title="Games > Weird West [6 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/weird-west">Weird West</a></em>, launched for <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,029 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox One [13,381 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [20,823 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1097350/Weird_West/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> on March 31, 2022, followed by <a title="Platforms > PS5 [7,609 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a> and <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [5,797 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a> on May 8, 2023. A <a title="Platforms > Switch [15,755 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a> version was <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2023/05/weird-west-definitive-edition-coming-to-switch">announced</a> in May 2023, but has yet to release.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gori: Cuddly Carnage demo now available for consoles, PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/gori-cuddly-carnage-demo-now-available-for-consoles-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gori-cuddly-carnage-demo-now-available-for-consoles-pc.947877/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/gori-cuddly-carnage-demo-now-available-for-consoles-pc<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Features the first level of the game.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>A demo for cat <a title="Genres > Action [2,057 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action game</a> <em><a title="Games > Gori: Cuddly Carnage [4 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/gori-cuddly-carnage">Gori: Cuddly Carnage</a></em> is now available for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [7,609 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [5,797 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,029 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox One [13,381 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a>, Switch, and <a title="Platforms > PC [20,823 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via Steam, publisher <a title="Companies > Wired Productions [82 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/wired-productions">Wired Productions</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Angry Demon Studio [5 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/angry-demon-studio">Angry Demon Studio</a> announced. <span id="more-903961"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the demo, via Wired Productions:</p><blockquote><p>The free demo features the first level of the game, which was previously only available for PC during the most recent Steam NextFest. Moreover, this is the first time <a title="Platforms > PlayStation [45,648 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation">PlayStation</a> and <a title="Platforms > Switch [15,755 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Nintendo Switch</a> players will have a demo of <em>Gori: Cuddly Carnage</em> on their preferred platforms. This new demo includes visual polish and the addition of enhancements and features including “finishers” on weakened enemies to generate health and energy. “Perfect Dodges” have also been added, where evading at the right time will slow down time momentarily to allow players to move quicker than the enemies.</p><p>The new <em>Gori: Cuddly Carnage</em> demo will be a wild and fun ride, not for the faint of heart. Players can expect even more cat-tastic and ultra-violent third-person hack-and-slash fun when the game launches next month. The game is set in a futuristic neon world, packed with vivid and immersive environments which allows players to perform gnarly acrobatics in a brutal combat experience filled with high-speed action and intense destruction. Gori takes on this world by riding the foul-mouthed death-dealing hoverboard, F.R.A.N.K., slicing and dicing through hordes of zombie-like, mutated toys. It is up to Gori to save the world!</p></blockquote><p><em>Gori: Cuddly Carnage</em> is due out for PlayStation 5, Xbox Series, PlayStation 4, Xbox One, Switch, and PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1299690/Gori_Cuddly_Carnage/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> on August 29.</p><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <h2><span>Demo Launch Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Gori: Cuddly Carnage | Demo Release Trailer ESRB" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/JlkMnaCIO_I?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dishonored Co-Creator's Next Game Should Make Fans Very Happy--And You Can Help]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/dishonored-co-creators-next-game-should-make-fans-very-happy-and-you-can-help/1100-6525626/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dishonored-co-creators-next-game-should-make-fans-very-happy-and-you-can-help.947874/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/dishonored-co-creators-next-game-should-make-fans-very-happy-and-you-can-help/1100-6525626/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6525626">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>After leaving Arkane Studios, Dishonored co-creator Raf Colantonio founded Wolfeye Studios and the company released the isometric immersive sim Weird West, but Wolfeye is now doing something that fans may like even more. Production has begun on a new first-person action-RPG with a retro-sci-fi aesthetic, and Dishonored (and Prey) fans can help shape development.</p><p>The still-untitled game, which just finished its pre-production phase, looks to draw heavily on the old-but-new technology seen in games like Dishonored, with huge automatons visible in concept art that Wolfeye shared alongside the announcement. Wolfeye says it's a brand-new IP that will be "built upon the DNA of earlier Arkane games to deliver a rich and detailed world, freedom of how to play, and a deep RPG experience."</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1597/15971423/4347482-final_canyon_8k.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4347482" data-ratio="0.56249153689912" data-width="7385" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1597/15971423/4347482-final_canyon_8k.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4347482"></a><figcaption>Don't look down.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1597/15971423/4347482-final_canyon_8k.jpg"></figure><figure data-embed-type="gallery" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1597/15971423/4347502-final_drone_8k.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1597/15971423/4347504-final_workshop_8k.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4347502,1300-4347504" data-resize-urls="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1597/15971423/4347502-final_drone_8k.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1597/15971423/4347504-final_workshop_8k.jpg"><p>Gallery</p>     <img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1597/15971423/4347502-final_drone_8k.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1597/15971423/4347504-final_workshop_8k.jpg"></figure><p>With Dishonored studio Arkane Austin shuttered by Microsoft, that may make Wolfeye's game its spiritual successor, and Colantonio is confident in the team's vision--but he also values your input. A sign-up form for a chance to get into a limited alpha test is available on the <a href="http://www.wolfeye-studios.com/signup" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">studio's website</a>.</p><p>"Fans of the past games I have been involved with such as Dishonored and Prey will feel at home, as well as fans of RPGs in general," he added. "While we look for the right publishing partner, our sights are firmly set on getting our community involved with the game's development with a limited private alpha in 2025. We cannot wait for fans to see what we are working on."</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>