<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 15:06:36 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Story of Seasons Studio Marvelous Changes Leadership Due to Poor Performance]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/marvelous-story-of-seasons-leadership-change</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/story-of-seasons-studio-marvelous-changes-leadership-due-to-poor-performance.1098648/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/marvelous-story-of-seasons-leadership-change<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Marvelous, the studio behind franchises like&nbsp;<em>Story of Seasons&nbsp;</em>(formerly&nbsp;<em>Harvest Moon</em>) and&nbsp;<em>Rune Factory</em>, has announced a change in leadership owing to its poor financial performance over the last nine months.</p>

<p>Per an Automaton Media <a href="https://automaton-media.com/en/news/rune-factory-developer-marvelous-announces-change-in-leadership-and-executive-pay-cuts-due-to-companys-recent-weak-performance/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">report</a>, the studio recently published its financial results for the first three quarters of the 2024-25 fiscal year, and sales and net profit are both down (by 4.8% and 12.4% respectively) when compared to the same period last year.</p>

<p>As a result, current CEO Sato Suminobu will step down from his position in March, although he'll remain a director at the company. He'll be replaced as company CEO by Shinichi Terui, who's currently serving as an executive director at Marvelous.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/marvelous-leadership-change-poor-performance-farmagia.jpg?itok=lLnr2z0q 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/marvelous-leadership-change-poor-performance-farmagia.jpg?itok=FshC_X8D 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Games like November's&nbsp;<em>Farmagia&nbsp;</em>failed to make enough of a dent to improve Marvelous' finances, it seems.</figcaption></figure><p>In the <a href="https://gamebiz.jp/news/400065" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Gamebiz</a> report that Automaton cites (for which we're using machine translation), it also sounds as though both Sato and Terui will receive 10% pay cuts, although Automaton says these cuts will apply to "two full-time executives" rather than the two named employees.</p>

<p>As Automaton points out, Marvelous released two major projects in the nine-month period between April and December 2024, namely farming RPG&nbsp;<em>Farmagia&nbsp;</em>and a re-release of the remake of&nbsp;<em>Story of Seasons: Friends of Mineral Town</em>.</p>

<p>The latter, according to Marvelous, performed "steadily", but there's no indication as to how the former did. Given the change in leadership and&nbsp;<em>Farmagia</em>'s <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2508770/Farmagia/#app_reviews_hash" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">terminally low Steam review count</a>, however, it's unlikely the game sold particularly well.</p>

<p>It is worth noting that a new&nbsp;<em>Rune Factory&nbsp;</em>game,&nbsp;<em>Rune Factory: Guardians of Azuma</em>, is <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/rune-factory-guardians-of-azuma-release-date" rel="nofollow">coming in May</a>, but since Marvelous' financial year ends in March, the game won't be released in time for it to affect the studio's 2024-25 fiscals.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/rune-factory-guardians-of-azuma-marvelous.jpg?itok=iFi4KA4E 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/rune-factory-guardians-of-azuma-marvelous.jpg?itok=1Dld7TmK 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Marvelous is gearing up to release&nbsp;<em>Rune Factory: Guardians of Azuma&nbsp;</em>in March.</figcaption></figure><p>It remains to be seen whether Marvelous' change in leadership will affect how the company operates, as well as whether it'll turn the studio's fortunes around. Stay tuned for more on this and all other things Marvelous.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Civilization VII is all about establishing your unique legacy]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/entertainment/604489/civilization-7-review</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/civilization-vii-is-all-about-establishing-your-unique-legacy.1098645/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/entertainment/604489/civilization-7-review<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Sid Meier developed the first <em>Civilization</em> game in 1991 and has contributed to every iteration since. When I visited Firaxis Games last year, I saw that the company maintains the very computer Meier used to develop the game, which can still be booted up and played. Walking through the halls of the studio, I saw not only the legacy of its games but its employees, too, some of whom have children who work or worked at Firaxis, including Meier’s own son. It’s no wonder, then, that <a href="https://www.theverge.com/24224489/civilization-7-hands-on-demo-impressions-firaxis-games"><em>Civilization VII</em> is a game about legacy</a> and all the ways it leaves a mark on history and contributes to the future.</p><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/8/20/24224532/civilization-7-release-date-february-2025"><em>Civilization VII</em></a> is a strategy game in which you shepherd a country or people plucked from throughout world history through the ages of time. As their leader, often a famous ruler or notable historical figure, your job is to grow your empire to become the preeminent society of the world either through conquest, commerce, culture, or scientific advancement. As time progresses, you must make choices and take actions for your civilization that determine how it develops into a world power. You must acquire resources, choose systems of government and social policy, research technologies to improve your civilization, defend it from threats, and keep your citizenry happy.</p><p>One way legacy manifests in <em><em>Civilization</em> VII</em> is through the game’s new civ and leader system. In previous games, choosing a leader locked you into a particular civilization. Now, a civ and a leader are chosen independently of one another. Caesar Augustus is no longer tied to Rome but can now be the pharaoh of Egypt or the king of Spain. Since the Roman Empire is my Roman Empire, I really enjoy this change. Augustus ruled an empire that encompassed Europe and North Africa, so it makes historical and narrative sense that he can lead the civilizations of those geographic locations. </p><p>But beyond the little thrill my historian heart gets from pairing Augustus with Gaul… err <em>France</em>, the new system is simply a way to give players more flexibility. You don’t have to abandon a favored leader just because you don’t want to play as their civ for the umpteenth time, and the game even has a recommendation system that matches leaders with civs that synergize with their abilities.</p><p>Perhaps the most profound example of legacy in <em><em><em>Civilization</em> VII</em></em> is the way civilizations transition between historical ages. Whereas a player’s civilization stayed the same throughout a game before, now, as you move between antiquity to the exploration age and the exploration age to the modern age, your civilization changes as well, evolving with history. Like Augustus and Egypt, it makes sense. Civilizations rise, fall, and change with the march of time. Depending on the choices you make and policies you pursue, yours will, too.</p><p>I started my game playing as the Mississippi empire of North America. Throughout the game, I had the choice of pursuing the goals of one of four advisers, each with their own sphere of influence: economic, military, culture, or science. They gave me quests to complete, like establish a certain number of cities or acquire different luxury resources. Since the Mississippi is a commerce and trade-focused civ, I chose the economic quests, and when it was time to transition to a new age, that choice unlocked more advanced economic-focused civilizations. It’s a really interesting, game mechanic version of that one <em>Gladiator</em> quote, “What we do now, echoes in eternity.” My Mississippi empire fell away and the Majapahit emerged in its place.</p><p>But legacy can also be complicated and difficult to navigate if you don’t understand the history it comes from. (Yes, I’m stretching this metaphor, but indulge me.) <em>Civilization V</em> is the only <em>Civ</em> I’ve played logging hundreds of hours, and going into <em>VII</em>, I’m kinda lost on some things. There’s an entire system that runs concurrently to the overall game, in which I have to figure out optimal building placement in my cities, taking into consideration things like “adjacency bonuses” and “specialist allocation” that I just do not understand after 20 hours. Reading the game’s prolific Civilopedia helps a little, but even that is so confusingly worded (and wordy!) that I’ve given up on trying to make sense of it. There are a lot of times when I make a choice with no strategy behind it because I simply have not figured out what’s going on. I get the feeling the whole system was put in place for players who like to min / max the hell out of their civs for competitive play, but I am a simple girl. I want to watch numbers go up and buy off my enemies with my massive piles of gold. </p><p>That’s worked out well for me. My civ is very wealthy and very well liked by my AI opponents, despite not totally understanding everything going on. There’s a level of satisfaction in slowly overcoming that learning curve that keeps me playing for “one more turn.” In a game of <em>Civilization VII,</em> some players will leave a legacy of conquest — others of inspiring cultural works. But the legacy I leave behind will be one of excellent civil engineering.</p><p><em>Civilization VII</em> launches on February 11th on PC, PlayStation, Xbox, and Switch.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fortnite Will Get More DC Collabs After Multiversus Shutdown, It’s Claimed]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-will-get-more-dc-collabs-after-multiversus-shutdown-its-claimed/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fortnite-will-get-more-dc-collabs-after-multiversus-shutdown-it%E2%80%99s-claimed.1098639/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-will-get-more-dc-collabs-after-multiversus-shutdown-its-claimed/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>A known Fortnite insider has claimed that DC collabs for Fortnite will increase after Multiversus has been shut down.&nbsp;</p>



<p>ShiinaBR, known for Fortnite leaks and rumours, <a href="https://x.com/ShiinaBR/status/1885376822830932335" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">spoke about</a> Warner Bros.’s “new tactic” for DC in gaming after Multiversus was discontinued. The insider revealed that due to Multiversus, DC had stopped collaborating with other games. However, since the title has announced its shutdown, its new strategy is to “double down on collabs with other games again,” this list includes Epic’s popular battle royale, Fortnite.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Fortnite has always had DC skins, but the collaboration is nowhere near how they have partnered with Marvel, with the latter getting new skins with each new movie or series. Fortnite already has some iconic DC skins, such as the Joker, Superman, Wonder Woman, Batman (multiple variants of him), and other heroes and villains. However, players would like to see a Fortnite season themed around the DC universe, especially with James Gunn and Peter Safran’s new DCEU.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Multiversus <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/multiversus-is-officially-shutting-down/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">announced</a> its official shutdown last week, with the game’s fifth season serving as the final update for the game. The last time to play Multiversus online will be May 30. After that, the game can only be accessed through the local gameplay mode, which allows you to fight solo against AI opponents or with up to three friends.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In other news, Fortnite Festival is seemingly bringing <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-festival-sabrina-carpenter/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Sabrina Carpenter</a> next season. Also, the game might receive <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-will-receive-red-hulk-falcon-and-superman-skins-its-claimed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Red Hulk, Falcon, and Superman skins</a> next. What are your thoughts on Fortnite receiving more DC content after Multiversus is shutting down?&nbsp;Let us know in the comments below or on our&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-labs-leaked/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">‘Battlefield Labs’, a new community test environment for Battlefield</a>,&nbsp;and don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Civilization VII review: A major overhaul solves Civ’s oldest problems]]></title>
            <link>https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/02/civilization-vii-review-a-major-overhaul-solves-civs-oldest-problems/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/civilization-vii-review-a-major-overhaul-solves-civ%E2%80%99s-oldest-problems.1098636/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/02/civilization-vii-review-a-major-overhaul-solves-civs-oldest-problems/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="app">
    <p><a href="#main">
  Skip to content
</a></p>



<main id="main">
            <article data-id="2073932">
  
  <header>
  <div>
    

    

    <p>
      Not all changes will be popular, but it's a great launching point for a new age.
    </p>

    

    <div id="caption-2074083">
    
    <p>
      One of the sprawling cities of <em>Civilization VII</em>.

              <span>
          Credit:

          
          Samuel Axon

                  </span>
          </p>
  </div>

    <div>
    
    <p>
      One of the sprawling cities of <em>Civilization VII</em>.

              <span>
          Credit:

          
          Samuel Axon

                  </span>
          </p>
  </div>
  </div>
</header>


  

  
      
    
    <div>
                      
                      
          
<p>There’s a lot of talk of cozy games these days, and Civilization is definitely my personal cozy game. It’s relaxing to get lost in a flow state, making “<a href="https://gdcvault.com/play/1015756/Interesting">a series of interesting decisions</a>” for “<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XnRrTEFZs60">one more turn</a>,” then another, late into the evening.</p>
<p>Change is almost definitionally not cozy, though, and <em>Civilization VII</em> changes quite a lot —especially about the game’s overall structure.</p>
<p>Frankly, I’ve long felt the series peaked with <em>Civilization IV</em>, at least for me. But after playing <em>VII</em> for a couple of dozen hours, there’s a chance it’s at least as good as <em>Civilization V</em>, and it has the potential to even match <em>IV</em> with just a little more refinement.</p>
<p>In this review, we’ll explore all the major changes, assess whether they are worth any trade-offs, and talk about why <em>VII</em> has the potential to be the best Civ game in recent memory.</p>
<p><span>Table of Contents</span>

  
</p>

<h2>A specific kind of Civ player</h2>
<p>Civilization is a franchise that caters to a broad range of players, and different people want different things from the games. It makes sense to clarify what kind of Civilization player I am so you know where I’m coming from and what kind of filter to run my take through.</p>
<p>I’ve played at least a few games of Civilization a year since <em>Civilization II</em> came out. All told, I probably have a cumulative 2,000 hours in the franchise. I skipped <em>Civilization III</em>, and I played the most in the <em>Civilization IV</em> era, when I played weekly hotseat games with my friends in college. I frequently played the 1,000 AD scenario solo. I continued to play <em>Civilization V</em>, but a little less than <em>IV</em>. When <em>Civilization VI</em> came out, I wasn’t as big a fan. I’ve played maybe two full games a year after an initial 50 or so hours when it first arrived.</p>
<p>I’ve usually played on low to mid difficulty levels and have enjoyed the inevitable march to victory. I did work my way up through the difficulty levels in <em>V</em> while Steam achievement-hunting, but I didn’t enjoy it as much as taking a relaxed approach.</p>

          
                      
                  </div>
                    
        
          
    
    <div>
          
          
<p>I’ve spent comparatively little time playing other 4X games. I had a couple of weeks where I got really into <em>Endless Legend</em>, but it didn’t stick long-term. I played a lot of <em>Master of Orion II</em> back in the day, but I’ve only played a couple dozen hours of <em>Stellaris</em>. I did, however, obsessively play <em>Alpha Centauri</em>. I also love <em>The Battle of Polytopia</em>.</p>
<p>If <em>VI</em> was your favorite Civ game, if you always play on Deity, or if you’re a hardcore player who plays 5,000 hours a year, just know that I’m coming at this from a different place than you are. I hope you can still filter through that and find the information you need here, though.</p>
<p>This review is based on two full-length playthroughs of all three ages of <em>Civilization VII</em>, plus a little extra dabbling—a total of about 35 hours. I mostly played on a Windows PC, but I also tested the game briefly on a Steam Deck. The Mac, Linux, and console versions were not made available to me.</p>
<p>Let’s dig in.</p>
<h2>The ages of civilization</h2>
<p><em>Civilization VII</em> overhauls the structure of a Civilization game more radically than we’ve ever seen. Whereas previous games had “eras” (Ancient, Classical, Medieval, Renaissance, Industrial, Modern, Atomic, Information, and Future in <em>VI</em>) that acted as a soft structure for how the game progressed, <em>VII</em> cuts everything down to just three and names them “ages”—Antiquity, Exploration, and Modern.</p>
<p>(This is not to be confused with the boom/bust system of the dark and golden ages in <em>VI</em>.)</p>
<figure>
    
          <figcaption>
        <div>
    
    <p>
      As in earlier titles, exploring with scouts plays a big role in the first age.

              <span>
          Credit:

          
          Samuel Axon

                  </span>
          </p>
  </div>
      </figcaption>
      </figure>

<p>But unlike the eras of yore, <em>VII</em>’s ages are presented and play almost as distinct games. Ages do not just mark the passage of time; transitioning from one to another involves significant changes to the map and objectives in the game, with a summary screen displayed during each transition.</p>
<p>Each age has its own tech and culture trees, buildings and units, and even unique victory conditions and game systems. For example, the system of spreading religions around the globe with missionaries and tracking the religious makeup of cities is exclusive to Exploration, even though there are some more basic applications of religion in Antiquity.</p>

          
                  </div>
                    
        
          
    
    <div>
          
          

<h3>Legacy paths</h3>
<p>Each age has its own “legacy paths” corresponding to the different victory types: economic, military, science, and culture. These paths include a sequence of objectives that must be fulfilled to gain points that are tallied at the end of the age to determine rankings and decide which options you have for bonuses to start with if you continue to the next age.</p>
<p>For example, the science legacy path in Exploration involves using specialists (urban population who build up the yields of tiles that have already been developed) to optimize city districts with very high yields, whereas the path in Modern involves using city production to build major flight and spaceflight projects.</p>
<p>All players transition from one age to another at once when enough progress has accumulated (either in just one path or all of them). The final legacy path, for Modern, is the path to the game’s ultimate win conditions.</p>
<div>
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 40 40"><defs><clipPath id="arrow-blocks-right_svg__a"><path fill="none" d="M0 0h40v40H0z"></path></clipPath></defs><g fill="currentColor" clip-path="url(#arrow-blocks-right_svg__a)"><path d="M32 16h8v8h-8zm-8 8h8v8h-8zm-8 8h8v8h-8zm8-24h8v8h-8zm-8-8h8v8h-8zM0 16h16v8H0z"></path></g></svg>

    <p><span>Legacy paths map to victory conditions and give you a linear series of objectives with which you can gain points that assist you in starting the next age with an advantage.</span>
                    <span>
                      Samuel Axon
                  </span>
          </p>
  </div>

<p>As an age nears its end, a “crisis” can happen that affects everyone. In one example, the plague begins to spread around the world toward the end of Exploration. Each crisis has some unique gameplay elements, including “crisis cards,” which force you to pick between some negative effects for your civilization to face as you tackle the problem.</p>
<p>After an age is complete, the crisis ends, a recap screen is shown, and you get to spend “legacy points” (which you accumulated by following the legacy paths) to gain bonuses or choose specializations for your civilization that apply when you start the next age.</p>
<p>You also pick a new civilization for the next age, which brings us to the other major overhaul to the game’s formula.</p>
<h3>Leaders and civilizations</h3>
<p>As in all prior titles, you select a leader to play as when you start a new game, and that leader has unique bonuses or mechanics that affect how you would optimally play the game.</p>

          
                  </div>
                    
        
          
    
    <div>
          
          
<p>But whereas leaders were tied to specific civilizations before, now they’re not. You can play as Benjamin Franklin, King of Persia. Those concerned with historical accuracy won’t love this change, though the developer clearly designed the leaders to have some mechanical synergy with historically appropriate civilizations; these pairings are even given special labeling in the civilization-selection screen.</p>
<p>When an age transition happens, though, you have to pick a completely new civilization—but not just any. Several factors contribute to the list of options. The civilization you picked and which things you accomplished in the previous age make up the bulk of those factors. Again, the game nudges you toward civs that make loose sense historically (I went from Isabella leading Rome in Antiquity to Isabella leading Spain in Exploration), but it’s possible in some cases to do something different.</p>


<p>This fits a general theme in <em>Civilization VII</em> of modeling the way cultures and cities in our own world are built in layers. For example, London was a Roman city before the Anglo-Saxons and Vikings built their own settlements on top of it.</p>
<p>To that point, you can "overbuild" buildings relevant in later ages to replace ones that were specific to an earlier age, which not-so-coincidentally helps solve the problem from <em>VI </em>of having to work around legacy decisions when working on optimizing your districts.</p>

<h3>Does it work, and is it still Civ?</h3>
<p>This controversial change to civilizations allows the game’s designers to better fine-tune civilizations’ bonuses, units, and buildings. Since they can be age-specific, they can tie deeply into mechanics that are endemic to a specific age. It also addresses the franchise’s long-standing balance problem of certain civilizations having an advantage in one part of a game’s trajectory but being weak in another.</p>
<p>Likewise, putting strong guardrails around each of the three ages allows the designers to better refine and balance certain gameplay systems to interact with each other better. It’s much easier to design a system that only has to be fun in a certain context than it is to produce one that needs to stay relevant and interesting throughout every phase of the game.</p>

          
                  </div>
                    
        
          
    
    <div>
          
          
<p>It also acts as a catch-up or rubber-banding device. Civilization has long been criticized for the tendency of its games to snowball early. Establishing a lead in the first few eras could sometimes all but guarantee the final outcome, making the back half of the game seem like a pointless exercise to some.</p>
<p>Since the age transitions in <em>VII</em> put all civs on relatively equal footing with regard to tech trees and so on, that’s less of a problem. Of course, there are still the era points to spend to make your successes or failures earlier on more meaningful—they're just not as game-defining.</p>
<p>There are some downsides besides pedantry about historical accuracy, too. Most notably, the last 15 or so turns of an age can be a bit of a bummer.</p>
<p>That’s because buildings and units late in an age’s tech or culture trees end up being mostly irrelevant as a result of the hard reset that happens so soon after you acquire them. I also found myself incentivized to slow my civilization’s progress to delay age transitions to get things optimally set up for the start of the next one, which feels unnatural and unintended.</p>
<h2>RIP busywork</h2>
<p>Amid a number of changes to the civilization formula, another one stands out: workers (called builders in <em>VI</em>) are no more. Instead of directing a unit to build improvements, you do so directly from the city view each time the city grows.</p>
<p>On one hand, this is a simplification at a time when a lot of people want their grand strategy games to get deeper and more complex. But I feel that it’s a good change. Workers always became unwieldy as the scale of your empire grew, and many players just ended up automating them by the later eras.</p>
<p>The change also allows building rural improvements to integrate more neatly with the urban district system introduced in <em>VI</em> and refined here.</p>

          
                  </div>
                    
        
          
    
    <div>
          
          
<div>
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 40 40"><defs><clipPath id="arrow-blocks-right_svg__a"><path fill="none" d="M0 0h40v40H0z"></path></clipPath></defs><g fill="currentColor" clip-path="url(#arrow-blocks-right_svg__a)"><path d="M32 16h8v8h-8zm-8 8h8v8h-8zm-8 8h8v8h-8zm8-24h8v8h-8zm-8-8h8v8h-8zM0 16h16v8H0z"></path></g></svg>

    <p><span>Worker units have been replaced by a centralized city management screen.</span>
                    <span>
                      Samuel Axon
                  </span>
          </p>
  </div>

<p>There are other refinements that reduce unit-based busywork, too. One of the reasons <em>IV</em> is my favorite game in the series is that it’s the last one with “stacks of death,” where you’d pile multiple military units onto one tile and move them as a group.</p>
<p>When stacks of death were replaced by a one-unit-of-each-type-per-hex approach in <em>V</em>, I felt it made moving armies in the late game an infuriatingly tedious process that wasn’t worth the added tactical complexity.</p>
<p>Firaxis has struck an ideal middle ground in <em>VII</em>. You can now pack up to five units into a single-hex-occupying group with a military commander unit. You then just have to move that one unit to the front line before deploying everyone and commanding them individually in battle.</p>
<p>It’s a great change! (Rivers are also fully navigable by naval units, by the way—another change that makes getting around a lot easier.)</p>
<h2>Small town, big city</h2>
<p>I mentioned that you now manage hex improvements via the city view. There are some other changes to cities to cover. First off, newly founded settlements start as towns, not cities. Towns can’t produce buildings or units normally, but you can purchase a subset of options with gold.</p>
<p>They grow by similar rules to cities, and they have multiple specialization options that customize how they benefit your wider civilization. You can spend gold to convert them to cities, and it costs less gold to do so the more they grow. There are pros and cons to each classification, and you’ll almost always end up going with a balance, regardless of the age.</p>
<p>There’s a settlement limit that is affected by ages, cultures, and technologies. Capturing or founding towns or cities beyond that limit comes with big penalties and is almost never worth it.</p>

          
                  </div>
                    
        
          
    
    <div>
          
          
<div>
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 40 40"><defs><clipPath id="arrow-blocks-right_svg__a"><path fill="none" d="M0 0h40v40H0z"></path></clipPath></defs><g fill="currentColor" clip-path="url(#arrow-blocks-right_svg__a)"><path d="M32 16h8v8h-8zm-8 8h8v8h-8zm-8 8h8v8h-8zm8-24h8v8h-8zm-8-8h8v8h-8zM0 16h16v8H0z"></path></g></svg>

    <p><span>City tiles sprawl out across the map. In this case, we have a Los Angeles-like situation where a sort of megalopolis has formed out of several cities growing into each other.</span>
                    <span>
                      Samuel Axon
                  </span>
          </p>
  </div>

<p>All told, I liked these systems. They’re big changes, but they feel natural. I wouldn’t tweak much about them.</p>
<p>This “towns” classification is also relevant to what used to be known as city-states. Barbarians and city-states have merged into one concept, called independents. These are single-settlement AI civs that are either hostile or friendly. I really enjoyed this system, as it allowed me to gradually befriend independents, convert them into towns I control through diplomacy, and ultimately upgrade them to cities within my civilization. It’s a satisfying progression.</p>
<p>You court independent settlements by spending a new yield called influence, which is the foundation of a significant overhaul of how diplomacy and espionage work in the game.</p>

<h2>How to win friends and influence people</h2>
<p>I hated the way diplomacy and war weariness worked in <em>VI</em>, especially at launch. I felt that the AI was hyper-focused on baiting me into wars, and if I ever responded in kind, it was too difficult to avoid all the AI leaders turning on me because they didn’t like what I was doing. Often, I would just ignore diplomacy and end up at war with almost everyone rather than engage with the systems the game had in place for managing all that.</p>
<p><em>VII</em>’s approach is much more straightforward. As noted, there’s a new yield called influence, and it sits alongside gold, science, and so on. It’s produced passively by certain buildings and the like. It has multiple uses, but all of them relate to affecting your relationships with other powers on the map.</p>
<p>You can use it to build favor with independent cities, levy their troops, or ultimately bring them into your civilization. You can use it to offer trade deals to or denounce other rulers. It’s also the resource used for espionage, like stealing technologies or sabotaging space race production.</p>

          
                  </div>
                    
        
          
    
    <div>
          
          
<p>That’s not where it stops, though. When other leaders offer you a deal of some kind, you’re given the option to spend a small amount of influence to prevent the deal from happening, no influence to accept the deal on terms that are slightly more beneficial for them, or a larger amount of influence to shift the terms of the deal to be significantly better for both of you.</p>


<p>Most critically, it plays a role in a system of war support. When a war occurs between two civilizations, every leader in the game (not just those two) can spend influence to support one side or another. The side with the most support suffers significantly less war weariness and fewer diplomatic consequences for the continuation of the war.</p>
<p>If you have high influence yields and pour it all into supporting a war that’s important to you strategically, you can put yourself in a much better position.</p>
<p>It works extremely well, and it simplifies a lot of disparate systems that have been tried in Civ over the years into one coherent thing that’s much easier to understand and manage than ever before.</p>
<p>Of all the major additions in <em>Civilization VII</em>, this is my favorite. For the first time, I find diplomacy fun instead of a chore.</p>
<h2>Grab bag: Steam Deck, minor gripes, and hopes for the future</h2>
<p>Those are the big categories of changes in <em>VII</em>, but there are a few things of note that don’t neatly fit into any of these buckets, so let’s rapid-fire through a few.</p>
<h3>Steam Deck, consoles, and controller support</h3>
<p>Consoles have always been a footnote in the Civilization franchise’s storied history. There was <em>Civilization Revolution</em>, a stripped-down version of the game that came out on Xbox 360 and PlayStation 3. (It was better than you’d think if you approached it on its own terms, but it wasn’t the desktop PC Civ experience by any stretch.)</p>

          
                  </div>
                    
        
          
    
    <div>
          
          
<p><em>Civilization VI</em> got ports for Xbox One, PlayStation 4, and Switch, but the ports were not very good at all. The game was playable, but the ports were definitely an afterthought.</p>
<p>So it’s interesting that <em>Civilization VII</em> will have PlayStation 4, PlayStation 5, Xbox One, Xbox Series X|S, and Nintendo Switch versions launching the same day as the PC, Mac, and Linux ones. Along with that, the game is Steam Deck Verified—which wasn’t even a concept when the last Civ game came out.</p>
<p>I wasn’t given access to the console versions during this review period, but I was able to try it out on Steam Deck, which gave me a sense of how it plays with a controller interface.</p>
<p>The left stick moves between tiles to select, while the right stick moves the camera and changes the zone the left stick effects. You tap A to select something and B to back out, while the left and right triggers can be used to zoom in and out. Pressing the right bumper brings up a radial menu that gives you access to everything from the tech tree to different leaders with whom you can engage in diplomacy. The remaining buttons are direct shortcuts to commonly used features, like mini-map options (yields and so on).</p>
<figure>
    
          <figcaption>
        <div>
    
    <p><em>Civilization VII</em> running on the Steam Deck.

              <span>
          Credit:

          
          Samuel Axon

                  </span>
          </p>
  </div>
      </figcaption>
      </figure>

<p>It works pretty well! It’s not as natural as using a mouse, of course, but it’s a big improvement on the mess that the console versions of <em>VI</em> presented you.</p>

<p>The game seemed to perform OK most of the time on low settings and the native 1280×800 resolution on the Steam Deck, but the exception was zooming in on large, sprawling cities in the late game. I saw some stutters and framerate chugging in that situation. That’s not a game-breaking problem in a turn-based game, but it's annoying. It's possible that more performance optimization will come later.</p>

          
                  </div>
                    
        
          
    
    <div>
          
          
<p>The performance is inconsistent enough to give me pause about recommending playing on Steam Deck; you’re probably better off using your laptop to play when you’re traveling. That said, the controller configuration (which is also an option on PC, by the way) is good enough that I’m optimistic about the PS5 and Xbox Series X|S versions. It's hard to imagine the game running well on the Switch, though, given that the much more powerful Steam Deck barely squeaks through.</p>
<h3>UI bugs aplenty at launch</h3>
<p>I believe the version I’m playing right now is the day-one release version (or close to it), so it’s worth mentioning I’ve run into some annoying UI bugs.</p>
<p>For example:</p>
<ul>
<li>I have to click several times to get it to register, or sometimes deselect and re-select the unit, to make ranged military units fire on units in other hexes.</li>
<li>In one game, I just could not create trade routes. I'd select the merchant, click on the target city, and nothing would happen. It's possible this was not a bug and that there was instead some reason in the game's mechanics for why I couldn't do it at this stage that I didn't understand, but there was no feedback about why it wasn't working.</li>
<li>There are some instances (like in the religion panel) where mouse wheel scrolling simultaneously scrolled the list in the panel while also zooming the map view behind it.</li>
</ul>
<p>This is the sort of stuff that will almost surely be fixed quickly, but it’s good to be aware if you’re planning on playing on launch day.</p>
<h3>Some of the balance is a little wonky</h3>
<p>As is the case for all games like this, there are a few systems that will need some post-launch refinement. Most notably, the balance between building units or buildings with gold versus production feels way off. By around the middle of the Exploration Age, I found myself using gold to purchase things far more than I bothered waiting on production. You just have too much gold in the late game. I imagine Firaxis will rein this in.</p>

          
                  </div>
                    
        
          
    
    <div>
          
          
<h3>Launch content is light</h3>
<p><em>Civilization VII</em> offers arguably the most complexity, depth, and breadth of systems of any Civilization game pre-expansion. That’s great! Yeah, there are some standards missing I imagine might come in expansions later, like the World Congress or nukes. But compared to earlier games, there’s more here on day one than usual.</p>
<p>That said, the actual content is pretty bare-bones. There aren’t a ton of leaders right now—though many more are planned within just a few months, according to Firaxis’ roadmap.</p>
<p>More critically, there are no scenarios at all, and there’s no mention of scenarios in the roadmap. Scenarios were always some of my favorite experiences in prior games, so that’s a disappointment. I hope Firaxis announces some plans on this front soon and that we won’t have to wait for a paid expansion to get something that has usually been part of the core of earlier titles.</p>
<p>There are some additions in this iteration that weren't there before to make the game stickier and reward long-term play, though. For example, completing an age with a specific leader levels them up, granting access to modifier cards you can use on future games with that leader. These aren't enough to make them radically more powerful; they're more like small extra tweaks to make it worth revisiting them. There's also a large library of challenges to complete.</p>
<figure>
    
          <figcaption>
        <div>
    
    <p>
      You can earn mementos by leveling your leaders up while playing; these can be used to grant modest gameplay modifiers for future games or ages.

              <span>
          Credit:

          
          Samuel Axon

                  </span>
          </p>
  </div>
      </figcaption>
      </figure>

<p>Also, multiplayer is pretty bare-bones feature-wise at launch, but Firaxis says it's planning on addressing that within a few weeks.</p>
<h3>You can’t rename your cities</h3>
<p>I am afraid to even write this out because it seems like such a glaringly obvious omission that I almost assume I’m just an idiot and haven’t been able to find the right thing to click. But I’ve looked and looked, and I’m pretty sure you can’t rename cities at all. That’s very perplexing.</p>

          
                  </div>
                    
        
          
    
    <div>

        
        <div>
          
          

<h2>A new age</h2>
<p>Change might not be cozy, but some of these changes have made a meaningful difference in countering Civilization's longest-standing frustrations—late-game fatigue, snowballing, and frustrating diplomacy, among other things.</p>
<p>If you're coming to Civilization with historical accuracy in mind, the divorce between leaders and civilizations will bug you. I will remind you, though, that this is a game infamous for Gandhi warmongering with nuclear weapons, so that's not new. (Notably, Gandhi is not a leader in <em>Civilization VII</em>, though I had an amusingly similar situation with Harriet Tubman taking a violent, scorched-earth approach to diplomacy.)</p>
<p>It's worth it, though, because it expands the strategic depth of the game while also addressing some classic balance problems.</p>
<p>Firaxis has added significantly more structure to Civilization here. The game is not as sandbox-y as previous versions of the game, as objectives within ages are much more clearly articulated. Fortunately, it drops the arbitrary objectives that dominated <em>VI</em> in that game's eureka and dark/golden age systems, so I feel it's a happy medium.</p>
<p>It was always going to be a challenge to make yet another Civilization game while retaining the guts that have been around for 34 years. Even though the structural changes are arguably radical, I believe they have more justification and upside than the ones we saw in <em>VI</em>, making <em>VII</em> feel like a return to form.</p>
<p>Systems-wise, <em>Civilization VII</em> is the most complete pre-expansion package we've seen in a long time. There are plenty of refinements and additions I'd like to see, but my general impressions are positive. This is still the best recent 4X game out there.</p>
<p>Let's see if future expansions and mod support have the potential to make it the best Civilization yet. It's not there yet, but there's ample reason to hope.</p>
<h3>The good</h3>
<ul>
<li>The ages system helps to solve many longstanding problems with the overall arc of a Civilization game</li>
<li>Influence yield makes diplomacy better than it's ever been</li>
<li>Tweaks and additions turn building city districts into the full realization of what <em>VI</em> was hinting at but never achieved</li>
<li>The visual presentation is excellent, with sprawling, intricate cities and detailed leaders</li>
<li>Several additions streamline annoying busywork the franchise is known for without curtailing depth</li>
</ul>
<h3>The bad</h3>
<ul>
<li>Content is light even though systems are robust; there are no scenarios at all</li>
<li>The final few turns of an age end up feeling wonky</li>
<li>You can't rename your cities for some reason</li>
</ul>
<h3>The ugly</h3>
<ul>
<li>Some launch-window bugs and other issues might make it worth waiting a few weeks before digging in</li>
</ul>


          
                  </div>

                  
          






  <div>
    

    <p>
      Samuel Axon is a senior editor at Ars Technica. He covers Apple, software development, gaming, AI, entertainment, and mixed reality. He has been writing about gaming and technology for nearly two decades at Engadget, PC World, Mashable, Vice, Polygon, Wired, and others. He previously ran a marketing and PR agency in the gaming industry, led editorial for the TV network CBS, and worked on social media marketing strategy for Samsung Mobile at the creative agency SPCSHP. He also is an independent software and game developer for iOS, Windows, and other platforms, and he&nbsp;is a graduate of DePaul University, where he studied interactive media and software development.
    </p>
  </div>


  <p>
    <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/02/civilization-vii-review-a-major-overhaul-solves-civs-oldest-problems/#comments" title="16 comments">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 80 80"><defs><clipPath id="bubble-zero_svg__a"><path fill="none" stroke-width="0" d="M0 0h80v80H0z"></path></clipPath><clipPath id="bubble-zero_svg__b"><path fill="none" stroke-width="0" d="M0 0h80v80H0z"></path></clipPath></defs><g clip-path="url(#bubble-zero_svg__a)"><g fill="currentColor" clip-path="url(#bubble-zero_svg__b)"><path d="M80 40c0 22.09-17.91 40-40 40S0 62.09 0 40 17.91 0 40 0s40 17.91 40 40"></path><path d="M40 40 .59 76.58C-.67 77.84.22 80 2.01 80H40z"></path></g></g></svg>
    16 Comments
  </a>
      </p>
              </div>
  </article>


  


  


  


  

  </main>





  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Big Helmet Heroes Review]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/02/03/big-helmet-heroes-review/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/big-helmet-heroes-review.1098621/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/02/03/big-helmet-heroes-review/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="gp-content-wrapper">

	<article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/Article">

		<meta itemprop="mainEntityOfPage" itemtype="https://schema.org/WebPage" itemscope="" content="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/02/03/big-helmet-heroes-review/">
		<meta itemprop="headline" content="Big Helmet Heroes Review">			
		
		<meta itemprop="author" content="Adrian Burrows">			
		<meta itemprop="datePublished" content="2025-02-03">
		<meta itemprop="dateModified" content="2025-02-03">
		
		
			
		
								
		
			

																		
		<div itemprop="text">
			
			<p>Do you remember <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2019/03/20/castle-crashers-remastered-heads-to-switch-and-playstation-4/">Castle Crashers</a>? Well, the developers of Big Helmet Heroes certainly do, as their game bears an uncanny resemblance to The Behemoth’s 2D side-scrolling shiny knight classic. Indeed, Big Helmet Heroes could well be Castle Crashers 2, only this time with bland 3D visuals replacing the charming hand-drawn aesthetic of The Behemoth’s finest. Oh, there’s one other noticeable difference between the two games I’m afraid; unlike Castle Crashers, Big Helmet Heroes isn’t very good.</p>
<p><iframe title="Big Helmet Heroes - Release Date Trailer | PS5 Games" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rreierpDUas?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Big Helmet Heroes certainly starts off promisingly enough, your large-bonced knight – and one other pal in local co-op – trundle from left to right, hacking up Medieval-themed minions. It’s your standard side-scrolling beat ‘em up fare, though with a couple of neat additions. As you hack and slash through lava filled labyrinths, foreboding castles, neon-soaked amusement arcades, and atop an enormous electric guitar – yes, really – you’ll rescue other Big Helmeted Heroes who can be added to your team for that level. This enables you to switch out characters, your tagged-out warrior gaining health as they rest on the sidelines. A well-timed swap out is vital to reach the end of later levels, demanding close monitoring of your various hero’s health levels. Admittedly, this doesn’t add much to the proceedings, but it’s a little bit of brain that serves to accentuate the lashings of brawn.</p>


<p>In comparison to many of the recent side-scrolling beat ‘em ups I’ve played; there’s also the welcome addition of literally hundreds of amusing over-the-top weapons to pick-up and unleash on your unwitting opponents. You’ll be zapping enemies with electric flyswatters, launching laser beams at them from futuristic space-rifles, and smashing them to oblivion with massive plastic toy hammers. It’s all very fun, silly, and satisfying, exactly as it should be.</p>


<p>Each hero, despite the visual differences, plays pretty much the same, with identikit moves and attack combos. What diversifies them are rather entertaining ultimate attacks that freshen up the never-ending combat. A highlight is summoning a horde of angry sheep to trample your foes beneath their cute chunky hooves; but turning into a giant to stomp puny henchmen and making everyone battle in John Woo slow-mo proved a laugh too. Levels also benefit from a welcome touch of imagination and creativity; at one point the camera switches to a birds-eye view, your knights now tasked with navigating a hay-bale maze. Or there’s a battle at sea which turns into a light-gun shooter for the closing moments, or occasions when the game switches over into a survival mode, enemies attacking in waves whilst you defend your position.</p>
<p>Keeping 2D side-scrolling beat ‘em ups engaging through to their conclusion isn’t a straightforward proposition, they are, through their defining mechanic, deeply repetitive, yet developers Exalted Studio have certainly taken a welcome stab at it.</p>
<p>So, where does it all go wrong? Primarily, Big Helmet Heroes, on PS5 at least, is unbelievably janky. Collision detection is laughable, particularly when it comes to the awfully implemented bosses, with attacks failing to register at all. It’s not just attacks either, the Big Helmet Heroes can’t seem to stay attached to the ground – when navigating bridges or platforms, they’ll just plunge off for no good reason, almost as if the game deliberately steers your player character into an early demise. This issue gets worse and worse as you make your way further into the game, rendering some sections nigh unplayable.</p>

<p>Then there’s the camera, which is broken, failing to show the on-screen action most of the time. All too often you’ll be battling enemies off-screen, the camera demanding it shows you empty environments instead of &nbsp;your player character. The camera is even worse during those aforementioned boss fights, failing to keep up with the action at all. One notable example against a giant octopus was dreadful, my partner and I making it through by button mashing, unable to see what we were doing. Perhaps those Big Helmet Heroes needed even bigger heads? At least that way they might stay on screen.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

			
		</div>

		
				
	<div id="gp-summary">
		<p>Summary</p><p>
		There’s a lot to like about Big Helmet Heroes, it’s a delightfully silly and fun side-scrolling beat ‘em up, but substantial patches are required to fix the game before contemplating a purchase.	</p></div>
		

	<div id="gp-review-results">

									<div id="gp-good-points">
						<p>Good</p>
						<ul>
														
								<li><i></i>Surprisingly inventive levels</li>
														
								<li><i></i>Hugely entertaining weapon pick-ups</li>
														
								<li><i></i>Solidly silly ultimate moves</li>
													</ul>
					</div>
				
									<div id="gp-bad-points">
						<p>Bad</p>
						<ul>
														
								<li><i></i>Terrible collision detection</li>
														
								<li><i></i>Even worse in-game camera</li>
													</ul>
					</div>
							
			</div>

					
	
								
			

			
					
		
					
 
	
	
				
	</article>

</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Civilization VII Review – Just One More Turn]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/review/civilization-vii-one-more-turn/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/civilization-vii-review-%E2%80%93-just-one-more-turn.1098618/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/review/civilization-vii-one-more-turn/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			<div><header>Game Info</header><div><div>
						<h5>Civilization VII</h5><p><span>February 11, 2025</span>
					</p></div><div>
							<h5>Platform</h5><p><span>PC (Windows, macOS, Linux), PlayStation 4, PlayStation 5, Xbox One, Xbox Series S|X, Nintendo Switch</span>
						</p></div></div></div>			
			<p>It seems ridiculous that the last Civilization entry - not including any DLC - came over eight years ago. In the games industry, not being seen for eight years generally means you've been put out to pasture, or more accurately, the money-men have milked you for everything you're worth, and they've gone Ol' Yeller on you. Since I adored Civilization VI, <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/civilization-vi-review-journey/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">giving it a near-perfect score</a>, and my general love of the franchise, I've been understandably excited about Civilization VII as the series comes close to its 35th anniversary.</p>
<p>Having played a few games across over sixty hours, some of which I didn't finish and others of which I achieved a victory, I have some thoughts about Civilization VII. A question that seems to be repeating is, "Why?". Sometimes, it's meant positively; other times, it is not.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Civilization-VII-Review-02-Combat-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>

<p>Civilization VII has made some sweeping changes, some for the better, others for the worse. At least at launch, it doesn't have a grand sandbox feel, arguably the most significant change. That is the first "Why?" This is the most directed Civilization entry ever, partly due to what feels like a shrinking of the game and the inclusion of the age system borrowed from Humankind.</p>
<p>Starting with the map options. You can pick between Tiny, Small, and Average. This gives you a maximum civilisation number of eight in a game. I should point out that, according to my calculations, the map size is roughly the same as that of Civilization VI, though I generally play on larger maps, so I'm not having much luck with this as everything is so compact.</p>
<p>A case in point is the spacing of cities. The AI doesn't seem to mind a lack of optimisation, so despite each city taking up a maximum space of three from the centre, the AI will have some far too close, hindering their chances of growing. With the first campaign I played to the end (winning despite not having finished any of the four paths), I figure there's enough space for a maximum of 70 well-spaced cities (or towns. From here on, when I write cities, I mean cities or towns)</p>
<p>You do have a city cap, which expands over time based on tech and social upgrades you research, but for you to reach that, there's maybe enough space on a map for three civilizations. This is after the advertised "map expansion" as you get to the second age, which isn't a map expansion in any real sense; it was always there; it's just that you don't have the required tech to go over there yet. It also seems that the AI is hamstrung in the second age, as I didn't notice any of them generating treasure fleets - or even trying to make it over to my continent, for that matter.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Civilization-VII-Review-03-Age-Ranking-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>

<p>Let's talk about the Age system. Unlike Humankind, Civilization VII has three ages, compared to seven eras. This is a good decision, as it doesn't split the game up too much. The move from age to age is something I like, with caveats. The ages can be irritating in that they can be too quick. I'm watching the age percentage tick by, and it's probably a good sign that I don't want it to end. I've found myself disappointed and frustrated that it's finished, if only because I haven't been able to make my way down a particular path.</p>
<p>This would be another "why?" for which I have a solution: Don't end an age when one faction has generated enough points across all victory paths; end it when at least one path has been achieved. As Ibn Battuta, I wanted to get the Silk Road victory that takes us to the next generation, but because I happened to do a little in science, I was locked out as I had enough advancement points to move the world ahead. Another example is that I won a whole campaign as Revolutionary Napoleon without achieving a single path across all three ages.</p>
<p>You could argue that this shows flexibility and allows for a jack-of-all-trades style approach. It's also a bit of a blue-ball situation, where I could be close to getting a space race victory to winning because I happened to build a bloody theatre. In my actual save, it was because I took a city. I wish the game were more flexible with this, letting people at least achieve something. It desperately needs an option that enables you to delay the end of an age and another that is essentially a conquest victory from the old games.</p>
<p>The only downside is that you must select some adverse effects as you approach the end of an age—the game calls this a crisis period. How accurate is it that every single age had a world-spanning crisis towards the end? I don't know, but it's the mechanic we have. Now, I wonder if the AI also gets this, because I never see them suffering the same issues as me! This could still be left in if only to disincentivise staying in age for too long when you could click to advance.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Civilization-VII-Review-04-Crisis-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>

<p>This is how the age system and civilisations work in Civilization VII. You pick a leader who lasts throughout the game and then a civilisation from the respective era. You don't have to start in the age of antiquity; you can drop in a game at a later era if wanted, though I think that takes away from the story element that Firaxis is going for. The whole idea is that you are evolving through the ages.</p>
<p>Adding to the feel of this being an evolution, you are restricted to what civilisation you can move to in the following age. Generally speaking, it's based on geography and historical accuracy. However, this can be circumvented by meeting set targets. For example, even as Amina (North African warrior princess), you can unlock the Incas for the following age by having multiple mountains in your cities.</p>
<p>An annoyance with the age system, though, is also that it soft-resets even your empire. I'm not a fan that you can have multiple cities, but - unless you have something to stop this - all bar your capital is reverted to a town, which means you must again pay gold to move it to a city. This can be even if it has the proper expansion, size, and buildings of a city. Parts of the soft reset, to give those behind a chance to be closer again, make sense - but it's a little too much sometimes.</p>
<p>Here's also where I have a bit of a "why?". Now, I've been called "woke" more than a few times, and if you go with the insane notion that believing in equality and acceptance is woke, then so be it. Still, I don't understand the choice of leaders in Civilization VII. I'm far from nationalistic, but we - the British - had the most prominent and influential empire ever. To not have somebody British, and it doesn't have to be militaristic, is insane. Shakespeare for culture, Newton or Darwin for science, Brunel for economics, the options are limitless.</p>
<p>I find that a little more limiting and perplexing when you have multiples of certain leaders: Ashoka (Maurya—India), Frederik (Prussia), Himiko (China), and Xerxes (Persia), plus Napoleon. That's five leaders doubled up to give a slightly different version. I think the omission of Britain, Greece (Alexander the Great?), any Scandinavian country, and some South American leaders or empires, despite their localised nature, is questionable, to say the least. Of course, some or all of these could be already announced DLC that releases close to launch, but that doesn't make the criticism moot.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Civilization-VII-Review-05-Incas-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>

<p>That I've said so much without even going into the finer details of gameplay should say a lot. I will make it simple and say the turn-by-turn play of Civilization VII is fantastic, even if some of the broader elements give me mixed feelings. There is more strategy and planning in this, particularly with city building, thanks to an overhaul of how you build, as each hex that makes part of your city as you expand will be either an urban or rural part of the city.</p>
<p>When you select a hex as the city grows, it becomes a rural part of the city, utilising the available resources on the tile. Each hex can hold up to two regular buildings or one wonder. Each hex is also separate when building city walls, so it will take some time if you have a big city, and location also comes very much into this, as your walls won't be crossing any rivers.</p>
<p>Walls - and other buildings - also can't be built over the "resources" that you can find on certain tiles, so depending on if you have a town, which can't hold every building or a city which can, will determine where you want to build, as these can limit expansion quite significantly. Of course, they are extremely valuable in their own right, significantly boosting development in many ways.</p>
<p>When it comes to rivers, they are probably the most impactful change in navigating Civilization VII. Rivers are now divided into two different types: navigable and non-navigable. Both will take up one hex, but you will be able to tell the difference. The navigable ones act as inland waterways for ships; you can also build on them, having your dock slightly away from the coast. It looks fantastic how the city is built around features like rivers, and having them be used as actual inland waterways is a game-changer for naval manoeuvrability.</p>
<p>In the city building, there is also another feature: overbuilding. As you move into a new age, you will naturally find new tech and buildings. Certain buildings and wonders are there until the end of the game, but a new structure can replace all others. Another thing with the building system is that certain civilisations have unique districts created by building two specific structures on the same hex, giving you an additional bonus. It allows for more tactical and strategic city-building, over-building on the districts introduced in the last entry.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Civilization-VII-Review-06-Over-building-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>

<p>Other new or enhanced features also include natural disasters, which are more localised. Floods, volcanic eruptions, sandstorms, and tornados can and will damage your structures and units. It's hazardous to settle on a reasonably active river, as I found out in my Napoleon campaign - the Tiber tended to floor at least every fifth turn, meaning I found myself paying for repairs far more than I would have liked to. Of course, all of this is controllable by turning them off or up, depending on how masochistic you are.</p>
<p>I've covered other aspects of the settings and the shortcomings of the lack of large maps and open-ended game options, so there's a little to discuss regarding length and difficulty. I haven't found this overly different from other games in the series, with longer games simply adding a multiplier to everything. The only thing I think has seen an improvement with difficulty, and also due to a change in the game, is diplomacy.</p>
<p>Firaxis certainly watched Amplitude and <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/humankind-review/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Humankind</a> regarding some things, and diplomacy is one of them. Diplomacy now uses a new resource called influence, which is also used in your dealings with city-states. The options in diplomacy also feel less easy to game. In most strategy games before, including Civ, it was too easy to bend the AI by simply throwing gold at them, twiddling with the "we like you meter" based on simple input. This doesn't seem as easy now, and the AI's favourability towards you appears to be based more on your longer-term agreements.</p>
<p>If I have a problem with the AI, it's the city-states. Even on the lower difficulties, I find them overly aggressive, and more are unfriendly from the get-go than friendly. It proves to be one of the more limiting factors for early expansion when you've got a random tribe deciding that - even before meeting you - you're the devil spawn and must be destroyed, yet the other civilisations are fine.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Civilization-VII-Review-07-Mementos-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>

<p>Which brings us to combat. This is another area where Civilization VII has seen some changes. The single-unit per tile system remains, with an adjustment to how types of stacking work. You can't stack units as with Civilization VI; you can recruit a commander to group several units, essentially making an army group. This allows you to transport units quickly. However, be warned that these groups don't have the fighting power of the units inside them; you need to deploy for combat.</p>
<p>Combat remains as expected from the series, with tweaks to how ranged units can attack and how terrain and height impact this. This makes it more tactical and adds more to the game. With this, the move to more realistic terrain from the last game, carried on here, keeps its impact. Honestly, though, I haven't seen the end of combat because, as mentioned earlier, the age system essentially hamstrings me and cuts me off before I experience it all.</p>
<p>With my usual narrative style now broken, I'm just listing things. Another new feature, which I think is partly why the game pushes for such quick conclusions, is the character and civilisation levelling systems. As you play, you gain experience. As you gain experience, your chosen leader - and the civilisation you are - level up by completing specific objectives. Other objectives also unlock "mementos" you can equip when starting a new game, giving you a slight boost.</p>
<p>I must say that I haven't played enough online to give you an accurate representation of that yet. I'm now on it with others, but that's for another piece, though the above is a way to bring more of an online progression system to the game.</p>
<p>Also, it looks and sounds great. I'm not going to go into that much detail on the aesthetics. But, the soundtrack is fantastic, with Christoper Tin knocking the theme out of the park again (I still prefer Sogno di Volare), each civ having its theme, and great effects in battle. The same is true for the visuals, with even the smaller elements like disasters and the units in combat having the details to make them stand out and fit in simultaneously.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Civilization-VII-Review-08-Wonder-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>

<p>My first maybe five hours with Civilization VII left me feeling a little despondent. I didn't have the same enthusiasm from the early gameplay that previous entries gave me. I am still questioning certain decisions, and I believe the speed and forced end of an age and the limitations of maps are fundamentally holding the game back. It gives Firaxis the narrative push they want, but lacking the ability of an open-ended game that Civilization has been from 1991 baffles me.</p>
<p>Now, even with that, I can't deny for a second that the more I have played this, and the more times I've started a game, I've been sucked into it. With over sixty hours on the clock, I've explored much of what the game has to offer, and what it offers is great. It keeps the series's one more turn aspect alive and kicking, and I've more than a few times found myself thinking, "Should be asleep now."</p>
<p>I genuinely think most of the changes are for the better, though some things, like how much of a reset an age gives, could be toned back a little. I also want an option to stop an age forcing itself on me, and I want a game on a huge map where I can reach the end I want. What I want, ironically, is "Just one more turn." This would have been the series' best if it hadn't been for some omissions and questionable decisions. Whatever my misgivings, this is still an incredibly addictive game.</p>
<p><em>Reviewed on PC (code provided by the publisher).</em></p>

				

						<div>
					
					<div>
						<p><span>8</span></p><h5>WCCFTECH RATING</h5>
					</div>
					<h2>Civilization VII</h2>
				</div>
			
						<section>
				<p>Civilization VII is a great game, that's the simple answer. With an improved city-building system, terrain features, and diplomacy, there is much to like in the new release of the three-and-a-half decade old franchise. However, long-time fans of the series will find some of the omissions, such as the ability to turn off victory conditions other than domination, limiting. This, and the rapid nature of the ages, will also leave some feeling that the epic nature of some longer games is altogether missing. Still, even with the games feeling a little rushed, the one-more-turn that makes Civilization one of the best series ever remains there.</p>
				<div>
												<ul>
							<h6>Pros</h6>
							<li>City and Town development is fantastically done, and adds a whole new layer to the game.
</li><li>Improved diplomacy removes some of the exploits found in previous games.
</li><li>Terrain features like navigable rivers add a whole new element to both army movement and city building.
</li><li>Gorgeous looking and sounding game.</li>						</ul>
																		<ul>
							<h6>Cons</h6>
							<li>The age system forces itself upon you, and can impact the enjoyability of a game - particularly towards the very end.
</li><li>Map sizes are too small, removing the "grand" feel that came with larger maps in previous entries.
</li><li>The AI around city-states can be a little too agressive and limiting early on.</li>						</ul>
										</div>
				<a rel="sponsored nofollow noskim" href="https://amzn.to/4aHppri">Buy for $59.99 from Amazon</a>
				<span>The links above are affiliate links. As an Amazon Associate, Wccftech.com may
					earn from qualifying purchases.</span>
			</section>
			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Six Invitational 2025 – Schedule, Teams, Prize Pool, and Where to Watch]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/six-invitational-2025-all-you-need-to-know-about-it/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/six-invitational-2025-%E2%80%93-schedule-teams-prize-pool-and-where-to-watch.1098609/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/six-invitational-2025-all-you-need-to-know-about-it/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>The Six Invitational 2025 is one of this year’s esports calendar’s biggest and most valuable events. Ubisoft backs this super-sized tournament, which features a massive prize pool worth $3 million – with $1 million going to the winning team. It’s set to run from February 3 – 16, and in that window, 20 of the best Rainbow Six Siege teams on Earth will go head-to-head.</p>



<p>Read on to learn everything you need to know about the Six Invitational 2025.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-six-invitational-2025-schedule">Six Invitational 2025 Schedule</h2>



<p>The Six Invitational 2025 schedule is broken into three ‘phases’. The first occurs between February 3 and 7, while the second will unravel between February 8 and 12. The third and final stage, open to the public in Boston, Massachusetts, will be held between February 14 and 16.</p>



<p>These phases have been dubbed the ‘Group Stage’, ‘Playoffs’, and ‘Finals’ – only the <strong>Finals </strong>stage is open to the public at the arena in Boston.</p>



<p>The action kicks off with an intense Group Stage, with all 20 teams (both invited and qualified) taking to the stage behind closed doors (but on stream) to battle it out in a best-of-three ‘Round Robin’ rotation. Four teams will be sent home, while 16 will go into the Playoffs.</p>



<p>Only six teams will make it to the Finals stage.</p>



<h2 id="h-six-invitational-2025-prize-pool">Six Invitational 2025 Prize Pool</h2>



<p>The $3 million prize pool for the Six Invitational 2025 is one of the biggest single prizes in esports. Here’s how that prize pool is broken down:</p>



<ul>
<li>1st Place – $1 million</li>



<li>2nd Place – $450,000</li>



<li>3rd Place – $240,000</li>



<li>4th Place – $170,000</li>



<li>5th – 6th Place – $135,000</li>



<li></li>
</ul>



<h2 id="h-six-invitational-2025-teams">Six Invitational 2025 Teams</h2>



<p>Here are all the teams competing at the Six Invitational, with a note on how they got there:</p>



<p><strong>Global Standings</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Team BDS</li>



<li>FaZe Clan</li>



<li>w7m Esports </li>



<li>Unwanted</li>



<li>Team Secret </li>



<li>Team Liquid</li>



<li>DarkZero Esports</li>



<li>Spacestation</li>



<li>Virtus.pro</li>



<li>Team Falcons </li>



<li>M80</li>



<li>FURIA</li>



<li>Shopify Rebellion</li>



<li>SCARZ</li>



<li>Team Joel</li>



<li>PSG Talon</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>LCQ</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>G2 Esports</li>



<li>RazaH Company Academy</li>



<li>Oxygen Esports</li>



<li>CAG Osaka</li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-who-is-most-likely-to-win-the-six-invitational-2025">Who is most likely to win the Six Invitational 2025?</h3>



<p>If you’re trying to take part in a little Rainbow Six betting, you might be wondering which team is the best prospect for the top spot at the Six Invitational 2025.</p>



<p>The odds-on favourite to win the Six Invitational 2025 is Team BDS. The team has secured the second-place spot at two BLAST Major events in the last year, but they won the Esports World Cup and have been white hot ever since. If it’s not Team BDS, it could be w7m Esports.</p>



<h2 id="h-where-to-watch-the-six-invitational-2025">Where to Watch the Six Invitational 2025</h2>



<p>If you want to check out the action from the Six Invitational 2025, you can make use of the following links:</p>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.twitch.tv/Rainbow6" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Rainbow Six on Twitch</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCWKHac5bjhsUtSnMDFCT-7A" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Rainbow Six on YouTube</a></li>
</ul>



<p>If you watch on Twitch, you’ll be able to soak up a Twitch Drops campaign established to celebrate the tournament. As the event unravels, you can watch and earn stacks of packs bursting with items like cosmetics and digital credits.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more of the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/category/esports/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">latest esports coverage,</a> stay tuned to Insider Gaming</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bleach: Rebirth of Souls character trailer – Ikkaku Madarame]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/02/bleach-rebirth-of-souls-character-trailer-ikkaku-madarame</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/bleach-rebirth-of-souls-character-trailer-%E2%80%93-ikkaku-madarame.1098603/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/02/bleach-rebirth-of-souls-character-trailer-ikkaku-madarame<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Bandai Namco Entertainment [6,635 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/bandai-namco-entertainment">Bandai Namco</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Tamsoft [313 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/tamsoft">Tamsoft</a> have released a new character trailer for fighting <a title="Genres > Action [2,454 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action game</a> <em><a title="Games > Bleach: Rebirth of Souls [31 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/bleach-rebirth-of-souls">Bleach: Rebirth of Souls</a></em> highlighting playable fighter Ikkaku Madarame. <span id="more-941833"></span></p><p>According to his description, Madarame is the luckiest man in the Soul Society, capable of overcoming superior opponents in close range combat.</p><p><em>Bleach: Rebirth of Souls</em> is due out for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,756 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [6,636 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,651 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [22,249 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1689620/BLEACH_Rebirth_of_Souls/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> on March 21.</p><p>Watch the trailer below.</p><h2><span>Character Trailer: Ikkaku Madarame</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><iframe title="BLEACH Rebirth of Souls — Ikkaku Madarame Character Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/pQU59aOdOOY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe title="「BLEACH Rebirth of Souls」キャラクタームービー #28｜斑目一角" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fBEu8HjbXFM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[TOKYO PSYCHODEMIC and KAMiBAKO: Mythology of Cube PS5 physical editions launch in Q2 2025 in the Americas]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/02/tokyo-psychodemic-and-kamibako-mythology-of-cube-ps5-physical-editions-launch-in-q2-2025-in-the-americas</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/tokyo-psychodemic-and-kamibako-mythology-of-cube-ps5-physical-editions-launch-in-q2-2025-in-the-americas.1098600/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/02/tokyo-psychodemic-and-kamibako-mythology-of-cube-ps5-physical-editions-launch-in-q2-2025-in-the-americas<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Distributed by PM Studios.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > PM Studios [101 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/pm-studios">PM Studios</a> will distribute physical editions of <a title="Companies > Gravity Game Arise [17 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/gravity-game-arise">Gravity Game Arise</a>-developed forensics investigation <a title="Genres > Simulation [640 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/simulation">simulation game</a> <em><a title="Games > TOKYO PSYCHODEMIC [4 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/tokyo-psychodemic">TOKYO PSYCHODEMIC</a></em> and RPG <em><a title="Games > KAMiBAKO: Mythology of Cube [4 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/kamibako-mythology-of-cube">KAMiBAKO: Mythology of Cube</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,756 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a> in Q2 2025 in North and South America, the company announced. <span id="more-941802"></span></p><p>“We’re incredibly excited to bring Gravity’s diverse and engaging catalog of games to a wider audience in the Americas through physical releases,” said PM Studios CEO Michael Yum in a press release. “Gravity has a proven track record of creating captivating gaming experiences, and we’re confident that players in our territories will embrace their titles. We believe this collaboration will be mutually beneficial, allowing us to expand our reach while providing Gravity with the distribution expertise and market knowledge PM Studios has cultivated over the years. We look forward to a long and successful partnership.”</p><p>Here is an overview of each game, via PM Studios:</p><blockquote><p><strong><em>TOKYO PSYCHODEMIC</em></strong></p><p><em>TOKYO PSYCHODEMIC</em> A new viral outbreak has forced Tokyo into an extended lockdown. After a three year epidemic, life seems to have returned to normal until a string of paranormal incidents occur. Players must solve these cases and confront the supernatural through the analyzing of evidence and consulting with specialists in this simulation game which blends 2D illustrations with real-life visuals.</p><p><strong><em>KAMiBAKO: Mythology of Cube</em></strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><em>KAMiBAKO: Mythology of Cube</em> A blend of puzzle-solving, <a title="Genres > RPG [16,962 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg">role-playing</a>, <a title="Genres > Crafting [26 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/crafting">crafting</a> and combat, <em>KAMiBAKO: Mythology of Cube</em> puts players in the role of the “Restorer” who must repair the land through puzzles, and rid the world of darkness by defeating dangerous monsters.</p></blockquote><p>Both <em>TOKYO PSYCHODEMIC</em> and <em>KAMiBAKO: Mythology of Cube</em> are available now digitally for PlayStation 5, PlayStation 4, Switch, and PC via Steam. In Japan, physical editions of both games are available for PlayStation 5, PlayStation 4, and Switch.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Former PlayStation Boss Is Optimistic About Xbox's Multiplatform Strategy]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/former-playstation-boss-is-optimistic-about-xbox-multiplatform-strategy/1100-6529186/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/former-playstation-boss-is-optimistic-about-xboxs-multiplatform-strategy.1098597/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/former-playstation-boss-is-optimistic-about-xbox-multiplatform-strategy/1100-6529186/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529186">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Microsoft has embarked on a new multiplatform direction for several of its Xbox games, and former PlayStation boss Shawn Layden believes that this new initiative could work in the company's favor if handled correctly--much like it has for Sega. Layden believes that Microsoft can benefit from having a wider market to sell its games to as part of its new multiplatform strategy, but the downside to this is that it could possibly make it harder for the company to attract more people to its platform.</p><p>"Multiplatform is a strategy, particularly in a world where the cost of development is increasing dramatically," Layden said to YouTube channel <a href="https://youtu.be/UAcM-xmUegs?t=2968" rel="nofollow ">Kiwi Talks</a>. "Multiplatform means widening your addressable market, as the marketing guys say. How do you create the fear of missing out, trying to do that by bringing everyone to your platform? Saying, 'If you're not here you're missing out,' but if it's available on all platforms, that's one of your marketing tactics. You can't say it's only available here if it's available everywhere. So it's a balancing act, right? I'm increasing my addressable market, that's good. I'm making it harder to sell only on my platform."</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UAcM-xmUegs" data-width="100%" data-height="100%" data-video-start="2968">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/UAcM-xmUegs?start=2968" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>As Layden noted, there was precedent for this shift in business tactics, as following the launch and poor sales of the Dreamcast, Sega dropped out of the console hardware race to focus on developing and publishing video games. "We've seen it before. I mean I was in the business when Sega brought their Dreamcast titles to PlayStation 2. And in time, Sega became a software-only company and have been a great transformation in that respect," Layden said.</p><p>Microsoft has two big games on the way to PS5 consoles this year. Last year it was confirmed that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-whips-up-4-million-players-before-ps5-debut/1100-6529145/">Indiana Jones and the Great Circle would reach that platform</a> several months after its Xbox and PC launch, and last week, the company revealed that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/forza-horizon-5-is-the-next-xbox-game-to-speed-onto-playstation-5/1100-6529156/">Forza Horizon 5 will also race onto PS5 in spring</a>.</p><p>In terms of hardware, Xbox Series X|S sales are reportedly behind the Xbox One at the same point in both of their lifecycles, while the PS5 is outpacing the PS4. The good news for Microsoft is that its multiplatform approach appears to be paying off <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/despite-xboxs-struggles-in-hardware-microsoft-was-reportedly-the-top-video-game-publisher-in-december/1100-6529088/">as it was apparently the number-one video game publisher in December 2024</a> thanks partly to its Call of Duty games.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                        
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/108490194306897153177?rel=author">Darryn Bonthuys</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Civilization 7 Difficulty Options And How To Change The Difficulty]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/civilization-7-difficulty-options-and-how-to-change-the-difficulty/1100-6528923/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/civilization-7-difficulty-options-and-how-to-change-the-difficulty.1098594/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/civilization-7-difficulty-options-and-how-to-change-the-difficulty/1100-6528923/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6528923">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Sid Meier's Civilization is known for being one of the most brutal <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/best-strategy-games/2900-5977/" data-ref-id="2900-5977">strategy games</a> you can play at the highest difficulty level. Of course, if you're looking for a more laid-back experience or you're a new player, the franchise has always let you swap to a lower difficulty. <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/sid-meiers-civilization-vii/" data-ref-id="5000-631817">Civilization VII</a> has brought back the difficulty levels and options from previous games, but they're not a copy-and-paste list of settings.</p><p>There are several difficulty levels, different map types and lengths, and other advanced settings that you'll want to know about before hopping into Civilization VII. The guide below explains how to change your difficulty level and everything about customizing your game.</p><h2>How to change difficulty in Civilization 7</h2><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1745/17457013/4431083-civ7screenshot2025.01.19-15.27.26.32.png" data-ref-id="1300-4431083" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="2560" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1745/17457013/4431083-civ7screenshot2025.01.19-15.27.26.32.png" data-ref-id="1300-4431083"></a><figcaption>The difficulty options in Civilization VII</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1745/17457013/4431083-civ7screenshot2025.01.19-15.27.26.32.png"></figure><p>First and foremost, let's go over how and where to change between the game's various difficulty levels. Unlike other games, this can't be done by going to the settings menu and flipping between the different levels. Instead, you have to start up a new game and go through a few menus before you're able to customize the difficulty level and other options in Civilization VII.</p><p>However, there's also a massive caveat with the difficulty level. In our version of the game on PC, <strong>we were</strong> <strong>not able to change the difficulty or set any other game options until after our first game was over</strong>. Once we beat one run, we could start a new game and access all the difficulty options. It's unclear if this is a bug or an intended feature.</p><p>To change the difficulty level, follow the steps below:</p><ul><li>Launch Civilization VII and press "New Game" from the main menu</li><li>Choose your desired Leader and Age and Civilization. It's highly recommended to always start from the Antiquity Age, as that's the formal beginning of the game.</li><li>Click "Continue" at the bottom of the screen to go to the "Confirm" tab</li><li>Here, you can access all the difficulty settings</li><li>The top option is your overall difficulty, and here are the different levels:  <ul><li>Scribe</li><li>Governor</li><li>Viceroy</li><li>Sovereign</li><li>Immortal</li><li>Deity</li></ul></li><li>The levels go from easiest to strongest, so for a standard playthrough, select either Governor or Viceroy</li><li>Once you're done with the difficulty level, you can customize the options below it before officially starting your game</li><li>Be warned, <strong>once you launch your game, you can't change the difficulty level</strong> or game options again unless you start a new save</li></ul><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1745/17457013/4431084-civ7screenshot2025.01.19-02.52.04.92.png" data-ref-id="1300-4431084" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="2560" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1745/17457013/4431084-civ7screenshot2025.01.19-02.52.04.92.png" data-ref-id="1300-4431084"></a><figcaption>The victory screen after winning a game</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1745/17457013/4431084-civ7screenshot2025.01.19-02.52.04.92.png"></figure><p>As we mentioned before, if you're loading up your first game of Civilization VII, the option to select your difficulty level might not be there. If what we experienced is intended, then it should take you roughly 10-15 hours of playtime to beat one run of the game on standard difficulty. After that point, you can make a new game and choose your difficulty options.</p><h2>All difficulty options in Civilization VII</h2><p>In addition to the difficulty levels in Civilization VII, you can also change a variety of game options. These include map type, game length, age length, and more. We'll go more in depth with each of those settings below:</p><p><strong>Game Speed </strong></p><ul><li>Online</li><li>Quick</li><li>Standard</li><li>Epic</li><li>Marathon</li></ul><p>This determines how long every game takes in turns and the number of overall turns per age. If you want a massive campaign that drags on for 30 hours, choose Marathon. However, most players will likely feel comfortable with Standard or Epic.</p><p><strong>Map Type </strong></p><ul><li>Continents Plus</li><li>Continents</li><li>Archipelago</li><li>Fractal</li><li>Shuffle</li><li>Terra Incognita</li></ul><p>Your map type is an important choice, as it controls what lands you'll be able to traverse. The standard option is Continents Plus, which gives you two continents to explore and some islands in between them. Continents takes out the islands while Archipelago makes it so your continents are broken up by islands. Fractal makes the continents more connected and offers less water between them. Then, Shuffle makes your map type random while Terra Incognita gives you one normal continent and a random second one.</p><p><strong>Map Size </strong></p><ul><li>Tiny</li><li>Small</li><li>Standard</li></ul><p>Finally, your map size determines the overall scale of the map you get to explore. Naturally, tiny and small sizes make for quicker games, as there's less to traverse and do. So, it's usually recommended for players to stick to the standard map size.</p><p><strong>Advanced Options </strong></p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1745/17457013/4431085-civ7screenshot2025.01.19-15.28.28.73.png" data-ref-id="1300-4431085" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="2560" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1745/17457013/4431085-civ7screenshot2025.01.19-15.28.28.73.png" data-ref-id="1300-4431085"></a><figcaption>Advanced Options give you more difficulty choices</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1745/17457013/4431085-civ7screenshot2025.01.19-15.28.28.73.png"></figure><ul><li>Age Length: Abbreviated, Standard, Long</li><li>Disaster Intensity: Light, Moderate, Catastrophic</li><li>Crises: Yes or No</li></ul><p>Advanced Options further customizes your game. The age length setting allows you to make your games shorter or longer depending on what game speed you set. Disasters and crises offer the chance to make things easier or harder on yourself. If you want a harder experience, turn crises on and pump disasters up to catastrophic level. However, neither of these settings will have too big of an effect on the difficulty unless you're playing on the higher difficulty levels.</p><p>You can also change the "Player Settings" within the Advanced Options menu. This allows you to set the world leaders you'll meet during a game and what civilizations they control. While this doesn't have a huge impact on difficulty, you can make your experience tougher by selecting leaders that are "militaristic." This makes them more prone to war, which is generally what difficulty levels are based on.</p><p>There's so much to learn and discover when you're exploring the massive world of Civ 7. Be sure to use our <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/civilization-7-guides-hub/1100-6529111/">Civilization 7 guides hub</a> to find all of our guides on the game in one spot.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Civilization 7: How Merchants And Trade Routes Work]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/civilization-7-how-merchants-and-trade-routes-work/1100-6528998/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/civilization-7-how-merchants-and-trade-routes-work.1098582/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/civilization-7-how-merchants-and-trade-routes-work/1100-6528998/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6528998">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Resources are what drive your individual settlements forward in <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/sid-meiers-civilization-vii/" data-ref-id="5000-631817">Civilization VII</a>. Not only do they improve all of the pertinent stats your empire needs to sustain itself, but they also improve relations with neighboring leaders. The more resources your civilization has access to, the better off you'll be.</p><p>The best way to acquire resources outside your settlements owning resource tiles is by establishing trade routes. Trade routes can only be established by merchants, who are individual units you can produce or purchase in a city or town. However, the process of using your merchants is not as simple as it sounds in Civilization 7.</p><h2>How to get Merchants in Civilization 7</h2><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1745/17457013/4432918-civ7screenshot2025.01.17-22.14.28.93.png" data-ref-id="1300-4432918" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="2560" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1745/17457013/4432918-civ7screenshot2025.01.17-22.14.28.93.png" data-ref-id="1300-4432918"></a><figcaption>The message that grants you access to Merchants</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1745/17457013/4432918-civ7screenshot2025.01.17-22.14.28.93.png"></figure><p>Merchants are one of the earlier units you can produce in Civilization VII. In our initial playthrough, we were first able to produce a merchant at the 50% mark of the Antiquity Age. You'll know you can start producing merchants when you see the first "Trade Opportunity" message appear during one of your turns. The message will state that a neighboring leader has abundant resources, and you should send a merchant to set up a trade route with them.</p><p>When you get this message, go to your capital city and scroll down the production units until you see "Merchant." The merchant takes roughly three or four turns to produce, but you can also purchase one for around 400 gold. Merchants can be produced in cities or bought in towns.</p><p>Once your merchant has been produced, you need to choose where they go to establish a trade route. By selecting the merchant during a turn, you'll see all the possible trade routes they can visit. These trade routes directly result from how many leaders you've met and all of their settlements you've discovered.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1745/17457013/4432919-civ7screenshot2025.01.17-22.52.55.65.png" data-ref-id="1300-4432919" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="2560" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1745/17457013/4432919-civ7screenshot2025.01.17-22.52.55.65.png" data-ref-id="1300-4432919"></a><figcaption>Producing a Merchant in Civilization VII</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1745/17457013/4432919-civ7screenshot2025.01.17-22.52.55.65.png"></figure><h2>How to establish Trade Routes in Civilization 7</h2><p>During your first turn with a merchant, select the settlement you want to set up a trade route with. You mainly want to look for what settlement has the most resources to offer, but you can also specialize your trade route if you're looking for one or two specific resources.</p><p>If you want to set up more possible trade routes, you need to discover more of the map and other leaders' settlements. The merchant also needs to be within a certain range of possible locations. With this in mind, it's wise to produce merchants at different settlements within your empire so you have a more extensive selection of places to go.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1745/17457013/4432920-civ7screenshot2025.01.17-22.16.08.76.png" data-ref-id="1300-4432920" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="2560" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1745/17457013/4432920-civ7screenshot2025.01.17-22.16.08.76.png" data-ref-id="1300-4432920"></a><figcaption>Your first look at the Merchant screen</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1745/17457013/4432920-civ7screenshot2025.01.17-22.16.08.76.png"></figure><p>You can send multiple merchants to the same settlement to establish a trade route. However, this requires going to a leader's portrait page and spending Influence to set up additional trade routes. You can only do this with leaders who are friendly or neutral with you. Leaders who you're warring with or have a negative relationship with will generally reject any trade route proposals.</p><p>You can see the status of your relationship with a leader by going to their portrait and selecting the tab with a heart and number on it. If the number is green, you're in good standing with the leader, but the leader is hostile towards you if it's red.</p><p>Returning to setting up trade routes, once you have selected the settlement you want to visit, select it from the "Possible Trade Routes" menu. Then, your game will take you to that location on the map. From here, right-click on the capital of the settlement and you'll send your merchant off on their journey.</p><p>Depending on how far the settlement is from your merchant's starting location, they could take several turns to reach their destination. Don't worry, though, as the merchants are automated, so you don't have to control each turn individually.</p><p>When the merchant arrives at the settlement, they'll be given a turn, and you have to decide what to do with them. To establish a trade route with the settlement they're in, view their box in the bottom-right and press the icon with two arrows and a plus sign, as seen in the screenshot below.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1745/17457013/4432914-civ7screenshot2025.01.18-15.30.49.02.png" data-ref-id="1300-4432914" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="2560" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1745/17457013/4432914-civ7screenshot2025.01.18-15.30.49.02.png" data-ref-id="1300-4432914"></a><figcaption>Choosing to establish a trade route to another settlement</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1745/17457013/4432914-civ7screenshot2025.01.18-15.30.49.02.png"></figure><p>This establishes a trade route with the settlement, granting you the resources it offers. From there, your merchant will disappear and you can allocate your newfound resources to cities or towns. If you send your merchant to a city, the resources in return can only be allocated to one of your cities. However, merchants visiting a town will grant you bonus resources, which can be allocated to cities or towns in your empire.</p><p>Your other option with the merchant is to send them to another settlement. This forgoes the establishment of a trade route. Generally, you want to ensure you're always establishing a trade route once your merchant arrives at their destination, or else you're just wasting turns with them traveling all over the map.</p><p>It's usually wise to have at least one or two merchants roaming the map in Civilization VII. This earns you more resources, increases your relationship with other leaders, and lets you increase the stats of your settlements.</p><p>There's so much to learn and discover when you're exploring the massive world of Civ 7. Be sure to use our <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/civilization-7-guides-hub/1100-6529111/">Civilization 7 guides hub</a> to find all of our guides on the game in one spot.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Grammy Award for best game soundtrack won by indie RPG, beating Spider-Man 2 and God of War Ragnarök]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/grammy-award-for-best-game-soundtrack-won-by-indie-rpg-beating-spider-man-2-and-god-of-war-ragnarok</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/grammy-award-for-best-game-soundtrack-won-by-indie-rpg-beating-spider-man-2-and-god-of-war-ragnar%C3%B6k.1098567/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/grammy-award-for-best-game-soundtrack-won-by-indie-rpg-beating-spider-man-2-and-god-of-war-ragnarok<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div>
        

        <p>"To have been recognised is just a highlight of my career, it truly is."</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Screenshot-2025-02-03-at-13.47.31.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Digital Eclipse</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Wizardry: Proving Grounds of the Mad Overlord beat competition from games like <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/spider-man-2-walkthrough-9356">Marvel's Spider-Man 2</a> and <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/god-of-war-ragnarok">God of War Ragnarök</a>: Valhalla to secure this year's Grammy for best video game soundtrack.</p>
<p>The soundtrack of Wizardry: Proving Grounds of the Mad Overlord - a remake of the 1981 RPG - was composed by famed musician Winifred Phillips, who has previously created scores for blockbusters like God of War, <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/assassins-creed-iii">Assassin's Creed 3</a>, and <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/littlebigplanet">LittleBigPlanet</a>.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="01 - Dragon Slayer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/bpdJDDwo_0Y?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>01 - Dragon Slayer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/bpdJDDwo_0Y?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/bpdJDDwo_0Y?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>01 - Dragon Slayer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bpdJDDwo_0Y" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>Wizardry: Proving Grounds of the Mad Overlord came on top after being nominated alongside Pinar Toprak (<a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/avatar-frontiers-of-pandora">Avatar: Frontiers of Pandora</a>), Bear McCreary (God of War Ragnarök: Valhalla), John Paesano (Marvel's Spider-Man 2), and Wilbert Roget, II (Star Wars Outlaws).</p>
<p>"I am totally blown away," Phillips <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NShT8a-9ME8">said</a>. "I cannot believe this, it's just amazing, and it's like a bright light just exploded in my head. I'm just blown over.</p>
<p>"It was just such a wonderful experience. Digital Eclipse developed Wizardry: Proving Grounds of the Mad Overlord and its a wonderful role-playing game. It's a medieval fantasy in the best tradition of Dungeons &amp; Dragons and traditional medieval fantasy so it was so inspiring to create the music for that.</p>
<p>"The category was populated with so much brilliance this year and I have so much deep respect for the other nominees in this category. To have been recognised is just a highlight of my career, it truly is."</p>
<p>This is the third year the category has run at the Grammy awards. <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/assassins-creed-valhalla">Assassin's Creed Valhalla</a> <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/and-the-first-grammy-for-video-game-music-goes-to">secured the inaugural award in 2023</a>, whilst Star Wars Jedi: Survivor <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/star-wars-jedi-survivor-takes-home-best-gaming-score-at-grammy-awards">won last year</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokémon TCG Pocket's Abysmal Trading Is Going To Be Addressed]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/pokemon-tcg-pocket-trading-tokens-broken-feature-1851753735</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pok%C3%A9mon-tcg-pockets-abysmal-trading-is-going-to-be-addressed.1098549/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/pokemon-tcg-pocket-trading-tokens-broken-feature-1851753735<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Last week, some three months after launch, <em>Pokémon TCG Pocket</em> finally adding the ‘T’ from the game’s title, the trading. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/pokemon-tcg-pocket-how-trades-work-tokens-crown-rare-1851750299&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-tcg-pocket-how-trades-work-tokens-crown-rare-1851750299">And it’s hard to imagine how it could have been worse</a></span>. Almost impossibly “expensive” to use, what were presumably measures to prevent real-money markets and scalpers have led to a system that is so punitive to players as to be useless. Thankfully, developers Creatures, Inc. and DeNA have since released a statement saying they recognize all is not OK.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196165" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="What’s Coming Out Beyond Pokémon: The Indigo Disk | The Week In Games" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="95" data-playlist="196165,194741,196790" data-current="196165"><div><p>What’s Coming Out Beyond Pokémon: The Indigo Disk | The Week In Games</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196165/196165_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196165/196165_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196165/196165_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196165/196165_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21711.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p><em>Pocket</em>’s trading is a ghastly mess. If you want to trade, say, a single one-star rarity card (typically a non-ex full-art card), you’ll require 400 trade tokens, which presently can only be gained by <em>destroying</em> four other one-star cards. Then, to trade for a card you actually want, you need to be in direct communication with the other person outside of the application, as there’s no way to communicate such information within. It’s very poor, and thank goodness, the negative reaction appears to have been heard.</p><p>“Since releasing the first iteration of the trading feature a few days ago,” <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/PokemonTCGP/status/1885447974094070090&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/PokemonTCGP/status/1885447974094070090" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">says a statement from the developers via X</a></span>, “we have received a large number of comments. Thank you all for sharing your feedback.”</p><p>The statement goes on to explain that the “requirements and restrictions” are there to prevent bots and malfeasance, and all this was done out of a desire to “maintain a fair environment for all players.” But, they go on, “we understand that some of the restrictions put in place are preventing players from being able to casually enjoy the feature as intended.” The developers are now investigating ways to improve things, as well as promising more ways to accrue trade tokens, “including through event distributions.”</p><p>What’s so interesting here is how this obnoxiously terrible feature was so obviously flawed. People didn’t discover the design’s issues through extensive experimentation, nor did they only show up once a large audience was participating. Instead it was, at a glance, blatantly horrible. You needed to destroy swathes of your most precious cards (and if sacrificial, inherently the very cards you would have wanted to trade away) to be able to get a single new one, and you couldn’t just click a button to say which card you wanted in return! The developers <em>had</em> to know it was awful—it’s inconceivable that they could not.</p><p>Yet, trading is extremely tricky ground for <em>Pokémon</em>. With the real-life versions of the cards, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/pokemon-tcg-prismatic-evolutions-prices-umbreon-1851747243&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-tcg-prismatic-evolutions-prices-umbreon-1851747243">as we’ve been reporting for a while</a></span>, prices for the rarest new cards are hitting all-time highs—we’re talking $1,500 for a single card from the most recent set. Being physical objects, The Pokémon Company International (TPCi) and Creatures aren’t able to impinge on such resale markets, and can only exercise any level of control by producing more product for people to buy. But here, in this digital-only realm, there was a presumed ability to prevent such a second-hand market growing out of control.</p><p>The problem is, there isn’t an elegant or reasonable way to allow a pleasant in-game trading mechanic that cannot be exploited by third-party marketplaces. If it exists in any practical way, it will immediately be exploited by those wishing to more easily secure the specific cards they want, and those wishing to take people’s money to allow them to do so. The only solution is to create an in-app version of the feature that’s as good as anything anyone’s offering externally, rather than making the act of trading so actively unpleasant and punishing that no one would ever want to pay to do it.</p><p>Oddly enough, TPCi <em>has</em> done this successfully before! The original digital version of the <em>Pokémon</em> trading card game, <em>PTCG Online</em>, had a fantastic in-app trading function. You publicly listed the card you were offering and the card you wanted in exchange, and then anyone else could search for the card <em>they</em> want, and see if they had the requested trade. Click, boom, done. For reasons TPCi has chosen never to divulge, the trading feature was removed entirely <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/pokemon-tcg-live-online-migrate-card-game-tips-guide-1849789809&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-tcg-live-online-migrate-card-game-tips-guide-1849789809">when the forced switch to the poorer replacement app, <em>PTCG Live</em>, was implemented.</a></span></p><p>So it’s good news that feedback has been heard, but it remains very unlikely that trading will ever become the feature people have hoped for in <em>Pocket</em>, given the seeming reluctance to allow any sort of third-party marketplace. Let’s hope it at least makes a significant improvement. In the meantime, it seems, the app will find new ways to hand out piles of trading tokens.</p><p>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marvel Star Is Trying To Get The Sleeping Dogs Movie Made--And A Game Sequel]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/marvel-star-is-trying-to-get-the-sleeping-dogs-movie-made-and-a-game-sequel/1100-6529185/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/marvel-star-is-trying-to-get-the-sleeping-dogs-movie-made-and-a-game-sequel.1098546/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/marvel-star-is-trying-to-get-the-sleeping-dogs-movie-made-and-a-game-sequel/1100-6529185/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529185">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Marvel actor Simu Liu has revealed that he is attempting to revive the Sleeping Dogs series with a movie and a sequel to the 2012 game. Liu, who starred in Shang-Chi and the Legend of the Ten Rings, said on social media that it's been a "tiring" process to pitch Sleeping Dogs to executives, going on to note how only a small percentage of film projects that are pitched ever get made.</p><p>"Everyone's overwhelming love of Sleeping Dogs here has give us life," he said, referring to the social media campaign to get a Sleeping Dogs movie off the ground. Liu said his plan is to make a Sleeping Dogs movie first, "then a sequel game for everyone," or at least, "that's always been the dream."</p><p><a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-sleeping-dogs-movie-is-in-development-and-were-hearing-shang-chi-star-simu-liu-is-set-to-play-wei-shen" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">A source told IGN</a> that a Sleeping Dogs movie is actually in development, with Liu on board to play the lead role of Wei Shen. A movie being in "development" doesn't mean it'll ever get made, though, only that <a href="https://blog.finaldraft.com/your-projects-in-development-now-what" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">pre-production work is being done in some capacity.</a></p><p>Plenty of video game movies get announced and never come out for any number of reasons. Sleeping Dogs itself has been in development as a movie in some form for nearly a decade, after all, as Donnie Yen was at one point trying to make a Sleeping Dogs movie before <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/sleeping-dogs-movie-from-donnie-yen-may-never-happen/1100-6528726/" data-ref-id="1100-6528726">apparently giving up. </a></p><div data-embed-type="tweet" data-src="https://x.com/simuliu/status/1885252869483340236?s=46" data-has-image="true"><blockquote data-conversation="none" data-mce-disable-toolbar="true"><p dir="ltr">So few film projects make it from pitch phase to greenlight. Pitching execs who don’t understand the game has been tiring. Everyone’s overwhelming love of Sleeping Dogs here has really given us life!<br>First a movie, then a sequel game for everyone… that’s always been the dream. <a href="https://t.co/g84r9Lf0SI" rel="nofollow ">pic.twitter.com/g84r9Lf0SI</a></p>  — Simu Liu (@SimuLiu) <a href="https://twitter.com/SimuLiu/status/1885252869483340236?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 31, 2025</a></blockquote>              </div><p>The original Sleeping Dogs game had players take control of undercover cop Wei Shen, who was tasked with infiltrating the Triad gangs operating in Hong Kong and gathering evidence on their various illegal activities.</p><p>Despite being well-received by critics and fans, Sleeping Dogs never managed to become a franchise. A spin-off, Triad Wars, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/sleeping-dogs-spin-off-triad-wars-shutting-down/1100-6433352/">was canceled during its beta</a>, and developer United Front Games <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/sleeping-dogs-developer-shuts-down-latest-game-no-/1100-6444545/">shut down in 2016</a>. A Sleeping Dogs Definitive Edition was released in 2014.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sodaman is here to drink soda and kick ass… and he’s all out of soda]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/02/03/sodaman-is-here-to-drink-soda-and-kick-ass-and-hes-all-out-of-soda/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sodaman-is-here-to-drink-soda-and-kick-ass%E2%80%A6-and-he%E2%80%99s-all-out-of-soda.1098540/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/02/03/sodaman-is-here-to-drink-soda-and-kick-ass-and-hes-all-out-of-soda/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Sometimes, video games are just pure, chaotic joy. Sure, we’ve got plenty of cosy adventures where you can pet the cat and launch a coffee shop, but unadulterated violence and mayhem are pretty popular (in the make-believe, pixellated forum, not so much in the real world. Sodaman is just about to launch into Early Access on the 17th of February, and this is one game where pixellated, chaotic violence looks as though it’s going to be a heck of a lot of fun.</p>
<p><iframe title="Sodaman - Official Release Date Gameplay Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9oDvs0dBmfo?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>Unsurprisingly, for a game called Sodaman, cans of soda (that’s pop to you UK readers), are integral and important, with Sodaman utilising his favourite fizzy beverages to power up his blasting and fighting powers. Set in a cyberpunk futuristic society, and pulling together the ever-popular Roguelike and Bullet Heaven genres, Sodaman has definitely taken a slurp of Hades and a sip of Death Must Die on its way to fruition. </p>
<p>Interestingly, the development team at Tape Corps have also included Balatro as in influence, so the way that you steadily improve your abilities in each run might take inspiration from there. Or you’re going to be firing Jokers at the bad guys that give you insane multipliers. Either sounds good.</p>
<p>While Sodamans powers are enhanced by the fizzy stuff, you can also pour them together to create hybrid, unusual drinks that are even more powerful. Like mixing Pepsi and Lilt. Wouldn’t that be something?</p>

<p>Sodaman, which will be published by GameDev.ist, will launch with a very reasonable price tag of $4.99 during Early Access on Steam. There’ll aslo be a 20% discount for two weeks following the Early Access exit. As you should expect, this is an unfinished project, and the team at Tape Corps will be paying close attention to player feedback during Early Access. It definitely looks like it’s worth jumping into!</p>



<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Red Dead Redemption 2 Has Set Another All-Time Peak Record on Steam]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/red-dead-redemption-2-has-set-another-new-all-time-peak-record-on-steam/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/red-dead-redemption-2-has-set-another-all-time-peak-record-on-steam.1098537/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/red-dead-redemption-2-has-set-another-new-all-time-peak-record-on-steam/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Red Dead Redemption 2 created two concurrent player peak records on Steam within a week, the latest one bringing the number to just under 100,000.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Just a week ago, Red Dead Redemption 2 hit a new all-time peak of 86,717 on Steam, beating the 2023 record of 77,655. The latest number has been topped, too. Spotted by <a href="https://www.thegamer.com/red-dead-red-dead-redemption-2-player-surge-on-steam-rockstar-games-sale/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">TheGamer</a>, RDR 2 hit an all-time peak of 99,993 in the past 24 hours (at the time of writing), according to <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/1174180/charts/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">SteamDB</a>. However, its new record is not even close to Rockstar’s 2013 hit title, GTA V, which managed to peak at 364,548 almost a decade ago and has brought in more than 200,000 players in the past 24 hours.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But what’s responsible for Red Dead Redemption 2 setting new player peak records on Steam? It’s none other than a discount, with Rockstar’s 2018 action-adventure game receiving a massive <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/red-dead-redeption-2-breaks-steam-concurrent/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">75% discount</a> on the platform, bringing its price down to $15. Grabbing Red Dead Redemption 2 for this price is an absolute steal, and the sale is not limited to RDR 2. The Rockstar Games Steam Sale offers up to <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/sale/rockstarpublishersale2025?tab=3" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">80% discount on their games</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Red Dead Redemption 2 features the most expansive and immersive open-world Rockstar has created, a world you could get lost in. If you don’t want to play the story, you can still get hours of content just by exploration, with each character in the open world having a new story and each corner opening a new secret. And that’s just one of the beauties of the games; the visuals, storytelling, character design and soundtrack of RDR 2 are second to none.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In other news, here’s <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/earn-money-fast-in-red-dead-online-this-holiday-season/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">how to earn money fast</a> in Red Dead Online. Also, the Red Dead Redemption <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/red-dead-redemption-series-sales/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">franchise has sold over 92 million units</a>. Do you think Red Dead Redemption 2 will create another concurrent player record on Steam?&nbsp;Let us know in the comments below or on our&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fromsoftware-is-not-chasing-a-trend-with-elden-ring-nightreign/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">FromSoftware ‘not chasing a trend’ with Elden Ring Nightreign</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sony PlayStation State of Play Reportedly Set for Next Week]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/sony-playstation-state-of-play-reportedly-set-for-next-week</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sony-playstation-state-of-play-reportedly-set-for-next-week.1098531/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/sony-playstation-state-of-play-reportedly-set-for-next-week<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">It's a Marathon, not a sprint.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Sony is reportedly set to deliver its now-standard February PlayStation State of Play broadcast next week.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Leaker NateTheHate, who accurately revealed the date of Nintendo’s Switch 2 reveal ahead of time, took to social media to <a href="https://x.com/NateTheHate2/status/1885748440132456877" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">tease</a> a State of Play for Valentine’s Day week (February 10 to 14).</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s speculation time! What could Sony have up its sleeve for this year’s State of Play? It’s worth going through the first-party games it has announced and coming out in 2025. Sucker Punch’s <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/ghost-of-yotei">Ghost of Yotei</a> currently has a 2025 release window. Perhaps we’ll get a fresh look at gameplay and a release date.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Meanwhile, Bungie’s PvP extraction shooter <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/marathon">Marathon</a> may be set for a showing if it still plans to open playtesting up this year. There’s also <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/fairgame">Fairgames</a>, the debut game from Haven Studios. Naughty Dog recently announced its brand new IP, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/intergalactic-the-heretic-prophet"><u>Intergalactic: The Heretic Prophet</u></a>, and Insomniac is working on <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/marvels-wolverine">Marvel’s Wolverine</a>. More likely, perhaps, is a fresh trailer for Hideo Kojima’s <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/death-stranding-2-on-the-beach">Death Stranding 2: On the Beach</a>, which is set for a 2025 release.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">What we won’t see are the various live service games Sony recently canned. Last month, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/playstation-cancels-two-unannounced-live-service-games"><u>Sony canceled two unannounced live-service games that were in development at Bend Studio and Bluepoint Games</u></a>. The Bluepoint game was reportedly a live-service God of War game. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/bend-studio-dev-says-we-still-plan-on-creating-cool-st-after-sony-live-service-cancelation">Bend Studio’s live-service game remains unknown</a>. Guerrilla Games' live service Horizon game reportedly survived the cull. Is it finally time for a reveal?</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Moving on to potential third-party announcements, Kojima has <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/physint-hideo-kojima-action-espionage-project"><u>Physint</u></a>, the upcoming stealth-action PlayStation exclusive in the works, but it feels a little early for that. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/phantom-blade-zero"><u>Phantom Blade Zero</u></a>, the flashy hack-and-slash action RPG from Chinese studio S-Game, is a safer bet.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">And let’s not forget Microsoft, now a significant publisher of games on PlayStation. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle">Indiana Jones and the Great Circle</a> is set to launch on PS5 soon, so maybe we will see a release date announced. And could Microsoft use State of Play to finally announce <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/halo-finally-looks-set-to-make-the-jump-to-playstation-this-year">the arrival of Halo on PlayStation</a>?</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In predicting the future, it’s helpful to look to the past. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/playstation-state-of-play-january-2024-everything-announced">Last year’s equivalent State of Play</a> showcased the likes of Death Stranding 2, Physint, Rise of the Ronin, the Until Dawn remaster, Stellar Blade, Dragon's Dogma 2, Sonic x Shadow Generations, various Silent Hill projects, Ken Levine’s Judas, Foamstars, and Helldivers 2.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokémon TCG Pocket Devs Looking to Improve Trading Following Major Player Backlash]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/pokmon-tcg-pocket-devs-looking-to-improve-trading-following-major-player-backlash</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pok%C3%A9mon-tcg-pocket-devs-looking-to-improve-trading-following-major-player-backlash.1098525/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/pokmon-tcg-pocket-devs-looking-to-improve-trading-following-major-player-backlash<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/pokemon-tcg-pocket">Pokémon Trading Card Game Pocket</a> developer Creatures Inc. is "actively investigating ways to improve" the trading feature which launched last week to major backlash from players.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Creatures Inc. released a statement on <a href="https://x.com/PokemonTCGP/status/1885447974094070090/photo/1" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">X/Twitter</a> that thanked players for their feedback and said they planned the controversial trading feature with the intention of stopping players from abusing it, but "some of the restrictions put in place are preventing players from being able to casually enjoy" it.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It also promised to alleviate complaints by introducing required items as rewards in upcoming events, but has already failed to do so as the Cresselia ex Drop Event released today, February 3, includes none.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Alongside the standard Pokémon TCG Pocket mechanic that restricts players from opening packs or Wonder Picking or, now, trading too much without spending real world money, the feature was also introduced with an extra restriction called Trade Tokens. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokmon-tcg-pocket-gets-trading-today-and-players-absolutely-hate-it">Players criticized the high cost of obtaining these</a>, as they essentially had to delete from their collections five cards before trading one of the same rarity.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Every Alternate Art 'Secret' Card in Pokémon TCG Pocket: Space Time Smackdown</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">"The item requirements and restrictions implemented for the trading feature were designed to prevent abuse from bots and other prohibited actions using multiple accounts," Creatures Inc. said. "Our goal was to balance the game while maintaining a fair environment for all players and preserving the fun of collecting cards that is core to the Pokémon TCG Pocket experience.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"However, thanks to your feedback, we understand that some of the restrictions put in place are preventing players from being able to casually enjoy the feature as intended. We are actively investigating ways to improve the feature to address these concerns. Going forward, we also plan to offer multiple ways to obtain Trade Tokens including through event distributions."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The statement is essentially as vague as it gets, with Creatures Inc. offering neither specifics into what changes will be made or when they will arrive, but it at least confirms that community concerns are heard.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Players of Pokémon TCG Pocket are also left in the dark as to if their current trades will be refunded or compensated in any way, as if the Trade Token cost changes, those taking advantage of the feature in its opening days may lose much more than if they waited.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Creatures Inc. doesn't seem particularly determined to include Trade Tokens in events either, as it only made a total of 200 available as premium rewards to those who pay $9.99 a month for the Battle Pass when the refresh arrived on February 1. This is enough to trade a single 3 Diamond card, the lowest rarity that requires Trade Tokens to trade.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It also failed to include any as rewards in the aforementioned Cresselia ex Drop Event which arrived today. Players can pick up new promo cards, Pack Hourglasses, Shinedust, shop tickets, and experience from completing the events, but Creatures Inc. doesn't offer a single Trade Token despite its vow to do so just yesterday.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Fans complained trading is fairly clearly being implemented as a means of increasing revenue for Pokémon TCG Pocket, which <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokmon-tcg-pocket-estimated-to-have-crossed-200-million-mark-already-outperforming-pokmon-sleep-and-unite">is estimated to have made $200 million in its first month</a>, before trading was possible.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">This is also evidenced by the inability to trade cards of 2 Star rarity or higher, as if players could immediately trade for their missing cards, they wouldn't need to spend $10 or $100 or more for a random chance of getting them. It cost one player around $1,500 just to complete the first set, for example, and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokmon-tcg-pocket-gets-space-time-smackdown-expansion-today-heres-everything-you-need-to-know">the third in three months arrived just a few days ago</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Players called the mechanic "predatory and downright greedy," "hilariously toxic," and a "monumental failure."</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Ryan Dinsdale is an IGN freelance reporter. He'll talk about The Witcher all day.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Wizardry: Proving Grounds of the Mad Overlord Composer Winifred Phillips Wins Grammy for Best Soundtrack in a Video Game]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/wizardry-proving-grounds-of-the-mad-overlord-composer-winifred-phillips-wins-grammy-for-best-soundtrack-in-a-video-game</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/wizardry-proving-grounds-of-the-mad-overlord-composer-winifred-phillips-wins-grammy-for-best-soundtrack-in-a-video-game.1098519/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/wizardry-proving-grounds-of-the-mad-overlord-composer-winifred-phillips-wins-grammy-for-best-soundtrack-in-a-video-game<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/wizardry-proving-grounds-of-the-mad-overlord-2023">Wizardry: Proving Grounds of the Mad Overlord</a> has won the Grammy for Best Score Soundtrack for Video Games and Other Interactive Media.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ot6ia8KDi9o&amp;t=9550s" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Accepting the award</a>, composer Winifred Phillips thanked developer Digital Eclipse and the audience for “believing in music for games and recognising it and for breathing life and enthusiasm and energy into what we do. It means so much.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Wizardry: Proving Grounds of the Mad Overlord is the 3D remake of the first game in the Wizardry series. 1981’s medieval fantasy Wizardy is considered the first party-based video game RPG ever released, and is credited as inspiring the likes of Final Fantasy and Dragon Quest. Wizardry: Proving Grounds of the Mad Overlord is built directly on top of the original game's code. You can even view the original Apple 2 interface as you play.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/02/03/gettyimages-2196802600-1738578849127.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Winifred Phillips at the 67th Grammy Awards. Photo by Rich Polk/Billboard via Getty Images.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Phillips took home the prize ahead of big hitter nominees including Wilbert Roget, II for Ubisoft’s Star Wars Outlaws, John Paesano for Marvel's Spider-Man 2, Bear McCreary for God of War Ragnarök: Valhalla, and Pinar Toprak for Avatar: Frontiers of Pandora.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In <a href="https://youtu.be/NShT8a-9ME8?feature=shared" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">a follow-up interview</a>, Phillips said she was “blown away.” “I really didn’t expect it," she added. "The category was populated with so much brilliance this year, and I have so much deep respect for the other nominees in this category. So to have been recognized is just a highlight of my career. It truly is.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“We do a very unique thing," Phillips continued. "We’re creating music that needs to accompany people who are having an experience and who are making choices, and having adventures and living a grand story, and we’re creating the music for that story. It’s such a wonderful privilege because you feel like you’re collaborating with the players. Like you know them and they know you. It’s really very special.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Previous winners of the coveted award include Stephanie Economou for Ubisoft’s Assassin's Creed Valhalla, and Stephen Barton and Gordy Haab for Respawn’s Star Wars Jedi: Survivor. The first piece of music from a video game ever to be nominated for and win a Grammy in any category was Baba Yetu, a song arranged by Christopher Tin for Firaxis’ Civilization 4, which won Best Instrumental Arrangement Accompanying Vocalist at the 53rd Annual Grammy Awards in 2011.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>