<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 21:19:06 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[AMD Surpasses 100 Million Gaming Consoles This Generation]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/amd-surpasses-100-million-gaming-consoles-this-generation/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/amd-surpasses-100-million-gaming-consoles-this-generation.1102497/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/amd-surpasses-100-million-gaming-consoles-this-generation/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Chipmaker AMD revealed in their <a href="https://wccftech.com/amd-beat-intel-earned-13-5-more-data-center-ai-revenue-in-q4/">Q4 Earnings Call</a> that this console generation has been incredibly strong, with the company's cumulative unit shipments surpassing $100 million during the fourth quarter. Those units are semi-custom processors that are used to power a vast majority of the gaming consoles that exist right now. This includes chips for the PlayStation 4, PlayStation 5, and even the Steam Deck. Although this is a huge milestone for AMD, it was unfortunately overshadowed by their revenue totals in the <a href="https://www.fool.com/earnings/call-transcripts/2025/02/05/advanced-micro-devices-amd-q4-2024-earnings-call-t/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Earnings Call</a>.</p>
<p>It was said that AMD gaming revenue was down by 59% year-over-year in the fourth quarter. AMD's gaming segment made $563 million in the three-month period ending December 2024. When comparing it to the year before, it was a pretty massive drop. The company made $1.4 billion in gaming revenue in the same period in 2024. However, revenue as a whole for AMD was a record $7.7 billion, growing 24% year over year, with the growth coming from the Data Center and Client segments.</p>
<p>However, it's said that annual revenue in the Data Center segment nearly doubled, and Client Segment revenue grew by 52%, which helped offset the declines from the Gaming segments.&nbsp; CEO Lisa Su said that she expects gaming revenue to continue to be down from the previous quarter but not as significant a decline as other parts of the business. Looking into the future, Lisa says that channel inventories have normalized, with semi-custom sales returning to historical patterns.</p>
<p>The Earnings Call also mentioned the plans for the next year in the AMD gaming segment. Lisa Su goes on to say, "Our focus with this generation is to address the highest volume portion of the enthusiast gaming market with our new RDNA 4 architecture. <a href="https://wccftech.com/new-steam-console-powered-by-rdna-4-might-be-in-the-works-at-valve/">RDNA 4</a> delivers significantly better ray tracing performance and adds support for AI-powered upscaling technology that will bring high-quality 4K gaming to mainstream players."</p>
<p>It's expected that there will be "modest increases" in the Gaming and Embedded businesses. For the 2025 financial reports, AMD plans to combine the client and the gaming segment into a single segment. It's also been said that revenue is expected to be approximately "$7.1 billion plus or minus $300 million, up 30% year-over-year, driven by strong growth in our data center and the client business."</p>
<p>While AMD had a successful fourth quarter of 2024, it has been mentioned multiple times that revenue is expected to decline in the gaming segment, which other areas of the company will offset. However, with the rise of handheld gaming PCs, AMD may end up in a better position than it once thought. Especially with the potential of a new Steam console being released, which will most likely utilize AMD.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Donald Duck: Happy Camper Board Game Celebrates Character's 90th Anniversary]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/new-donald-duck-happy-camper-board-game-celebrates-characters-90th-anniversary</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-donald-duck-happy-camper-board-game-celebrates-characters-90th-anniversary.1102494/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/new-donald-duck-happy-camper-board-game-celebrates-characters-90th-anniversary<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Diehard Disney fans have a new collectible to hunt down. In celebration of Donald Duck's 90th anniversary, The Walt Disney Company and Maestro Media have announced the <em>Donald Duck: Happy Camper</em> board game is now available.</p>

<h2>The <em>Donald Duck: Happy Camper</em> Announcement</h2>

<p>According to an official press release <em>Donald Duck: Happy Camper</em> is a board game that is both fun and accessible for players of all ages. Two to four players can complete a game in 30-45 minutes, making it perfect fit for family game nights.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/donald-duck-happy-camper-board-set-up.jpg?itok=_bLt2QKD 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/donald-duck-happy-camper-board-set-up.jpg?itok=_uvPaMSy 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>The game in question is exactly what it looks like on the box. Players are on a camping trip with Donald, Webby, Huey, Dewie, and Louie. Players will explore the wilderness, set up camp, take scenic photos, and earn Junior Woodchuck badges. All of these activities earn points, however you get bonus points for doing them first. Race among your friends to get the most out of your camping trip.</p>

<p><em>Donald Duck: Happy Camper</em> was designed by Wolfgang Kramer and Daryl Andrews. Kramer is the five-time winner of the Spiel des Jahres and the lead designer of <em>El Grande</em>. Andrews won the 2022 Game Innovator of the Year award and was the designer of <em>Sagrada</em>.</p>

<p>The game marks the first collaboration between the Walt Disney Company and Maestro Media. Maestro was founded in 2015 known for adapting various properties into tabletop games and merchandise. Their past works include<a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/binding-of-isaac-four-souls-requiem-expansion-announced" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"> </a><em><a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/binding-of-isaac-four-souls-requiem-expansion-announced" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Binding of Isaac: Four Souls</a>, <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/maestro-media-announces-multi-year-partnership-to-create-hello-kitty-tabletop-games" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Hello Kitty</a>,</em> and <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/maestro-media-announces-smurfs-board-game" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"><em>The Smurfs: Hidden Village</em></a>.</p>

<blockquote>
<p>“We are honored to work with Disney on this special project celebrating Donald Duck’s 90th anniversary and we’ve been working hard behind the scenes to create a game that captures the fun and magic of Disney!” said Javon Frazier, Founder and CEO of Maestro Media. “Grab your family and friends for a camping experience full of laughs, surprises, and a whole lot of quacking!”</p>
</blockquote>

<p><em>Donald Duck: Happy Camper</em> is available for purchase now on Maestro's website. It is currently being sold at an MSRP of $39.99.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Ever since he was small, Tyler Chancey has had a deep, abiding love for video games and a tendency to think and overanalyze everything he enjoyed. This… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/tyler-chancey">More about Tyler</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Patent Confirms Switch 2 Joy-Con's Most Innovative Feature]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/switch-2-joycon-mouse-pc-civ-7-halo-nintendo-direct-1851757351</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-patent-confirms-switch-2-joy-cons-most-innovative-feature.1102479/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/switch-2-joycon-mouse-pc-civ-7-halo-nintendo-direct-1851757351<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="8997bcdff410a320304a57d189ed8068" data-recommend-id="image://8997bcdff410a320304a57d189ed8068" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A Switch 2 patent appears on the screen of a Switch 2. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A Switch 2 patent appears on the screen of a Switch 2. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Nintendo / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="8997bcdff410a320304a57d189ed8068" data-recommend-id="image://8997bcdff410a320304a57d189ed8068" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A Switch 2 patent appears on the screen of a Switch 2. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>Fans have been speculating about <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/switch-2-pc-mouse-joycon-civilization-7-1851741008&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/switch-2-pc-mouse-joycon-civilization-7-1851741008">PC gaming mouse-like functionality for the Switch 2</a></span> ever since optical sensors appeared in leaks last month. Nintendo then teased the feature in the new Switch’s reveal trailer shortly after. Now the potential game-changer has been all but officially announced thanks to a new patent breaking down how  the Joy-Con mouse functionality will work.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196181" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="The Best Reveals From The Game Awards 2023" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="180" data-playlist="196181,196230,194644" data-current="196181"><div><p>The Best Reveals From The Game Awards 2023</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196181/196181_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196181/196181_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196181/196181_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196181/196181_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21718.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>The patent documents were filed back in 2023 and <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://patentscope.wipo.int/search/en/detail.jsf?docId=WO2025027803&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://patentscope.wipo.int/search/en/detail.jsf?docId=WO2025027803" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">published on Thursday</a></span> before being shared on social media <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/Wario64/status/1887587009067102593&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/Wario64/status/1887587009067102593" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">by Wario64</a></span>. “This input device comprises a front surface, an upper surface, a first side surface, a second side surface, a direction input unit, a first upper surface button, and a sensor for mouse operation,” it reads. </p><p>The patent description continues, “The sensor for mouse operation detects reflected light from a detected surface, the light changing by moving over the detected surface in a state in which either the first side surface or the second side surface is placed on the detected surface.”</p><p>This confirms what many fans suspected upon seeing the Joy-Con controllers sliding around a surface on their sides during the announcement trailer last month. Presumably, the “mouse operation” feature will allow some games on Switch 2 to be played with either traditional controller inputs or mouse inputs. </p><p>That could make it ideal for games like <em>Civilization 7</em> and potentially shooters like <em>Fortnite </em>and<em> Call of Duty</em>, which Microsoft is expected to begin porting to the Switch 2 at some point in the future. Other Microsoft shooters like <em>Halo</em> and <em>Doom</em> are also expected to get ported at some point, and the new Joy-Con could let players aim with traditional PC mouse precision while moving and strafing with a controller thumbstick. </p><p>Even more exciting is how Nintendo might find ways to use a dual-mouse feature for creative new gameplay. One of the patent drawings shows both Joy-Con being used as mice simultaneously. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.patreon.com/jeffgerstmann&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.patreon.com/jeffgerstmann" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">On his podcast</a></span>, <em>Giant Bomb</em> co-founder Jeff Gerstmann speculated that dual mice might let players control something like a mech with two reticles for aiming arm-mounted weapons. Or it could be used for some very weird, innovative launch game only Nintendo would think of. We’ll know better when the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/nintendo-direct-switch-2-release-date-april-2025-1851740848&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/nintendo-direct-switch-2-release-date-april-2025-1851740848">Switch 2 Nintendo Direct airs in April</a></span>. </p><p>.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What is the CS2 Active Duty Map Pool? All Currently Active CS2 Maps]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/what-is-the-cs2-active-duty-map-pool/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/what-is-the-cs2-active-duty-map-pool-all-currently-active-cs2-maps.1102476/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/what-is-the-cs2-active-duty-map-pool/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Valve and numerous community creators have created hundreds of Counter-Strike maps over the years, but CS2 currently utilizes what’s called the Active Duty map pool. Active Duty maps, in Valve’s own words, represent the most balanced and competitive maps in the total pool.</p>



<p>But the Active Duty pool is subject to change, in order to keep the iconic first-person shooter gameplay from feeling too stale.</p>



<p><em>Before you jump below, consider&nbsp;<a href="https://trk.clash.gg/click?o=2&amp;a=47&amp;c=11&amp;sub_id1=Best4" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">trying your luck on Clash.gg</a>&nbsp;– you could turn your unwanted skins into something much more valuable (18+ only)</em></p>



<h2 id="h-what-is-the-current-cs2-active-duty-map-pool">What is the current CS2 Active Duty map pool?</h2>



<p>The Active Duty map pool consists of seven maps that are used in CS2’s primary competitive mode, Premier. The Active Duty map pool is also the selection of maps used at every competitive tournament, from smaller online and local events to the illustrious Majors.</p>



<p>While Valve doesn’t always make a change to the Active Duty pool after every Major, the changes do occur then. This gives pro teams time to get used to the current map pool before the start of the next Major.</p>



<p><strong>Here is the current Active Duty map pool in Counter-Strike 2:</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Ancient</li>



<li>Anubis</li>



<li>Dust II</li>



<li>Inferno</li>



<li>Mirage</li>



<li>Nuke</li>



<li>Train</li>
</ul>



<p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/cs2-adds-train-to-map-pool/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Train is the newest addition to the Active Duty pool</a>, having been added in January 2025 after making its CS2 debut months earlier. Mirage is the longest standing map in the Active Duty pool, and it is the only map that has never been rotated out. Mirage has been played at every single Counter-Strike Major, dating back to DreamHack Winter 2013. Overpass, Cobblestone, Vertigo, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/where-is-cache-in-counter-strike-2-answered/">and Cache</a> have also spent time in the Active Duty pool.</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>The Active Duty pool is only a fraction of the total number of maps available in Counter-Strike 2. CS2 also features newer community creations like Edin and Basalt, or the maps specifically made for modes like Wingman or Arms Race. Still, Active Duty maps are the most recognizable ones to most Counter-Strike players.</p>



<p>How would you change the Active Duty map pool after the next Major? Let us know in the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<p><em>If you want to unlock free daily cases and rewards in CS2,&nbsp;<a href="https://trk.clash.gg/click?o=2&amp;a=47&amp;c=11&amp;sub_id1=Best4" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">check out Clash.gg</a>&nbsp;(18+ only)</em></p>



<hr>



<p>Stay tuned to Insider Gaming for the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/category/esports/">latest esports news</a>. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Patent Shows Nintendo Switch 2 Joy-Con Used As Wireless Mouse]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/patent-shows-nintendo-switch-2-joy-con-used-as-wireless-mouse/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/patent-shows-nintendo-switch-2-joy-con-used-as-wireless-mouse.1102473/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/patent-shows-nintendo-switch-2-joy-con-used-as-wireless-mouse/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-88928">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>The tease of wireless mouse functionality for the new Joy-Cons on the Nintendo Switch 2 appears to be more than just that. A recently <a href="https://patentscope.wipo.int/search/en/detail.jsf?docId=WO2025027803" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">discovered patent</a> seems to explain the feature while also providing drawings of the mouse functionality.</p>



<p>According to the patent, the Joy-Con features a “mouse operation sensor” that “detects reflected light from the detected surface that changes by moving on the detected surface with one of the first side surface and the second side surface placed on the detected surface.”</p>







<p>The sensor is located under the side of the Joy-Con—callout 170 in the images below. Based on the images, it appears players will be able to use one Joy-Con as a mouse while using the other in a standard way. Both Joy-Cons, however, appear to have the mouse sensor feature.</p>



<p>You can see the patent drawings depicting the feature below (click the image to enlarge).</p>



<figure>
<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>
</figure>







<p>Full details on how this new use for the Joy-Con have yet to be revealed. However, it could be assumed that Nintendo will go into more detail on that when it hosts its Nintendo Switch 2 <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-confirms-switch-2-direct-start-time/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">direct event on April 2</a>. During the show, Nintendo is expected to reveal full specs about the console as well as show the first set of games for the system. A price and release date announcement is also anticipated.</p>



<p>What do you think of this new mouse functionality for the Nintendo Switch 2 Joy-Cons? Let us know down below, and join more discussions in the official&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums.</a></p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, check out the official&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-confirms-switch-2-direct-start-time/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">start time for the Nintendo Switch 2 direct</a>&nbsp;and read about the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ea-working-major-apex-legends-update-after-battlefield/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">current plans for Apex Legends</a>&nbsp;from EA. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/smite-2-developer-hi-rez-holds-more-layoffs/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/smite-2-developer-hi-rez-holds-more-layoffs/">Smite 2 Developer Hi-Rez Holds More Layoffs As CEO Deletes Social Media</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Smite 2 developer Hi-Rez has held more layoffs across multiple departments of the company, including development and esports.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/assassins-creed-shadows-prequel-manga/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/assassins-creed-shadows-prequel-manga/">Assassin’s Creed Shadows is Receiving an Official Prequel Manga&nbsp;</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Today, Ubisoft revealed that a prequel manga for Assassin’s Creed Shadows will debut in Japan with the game.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/more-power-rangers-content-is-coming-to-ark-survival-ascended/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/more-power-rangers-content-is-coming-to-ark-survival-ascended/">More Power Rangers Content Is Coming To Ark: Survival Ascended</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Studio Wildcard has announced that more Power Rangers content is coming to Ark: Survival Evolved, including new character and creature skins.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-esa-announces-new-iicon-conference-for-visionaries/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-esa-announces-new-iicon-conference-for-visionaries/">The ESA Announces New Iicon Conference For “Visionaries”</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>The ESA has announced a new conference dubbed “Iicon” that is “tailored for visionaries” and “changemakers”.</p>
                    </div>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Madden NFL 25 Hits Game Pass Today, And Now You Can Make Your Super Bowl Predictions]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/madden-nfl-25-hits-game-pass-today-and-now-you-can-make-your-super-bowl-predictions/1100-6529306/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/madden-nfl-25-hits-game-pass-today-and-now-you-can-make-your-super-bowl-predictions.1102470/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/madden-nfl-25-hits-game-pass-today-and-now-you-can-make-your-super-bowl-predictions/1100-6529306/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-main">

      
                    
  
              <header id="masthead"><nav></nav></header>      
                            <div id="site-wrapper" role="main">
          <div id="default-content">
        
          <p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p>
  
    <article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529306">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/madden-nfl-25-review-gridiron-grates/1900-6418271/" data-ref-id="1900-6418271">Madden NFL 25</a> debuted last summer shortly before the start of the current NFL season, so it's fitting that it <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/new-xbox-game-pass-titles-revealed-for-february-2025-including-starfield-for-standard-tier/2900-6219/" data-ref-id="2900-6219">arrived on Game Pass today</a> before the end of the post-season. That means Game Pass Ultimate and PC Game Pass subscribers can run their own Super Bowl simulations before the Kansas City Chiefs and the Philadelphia Eagles meet again on Sunday.</p><p>EA has traditionally released its Madden NFL Super Bowl predictions ahead of the game, but the publisher has yet to do so this year. Officially, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/madden-super-bowl-predictions-over-the-years-how-often-does-ea-get-it-right/1100-6487137/" data-ref-id="1100-6487137">Madden NFL's Super Bowl projections</a> have only been right six out of the last 13 years, which gives it a 46% accuracy rating. Some years are closer than others, but Madden NFL successfully picked the exact score for Super Bowl 49 before the New England Patriots downed the Seattle Seahawks 28-24.</p><p>You may have noticed that the cover athlete for Madden NFL 25--Christian McCaffrey--doesn't play for either the Chiefs or the Eagles. Instead, McCaffrey is a running back for the San Francisco 49ers who <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/madden-25-cover-athlete-christian-mccaffrey-injured-will-miss-4-games/1100-6526490/" data-ref-id="1100-6526490">spent some time on the injured list</a> this year, reviving talk about <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/super-bowl-2020-patrick-mahomes-and-the-madden-cur/1100-6473047/" data-ref-id="1100-6473047">the infamous Madden curse</a>. The reality is that football is a physically taxing sport, and almost every player deals with injuries at some point. That hasn't stopped Cincinnati Bengals wide receiver Ja'Marr Chase from proclaiming that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nfls-best-wide-receiver-is-aware-of-madden-curse-doesnt-want-to-be-cover-star/1100-6528594/" data-ref-id="1100-6528594">he's aware of the so-called curse</a>, and doesn't want to be a Madden NFL cover star.</p><p>Madden NFL 26 will likely arrive this summer, but it has yet to receive an official announcement from EA. Although it's been 13 years since Madden appeared on a Nintendo console, EA is very optimistic about the franchise <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/madden-may-return-to-nintendo-with-switch-2-ea-ceo-hints/1100-6529253/" data-ref-id="1100-6529253">making a comeback on Switch 2</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article>

    
  

</div>
                      <meta itemprop="seamless-content-list-items" data-list-items="[{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529297&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/madden-isnt-the-only-football-game-you-can-play-to-get-hyped-for-the-super-bowl\/1100-6529297\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529253&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/madden-may-return-to-nintendo-with-switch-2-ea-ceo-hints\/1100-6529253\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529229&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/mlb-the-show-25-revamps-road-to-the-show-adds-high-school-and-college-ball\/1100-6529229\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529227&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/mlb-the-show-25-limited-edition-is-up-for-preorder-includes-topps-baseball-card\/1100-6529227\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529256&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/now-we-know-exactly-when-switch-2-nintendo-direct-is-happening\/1100-6529256\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529195&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/triguns-new-deluxe-edition-manga-is-50-off-at-amazon\/1100-6529195\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529201&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/gta-6-will-be-worth-the-wait-so-just-be-patient-gta-5-actor-says\/1100-6529201\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529198&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/need-for-speed-isnt-dead-but-criterion-is-focused-on-road-ahead-with-battlefield\/1100-6529198\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529199&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/why-the-last-of-us-season-2-made-this-major-change-to-abby\/1100-6529199\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529200&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/fallout-season-2-leaked-pic-teases-trip-to-new-vegas\/1100-6529200\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529197&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/esa-warns-trump-tariffs-could-harm-the-video-game-industry\/1100-6529197\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529251&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/get-the-entire-destiny-2-experience-for-30-at-humble\/1100-6529251\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6524458&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/mega-bloks-pokemon-pokedex-building-set-is-nearly-50-off-only-18-at-amazon\/1100-6524458\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529234&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-off-to-an-enormous-start-on-steam\/1100-6529234\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529260&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/apex-legends-season-24-kicks-off-with-big-buffs-to-weapons-and-a-quicker-time-to-kill\/1100-6529260\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529252&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/ea-reacts-to-dragon-age-the-veilguard-coming-up-short-and-explains-what-happened\/1100-6529252\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529254&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-npcs-can-catch-you-if-you-dont-bathe-and-smell-bad\/1100-6529254\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529255&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/these-analysts-expect-the-switch-2-will-launch-for-400\/1100-6529255\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529245&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/onimusha-2-samurais-destiny-gets-a-modern-remaster-this-year\/1100-6529245\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529258&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/it-sounds-like-battlefield-6s-release-date-will-avoid-gta-6\/1100-6529258\/&quot;}]">
            </div>
              
    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Avowed Is Now Capable Of Running At 60FPS On Xbox Series X, Will Have "Jank" At Launch]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/avowed-is-now-capable-of-running-at-60fps-on-xbox-series-x-will-have-jank-at-launch/1100-6529303/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/avowed-is-now-capable-of-running-at-60fps-on-xbox-series-x-will-have-jank-at-launch.1102467/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/avowed-is-now-capable-of-running-at-60fps-on-xbox-series-x-will-have-jank-at-launch/1100-6529303/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529303">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Microsoft's next big game, the RPG Avowed from The Outer Worlds developer Obsidian, is capable of running at up to 60fps on Xbox Series X, game director Carrie Patel has confirmed.</p><p>Patel said on the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dAtStowg2Rk" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">MinnMax podcast</a>, "You can get up to 60[fps]" on Xbox Series X. The use of "can" here might indicate an alternative graphics mode that prioritizes image quality over frame rate, but we don't know for sure as of yet.</p><p>The frame rate reaching 60fps on Series X is newsworthy in part because Obsidian previously said the game was <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/avowed-will-be-30fps-on-xbox-series-x-allowing-for-juicier-visual-effects/1100-6526077/" data-ref-id="1100-6526077">only capable of reaching 30fps on Xbox Series X.</a> Obsidian said this decision was made early on in the development of the game and has allowed the studio to get "a lot juicier" with visual effects. Things have changed since then, though, and Avowed can now run at a higher frame rate on Series X.</p><p>Patel also told fans to expect some amount of bugs and issues. "You gotta accept a little jank to do something fun and creative, I think," Patel said.</p><p>Avowed was previously set for release at the end of 2024 but was <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/xbox-boss-says-avowed-was-delayed-due-to-scheduling-not-quality/1100-6527757/" data-ref-id="1100-6527757">delayed to February for scheduling purposes, not due to quality.</a> The game officially launches on February 18, but the $90 Premium edition unlocks five days early, beginning February 13.</p><p>Like Microsoft's other first-party games, Avowed is included with Game Pass Ultimate at launch. Members can <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/game-pass-members-can-upgrade-to-avoweds-90-premium-edition-for-a-fraction-of-the-price/1100-6529257/" data-ref-id="1100-6529257">buy an upgrade add-on to the Premium edition for $22.50 to get all the perks</a>, including early access.</p><p>Avowed is Obsidian's first new release since 2022's Pentiment. It's not Obsidian's only in-development project, either, as the studio is also making <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/the-outer-worlds-2/" data-ref-id="5000-533237">The Outer Worlds 2</a>, which is planned for release this year.</p><p>For more, be sure to check out GameSpot's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/avowed-steelbook-premium-edition-is-up-for-preorder-comes-with-five-day-early-access/1100-6527801/" data-ref-id="1100-6527801">Avowed preorder guide.</a></p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apex Legends Season 24 Lets Livestreamers Run The Show]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/apex-legends-season-24-lets-livestreamers-run-the-show/1100-6529305/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/apex-legends-season-24-lets-livestreamers-run-the-show.1102464/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/apex-legends-season-24-lets-livestreamers-run-the-show/1100-6529305/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529305">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">A new gameplay trailer for <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/apex-legends/">Apex Legends</a>' upcoming <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/apex-legends-season-24-kicks-off-with-big-buffs-to-weapons-and-a-quicker-time-to-kill/1100-6529260/">Season 24: Takeover</a> has been released, and it features a major surprise: Respawn is kicking off Apex's sixth anniversary by letting content creators step into the shoes of the (fictional) Apex Games Commissioner, <a href="https://apexlegends.fandom.com/wiki/Kuben_Blisk" rel="nofollow ">Kuben Blisk</a>.</p><p dir="ltr">Four different "Content Commissioners" will take the stage from February 25 to April 28 (two weeks per content creator), introducing special challenges for players to overcome, exclusive cosmetic rewards, and fan-favorite limited-time modes for the duration of their two-week takeover.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="2127706205" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6465669,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Apex%20Legends%3A%20Takeover%20Gameplay%20Trailer&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:139,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/apex-legends-takeover-gameplay-trailer\/2300-6465669\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465669\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465669\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465669\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6465669&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6465669,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6529305&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;apex-legends&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;action,first-person,shooter,tactical&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;playstation-4,xbox-one,pc,nintendo-switch,playstation-5,xbox-series-x&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;electronic-arts&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;franchise&quot;:&quot;apex-legends&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;franchiseRoot&quot;:&quot;titanfall&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6465669},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6465669\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;Publisher Asset&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4439829-11.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/jfknLiBW.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1738859400,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="jfknLiBW" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> Apex Legends: Takeover Gameplay Trailer</p>
      </div>
<p dir="ltr">For the first week of each Content Commissioner takeover, players will "chase glory together to complete Community challenges and ultimately determine how many Apex Packs will be up for grabs the following week," according to <a href="https://www.ea.com/games/apex-legends/news/takeover-game-updates" rel="nofollow ">a new blog post</a> on the official Apex Legends website.</p><p dir="ltr">The community goals for the first week of each takeover are as follows:</p><ul><li dir="ltr"><strong>Complete Tier 1 challenges:</strong> 10 Apex Packs earnable</li><li dir="ltr"><strong>Complete Tier 2 challenges:</strong> 15 Apex Packs earnable</li><li dir="ltr"><strong>Complete Tier 3 challenges:</strong> 20 Apex Packs earnable</li></ul><p dir="ltr">The second week of each takeover is when players will get a chance to earn those Apex Packs. Players will be faced with five in-game challenges. Players who complete all five will gain access to the Apex Packs they unlocked during the previous week, along with a special Creator Commissioner-selected Legendary-tier weapon skin.</p><p dir="ltr">Players can also earn a free banner frame via Twitch Drops if they tune in to a Twitch stream from an approved Apex Legends content creator. A free Creator Commissioner-themed stat tracker will be available for players to <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/how-to-send-gifts-in-apex-legends/1100-6508429/">gift to their friends</a> via the in-game store.</p><p dir="ltr">The Apex Legends Season 24 Creator Commissioners schedule--and the Legendary-tier skins they've chosen for their two-week time in the spotlight--are listed below:</p><ul><li dir="ltr"><strong>February 25 - March 10:</strong> <a href="https://www.twitch.tv/ninjayla">Ninjayla</a> (Legendary skin: Death Ray Wingman)</li><li dir="ltr"><strong>March 11 - 24:</strong> <a href="https://www.twitch.tv/oraxe">Oraxe</a> (Legendary skin: The Pioneer Kraber)</li><li dir="ltr"><strong>April 1 - 14:</strong> <a href="https://www.twitch.tv/apryze">Apryze</a> (Legendary skin: Bone Breaker Mastiff)</li><li dir="ltr"><strong>April 15 - 28:</strong> <a href="https://www.twitch.tv/kaminariqpi/">Kaminari Qpi</a> (Legendary skin: Tombstick Mastiff)</li></ul><p dir="ltr">Respawn hasn't yet announced which limited-time modes will be available during the Creator Commissioner takeovers, though more information is likely to be shared when the Season 24 patch notes are released. The trailer did mention that both Ash and Ballistic were buffed, and details on those changes will also be available once patch notes are live.</p><p dir="ltr">The trailer also gave players a glimpse of the game's new Arsenals: special Loot Bins available in battle royale mode that include a weapon, ammo for that weapon, and a special attachment or hop-up for that weapon.</p><p dir="ltr">Apex Legends Season 24: Takeover begins on Tuesday, February 11 at 10 AM PT / 1 PM ET.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Prime Gaming gets another 20 games in February, including one for Xbox]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/prime-gaming-gets-another-20-games-in-february-including-one-for-xbox</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/prime-gaming-gets-another-20-games-in-february-including-one-for-xbox.1102458/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/prime-gaming-gets-another-20-games-in-february-including-one-for-xbox<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div>
        

        <p>BioShock Infinite! Talos Principle! More!</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/prime-gaming-feb-25.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Eurogamer</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
With February upon us, it's time to vigorously rub hands together as subscription services up and down the land lob a fresh batch of titles at their members, expanding those already bulging backlogs to increasingly calamtous extremes. And now it's Amazon's turn, with the company having announced 20 more titles it's bringing to Prime Gaming before February is through.
</p>
<p>
This month's offerings - as is customary for Prime Gaming - arrive over the course of several scheduled content drops. And following the inclusion of <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/bioshock-2">BioShock 2</a> Remastered in <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/amazon-reveals-16-titles-heading-to-prime-gaming-in-january">last month's Prime Gaming bucket</a>, February's line-up continues the theme with the inclusion of <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/bioshock-infinite">BioShock Infinite</a>. That's available right now, alongside the likes of <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/the-talos-principle">The Talos Principle</a>: Gold Edition, which bundles together Croteam's excellent philosophically minded puzzler and all its DLC.
</p>
<p>
Then, as we get further into February, Prime Gaming subscribers can look forward to a whole bunch more title,s including sci-fi salvage sim Hardspace: Shipbreaker, RPG deckbuilder Dark Sky, isometric stealth adventure El Hijo – A Wild West Tale, and <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/deus-ex-human-revolution">Deus Ex: Human Revolution</a>. Additionally, <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/wolfenstein-youngblood">Wolfenstein: Youngblood</a> pops up before the end of the most, which is mostly notable for the fact its Microsoft Store code means it's playable on both Xbox and PC. The full list of incoming titles (plus the stores they can be grabbed from) are below.
</p>
<p>
<strong>Available now:</strong>
</p>
<ul>
<li>BioShock Infinite Complete Edition [GOG Code]</li>
<li>Surf World Series [Amazon Games App]</li>
<li>AK-xolotl: Together [Epic Games Store]</li>
<li>Sands of Aura [Epic Games Store]</li>
<li>The Talos Principle: Gold Edition [GOG Code]</li>
</ul>
<p>
<strong>13th February:</strong>
</p>
<ul>
<li>Stunt Kite Party [Amazon Games App]</li>
<li>The Smurfs 2 - The Prisoner of the Green Stone [GOG Code]</li>
<li>Hardspace: Shipbreaker [Epic Games Store]</li>
<li>Lysfanga: The Time Shift Warrior [Epic Games Store]</li>
<li>Dark Sky [GOG Code]</li>
</ul>
<p>
<strong>20th February:</strong>
</p>
<ul>
<li>Wolfenstein: Youngblood [Xbox and PC via Microsoft Store Code]</li>
<li>El Hijo – A Wild West Tale [Epic Games Store]</li>
<li>Colt Canyon [GOG Code]</li>
<li>Republic of Jungle [Epic Games Store]</li>
<li>Royal Romances: Cursed Hearts Collector's Edition [Legacy Games Code]</li>
</ul>
<p>
<strong>27th February:</strong>
</p>
<ul>
<li>Deus Ex: Human Revolution - Director's Cut [GOG Code]</li>
<li>Night Reverie [Amazon Games App]</li>
<li>Sine Mora EX [Amazon Games App]</li>
<li>Redemption Reapers [Epic Games Store]</li>
<li>Yes, Your Grace [GOG Code]</li>
</ul>
<p>
Alongside all the above, Prime Gaming subscribers in the UK, US, Canada, Germany, France, Italy, Spain, Austria, the Netherlands, and Poland get access to a rotating selection of titles via Amazon's cloud gaming service, Luna. This month, these include Nobody Saves the World Complete, Ride 4, Devil May Cry 5, Batora: Lost Haven, and Hot Wheels Unleashed 2 — Turbocharged. That's alongside Luna regulars Fallout New Vegas: Ultimate Edition, Fallout 3: Game of the Year Edition, Fortnite, and Trackmania.

</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hi-Rez Studios Lays Off Developers from Smite Team]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/hi-rez-studios-lays-off-developers-from-smite-team/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hi-rez-studios-lays-off-developers-from-smite-team.1102431/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/hi-rez-studios-lays-off-developers-from-smite-team/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The last layoffs from Hi-Rez Studios came in late 2024, and now they have seemingly conducted layoffs again this week. At the time of writing, approximately 30 employees have revealed that they were impacted by these layoffs across social media. Their announcements have been compiled into a single <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Smite/comments/1ij5sjy/hirez_layoffs_megathread/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Reddit megathread</a>.</p>
<p>So far, the reason behind the layoffs hasn't been disclosed.&nbsp;<span><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:7293312305092599809/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Jake Lucky suggests</a></span> that the cuts to the team are "massive," with most of the layoffs impacting the Smite team, with a team currently working on Smite 2, which is in Open Beta.</p>
<p>The previous layoffs at Hi-Rez came in <a href="https://wccftech.com/smite-developer-hi-rez-lays-off-employees-focusing-on-smite-2/">October 2024</a>, with the impacted staff working on cosmetic and system features on the original Smite. However, this new round of layoffs seems to have impacted a wide variety of roles across the company. This includes producers, designers, programmers, and even Esports commentators.</p>
<p>It's uncertain whether Hi-Rez will make a comment about these layoffs or whether they are trying to keep them on the down low. However, when the layoffs in October took place, CEO Stewart Chisam took to social media to explain the reasoning behind the layoffs, saying that it was to ensure the longevity of Smite 2, with hopes that the game would "last into the 2030s."</p>
<p>However, since those layoffs, Chisam's X account has been deleted, which is where he originally made his announcement regarding the layoffs. His announcement was also posted on LinkedIn. At present, there has been no sign of an announcement or explanation behind these layoffs.</p>
<p>The staff impacted have been releasing their statements regarding their time at Hi-Rez Studios and also going on to express their frustration regarding the layoffs. Some stated that they knew that it was coming, even though they felt it shouldn't have happened.</p>
<p>It's likely that this is part of a strategy shift, much like the layoffs that took place in October, to downsize the amount of staff that are currently working on the original Smite. Whether any of the staff members impacted will be given an opportunity to transfer to other departments within the company remains to be seen, alongside whether or not Hi-Rez Studios will be aiding the staff impacted.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New 2K Sale Gives You 20 Games For $20, But There's A Catch]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/steam-sale-2k-civ-borderlands-mafia-pc-20-for-20-deal-1851757287</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-2k-sale-gives-you-20-games-for-20-but-theres-a-catch.1102425/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/steam-sale-2k-civ-borderlands-mafia-pc-20-for-20-deal-1851757287<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="ef71e1197684fc9bc1c4a0f138c8fe8a" data-recommend-id="image://ef71e1197684fc9bc1c4a0f138c8fe8a" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->2K Games / Valve / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="ef71e1197684fc9bc1c4a0f138c8fe8a" data-recommend-id="image://ef71e1197684fc9bc1c4a0f138c8fe8a" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>This year marks the 20th anniversary of <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/michael-condrey-projet-ethos-31st-union-2k-games-1851756173&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/michael-condrey-projet-ethos-31st-union-2k-games-1851756173">2K Games</a></span>. Normally we don’t celebrate publisher birthdays, but we’ll make an exception this time as 2K Games is honoring the milestone with a big sale on Steam that has one particularly noteworthy offer: a package that includes 20 games for $20. Is this an incredible deal? Maybe. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196653" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="The Week In Games: A Star Wars Classic Returns &amp; More New Releases" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="105" data-playlist="196653,195371,195386" data-current="196653"><div><p>The Week In Games: A Star Wars Classic Returns &amp; More New Releases</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196653/196653_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196653/196653_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196653/196653_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196653/196653_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/22209.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>On February 6, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://store.steampowered.com/sale/2k20thanniversary&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://store.steampowered.com/sale/2k20thanniversary" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">2K announced its massive 20th Anniversary sale event on Steam</a></span>. The publisher behind <em>Borderlands, Mafia, Bioshock, NBA 2K,</em> and more has marked down nearly all of its games available on Valve’s PC storefront. The exact discount varies game to game, but overall this is a massive sale that includes newer games like<em> </em><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/marvel-midnight-suns-impressions-xcom-firaxis-pc-rpg-1849793171&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/marvel-midnight-suns-impressions-xcom-firaxis-pc-rpg-1849793171"><em>Midnight Suns</em></a></span> and older games like <em>Civilization III.</em> The sale ends on February 20, which is cute. </p><p>The biggest deal in the 20th Anniversary sale, though, is the “20 for 20" bundle. This brings together 20 games into one big package that only costs $20. Here are the games included in the bundle: </p><blockquote data-type="BlockQuote"><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li><em>Sid Meier’s Civilization® IV, </em></li><li><em>Sid Meier’s Pirates!</em></li><li><em>Sid Meier’s Railroads!</em></li><li><em>Railroad Tycoon 3</em></li><li><em>BioShock</em></li><li><em>Borderlands Game of the Year </em>(And its DLC)</li><li><em>The Misadventures of P.B. Winterbottom</em></li><li><em>Mafia</em></li><li><em>Duke Nukem Forever</em></li><li><em>Sid Meier’s Civilization®: Beyond Earth</em></li><li><em>The Darkness II</em></li><li><em>Sid Meier’s Ace Patrol: Pacific Skies</em></li><li><em>Sid Meier’s Starships</em></li><li><em>Tales from the Borderlands</em></li><li><em>BioShock™ Remastered</em></li><li><em>Hidden &amp; Dangerous 2: Courage Under Fire</em></li><li><em>NBA 2K Playgrounds 2</em></li><li><em>Borderlands Game of the Year Enhanced</em></li><li><em>XCOM®: Chimera Squad</em></li><li><em>Godfall Ultimate Edition</em></li><li><em>Carnival Games</em></li><li><em>Tiny Tina’s Assault on Dragon Keep: A Wonderlands One-shot Adventure</em></li></ul></blockquote><p>That’s a lot of good games (and some bad games) for not much money. Seems like a great deal! And it is, but whether or not it’s a great deal <em>for you </em>depends on something. See, this bundle doesn’t give you a discount if you already own one or more games in it. And you don’t get extra copies of those games you already own. </p><p>So if, for example, you own<em> BioShock, The Darkness II, </em>and <em>Borderlands</em> already, you still have to pay $20 for this bundle and you don’t get digital copies of those games to give to friends. In that example, the deal becomes less great. It’s still not bad and you might still want the other games in the 20 for 20 bundle, but just double-check what you own already before purchasing the package. </p><p> .<br></p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Assassin’s Creed Shadows is Receiving an Official Prequel Manga]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/assassins-creed-shadows-prequel-manga/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/assassin%E2%80%99s-creed-shadows-is-receiving-an-official-prequel-manga.1102419/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/assassins-creed-shadows-prequel-manga/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-88926">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>Ubisoft is releasing a manga that will dive into the prequel story of Assassin’s Creed Shadows.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The official Assassin’s Creed <a href="https://x.com/assassinscreed/status/1887426010427089267" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">X</a> account (formerly Twitter) announced the arrival of this Shadows Prequel Manga today. Interested players can purchase it in Japan when the game releases on March 20, 2025. Availability for other regions will arrive later.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Assassin’s Creed Shadows prequel manga will focus on the journey of “a young Assassin apprentice.” It isn’t clear whether Naoe is this “Assassin apprentice,” as the cover art features a different woman. This Assassin will fight “against the growing presence of the Templars order in Japan.” The cover art features a woman perched on a roof, wearing the famed white Assassin hood. She holds a katana in her right hand and the iconic Hidden Blade in her left.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Some commenters have predicted that the woman featured in the cover art could be “<a href="https://x.com/SuperDropKick17/status/1887532530879942672" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Naoe’s Mom</a>.” Others wonder why nothing related to <a href="https://x.com/readonlyac36188/status/1887451162103763304" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Yasuke</a> was included in the cover art. More details about the manga should be revealed closer to release.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Assassin’s Creed Shadows can now be pre-ordered for $69.99 on PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X/S, and PC via Steam, Epic Games Store, and Ubisoft.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In other news, the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/assassins-creed-shadows-game-size/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">file size</a> of Assassin’s Creed Shadows was revealed through its listing on the Mac App Store. The game’s art book, which showcases new art, also <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/assassins-creed-shadows-artwork/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">leaked recently on an 18+ website</a>. What are your thoughts on the Assassin’s Creed Shadows prequel manga?&nbsp;Let us know in the comments or on our new&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-esa-announces-new-iicon-conference-for-visionaries/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the ESA announcing a new iicon conference for “Visionaries”</a>.&nbsp;Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/more-power-rangers-content-is-coming-to-ark-survival-ascended/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/more-power-rangers-content-is-coming-to-ark-survival-ascended/">More Power Rangers Content Is Coming To Ark: Survival Ascended</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Studio Wildcard has announced that more Power Rangers content is coming to Ark: Survival Evolved, including new character and creature skins.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-esa-announces-new-iicon-conference-for-visionaries/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-esa-announces-new-iicon-conference-for-visionaries/">The ESA Announces New Iicon Conference For “Visionaries”</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>The ESA has announced a new conference dubbed “Iicon” that is “tailored for visionaries” and “changemakers”.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/paradox-acquires-former-tropico-developer-haemimont-games/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/paradox-acquires-former-tropico-developer-haemimont-games/">Paradox Acquires Former Tropico Developer Haemimont Games</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Paradox Interactive has added another studio under its umbrella as the company has announced the acquisition of Haemimont Games. The move makes Haemimont Games a solely owned subsidiary of Paradox Interactive. “We are very happy to welcome Haemimont Games to Paradox!” Paradox CEO Fredrik Wester said via media release. “They bring a tight-knit team with […]</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/final-fantasy-16-xbox-release-announcement/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/final-fantasy-16-xbox-release-announcement/">Final Fantasy 16’s Xbox Release Announcement is Imminent, It’s Claimed</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Final Fantasy 16’s Xbox release announcement will reportedly arrive soon, and FF7 Remake could be released later this year for the platform. </p>
                    </div>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[More Power Rangers Content Is Coming To Ark: Survival Ascended]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/more-power-rangers-content-is-coming-to-ark-survival-ascended/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/more-power-rangers-content-is-coming-to-ark-survival-ascended.1102416/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/more-power-rangers-content-is-coming-to-ark-survival-ascended/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Even more Power Rangers content is coming to Ark. Studio Wildcard has announced that it, alongside CurseForge and Hasbro, have announced an expansion of its collaboration that will bring more of the Power Rangers into Ark: Survival Ascended.</p>



<p>Retailing for $9.99, the new mod pack is available starting today, February 6.</p>



<p>The expansion comes after the Power Rangers first made its debut with a premium mod in June 2024. The original mod introduced the five original Mighty Morphin’ Power Rangers—Red, Black, Yellow, Blue, and Pink—along with power weapons and the original Dinozords. </p>



<p>“With the ARK x&nbsp;Power&nbsp;Rangers&nbsp;Wave 2 Premium Mod, we aim to offer players a unique blend of nostalgic and modern gameplay, filled with detailed cosmetics and epic game styles that bring iconic IPs to life like never before,””” Alex Seropian, Founder and CEO of Look North World, said.</p>



<h6 id="h-more-insider-gaming-the-esa-announces-new-iicon-conference-for-visionaries">More Insider Gaming: <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-esa-announces-new-iicon-conference-for-visionaries/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The ESA Announces New Iicon Conference For “Visionaries”</a></h6>



<p>This new mod brings both the Green and White Rangers along with the Tigerzord, Titanus, Dragonzord, and Megazord.  Also joining as character skins are Lord Zedd, Rita Repulsa, Goldar, Alpha 5, and Putty. All characters will have unique emotes. </p>



<p>Lastly, new weapons such as Zedd’s staff, the Green Dagger, and White Saba Sword will be part of the mod pack.</p>



<p>You can check out the first look at the new skins and Zords in the gallery below (click an image to enlarge and slide through).</p>



<figure>
<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>
</figure>







<p>What do you think of more Power Rangers coming to Ark: Survival Ascended with this new mod pack? Let us know down below, and join more discussions in the official&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums.</a></p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read about the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/2k-fires-31st-union-president-after-project-ethos-poor-response/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">changes atop the studio</a>&nbsp;behind Project Ethos&nbsp;and find out the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/metal-gear-solid-3-release/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">release date for Metal Gear Solid 3: Snake Eater</a>. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our newsletter</a>.</p>




    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Is The 2005 Fantastic Four Movie As Bad As You Remember? Pretty Much]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/fantastic-four-first-steps-2005-movie-mcu-chris-evans-1851757273</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/is-the-2005-fantastic-four-movie-as-bad-as-you-remember-pretty-much.1102395/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/fantastic-four-first-steps-2005-movie-mcu-chris-evans-1851757273<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>We’re coming up on the 20th anniversary of 20th Century Fox’s first attempt at bringing the Fantastic Four to the big screen, and it’s probably been just as long since I watched the 2005 movie in full. Unlike <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/x-men-movies-best-worst-ranked-deadpool-logan-wolverine-1851595435&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/x-men-movies-best-worst-ranked-deadpool-logan-wolverine-1851595435">the <em>X-Men</em></a></span>, the First Family didn’t take off at all in the mid-2000s as the focus of a lucrative film franchise. While the movie got a sequel two years later, Fox axed plans for a full trilogy and we didn’t see Mr. Fantastic, Invisible Woman, Human Torch or The Thing back in theaters until the much-maligned 2015 reboot. With the characters now in the hands of Disney, and MCU entry <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/fantastic-four-first-steps-galactus-thing-trailer-mcu-1851755094&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/fantastic-four-first-steps-galactus-thing-trailer-mcu-1851755094"><em>Fantastic Four: First Steps</em></a></span><em> </em>just a few months out, I wondered if the original 2005 film was as bad as it’s remembered, so I pulled it up on Disney+ and gave it an earnest shot.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196406" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Why This Under-the-Radar AAA Title Is More Than Just A Far Cry Clone" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="102" data-playlist="196406,197298,197284" data-current="196406"><div><p>Why This Under-the-Radar AAA Title Is More Than Just A Far Cry Clone</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196406/196406_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196406/196406_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196406/196406_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196406/196406_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21954.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>Sadly, yeah, it’s pretty bad. The <em>Fantastic Four </em>movie is weighed down by too many of the worst aspects of its mid-2000s era, and I’m not just talking about very ropey CGI. There’s cheesy butt rock that follows the chaotic playboy Johnny Storm in nearly every scene he gets by himself, half the scenes are bogged down by a stilted Disney Channel awkwardness that never quite reaches endearing camp, and there’s even a blatant, intrusive ad for the original Xbox featured prominently onscreen at one point. But even with these aspects put aside, the movie fails to scratch the surface of why the Fantastic Four have been mainstays in Marvel’s catalog.</p><p>Sure, it hits the two major bullet points: The quartet goes up into space and is exposed to a cosmic cloud that alters their DNA and gives them superpowers, and a person going by the name Victor Von Doom is the baddy. The problem is that <em>Fantastic Four </em>portrays the fiery familial passion of the group with the intensity of lightly flavored mineral water. Ioan Gruffudd and Jessica Alba’s Mr. Fantastic and Invisible Woman are devoid of any romantic magnetism, but I’m supposed to believe they have a storied, angsty past as they argue about Reed’s meticulous nature in a flat monotone. Julian McMahon’s Doom is supposed to complete a love triangle, but everyone in this group talks to each other as if they just met at a bar, aren’t interested in each other, and are trying to politely let each other down. Making matters worse, Doom is such a non-presence in the film that when he starts to do villain-y things, it feels like someone speaking up at a party after sitting in the corner alone for an hour. I don’t believe he loves Sue (or even thinks he does) when he proposes to her. I barely believe that he’s human, even before he gets hit with cosmic rays and turns into a deteriorating metallic villain. Doom as a bastard billionaire instead of a mystical tyrant probably focus-tested better 20 years ago, but it’s another example of the movie robbing the <em>Fantastic Four </em>of any vibrancy.</p><p>The saving graces of the cast are Chris Evans as the Human Torch and Michael Chiklis as the Thing. Though I’m not thrilled with the throat-destroyingly gravelly voice Chiklis puts on, there are affecting moments when he struggles with his new golem-like appearance, trying to find people who will accept him now rather than cower in fear. Evans is the standout, however, and it’s not surprising that he would be the one to stay in the superhero business after these movies. He lucked out, being the only character who’s happy with this superpowered turn of events, but he’s also the only actor who seems excited to be there.</p><h2 id="h6960"><a id=""></a><strong>Fantastic Four’s biggest problem is that it’s boring</strong></h2><p>While many are wont to claim the Marvel Cinematic Universe is the harbinger of the end of cinema, at least many of its movies aren’t a complete slog. <em>Fantastic Four</em>, on the other hand,<em> </em>carries itself with a dreary level of self-seriousness. It’s a superpowered soap opera that lacks the charisma or chemistry that makes you care about the drama. The stoicism of this film is so suffocating that even Evans’ joy is smothered.</p><p>That’s <em>Fantastic Four</em>’s biggest problem: not the weird deviations from the source material, but just how boring it all is. Emotionally, visually, and cinematically, everything about the film is flat. I’m surprised that its memetic notoriety for being bad has persisted this long because it’s not even bad in any way that’s interesting; it’s simply forgettable. For a group of heroes known as a family above all else, it’s jarring how much this version of the Fantastic Four feels like coworkers acting out a corporate-mandated skit. It’s giving when your corpo boss says “We’re a family” and throws a pizza party.</p><p>It’s encouraging that <em>First Steps </em>seems to have learned some lessons from Fox’s failures, with the group’s proper MCU debut leaning into a distinct retro-future aesthetic that distinguishes it from the rest of the franchise. Hopefully it feels like the proper adaptation the First Family deserves when it premieres on July 25.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Watch Homelander Audition To Be James Bond As Fans Joke: 'Breast Milk, Squeezed Not Pumped']]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/henry-cavill-james-bond-homelander-audition-youtube-1851757227</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/watch-homelander-audition-to-be-james-bond-as-fans-joke-breast-milk-squeezed-not-pumped.1102392/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/henry-cavill-james-bond-homelander-audition-youtube-1851757227<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>In hindsight it feels like Daniel Craig was born to play James Bond, but picking who to play the world’s most iconic spy is is big decision with lots of risks. Many other actors tried out for the role in 2006's <em>Casino Royale </em>and their screen tests were recently uploaded to a small YouTube account for the whole world to gawk at. It’s a fascinating inside look at what might have been, and at just how awkward tryouts can be. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="197298" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Live Forever in the Universe of 'New World: Aeternum'" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="108" data-playlist="197298,197284,197260" data-current="197298"><div><p>Live Forever in the Universe of 'New World: Aeternum'</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"></video></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>Antony Starr, who currently plays the sociopathic Nazi superhero Homelander on <em>The Boys</em>, was one of those candidates tapped to do a screen test for the role of MI6's 007. In it, he recites a scene from the <em>GoldenEye </em>screenplay in which <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Oz8TYyn-k40&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Oz8TYyn-k40" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Bond is at a Blackjack table flirting with femme fatale assassin Xenia Onatopp</a></span>. Except instead of being in a fancy hotel, he’s acting from a bed in a random hotel room. </p><p>Starr punctuates a lot of the tit-for-tat dialogue with raised eyebrows and cocking his head to the side. There’s a ton of lip-smacking at the start of every line. It’s not great! But it’s one of the better “what if” <em>Bond</em> screen tests the mysterious Ron South YouTube account has uploaded so far:</p><p>Starr had appeared a bunch in the New Zealand show <em>Mercy Peak</em> at the time but was still basically unknown until he broke out years later with the crime drama <em>Banshee</em>. He’s of course best known now for his unhinged role in <em>The Boys</em>, spawning numerous notorious GIFs and memes in the process. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.gamesradar.com/entertainment/james-bond-movies/homelander-actor-antony-starrs-james-bond-screen-test-for-casino-royale-has-been-leaked-online-and-the-boys-fans-are-all-making-the-same-joke/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.gamesradar.com/entertainment/james-bond-movies/homelander-actor-antony-starrs-james-bond-screen-test-for-casino-royale-has-been-leaked-online-and-the-boys-fans-are-all-making-the-same-joke/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">So as <em>Gamesradar</em> notes</a></span>, existing fans have had a field day going back and imaging his James Bond performance through the lens of Homelander. “Breast milk, squeezed not pumped,” joked one user <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/JamesBond/comments/1iionw2/anthony_starr_james_bond_screen_tests_2005/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/JamesBond/comments/1iionw2/anthony_starr_james_bond_screen_tests_2005/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">on Reddit</a></span>. “Lander, Homelander,” wrote another (<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7vs8tZwRGOs&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7vs8tZwRGOs" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">if you’re not familiar with <em>The Boys </em>then, uh, how do I explain...</a></span>)</p><p>But screen tests are all relative. Moviemakers are looking for something they can work with, cultivate, and shape into what might be best in the final movie once everything is rehearsed, shot, edited, and brought to life with music, sets, costumes, and props. As twitchy and off as Starr’s test looks, Henry Cavill’s was arguably even rougher. </p><p>From the long black hair and facial stubble to the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://boymeetsworld.fandom.com/wiki/Jonathan_Turner&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://boymeetsworld.fandom.com/wiki/Jonathan_Turner" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Jonathan Turner biker jacket</a></span>, it’s all very not Bond. And then Cavill opens his mouth, almost speaking through gritted teeth, appearing almost ponderous at times. It reads like a young boy trying on daddy’s clothes in the mirror. Maybe a good place to explore for a Bond origin movie, but clearly not what the studio was looking for with <em>Casino Royale</em> (Cavill’s full-blown himbo hunk debut didn’t come until 2011's <em>Immortals</em>). </p><p>Of course, the movie’s producers maintain they always wanted Daniel Craig from the start. You can watch his much more polished screen test and see that they maybe had a point, and Starr, Cavill, and others may have just been backups in case the brooding <em>Layer Cake </em>star never said yes. Sean Connery apparently didn’t make a great first impression either when he was scouted for the role all those years ago. Bond author Ian Flemming <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.thegentlemansjournal.com/article/true-story-how-sean-connery-became-james-bond-007/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.thegentlemansjournal.com/article/true-story-how-sean-connery-became-james-bond-007/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">reportedly hated him for the part</a></span>. It wasn’t until he walked out of the 1962 premiere of <em>Dr. No </em>that he became a believer. </p><p>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mythwrecked: Ambrosia Island coming to PS5, PS4 in 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/02/mythwrecked-ambrosia-island-coming-to-ps5-ps4-in-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mythwrecked-ambrosia-island-coming-to-ps5-ps4-in-2025.1102383/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/02/mythwrecked-ambrosia-island-coming-to-ps5-ps4-in-2025<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Currently available for Xbox Series, Xbox One, Switch, and PC.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Whitethorn Games [33 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/whitethorn-games">Whitethorn Games</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Polygon Treehouse [7 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/polygon-treehouse">Polygon Treehouse</a> will release exploration friendship <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,028 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure game</a> <em><a title="Games > Mythwrecked: Ambrosia Island [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/mythwrecked-ambrosia-island">Mythwrecked: Ambrosia Island</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,790 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a> and <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,670 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a> in 2025, the companies announced. <span id="more-942431"></span></p><p><em>Mythwrecked: Ambrosia Island</em> first launched for Xbox Series, Xbox One, Switch, and PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2000210/Mythwrecked_Ambrosia_Island/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-us/games/store/mythwrecked-ambrosia-island/9nc4x3lp87tn" target="_blank">Microsoft Store</a> on December 5, 2024.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Whitethorn Games:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>In <em>Mythwrecked: Ambrosia Island</em>, players take on the role of backpacker Alex, who has found herself stranded on the mysterious shores of Ambrosia Island. As she begins to explore her surroundings, she discovers that she is not alone—the island is populated by the gods of Greek myth and legend! However, something is amiss—the gods are unable to remember who they are. In order to find her way home, she must befriend the inhabitants and help them to restore their memories.</p><p>Explore the dynamic island in this non-linear adventure inspired by elements of the Ace Attorney franchise and <a title="Games > A Short Hike [4 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/a-short-hike">A Short Hike</a>. Unravel the story of the island and build friendships with the gods through a unique relationship mechanic. The closer you become, the more they are willing to help Alex with their godly powers. Solve the mystery of Ambrosia Island, save the gods, and help Alex find a way back home!</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Gods <a title="Games > Among Us [8 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/among-us">Among Us</a></strong> – Many Gods call Ambrosia Island home, from Ares to Athena, Hermes to Hades. Tracking them all down is made easier with the Ambrosidex, though some may be harder to meet than others.</li><li><strong><a title="Companies > Treasure [14 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/treasure">Treasure</a> in the Sandbox</strong> – Use the radar signal on the Ambrosidex to hunt for lost godly treasures hidden all over the island! Return them to their rightful owners to help rekindle their memories and learn more about the island’s fate.</li><li><strong>Conversational Wizard</strong> – Explore the island, examine new objects and locations, and talk to others to unlock new conversation topics. Maybe some Gods know something that will help Alex on her adventure, but some sensitive topics may be off-limits until you have earned their friendship.</li><li><strong>Even Gods Need a Friend</strong> – <a title="Companies > Experience [210 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/experience">Experience</a> a non-linear, emotional story about the importance of friendship, family, and community.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span><a title="Platforms > PlayStation [46,883 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation">PlayStation</a> Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Mythwrecked: Ambrosia Island - PlayStation Announce Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/SuOIP4cLrLY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Slime Heroes coming to PS5, PS4 in 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/02/slime-heroes-coming-to-ps5-ps4-in-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/slime-heroes-coming-to-ps5-ps4-in-2025.1102377/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/02/slime-heroes-coming-to-ps5-ps4-in-2025<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Xbox Series, Xbox One, Switch, and PC versions launch February 13.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Whitethorn Games [33 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/whitethorn-games">Whitethorn Games</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Pancake Games [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/pancake-games">Pancake Games</a> will release 3D <a title="Genres > Action [2,468 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a> <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,028 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure game</a> <em><a title="Games > Slime Heroes [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/slime-heroes">Slime Heroes</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,790 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a> and <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,670 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a> in 2025, the companies announced. <span id="more-942430"></span></p><p><em>Slime Heroes</em> will launch first for Xbox Series, Xbox One, Switch, and PC via <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-us/games/store/slime-heroes/9nbr0qg1c3fq" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-us/games/store/slime-heroes/9nbr0qg1c3fq" target="_blank">Microsoft Store</a> on February 13.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Whitethorn Games:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>In <em>Slime Heroes</em>, journey through a whimsical world entrusted to an unlikely hero, a slime, tasked to save it from a mysterious corruption. Explore the expansive 3D world—alone or with a friend—and encounter ferocious enemies, challenging but approachable puzzles, and uncover forgotten treasures. Gain magical gems throughout the world and dynamically combine them to create unique and powerful magical skills that can take down even the most corrupt minions and bosses. Discover a touching story of overcoming expectations, friendship, and forgiveness as you progress because even slimes can be heroes!</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <ul><li><strong>Gain Abilities and Change Them Up On the Fly</strong> – Collect and consume an arsenal of gems obtained from defeating enemies, and dynamically combine skills to craft unique attacks that suit your playstyle at any time.</li><li><strong>Play Alone or With a Friend</strong> – Venture off solo or jump into a friend’s game at any time for a fun couch and online <a title="Genres > Co-Op [230 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer/co-op">cooperative</a> adventure. With a shared loot system, you’ll both be able to create complimentary abilities to take on the fiercest corrupted enemies.</li><li><strong>Travel Across an Expansive World</strong> – Explore six distinct regions in a vibrant, vast open world and meet the gods that rule over each region. Discover secret passageways, hidden areas and unique puzzle dungeons each with their own challenges to overcome.</li><li><strong>Make Your Slime Your Own</strong> – Give your slime some personality as you customize their face and colors to your liking. Find hats throughout the map that not only give your slime that little extra pizazz but also provide helpful stat buffs, keeping you fashionable and ready for battle.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span><a title="Platforms > PlayStation [46,883 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation">PlayStation</a> Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Slime Heroes - PlayStation Announce Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/pbmn_oLG7uU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dungeons of Hinterberg coming to PS5, PS4 on March 13]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/02/dungeons-of-hinterberg-coming-to-ps5-ps4-on-march-13</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dungeons-of-hinterberg-coming-to-ps5-ps4-on-march-13.1102374/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/02/dungeons-of-hinterberg-coming-to-ps5-ps4-on-march-13<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Currently available for Xbox Series, Xbox One, and PC.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Curve Games [55 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/curve-games">Curve Games</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Microbird [5 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/microbird">Microbird</a> will release single-player <a title="Genres > Action RPG [1,489 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg/action-rpg">action RPG</a> and social <a title="Genres > Simulation [643 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/simulation">simulation game</a> hybrid <em><a title="Games > Dungeons of Hinterberg [5 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/dungeons-of-hinterberg">Dungeons of Hinterberg</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,790 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a> and <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,670 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a> on March 13, the companies <a href="https://twitter.com/MicrobirdGames/status/1887517123456430204" target="_blank">announced</a>. Wishlisting is available now via <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/concept/10007196" target="_blank">PlayStation Store</a>. <span id="more-942461"></span></p><p><em>Dungeons of Hinterberg</em> first launched for Xbox Series and PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1983260/Dungeons_of_Hinterberg/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a>, <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/p/dungeons-of-hinterberg-854b1e" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Epic Games Store</a>, and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-us/games/store/dungeons-of-hinterberg/9pgx472j0rjp" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Microsoft Store</a> on July 18, 2024, followed by Xbox One on December 4, 2024.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Curve Games:</p><blockquote><p>Welcome to Hinterberg, a new tourist hotspot in the idyllic Austrian Alps! As Luisa, your escape from the treadmill of corporate life quickly unravels when the mysterious local dungeons stir back into life once more. Will you restore peace to this once-serene alpine paradise, or be sent straight back to your humdrum life back home?</p><p>Every inch of Hinterberg has been crafted with a captivating art style you’ll want to savor. Whether you’re snowboarding down a glacier, climbing mountains, or taking in the lakeside scenery, there’s so much available to explore.</p><p>Hinterberg’s dungeons are packed full of playful puzzles designed to surprise and challenge you. Get your thinking cap on and use every spell at your disposal to tackle each dungeon’s unique puzzling twist. Monsters lurk around every corner in Hinterberg, and your sword and magic skills are essential for keeping them at bay. Harness the wind, conjure a hoverboard out of thin air, or freeze your enemies in a jelly block.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Explore the world or conquer dungeons by day, then spend your evenings forging friendships with the locals and other adventurers in town. Some will help you get stronger, while others are here strictly for the excitement and the selfies. Stop by Olivia’s Store in town and browse through a collection of stylish outfits! Once you’re decked out in your finest, simply fire up Photo Mode where you can apply filters, poses and overlays to capture a lasting memory of your very own Luisa.</p></blockquote></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The First Twitch Stream From The International Space Station Is Happening On February 12]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-first-twitch-stream-from-the-international-space-station-is-happening-on-february-12/1100-6529302/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-first-twitch-stream-from-the-international-space-station-is-happening-on-february-12.1102371/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-first-twitch-stream-from-the-international-space-station-is-happening-on-february-12/1100-6529302/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529302">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">NASA will be hosting its first-ever Twitch stream from the International Space Station (ISS) next week. The National Aeronautics and Space Administration made the announcement via its official X (formerly Twitter) account, and shared some details on what viewers can expect from the stream.</p><p dir="ltr">"This Twitch event from space is the first of many," said Brittany Brown, who directs NASA's Office of Communications Digital and Technology Division. "We spoke with digital creators at TwitchCon about their desire for streams designed with their communities in mind, and we listened. In addition to our spacewalks, launches, and landings, we’ll host more Twitch-exclusive streams like this one. Twitch is one of the many digital platforms we use to reach new audiences and get them excited about all things space."</p><p>The stream itself will take place on the ISS--roughly 250 miles above Earth's surface--and will feature appearances from NASA astronauts Don Pettit (who is currently aboard the ISS) and Matt Dominick (who recently returned to Earth after participating in NASA's Crew-8 mission). The spacefaring duo will discuss topics like daily life aboard the ISS and the microgravity experiments currently being performed on board, while also highlighting "ways for Twitch users to engage with NASA, including citizen science projects and science, technology, engineering, and math programs designed to inspire the Artemis Generation."</p><p dir="ltr">The Artemis Generation refers to the astronauts who will explore Earth's moon as a part of NASA's Artemis Program.</p><p dir="ltr">"We will collaborate with commercial and international partners and establish the first long-term presence on the Moon," the <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/humans-in-space/artemis/" rel="nofollow ">official Artemis Program website</a> reads. "NASA will land the first woman, first person of color, and first international partner astronaut on the Moon using innovative technologies to explore more of the lunar surface than ever before."</p><p dir="ltr">This isn't the first time NASA has conducted a Twitch livestream, nor is it the first time the agency has broadcast a livestream from the ISS. But according to the <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/news-release/nasa-goes-live-first-twitch-stream-from-space-station/" rel="nofollow ">official NASA website</a>, "This conversation will be the first NASA event [livestreamed] from the International Space Station developed specifically for the agency’s Twitch platform."</p><p>The stream will take place on <a href="https://www.twitch.tv/nasa">NASA's Twitch channel</a> on Wednesday, February 12 at 8:45 AM PT / 11:45 AM ET.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[World of Warcraft finally tackles the housing crisis]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/games/607646/world-of-warcraft-player-housing-details</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/world-of-warcraft-finally-tackles-the-housing-crisis.1102341/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/games/607646/world-of-warcraft-player-housing-details<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>After 20 years, <em>World of Warcraft</em> is finally adding player housing. During its <a href="https://www.youtube.com/live/0rEfOTxr59o?si=pyWkjBlqsZZ0IuAa"><em>Warcraft</em> 30th Anniversary Direct</a> last year, Blizzard delighted players with the surprise announcement that the feature — a long-time staple in other MMOs — was on the way. Now the studio has revealed a bit more information <a href="https://worldofwarcraft.blizzard.com/en-us/news/24176592">with a new blog</a> explaining how it’s all supposed to work.</p><p>In the past, <em>WoW</em> has obliquely flirted with the concept of player housing with the garrison feature from the <a href="https://www.polygon.com/2014/11/26/7297125/world-of-warcraft-warlords-draenor-review-pc-mac-mmo"><em>Warlords of Draenor</em></a> expansion in 2014. Players had their own home base or “garrisons” that they could customize from a pool of buildings, but they couldn’t invite others in to see them or have any say over decor. Player housing, on the other hand, is meant to give players greater control over everything.</p><p>According to Blizzard there are three principles driving the development of player housing in Azeroth: self-expression, sociability, and longevity. The team wants players to be able easily customize their houses and socialize with their friends and guildmates within a feature that’s meant to last for expansions to come.</p><p>Initially, Blizzard plans on implementing only two housing areas, one for each faction. These houses will be arranged into neighborhoods that are either public with everyone free to come and go as they please, or private neighborhoods established and maintained by friend groups or guilds. Decor for these homes will be obtained either by questing or purchasing and are meant to reflect all the different aesthetics of the game’s numerous races, cultures, and locations that make up <em>WoW</em>’s ever expanding world. </p><p>Interestingly,<em> WoW</em> has also said it wants to make player housing available for everyone which included a very pointed shot across the bow at one of <em>WoW</em>’s biggest competitors —<em> Final Fantasy XIV</em> — which has had player housing for several years. As a player of the “critically acclaimed MMORPG,” I can tell you the requirements for obtaining housing (and <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/buying-a-house-in-final-fantasy-14-left-me-a-broken-woman/">the hoops you have to go through to actually get and keep one</a>) <a href="https://www.polygon.com/24115574/how-to-get-a-house-apartment-lottery-wards-plots">are so onerous</a> that it’s never been worth pursuing. It’s good that Blizzard is differentiating its housing initiative from others by making it clear what players can expect in that regard.</p><p>“If you want a house, you can have a house,” Blizzard’s post read. “No exorbitant requirements or high purchase costs, no lotteries, and no onerous upkeep (and if your subscription lapses, don’t worry, your house doesn’t get repossessed!).” </p><p>Blizzard hasn’t given a timeline on when housing will be implemented. The company released its latest expansion <em>War Within</em>, last year as the first part of its <a href="https://www.theverge.com/games/2023/11/3/23945426/blizzard-announces-the-next-three-wow-expansions">three-expansion long continuous story</a> dubbed “The Worldsoul Saga.” Housing could come as soon as a <em>War Within</em> patch or when the next expansion, <em>Midnight</em>, releases likely sometime in 2026.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indiana Jones and the Great Circle Is Proof 'You Don't Need AI to Steal My Soul,' Harrison Ford Says]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-is-proof-you-dont-need-ai-to-steal-my-soul-harrison-ford-says</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-is-proof-you-dont-need-ai-to-steal-my-soul-harrison-ford-says.1102335/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-is-proof-you-dont-need-ai-to-steal-my-soul-harrison-ford-says<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Indiana Jones actor Harrison Ford has said Troy Baker playing the beloved character in video game Indiana Jones and the Great Circle is proof "you don't need artificial intelligence to steal my soul."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Ford discussed alleviating control of Indy with <a href="https://www.wsj.com/style/harrison-ford-shrinking-1923-captain-america-7b1f9b3f" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Wall Street Journal Magazine</a>, saying he was very happy with the performance of The Last of Us actor Baker.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"You don’t need artificial intelligence to steal my soul," Ford said. "You can already do it for nickels and dimes with good ideas and talent. He did a brilliant job, and it didn’t take AI to do it."</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/indiana-jones-devs-interview-machine-games-lucasfilm-games">The Great Circle arrived in December as an "authentic"</a> but maybe not canonical entry in the long running series, which received its first new film in a long time in 2023 with Indiana Jones and the Dial of Destiny.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/indiana-jones-and-the-dial-of-destiny-review">This wasn't well received at all</a>, however, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-review">while the game was</a>, so the creatives behind the franchise might be inclined to go in this new direction instead of having Ford put the hat back on.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The legendary actor of Star Wars, Indiana Jones, and soon Marvel fame is one of many creatives to criticize the use of AI in films and other forms of media, with the likes of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/tim-burton-slams-ai-generated-artwork">Tim Burton calling AI generated art "very disturbing"</a> and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nicolas-cage-calls-ai-performances-a-dead-end-as-robots-cannot-reflect-the-human-condition">Nicolas Cage calling it a "dead end."</a></p><p data-cy="paragraph">Several voice actors have rallied against it too, including <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/gta-5-actor-ned-luke-calls-out-bullst-ai-chatbot-that-uses-his-voice">Grand Theft Auto 5's Ned Luke</a> who called out a chatbot which used his voice. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-witcher-voice-actor-doug-cockle-calls-ai-inevitable-but-dangerous">The Witcher voice actor Doug Cockle also told IGN that AI was "inevitable" but "dangerous"</a>, sharing in Luke's assessment that chatbots and similar uses are "effectively robbing [voice actors] of income."</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Ryan Dinsdale is an IGN freelance reporter. He'll talk about The Witcher all day.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Paradox Interactive to acquire Haemimont Games]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/02/paradox-interactive-to-acquire-haemimont-games</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/paradox-interactive-to-acquire-haemimont-games.1102332/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/02/paradox-interactive-to-acquire-haemimont-games<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
        </ul>

    
    <p><span>Acquisition expected to close within a few days.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Paradox Interactive [103 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/paradox-interactive">Paradox Interactive</a> has signed an agreement to acquire all shares in <em><a title="Games > Jagged Alliance 3 [6 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/jagged-alliance-3">Jagged Alliance 3</a></em> developer <a title="Companies > Haemimont Games [11 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/haemimont-games">Haemimont Games</a>, the companies <a href="https://www.paradoxinteractive.com/media/press-releases/press-release/paradox-interactive-acquires-haemimont-games" target="_blank">announced</a>. The acquisition, the purchasing price of which was not disclosed, is expected to close within a few days. <span id="more-942636"></span></p><p>Following the acquisition, the current leadership and development team of Haemimont Games will remain active with the studio, and the studio’s ongoing projects will remain in development.</p><p>“We are very happy to welcome Haemimont Games to Paradox!” said Paradox Interactive CE Fredrik Wester in a press release. “They bring a tight-knit team with long experience in developing <a title="Genres > Management [27 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/management">management games</a> with many well received projects in their portfolio. Moreover, they have a strong creative streak, technology developed for their niche, a new [intellectual property] in development and a strong culture that fits Paradox’s way of working. We have strong faith in their team and leadership, and our main focus now is to ensure that they can continue to create great games under new ownership.”</p><p>Haemimont Games founder Gabriel Dobrev aded, “We’re delighted to become a part of the Paradox family! The cultural fit between our companies is remarkable, and we already feel at home. This partnership empowers us to push the boundaries of our games, delivering deeper and more intense experiences to our players. It also opens new horizons for our team, technology, and creative processes, which we’re eager to explore. Expect amazing new games from us!”</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Baldur's Gate 3 Patch 8 Update Hammers Out Some Of The Bugs]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/baldurs-gate-3-patch-8-update-hammers-out-some-of-the-bugs/1100-6529301/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/baldurs-gate-3-patch-8-update-hammers-out-some-of-the-bugs.1102329/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/baldurs-gate-3-patch-8-update-hammers-out-some-of-the-bugs/1100-6529301/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-main">

      
                    
  
              <header id="masthead"><nav></nav></header>      
                            <div id="site-wrapper" role="main">
          <div id="default-content">
        
          <p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p>
  
    <article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529301">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/baldurs-gate-3-review-let-freedom-reign/1900-6418131/" data-ref-id="1900-6418131">Baldur's Gate 3</a> may be a work of art, but <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/baldurs-gate-3-patch-8-introduces-cross-play-photo-mode-and-more/1100-6528863/" data-ref-id="1100-6528863">Patch 8</a> remains a work in progress. A select group of players were invited to take part in Larian Studios' stress test for Patch 8, which is still ongoing. However, Larian has already put together an update that addresses some of the bugs that have been uncovered in Patch 8.</p><p>As laid out in <a href="https://baldursgate3.game/news/stress-test-update-1_135" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">a new post by Larian Studios</a>, there don't appear to be any game-breaking bugs in Patch 8. But there are issues that have come up in several areas, including the newly added Photo Mode. Now, creatures will supposedly obey the "look at the camera" command, and dragonborn won't lose their tails in the pictures. </p><p>Cross-play is another big addition of Patch 8, which is meant to connect players from consoles and PCs. This update only has a small number of fixes, but Larian notes that "we are still investigating instances of cross-play not working as intended." Other changes are meant to smooth out unintended effects, including an "issue causing the Flaming Fist armor to clip and generally freak out a bit."</p><p>Patch 8 Update 1 is expected to go live later today, but only for Baldur's Gate 3 players who were invited to take part in the stress test. Everyone else will get the complete Patch 8 after it receives refinement from Larian. After Larian wraps up its work on Patch 8, the studio will turn its full attention to its next project, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/baldurs-gate-3-dev-now-giving-full-attention-to-next-game-codenamed-excalibur/1100-6528758/" data-ref-id="1100-6528758">codenamed Excalibur</a>. Baldur's Gate 3 is almost certainly going to get a sequel, which <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/hasbro-hopes-next-baldurs-gate-game-is-here-before-2050/1100-6522712/" data-ref-id="1100-6522712">will be developed by another studio</a>.</p><p>You can find the Patch 8 Update 1 notes below.</p><h3>Gameplay</h3><ul><li>Fixed containers inside inventories not scattering their contents when they get destroyed, which could potentially lead to key quest items getting lost for good.</li><li>Fixed a bug causing Oath of the Crown paladins to lose spell slots instead of gaining them when levelling up.</li><li>Fixed an issue where picking up items from the ground in multiplayer could then block movement via the controller stick.</li><li>Fixed the Wild Shape: Panther's Prowl action and Prowling condition not working correctly.</li><li>Fixed a bug where items getting added to the inventory would lose their conditions. This could cause, for example, the Elemental Cleaver buff to disappear when the imbued weapon is thrown.</li><li>Shadow Blade will now retain the behavior of being locked to the caster when upcast.</li></ul><h3>Photo Mode</h3><ul><li>Added an in-game pop-up for Photo Mode that triggers at the beach at the start of the game and can be found in the Journal.</li><li>Updated Photo Mode's screenshot function on Steam Deck so that it uses Steam's proprietary screenshot function, so you can access your photos more readily from the Steam Screenshots page.</li><li>Prevented characters from being able to pop into private cutscenes while activating Photo Mode when playing in multiplayer.</li><li>Hid the 'Toggle Photo Preview' legend while taking screenshots via Steam's screenshot function.</li><li>Fixed Photo Mode making the screen go blurry when opened on split screen.</li><li>Added camera shutter SFX when taking a photo in Photo Mode.</li><li>Fixed the Attacking and Jumping poses for wolves.</li><li>Fixed a cross appearing in the middle of the screen when the Vignette is at its thickest setting.</li><li>Fixed some creatures not listening when you select the 'Look At Camera' option.</li><li>Fixed the game sometimes freezing when switching quickly between tabs in Photo Mode.</li><li>Improved the Depth of Field sliders so the strength and distance scale in proportion to the slider itself.</li><li>Fixed an issue causing dragonborn tails to appear detached from the body.</li><li>The Grasping Vine's poses now work correctly.</li></ul><h3>Cross-Play</h3><ul><li>Fixed an issue that could get the client stuck in a loading screen if the client unfriends the host and then clicks 'Join Party' after re-adding the host.</li><li>Fixed some of the PS5 splashscreens not showing up when they should.</li><li>Fixed a crash at the start of combat.</li></ul><h3>Subclasses</h3><ul><li>The Booming Blade tooltip now updates its values when upcast.</li><li>Fixed an inaccurate bonus value in the Rakish Audacity tooltip.</li><li>Updated Toll the Dead and Bursting Sinew to work with Potent Cantrip and deal half damage on saves.</li><li>Fixed Pact of the Blade's Extra Attack being added to Deepened Pact even if you didn't choose Pact of the Blade.</li></ul><h3>Art</h3><ul><li>Fixed an issue causing the Flaming Fist armor to clip and generally freak out a bit.</li></ul><h3>UI</h3><ul><li>Fixed a bug with Gale's donation UI preventing you from feeding him magical items.</li><li>All of the Hexblade's class actions and subclass features are now shown correctly in Character Creation.</li><li>Fixed button or keyboard shortcut inputs in the UI sometimes not working.</li><li>Fixed some Reaction tooltips like Divine Allegiance not showing some values correctly in the description.</li><li>Fixed a bug causing the UI to lock up when rapidly switching between keyboard and mouse input and controller input.</li><li>Fixed a bug where opening the Main Menu on controller wouldn't automatically select the 'Resume' option at the top of the menu.</li><li>Fixed the condition icons on the party line getting duplicated when transitioning between acts during cross-play.</li><li>Fixed some settings that were missing their wrap-around navigation functionality on controller, preventing you from looping from the last option back to the first option with the same button input.</li><li>Fixed a bug where you'd have to deselect your current passive when respeccing a character before selecting a new one. Now, you can just click the new one.</li><li>Fixed a bug that caused the toggleable Illithid Powers to disappear from the Character Sheet and be uninteractable in the Illithid Powers UI.</li><li>Fixed player avatars not showing up in the multiplayer/cross-play lobby.</li></ul><h3>Scripting</h3><ul><li>With 12 new subclasses arriving in Patch 8, we’ve rechecked some achievements, including ensuring the armed version of Stunning Strike no longer counts as an unarmed attack for the Fists of Fury achievement, and its unarmed variant now does.</li><li>Monks' Unarmed Strike bonus action now also correctly counts toward the Action Surge achievement.</li></ul><h3>Crashes</h3><ul><li>Fixed a crash when trying to start a game from a lobby multiple times.</li><li>Fixed several crashes and freezes related to the UI.</li><li>Fixed a crash on Vulkan when taking a photo in Photo Mode.</li></ul>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article>

    
  

</div>
                      <meta itemprop="seamless-content-list-items" data-list-items="[{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529264&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-tops-1-million-copies-sold-in-a-single-day\/1100-6529264\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529234&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-off-to-an-enormous-start-on-steam\/1100-6529234\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529205&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/the-sims-and-sims-2-legacy-editions-are-full-of-bugs-according-to-players\/1100-6529205\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529233&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/check-out-this-new-book-that-chronicles-the-rise-of-nvidia\/1100-6529233\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529165&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/clair-obscur-expedition-33-joins-the-list-of-gestating-live-action-movie-adaptations\/1100-6529165\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529108&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/meet-the-incredible-sci-fi-novels-that-inspired-some-of-your-favorite-video-games\/1100-6529108\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529182&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/destiny-2-heresy-will-be-missing-some-voice-content-because-of-the-ongoing-actors-strike\/1100-6529182\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529164&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/popular-call-of-duty-warzone-guns-are-getting-changes-next-week\/1100-6529164\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529140&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/the-sims-1-and-2-are-now-available-on-pc-every-expansion-included\/1100-6529140\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529170&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/amazon-exclusive-pokemon-tcg-poke-ball-tin-bundles-get-first-discounts\/1100-6529170\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529168&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/marvels-spider-man-2-is-apparently-off-to-rough-start-on-pc\/1100-6529168\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529167&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/classic-cartoon-style-shooter-mouse-p-i-for-hire-wont-have-microtransactions\/1100-6529167\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529169&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/multiversus-shuts-down-in-may-but-can-still-be-played-offline-if-you-update-in-time\/1100-6529169\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529166&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/elden-ring-nightreign-network-test-codes-are-being-scalped-on-ebay\/1100-6529166\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526687&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/monster-hunter-wilds-preorders-where-to-get-steelbook-edition-and-best-deals\/1100-6526687\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529177&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/killing-floor-3-has-three-editions-physical-preorders-available-now\/1100-6529177\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529162&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/diablo-4-season-7-bug-is-letting-players-deal-near-infinite-damage-but-nobody-knows-exactly-why\/1100-6529162\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6528998&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/civilization-7-how-merchants-and-trade-routes-work\/1100-6528998\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529056&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/civilization-7-how-to-upgrade-towns-into-cities\/1100-6529056\/&quot;}]">
            </div>
              
    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>