<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2024 08:07:03 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[INTERVIEW: Techland’s Tymon Smektała On Supporting Dying Light 2 Until 2027]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/interview-tymon-smektala-techland-dying-light-2/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/interview-techland%E2%80%99s-tymon-smekta%C5%82a-on-supporting-dying-light-2-until-2027.962730/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/interview-tymon-smektala-techland-dying-light-2/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Techland had one of the most successful reveals during Gamescom, debuting the first trailer for Dying Light: The Beast during the Opening Night Live showcase. I then followed up with Techland twice, once to check out an exclusive extended gameplay demo and again to catch up with Tymon Smektała, the franchise director working on the Dying Light series.</p>



<p>Dying Light: The Beast is an all-new, standalone adventure that started life as the second paid DLC for 2022’s Dying Light 2. I had the opportunity to ask Tymon a few questions about the expansion and the future of Dying Light 2.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-is-this-the-end">Is This The End?</h2>



<p>Dying Light 2 fans have been awaiting news regarding the second DLC for the game for quite some time. This isn’t what they expected, but in so many ways, it’s much better. Dying Light: The Beast brings back <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/interview-roger-craig-smith-dying-light/">Roger Craig Smith as Kyle Crane</a>, offering players an 18-hour story that explains the lengthy gap between the first two games in the series.</p>



<p>I was curious to learn about Techland’s plans for Dying Light 2 now that the second (and assumedly final) DLC has become a standalone project:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>We had to slow down things a little for the crucial preparation of The Beast for Gamescom, but even on the day of the announcement we released an update to Dying Light 2. We promised five years of support and we’re sticking to that promise. Expect new content updates, also coming this year.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>As we looked back at the success of the series, Tymon admitted that Dying Light’s (2015) major expansion, The Following, could also have been a standalone title, but ‘this time around it’s different’. </p>



<p>He advised that The Beast will answer a lot of lingering questions that firm up the series’ lore – along with making the newest entry in the Dying Light series much more accessible to all players. As Tymon stressed, you can now play The Beast without having to ‘convert’ to Dying Light 2.</p>



<p>Speaking retrospectively, Tymon admitted that if they could do Dying Light 2 all over again, they’d let the game ‘mature’ first before announcing it:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>At some point in 2021, we started feeling pressure to get it out of the gate, especially as we announced it really early. If I could change naything I’d do just that, allow the game to mature a little internally, allowing us to focus and polish the details that make a good game and an exceptional one. A lesson learned, I guess.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>We then looked forward, and Tymon revealed his desire to make Dying Light <strong>the </strong>zombie experience. He hopes that one day when someone asks what the best zombie game is, the first title on everyone’s mind will be ‘Dying Light’.</p>



<p>I say it’s already there.</p>



<p>I couldn’t have ended the interview without asking about ‘Dying Light 3’, and while Tymon stressed that there are ‘many possible ideas’ for the game, he couldn’t divulge any information.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/valve-deadlock-announce/">Valve has finally listed Deadlock on Steam</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>
    
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Valve Finally Lists Deadlock on Steam, But You Still Can’t Get Easy Access]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/valve-deadlock-announce/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/valve-finally-lists-deadlock-on-steam-but-you-still-can%E2%80%99t-get-easy-access.962727/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/valve-deadlock-announce/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>For weeks, tens of thousands of players have been finding their way into Deadlock, an all-new competitive shooter developed by Valve. Despite that fact, the tech titan hadn’t ever acknowledged the existence of the game and was operating under a policy of blanket silence. Now, the company has connected itself to Deadlock in a remarkably minor way – by publishing a Steam listing that links Valve to the hero shooter as both the developer and publisher.</p>



<p>Not only that but the official Discord server for the game received a message from an admin updating the state of play for streamers and those neck-deep in the closed playtest.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-kept-you-waiting-huh">Kept You Waiting, Huh?</h2>



<p>Valve has published a <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1422450/Deadlock/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">listing on Steam for Deadlock</a>, a brand-new competitive shooter with hero mechanics and a lot of hype. In the last few weeks, the game has pulled in tens of thousands of players, with the peak concurrent count hitting more than 40,000 users – which is higher than <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/concords-launch-is-worse-than-expected/">some recently released shooters</a>…</p>



<p>Aside from a brief animated teaser, there’s not much to take away from the Steam page for Deadlock. There’s almost nothing in the way of technical specifications or product patter, and all-in-all, it’s a very ‘underwhelming’ announcement from Valve.</p>



<p>Here’s the message that was posted by the Discord server’s admins to reflect this step up from Valve:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>We are lifting the rules for public conversation about Deadlock to allow for things like streaming, community websites, and discussions. Nothing else is changing with our state of development. We are remaining invite-only and contineu to be in an early development stage with lots of temporary art and experimental gameplay.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>So, while a Steam listing now exists for Deadlock, you can’t access the game unless you’re invited by someone <strong>already testing </strong>the game. Perhaps this will change in the coming weeks.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/avowed-doesnt-need-60-fps-mode-says-obsidian/">news about Avowed’s 60 FPS mode</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>
    
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sony Launching Its Own Blockchain For NFTs and Play to Earn Games]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/sony-launching-its-own-blockchain-for-nfts-and-play-to-earn-games</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sony-launching-its-own-blockchain-for-nfts-and-play-to-earn-games.962688/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/sony-launching-its-own-blockchain-for-nfts-and-play-to-earn-games<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Sony announced today that it's catching up to 2021's hottest trend, by launching its own blockchain which will be able to support NFTs, and play-to-earn games.</p>
<p>While Sony's blockchain <a href="https://www.sony.com/en/SonyInfo/News/Press/202408/24-029E/" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="Development of Blockchain &quot;Soneium&quot;">announcement </a>is not exclusively aimed at gaming, a segment of the announcement mentions what they are looking at in the gaming region potentially with their new Soneium blockchain.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>End users will be able to access Soneium through applications that are compatible with Soneium's network, and will be able to interact with Web3 games and NFT marketplaces provided by each app, as well as entertainment-related services.</p>
</blockquote>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/go-mainstream-soneium.jpg?itok=8ClXt75w 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/go-mainstream-soneium.jpg?itok=hBbwGbrn 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>The cringe inducing hashtage effort to "#GMwithSoneium" - or Go Mainstream which every other NFT project has failed at, perhaps due to solving problems that don't exist.</figcaption></figure><p>Sony is launching its own support for NFTs with the Soneium blockchain that they announced. NFTs have been unpopular with <a href="https://medium.com/r/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamedeveloper.com%2Fgame-platforms%2Fgamers-hate-nfts-here-s-why-that-s-good-for-the-game-industry" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="Gamers hate NFTs—here's why that's good for the game industry">gamers since about two seconds after they were revealed,</a> and Sony launching this in 2024 shows how the company is sometimes slow to adapt to trends, as it is now years after other companies have entered, and exited the field of NFTs. Sony's Jun Watanabe, the head of their 'advanced business search department' and chairman of Sony Block Solutions, shared the following thoughts on the matter:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>I think the development of a comprehensive Web3 solution based on blockchain is very significant to the Sony Group, which has developed a wide variety of businesses under its purpose of "Fill the world with emotion, through the power of creativity and technology." We will work to create diverse businesses and new use cases with the aim of delivering customer value that can only be enjoyed through Web3 technology to as many users as possible and making people's lives richer and more colorful.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>It is worth noting that this doesn't mean that Sony is necessarily planning to make play-to-earn games itself, or implementing NFTs in its upcoming games, but it definitely opens the door to it. It also opens the path to play-to-earn games being on PlayStation for other developers, while Sony still collects its tithe as platform, and presumably now blockchain, czar.</p>
<h2>What is the history of NFTs in Gaming?</h2>
<p>There's been a lot of noise about gaming and NFTs over the past few years. During that time we have seen Ubisoft <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/ubisoft-ends-its-nft-experiment-in-ghost-recon-breakpoint-but-promises-theyre-coming-to-other-games/" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="Ubisoft ends its NFT experiment in Ghost Recon Breakpoint but promises they're 'coming to other games'">experiment with NFTs lightly in Ghost Recon Wildlands</a>, as well as other companies dabble in the space (like <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/stalker-2-is-going-all-in-on-nfts" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title=" Stalker 2 is Going All-In on NFTs"><em>Stalker </em>developer GSC World</a>), before meeting backlash and often retreating from it (though <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/square-enix-nft-and-blockchain-plans-laid-out-in-annual-report" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title=" Square Enix NFT And Blockchain Plans Laid Out In Annual Report">Square Enix continues in the space</a> as well). Reasons for dislike of NFTs vary among gamers but they can be briefly summed up in a few points:</p>
<ul><li>They are <a href="https://earth.org/nfts-environmental-impact/" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="Explainer: What Are NFTs, And What is Their Environmental Impact?">ecologically damaging</a>,</li>
<li>Rampant speculation <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/855453ac-7011-448a-90b1-b0d7fedd43ac" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="What NFT mania can tell us about market bubbles">drives the entire market</a>,</li>
<li>They don't actually do anything, being essentially JPGs (<a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2021/04/nfts-werent-supposed-end-like/618488/" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="NFTs Weren’t Supposed to End Like This">It's worse, it's links to JPEGs</a>),</li>
<li>There's an abundance of scammers and grifters in the market (See: <a href="https://www.web3isgoinggreat.com/" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="Web3 is Going Just Greant">Web3 is going great</a>).</li>
</ul><p>Regardless of the individual reason, players pushed back against NFTs a lot. While mention of interoperability of NFTs was mentioned a lot by those pitching them, it's either not feasible as developer <a href="https://x.com/tha_rami/status/1480404407187656705" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="Rami Ismail on Twitter/X">Rami Ismail explained</a>, or you can do it perfectly fine without them. The easiest way to view most NFTs is that imagine its a blockchain version of the Steam Marketplace, as they are like <em>Team Fortress 2 </em>Hats and <em>Counter-Strike 2</em> skins with all the issues those markets have dialed up to 11, and massive amounts of power usage.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/axie-infinity.jpg?itok=-e_oSkdj 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/axie-infinity.jpg?itok=aEVfCCd4 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Perhaps the most notable NFT game, Axie Infinity got tons of press before it essentially imploaded</figcaption></figure><p>There is one other sector of games though in NFTs that got a lot of attention - play to earn. These games were all about earning NFTs, and you could sell them to make money (or crypto currency to be more exact). To return to our Steam Marketplace analogy, these are the <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/banana-steam-popular" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title=" Why Is a Picture of a Banana So Popular on Steam?">Banana game</a> and similar titles that exist just to create inventory items that spark speculative bubbles and are full of bots. The most famous of these was Axie Infinity, which garnered attention for Philippines and other lower-wage countries having people earn money playing the game to get resources for others who paid them… before it all <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/4/8/23015468/axie-infinity-blockchain-nft-play-to-earn-game-economics-hack" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="Axie Infinity’s financial mess started long before its $600 million hack">came screeching to a halt</a> even before the game suffered a massive hack.</p>
<p>The issues with the sector have led to actions being taken like <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/valve-bans-cryptocurrency-games-on-steam" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title=" Valve Bans Cryptocurrency Games on Steam">Valve banning them on Steam</a>, and <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/minecraft-to-ban-nfts-on-game-servers" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title=" Minecraft To Ban NFTs on Game Servers">Minecraft banning NFTs</a> as well. Developers like <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/bungie-dev-claims-gaming-nfts-are-harmful-to-game-design-environment" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title=" Bungie Dev Claims Gaming NFTs Are Harmful to Game Design, Environment">Bungie's Max Nicols</a>, and organizations like the <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/igda-calls-for-halt-in-unnecessary-gaming-nfts" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title=" IGDA Calls For Halt In Unnecessary Gaming NFTs">IGDA have spoken out against them as well</a>.&nbsp;</p>
<p>As for what more Sony will do with the blockchain, and NFTs we'll have to just wait and see.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>

<p>A longtime lover of speculative fiction, in almost all its forms, Don joined TechRaptor in 2014 on a whim sending in an application as he was looking for… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/don-parsons">More about Don</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Best Deals On MMO Gaming Mice For World Of Warcraft: The War Within]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/best-deals-on-mmo-gaming-mice-for-world-of-warcraft-the-war-within/1100-6526097/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/best-deals-on-mmo-gaming-mice-for-world-of-warcraft-the-war-within.962634/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/best-deals-on-mmo-gaming-mice-for-world-of-warcraft-the-war-within/1100-6526097/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6526097">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">If you're planning to return to Azeroth when the new <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/wow-the-war-withins-warbands-were-born-out-of-a-desire-to-keep-pushing-for-an-account-wide-future/1100-6525203/" data-ref-id="1100-6525203">World of Warcraft expansion The War Within</a> launches on August 26 (or you've already jumped into the early access period this week), you should consider equipping yourself with an MMO mouse.</p><p dir="ltr">To be clear, almost every mouse will work for general MMO gameplay, and most devices marketed as "MMO mice" aren't much different from other PC gaming models, but there's one crucial difference: extra buttons. <em>Lots </em>of extra buttons, in fact. We're talking anywhere from 10 to 20 or more additional buttons. These extra inputs usually sit on the side of the mouse for easy access with your thumb. The buttons can be mapped to the various skills and abilities you use in-game, making it easier to stay consistent with your combat rotations, pop a weave ability at the opportune moment, or even just navigate menus faster than dragging your mouse around and clicking on-screen icons.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1701/17013431/4356484-mcie.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4356484" data-ratio="0.552" data-width="1000" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1701/17013431/4356484-mcie.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4356484"></a><figcaption>Logitech G502 Hero and UtechSmart Venus Pro gaming mice</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1701/17013431/4356484-mcie.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">If that sounds like something you'd want from a new mouse, you're in luck. There are dozens of mice out there sporting extra buttons and other MMO-friendly features, and a bunch of them are on sale right now--including one of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/best-gaming-mouse/1100-6471780/">our favorite gaming mice</a>, the <strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Logitech-G502-Performance-Gaming-Mouse/dp/B07GBZ4Q68?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Logitech G502 Hero</a></strong>. This wired mouse features 11 programmable buttons, and you can grab it from Amazon for $42.29, which is nearly half off its normal $80 price.</p><p dir="ltr">Another option with even more buttons is the <strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/UtechSmart-transmission-technology-Ergonomic-programmable/dp/B07XP4K152?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">UtechSmart Venus Pro</a></strong>. This wireless model has 16 buttons and rates highly among users. You can grab it for $38.39 (was $60). And while it's not a mouse, you should also consider the <strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Razer-Tartarus-Progammable-Detachable-Mecha-Membrane/dp/B07754PYFK?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Razer Tartarus V2</a></strong>, which is a keypad featuring an assortment of gaming inputs, including 32 programmable keyboard keys, a controller-style thumbstick, a scroll wheel, and more. It's on sale at Amazon for $70 (was $80).</p><p dir="ltr">Several other MMO gaming mice from notable brands like Corsair, Asus, SteelSeries, and more are also discounted at Amazon. <strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Razer-Naga-Wireless-Gaming-Mouse/dp/B08D27XXRY?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Razer's Naga Pro</a></strong> is a versatile option, as it actually comes with three interchangeable side plates, so you can switch between a 12-button plate for WoW, swap it out for a six-button plate for Diablo 4, and use the two-button attachment for FPS games.</p><p dir="ltr">We've rounded up a list of some of the best MMO gaming mouse deals to help you find one that fits your needs and budget. For more recommendations, check out our roundups of the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/best-gaming-mouse/1100-6471780/" data-ref-id="1100-6471780">best gaming mice</a> and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/best-gaming-keyboard/1100-6471785/" data-ref-id="1100-6471785">best gaming keyboards</a>.</p><h2 dir="ltr">MMO gaming mice deals at Amazon</h2><ul><li dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/ASUS-ROG-Wireless-Magnetic-Programmable/dp/B09726KT4R?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">ASUS ROG Spatha X Wireless Gaming Mouse</a> (12 buttons) -- $120 (<del>$150</del>)</li><li dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/CORSAIR-SCIMITAR-ELITE-WIRELESS-Gaming/dp/B0CCVYHZ9N?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Corsair Scimitar Elite RGB Wireless MMO Gaming Mouse</a> (16 buttons) -- $110 (<del>$130</del>)</li><li dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Corsair-Scimitar-Gaming-Backlit-Optical/dp/B082LRMY53?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Corsair Scimitar Elite Wired Gaming</a> (17 buttons) -- $60 (<del>$80</del>)</li><li dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Logitech-G502-Performance-Gaming-Mouse/dp/B07GBZ4Q68?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Logitech G502 Hero Wired Gaming Mouse</a> (11 buttons) -- $42.49 (<del>$80</del>)</li><li dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Razer-Naga-Wireless-Gaming-Mouse/dp/B08D27XXRY?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Razer Naga Pro Wireless Gaming Mouse</a> (12 buttons) -- $120 (<del>$150</del>)</li><li dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Redragon-Impact-Buttons-Precision-Programmable/dp/B07HC4NBQ8?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Redragon M908 Impact RGB Wired MMO Gaming Mouse</a> (12 buttons) -- $28.80 with coupon code (<del>$47</del>)</li><li dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Redragon-Wireless-Programmable-Buttons-Battery/dp/B088B3ZM7?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Redragon M913 Impact Elite Wireless Gaming Mouse</a> (16 buttons) -- $42 with coupon code (<del>$47</del>)</li><li dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Redragon-Impact-Buttons-Precision-Programmable/dp/B0C1Z6VLTP?tag=gamespot-promos-20&amp;th=1" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Redragon M913 Impact Elite Wireless Gaming Mouse</a> (12 buttons) -- $40.50 (<del>$45</del>)</li><li dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/SteelSeries-Aerox-Wireless-Ultra-Lightweight-Programmable/dp/B09VNPB6Q1?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">SteelSeries Aerox 9 Wireless</a> (18 buttons) -- $110 (<del>$150</del>)</li><li dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/UtechSmart-transmission-technology-Ergonomic-programmable/dp/B07XP4K152?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">UtechSmart Venus Pro RGB Wireless MMO Gaming Mouse</a> (16 buttons) -- $38.39 (<del>$60</del>)</li><li dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Razer-Tartarus-Progammable-Detachable-Mecha-Membrane/dp/B07754PYFK?tag=gamespot-promos-20" rel="nofollow ">Razer Tartarus V2 Gaming Keypad</a> (32 buttons) -- $70 (<del>$80</del>)</li></ul><div data-embed-type="pinbox" data-ref-id="4304">  <ul>                              <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/star-wars-outlaws-preorder-guide/1100-6522523/">Star Wars Outlaws Preorders - Where To Find The Best Bonuses</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/buy-two-get-one-free-nintendo-switch-games-and-preorders-my-best-buy-members/1100-6525928/">B2G1 Free All Nintendo Switch Games - Zelda: Echoes Of Wisdom, Mario &amp; Luigi, And More Preorders</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/dragon-age-the-veilguard-preorder-guide/1100-6525830/">Dragon Age: The Veilguard Collector's Edition Preorders Live Now</a></li>                          <li>         <span>+ Show More More Gaming, Tech, and Entertainment Deals &amp; Preorders Links (5)</span>       </li>          <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/doom-anthology-preorders-quakecon-2024/1100-6525656/">Doom Anthology Preorders Are Live - Comes With 6 Games, Steelbook Case, And Replica BFG</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/retrorealms-halloween-ash-vs-evil-dead-retro-game-preorder-guide/1100-6525752/">Halloween And Ash Vs. Evil Dead Retro Games Revealed - Collector's Bundle Preorders Live</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/amiibo-nintendo-switch-restocks-reprints-2024/2900-5671/">Rare Nintendo Amiibo Figures Restocked - Ness, Mr. Game &amp; Watch, ROB, Charizard, And More</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/final-fantasy-i-vi-pixel-remaster-collection-north-america-release/1100-6525641/">Final Fantasy Pixel Remaster Collection Anniversary Edition Preorders Live At Amazon</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/retro-pokemon-brick-sets-in-stock-at-target-pixel-art-mew-pikachu-charmander-and-more/1100-6525719/">Retro Pokemon Brick Sets In Stock At Target - Pixel Art Mew, Pikachu, Charmander, And More</a></li>   </ul> </div>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/104300651635509044736?rel=author">Brendan Hesse</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Deadlock's Existence Finally Acknowledged by Valve With a Store Page and Official Announcement]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/deadlock-valve-steam-announcement-page</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/deadlocks-existence-finally-acknowledged-by-valve-with-a-store-page-and-official-announcement.962616/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/deadlock-valve-steam-announcement-page<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Thousands of players have been playing Valve's "secret" multiplayer game for weeks.</h2></div><section><p>Valve is finally ready to take the wraps off Deadlock, its not-so-secret multiplayer game that thousands of people have been playing for weeks.</p><p>Throughout August, Deadlock has slowly been gaining attention and player population via a system of invites, with existing playtesters able to invite their friends. As a result, it quietly amassed thousands of players, reaching <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/deadlock-valves-new-hero-shooter-is-quietly-amassing-thousands-of-playtesters">over 18,000 concurrent players mid-August</a> and climbing to a <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/1422450/charts/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">peak of over 44,000 players</a> earlier this week.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/08/23/deadlock-image-1724453496539.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption>A short video plays on the official Steam page for Deadlock. Image source: IGN.</figcaption></figure></output><p>However, despite the game being generally available to anyone who knew anyone else playing it, a splash screen at the start of the game asked players to "not share anything about the game with anyone." Many players, naturally, ignored the relatively gentle and not-legally-binding warning, resulting in a number of videos popping up on YouTube showcasing gameplay and at least <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/8/12/24219016/valve-deadlock-hands-on-secret-new-game" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">one media write-up in The Verge</a>.</p><p>As a result, we've known for weeks now that Deadlock is a 6v6 third-person hero shooter with a bit of a MOBA twist, in that iot takes place across four lanes with aggressively respawning waves of troopers. It's still in "early development," Valve warns, "with lots of temporary art and experimental gameplay." However, Valve has now officially lifted its request not to share information about the game and <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1422450/Deadlock/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">revealed its official store page.</a></p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3>Every IGN Valve Game Review Ever</h3></div></output><p>Deadlock is still invite-only for now, but with it out in the open at last, it seems likely we'll start seeing Valve actively discussing what Deadlock is, alongside critics and content creators, as well as a potential surge in new players. Maybe one of them will be able to explain what's going on with the goofy dragon-person in a newsboy cap we keep seeing everywhere.</p><p><em>Rebekah Valentine is a senior reporter for IGN. Got a story tip? Send it to rvalentine@ign.com.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Valve officially announces Deadlock, a game ‘in early development’]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2024/8/23/24219054/valve-deadlock-announcement</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/valve-officially-announces-deadlock-a-game-%E2%80%98in-early-development%E2%80%99.962601/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/2024/8/23/24219054/valve-deadlock-announcement<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><article id="content"><div><div><h2>Valve officially announces Deadlock, a game ‘in early development’</h2><p><span><span> / </span><h2>The multiplayer game had been something of an open secret for months.</h2></span></p></div><div><p><time datetime="2024-08-23T23:00:54.030Z"> <!-- -->Aug 23, 2024, 11:00 PM UTC</time></p><div><h2>Share this story</h2></div><p>If you buy something from a Verge link, Vox Media may earn a commission.<!-- --> <a href="https://www.theverge.com/ethics-statement">See our ethics statement.</a></p></div></div><div><div><p>Valve has finally, officially announced <em>Deadlock</em>, in the most minimal way imaginable. The game <a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=1025X1701640&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fstore.steampowered.com%2Fapp%2F1422450%2FDeadlock%2F">now has a Steam page</a> that lists Valve as its developer and publisher, and a simple notice: </p><div><blockquote><p>Deadlock is in early development with lots of temporary art and experimental gameplay. Access is currently limited to friend invite via our playtesters.</p></blockquote></div><p>Valve provides no other details, just an animated teaser image. (You can see a still screenshot of it above.) The system requirements only mention that the game requires a 64-bit processor and operating system.</p><p>While the game has ostensibly been a secret until now, details about it have been trickling out for months. Information started to emerge <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/images-leak-of-valves-next-game-and-its-an-overwatch-style-hero-shooter">from closed playtests</a> in May. By August, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/valve-hero-shooter-deadlock-still-hasnt-been-announced-but-had-16k-steam-concurrent-players-this-weekend">tens of thousands of people were playing the game</a>, as more players invited their friends to check it out. <em>The Verge</em> received an invite and published <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/8/12/24219016/valve-deadlock-hands-on-secret-new-game">a hands-on preview</a> last week.</p><p>Today, <a href="https://www.twitch.tv/directory/category/deadlock-2016">many streamers</a> are playing the game live, <a href="https://www.twitch.tv/shroud">including Shroud</a>, after admin Yoshi said in the game’s Discord that Valve was lifting its rules against public conversation.</p><div><p><cite>Screenshot by Tom Warren / The Verge</cite></p></div><p>While <em>Deadlock</em> seems like another promising addition to Valve’s lineup of big multiplayer games, it’s unclear if it will have sustained popularity like <em>Counter-Strike</em> or <em>Dota 2</em> or will eventually fizzle out <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/4/22314103/valve-ending-development-artifact-tcg-dota-2">like <em>Artifact</em></a>. </p></div><div><p>Most Popular</p><p>Most Popular</p><ol><li><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/8/22/24225972/ai-photo-era-what-is-reality-google-pixel-9"><h2>No one’s ready for this</h2></a><hr></li><li><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/8/23/24226830/elon-musk-email-x-twitter-stock-grants"><h2>Elon Musk says X staff can get their stock — if they prove they deserve it</h2></a><hr></li><li><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/8/22/24225997/microsoft-copilot-rebrand-changes"><h2>Microsoft is rebranding Copilot in the most Microsoft way possible</h2></a><hr></li><li><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/8/23/24226684/starlink-satellite-internet-scalpers-fee"><h2>Starlink has a pricey new plan to stop scalpers</h2></a><hr></li><li><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/8/21/24225169/nothing-employees-office-work-mandate-five-days"><h2>Nothing is requiring employees to be in the office five days a week</h2></a><hr></li></ol></div></div></article></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kamala Harris’ First Twitch Stream Peaked At Under 1,000 Viewers, Some Of Whom Spammed Palestinian Flags]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/kamala-harris-twitch-stream-dnc-palestine</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/kamala-harris%E2%80%99-first-twitch-stream-peaked-at-under-1-000-viewers-some-of-whom-spammed-palestinian-flags.962598/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://aftermath.site/kamala-harris-twitch-stream-dnc-palestine<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Kamala Harris, current United States vice president and the Democratic Party’s candidate for president, now <a href="https://www.twitch.tv/kamalaharris" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">has a Twitch channel</a>. Yesterday evening, her team broadcasted from it for the first time, allowing Twitch viewers to tune into a couple hours of speeches from the final night of the DNC, including Harris’ big coronation. The stream peaked at 933 concurrent viewers, well below the Twitch debuts of other presidential aspirants like Bernie Sanders (7,233) and Donald Trump (12,826).</p><p>During the broadcast, chat was largely in emote-only mode, with many seemingly intended to express enthusiasm (hearts, raised hands, signs that read ‘yea,’ etc). These were sporadically broken up by floods of Palestinian flags, as well as images of letters that spelled out “Free Palestine.”&nbsp;</p><figure><figcaption>Twitch</figcaption></figure><p>This followed a week of thousands-strong pro-Palestinian protests outside the DNC, as well as demonstrations from <a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2024/8/21/meet-the-uncommitted-how-gaza-hangs-over-democratic-national-convention" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the Uncommitted Movement</a>, a group led by delegates representing hundreds of thousands of people who voted “uncommitted” in the Democratic primaries as a result of Biden's seemingly bottomless well – and <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/us-approves-20-billion-weapons-sales-israel-hamas-backs-out-cease-fire-talks/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">warchest</a> –&nbsp; of support for Israel. The Uncommitted Movement attempted to negotiate with the Democratic Party to get a Palestinian American speaker, whose <a href="https://www.motherjones.com/politics/2024/08/dnc-speech-uncommitted-movement-harris-walz-ruwan-romman/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">brief speech</a> would have been vetted, on stage at the DNC, only to be <a href="https://apnews.com/article/uncommitted-palestinian-convention-harris-918812eb0e19b9669f8b9b9cd88c6360" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">turned away Wednesday night</a>. The day before, the DNC handed the mic over to parents of an Israeli American hostage held by Hamas, prompting demands from the left and <a href="https://www.npr.org/2024/08/22/g-s1-19169/palestinian-protests-dnc-united-autoworkers" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">powerful unions like United Auto Workers</a> for someone of Palestinian descent to be granted the same privilege.</p><p>During her own speech, Harris disappointed those who hoped she might deviate from Biden’s bloody path, <a href="https://www.npr.org/2024/08/23/g-s1-19232/kamala-harris-israel-gaza-dnc" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">saying</a> that she “will always stand up for Israel's right to defend itself” and “will always ensure Israel has the ability to defend itself.” However, she also acknowledged the “heartbreaking” scale of suffering in Gaza and said that she and Biden continue to push for a ceasefire deal so that "Palestinian people can realize their right to dignity, security, freedom, and self determination." Granted, Biden has been saying things like this for the past ten months, and it has done absolutely nothing to change the material reality of the situation – which is continuous, pointless slaughter of <a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2024/7/8/gaza-toll-could-exceed-186000-lancet-study-says" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">(at least) tens of thousands of innocent people</a>.</p><p>Harris’ poor performance on Twitch does not indicate a lack of interest in her campaign, even on the platform. At the same time as Harris’ channel, Hasan “HasanAbi” Piker, the biggest political commentator on Twitch, <a href="https://www.twitch.tv/videos/2231129523?filter=archives&amp;sort=time" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">streamed Harris’ speech</a> to an audience that maxed out at nearly 60,000 concurrent viewers. Other, smaller politically-focused channels simultaneously broadcast her speech to thousands more.&nbsp;</p><p>Harris also does not have novelty on her side; when Sanders and Trump joined Twitch, it was nearly unheard of for politicians to do such a thing. Now many have tried to varying degrees of success, from Democratic Representative Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez with her <a href="https://kotaku.com/alexandria-ocasio-cortez-streams-on-twitch-with-hasan-p-1845431479" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">430,000-viewer <em>Among Us</em> stream in 2020</a> (which included Piker, among many other big-name content creators) to Republican Representative Matt Gaetz’s <a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/matt-gaetz-twitch/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">comically sad six-viewer showing in 2022</a>. More recently, Trump has <a href="https://aftermath.site/aftermath-hours-podcast-adin-ross-donald-trump-kick-stream" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">cameoed in content from somehow-popular bottom feeders</a> like Kick streamer Adin Ross to the tune of hundreds of thousands of viewers. The DNC, meanwhile, just allowed content creators to attend for the first time, granting special access to 200 and <a href="https://archive.is/AaXVb" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">even special-er access to a select handful</a>. The RNC ran a similar, albeit more limited, playbook, opening its doors to around 70 content creators in July.</p><p>It’s worth noting that Sanders and Trump’s Twitch channels no longer post numbers even remotely as impressive as they used to back in 2020. These days, Sanders is lucky to break 1,000, while Trump tends to hover between 2,000 and 5,000, with one recent spike that went beyond 10,000. Granted, <a href="https://www.polygon.com/24203801/donald-trump-twitch-channel-unbanned" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">until July</a>, Trump was banned from Twitch following the January 6, 2021 insurrection, and nothing boosts numbers on livestreaming platforms like a long-awaited return.&nbsp;</p><p>What these channels and Harris’ have in common is that, so far, they’ve largely been content to broadcast speeches, rallies, and other events rather than directly interact with Twitch streamers or viewers. On Twitch, scanning and responding to chat is the bare minimum, and if you want your channel to grow, the meta these days is to form relationships with well-known streamers with whom you share values and a general vibe. No politician has successfully pulled this off, and the reason why is simple: It’s a full-time job. Politicians – at least, if they’re halfway decent – already have one of those.</p><p>That said, Harris’ team has proven impressively social-media savvy, <a href="https://aftermath.site/charli-brat-kamala-vibes" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">embracing the summer’s inescapable brat meme</a> and <a href="https://www.avclub.com/harris-walz-campaign-uses-dril-tweet-in-email" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">invoking Weird Twitter legend Dril</a> in a campaign email (although you could argue that <a href="https://www.rollingstone.com/politics/politics-features/dril-kamala-harris-trump-post-1235084267/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">that second one ended up backfiring</a>). Perhaps, then, this is just the beginning for Harris’ humble little Twitch channel. Who knows? Maybe Tim Walz will go live tomorrow and <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/vp-candidate-tim-walz-was-a-big-dreamcast-fan-and-we-think-weve-found-his-favorite-game" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">play some <em>Crazy Taxi</em></a>.&nbsp;</p><p><em>Additional reporting by Riley MacLeod.</em></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ulsan Wins The Tekken 8 Esports World Cup Grand Final]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/ulsan-wins-the-tekken-8-esports-world-cup-grand-final/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ulsan-wins-the-tekken-8-esports-world-cup-grand-final.962577/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/ulsan-wins-the-tekken-8-esports-world-cup-grand-final/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Popular Tekken 8 competitors, Ulsan and Atif went up against each other today in the Tekken 8 Esports World Cup Grand Final. Though, both fought hard, only one player was to walk out as the Tekken 8 Esports World Cup Champion. </p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-ulsan-wins-the-tekken-8-esports-world-cup">Ulsan Wins The Tekken 8 Esports World Cup</h2>



<p>The two competitors took the battlefield in a first-to-five competition. Atif, began the tournament with quite a bit of momentum, as the player won the first two rounds of Game 1. Ulsan, though, was not allowing for a sweep, coming back and winning the game 3-2. </p>



<p>Both players played as the infamous Dragonuv.</p>



<p>Going into Game 2, Ulsan did not drag behind from his momentum during Game 1, winning the game 3-1 and putting himself ahead 2-0. Atif, though, desperately wanted a comeback, winning the first two rounds of Game 3. Still, Ulsan proved why he does the best under pressure, coming back and winning the game 3-2.</p>



<figure></figure>







<p>Game 4 was no different for Ulsan, as the competitor won 3-1, putting himself in a 4-0 lead, with only one more win needed to grab that Esports World Cup victory.</p>



<p>While some fans were probably hoping for a historic comeback from Atif, it sadly did not happen, as Ulsan swept the player with a 5-0 win, certifying himself as the Tekken 8 Esports World Cup Champion and walking out with a whopping $300,000.</p>



<hr>



<h3 id="h-about-ulsan">About Ulsan</h3>



<p>Ulsan has been competing in the Tekken esports scene since 2018 when the South Korean player would dominate in Tekken 7 tournaments. The competitor has walked out of various Tier 1 tournaments with first place, making him one of the most decorated Tekken players out there.</p>



<p>Now, playing for KWANGDONG FREECS, Ulsan continues to push the Tekken esports scene to a new level.</p>



<hr>



<h3 id="h-about-atif">About Atif</h3>



<p>Atif has been competing in the Tekken esports scene since 2019, as the Pakistani fighting games player currently plays for Team Falcons. Atif has only placed in one Tekken Teams tournament but has claimed various first places in multiple big 1v1 events.</p>



<p>Stay tuned to Insider Gaming for more <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/category/esports/">esports news</a>.</p>



<hr>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>
    
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sony's Noise-Canceling Gaming Earbuds For PC And PS5 Drop To Best Price Yet]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/sony-inzone-gaming-earbuds-pc-and-ps5-headset-amazon-deals/1100-6526096/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sonys-noise-canceling-gaming-earbuds-for-pc-and-ps5-drop-to-best-price-yet.962574/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/sony-inzone-gaming-earbuds-pc-and-ps5-headset-amazon-deals/1100-6526096/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="default-content">
        
          <p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p>
  
    <article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6526096">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>If you prefer earbuds over gaming headsets, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/best-wireless-gaming-headset/1100-6525389/" data-ref-id="1100-6525389">our favorite pair of wireless gaming earbuds</a> are on sale for a limited time. Both the white-and-black and all-black models of <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Sony-Wireless-Cancelling-Earbuds-WF-G700N/dp/B0CJH6NV38?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Sony's Inzone Buds are discounted to $178 (was $200)</a> at Amazon. This matches the lowest price since launch last holiday. Amazon hasn't listed an end date for the deal, but if the retailer sells out, you can grab a pair of <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fshop-links.co%2F1851609106618159245%3Fu1%3Dsubid_value&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fsony-inzone-gaming-earbuds-pc-and-ps5-headset-amazon-deals%2F1100-6526096%2F%3Fftag%3DCAD-01-10abi2f&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Inzone Buds from Best Buy for $180</a>.</p><p>Made by Sony Electronics--not PlayStation--the Inzone Buds are designed for PC gaming, but they are fully compatible with PS5, Nintendo Switch, Steam Deck, Android, and iPhone 15 via the 2.4GHz dongle. They offer more bang for your buck than <a href="https://www.amazon.com/PULSE-Explore-Wireless-Earbuds-PlayStation-5/dp/B0CMDFSB89?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">PlayStation's Pulse Explore earbuds</a> ($200). Since they're equipped with the same drivers as the popular <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Sony-WF-1000XM5-Bluetooth-Canceling-Headphones/dp/B0C33XXS56?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">WF-1000XM5 earbuds</a> that carry a list price of $300 (on sale for $52 off at Amazon) <em>and</em> implement Sony's excellent noise-canceling tech, they're an easy recommendation at full price. PlayStation's Pulse Explore wireless earbuds do well in the sound department, and while they do a good job isolating noise, they aren't equipped with true ANC.</p><div title="6522763 - Inzone Buds First Discount" data-embed-type="buylink" data-ref-id="2329" data-template="4" data-size="buylink__listicle" data-title="6522763 - Inzone Buds First Discount" data-collection="">                                                                     <div>             <h2>                    <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Sony-Wireless-Cancelling-Earbuds-WF-G700N/dp/B0CJH6NV38?tag=gamespot-promos-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/Sony-Wireless-Cancelling-Earbuds-WF-G700N\/dp\/B0CJH6NV38?tag=gamespot-promos-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/Sony-Wireless-Cancelling-Earbuds-WF-G700N/dp/B0CJH6NV38?tag=gamespot-promos-20">Sony Inzone Buds - Wireless Noise-Canceling Gaming Earbuds</a>       </h2>                                   <h3>                      <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Sony-Wireless-Cancelling-Earbuds-WF-G700N/dp/B0CJH6NV38?tag=gamespot-promos-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/Sony-Wireless-Cancelling-Earbuds-WF-G700N\/dp\/B0CJH6NV38?tag=gamespot-promos-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/Sony-Wireless-Cancelling-Earbuds-WF-G700N/dp/B0CJH6NV38?tag=gamespot-promos-20">$178 (was $200)</a>         </h3>                                                                                                                      <div><p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Sony-Wireless-Cancelling-Earbuds-WF-G700N/dp/B0CJH6NV38?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Sony Inzone Buds</a> are available in either a combo white/black color scheme or black. Both models are eligible for the current Amazon deal. Along with superb active noise cancellation and up to 12 hours of battery life (24 with the charging case), PC users can use the Inzone Hub software to fully customize their performance. Those settings, including one of up to 256 sound profiles, can be synced to the earbuds and used on PS5 and other devices. The PS5's audio features, such as Tempest 3D Audio and Dolby Atmos, are fully compatible with the Inzone Buds.</p><p>Like most wireless earbuds, the Inzone Buds have tap/touch controls that work well. You can use the controls to turn ANC on or off, adjust the volume, tinker with the sound mix, and more. Tap controls can be programmed to different functions. If you worry about latency with wireless headsets, the 2.4GHz connection has only 30ms of latency, which helps create a seamless and reliable listening experience. An AI-assisted microphone enhances your voice to help your words ring out clearly to your teammates.</p><p>The gaming earbud space isn't loaded with anywhere close to as many competitors as the established gaming headset market, but Inzone Buds are the best we've used so far. Sony's experience manufacturing high-end earbuds certainly helped when designing the Inzone Buds. They are comfortable to wear for hours of continuous use and inside the box you'll find four sets of silicone eartips of varying sizes.</p><p>The biggest downside to the earbuds is that many users will the included USB-C dongle on mobile, as its Bluetooth LE Audio connection isn't supported by many devices. Some newer Android phones have Bluetooth LE, but Apple's iPhones aren't part of that small ecosystem. iOS users with an iPhone 15 can simply connect the USB-C dongle for playback, but if you have an iPhone with a Lightning port, you'll need a Lightning to USB-C adapter that supports audio. (including iPhone). <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0CDLGYS1G?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">This $15 adapter</a> works perfectly in our experience, but it obviously adds a dangling cord to your iPhone and introduces the risk of diminishing sound quality and increased latency--we never noticed this, but different adapters and phones may lead to different results.</p><p>If you want to read more about Sony's gaming earbuds, check out our <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/sonys-new-inzone-buds-aim-to-replace-your-gaming-headset/1100-6518375/" data-ref-id="1100-6518375">Sony Inzone Buds review</a>.</p></div>                      </div>                                                                     <div>             <h2>                    <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Sony-INZONE-Wireless-Canceling-Over-ear-Headphones/dp/B0B1TDHLPT?tag=gamespot-promos-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/Sony-INZONE-Wireless-Canceling-Over-ear-Headphones\/dp\/B0B1TDHLPT?tag=gamespot-promos-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/Sony-INZONE-Wireless-Canceling-Over-ear-Headphones/dp/B0B1TDHLPT?tag=gamespot-promos-20">Sony Inzone H9 Wireless Noise-Canceling Gaming Headset</a>       </h2>                                   <h3>                      <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Sony-INZONE-Wireless-Canceling-Over-ear-Headphones/dp/B0B1TDHLPT?tag=gamespot-promos-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/Sony-INZONE-Wireless-Canceling-Over-ear-Headphones\/dp\/B0B1TDHLPT?tag=gamespot-promos-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/Sony-INZONE-Wireless-Canceling-Over-ear-Headphones/dp/B0B1TDHLPT?tag=gamespot-promos-20">$228 (was $300)</a>         </h3>                                                                                                                      <div><p>Amazon also has discounts on over-ear Inzone gaming headsets, including the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Sony-INZONE-Wireless-Canceling-Over-ear-Headphones/dp/B0B1TDHLPT?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">premium Inzone H9 wireless headset</a>, which takes cues from <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Sony-WH-1000XM5-Canceling-Headphones-Hands-Free/dp/B09XS7JWHH?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Sony's flagship WH-1000XM5 headphones</a>, for $228 (was $300). Speaking of the WH-1000XM5 headphones, they are <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Sony-WH-1000XM5-Canceling-Headphones-Hands-Free/dp/B09XS7JWHH?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">on sale for $100 off at Amazon</a>.</p><p>The H9 uses the same leatherette and memory foam cushions as the WH-1000XM5. It has ANC, full support with Inzone Hub for customization, and is compatible with all of the PS5's audio features. It has 2.4GHz and Bluetooth for wireless connectivity, but it's worth noting the dongle is USB-A, not USB-C. On the plus side, it has wider Bluetooth compatibility, as it doesn't use Bluetooth LE--so it'll sync via Bluetooth to your iPhone, Android phone, Switch, Steam Deck, etc.</p><p>The <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Sony-INZONE-Wireless-Canceling-Over-ear-Headphones/dp/B0CJGV2DQT?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">mid-range wireless Inzone H5 headset</a> without noise-canceling tech is on sale for $128 (was $150).</p><p>Here's a list of all of the Sony Inzone audio deals available now at Amazon:</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Sony-Wireless-Cancelling-Earbuds-WF-G700N/dp/B0CJH6NV38?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Sony Inzone Buds Wireless Noise-Canceling Gaming Earbuds (White)</a> -- $178 (<del>$200</del>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Sony-Wireless-Cancelling-Earbuds-WF-G700N/dp/B0CJHB7B59?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Sony Inzone Buds Wireless Noise-Canceling Gaming Earbuds (Black)</a> -- $178 (<del>$200</del>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Sony-INZONE-Wireless-Canceling-Over-ear-Headphones/dp/B0B1TDHLPT?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Sony Inzone H9 Wireless Noise-Canceling Gaming Headset (White)</a> -- $228 (<del>$300</del>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Sony-INZONE-Wireless-Canceling-Over-ear-Headphones/dp/B0CJH3DJ36?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Sony Inzone H9 Wireless Noise-Canceling Gaming Headset (Black)</a> -- $228 (<del>$300</del>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Sony-INZONE-Wireless-Canceling-Over-ear-Headphones/dp/B0CJGV2DQT?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Sony Inzone H5 Wireless Gaming Headset (White)</a> -- $128 (<del>$150</del>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Sony-INZONE-Wireless-Canceling-Over-ear-Headphones/dp/B0CJH8PSBS?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Sony Inzone H5 Wireless Gaming Headset (Black)</a> -- $128 (<del>$150</del>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Sony-INZONE-Wireless-Canceling-Over-ear-Headphones/dp/B0B1SXW7LB?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Sony Inzone H3 Wired Gaming Headset</a> -- $78 (<del>$100</del>)</li></ul></div>                      </div>   </div><p>The Inzone Buds are the best earbuds we've tried in the still-small gaming category, but they aren't your only solid option. Asus has two different models of its ROG Cetra: the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/ASUS-ROG-Headphones-Bone-Conduction-Microphones/dp/B0CXS16KNF?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">high-end SpeedNova with 2.4GHz and Bluetooth 5.3 for $190</a> (was $200) and the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/ASUS-ROG-Headphones-Low-Latency-Cancelation/dp/B0BRSCKG2D?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Bluetooth-only ROG Cetra for $80 (was $100)</a>. Both support Bluetooth connections on a wider array of devices, including iPhone, Android, Nintendo Switch, and Steam Deck.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article>

    
  

</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Report: Deleted Megalopolis Trailer Used Fake Quotes Generated By AI]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/megalopolis-trailer-fake-ai-coppola-release-date-1851630700</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/report-deleted-megalopolis-trailer-used-fake-quotes-generated-by-ai.962541/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/megalopolis-trailer-fake-ai-coppola-release-date-1851630700<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="ffe8f98404179f69dee88a4210f54b92" data-recommend-id="image://ffe8f98404179f69dee88a4210f54b92" data-format="jpg" data-width="1200" data-height="675" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Adam Driver holds up a T-ruler. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Adam Driver holds up a T-ruler. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Lionsgate</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="ffe8f98404179f69dee88a4210f54b92" data-recommend-id="image://ffe8f98404179f69dee88a4210f54b92" data-format="jpg" data-width="1200" data-height="675" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Adam Driver holds up a T-ruler. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p><em>Apocalypse Now </em>director Francis Ford Coppola’s sci-fi passion project <em>Megalopolis</em> continues to be one of Hollywood’s biggest train wrecks. The latest derailment was a trailer that had to be pulled for fabricating quotes. It’s now <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://variety.com/2024/film/news/megalopolis-trailer-fake-quotes-ai-lionsgate-1236116485/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://variety.com/2024/film/news/megalopolis-trailer-fake-quotes-ai-lionsgate-1236116485/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">being reported</a></span> that, surprise, the trailer quotes were generated by AI.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="197209" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="The Boys Star Karen Fukuhara On Kimiko’s Character Arc, Karate, And More" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="319" data-playlist="197209,196923,196922" data-current="197209"><div><p>The Boys Star Karen Fukuhara On Kimiko’s Character Arc, Karate, And More</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197209/197209_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197209/197209_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197209/197209_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197209/197209_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/22759.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>Where to begin with <em>Megalopolis</em>? The short version is that it’s a heady but big-budget art house movie with an eclectic but all-star cast led by Adam Driver about an architect facing an existential crisis in a futuristic city. Coppola has apparently wanted to make it for decades, and even sold part of his winery to finance the $120 million budget. Its <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/film/article/2024/may/17/francis-ford-coppola-megalopolis-critic-reviews-roundup-cannes-film-festival&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.theguardian.com/film/article/2024/may/17/francis-ford-coppola-megalopolis-critic-reviews-roundup-cannes-film-festival" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">divided critics</a></span> with a roughly <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.rottentomatoes.com/m/megalopolis&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.rottentomatoes.com/m/megalopolis" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">50 percent on Rotten Tomatoes</a></span> and Coppola <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://variety.com/2024/film/news/megalopolis-set-video-francis-ford-coppola-kissing-extras-1236082653/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://variety.com/2024/film/news/megalopolis-set-video-francis-ford-coppola-kissing-extras-1236082653/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">has been accused of inappropriate behavior</a></span> on the set, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.ign.com/articles/video-of-francis-ford-coppola-kissing-extras-on-megalopolis-set-emerges-after-accusations-of-inappropriate-behavior&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/video-of-francis-ford-coppola-kissing-extras-on-megalopolis-set-emerges-after-accusations-of-inappropriate-behavior" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">including a video showing him kissing female extras</a></span>.</p><p>Then this week a trailer came out that included famous movie critics panning various past films of Coppola’s like <em>Bram Stoker’s Dracula.</em> “Diminished by its artsiness,” read a quote attributed to Pauline Kael about <em>The Godfather</em> for <em>The New Yorker</em> that flashes onscreen, trying to make the point that any recent negative press around <em>Megalopolis</em> is similarly mistaken. The only problem was that Kael never wrote it. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://variety.com/2024/film/news/megalopolis-trailer-fake-quotes-ai-lionsgate-1236116485/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://variety.com/2024/film/news/megalopolis-trailer-fake-quotes-ai-lionsgate-1236116485/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Variety</em> now reports</a></span> that generative AI did.<br></p><p>“Sources tell <em>Variety</em> it was not Lionsgate or Egan’s intention to fabricate quotes, but was an error in properly vetting and fact-checking the phrases provided by the consultant,” reads the report. “It appears that AI was used to generate the false quotes from the critics.”</p><p>Lionsgate didn’t comment on the allegation, but it has parted ways with Eddie Egan, the marketing consultant now being blamed for the embarrassing controversy. “Lionsgate is immediately recalling our trailer for <em>Megalopolis</em>,” the company which is distributing the movie announced earlier this week. “We offer our sincere apologies to the critics involved and to Francis Ford Coppola and American Zoetrope for this inexcusable error in our vetting process. We screwed up. We are sorry.”</p><p><em>Megalopolis</em> comes to theaters in wide-release on September 27 and I am morbidly curious. </p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PlayStation Plus Classics update could fix major TimeSplitters issue]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/08/23/playstation-plus-classics-update-could-fix-major-timesplitters-issue/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/playstation-plus-classics-update-could-fix-major-timesplitters-issue.962520/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/08/23/playstation-plus-classics-update-could-fix-major-timesplitters-issue/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>In case you missed it, earlier this week <a href="http://thesixthaxis.com/tag/sony">Sony</a> updated its <a href="http://thesixthaxis.com/tag/playstation-plus">PlayStation Plus</a> Classics lineup with a slew of new arrivals. Among them were TimeSplitters and its two sequels, <a href="http://thesixthaxis.com/tag/timesplitters">TimeSplitters</a> 2, and TimeSplitters: Future Perfect, making the trilogy fully playable on PS4 and PS5 consoles.</p>
<p><iframe title="TIME SPLITTERS: FUTURE PERFECT - Trailer" width="780" height="585" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ViC2gbGcJhM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>However, it didn’t take PlayStation gamers long to realise something was missing. When Sony first added PS2 games to its growing PlayStation Plus Classics library, each of them (Tomb Raider: Legend, Sly Raccoon, and Star Wars: The Clone Wars) came with full <a href="http://thesixthaxis.com/tag/playstation-trophies">trophy</a> support. Subsequent PS2 titles including Ghosthunter and Summoner also touted this feature. For some reason, the TimeSplitters games don’t have any virtual silverware for retro FPS fans to collect.</p>
<p>Clearly disappointed, one PSN user (<a href="https://www.truetrophies.com/news/timesplitters-ps2-trophy-patch">via TrueTrophies</a>) reached out to TimeSplitters IP holder and publisher <a href="http://thesixthaxis.com/tag/deep-silver">Deep Silver</a> asking about trophy support. Their response was that “trophies are considered and should be available in a future patch” though “currently we do not have an official release date.”</p>
<p>Many trophy hunters will no doubt wait to pull the trigger on the TimeSplitters trilogy until then. Still, the temptation to blast through these time-hopping classics may prove irresistible. While they might pave the way for a welcome trip down memory lane, the trilogy’s return to PlayStation is also a painful reminder of the cancelled TimeSplitters projects that will never come to light.</p>

<p>For those who remember, developer Free Radical had been working on a TimeSplitters 4 though the studio was almost shut down following the PS3 exclusives flop that was Haze. The team was snapped up by Crysis and Hunt: Showdown publisher, Crytek, before later being bought by Embracer Group.</p>
<p>Sadly, <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2023/12/11/free-radical-design-shutdown-timesplitters-cancelled/">Free Radical closed its doors for good earlier this year</a> amidst a wave of devastating layoffs and closures that swept the industry far and wide. A project titled TimeSplitters Next was cancelled as a result – a modernised, trend-chasing take on the series that later pivoted towards being an expanded TimeSplitters 2 remake before the axe finally fell.</p>
<p>Let’s hope that TimeSplitters isn’t gone for good and that another studio can take a swing at restoring it to its former glory.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Concord’s Launch Is Worse Than Expected]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/concords-launch-is-worse-than-expected/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/concord%E2%80%99s-launch-is-worse-than-expected.962502/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/concords-launch-is-worse-than-expected/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>The struggle of hero-shooter Concord continues as the game is officially out, and no one seems to care. In its first few hours available worldwide, Concord has yet to surpass even 1,000 players on Steam since launch.</p>



<p>As of writing, <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/2443720/charts/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">less than 700 players</a> are actively playing the online PvP title.</p>



<p>To be honest, this shouldn’t be too surprising based on the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-concord-open-beta-bombed-on-steam/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">poor open beta numbers</a> when no one had to pay to access the game. Now that you have to spend the full $40 to play, it’s hard to see it becoming a hit out of nowhere.</p>



<p>Obviously the numbers should go up over the weekend as more people have time to play the game. But it’s unlikely we’ll see them go up to a point where both Sony and Firewalk Studios are happy with the numbers. As far as PlayStation 5 player numbers, that information isn’t publicly available. It could be assumed, however, that numbers on the console would be higher than PC. How much higher, though, is unclear.</p>



<p>With all that said, Firewalk seems set to support Concord — a game that has been <a href="https://x.com/sharkeatsman/status/1826122649963245882" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">in development for eight years</a> — at least through the winter. The game’s <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/concord-post-launch-roadmap-outlines-new-characters-maps-and-mode/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">first two seasons</a> have already been announced as coming in October and January. There’s also a tease for a third season in April. But beyond that, questions are going to continue about the viability of the game that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/concord-hit-with-overly-negative-response-after-reveal/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">fans seemed to be turned off by</a> right from the start.</p>



<hr>



<p>Are you going to give Concord a shot with its launch, or is it a game that doesn’t interest you? For more Insider Gaming, check out the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/new-the-wrestling-code-tech-demo-shows-gameplay-arena-crowd-and-more/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">new tech demo for The Wrestling Code</a> that shows off new gameplay, lighting systems, crowds, and more.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>
    
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Paizo Backtracks On Fan Content Policy, Reinstates Older Community Use Policy]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/paizo-backtracks-on-fan-content-policy-reinstates-older-community-use-policy</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/paizo-backtracks-on-fan-content-policy-reinstates-older-community-use-policy.962484/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/paizo-backtracks-on-fan-content-policy-reinstates-older-community-use-policy<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Back in July, Paizo Inc. replaced their <a href="https://paizo.com/community/blog/v5748dyo6sid6?Update-from-Paizo-President-Jim-Butler">Community Use</a> policy with a new Fan Content policy. This was a controversial move since it drastically altered and restricted what players and creators could do with fan-created <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/games/pathfinder" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><em>Pathfinder</em></a> material. Paizo is now taking steps to walking back this policy, including reinstating the original Community Use Policy.</p>
<h2>The Paizo Fan Content Walk Back</h2>
<p>In an official <a href="https://paizo.com/community/blog/v5748dyo6w469?Updates-on-the-Community-Use-Policy-and-Fan">blog post</a>, Paizo announced they would be making changes to their Fan Content policy while reinstating their original Community Use Policy. In addition, updates and clarifications will be implemented, making the policies easier to parse.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/pathfinder-2e-ice-mountain-artwork.jpg?itok=BscKfJnF 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/pathfinder-2e-ice-mountain-artwork.jpg?itok=JNj3exDJ 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>For those unaware, Paizo's original Community Use policy was in place for over 15 years. In broad terms it allowed players to create original content for <em>Pathfinder</em> and <em>Starfinder</em>. The only catch was you couldn't charge for access. This was a boon for fan projects since it permitted the use of named characters and locations.</p>
<p>A version of this policy was also in effect for different <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/paizo-announces-pathfinder-second-edition-remaster-project" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><em>Pathfinder 2e</em></a> materials. This included Foundry VTT support</p>
<p>With Paizo shifting to the <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/pathfinder-creator-paizo-releases-first-draft-of-open-rpg-creative-license-asking-for" rel="noopener" target="_blank">ORC license</a>, the company implemented their Fan Content policy. This was a more restrictive policy since it required creators to remove setting specific characters and terms to comply with the ORC and limited the publishing of work to approved platforms like Roll20 or <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/pathfinder-infinite-coming-to-roll20" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><em>Pathfinder Infinite</em></a>.</p>
<p>The post further details the policy changes coming with the Fan Content and Community Use policies. First, the Approved Products List and Community Use Registry have been removed. For the latter, you must include contact information on your product.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/pathfinder-rise-of-the-rune-lords-artwork.jpg?itok=xzTyUwgV 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/pathfinder-rise-of-the-rune-lords-artwork.jpg?itok=dIUZ9r77 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>With these changes, fans can still monetize their creations through the Fan Content policy, just with the freedoms permitted under the Community Use policy. Paizo has confirmed they will be refining these policies to clearly define what commercial uses of their products are allowed.</p>
<p>The post concludes with Paizo apologizing to the community for their misstep with these policies, promising to inform the community as soon as these revised policies go into effect.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Ever since he was small, Tyler Chancey has had a deep, abiding love for video games and a tendency to think and overanalyze everything he enjoyed. This… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/tyler-chancey">More about Tyler</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Yu-Gi-Oh's $18 Retro Pack Brings Vintage Booster Set To North America For The First Time]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/yu-gi-ohs-18-retro-pack-brings-vintage-booster-set-to-north-america-for-the-first-time/1100-6526083/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/yu-gi-ohs-18-retro-pack-brings-vintage-booster-set-to-north-america-for-the-first-time.962478/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/yu-gi-ohs-18-retro-pack-brings-vintage-booster-set-to-north-america-for-the-first-time/1100-6526083/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6526083">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>There's never been a better time to be a fan of trading card games, and for those of you who grew up on Yu-Gi-Oh, this special edition booster set is going to have you ready to duel all over again. Released today, August 23, <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fshop-links.co%2F1851589040090220250%3Fu1%3Dsubid_value&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fyu-gi-ohs-18-retro-pack-brings-vintage-booster-set-to-north-america-for-the-first-time%2F1100-6526083%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Yu-Gi-Oh TCG: Retro Pack</a> contains a bunch of vintage cards and only costs $18. Here's what you get:</p><h2><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fshop-links.co%2F1851589040090220250%3Fu1%3Dsubid_value&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fyu-gi-ohs-18-retro-pack-brings-vintage-booster-set-to-north-america-for-the-first-time%2F1100-6526083%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Yu-Gi-Oh TCG: Retro Pack</a></h2><ul><li>48 common cards</li><li>24 rare cards</li><li>10 super-rare cards</li><li>8 ultra-rare cards</li><li>11 secret-rare cards</li></ul><p>The story behind this retro pack is that it was originally an overseas exclusive, as it featured a collection of vintage cards from the earliest days of the game and was made to catch up other countries to the US card pool. The exact cards were hard to find in the US--unless you wanted to pay an obscene amount for them on the reseller market--and this set goes an extra retro-step further by including the original card frames, illustrations, names, and texts.</p><p>Another nice added touch is that the drop-rates for the foil cards are double that of the original version, so this is a good opportunity to finally get that Blue-Eyes Ultimate Dragon with limited-edition labelling that you've been after.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/scale_super/1601/16018044/4356103-yu-gi-oh-tcg.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4356103" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/scale_super/1601/16018044/4356103-yu-gi-oh-tcg.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4356103"></a><figcaption>Yu-Gi-Oh Trading Card Game: Retro Pack</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/scale_super/1601/16018044/4356103-yu-gi-oh-tcg.jpg"></figure><p>The Retro Pack isn't the only recent Yu-Gi-Oh release designed to appeal to the nostalgic adults who grew up playing Yu-Gi-Oh. If you're a new or returning player, <strong><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fshop-links.co%2F1851587307102140102%3Fu1%3Dsubid_value&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fyu-gi-ohs-18-retro-pack-brings-vintage-booster-set-to-north-america-for-the-first-time%2F1100-6526083%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">there's a $20 two-player starter set</a></strong> with two 44-card decks and a 64-page comic book to teach you the rules.</p><p>If you're looking to celebrate the 25th anniversary of Yu-Gi-Oh, <strong><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fshop-links.co%2F1851587318097539809%3Fu1%3Dsubid_value&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fyu-gi-ohs-18-retro-pack-brings-vintage-booster-set-to-north-america-for-the-first-time%2F1100-6526083%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">there's a collector's edition tin with 300 cards</a></strong>--six of which are secret-rare prismatic cards--<strong><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fshop-links.co%2F1851587314770119191%3Fu1%3Dsubid_value&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fyu-gi-ohs-18-retro-pack-brings-vintage-booster-set-to-north-america-for-the-first-time%2F1100-6526083%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">and there's a box set themed around Yugi, Seto Kaiba, and Joey</a></strong>, allowing you to wield their signature monsters and the Egyptian God cards.</p><p>Lastly, the <strong><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fshop-links.co%2F1851587310809300492%3Fu1%3Dsubid_value&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fyu-gi-ohs-18-retro-pack-brings-vintage-booster-set-to-north-america-for-the-first-time%2F1100-6526083%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Yu-Gi-Oh: 25th Anniversary Rarity Collection 2</a></strong> has packs with an increased drop-rate for ultra and secret-rare cards, in case you're on the hunt for luxury versions of the cards that have a luxurious foil finish.</p><h3>More Yu-Gi-Oh products for nostalgic fans</h3><ul><li><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fshop-links.co%2F1851587307102140102%3Fu1%3Dsubid_value&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fyu-gi-ohs-18-retro-pack-brings-vintage-booster-set-to-north-america-for-the-first-time%2F1100-6526083%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Yu-Gi-Oh: Two-player starter set</a> -- $20</li><li><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fshop-links.co%2F1851587310809300492%3Fu1%3Dsubid_value&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fyu-gi-ohs-18-retro-pack-brings-vintage-booster-set-to-north-america-for-the-first-time%2F1100-6526083%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Yu-Gi-Oh: 25th anniversary Rarity Collection 2</a> -- $30</li><li><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fshop-links.co%2F1851587314770119191%3Fu1%3Dsubid_value&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fyu-gi-ohs-18-retro-pack-brings-vintage-booster-set-to-north-america-for-the-first-time%2F1100-6526083%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Yu-Gi-Oh: Legendary Decks 2</a> -- $30</li><li><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fshop-links.co%2F1851587318097539809%3Fu1%3Dsubid_value&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fyu-gi-ohs-18-retro-pack-brings-vintage-booster-set-to-north-america-for-the-first-time%2F1100-6526083%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Yu-Gi-Oh: 25th Anniversary Dueling Heroes</a> -- $22</li></ul><p>On the entertainment side, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-first-yu-gi-oh-movie-is-coming-back-with-a-steelbook-blu-ray-release/1100-6523732/" data-ref-id="1100-6523732">fresh stock of the very first Yu-Gi-Oh movie is releasing September 10</a>, so don't miss out on a chance to grab this <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0D3MM6B8H?tag=gamespot-preorders-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow"><strong>steelbook edition of Yu-Gi-Oh The Movie</strong></a>.</p><hr><p>Originally released in 2004, Yu-Gi-Oh: The Movie takes place between Seasons 3 and 4 of the anime series and features a high-stakes duel between Yugi and his rival Seto Kaiba, a pyramid controlled by the Egyptian Lord of the Dead, Anubis, and proof that even legions of undead monsters are no match for the power of anime-friendship. Video game fans can check out the upcoming Switch release of <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Yu-Gi-Oh-Early-Days-Collection-Nintendo-Switch/dp/B0D9PKCT42?tag=gamespot-preorders-20" rel="nofollow ">Yu-Gi-Oh: Early Days</a> Collection, a fun compilation of games from the formative years of the franchise, like Yu-Gi-Oh Duel Monsters 4: Battle of Great Duelists &amp; 2001's Yu-Gi-Oh Duel Monsters 6: Expert 2.</p><p>You can also preorder the upcoming <strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Yu-Gi-Oh-Early-Days-Collection-Nintendo-Switch/dp/B0D9PKCT42?tag=gamespot-preorders-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Yu-Gi-Oh: Early Days Collection</a></strong>, an "expansive" compilation of retro games, including Duel Monsters 4 and Duel Monsters 6. We're still waiting on Konami to reveal the full lineup, but the collection promises to include games that weren't released in the US the first time around.</p><div data-embed-type="pinbox" data-ref-id="4304">  <ul>                              <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/star-wars-outlaws-preorder-guide/1100-6522523/">Star Wars Outlaws Preorders - Where To Find The Best Bonuses</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/buy-two-get-one-free-nintendo-switch-games-and-preorders-my-best-buy-members/1100-6525928/">B2G1 Free All Nintendo Switch Games - Zelda: Echoes Of Wisdom, Mario &amp; Luigi, And More Preorders</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/dragon-age-the-veilguard-preorder-guide/1100-6525830/">Dragon Age: The Veilguard Collector's Edition Preorders Live Now</a></li>                          <li>         <span>+ Show More More Gaming, Tech, and Entertainment Deals &amp; Preorders Links (5)</span>       </li>          <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/doom-anthology-preorders-quakecon-2024/1100-6525656/">Doom Anthology Preorders Are Live - Comes With 6 Games, Steelbook Case, And Replica BFG</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/retrorealms-halloween-ash-vs-evil-dead-retro-game-preorder-guide/1100-6525752/">Halloween And Ash Vs. Evil Dead Retro Games Revealed - Collector's Bundle Preorders Live</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/amiibo-nintendo-switch-restocks-reprints-2024/2900-5671/">Rare Nintendo Amiibo Figures Restocked - Ness, Mr. Game &amp; Watch, ROB, Charizard, And More</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/final-fantasy-i-vi-pixel-remaster-collection-north-america-release/1100-6525641/">Final Fantasy Pixel Remaster Collection Anniversary Edition Preorders Live At Amazon</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/retro-pokemon-brick-sets-in-stock-at-target-pixel-art-mew-pikachu-charmander-and-more/1100-6525719/">Retro Pokemon Brick Sets In Stock At Target - Pixel Art Mew, Pikachu, Charmander, And More</a></li>   </ul> </div>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/108490194306897153177?rel=author">Darryn Bonthuys</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Scientists Discover Non-Living Hydrogel Can Play And Improve At Pong]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/scientists-discover-non-living-hydrogel-can-be-used-to-play-and-improve-at-pong/1100-6526095/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/scientists-discover-non-living-hydrogel-can-play-and-improve-at-pong.962475/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/scientists-discover-non-living-hydrogel-can-be-used-to-play-and-improve-at-pong/1100-6526095/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="default-content">
        
          <p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p>
  
    <article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6526095">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Researchers discovered that the polymer material hydrogel can play and improve its gameplay experience by playing the prolific video game Pong.</p><p>As reported in the findings from the <a href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2024/08/240822125903.htm" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Cell Press journal</a>, scientists were able to hook up non-living hydrogels with electrical stimulation in a virtual video game environment. This then allowed the non-living hydrogel to improve its gameplay by up to 10% with practice and was even able to create longer rallies between the paddles alongside an increased hit rate. It took 20 minutes for the hydrogel to reach its maximum "Pong potential," the journal states.</p><p>"We showed that hydrogels are not only able to play Pong; they can actually get better at it over time," said first author and robotics engineer Vincent Strong from the University of Reading.</p><p>More research is still needed, but the researchers said that this showcases the ability of non-living materials--hydrogel in this case--to use memory to update the hydrogel's understanding of its immediate environment.</p><p>This latest study and research were inspired by the testing from a <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2022/oct/13/scientists-teach-brain-cells-to-play-virtual-pong" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">few years ago on a dish of brain cells that were taught to play Pong</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article>

    
  

</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[9 Things We Learned About Monster Hunter Wilds At Gamescom]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/monster-hunter-wilds-gamescom-new-features-1851630592</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/9-things-we-learned-about-monster-hunter-wilds-at-gamescom.962442/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/monster-hunter-wilds-gamescom-new-features-1851630592<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><figure id="" data-id="7d8a6aa6f69cd10c8e9af1a396c2c31e" data-recommend-id="image://7d8a6aa6f69cd10c8e9af1a396c2c31e" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A screenshot of a recent Monster Hunter Wilds trailer showing the main character and some of the supporting cast." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A screenshot of a recent Monster Hunter Wilds trailer showing the main character and some of the supporting cast." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="false" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Kotaku / Capcom</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="7d8a6aa6f69cd10c8e9af1a396c2c31e" data-recommend-id="image://7d8a6aa6f69cd10c8e9af1a396c2c31e" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A screenshot of a recent Monster Hunter Wilds trailer showing the main character and some of the supporting cast." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/monster-hunter-wilds-ps5-preview-release-date-1851535133&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/monster-hunter-wilds-ps5-preview-release-date-1851535133"><em>Monster Hunter Wilds</em></a></span><em> </em>is looking like it’s going to be one of the biggest games of 2025 already, and its showing at <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/gamescom-opening-night-live-trailers-announcements-1851627031&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/gamescom-opening-night-live-trailers-announcements-1851627031">Gamescom</a></span> is going incredibly well. The game is playable for the first time to the public, and the amount of information coming out of just that preview build is insane. We’ve learned a <em>lot </em>just from three days of developer interviews and fans collating all the info they’ve gleaned from the demo, and here’s just some of the biggest things we’ve spotted over the past week. </p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="109b72969ab1299e0392af3a35637068" data-recommend-id="image://109b72969ab1299e0392af3a35637068" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A screenshot of Monster Hunter Wilds showing the new 3D map." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A screenshot of Monster Hunter Wilds showing the new 3D map." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="false" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Kotaku / Capcom</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="109b72969ab1299e0392af3a35637068" data-recommend-id="image://109b72969ab1299e0392af3a35637068" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A screenshot of Monster Hunter Wilds showing the new 3D map." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>As you might expect, a new <em>Monster Hunter </em>game is bound to pack in a bunch of quality-of-life changes that series veterans and newcomers alike will appreciate. One of the biggest tweaks comes to <em>Monster Hunter Wilds</em>’ map, which is now 3D. In the past, maps have been flat while trying to communicate the sheer density of the different biomes, which made them a bit of a confusing mess for players who weren’t already familiar with the layouts of the areas. Now, it should be <em>much </em>easier to maneuver across <em>Wilds</em>’ huge new environments.</p><p>When you’re in a big fight, you’re typically picking at weak points in the hope of crippling the monster’s movement or abilities and getting monster parts, which used to break off and appear as shiny bits you needed to manually collect. That no longer seems to be entirely the case, and now when you break parts of the monster, you’ll automatically pick up smaller pieces, meaning you don’t have to scramble in or out of combat to get every last scrap now. You’ll still need to carve bigger pieces, like tails, and dead monsters can now be climbed on in order to harvest them. And hey, if you’re hurting after a fight or on your way to another one and don’t want to choose between your different potions, there’s now a dynamic healing option that’ll pick the best fit based on your health.</p><p>Funnily enough, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/MonsterHunter/comments/1ext4ve/barrel_bombs_can_now_be_picked_up_after_being/#:~:text=Xanek-,Barrel%20bombs%20can%20now%20be%20picked%20up%20after%20being%20placed,thrown%20to%20roll%20into%20monsters&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/MonsterHunter/comments/1ext4ve/barrel_bombs_can_now_be_picked_up_after_being/#:~:text=Xanek-,Barrel%20bombs%20can%20now%20be%20picked%20up%20after%20being%20placed,thrown%20to%20roll%20into%20monsters" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">explosive barrels</a></span> (which used to be static) can now be picked up and thrown at enemies, and potentially even teammates. There’s a million little changes like this that should make dealing with all the nuts-and-bolts stuff outside of monster-killing simpler and more approachable than in its predecessors. Oh, and as a fun aside that I’ll also chalk up to “quality-of-life changes,” <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/MonsterHunter/comments/1ext4ve/barrel_bombs_can_now_be_picked_up_after_being/#:~:text=Xanek-,Barrel%20bombs%20can%20now%20be%20picked%20up%20after%20being%20placed,thrown%20to%20roll%20into%20monsters&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/MonsterHunter/comments/1ext4ve/barrel_bombs_can_now_be_picked_up_after_being/#:~:text=Xanek-,Barrel%20bombs%20can%20now%20be%20picked%20up%20after%20being%20placed,thrown%20to%20roll%20into%20monsters" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">explosive barrels</a></span> (which used to be static) can now be picked up and thrown at enemies, and potentially even teammates. Look, being able to troll my friends is important to the “quality” of my “life.” It counts! </p></div></div><div><figure id="" data-id="e90fc7908e258897a6d8719b4975fa27" data-recommend-id="image://e90fc7908e258897a6d8719b4975fa27" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A screenshot of Monster Hunter Wilds showing the player character walking around the village hub area." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A screenshot of Monster Hunter Wilds showing the player character walking around the village hub area." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="false" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Kotaku / Capcom</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="e90fc7908e258897a6d8719b4975fa27" data-recommend-id="image://e90fc7908e258897a6d8719b4975fa27" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A screenshot of Monster Hunter Wilds showing the player character walking around the village hub area." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>That’s not all that Capcom’s been up to, though. If you’re playing the game in single-player mode, you can now pause, which hasn’t been available for a while, and you can even skip the quest-end timer in solo play and multiplayer, assuming everyone agrees to skip it. Finishing a hunt will no longer kick you back to camp either, and on that note, you can also pick up quests in the field dynamically. Just running across a monster can trigger its hunt, so you no longer have to initiate missions from the village.</p><p>It also appears that you can <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/lovebreaddd/status/1826281126283157682&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/lovebreaddd/status/1826281126283157682" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">dodge out of certain moves</a></span> or sheathe your weapon mid-animation, which is going to save people tons of time and hardship. Previously, <em>Monster Hunter </em>players have had to simply commit to the animation of whatever attack they unleashed, whether it connected or not, which <em>could </em>open them up to attacks from the massive monsters that they’re charged with hunting. </p></div></div><div><figure id="" data-id="89c69ec7add1d701822a12e0ca9cbe63" data-recommend-id="image://89c69ec7add1d701822a12e0ca9cbe63" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A screenshot of Monster Hunter Wilds showing multiplayer gameplay from Gamescom." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A screenshot of Monster Hunter Wilds showing multiplayer gameplay from Gamescom." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="false" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Kotaku / Capcom</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="89c69ec7add1d701822a12e0ca9cbe63" data-recommend-id="image://89c69ec7add1d701822a12e0ca9cbe63" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A screenshot of Monster Hunter Wilds showing multiplayer gameplay from Gamescom." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p><em>Monster Hunter </em>games have always been big on multiplayer, typically allowing squads of up to four players (as well as smaller AI companions) to take on hunts and synergize their loadouts to maximize the results of the missions. In a drastic change, <em>Monster Hunter Wilds </em>now features AI hunters that can support the player in hunts if desired. SOS flares can now be customized to only summon NPCs or players depending on what you want, but by default they will populate the game with NPCs if you can’t find a party to play with. </p></div><div><p>One of the smaller but still significant features to return in <em>Monster Hunter Wilds </em>is the ability to swim underwater. Though it has existed in previous games and underwater combat was included in <em>Monster Hunter 3 </em>and <em>3 Ultimate</em>, water sections have largely been MIA for the last several installments due to the polarizing reception to them in the past. Though <em>Wilds </em>doesn’t have underwater combat, the team seems to be testing the waters (so to speak) by implementing underwater areas again at all, which has some fans hoping that DLC may eventually bring the full feature back. </p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="28f25574e6cd3effbde039ec1b94924b" data-recommend-id="image://28f25574e6cd3effbde039ec1b94924b" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A screenshot of Monster Hunter Wilds showing a hunter with the insect glaive weapon." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A screenshot of Monster Hunter Wilds showing a hunter with the insect glaive weapon." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="false" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Kotaku / Capcom</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="28f25574e6cd3effbde039ec1b94924b" data-recommend-id="image://28f25574e6cd3effbde039ec1b94924b" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A screenshot of Monster Hunter Wilds showing a hunter with the insect glaive weapon." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>I used to think that the Insect Glaive, one of <em>Monster Hunter</em>’s more ludicrous and complex weapons, was a very niche loadout, but turns out a lot of people love it and especially appreciate the air acrobatics it allowed players to do. That no longer seems to be the case in <em>Wilds</em>, which appears to have nerfed the bounce that players would get off of a mid-air slashing combo. The thing effectively let you stay in the air forever, and while it looked quite silly, it was also great at making the class visually distinct from others, which are largely terrestrial. </p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="773b3bdd85a1082af53fbff216a5407f" data-recommend-id="image://773b3bdd85a1082af53fbff216a5407f" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A screenshot of Monster Hunter Wilds showing the armor and equipment screen." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A screenshot of Monster Hunter Wilds showing the armor and equipment screen." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="false" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Kotaku / Capcom</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="773b3bdd85a1082af53fbff216a5407f" data-recommend-id="image://773b3bdd85a1082af53fbff216a5407f" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A screenshot of Monster Hunter Wilds showing the armor and equipment screen." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>In a win for truly everyone, armor is no longer gender-locked in <em>Monster Hunter Wilds. </em>This has never been the case before, and has meant that sometimes a player couldn’t get armor they really wanted because they locked themselves in when choosing their character’s gender as they were customizing them. Now, you can slap on whatever you want. Additionally, armors have bonuses for completing sets, but there will also be bonuses for armor pieces from different monsters as long as they fit a common theme!</p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="a2bebfdebb1441297a7814c2001a0b34" data-recommend-id="image://a2bebfdebb1441297a7814c2001a0b34" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A screenshot of Monster Hunter Wilds showing a perfect block on an enemy." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A screenshot of Monster Hunter Wilds showing a perfect block on an enemy." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="false" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Kotaku / Capcom / PlayStation</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="a2bebfdebb1441297a7814c2001a0b34" data-recommend-id="image://a2bebfdebb1441297a7814c2001a0b34" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A screenshot of Monster Hunter Wilds showing a perfect block on an enemy." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>The <em>Monster Hunter </em>series has some of the most entertaining weapons in all of gaming, and incredibly deep mechanics for each one. Think of a weapon in these games as the equivalent of a fighting game character, complete with their own moveset, unique combos, and latent abilities. Not only are most of them getting tweaked or reworked in some way, but now Capcom is adding perfect-timing mechanics to a slew of them, too.</p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="46f778e49cd3ef97782fb53fa7add01b" data-recommend-id="image://46f778e49cd3ef97782fb53fa7add01b" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A screenshot of a trailer showing the player and their mount dodging an incoming attack." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A screenshot of a trailer showing the player and their mount dodging an incoming attack." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="false" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Kotaku / Capcom</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="46f778e49cd3ef97782fb53fa7add01b" data-recommend-id="image://46f778e49cd3ef97782fb53fa7add01b" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A screenshot of a trailer showing the player and their mount dodging an incoming attack." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p><em>Monster Hunter Wilds </em>features dynamic weather effects called Inclemencies that roll through the biomes and drastically change the nature of the arena. The most common one we’ve seen through trailers and previews is a mixture of a sandstorm and thunderstorm, and these will affect monsters and hunters alike. However, even outside of these effects, aspects of the environment can set you up for failure. On one of the developer streams out of Gamescom, the players lured one monster to a sand dune that caused the monster to trip over itself more easily, making it vulnerable to more attacks from the hunters. Another creature that could crawl on surfaces that players couldn’t reach could be toppled and stunned by using the hunter’s slinger (and specifically the grapple ability on it) to bring the column it was climbing on down.</p></div><div><p>In case you haven’t realized, there’s a lot to cover that’s new in <em>Monster Hunter Wilds</em>. For example, you will be able to cook meals that account for changes in the climate, such as whipping up foodthat negates the effects of cold or hot weather. Mounting monsters in this game is also pretty similar to how it functioned in <em>Monster Hunter World </em>and you now have more moves when you’re riding a creature. Alongside the basic dagger plunge, you can now do a heavy attack and a signature finisher based on your weapon. </p><p>That isn’t all either. Large dung pods can be used to disperse herds of monsters, which is going to be especially helpful since <em>Wilds </em>seems to be going in on monsters that have swarms of little minions. There are also now up-close Power Clash moments, such as perfect guarding with a shield which results in a quick-time event where you beat back the monster. When a monster is going to unleash a particularly nasty attack, your life bar will also flash quite dramatically to warn you to guard or dodge out of the way. There’s literally too many cool polishes and changes to count. <br></p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[World of Warcraft: The War Within Review in Progress]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/world-of-warcraft-the-war-within-review</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/world-of-warcraft-the-war-within-review-in-progress.962439/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/world-of-warcraft-the-war-within-review<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>At the time I'm writing this, I've put about seven hours into World of Warcraft: The War Within – basically every moment between when it unlocked and when I could no longer keep my eyes open. And that's very early to say anything definitive. But… I have a very good feeling about this one, you guys. From the story, to the environments, to the new features, this is World of Warcraft firing on all cylinders. I'm not utterly blown away or anything that hyperbolic, but compared to the last three expansions' launches, the warm glow of new adventure is hitting different this time.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>I've been taking my sweet time – relatively speaking – so while <a href="https://www.icy-veins.com/wow/news/incredible-world-first-level-80-in-the-war-within-completed-already/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">some bedlamites</a> had already hit 80 inside of a couple hours, I logged off for the night at level 73. That pace allowed me to collect three of my new Hero Talents for my Marksmanship Hunter, and I chose to go with the night elf-themed Sentinel over the tortured soul, Sylvanas-inspired Dark Ranger. I'm not super thrilled with these talents yet; we'll see how it feels at 80, but I'm not getting the sense of a significant change in my power or my playstyle with each level like I'd hoped. </p><p>I do like that The War Within doesn't add a bunch of new buttons to my hotbar, though. Part of why I picked Sentinel over Dark Ranger is that the latter makes you incorporate a new attack into your rotation, and I like that I have the option not to have to worry about that.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3>Every IGN World of Warcraft Review</h3></div></output><h2><strong>Setting the Stage</strong></h2><p>If you missed the big announcement last BlizzCon, The War Within is intended as the first part of a trilogy of expansions that aim to tell a larger, complete story. This is something WoW has never done before, and I'm pretty excited about it. Without spoiling too much, the first hour of the story definitely feels like we're going full speed ahead into something sweeping and epic. Some major sacred cows in the lore are actually on the chopping block (not literally – Baine is fine, don't worry). And Xal'atath is a compelling new nemesis – not just because she's a hot goth mommy.</p><p>I mean, it's partly that. But it's not <em>just</em> that.</p><p>I've only seen the first of The War Within's zones, the verdant and picturesque Isle of Dorn, which exists on the surface just above where the other 80 percent takes place. It feels very familiar to a long-time WoW player in a lot of the same ways the Dragon Isles did, and basically all of the best features from Dragonflight are back. You get Dynamic Flying (what used to be called Dragonriding) almost immediately, which I'm still conflicted about just because I think exploring new zones for the first time on the ground gives you more of a sense of place and grandeur. But I'm not conflicted at all about the return of thrilling aerial race courses and the expanded profession system.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>The Isle of Dorn has some of my favorite music since Wrath of the Lich King.</p></div><p>Dornogal, the capital of the Earthen who protect Azeroth's depths, is one of the coolest hub cities we've ever gotten thanks to its majestic Titan architecture and an interesting political storyline to unravel. It's also quite a bit more organized and easier to navigate than the sometimes disorienting vertical layout of Valdrakken.</p><p>And the music! I can easily say the Isle of Dorn has some of my favorite music in WoW since, dang, Wrath of the Lich King maybe? Since Blizzard’s composers always kill it with their orchestral excellence, it's really something when they release this many tracks that stand out even by their high standards.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><h2><strong>The Long Road Ahead</strong></h2><p>Just like Dragonflight, the smaller zone quests are often memorable and touching. I think the one everybody's going to be talking about this time involves one of the semi-immortal Earthen realizing that his mind is starting to deteriorate, and asking you to help him set his affairs in order as he plans to end his own life in the traditional fashion of his people. I never get tired of being reminded that, for all the world-shaking, high-fantasy shenanigans driving World of Warcraft at the plot level, these kinds of heartfelt and relatable tales are what actually make it special.</p><p>I'm also quite optimistic about Delves, the new solo content that's meant to be something of an alternative to raids and Mythic+ in the endgame, for people like me who don't like to interact with randos and don't have any friends left who still play this game from the group I started out with in 2004. They feature the same kinds of silly and ridiculous temporary power-ups I adored from Torghast, including one that gives you a double jump and another that greatly increases your damage as long as you never fall below half health. If Torghast has only one fan, it is me. If Torghast has no fans, then I am gone from this Earth. So it's great to see some of the things that worked about it coming back.</p><div data-cy="playlist-view-trigger"><h3>Len Ranks All the WoW Expansions</h3><p>Every WoW expansion ranked best to worst. Dragonflight is not included since we won't really know for a couple years where it falls.</p></div><p>One delve I played has what are effectively the jump mushrooms from Sonic the Hedgehog, allowing you to explore vertically in a new way, and another features wall-mounted ledges you can zip up to with a grappling hook. The only thing hurting my excitement about these is that they seem really, really short so far – less than 15 minutes in some cases. Part of it is that I haven't unlocked the higher difficulties yet, so I can basically Arcane Shot-spam my way through the entire thing without looking at my health bar. And I've only seen the first three. But I was hoping for something closer to the length of a five-person dungeon experience.</p><p>There's way, way more of The War Within I haven't seen at this point than what I have, but I'm thoroughly enjoying myself so far, and that’s just about the highest praise one can give an expansion at launch. Check back next week for the first big update on my progress, and for a final verdict some time after Season 1 and the first raid unlock on September 10.</p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>