<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 20:54:25 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ghost of Tsushima PC PSN-Requiring Crossplay Launches in Beta, Game Optimized for Steam Deck]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/ghost-of-tsushima-pc-psn-crossplay-beta-launch-steam-deck-optimized/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ghost-of-tsushima-pc-psn-requiring-crossplay-launches-in-beta-game-optimized-for-steam-deck.870834/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/ghost-of-tsushima-pc-psn-crossplay-beta-launch-steam-deck-optimized/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p><a href="https://wccftech.com/tag/ghost-of-tsushima/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Ghost of Tsushima Director’s Cut</a> arrives on PC this week, and port developer Nixxes has laid out a few additional details about the launch. As we’ve reported, Ghost of Tsushima is the latest Sony-published title to <a href="https://wccftech.com/ghost-of-tsushima-pc-delisted-steam-psn-despite-singleplayer-not-needing/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">generate controversy for requiring a PlayStation Network sign-in on PC</a>. Granted, <a href="https://wccftech.com/ghost-of-tsushima-pc-psn-account-single-player/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">GoT only requires PSN on PC for the Legends multiplayer mode</a>, you can play the single-player campaign without it, but the game has still been delisted from Steam in a long list of countries without access to PSN.</p>
<p>Well, interestingly, Nixxes now claims that Ghost of Tsushima PC-console crossplay, presumably the main reason a PSN sign-in is required, <a href="https://twitter.com/NixxesSoftware/article/1790396884873355624" target="_blank" rel="noopener">will launch in “beta.”</a></p>
<p><em>“As previously announced, Legends co-op multiplayer mode will include cross-play between players on PS4 consoles, PS5 consoles and PC. Legends will be functional on PC at launch, but you won't be automatically matched with players on different platforms. Cross-play will launch in beta, meaning you can try it out by inviting your PlayStation Network friends.”</em></p>
<p>As may have pointed out, it feels like this could be Sony providing themselves an out – if there’s too much backlash to PSN, they can simply remove the PSN requirement as they move crossplay out of beta without having to officially backtrack.</p>
<p>In another oddity related to PSN, Nixxes claims they’ve fully optimized Ghost of Tsushima for Steam Deck and other portable gaming PCs, but the game is still listed as “unsupported” because, you guessed it, accessing PSN requires Windows.</p>
<p><em>“We know many of you are eager to play Ghost of Tsushima Director's Cut on handheld gaming devices like the Steam Deck. We're happy to share that the single player experience, including the Iki Island expansion, can be enjoyed on Steam Deck and similar handheld gaming PCs as we’ve worked extensively to optimize performance and deliver the best possible experience on these devices. You may notice that Steam marks the game as 'Unsupported' for Steam Deck. This is due to the Legends co-op multiplayer mode requiring Windows to access PlayStation Network integrated features.”</em></p>
<p>Ghost of Tsushima Director’s Cut launches on PC on May 16, and is currently available on PS4 and PS5.</p>

				

			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[For The Queen Review - Pure Storytelling]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/for-queen-review-pure-storytelling</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/for-the-queen-review-pure-storytelling.870831/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/for-queen-review-pure-storytelling<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>It's so interesting that when you pick up something that is a game you intrinsically think about winning, or competition, maybe points to keep track of. That's what I expected opening up <em>For The Queen</em>, a Storytelling Card Game by Alex Roberts. What I got though totally relaxed my definition of a game and I was so happy for it.</p>
<p><em>For The Queen</em> is an improvisational character and world-building game where questions are posed to you about a fictitious Queen and your relationship and history with them while you journey to a foreign land.</p>
<p>You can decide on the Queen you're travelling with from any of the twenty-five included Queens, or make up your own.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/for-the-queen-review-box-open.jpg?itok=VTlFi2-_ 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/for-the-queen-review-box-open.jpg?itok=pOz5UFsb 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>The box, designed to look like a book, opens to reveal the hook of the game and all of the cards</figcaption></figure><h2>Choose Your Queen</h2>
<p>I loved the selection of Queens. You have traditional Disney princess-styled queens, 21st-century pantsuit queens, high-fantasy, edo, and even futuristic Queens. While there are some Queens that immediately build a friendly aura, there are others that you likely wouldn't dare talk back on.</p>
<p>The game does recommend picking a Queen as a group, for a planned session with a theme and approach in mind this makes a lot of sense but I ended up enjoying letting fate decide by shuffling the Queens around and having to adapt.</p>
<p>Players will then begin to pull cards from the shuffled deck of questions. These questions will prod you with character and world-building questions forcing you to be introspective of a character you're creating on the fly.</p>

<p>Examples of these questions include "What question do you wish you could ask the Queen? What keeps you from asking it?", "The Queen trusts you, but no one else in the royal court does. Why?", or "What promise did the Queen make to you before this journey? Do you think she'll keep it?"</p>
<p>There are certainly no simple questions to be found in this box, and as you continue to build up the idea of who the players are and what kind of person their Queen is each question can become increasingly complex.</p>
<p>The tone of the game can also change as different players reveal new things. My answer to "What makes you want to abandon the retinue, and who, besides the Queen makes you stay?" was wildly influenced after another player revealed something they had been ordered to do by the Queen that they regretted.</p>
<h2>The Unplayed Character of <em>For The Queen</em></h2>
<p>The focus of the game, the Queen, is an unrepresented entity at the table and is shaped by the stories. I was really intrigued by a narrative game about a character that's a blank slate for everyone to craft in their own way. The same Queen may end up entirely different depending on who you're playing the game with.</p>

<p>The game ends as the question "The Queen is under attack. Do you defend her?" is drawn. Each player makes their decision and with that the game is over.</p>
<p>Each game can last for as long as you wish to place the attack card into the deck making it as short as a 15-minute game, or it can go on for two hours.&nbsp;</p>
<h2><em>For The Queen</em> Review | Final Thoughts</h2>
<p>Playing <em>For The Queen</em> was an incredibly refreshing experience. From it's lack of innate competitivity, to it's simple setup and premise this is a fun exercise in worldbuilding and introspection that I have yet to experience before.</p>
<p>Understandably if the idea of roleplay isn't something that you are a fan of then this certainly isn't going to move your dial, but if you're looking for a fun storytelling game that can be set up in seconds and that can have wildly different outcomes you should keep this in reach.</p>
<hr><p><em>The copy of&nbsp;</em><strong>For The Queen</strong><em>&nbsp;used in the creation of this review was provided by Darrington Press</em>.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
<div>
<h2>Review Summary</h2>

<p>
For The Queen is an entertaining Storytelling game that relies on roleplay and building up a world and characters through interesting prompts. While it did take a bit to wrap my head around the concept once we got to playing it was nothing but a unique experience. (<a href="https://techraptor.net/review-score-policy">Review Policy</a>)
</p>
</div>
<div>
<div>
<h3>Pros</h3>
<div><ul><li>Unique Storytelling Game</li><li>Beautiful Presentation</li></ul></div>
</div>
<div>
<h3>Cons</h3>
<div><ul><li>Need a Narrative Buy In</li></ul></div>
</div>
</div>
</div></span></p></div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Andrew has written Video Game and Entertainment news, reviews, and guides for 10+ years. As Senior Content Manager, he assists in creating and editing… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/andrew-stretch">More about Andrew</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Final Fantasy 8 Is The Perfect Follow-Up To FF7]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-7-8-ff7-ff8-cloud-squall-rinoa-tifa-1851476972</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/final-fantasy-8-is-the-perfect-follow-up-to-ff7.870828/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-7-8-ff7-ff8-cloud-squall-rinoa-tifa-1851476972<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>After replaying the original, 1997, <em>Final Fantasy VII</em> recently, I knew the next step for me was to immediately jump into <em>Final Fantasy VIII</em>. As my favorite<em> </em>game in the franchise, I can hardly resist any opportunity to play <em>FF8</em>, but this time I felt more encouraged to draw points of comparison and differences between it and <em>FF7</em>. Though they feature totally different worlds, characters, and stories, they work together as almost narrative cousins in an inspiring and fascinating way.</p><div data-video-id="196923" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Kotaku’s Hopes For Spyro The Dragon’s (Reported) Comeback" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="355" data-playlist="196923,196922,196918" data-current="196923"><div><p>Kotaku’s Hopes For Spyro The Dragon’s (Reported) Comeback</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196923/196923_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196923/196923_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196923/196923_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196923/196923_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/22494.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><p><strong>Read More:</strong> <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-7-ff7-review-1997-worth-playing-1851411735&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-7-ff7-review-1997-worth-playing-1851411735"><em>Final Fantasy VII</em>: The <em>Kotaku</em> Retro Review</a></span></p><p>Though they have their clear differences, I was always struck by how<em>FF7 and FF8 </em>operate on similar wavelengths. They tell similar stories—albeit with very different tones, and are both a fusion of science fiction and fantasy, utilizing the tech of the ‘90s with 3D models superimposed over pre-rendered backgrounds with fixed camera angles. Playing them often feels like a very similar experience. And, notably, both games feature characters who struggle with memory loss.</p><figure id="" data-id="c19af06cc8baa1146ed3a84bc3bc46bd" data-recommend-id="image://c19af06cc8baa1146ed3a84bc3bc46bd" data-format="jpg" data-width="1280" data-height="720" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Cloud questions if his memories are a lie in Final Fantasy VII." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Cloud questions if his memories are a lie in Final Fantasy VII." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Square Enix / Claire Jackson / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="c19af06cc8baa1146ed3a84bc3bc46bd" data-recommend-id="image://c19af06cc8baa1146ed3a84bc3bc46bd" data-format="jpg" data-width="1280" data-height="720" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Cloud questions if his memories are a lie in Final Fantasy VII." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>But whereas <em>FF7</em> puts its protagonist, Cloud, through crippling episodes of pain at the reemergence of his memories, <em>FF8</em> is far more gentle with its cast of orphans, almost as if it wants to imagine a better future and present for them than <em>FF7</em> affords its cast. </p><p><strong>Read More:</strong> <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-8-ff8-worth-playing-remastered-1851417540&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-8-ff8-worth-playing-remastered-1851417540">Playing <em>Final Fantasy VIII</em> In 2024: Everything You Need To Know</a></span></p><p><em>FF7</em>’s narrative often feels sinister at times, with bursts of static punctuating the frail mind of the aptly named Cloud Strife, with the menacing threats of the game’s antagonists Jenova and Sephiroth lurking behind every corner. Cloud is rarely afforded a moment to be a normal person, to have normal thoughts. Instead, he spends much of the game posing as someone he’s not. </p><figure id="" data-id="97746ae15a5cf09e4899a372c6aa15cb" data-recommend-id="image://97746ae15a5cf09e4899a372c6aa15cb" data-format="jpg" data-width="1280" data-height="720" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Jenova taunts Cloud by calling him a puppet." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Jenova taunts Cloud by calling him a puppet." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Square Enix / Claire Jackson / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="97746ae15a5cf09e4899a372c6aa15cb" data-recommend-id="image://97746ae15a5cf09e4899a372c6aa15cb" data-format="jpg" data-width="1280" data-height="720" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Jenova taunts Cloud by calling him a puppet." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>While <em>FF8</em>’s characters have also lost their memories, they’re allowed more space to be themselves. Protagonist Squall’s realizations and internal monologues are allowed to breathe and mentally wander. <em>FF8</em> features far more internal monologues, many of which document the characters working through difficult and confusing situations. It’s something that Cloud is rarely afforded the opportunity to do. Squall’s thoughts are befitting of an awkward 17-year-old kid whose childhood memories have faded, as he’s forced to contend with a set of cosmic expectations that are hard to fully comprehend. Whereas Cloud emerges from a far more traumatic past, with sharp internal thoughts that quite literally wound him. Unpacking his memories is a violent ordeal, one that forces him, and his childhood friend Tifa, to go through a surreal and painful journey of recollection. </p><p><strong>Read More:</strong> <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-7-ff7-aeris-aerith-death-ghost-1851476144&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-7-ff7-aeris-aerith-death-ghost-1851476144">Is This Aerith’s Ghost In The Original <em>Final Fantasy VII</em>?</a></span></p><p>In <em>FF8</em>, the pressures of the geo-political situation around Squall and the other characters are intimidating, no doubt, but the tone is wildly different. This is especially true of the moment the characters regain their memories of themselves and each other.</p><p><em>FF7</em>’s biggest tragedy is impactful, sharp, and harrowing, featuring the irreversible death of a character. <em>FF8</em> feels like it wants to be kinder to its cast. Moments that could be a matter of life and death, such as deciding how to split the party when Galbadia launches missiles at Balamb Garden, don’t end in irreversible tragedy. <em>FF8</em>’s characters live to see each other again, and live to remember each other in a more gentle way. </p><figure id="" data-id="da9417ece719120d2f90fc08108394b1" data-recommend-id="image://da9417ece719120d2f90fc08108394b1" data-format="jpg" data-width="1280" data-height="720" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A young Squall stands in a rainstorm and says he'll be okay." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A young Squall stands in a rainstorm and says he'll be okay." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Square Enix / Claire Jackson / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="da9417ece719120d2f90fc08108394b1" data-recommend-id="image://da9417ece719120d2f90fc08108394b1" data-format="jpg" data-width="1280" data-height="720" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A young Squall stands in a rainstorm and says he'll be okay." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>The differences in how both games depict their worlds, and the spaces give to the player are also of note. <em>FF8</em>’s Balamb Garden, for example, is a kind of home that <em>FF7</em>’s characters, perhaps with the exception of Red XIII and maybe Yuffie, are afforded. Most places in <em>FF7</em> are in some state of oppression and tragedy. <em>FF8</em>, though, portrays more normal, varied domestic settings that aren’t as downtrodden and reliant on a risky energy source owned and distributed by a vicious, militant corporation. I often find the world of <em>FF8</em> more alluring to day dream about because of this. Or, at the very least, it’s a setting that inspires more optimism.</p><p><strong>Read More:</strong> <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-7-original-worth-playing-before-rebirth-1851390539&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-7-original-worth-playing-before-rebirth-1851390539">So You Want To Play The Original <em>Final Fantasy VII</em>?</a></span></p><p>That difference is what makes playing these two back-to-back always a pleasant experience. It’s easy to walk away from <em>FF7</em>, I think, with a sense of despair and uncertainty. True, <em>FF8</em>’s conclusion is also quite mysterious, but it spends less time under immediate narrative pressure like <em>FF7</em> does. As a result, playing <em>FF8</em> immediately after <em>FF7</em> provides alternate perspectives and inspires different emotional contours. The experience of playing both affords a kind of trans-narrative resolution that’s refreshing in a world dominated by a steady progression of direct sequels, prequels, and remakes in games.</p><figure id="" data-id="ed1a5a953bd828896ccfeb9151f2030b" data-recommend-id="image://ed1a5a953bd828896ccfeb9151f2030b" data-format="jpg" data-width="1280" data-height="720" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Squall ponders why people depend on each other." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Squall ponders why people depend on each other." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Square Enix / Claire Jackson / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="ed1a5a953bd828896ccfeb9151f2030b" data-recommend-id="image://ed1a5a953bd828896ccfeb9151f2030b" data-format="jpg" data-width="1280" data-height="720" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Squall ponders why people depend on each other." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p><em>FF8</em> will always be my favorite <em>Final Fantasy</em>, but I do love thinking of <em>FF7 </em>and <em>FF8</em> as related to one another, handling similar settings and themes with different approaches. And moving from one universe to a completely different one, as <em>Final Fantasy </em>used to, is the kind of thing I hope the series regains. Much as I’ve enjoyed some sequels like <em>X-2</em>, <em>XIII-2</em>, and both <em>FF7 </em>remake installments, moving across separate worlds while still vibing on compatible themes is something <em>Final Fantasy</em> used to do well, and is in my opinion far more interesting than sequels that offer little more than additional lore dumps. <br></p><p>.<br></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ghost of Tsushima PC Cross-Play Will Launch With a Beta Label Attached]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/ghost-of-tsushima-on-pc-will-launch-with-a-beta-label-attached</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ghost-of-tsushima-pc-cross-play-will-launch-with-a-beta-label-attached.870822/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/ghost-of-tsushima-on-pc-will-launch-with-a-beta-label-attached<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>PlayStation reversed course on the unpopular decision to require a PSN login for the Steam version of Helldivers 2, but headaches remain for Ghost of Tsushima on PC, which is set to release later this week.</p><p>In a <a href="https://x.com/NixxesSoftware/status/1790396884873355624" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">post published on X / Twitter</a>, developer Nixxes Software announced that Legends — Ghost of Tsushima's cooperative multiplayer game requiring a PSN login — will be functional on PC at launch, but won't automatically match players on different platforms. Instead, cross-play will carry a beta tag.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>"Cross-play will launch in beta, meaning you can try it out by inviting your PlayStation Network friends," the post reads. "We would love your feedback as we continue to make adjustments in the weeks following launch!"</p><p>What this means for the future is unclear. In the wake of the Helldivers 2 debacle, Sucker Punch clarified that the online portion of the <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/helldivers-2-pc-escapes-psn-account-requirement-but-ghost-of-tsushima-multiplayer-does-not">PC release would require a login, but that the single-player would not</a>. Despite that, the purchase of <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ghost-of-tsushima-on-steam-helldivers-2-psn">Ghost to Tsushima on Steam is currently restricted</a> in numerous countries where PSN is unavailable. In response, Steam has begun auto-refunding players in affected countries.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div><h3>The Best PS5 Games</h3></div></output><p>Ghost of Tsushima is the latest PlayStation game to make its way to PSN, and the first to <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ghost-of-tsushima-directors-cut-pc-requirements-revealed-playstation-trophy-support-confirmed">introduce a new overlay that includes trophy support and other perks</a>. However, the backlash against Helldivers 2's PSN requirements has apparently forced PlayStation to reconsider its plans for the platform.</p><p>"We’re still learning what is best for PC players and your feedback has been invaluable," PlayStation <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/playstation-reverses-course-on-helldivers-2-psn-account-requirement">wrote at the time</a>.</p><p>We should get a clearer picture of what the future holds when Ghost of Tsushima launches on PC on May 16. In the meantime, check out our column from earlier today asking a simple question: <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/where-are-all-the-ps5-games">Where are all the PS5 games?</a></p><p><em>Kat Bailey is IGN's News Director as well as co-host of Nintendo Voice Chat. Have a tip? Send her a DM at @the_katbot.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Baldur’s Gate 3: How to take out Dror Ragzlin]]></title>
            <link>https://www.destructoid.com/baldurs-gate-3-how-to-take-out-dror-ragzlin/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=baldurs-gate-3-how-to-take-out-dror-ragzlin</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/baldur%E2%80%99s-gate-3-how-to-take-out-dror-ragzlin.870816/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.destructoid.com/baldurs-gate-3-how-to-take-out-dror-ragzlin/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=baldurs-gate-3-how-to-take-out-dror-ragzlin<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p data-characters="274" data-injectable="true" data-video="true">The three goblin leaders in&nbsp;<em>Baldur’s Gate 3&nbsp;</em>are tough to handle, especially Dror Ragzlin. He deals a ton of damage to anyone he hits. However, with the right preparations, you can make it through. Here’s how to take out Dror Ragzlin in <em>Baldur’s Gate 3.&nbsp;</em></p> <div data-current-count="200" data-injectable="false"> <p><span>Tip:</span></p><p> Whether or not you fight Dror Ragzlin depends on whether you side with him and Minthara or the Tieflings in the Emerald Grove. You can avoid this fight entirely if you ally with him and his army during this section of Act One’s story. </p> </div> <h2 id="h-how-to-make-it-past-the-guards" data-injectable="false">How to make it past the guards</h2> <p data-characters="514" data-current-count="714" data-injectable="true">Once you enter the goblin’s prison, you’re stopped at the front gate by security. Warrior Trinzas asks what your intentions are. There are multiple ways to go about this. As a magical class, I was able to peer through her mind. There’s an Intelligence check, but it’s fairly easy to beat, especially if you <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/its-worth-embracing-a-few-failed-rolls-in-baldurs-gate-3/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">manually save just before</a> the encounter. If you lose the roll, they will all attack you. When you succeed, she’ll tell you about the True Souls that have gathered in their base.</p>
 <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"><figcaption>Screenshot by Destructoid</figcaption></figure> <p data-characters="310" data-current-count="610" data-injectable="true">Tell Trinzas that you’re here for the True Souls, and they’ll let you through. You can also use some Deception to pass through the guards. This is difficult, however, as you’ll need roll over 15 on your D20 dice. The first option is likely better if you’re not specialized in Deception.</p>
 <h2 id="h-how-to-take-out-the-baldur-s-gate-3-dror-ragzlin-boss" data-injectable="false">How to take out the Baldur’s Gate 3 Dror Ragzlin boss</h2> <p data-characters="488" data-current-count="488" data-injectable="true">If you’ve already fought another one of the goblin leaders in <em>Baldur’s Gate 3</em>, make sure to rest up before the Dror Ragzlin fight begins. Either a Short or a Long Rest at the camp will do. Taking the latter, however, will let you recover your more powerful spells and abilities. This red-skinned goblin Dror Ragzlin is much more powerful than the other two goblin bosses. He has 52 HP and is Level 5. He can dish out upwards of 21 damage in one strike, as well, so be careful.</p>
 <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"><figcaption>Screenshot by Destructoid</figcaption></figure> <p data-characters="443" data-current-count="743" data-injectable="true">Before taking on the Dror Ragzlin fight, find the war drum on the right-hand side. It’s next to the stairway in that area. If you fail to destroy it straight away with an arrow or a spell, you’ll be facing nine enemies in total after taking out Dror Ragzlin. It could be too much to handle, but honestly, it can also be tough to take out on your first turn. You might want to have someone like Astarion nearby to eliminate it ASAP.</p>
 <p data-characters="749" data-current-count="749" data-injectable="true">Try to take out Dror Ragzlin as quickly as possible during the fight. In order to do this, try to <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/a-handy-guide-to-baldurs-gate-3s-classes-subclasses/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">use a spell</a> that stuns him for a move or two. I used Tasha’s Hideous Laughter on him. It’s not a guaranteed move, but if it lands, it will leave Dror Ragzlin prone with crazed laughter. He’ll be phased, leaving you a chance to get a lot of damage in before he could even say hello. You can get in an extra attack with <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/how-to-complete-gauntlet-of-shar-in-baldurs-gate-3/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Lae’zel</a>‘s Action Surge and then try to take his hammer off his hands with a powerful Disarming Strike. Using several strikes in a row can really rack up the damage on him. <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/best-origin-characters-in-baldurs-gate-3-ranked/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Shadowheart</a>‘s Inflict Wounds can also effectively lower a foe’s health. His 52 HP will dwindle down to zero in no time.</p>
 <p data-characters="653" data-current-count="653" data-injectable="true">Dror Ragzlin may also take a lot of health from your party, so try to get a healer into the squad to remedy a potentially bad situation. Just be careful while doing this during <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/how-to-beat-dror-ragzlin-in-bg3-honour-mode-including-new-legendary-actions/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Dror Ragzlin’s Honour Mode fight</a>, as buffing your allies can make things complicated with his passive. Outside of that, you’ll want to remove his minions from the picture. They’ll be fairly easy to dispatch, but just in case, you can quicksave after eliminating Ragzlin if you’re in one of the regular difficulty modes. On the left-hand side, near the stairway, there’s a ladder that can help archers get a better aim at their victims down below.</p>
 <p data-characters="80" data-current-count="80" data-injectable="false">You’ve now defeated the <em><a href="https://baldursgate3.game/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Baldur’s Gate 3</a> </em>Dror Ragzlin boss. Congrats!</p>

<hr>
<p><i data-stringify-type="italic"> Destructoid is supported by our audience. When you purchase through links on our site, we may earn a small affiliate commission.&nbsp;</i><i data-stringify-type="italic"><a href="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-stringify-link="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" data-sk="tooltip_parent">Learn more</a></i> </p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Please Please Please Watch Interview With The Vampire Or Else I Will Die]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/interview-with-the-vampire-amc-anne-rice-lestat</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/please-please-please-watch-interview-with-the-vampire-or-else-i-will-die.870813/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://aftermath.site/interview-with-the-vampire-amc-anne-rice-lestat<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>My favorite gay vampires have returned, and they’re just as toxic as I remember. If you’re not yet caught up on AMC’s <em>Interview With The Vampire</em>, now is the time. Season 2 started on Sunday, and they’re about to get to the Good Shit.</p><p>The first season of <em>Interview with the Vampire</em> almost passed me by. I have been a longtime fan of the original 1994 movie, starring Brad Pitt as Louis Pointe du Lac and Tom Cruise as Lestat de Lioncourt. I believed that even though that movie wasn’t perfect, it was a lovely adaptation of Anne Rice’s work. AMC’s series showed me that I was absolutely wrong on that count—while the new adaptation makes radical changes to the text, they all serve to bring the viewer closer to the sumptuous, melodramatic tone of the original novel. In particular, Sam Reid as Lestat is a delight, constantly prancing around every scene like a pony on cocaine.&nbsp;</p><p>This adaptation also makes good use of the actual narrative conceit of the interview occurring, which the movie kept in the background. Half the show takes place in the present day, where Louis has shacked up with his new lover, Armand (played by theater actor Assad Zaman with evil glee), in Dubai. There, Daniel Molloy, played by the wonderful Eric Bogosian doing Anthony-Bourdain-if-he-were-a-journalist, interviews Louis and pokes holes in the smoothed-over version of history that he presents.</p><div><figure><p><iframe title="An Extended Look at Season 2 | Interview with the Vampire | Premieres May 12 | AMC+" width="710" height="399" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/w1DNtxOO0DI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></figure></div><p>Lestat will sadly be absent for much of this season, as it is adapting the second half of <em>Interview</em>, which takes place after Louis believes he has killed his lover. I am so pumped for what they’re going to cover this season that it becomes hard not to spoil it for newcomers. Suffice it to say, the tragedy that these characters are hurtling towards will be heartbreaking and I am gnawing my fingernails down to the quick in anticipation. This season will be Paris and the Theatre des Vampires—these are some of the iconic aspects of the original novel, and the place where Rice’s vampire cosmology expands into a whole world of love and loss rather than focusing exclusively on Louis’ perspective. Because I know where this season is headed, I know that it will hurt my feelings a lot, and therefore I need to get everyone else on board so we can all share in the delicious pain.</p><p>Last Sunday’s premiere episode was just a taste of the angst that these characters will endure. Louis Pointe du Lac, played by <em>Game of Thrones</em>’ Jacod Anderson, is essentially drowning in guilt as he and his teenage sire Claudia, <a href="https://ew.com/interview-with-the-vampire-season-2-delainey-hayles-claudia-8646133" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">this season</a> played by Delainey Hayles, traverse war-torn Europe for evidence of other vampires. Louis hallucinates a dead Lestat to torment himself, while Claudia mostly ignores his mounting mental health issues. It’s a meditative episode—a lot of the forward motion in the plot happens in the present day interview sequences—but it leaves the audience at a perfect place to prepare themselves for the events to come. By the end of the episode they prepare to travel to Paris. Louis declares to Claudia that he is devoted to her like a father is to a child, but he delivers his impassioned monologue while a hallucination of his dead lover smirks at him. The dramatic turns of the season will balance on that fulcrum. Can Louis protect Claudia, or does he still long for a love that he betrayed and left for dead?</p><p>Lestat haunts the interview sequences as well, but mostly in the way that Louis and Armand insist that they’re perfectly happy while it is obvious that despite loving each other, they don’t quite connect. In one scene they enter the room aggressively holding hands as a power play, while Molloy struggles not to roll his eyes at this manufactured depiction of a healthy relationship. Fascinatingly, Molloy appears to have more chemistry with Armand than Louis does. Again, I don’t want to spoil where this might be headed but please, I pray on all that is holy: I need that vampire to fuck that old man.</p><figure><figcaption>Image Source: Interview with the Vampire, AMC</figcaption></figure><p>If you haven’t watched this show but any of that sounds appealing, please, for the love of god, get caught up on the first season and join me. <em>Interview with the Vampire</em> is a rare jewel of a television show. The acting is often revelatory—as much as I love Sam Reid’s Lestat, Jacob Anderson has completely changed how I feel about Louis, unearthing richness and subtlety in a character I used to find boring. Sometimes watching this show feels like going to the theater every Sunday; when I turn off the lights and settle into the couch, I feel like I’m letting the curtains rise before I get whisked away just on the energy of the performances and writing. As Louis says early on in the first season, let the tale seduce you—though the price of that seduction may be more than you’ve bargained for.</p></div><div><h2>Stay in touch</h2><p>Sign up for our free newsletter</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Diablo 4's Massive Loot Reborn Update Is Live, Season 4 Patch Notes Released]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/diablo-4-massive-loot-reborn-update-is-live-now-read-the-full-season-4-patch-notes/1100-6523441/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/diablo-4s-massive-loot-reborn-update-is-live-season-4-patch-notes-released.870801/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/diablo-4-massive-loot-reborn-update-is-live-now-read-the-full-season-4-patch-notes/1100-6523441/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6523441">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/diablo-iv/" data-ref-id="5000-504255">Diablo 4</a> Season 4, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/how-diablo-4-loot-reborn-update-will-make-its-items-and-players-more-powerful-than-ever/1100-6523061/" data-ref-id="1100-6523061">Loot Reborn</a>, is now live on all platforms, and it brings the biggest changes yet for Blizzard's ARPG across both the Eternal and seasonal realms. We've also gotten a very extensive set of patch notes for the update.</p><p dir="ltr">Unlike previous Diablo 4 seasons, which introduced new questlines and unique seasonal mechanics, Season 4 instead focuses on and retools core aspects of the game going forward. Gear in the demon-slaying ARPG has undergone a significant overhaul as a result.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QdSehRhUOXM" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/QdSehRhUOXM" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p dir="ltr">Items will now roll with fewer, but more-potent and less-niche affixes, and can be upgraded in two new ways. One is by Tempering, which adds an additional affix from a new Tempering Recipes, while Masterworking makes the affixes on an item even more powerful. Legendary Aspects are now automatically added to the Codex of Power, no extracting required, allowing players to more freely swap their Legendary Powers in and out as they acquire new gear. In another nice change, playing on World Tier 3 will always reward Sacred items, while playing on World Tier 4 will always reward Ancestral items.</p><p dir="ltr">That should result in players being more powerful than ever before, and they'll need that power to conquer a challenging new 200-floor endgame dungeon, where higher-level Masterworking materials are found. There are significant changes to Helltides, too, with the addition of the endgame activity to lower-level World Tiers, new Accursed Rituals within the Helltides that can be used to summon the new Blood Maiden mini-boss, and a new threat mechanic within Helltides that will see players face off against evil versions of each Diablo 4 class called the Hellborne.</p><p dir="ltr">Of course, it wouldn't be a new season without balance changes, and there are plenty of class adjustments and tweaks to Legendary Powers and Unique items. Diablo 4 Season 4 was the first of the game's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/diablo-4s-first-ever-public-test-realm-is-live-now/1100-6522348/" data-ref-id="1100-6522348">seasons to undergo extensive playtesting on a public test realm</a>, and it looks like Blizzard gained some invaluable feedback as part of that process. Some of the changes thanks to player feedback from the PTR include the fact that Masterworking no longer has a chance to fail, improvements to the new Tempering and Masterworking UIs, better rewards from defeating the Blood Maiden, an icon to designate when an item has rolled with a rare Greater Affix, and more.</p><p dir="ltr">With such a massive update, some fans were upset to learn there was no way to pre-download the patch days in advance. According to <a href="https://x.com/PezRadar/status/1790432064019341447" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Diablo community development director Adam Fletcher</a>, Blizzard will look to address that complaint in future seasons to allow for "more of a window for players to grab the patch earlier."</p><p dir="ltr">You can see a selection from the patch notes below, but you'll need to head over to <a href="https://news.blizzard.com/en-us/diablo4/23964909/diablo-iv-patch-notes" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Blizzard's site</a> to see the full list--they are <em>long.</em><em><br></em></p><h2>UPDATES FROM THE PUBLIC TEST REALM</h2><p><em>Developer’s Note: We appreciate all the feedback our players provided us during our Public Test Realm for Season 4: Loot Reborn. The following section highlights key bug fixes and feedback adjustments.</em></p><h3>Feature Updates</h3><ul><li>There is no longer a chance for Masterworking to fail.</li><li>The Masterwork animation has been removed for non-milestone Ranks (1-3, 5-7, etc).</li><li>The Tempering Result screen now shows the result affix, its roll, and the affix range.</li><li>Various UI improvements for the Tempering and Masterworking experiences.</li><li>Added multiple tiers of Masterworking Material caches that transmute far more materials than were previously available.</li><li>A visual indication has been added to the imprint UI which indicates which Legendary affixes are currently equipped.</li><li>You can now search the term ‘equip’ or ‘equipped’ within the Codex of Power to list currently equipped affixes.</li><li>We’ve added an inventory icon to indicate items that have at least one Greater Affix.  <ul><li>When items with Greater Affixes drop in-game, they will also have the same icon to indicate they possess a Greater Affix.</li></ul></li></ul><h3>Helltide and The Pit</h3><ul><li>The Party member that spends the Runeshards to open the Pit gets 100% of the Masterworking materials, the rest of the party receives half the amount.</li><li>Artillery and Blast Wave shrines no longer spawn in the Pit.</li><li>Hellborne spawn chance in Helltide zones has been increased.</li><li>Baneful Heart drop rate has been adjusted to be more consistent.</li><li>Overall loot quality from the Blood Maiden has been improved.  <ul><li>Loot quality has also been improved for players that contribute materials to summon the Blood Maiden, as a contribution bonus reward.</li></ul></li><li>Doomsayer variants, which used to drop a Chest of Doomsaying on defeat, will now drop the contents of a Doomsaying Chest on death with no additional Cinders cost.</li></ul><h3>Balance Adjustments</h3><ul><li>Many Tempering affixes that were either over-performing or under-performing have been adjusted to meet intended power levels.</li><li>The Tempering Affix for Maximum Size increase for various skills and effects, such as Dust Devils or Bone Spirit, is now capped at 100%.</li></ul><h3>Itemization Updates</h3><p>For full details on Itemization including Legendary Aspects and the Codex of Power, Item Affixes, Greater Affixes, Tempering, Masterworking, please read our Season 4 blog here.</p><p>Here are some of the major items coming with Itemization updates:</p><ul><li>Extracting an aspect now upgrades it in the Codex of Power. All Aspects now exist in the Codex of Power.</li><li>Various item affixes have been updated and the overall pool of affixes has been condensed. Additionally, Greater Affixes have been introduced.  <ul><li>Appearing only on Ancestral Legendary and Unique items, these are more powerful (1.5x) versions of normal affixes.</li><li>Each item affix has a chance to be a Greater Affix in World Tier IV.</li></ul></li><li>New Tempering and Masterworking Systems allow deeper customization of items and access to new affixes.</li><li>Legendary items dropped from enemy level 95+ are always 925 item power.</li><li>Unique Items can now drop earlier in the game:  <ul><li>World Tier III Unique Items now drop as non-Sacred in World Tier I and II.</li><li>World Tier IV Unique Items now drop as Sacred in World Tier III.</li><li>Uber Unique Items can start dropping from monster level 55, drops at 925 item power.</li></ul></li><li>The Minimum levels required to equip Sacred and Ancestral items has been reduced.  <ul><li>Sacred: 35</li><li>Ancestral: 55</li></ul></li></ul>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marvel's Midnight Suns director worries the card-based combat kept players away]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/marvel-s-midnight-suns-director-worries-the-card-mechanic-kept-players-away</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/marvels-midnight-suns-director-worries-the-card-based-combat-kept-players-away.870798/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/marvel-s-midnight-suns-director-worries-the-card-mechanic-kept-players-away<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="captioned-content"><p><span>Image via Firaxis Games/Take-Two.</span></p></div><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Firaxis Games' 2022 game </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Marvel's Midnight Suns</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> won praise from critics and dedicated players for its crunchy in-depth strategy (and surprisingly robust narrative design), but the quality of its gameplay wasn't enough to drive sales. Take-Two CEO Strauss Zelnick </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://x.com/jasonschreier/status/1622707723480563721">told Bloomberg in 2023</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> that the game wasn't living up to expectations, saying at the time that the game's December release window may not have been "perfect."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">But if there's anyone who has reason to do a postmortem on </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Midnight Suns</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, it's Midsummer Studios cofounder Jake Solomon. Solomon, who </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/firaxis-veterans-jake-solomon-and-steve-martin-depart-studio">departed Firaxis in 2023</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> after the game released, was the brain behind the game's card-based combat system.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">In an interview with Game Developer discussing </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/firaxis-vet-jake-solomon-unveils-new-studio-working-on-a-life-sim-game">the founding of Midsummer Studios</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, Solomon looked back on his final project at Firaxis and admitted his passion for the system may have missed the mark with players. "I think about </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Midnight Suns</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> a lot, and I think about the card mechanic—which I designed, so I take responsibility for it—I think that [discouraged] players from even trying trying the game because they saw it and went 'what the heck is that?'"</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Hindsight is 20/20, but Solomon's observation holds weight if you think back to what Firaxis and Take-Two were pitching players. The game was a turn-based tactical game (targeting a niche audience), themed on Marvel characters (targeting a mainstream audience), with combat built on a card-drawing, deckbuilding mechanic that visualized the characters' superhero abilities (not a feature something either audience would be familiar with).</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">To top it off, Firaxis faced headwinds from audience disinterest in Marvel-branded narrative games. Crystal Dynamics' </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Marvel's Avengers</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> struggled to keep players attracted to its live service gameplay and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/report-development-on-i-marvel-s-avengers-i-is-ending-at-crystal-dynamics">eventually shut down</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, and Eidos-Montreal's </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Marvel's Guardians of the Galaxy</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> "</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/square-enix-says-guardians-of-the-galaxy-undershot-launch-expectations">undershot"</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> its launch expectations.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Both games were also praised for their </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/design-lessons-from-the-making-of-marvel-s-midnight-suns">combat</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/opinion-marvel-s-guardians-of-the-galaxy-does-dadification-so-dang-right">storytelling</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, despite disinterest from the market.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Great games don't guarantee game sales">Great games don't guarantee game sales</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Solomon had been musing on the struggle studios face in the modern era of massive Steam backlogs and a near-constant flood of great game releases. "I'm very naïve when it comes to the business side of things," he admitted. "You want to believe 'if I just make a good game, everything will take care of itself.' That's not true anymore. That used to be true 20 years ago. There are so many games out there, and so many things vying for people's attention."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">For context, 20 years ago, Solomon was fresh out of college and working on Sid Meier's Civilization III. He remembered Firaxis's anxiety over the recently released Age of Empires: Age of Kings and how its beautiful 3D visuals risked outshining </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Civilization III</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">'s 2D visuals.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Then </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Civilization III </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">sold like gangbusters—fueling his belief that all you needed to run a game studio was just to make good games.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Solomon said he wants to be more conscious of the audience needs while making Midsummer, and why an Early Access launch for its "life sim" game will be key to the company's strategy.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author(s)</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Senior Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Bryant Francis is a writer, journalist, and narrative designer based in Boston, MA. He currently writes for Game Developer, a leading B2B publication for the video game industry. His credits include Proxy Studios' upcoming 4X strategy game Zephon and Amplitude Studio's 2017 game Endless Space 2.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Where to buy the Dead by Daylight Pools of Blood Dice Set]]></title>
            <link>https://www.destructoid.com/where-to-buy-the-dead-by-daylight-pools-of-blood-dice-set/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=where-to-buy-the-dead-by-daylight-pools-of-blood-dice-set</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/where-to-buy-the-dead-by-daylight-pools-of-blood-dice-set.870795/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.destructoid.com/where-to-buy-the-dead-by-daylight-pools-of-blood-dice-set/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=where-to-buy-the-dead-by-daylight-pools-of-blood-dice-set<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p data-characters="227" data-injectable="true" data-video="true">Following the gameplay reveal of the <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/behaviour-interactive-teases-dungeons-dragons-coming-to-dead-by-daylight/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Dead by Daylight Dungeons &amp; Dragons</em> Chapter</a>, Behaviour Interactive announced a new product for its growing line of merch: a set of dice inspired by <em>Dead by Daylight</em> for use in any TTRPG.</p> <p data-characters="476" data-current-count="476" data-injectable="true">The Entity’s tentacles have successfully breached almost every realm in existence. By far the most impressive is that of <em>Dungeons &amp; Dragons</em>, dragging the almighty Vecna into Trials to feed the unknowable creature with the screams and suffering of even more Survivors. To celebrate this mashup of monsters, you can purchase the <em>Dead by Daylight Pools of Blood Dice Set</em> and bring a little piece of The Entity to help you or hinder you while your party ventures forth. </p>
 <h2 id="h-where-to-buy-the-dead-by-daylight-pools-of-blood-dice-set" data-injectable="false">Where to buy the <em>Dead by Daylight Pools of Blood Dice Set</em></h2> <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"><figcaption>Image via Behaviour Interactive</figcaption></figure> <p data-characters="241" data-current-count="541" data-injectable="true">You can buy the <em>Dead by Daylight Pools of Blood Dice Set</em> from the <a href="https://shop.deadbydaylight.com/en-gb/products/dead-by-daylight-deluxe-blood-core-dice-set?_pos=2&amp;_sid=d8ff66fe2&amp;_ss=r">official <em>Dead by Daylight</em> merch store</a>. For the first 48 hours, the set is on sale, those who buy it can get it at a 10% discount. After that, the set will cost $39.95/£40.28.</p>
 <p data-characters="451" data-current-count="451" data-injectable="true">This set was announced during the <em>Dead by Daylight</em> 8th Anniversary livestream event but only as a footnote at the end of the stream. Coupled with the crush on Behaviour Interactive’s servers from launching <em><a href="https://www.destructoid.com/what-the-fog-is-a-free-dbd-co-op-shooter-and-surprise-its-out-now/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">What the Fog</a></em> for free, finding where you could buy these dice was impossible. I had to wait a few hours, open the merch store, and search for “dice” to find them because they weren’t advertised anywhere on the home page. </p>
 <h2 data-injectable="false">What is the <em>Dead by Daylight Pools of Blood Dice Set</em>?</h2> <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"><figcaption>Image via Behaviour Interactive</figcaption></figure> <p data-characters="386" data-current-count="686" data-injectable="true">The <em>Dead by Daylight Pools of Blood Dice Set</em> is a set of 7 dice that come with a core of bloody red liquid and the Dead by Daylight logo on the 20 of the D20 to make a natural 20 even more special. The dice are packed in a case inspired by the Med-Kit item from the game, so it looks like you’re rocking up to your next <em>D&amp;D</em> session, ready to take a lot of hits for the party. </p>
 <p data-characters="282" data-current-count="282" data-injectable="false">The set might include a D20, but there are smaller dice as well, so it can be used in dozens of games. If you want to bring a bit of flair to Monopoly or any board game that uses dice you’re playing with friends, this is a great set to use to add some personality to the mix. </p> <p data-characters="178" data-current-count="460" data-injectable="false">In addition to the dice set, the product also entitles all those who purchase it to 2 million Bloodpoints in <em>Dead by Daylight</em>. That’s enough to Prestige a character twice. </p>

<hr>
<p><i data-stringify-type="italic"> Destructoid is supported by our audience. When you purchase through links on our site, we may earn a small affiliate commission.&nbsp;</i><i data-stringify-type="italic"><a href="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-stringify-link="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" data-sk="tooltip_parent">Learn more</a></i> </p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Flee, Mortals! Now Available On D&D Beyond]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/flee-mortals-now-available-on-dd-beyond</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/flee-mortals-now-available-on-d-d-beyond.870762/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/flee-mortals-now-available-on-dd-beyond<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>The go-to platform for <em>Dungeons &amp; Dragons</em> content has received another third-party supplement. The new content is <em>Flee, Mortals!</em>, a monster-focused supplement developed by TTRPG personality and game designer Matt Colville.</p>

<p>According to its <a href="https://marketplace.dndbeyond.com/rulebooks/SRC-00142" rel="noopener" target="_blank">store page</a> listing, <em>Flee, Mortals! </em>is a supplement all about adding new and interesting monsters to your <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/games/dungeons-dragons"><em>Dungeons &amp; Dragons</em></a> campaign. Facing challenging monsters is the biggest draw to the world's most popular fantasy TTRPG.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/flee-mortals-goblin-artwork.jpg?itok=yc_GIvIa 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/flee-mortals-goblin-artwork.jpg?itok=z-diEKt3 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Even goblins are a little extra in this book.</figcaption></figure><p>The supplement contains 293 unique monster statblocks. These include variations on classic <em>D&amp;D</em> monsters, special abilities meant to surprise veteran players, and rules and mechanics for minions. Minions are designed as challenging cannon fodder to make players feel powerful.</p>
<p>Furthermore, <em>Flee, Mortals!</em> contains rules for allies and retainers. These support NPCs can even level up alongside an adventuring party. Lastly, the supplement contains 9 battlemaps and 19 magic items for DMs to use as they see fit.</p>
<p>The D&amp;D Beyond store page shows that this will not be the last supplement developed by Matt Colville and MCDM featured on the platform. In addition to buying standalone, there is an option for a bundle, which includes another MCDM supplement: the boss battle-focused book <em>Where Evil Lives</em>.</p>
<p>Matt Colville's influence in the TTRPG space cannot be understated. He has contributed to multiple books including <em>Explorer's Guide to Wildemount</em>, the CODA System <em>Star Trek RPG</em>, the (now-discontinued) <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/mcdm-announces-end-of-arcadia-magazine"><em>Arcadia</em></a> magazine, and multiple supplements for <em>D&amp;D 3e</em>.</p>
<p>Notably, Colville's MCDM studio has also developed their own fantasy TTRPG competitor to <em>D&amp;D</em>. The aptly titled <a href="https://mcdm-rpg.backerkit.com/hosted_preorders" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><em>MCDM RPG</em></a> was successfully crowdfunded on Gamefound, raising a staggering $4.5 million during its initial campaign.</p>
<p><em>Flee, Mortals!</em> joins a handful of beloved third-party supplements on D&amp;D Beyond. Those supplements include Darrington Press' <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/taldorei-reborn-now-available-on-dd-beyond"><em>Tal'Dorei Reborn</em></a>, Hitpoint Press' <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/humblewood-debuts-on-dd-beyond"><em>Humblewood</em></a>, and the Dungeon Dudes' <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/dungeons-of-drakkenheim-now-available-on-dd-beyond"><em>Dungeons of Drakkenheim</em></a>.</p>
<p><em>Flee, Mortals!</em> is available right now at an MSRP of $39.99, or bundled with <em>Where Evil Lives</em> for $59.99. <em>Where Evil Lives</em> is set to go live on the platform May 28.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Ever since he was small, Tyler Chancey has had a deep, abiding love for video games and a tendency to think and overanalyze everything he enjoyed. This… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/tyler-chancey">More about Tyler</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Inworld Reckons Costs Are Going to Go Down a Lot, and Its Gen AI NPC Tech Will Run Locally, even on Consoles]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/inworld-reckons-costs-are-going-to-go-down-a-lot-and-its-gen-ai-npc-tech-will-run-locally-even-on-consoles/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/inworld-reckons-costs-are-going-to-go-down-a-lot-and-its-gen-ai-npc-tech-will-run-locally-even-on-consoles.870759/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/inworld-reckons-costs-are-going-to-go-down-a-lot-and-its-gen-ai-npc-tech-will-run-locally-even-on-consoles/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>While the generative AI technology for NPCs (non-player characters) <a href="https://wccftech.com/inworld-ai-npc-gdc-2024-hands-on-nvidia-and-ubisoft-show-a-glimpse-of-the-future/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">demonstrated at GDC 2024</a> by Inworld is very exciting for its potential applications in games, one of the main drawbacks is the cost associated with it. The simulation currently has to run on Inworld's servers, which comes at a price.</p>
<p>In <a href="https://wccftech.com/the-big-inworld-ai-qa-everyone-in-gaming-sees-the-potential-of-generative-ai/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">our big interview</a> with Inworld GM of Labs Nathan Yu, we asked how they're planning to overcome such a big hurdle. Yu was confident that costs would go down significantly, especially when applied to a large-scale game.</p>
<p><em>Moving forward, the costs are going to go down significantly; we all understand that. But even then, it's the design, right? Do you really need all secondary NPCs to be hyper-intelligent? Maybe not; maybe we use smaller models there, but for the core companion character, there is a value added.</em></p>
<p><em>But I'm not too concerned. </em><em>I think if we give it another couple of months, the conversation will be different as soon as we see viable, profitable use cases being deployed.</em></p>
<p><em>I do see experiences where players will be contributing to the cost directly because there's like a premium upsell there that makes sense for them. I do see other examples where it doesn't make sense. Players are purchasing a flat game cost for $59.99 or other and it'll be fully maintained just through other monetization structures, or it's already amortized over time.</em></p>
<p><em>As we get to scale for AAA titles, costs will go down so that it's no longer variable. If we've got millions of users, there's lots of techniques that can be leveraged to drive down costs there.</em></p>
<p>One way to reduce costs would be to run the generative AI technology locally on the device used. Would that work for Inworld? The answer was positive.</p>
<p><em>Yes. we'll definitely get there. We saw a lot of exciting announcements even at GTC for dedicated hardware in the future for AI versus rendering.</em></p>
<p><em>Today, t</em><em>here's a lot of questions, like, if we do move to on devices, will that impact graphics rendering? That becomes a nonstarter conversation for a lot of studios. But at Inworld we do support hybrid as well. Some services could run locally, some services run on cloud inferencing and that can short-term optimize costs and latency. But in the future, I think we can all agree that it's going to get there. It's gonna run locally, offline, on devices like consoles. It's just a matter of time. I'm excited to see that as well.</em></p>
<p>We'll continue to follow the implementation of Inworld technology in games and game making tools very closely. Stay tuned on Wccftech for more on the subject.</p>

				

			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Valheim heats up with new, ultra-deadly biome in Ashlands update]]></title>
            <link>https://www.polygon.com/24156665/valheim-firelands-update-live-new-biome-siege-weapons-charred</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/valheim-heats-up-with-new-ultra-deadly-biome-in-ashlands-update.870756/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.polygon.com/24156665/valheim-firelands-update-live-new-biome-siege-weapons-charred<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  <p id="W2oYsr"><em>Valheim</em> is a fantastic sandbox survival game, set in a fantastical 10th realm of the Norse afterlife. Adventurers explore from the peaceful meadows <a href="https://www.polygon.com/valheim-guide/22295460/biome-progression-order-meadow-black-forest-swamp-plains-mountain-ocean-mistaland-deep-north-ashland">out into more dangerous biomes</a>, and today, the most dangerous one yet is available to explore. The last biome update was the Mistlands; today, players can venture out into the Ashlands.</p>
<p id="Gu9PJf">Of course, that’s much easier said than done, since the Ashlands is a very hostile environment. Vikings will need to build ships strong enough to survive its boiling waters, and things don’t get better upon landfall. Undead known as Charred wander the lands, a fearsome Fallen Valkyrie attacks from the skies, and a beastly creature known as the Morgen hunts prey, along with other enemies. </p>
<p id="3VTZvG">Luckily, new enemies means new loot, which can be turned into new weapons. Flametal can be crafted into a new greatsword, spear, and crossbow, and further enhanced with jade, bloodstone, and isoite gems. Building outposts in the Ashlands is meant to feel like a constant struggle, and the Charred control the territory from fortresses. Luckily, players can now craft siege weaponry. Catapults and battering rams allow players to attack fortresses directly, expanding their reach over the new biome.</p>
<p id="72bBHw">“Ashlands is supposed to feel like a struggle, and players should expect a challenge. Every inch of territory you claim has to be earned, and every outpost has to be reinforced before you venture deeper. We’re entering endgame territory here, and players need to be ready for what comes in the Deep North,” said Andreas Tomasson,<em> Valheim </em>producer, in a press release.</p>
<p id="rTxvH0"><em>Valheim</em> is available on PC, and is still in early access. The Viking survival game <a href="https://www.polygon.com/reviews/22303522/valheim-review-coffee-stain-early-access-pc">had a huge launch in 2021</a>, thanks to developer Iron Gate’s ability to craft a <a href="https://www.polygon.com/22340357/valheim-game-design-coziness-hygge-danger-trees-hunger-cottagecore">compelling range of experiences across the biomes</a>, from cozy and comfortable to striving for survival. The game has remained relevant through to 2024,<a href="https://www.polygon.com/24099909/open-world-survival-crafting-games-2024"> attracting an audience of survival game fans</a>. The Mistlands update expanded the game with a mysterious, mountainous region with low visibility and insectoid enemies, but the Ashlands sounds like a whole new level of danger.</p>
  
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[You can get the Eye of Sauron in Lego form with the new Barad-dûr set]]></title>
            <link>https://www.polygon.com/24156614/barad-dur-lego-set-eye-sauron-lord-rings-release-date-price</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/you-can-get-the-eye-of-sauron-in-lego-form-with-the-new-barad-d%C3%BBr-set.870753/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.polygon.com/24156614/barad-dur-lego-set-eye-sauron-lord-rings-release-date-price<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  <p id="r-49">Mordor’s most terrifying monument will soon be available in Lego form. A <a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;mid=13923&amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.lego.com%2Fen-us%2Faboutus%2Fnews%2F2024%2Fmay%2Fthe-new-lego-lego-icons-lord-of-the-rings-barad-d-r-set&amp;u1=Polygon051424" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank" has-subtag="true" data-cdata="{&quot;rewritten_url&quot;:&quot;https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?u1=[]pl[p]23920655[m]m-placeholder[s]s-placeholder[t]w[c]c-placeholder[r]r-placeholder[d]d-placeholder\u0026id=nOD/rLJHOac\u0026mid=13923\u0026murl=https://www.lego.com/en-us/aboutus/news/2024/may/the-new-lego-lego-icons-lord-of-the-rings-barad-d-r-set&quot;,&quot;subtag_max_length&quot;:72,&quot;subtag_delim_length&quot;:2,&quot;subtag_key&quot;:&quot;u1&quot;,&quot;subtag_data&quot;:{&quot;u1&quot;:&quot;[]pl[p]23920655[m]m-placeholder[s]s-placeholder[t]w[c]c-placeholder[r]r-placeholder[d]d-placeholder&quot;,&quot;id&quot;:&quot;nOD/rLJHOac&quot;,&quot;mid&quot;:&quot;13923&quot;,&quot;murl&quot;:&quot;https://www.lego.com/en-us/aboutus/news/2024/may/the-new-lego-lego-icons-lord-of-the-rings-barad-d-r-set&quot;},&quot;encode_subtag&quot;:false}">new Barad-dûr Lego set</a> is coming from <a href="https://www.polygon.com/24105226/lego-dungeons-and-dragons-set-announcement-pre-order">Lego</a> and Warner Bros. Discovery this summer, the <a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;mid=13923&amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.lego.com%2Fen-us%2Faboutus%2Fnews%2F2024%2Fmay%2Fthe-new-lego-lego-icons-lord-of-the-rings-barad-d-r-set&amp;u1=Polygon051424" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank" has-subtag="true" data-cdata="{&quot;rewritten_url&quot;:&quot;https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?u1=[]pl[p]23920655[m]m-placeholder[s]s-placeholder[t]w[c]c-placeholder[r]r-placeholder[d]d-placeholder\u0026id=nOD/rLJHOac\u0026mid=13923\u0026murl=https://www.lego.com/en-us/aboutus/news/2024/may/the-new-lego-lego-icons-lord-of-the-rings-barad-d-r-set&quot;,&quot;subtag_max_length&quot;:72,&quot;subtag_delim_length&quot;:2,&quot;subtag_key&quot;:&quot;u1&quot;,&quot;subtag_data&quot;:{&quot;u1&quot;:&quot;[]pl[p]23920655[m]m-placeholder[s]s-placeholder[t]w[c]c-placeholder[r]r-placeholder[d]d-placeholder&quot;,&quot;id&quot;:&quot;nOD/rLJHOac&quot;,&quot;mid&quot;:&quot;13923&quot;,&quot;murl&quot;:&quot;https://www.lego.com/en-us/aboutus/news/2024/may/the-new-lego-lego-icons-lord-of-the-rings-barad-d-r-set&quot;},&quot;encode_subtag&quot;:false}">two companies announced on Tuesday</a>. </p>
<p id="nmsNdX">The set depicts Sauron’s massive tower as well as his glowing Eye that sits at its peak. The tower also opens up into a detailed throne room that includes a hidden map and a ladder to the top floor. The middle sections of the tower also have a variety of different modable options, including a feast table, an orc armory, and more, while the bottom of the tower includes a working door at the base..</p>
<p id="sEGJ0s">The Lego set will stand at over 32 inches tall, 11 inches wide, and 17 inches long. It comes with a hidden secret as well: if you buy multiple sets, you can stack several different versions of the middle section to make an even more imposing version of Barad-dûr. But the price for multiple versions of this new 5,471 piece Lord of the Rings set will be pretty steep, with each one running $459.99. </p>
  <figure>
  <span>
    
    <span data-original="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25447902/lego_minifigs_lotr_sauron.jpg">
      
        <picture data-cid="site/picture_element-1715714054_4475_282647" data-cdata="{&quot;asset_id&quot;:25447902,&quot;ratio&quot;:&quot;*&quot;}">
  


  <source srcset="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/trYT-qDOQl25dKFJo1MfgBg7KDY=/0x0:2146x1080/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:2146x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25447902/lego_minifigs_lotr_sauron.jpg 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/muEu3ghVvoPnEHR0aTLl4512lDA=/0x0:2146x1080/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:2146x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25447902/lego_minifigs_lotr_sauron.jpg 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VD2xH38qx_DNHSnB3wm2Gwu6mgk=/0x0:2146x1080/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:2146x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25447902/lego_minifigs_lotr_sauron.jpg 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zNg32c5uDzgkhRNxbJ0jZJQDrj8=/0x0:2146x1080/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:2146x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25447902/lego_minifigs_lotr_sauron.jpg 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/XX5i7jZ7NTixi-07WtPsqwAwcCc=/0x0:2146x1080/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:2146x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25447902/lego_minifigs_lotr_sauron.jpg 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/D4LDe53LrhoN6hxSoLdzbP8R6iw=/0x0:2146x1080/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:2146x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25447902/lego_minifigs_lotr_sauron.jpg 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/mDrWPeybglKqXKERKoY0qeyQhgM=/0x0:2146x1080/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:2146x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25447902/lego_minifigs_lotr_sauron.jpg 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4l-3j4AUAovBuF-j1ViYN9Y_0KU=/0x0:2146x1080/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:2146x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25447902/lego_minifigs_lotr_sauron.jpg 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VLNe9kwt3vBeI-pp1CpbTiIS6v0=/0x0:2146x1080/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:2146x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25447902/lego_minifigs_lotr_sauron.jpg 1920w" sizes="(min-width: 1221px) 846px, (min-width: 880px) calc(100vw - 334px), 100vw" type="image/webp">




</picture>

      
    </span>
    
  </span>
  
    <span>
      
      
        <cite>Photo: Lego</cite>
      
    </span>
  
</figure>



<p id="K2gKin">Along with the tower itself, and a glowing center brick for the Eye of Sauron, the Barad-dûr set will include 10 minifigures, including Sauron, the Mouth of Sauron, an Orc, Frodo, Sam, Gollum, <a href="https://www.polygon.com/lord-of-the-rings/2021/2/10/22272503/orcs-lotr-movies-ranked">Gothmog</a>, and more. On top of all that, if you buy the set between June 1 and June 7, you’ll also get a Lord of the Rings: Fell Beast Lego seat, which features a version of the ominous flying creature with fully posable wings alongside A Nazgul minifigure. </p>
<p id="beV9x6">The Lord of the Rings: Barad-dûr set comes out on June 1. </p>



  
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A Bunch Of Slept-On Games Are About To Hit Game Pass]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/xbox-game-pass-may-2024-full-list-leaving-hellblade-2-1851476811</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/a-bunch-of-slept-on-games-are-about-to-hit-game-pass.870750/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/xbox-game-pass-may-2024-full-list-leaving-hellblade-2-1851476811<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="1900a7f8c4d88ef953547efc192586f6" data-recommend-id="image://1900a7f8c4d88ef953547efc192586f6" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="An image shows a CG man with a blue, glowing tattoo on his face. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="An image shows a CG man with a blue, glowing tattoo on his face. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->EA</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="1900a7f8c4d88ef953547efc192586f6" data-recommend-id="image://1900a7f8c4d88ef953547efc192586f6" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="An image shows a CG man with a blue, glowing tattoo on his face. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>May is shaping up to be a very, very good month for Xbox Game Pass—with some sleeper hits, like magic FPS <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/immortals-of-aveum-budget-aaa-single-player-shooter-1851252502&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/immortals-of-aveum-budget-aaa-single-player-shooter-1851252502"><em>Immortals of Aveum</em></a></span>, and new games, like <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/hellblade-2-senua-s-saga-how-long-to-beat-shorter-games-1851387180&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/hellblade-2-senua-s-saga-how-long-to-beat-shorter-games-1851387180"><em>Senua’s Saga: Hellblade II</em></a></span>, arriving soon. And I bet Xbox is happy to have some good news to share right now, following the last few months.<br></p><div data-video-id="196470" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="The Week In Games: Reignited Rivalries And More New Releases" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="123" data-playlist="196470,195922,196345" data-current="196470"><div><p>The Week In Games: Reignited Rivalries And More New Releases</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196470/196470_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196470/196470_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196470/196470_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196470/196470_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/22020.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2024/05/14/xbox-game-pass-may-2024-wave-2/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2024/05/14/xbox-game-pass-may-2024-wave-2/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">On May 14</a></span>, as Xbox does every month, the company announced all of the games coming to Game Pass over the next few weeks. The headliner of the month is definitely <em>Senua’s Saga: Hellblade II</em>, a big first-party exclusive from Xbox and Ninja Theory and the sequel to 2017’s <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/hellblade-is-great-because-it-s-frustrating-1797654673&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/hellblade-is-great-because-it-s-frustrating-1797654673"><em>Hellblade: Senua’s Sacrifice</em></a></span><em>. </em>That big action game launches on Game Pass on May 21. </p><p>However, beyond <em>Hellblade II,</em> this month’s Xbox Game Pass line-up is filled with some genuine gems, including some games released last year that were overshadowed by the flood of <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/goty-best-games-2023-totk-baldurs-gate-3-alan-wake-2-1851109182&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/goty-best-games-2023-totk-baldurs-gate-3-alan-wake-2-1851109182">great releases we saw in 2023</a></span>. </p><p>Here’s the full list of games coming to <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://howl.me/cmfDGIIoWJH&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://howl.me/cmfDGIIoWJH" target="_blank" rel="sponsored noopener noreferrer nofollow noskim" data-vtas-click="self:InlineUrl:inline-url-postbody">Xbox Game Pass</a></span> in May and early June:</p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li><strong><em>Brothers: A Tale of Two Sons </em></strong>- Available Today</li><li>  <strong><em>Chants of Sennaar</em> – </strong>May 15</li><li>  <strong><em>EA Sports NHL 24 </em></strong>– May 16</li><li>  <strong><em>Immortals of Aveum</em> – </strong>May 16</li><li>  <strong><em>Senua’s Saga: Hellblade II </em></strong>- May 21</li><li>  <strong><em>Galacticare </em></strong><em>- </em>May 23</li><li>  <strong><em>Hauntii </em></strong>- May 23</li><li><strong><em>Moving Out 2 </em></strong>- May 28</li><li><strong><em>Humanity </em></strong>- May 30</li><li><strong><em>Lords of the Fallen </em></strong>- May 30</li><li><strong><em>Firework</em></strong><em> </em>- June 4</li><li><strong><em>Rolling Hills</em></strong> - June 4</li></ul><p>Yet, the universe (and Microsoft) take as they as give, and so six games are leaving Xbox Game Pass at the end of May. As always, you can buy these games at a 20 percent discount if you are a Game Pass subscriber and want to keep playing them after their removal. </p><p>Here’s the full list of titles leaving the subscription service on May 31:</p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li><strong><em>Chicory: A Colorful Tale</em></strong></li><li><strong><em>Farworld Pioneers</em></strong></li><li><strong><em>JoJo’s Bizarre Adventure: All-Star Battle</em></strong></li><li><strong><em>Pac-Man Museum Plus</em></strong><em>&nbsp;</em></li></ul><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li><strong><em>Little Witch in the Woods</em></strong><em>&nbsp;</em></li><li><strong><em>Railway Empire II</em></strong></li></ul></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Assassin’s Creed Shadows Key Art Leaks Online Ahead of Reveal]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/assassins-creed-shadows-keyart-leaked/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-assassin%E2%80%99s-creed-shadows-key-art-leaks-online-ahead-of-reveal.870747/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/assassins-creed-shadows-keyart-leaked/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>Several new images of Assassin’s Creed Shadows keyart have leaked online ahead of the game’s official reveal.</p>



<p>The images were first posted by dataminer user <a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/fraxR6/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">/u/fraxR6</a>, who obtains information and images from the Ubisoft store backend. While the original images have since been deleted, Insider Gaming’s Mike Straw has uploaded the images to his Twitter account.</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>The images confirm <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/assassins-creed-red-yasuke/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming’s past reporting that the game</a> will feature two protagonists, a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/who-is-yasuke-in-assassins-creed-shadows/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">male samurai named Yasuke</a> and a female Shinobi named Naoe. Warning, some slight story spoilers ahead.</p>



<p>Yasuke’s story starts off with tragedy and unlike his real-life story, his story has been rewritten. In Assassin’s Creed Shadows, Yasuke was a slave traveling on a slave ship when it was attacked and everyone was killed, including his lover, but he survived. Yasuke was then rescued and brought to Japan, where he learned the way of the samurai under Nobunaga’s service.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It’s understood that at the beginning of the game, Naoe and Yasuke are fierce enemies, but later become allies on their desire for Japan’s unification.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Insider Gaming understands that the other historical characters to make their appearance in Assassin’s Creed Red include; Fujibayashi Nagato (Naoe’s father), Oda Nobunaga, Akechi Mitsuhide, Hattori Hanzo (returning character), Toyotomi Hideyoshi, Kōdai-in (Hideyoshi’s wife), Oichi, Ashikaga Yoshiaki, Akechi Kagemitsu, and more.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What do you think of the Assassin’s Creed Shadows key art? Let us know in the comments below!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read&nbsp;our&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/interview-exocross-arcade-racing/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">exclusive interview with the creative director of ExoCross</a>, Paul Coleman ,&nbsp;and subscribe to the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/newsletter/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Newsletter</a>&nbsp;to keep up to date with all things gaming.</p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bloodborne Figma Action Figure Gets Big Discount At Amazon]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/bloodborne-figma-action-figure-gets-big-discount-at-amazon/1100-6523430/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/bloodborne-figma-action-figure-gets-big-discount-at-amazon.870744/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/bloodborne-figma-action-figure-gets-big-discount-at-amazon/1100-6523430/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6523430">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Sony might not be ready to bankroll a Bloodborne remaster for PS5, but who really needs it when you can make your own Yharnam adventures? Thanks to this affordable Figma action figure of the game's titular Hunter--which is <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Max-Factory-Bloodborne-Hunter-Action/dp/B075N75GYQ?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">on sale at Amazon for $86.30 (was $116)</a>--you can tackle terrifying new bosses like your uninterested cat or hyperactive dog instead. Or you can figure out a great pose for this collectible, lock it in, and proudly display it. This figure tends to sell out fairly quickly, and Amazon doesn't often refresh its stock, so grab it while you can.</p><p><em>Note: To get this deal, you may need to click "Other sellers on Amazon" below the "Buy Now" button on mobile or desktop. The listing defaults to a third-party reseller instead of the deal that's shipped and sold by Amazon. The Amazon listing should be the top option in that list. Click "Add to Cart" and the correct price will be reflected in your order total.</em></p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4302786-figma-bloodborne.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4302786" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4302786-figma-bloodborne.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4302786"></a><figcaption>Figma Bloodborne Hunter</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4302786-figma-bloodborne.jpg"></figure><figure data-embed-type="gallery" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4302787-figmabloodbornehunter%281%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4302788-figmabloodbornehunter%282%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4302789-figmabloodbornehunter%283%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4302790-figmabloodbornehunter%284%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4302791-figmabloodbornehunter%285%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4302792-figmabloodbornehunter%286%29.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4302787,1300-4302788,1300-4302789,1300-4302790,1300-4302791,1300-4302792" data-resize-urls="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1601/16018044/4302787-figmabloodbornehunter%281%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1601/16018044/4302788-figmabloodbornehunter%282%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1601/16018044/4302789-figmabloodbornehunter%283%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1601/16018044/4302790-figmabloodbornehunter%284%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1601/16018044/4302791-figmabloodbornehunter%285%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1601/16018044/4302792-figmabloodbornehunter%286%29.jpg"><p>Gallery</p>     <img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4302787-figmabloodbornehunter%281%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4302788-figmabloodbornehunter%282%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4302789-figmabloodbornehunter%283%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4302790-figmabloodbornehunter%284%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4302791-figmabloodbornehunter%285%29.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4302792-figmabloodbornehunter%286%29.jpg"></figure><p>Whatever your choice, this is a nice deal on an even nicer action figure. Like other Figma figures, the Bloodborne Hunter is highly detailed and features an impressive amount of articulation. It has a great shelf presence, and with its included cleaver and blunderbuss weapons, you can pose it in several exciting ways. The saw cleaver can be transformed into the extended cleaver mode just like in the game, and you'll get a display stand for those more dynamic poses you think up.</p><p>While there's no (sadly) word yet on a Bloodborne remaster or sequel, you can explore more of its captivating universe with other media that has released over the last couple of years. Several Bloodborne graphic novels are available, and if you're interested, you can get a pretty good box set deal on the first three trade paperbacks. Normally $50, it can be yours for just $30. You have plenty of time to catch up on this series ahead of <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Bloodborne-Bleak-Dominion-Cullen-Bunn/dp/1787740633?tag=gamespot-preorders-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Volume 6's July 9 release</a>.</p><h3>Bloodborne graphic novels</h3><ul><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Bloodborne-1-3-Boxed-Set-Ales/dp/1787735338?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Bloodborne Volumes 1-3 box set</a> -- $30 ($<strike>50</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Bloodborne-4-Veil-Torn-Asunder/dp/1787730158?tag=gamespot-promos-20&amp;tag=gamespot-buybutton-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Bloodborne Volume 4: The Veil, Torn Asunder</a> -- $16 ($<strike>18</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Bloodborne-Lady-Lanterns-Graphic-Novel/dp/1787735990?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Bloodborne Volume 5: Lady of the Lanterns</a> -- $12.80 ($<strike>18</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Bloodborne-Bleak-Dominion-Cullen-Bunn/dp/1787740633?tag=gamespot-preorders-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Bloodborne Volume 6: The Bleak Dominion</a> -- $16.20 ($<strike>18</strike>) | Releases July 9</li></ul><p>Outside of the reading material, there are also Bloodborne board and card games to collect. These aren't currently on sale, but they have received positive reviews from fans who have tried them out.</p><h3>Bloodborne board and card games</h3><ul><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/CMON-BBN001-Bloodborne/dp/B01HYVKY80?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Bloodborne: The Card Game</a> -- $50</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/CMON-Bloodborne-The-Hunters-Nightmare/dp/B07BBG7ZPD?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Bloodborne: The Card Game - Hunters Nightmare expansion</a> -- $25</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Bloodborne-Board-Strategy-Adults-Adventure/dp/B08TBF84S1?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Bloodborne: The Board Game</a> -- $120</li></ul><div data-embed-type="pinbox" data-ref-id="4304">  <ul>                              <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/apple-ipad-pro-ipad-air-2024-preorder-guide/1100-6523258/">Preorder Apple's 2024 iPad Pro And iPad Air - How To Get The Best Deal</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-world-championships-nes-edition-preorder-guide-nintendo-switch/1100-6523267/">Nintendo World Championships: NES Edition Preorders Are Selling Out Fast</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/playstation-portal-restock-guide/1100-6520876/">PlayStation Portal Is Back In Stock At Multiple Major Retailers</a></li>                          <li>         <span>+ Show More Best Gaming &amp; Tech Deals This Week Links (3)</span>       </li>          <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/grab-7-awesome-dungeon-crawlers-for-only-15/1100-6523253/">Grab 7 Awesome Dungeon Crawlers For Only $15</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/xbox-game-pass-ultimate-deal-saves-you-over-50-for-12-month-membership/1100-6523230/">Xbox Game Pass Ultimate Deal Saves You Over $50 For 12-Month Membership</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/new-star-wars-and-marvel-disney-plus-blu-rays-have-arrived-but-you-may-want-to-order-soon/1100-6521604/">New Star Wars And Marvel Disney Plus Blu-Rays Have Arrived, But You May Want To Order Soon</a></li>   </ul> </div>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/108490194306897153177?rel=author">Darryn Bonthuys</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Madden NFL 25 Release Date, Early Access Info, Deluxe Edition, And More Reportedly Leaked]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/madden-nfl-25-release-date-early-access-info-deluxe-edition-and-more-reportedly-leaked/1100-6523443/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/madden-nfl-25-release-date-early-access-info-deluxe-edition-and-more-reportedly-leaked.870741/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/madden-nfl-25-release-date-early-access-info-deluxe-edition-and-more-reportedly-leaked/1100-6523443/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6523443">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>The next Madden game will be announced this week, release in August, and include a $100 premium edition that gets players into the game a few days early. That's according to a leak from <a href="https://www.dealabs.com/magazine/on-connait-la-date-de-sortie-du-prochain-madden-nfl-25-50251" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">billbil-kun</a> (<a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/madden-nfl-25-will-be-revealed-this-week-ahead-of-august-release-its-claimed/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">via VGC</a>), who has a solid track record for reporting on unannounced video game news.</p><p>The game will be announced on May 16, the report said, and that's the same day that the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ea-sports-college-football-25-cover-leaks-early-full-reveal-coming-next-week/1100-6523365/" data-ref-id="1100-6523365">official countdown clock for EA Sports College Football expires</a>. So EA may have two big football announcements to make that day.</p><p>The report said Madden NFL 25 will launch on August 16, but people who buy the Deluxe edition or subscribe to EA Play can begin playing on August 12. This is standard procedure for Madden games, as EA is known to give early access to people who spend more money.</p><p>The report said Madden NFL 25's standard edition will go for $70, with the Deluxe edition selling for $100. The story didn't have any information on who might be the cover star for Madden NFL 25, however, though the report said the cover star may be announced after the game is.</p><p>This year's Madden game could have the same name as 2013's Madden title, which was also called Madden NFL 25 due to its celebration of the franchise's 25th anniversary. It remains to be seen how EA might address that this year.</p><p>In other Madden news, Prime Video just announced a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/madden-nfl-video-game-documentary-announced-by-prime-video/1100-6523426/" data-ref-id="1100-6523426">four-part documentary series about the video game franchise</a>. Camera crews visited Madden's developer and the documentary will dig into the history of the franchise and the making of the latest entry in the series.</p><p>Expectations are always high for the newest Madden games, and that's no different this year. The franchise is a sales juggernaut, regularly ranking among the best-selling games of the year. In 2023, Madden NFL 24 was the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/the-20-best-selling-games-of-2023-in-the-us/2900-4951/#19" data-ref-id="2900-4951">No. 3 best-selling game in the US.</a></p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stellaris' new AI characters are powered by AI voices]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/audio/stellaris-new-ai-characters-are-powered-by-ai-voices</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/stellaris-new-ai-characters-are-powered-by-ai-voices.870738/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/audio/stellaris-new-ai-characters-are-powered-by-ai-voices<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="captioned-content"><p><span>Image via Paradox Interactive.</span></p></div><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Paradox Interactive subsidiary Paradox Development Studio is the next major developer to roll out generative AI content in their game. As spotted by the folks at </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/stellaris-director-insists-ethical-use-of-ai-is-very-important-to-us-after-generating-voices-in-latest-dlc">Rock Paper Shotgun</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, the newest DLC for </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Stellaris</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, titled </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>The Machine Age</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, launched with a disclaimer on its </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2840100/Stellaris_The_Machine_Age/">Steam page</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> indicating it makes use of content made by generative AI.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">How is it being used? In a limited fashion. Game director Stephen 'Eladrin' Muray took to the Steam forums and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Stellaris/comments/1cop93r/comment/l3fsoez/">Reddit</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> to explain that the tech was used to create voice lines for two characters: the Synthetic Queen Cetana and a new player advisor. Both characters are themselves artificially intelligent machines.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Muray stressed to players that Paradox did not use this technology to avoid hiring actors. "The AI voice generation tools we use on </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Stellaris </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">ensure that the voice actors that signed up and built the models receive royalties for every line we create," he said. "Ethical use of AI technology is very important to us— we're pretty good at exploring dystopian sci-fi and don't want to end up there ourselves."</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Stellaris' "><span>Stellaris' </span>AI voices seem to not hurt voice actors</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Worries over how generative AI technology could impact opportunities for voice actors have caused stress for performers and developers alike. A chief cause for concern is that developers will choose to use such technology instead of hiring actors whose voices may have been sampled in datasets used to train them.</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ex-steam-labs-dev-claims-1-000-steam-games-use-generative-ai" target="_self">Ex-Steam Labs dev claims 1,000 Steam games use generative AI</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Additionally, developers have worried that audio AI tools may violate the copyright of any actor who didn't sign their voice away to be used in the training data. Actor's union SAG-AFTRA recently </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/production/sag-aftra-says-terms-of-controversial-ai-voice-deal-will-inform-future-negotiations">struck a deal</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> with one company to allow them to work with union voice actors and ensure they are properly compensated.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Some companies, like </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/embark-studios-i-the-finals-i-uses-text-to-speech-ai-for-in-game-voices">Embark Studios</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, have stated they use the technology to incorporate voice performances in their games that would otherwise have been unaffordable. Meanwhile voice actors are also stressed over how their voices are being </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/audio/voice-actors-express-worry-over-modders-cloning-voices-with-ai">co-opted by modders</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> to rewrite their existing performances.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Muray wrote that Paradox has "strict guidelines" in place so the studio uses AI tools "legally and ethically." He said that some team members (including himself) use image and text generators to brainstorm concepts, but that no assets from said tools make it into </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Stellaris</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">This seems like a fairly humdrum use of generative AI technology—in theory the performers who provided their voices are receiving equal (or greater) compensation as if they'd hopped in the booth themselves, and can have their voices featured without straining their larynxes. Meanwhile Paradox can generate and implement the lines faster than if they needed a regular recording session.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">It's use cases like this that add nuance to conversations about generative AI. With </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/near-half-of-game-devs-say-they-re-working-with-generative-ai-tools">nearly half of game developers</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> reporting that said tools are being used in the workplace, seeing how tools can benefit actors and developers alike is important.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">That said, Muray didn't address one major concern about generative AI technology: the </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.theverge.com/24066646/ai-electricity-energy-watts-generative-consumption">immense amount of power</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> it takes to respond to each prompt.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author(s)</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Senior Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Bryant Francis is a writer, journalist, and narrative designer based in Boston, MA. He currently writes for Game Developer, a leading B2B publication for the video game industry. His credits include Proxy Studios' upcoming 4X strategy game Zephon and Amplitude Studio's 2017 game Endless Space 2.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[XDefiant will not use skill-based matchmaking in casual game modes]]></title>
            <link>https://www.destructoid.com/xdefiant-will-not-use-skill-based-matchmaking-in-casual-game-modes/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=xdefiant-will-not-use-skill-based-matchmaking-in-casual-game-modes</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/xdefiant-will-not-use-skill-based-matchmaking-in-casual-game-modes.870735/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.destructoid.com/xdefiant-will-not-use-skill-based-matchmaking-in-casual-game-modes/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=xdefiant-will-not-use-skill-based-matchmaking-in-casual-game-modes<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p data-characters="369" data-injectable="true" data-video="true"><a href="https://www.destructoid.com/xdefiant-release-date-and-countdown/"><em>XDefiant</em>‘s release date is fast approaching</a>. As it draws closer, we’re learning more and more about the <em>Call of Duty</em> competitor. For example, the developers just posted a much-appreciated breakdown of exactly how matchmaking works. The good news? Casual game modes don’t prioritize skill level, meaning skill-based matchmaking is only in ranked modes.</p> <h2 id="h-xdefiant-casual-play-has-no-skill-based-matchmaking" data-injectable="false">XDefiant casual play has no skill-based matchmaking</h2> <p data-characters="340" data-current-count="340" data-injectable="false"><em>Call of Duty</em> multiplayer warriors know all too well the problem with skill-based matchmaking in casual game modes. There’s no way to use non-meta weapons, have fun with friends, or do anything but sweat. This is because even when there’s no rank on the line, the game throws you into a blender with players of your skill level. </p> <p data-characters="516" data-current-count="856" data-injectable="true">Defying the logic of its biggest competitor, the upcoming <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/is-xdefiant-free-to-play-status-confirmed/">free-to-play multiplayer shooter <em>XDefian</em>t</a> offered us all the details on how matchmaking will work. Although at early access launch there won’t be a ranked mode just yet, when it comes it’ll be the only way to be matched against players of the same skill level. Unless, of course, you just happen to share a great connection with players of a similar or better skill level. It’ll be mostly random once an excellent connection is established.</p>
 <h2 id="h-how-does-xdefiant-matchmaking-work" data-injectable="false">How does XDefiant matchmaking work?</h2> <p data-characters="283" data-current-count="283" data-injectable="false">According to <a href="https://www.ubisoft.com/en-us/game/xdefiant/news/73QFbfzYxQbbL4ua8DValH" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a blog post by the <em>XDefiant </em>team</a>, the FPS will use a specific order of priorities for matchmaking in casual vs ranked play. Skill level isn’t just not prioritized for casual play, it was left off the list completely. Here’s a breakdown for casual game modes:</p> <ol data-found-items="6" data-current-count="523" data-injectable="true"> <li><strong>Latency </strong>– The game will match you with players on similar ping/connection to you for the best experience.</li> <li><strong>Avoided Players</strong> – Next, it will eliminate players you’ve blocked or avoided on your platform or in-game.</li> <li><strong>Party Size</strong> – Once a good connection is made, it will sort players by party size to avoid a full-stack team destroying a bunch of solo-queue players.</li> <li><strong>Region</strong> – Matchmaking will then prefer players from the same region, who speak the same language as you.</li> <li><strong>Input Device</strong> – Since the game is crossplay, <em>XDefiant</em> will do its best to place controller players vs controller players, mouse and keyboard vs mouse and keyboard.</li> <li><strong>Platform</strong> – Finally, the casual play modes will prefer players using the same platform. (PC, Xbox, PlayStation)</li> </ol>
 <p data-characters="109" data-current-count="109" data-injectable="false">When ranked mode launches in a future season, here’s a breakdown of how it will prioritize matchmaking:</p> <ol data-found-items="6" data-current-count="349" data-injectable="false"> <li><strong>Rank Points</strong> – Prefers players within your rank range, this is skill-based matchmaking.</li> <li><strong>Latency</strong></li> <li><strong>Party Size</strong></li> <li><strong>Region</strong></li> <li><strong>Input Device</strong></li> <li><strong>Platform</strong></li> </ol> <p data-characters="395" data-current-count="744" data-injectable="true">Keep in mind that the game is crossplay and this doesn’t mean you won’t face players of the <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/will-xdefiant-be-on-steam/">opposite input device or on another platform</a>. They are the lowest prioritized factor in matchmaking. If the most ideal lobby, using latency, party size, and region, is a bunch of players on another platform using another input device, you will be placed in that lobby for faster matchmaking.</p>
 <h2 id="h-what-else-can-affect-matchmaking" data-injectable="false">What else can affect matchmaking?</h2> <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"><figcaption>Image via Ubisoft</figcaption></figure> <p data-characters="361" data-current-count="661" data-injectable="true">Although these priorities explain most of how you’ll be placed in a match for <em>XDefiant</em>, even more factors come into play. For example, team balancing will take place once a lobby is populated. If a full lobby of solo players are placed together, they’ll be sorted into teams based on skill in an attempt to evenly balance the match for optimal fun. </p>
 <p data-characters="291" data-current-count="291" data-injectable="false">Next, some playlists, like ranked modes, will use input locking. So once you’re placed into a match, your current input device will be locked so you can’t change it in the pregame lobby or mid-match. Be sure to have the proper input device equipped prior to searching for a game.</p> <p data-characters="266" data-current-count="557" data-injectable="true">Finally, lobbies will rollover using the same players unless most of the players manually leave. So you won’t have to matchmake again between casual matches. Typically, your next lobby will fill instantly with most of the same players from the previous match. </p>
 <p data-characters="283" data-current-count="283" data-injectable="false">This type of matchmaking breakdown isn’t usually offered by many developers, so it is certainly appreciated. Additionally, all seems very positive for the <em>XDefiant</em> team’s outlook on how matchmaking should work as far as skill-based matchmaking, lobby rollovers, and more.</p>

<hr>
<p><i data-stringify-type="italic"> Destructoid is supported by our audience. When you purchase through links on our site, we may earn a small affiliate commission.&nbsp;</i><i data-stringify-type="italic"><a href="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-stringify-link="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" data-sk="tooltip_parent">Learn more</a></i> </p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Recap: Dead by Daylight showcase spotlights DnD chapter, a new shooter, and more]]></title>
            <link>https://www.destructoid.com/recap-dead-by-daylight-showcase-spotlights-dnd-chapter-a-new-shooter-and-more/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=recap-dead-by-daylight-showcase-spotlights-dnd-chapter-a-new-shooter-and-more</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/recap-dead-by-daylight-showcase-spotlights-dnd-chapter-a-new-shooter-and-more.870729/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.destructoid.com/recap-dead-by-daylight-showcase-spotlights-dnd-chapter-a-new-shooter-and-more/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=recap-dead-by-daylight-showcase-spotlights-dnd-chapter-a-new-shooter-and-more<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p data-characters="272" data-injectable="true" data-video="true">Behaviour Interactive’s <em>Dead by Daylight</em> 8th Anniversary livestream event included gameplay reveals and incredible news for <em><a href="https://www.destructoid.com/reviews/review-dead-by-daylight/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Dead by Daylight</a></em> fans from start to finish. There’s a lot to go through, but I’ve got you covered if you just want the highlights.</p> <p data-characters="571" data-current-count="571" data-injectable="true">Every year since the 3rd anniversary of <em>Dead by Daylight</em>, Behaviour Interactive has held an anniversary stream to celebrate the community, tease upcoming Chapters, events, and changes, and give something back to the players. This year is probably the best I’ve ever seen, as a fan who has been playing since the game’s initial console release in 2017, though it had been out on PC for a year before that. Regardless of whether you’re a long-time player or brand-new to <em>Dead by Daylight</em>, there’s a reason to be excited as we enter its ninth year. </p>
 <h2 id="h-all-dead-by-daylight-8th-anniversary-announcements" data-injectable="false">All <em>Dead by Daylight</em> 8th Anniversary announcements</h2> <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"><p> <iframe title="Dead by Daylight | Year 8 Anniversary Broadcast" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/GIwtIGmevQE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe> </p></figure> <p data-characters="278" data-current-count="578" data-injectable="true">The <em>Dead by Daylight</em> 8th Anniversary livestream featured a lot of amazing reveals and is worth watching so you get to see the new content and reveals in action. I’ve listed each one below so you don’t miss anything coming to the <em>Dead by Daylight</em> universe this year. </p>
 <h3 data-injectable="false"><em>Dead by Daylight</em> cross-progression</h3> <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"><figcaption>Image via Behaviour Interactive</figcaption></figure> <p data-characters="313" data-current-count="613" data-injectable="true">At long last, Behaviour Interactive will bring cross-progression to <em>Dead by Daylight</em>. Players will need to own a copy of the base game on the platforms where they wish to play, and then they’ll be able to use their Behaviour Interactive account to continue playing on their account anywhere they own a copy.</p>
 <p data-characters="462" data-current-count="462" data-injectable="true">Cross-progression will come to <em>Dead by Daylight</em> later in <strong>summer 2024</strong>, and there will be a few limitations. However, the developer hasn’t explained what those limitations will be just yet. We’ll need to wait until closer to the feature’s launch to find out exactly what will be accessible across every platform. In the meantime, it’s worth getting a Behaviour Interactive account so that you don’t miss out on this when it launches. </p>
 <h3 data-injectable="false"><em>Dead by Daylight</em> 2v8 Mode</h3> <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"><figcaption>Image via Behaviour Interactive</figcaption></figure> <p data-characters="318" data-current-count="618" data-injectable="true">Behaviour Interactive blew me away with the announcement of its upcoming 2v8 game mode for <em>Dead by Dyalight</em>. It’s exactly what it sounds like: 2 Killers and 8 Survivors going head-to-head in a chaotic Trial where generators still need to be repaired, sacrifices must be made, and there’s blood everywhere. </p>
 <p data-characters="336" data-current-count="336" data-injectable="false">This game mode will be a time-limited event towards the end of this summer but is being built to become a permanent game mode eventually. It’ll only have the five basic Killers <em>Dead by Daylight</em> was initially released with at first; The Trapper, The Wraith, The Nurse, The Hillbilly, and The Huntress. More will be added over time.</p> <p data-characters="572" data-current-count="908" data-injectable="true">The maps for this game mode are being enlarged to make them feel as big as the number of players in them. They’ll have new paths and points of interest to ensure they never get stale too. One key change that will keep the pace up is that there are no hooks in 2v8. Instead, Killers will perform an attack to transport Survivors in the Dying State to a new type of cage that The Entity is using elsewhere on the map. Survivors can still rescue each other, but the hook states will still apply when it comes to how many chances you have before you’re worm food. </p>
 <p data-characters="255" data-current-count="255" data-injectable="false">This mode is designed to be more cooperative than basic Trials. As such, players pick a class when playing as Survivors instead of using specific Perks. This ensures a steady loadout, but also forces you to play to your class strengths and help the team. </p> <p data-characters="329" data-current-count="584" data-injectable="true">The big change for Killers is how their abilities will impact each other. Any effects an ability applies to one Killer will apply to the other if they’re close enough, which could let them double up with their own ability and attack Survivors in unexpected ways. Hopefully, this will finally make The Nurse playable for me.</p>
 <h3 data-injectable="false"><em>Dead by Daylight</em> 8th Anniversary in-game celebrations and Year 9 roadmap</h3> <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"><figcaption>Screenshot via Behaviour Interactive</figcaption></figure> <p data-characters="375" data-current-count="675" data-injectable="true">Behaviour Interactive gave fans a look at what’s to come in<em> Dead by Daylight</em>‘s Year 9 roadmap. It should give all fans a decent idea of when new Chapters, events, Tomes, and more are planned. The developer also explained that in-game celebrations fans can take part in are part of how it’s giving back to the community for the game’s 8th anniversary. </p>
 <p data-characters="306" data-current-count="306" data-injectable="false">A new in-game challenge system will be added to the game this year, giving players a way to progress challenges passively. These challenges will be simple at first but build up to increase rewards for those who work through every Tome pretty quickly and end up running out of challenges to keep them busy. </p> <p data-characters="460" data-current-count="766" data-injectable="true">The Before the Masquerade event began today after the livestream. It features free in-game cosmetics for players to earn just from launching the game, as well as boosts for rewards earned from specific maps over the course of the next few weeks. Once it ends, the Twisted Masquerade event will begin in June 2024, marking the first in-game event of the year and a chance to experience the most complex event game mode I’ve ever seen in <em>Dead by Daylight</em>. </p>
 <h3 data-injectable="false"><em>Dead by Daylight</em> <em>Chapter 32: Dungeons &amp; Dragons</em></h3> <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"><figcaption>Image via Behaviour Interactive</figcaption></figure> <p data-characters="406" data-current-count="706" data-injectable="true">We now have a lot more information on <em>Dead by Daylight Chapter 32: Dungeons &amp; Dragons</em>, which was <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/behaviour-interactive-teases-dungeons-dragons-coming-to-dead-by-daylight/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">teased last week</a>. As many fans suspected, this Chapter adds Vecna from <em>D&amp;D</em>, a character who has grown in power to pretty much become the ultimate being within that universe. He’s nothing compared to The Entity, though, and now he’s trapped in a realm that <em>D&amp;D</em> fans will find familiar. </p>
 <p data-characters="328" data-current-count="328" data-injectable="false">The Chapter adds Vecna as a new Killer along with a new map, Forgotten Ruins. It features a large tower that Survivors will venture into to explore a vast dungeon beneath the surface. Critical Role’s Matt Mercer voices the necromancer, so if you think you recognize what’s left of Vecna’s vocal cords, you do. </p> <p data-characters="72" data-current-count="400" data-injectable="true">Vecna’s Perks, which are based on<em> D&amp;D</em> spells, are as follows. </p>
 <ul data-found-items="4" data-current-count="160" data-injectable="false"> <li><strong>Fly</strong>: The Killer can float for a short time and pass through obstacles. </li> <li><strong>Flight of the Damned</strong>: Summons spectral entities that pass through objects and harm those they touch. </li> <li><strong>Mage Hand</strong>: Casts a spectral hand that can block tasks like using pallets. </li> <li><strong>Dispelling Sphere</strong>: Casts a moving, magical sphere that dispels magical items and detects Survivors. </li> </ul> <p data-characters="355" data-current-count="515" data-injectable="true">The most exciting thing about this Chapter is how it twists the traditional <em>Dead by Daylight</em> Trial formula. There are skill hooks to hang Survivors on and generators to repair, but there’s so much more to the game when facing Vecna. For example, this Killer causes 4 chests to spawn around the map, and players will roll a dice when they open them. </p>
 <p data-characters="497" data-current-count="497" data-injectable="true">The dice rolls dictate whether they get a magical or a basic item. Magical items provide certain buffs to Survivors, but it’s the critical success rolls they want. These rolls award cursed items. The eye of Vecna allows you to become invisible after leaving a locker, while the Hand of Vecna lets you teleport between lockers, and, if you’re incredibly lucky, you can combine them both to dominate the Killer. These have a caveat, though, costing you a health state when you get them. </p>
 <p data-characters="231" data-current-count="231" data-injectable="false">Critical failures are also possible, and they’ll punish players in unexpected ways. I’m already getting flashbacks of The Cenotaph teleporting to me as its hooks hold me in place, and I wonder how Vecna could be worse. </p> <p data-characters="355" data-current-count="586" data-injectable="true">Survivors can fight back against Vecna by taking on the role of two new Bard characters. These are the elf Aestri Yazar, who is the new Survivor for the Chapter, and the human Baermar Uraz. It’s important to note that while Aestri is the new Survivor, Baermar is another character in the game, but you’ll swap between the two using cosmetics. </p>
 <p data-characters="120" data-current-count="120" data-injectable="false">This Survivor enters the game with three Perks to help the party avoid being sacrificed by Vecna. These are as follows: </p> <ul data-found-items="3" data-current-count="240" data-injectable="false"> <li><strong>Mirrored Illusion</strong>: Spawns a static copy of a Survivor in front of a chest, generator, totem, or exit gate for a short time. </li> <li><strong>Bardic Inspiration</strong>: Play a song to cause all Survivors to roll a D20 and perform a skill check to receive a buff. </li> <li><strong>Still Sight</strong>: When not in motion, you can briefly see the auras of Survivors near generators, totems, and chests. </li> </ul> <p data-characters="254" data-current-count="494" data-injectable="true">This Chapter is live right now in the <em>Dead by Daylight </em>PTB. It’ll be released for all players on <strong>June 3, 2024</strong>, meaning you have very little time to wait until you can combine the horrific world of <em>Dead by Daylight</em> with the deep fantasy of <em>D&amp;D</em>. </p>
 <p data-characters="256" data-current-count="256" data-injectable="false">I also want to add that in a press event before the livestream, Behaviour Interactive’s Mathieu Cote confirmed that, sadly, no <em>D&amp;D </em>one-shot is currently planned for the TTRPG. But it’s not off the table. It’s just not been discussed. </p> <h3 data-injectable="false"><em>Project T</em> revealed with playtests sign ups now live</h3> <figure data-current-count="556" data-injectable="true"><figcaption>Image via Behaviour Interactive</figcaption></figure>
 <p data-characters="382" data-current-count="382" data-injectable="false">For one segment of the livestream, Behaviour Interactive handed things over to Midwinter Entertainment to discuss <em><a href="https://www.destructoid.com/dead-by-daylight-shared-world-shooter-project-t-announced-playtest-registration-available-now/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Project T</a></em>. This game is a shared world third-person shooter set in the same universe as <em>Dead by Daylight</em>. In it, players become Trespassers in The Backwater, a horrific realm of The Entity where a race of monsters called The Thrall tries to kill anything that enters. </p> <p data-characters="264" data-current-count="646" data-injectable="true">Players will need to work together to complete objectives in The Backwater and escape alive. To do this, they’ll need to collect the best guns available and defend themselves while half the team tackles an objective and the other half deals with The Thrall. </p>
 <p data-characters="321" data-current-count="321" data-injectable="false"><em>Project T</em> is still in the very early stages of development, but Midwinter Entertainment has invited all fans to join its <a href="https://insiderprogram.bhvr.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Program</a>. Those signed up will receive invitations to playtests on PC and, eventually, console, and exclusive rewards will be available to those who contribute feedback to help shape the game. </p> <h3 data-injectable="false">New trailer for <em>The Casting of Frank Stone</em></h3> <figure data-current-count="621" data-injectable="true"><p> <iframe loading="lazy" title="The Casting of Frank Stone - Gameplay Trailer | PS5 Games" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/0CFXLyBwtjs?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe> </p></figure>
 <p data-characters="321" data-current-count="321" data-injectable="false">A new trailer trailer for Supermassive Games’ <em>The Casting of Frank Stone</em> revealed a lot more about the story than ever before. While it’s still a little unclear, we do now know we’ll be playing as a group of teenagers who all head to an incredibly dangerous abandoned industrial site to create a movie. </p> <p data-characters="385" data-current-count="706" data-injectable="true">There seems to be some degree of time manipulation going on, but it’s hard to tell how this works from the trailer alone. During a press event before the livestream, Supermassive Games explained how player choices will matter a lot as they play. One choice could see characters live or die, and entire sections of the game can be missed or explored based on simple interactions. </p>
 <p data-characters="408" data-current-count="408" data-injectable="true">In addition to being akin to an interactive movie with QTEs like <em>Until Dawn</em>, <em>The Casting of Frank Stone</em> will also include puzzles to solve throughout. the developer couldn’t tell us more about these, but they can also impact the story, so it sounds like you can completely mess up and still continue through to a conclusion regardless of whether you complete a puzzle, get it wrong, or even ignore it. </p>
 <h3 data-injectable="false"><em>What the Fog </em>announced and released for free</h3> <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"><figcaption>Image via Behaviour Interactive</figcaption></figure> <p data-characters="398" data-current-count="698" data-injectable="true">As a thank you to all <em>Dead by Daylight</em> fans, Behaviour Interactive has built, announced, and released a game called <em><a href="https://www.destructoid.com/what-the-fog-is-a-free-dbd-co-op-shooter-and-surprise-its-out-now/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">What the Fog</a></em>, and it’s free on PC right now. Anyone with a Behaviour Interactive account can claim it and begin playing this cute little co-op shooter set in the same universe on Steam today. If you don’t have one, <a href="https://account.bhvr.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up now</a> to get it before it costs you $4.99/£4.99.</p>
 <h3 data-injectable="false"><em>Dead by Daylight</em> heads to <em>Castlevania</em></h3> <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"><figcaption>Screenshot by Destructoid</figcaption></figure> <p data-characters="205" data-current-count="505" data-injectable="true">Finally, Behaviour Interactive dropped a short teaser for an upcoming Chapter, <em>Dead by Daylight X Castlevania</em>. Not much more was detailed, but it’s likely this will include a new Killer and Survivor.</p>
 <p data-characters="227" data-current-count="227" data-injectable="false">That’s super exciting to me, because I remember playing the <em>Castlevania</em> games when they were 2D, pixels, and imagination. More information will be revealed on <strong>August 6, 2024</strong>, so there really isn’t that long to wait.</p>

<hr>
<p><i data-stringify-type="italic"> Destructoid is supported by our audience. When you purchase through links on our site, we may earn a small affiliate commission.&nbsp;</i><i data-stringify-type="italic"><a href="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-stringify-link="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" data-sk="tooltip_parent">Learn more</a></i> </p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Roblox Classic event: Release date, game predictions, and more]]></title>
            <link>https://www.destructoid.com/roblox-classic-event-release-date/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=roblox-classic-event-release-date</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/roblox-classic-event-release-date-game-predictions-and-more.870726/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.destructoid.com/roblox-classic-event-release-date/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=roblox-classic-event-release-date<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p data-characters="403" data-injectable="true" data-video="true">The&nbsp;<em><a href="https://www.destructoid.com/best-roblox-games-for-adults/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Roblox</a>&nbsp;</em>phenomenon began in 2006 and has increased in popularity with each passing year. If you’ve been an OG fan, you may be reminiscent of the game’s past features, back when it looked similar to a LEGO world. Fortunately, the&nbsp;<em>Roblox</em>&nbsp;Classic event showcases the return of vintage content. We’re here to show you when to expect this celebration and possible upcoming content.&nbsp;</p> <h2 id="h-when-does-the-roblox-classic-event-come-out" data-injectable="false">When does the Roblox Classic event come out?</h2> <p data-characters="291" data-current-count="291" data-injectable="false">The&nbsp;<em>Roblox&nbsp;</em>Classic event, as announced on the official <em>Roblox</em> Twitter/X account, is set to begin&nbsp;on&nbsp;<strong>May 23, 2024</strong>. However, the exact release time has yet to be revealed. If past events like <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/all-roblox-the-hunt-games/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The Hunt</a> are any indication, it’s likely to drop around 10 a.m. PT/ 1 p.m. CT/ 2 p.m. ET.&nbsp;</p> <p data-characters="216" data-current-count="507" data-injectable="true">While there have been few details on the&nbsp;<em>Roblox&nbsp;</em>Classic event, it will likely return old features from the past. It may function similarly to&nbsp;<a href="https://www.destructoid.com/what-is-fortnite-ogs-lore-fortnite-story-guide/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Fortnite’s OG</em>&nbsp;update</a>, which brought back classic maps and items.</p>
 <p data-characters="189" data-current-count="189" data-injectable="false">In the brief announcement video, we see many iconic features from the old days of&nbsp;<em>Roblox.</em>&nbsp;Specifically, the Cheezburger,&nbsp;<em>Roblox</em>&nbsp;Classic hat, and Epic Duck can be seen floating around.&nbsp;</p> <figure data-current-count="489" data-injectable="true"></figure>
 <p data-characters="209" data-current-count="209" data-injectable="false">It isn’t clear what exact period&nbsp;<em>Roblox&nbsp;</em>Classic will involve. Based on the announcement’s artwork, it will likely be around its 2006 debut, but&nbsp;it could also be set&nbsp;around its 2010s duration.&nbsp;</p> <h2 id="h-roblox-classic-event-game-predictions" data-injectable="false">Roblox Classic event game predictions</h2> <p data-characters="260" data-current-count="469" data-injectable="true">If&nbsp;<em>Roblox&nbsp;</em>Classic is anything like previous events, there will be various games to participate in for exclusive rewards. Some players have noticed that several games, such as BedWars, Livetopia, and Blade Ball, have updated their badges with classic looks.&nbsp;</p>
 <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"><figcaption>Image via Roblox Corporation</figcaption></figure> <p data-characters="267" data-current-count="567" data-injectable="true">Other rumors have also suggested&nbsp;that Adopt Me!, Restaurant Tycoon 2, and <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/toilet-wars-tower-defense-codes/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Toilet Tower Defense</a>. But if the&nbsp;<em>Roblox&nbsp;</em>Classic event truly kicks it old school, we may see the comeback of a few early entries, like Work at a Pizza Place and Survive The Natural Disasters.</p>
 <p data-characters="131" data-current-count="131" data-injectable="false"><em>Roblox&nbsp;</em>Classic event games have yet to be confirmed, so we’ll update this guide with more details when they are available.&nbsp;</p> <h2 id="h-how-long-will-the-roblox-classic-event-last" data-injectable="false">How long will the Roblox Classic event last?</h2> <p data-characters="210" data-current-count="341" data-injectable="false">Currently, there is no set duration for the&nbsp;<em>Roblox&nbsp;</em>Classic event. It may last two weeks, like The Hunt extravaganza. However, depending on how the event goes, it may be more time-restrictive or last longer.&nbsp;</p>

<hr>
<p><i data-stringify-type="italic"> Destructoid is supported by our audience. When you purchase through links on our site, we may earn a small affiliate commission.&nbsp;</i><i data-stringify-type="italic"><a href="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-stringify-link="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" data-sk="tooltip_parent">Learn more</a></i> </p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[8 Movies We Want To See In Chris Pratt's Proposed Nintendo Cinematic Universe]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/mario-movie-zelda-animal-crossing-animated-smash-bros-1851476716</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/8-movies-we-want-to-see-in-chris-pratts-proposed-nintendo-cinematic-universe.870696/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/mario-movie-zelda-animal-crossing-animated-smash-bros-1851476716<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><figure id="" data-id="ad8eb28b64aabcb74d6be417e9ff8a6e" data-recommend-id="image://ad8eb28b64aabcb74d6be417e9ff8a6e" data-format="jpg" data-width="1690" data-height="949" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Mario, Link, and a bunch of other characters do sick action poses." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Mario, Link, and a bunch of other characters do sick action poses." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Nintendo</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="ad8eb28b64aabcb74d6be417e9ff8a6e" data-recommend-id="image://ad8eb28b64aabcb74d6be417e9ff8a6e" data-format="jpg" data-width="1690" data-height="949" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Mario, Link, and a bunch of other characters do sick action poses." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>Nintendo wants to lean hard into movies. After the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/super-mario-bros-movie-nintendo-box-office-jack-black-1850343976&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/super-mario-bros-movie-nintendo-box-office-jack-black-1850343976">astronomical success</a></span> of <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/super-mario-bros-movie-review-chris-pratt-jack-black-1850309488&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/super-mario-bros-movie-review-chris-pratt-jack-black-1850309488"><em>The Super Mario Bros. Movie</em></a></span>, why wouldn’t it? But <em>Mario</em> actor Chris Pratt is dreaming even bigger—He wants the company to think beyond just having an adaptation in theaters every few years and consider an extended film universe.<br></p><p>In an interview with <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://screenrant.com/super-mario-bros-2-movie-nintendo-cinematic-universe-plan-chris-pratt-explained/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://screenrant.com/super-mario-bros-2-movie-nintendo-cinematic-universe-plan-chris-pratt-explained/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Screen Rant</em></a></span>, Pratt said there’s material in all of Nintendo’s big franchises to create a “Nintendo Cinematic Universe” to rival something like Marvel’s interconnected films. He’s not wrong. There’s a reason <em>Super Smash Bros. </em>exists. Nintendo has so many beloved characters and worlds to draw from that it sustains one of the biggest crossovers in video game history.</p><p>But it does leave one to wonder what a Nintendo Cinematic Universe looks like. <em>Mario </em>was an origin story for the titular plumber, and if Nintendo is looking to make introductory movies for its heroes, there’s a surprising amount of genre variety the company could pull from leading into a hypothetical <em>Super Smash Bros. </em>movie. Grab your popcorn and Switch, Nintendo fans. Let’s speculate about what some other Nintendo movies might look like.</p></div></div><div><p>Imagine this: Fox McCloud is a rookie arwing pilot in his first year of flight academy. He’s cocky, but that’d be a dude he’s compensating for a life lived under his father James’ shadow. His dad is a legendary pilot and everyone clearly has a lot of expectations for Fox as his son. At school he meets his friends Falco and Slippy, and under the guidance of his teacher Peppy Hare, they undergo their training to become the titular Star Fox team. But can he overcome the pressures (internal and external), and save the galaxy from an incoming threat? He’s only a beginner on paper, but inside, he has the blood of a legend. He was born to be a pilot. Come on, tell me you aren’t itching to see Nintendo’s take on <em>Top Gun</em>?<br></p></div><div><p>When I proposed an animated <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/fire-emblem-three-houses-the-kotaku-review-1836675912&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/fire-emblem-three-houses-the-kotaku-review-1836675912"><em>Fire Emblem</em></a></span><em> </em>film would be a political fantasy drama, <em>Kotaku </em>staff writer Moises Taveras said “<em>Fire Emblem</em> as <em>Game of Thrones</em> for kids goes so hard.” Which is true, because that’s basically what <em>Fire Emblem </em>is in video game form—a lot of politicking, intrigue, catty interpersonal relationships, and big fantasy battles. You don’t even need me to spell out how a <em>Three Houses</em> movie would play out because it’s basically <em>Game of Thrones </em>without the on-screen sex.<br></p></div><div><p>Sony was able to make a <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/gran-turismo-movie-review-playstation-harbour-polyphony-1850781739&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/gran-turismo-movie-review-playstation-harbour-polyphony-1850781739"><em>Gran Turismo </em>movie</a></span>, a series without characters, into a live-action film that <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.boxofficemojo.com/release/rl3788079873/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.boxofficemojo.com/release/rl3788079873/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">did pretty alright for itself</a></span>. So if Nintendo wants to get in on the toy car market by putting out an <em>F-Zero </em>movie, they’re even more primed for success. Kids love a racing movie, and more than anything else, they love to buy toy cars based on racing movies. How do you think we ended up with three <em>Cars </em>films despite that whole franchise being mid as hell? <em>F-Zero </em>at least has a colorful cast of weirdos to put behind the wheel. And you know they’d put in a scene where Captain Falcon straight up Falcon Punches a car on the tracks. The crowd goes wild.<br></p></div><div><p>Nintendo’s life simulator is probably better for an animated television series than it is a movie, but imagine it: a workplace comedy starring Tom Nook, Isabelle, and all the other villagers. Isabelle <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.gamespot.com/articles/isabelle-could-show-up-in-animal-crossing-new-hori/1100-6467762/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/isabelle-could-show-up-in-animal-crossing-new-hori/1100-6467762/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">has already been compared to workplace comedy royalty</a></span> <em>Parks and Recreation</em> Leslie Knope, and putting all those other colorful characters in the workplace documentary format of that or <em>The Office</em> is a great way to adapt the spirit of a video game into a new medium. You spend dozens to hundreds of hours in <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/animal-crossing-new-horizons-the-kotaku-review-1842321314&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/animal-crossing-new-horizons-the-kotaku-review-1842321314"><em>Animal Crossing</em></a></span><em> </em>dealing with the thorny-but-endearing aspects of coexisting with others. Just put Isabelle in front of a camera and let her bitch about her work day.<br></p></div><div><p><em>Punch-Out </em>is another example of a game so well-suited to a specific film genre that you can easily envision its plot beats. The <em>Rocky </em>movies are the blueprint for boxing films, and <em>Punch-Out </em>could be easily mapped onto something along those lines. Little Mac coming up the ranks in his local boxing tournament is primed to teach kids not to give up in the face of struggle. The matches would be flashy and action-packed, and so long as Little Mac doesn’t find himself on the wrong side of a corner stool <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RxCGmCQYnEM&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RxCGmCQYnEM" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">like a million-dollar baby</a></span>, it should be a feel-good experience for the whole family.<br></p></div><div><p>For this one, we won’t have to speculate for too long, as Nintendo already has a <em>Legend of Zelda</em> movie in the works. However, it will <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/legend-of-zelda-movie-kingdom-of-the-planet-of-the-apes-1851448204&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/legend-of-zelda-movie-kingdom-of-the-planet-of-the-apes-1851448204">be live-action</a></span>, unlike the <em>Mario </em>movie. Director Wes Ball has stated he wants the film to prioritize those live-action elements instead of relying on CGI, so it sounds like we’ll likely get a more realistic take on the series with more practical effects. That probably throws out stuff like <em>Wind Waker</em>’s sea-faring travel or <em>Twilight Princess</em>’ wolf transformations. But it would be refreshing if it was more inspired by the original NES game, which doesn’t delve into the complex lore of future games.<br></p></div><div><p>Samus Aran’s story is probably the darkest of any of the games we have listed here, which makes adapting it into a hypothetical animated feature film a bit more complicated. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/metroid-dread-the-kotaku-review-1847823602&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/metroid-dread-the-kotaku-review-1847823602"><em>Metroid</em></a></span><em> </em>games are often isolating, with its heroine off on some space-faring mission by her lonesome. A movie that captures that essence would likely be more along the lines of <em>Alien</em> than something comparable to <em>The Super Mario Bros. Movie</em>. Damn, I’m actually really into this idea but it will never get approved by Nintendo.<br></p></div><div><p>Though I played plenty of <em>Kid Icarus </em>as a kid, it was overshadowed by NES games with a bit more oomph: your <em>Mario</em>s, your <em>Zelda</em>s, your <em>Metroid</em>s. (Well, there was only one NES <em>Metroid </em>but you get my point.) But now, whenever I revisit it, I appreciate the inviting, distinctly Nintendo charm of its take on Greek mythology, a hot topic these days days thanks to Supergiant’s super-successful roguelike <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/hades-the-kotaku-review-1845204803&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/hades-the-kotaku-review-1845204803"><em>Hades</em></a></span><em> </em>(and <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/hades-2-gameplay-technical-test-crafting-incantations-1851420083&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/hades-2-gameplay-technical-test-crafting-incantations-1851420083">its sequel</a></span>). But <em>Hades </em>features overtly sexy gods and their sexy sex lives; Nintendo, ever the family-friendly company, may want something that capitalizes on the appeal of a world of gods and adventure, but that’s squarely aimed at the younger set. That makes this precisely the moment for a big <em>Kid Icarus </em>comeback.</p><p>With its cherubic hero Pit and its charming take on a Greek-inspired land of myth and monsters, a <em>Kid Icarus </em>film could walk that line of being entertaining to both kids and their parents, with plenty of charm and humor the little ones can enjoy, but also moments of genuine thrills and peril. I mean look, the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://kidicarus.fandom.com/wiki/Eggplant_Wizard&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kidicarus.fandom.com/wiki/Eggplant_Wizard" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Eggplant Wizards</a></span>, who literally turn you into an eggplant, scared the <em>hell </em>out of me as a kid. Hmm. “Eggplant Wizards” may play a bit differently today. Ah well, that’s a problem for Nintendo to deal with. In any case, <em>Kid Icarus </em>would be fantastic source material for an upbeat, crowd pleasing, comedic adventure film for the whole family that leans into Greek mythology in a lighthearted way but still fires the imaginations of children with its sense of magic and possibility. If the <em>Zelda </em>movie is going for <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/legend-of-zelda-movie-kingdom-of-the-planet-of-the-apes-1851448204&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/legend-of-zelda-movie-kingdom-of-the-planet-of-the-apes-1851448204">a more grounded approach</a></span>—and it sounds like it is—then let <em>Kid Icarus </em>fill the more breezy, kid-friendly fantasy adventure niche in Nintendo’s cinematic offerings. And put out a great new <em>Kid Icarus </em>game alongside it, too!—Carolyn Petit</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Monkey Island Creator's Next Game Is A Mashup Of Everything We Love]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/ron-gilbert-new-game-rpg-zelda-diablo-thimbleweed-park-1851476567</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/monkey-island-creators-next-game-is-a-mashup-of-everything-we-love.870693/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/ron-gilbert-new-game-rpg-zelda-diablo-thimbleweed-park-1851476567<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="a5f71882469a1e3b42ab81918cc37849" data-recommend-id="image://a5f71882469a1e3b42ab81918cc37849" data-format="jpg" data-width="1200" data-height="630" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A screenshot of Ron Gilbert's untitled new game, featuring sprites of characters in a wooded area outside of a home. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A screenshot of Ron Gilbert's untitled new game, featuring sprites of characters in a wooded area outside of a home. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="false" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Terrible Toybox</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="a5f71882469a1e3b42ab81918cc37849" data-recommend-id="image://a5f71882469a1e3b42ab81918cc37849" data-format="jpg" data-width="1200" data-height="630" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A screenshot of Ron Gilbert's untitled new game, featuring sprites of characters in a wooded area outside of a home. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>Renowned game developer <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://www.kotaku.com.au/2023/06/monkey-island-creator-says-he-wasnt-aware-sea-of-thieves-dlc-was-happening/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.kotaku.com.au/2023/06/monkey-island-creator-says-he-wasnt-aware-sea-of-thieves-dlc-was-happening/">Ron Gilbert</a></span>’s latest game is not at all what any of us might’ve expected. As spotted by <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.timeextension.com/news/2024/05/monkey-island-creator-ron-gilbert-is-working-on-a-zelda-style-rpg-adventure&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.timeextension.com/news/2024/05/monkey-island-creator-ron-gilbert-is-working-on-a-zelda-style-rpg-adventure" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Time Extension</em></a></span>, the game’s been teased as “Classic <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/the-legend-of-zelda-tears-of-the-kingdom-the-kotaku-r-1850570840&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/the-legend-of-zelda-tears-of-the-kingdom-the-kotaku-r-1850570840"><em>Zelda</em></a></span> meets <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/tag/diablo&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/tag/diablo"><em>Diablo</em></a></span> meets <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/thimbleweed-park-the-kotaku-review-1793821288&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/thimbleweed-park-the-kotaku-review-1793821288"><em>Thimbleweed Park</em></a></span>,” and is set to release in 2024…maybe.</p><div data-video-id="196013" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="The Top 10 Most-Played Games On Steam Deck: October 2023 Edition" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="316" data-playlist="196013,195301,196345" data-current="196013"><div><p>The Top 10 Most-Played Games On Steam Deck: October 2023 Edition</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196013/196013_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196013/196013_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196013/196013_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196013/196013_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21533.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><p>Gilbert, famed for his tenure at LucasArts where he developed legendary adventure games like <em>Maniac Mansion </em>and the <em>Monkey Island </em>series, began work on the title earlier this year, and has been teasing out its development on his <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://mastodon.gamedev.place/@grumpygamer&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://mastodon.gamedev.place/@grumpygamer" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Mastodon</a></span> account. We know little else about the game at this moment, but as of a few days ago, Gilbert formally unveiled the game and revealed that Elissa Black (who co-founded Flat Earth Games, makers of <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://store.steampowered.com/app/824070/Objects_in_Space/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/824070/Objects_in_Space/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Objects in Space</em></a></span>) would be joining the team as a quest designer. Gilbert joked that her addition to the team “ups the chance by 37% that I’ll finish the game before becoming bored and disillusioned.”</p><p>The <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://mastodon.gamedev.place/@grumpygamer/112401714030473672&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://mastodon.gamedev.place/@grumpygamer/112401714030473672" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">post</a></span> also features a screenshot of the in-development RPG, which boasts a cozy but familiar pixel-art style. The few sprites featured in the image don’t look too different from characters featured in some of Gilbert’s other games, especially <em>Thimbleweed Park</em>.</p><p>Since leaving LucasArts, Gilbert has remained active in the games industry, joining forces with TIm Schafer at Double Fine Entertainment in the early 2010s to develop the adventure game <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/the-cave-the-kotaku-review-5977478&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/the-cave-the-kotaku-review-5977478"><em>The Cave</em></a></span>, before eventually leaving and founding his own studio, Terrible Toybox, where he worked on the throwback point-and-click <em>Thimbleweed Park</em>. Yes, the very same <em>Thimbleweed Park </em>that is inspiring Gilbert’s latest game. More of us should <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-shadow-of-erdtree-bloodborne-enemy-1851473804&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-shadow-of-erdtree-bloodborne-enemy-1851473804">take inspiration from ourselves</a></span>. Fuck yeah, Ron.</p><p>Since <em>Thimbleweed Park</em>’s release in 2017, Gilbert and his studio also sneakily worked on and released 2022’s acclaimed <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/return-to-monkey-island-ron-gilbert-devolver-digital-ad-1849117475&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/return-to-monkey-island-ron-gilbert-devolver-digital-ad-1849117475"><em>Return to Monkey Island</em></a></span>. The game marked Gilbert’s first contribution to the series he created since <em>Monkey Island 2: LeChuck’s Revenge </em>in 1991.<br></p><p>Though Gilbert seems to believe that he and the team at Terrible Toybox could launch the game later this year, the listing on the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://terribletoybox.com/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://terribletoybox.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">company’s website</a></span> does throw in a parenthetical that jokes, “maybe early 2025, this is gamedev after all.” No matter what, it sounds like we’re getting a new Ron Gilbert game relatively soon, folks!<br></p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Madden NFL 25's Release Date Leaked Ahead of Reveal Later This Week]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/madden-nfl-25s-release-date-leaked</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/madden-nfl-25s-release-date-leaked-ahead-of-reveal-later-this-week.870690/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/madden-nfl-25s-release-date-leaked<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>Madden NFL 25 is apparently set to release on August 16, according to a new report. </p><p>Reliable video game leaker and data miner billbil-kun has <a href="https://www.dealabs.com/magazine/on-connait-la-date-de-sortie-du-prochain-madden-nfl-25-50251" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">published a new report</a> detailing what fans can expect from this year's Madden. According to billbil-kun, Madden NFL 25 will be released on August 16, but those who own the Deluxe Edition or subscribe to EA Play will get access as early as August 12. </p><p>Although billbil-kun has not revealed any details as to who the cover athlete(s) for Madden 25 will be, the report does confirm that EA Orlando (formerly EA Tiburon) will once again develop the next Madden game. Madden NFL 25 will have two editions: Standard and Deluxe; the former will retail for $69.99, while the latter will cost $99.99. </p><p>A proper reveal for Madden NFL is supposedly happening on May 16 — the same day the publisher is set to <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/college-football-25-deluxe-edition-cover-leaked-online">reveal the official covers for College Football 25</a>, its first entry in the college football video game series since 2013. </p><p>The report also claims that Madden NFL 25 will improve the FieldSense technology. This feature originally debuted in <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/madden-nfl-23-review-ps5-xbox-series-x">Madden NFL 23</a>, with the physics engine being reworked for the newest entry to provide more "realistic animations with fluid gameplay." </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>The news comes the same day Prime Video announced new content for its streaming service, including <a href="https://www.aboutamazon.com/news/entertainment/prime-video-new-tv-series-movies-announcements-2024" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">a four-part docuseries</a> focusing on the history of the Madden video game franchise. </p><p>In <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/madden-nfl-24-review">our review of Madden NFL 24</a>, IGN wrote: "New animations and improved AI make Madden NFL 24’s on-field action the best it's ever been, but everything that happens off the field is a slog of dated modes and laggy menus that brings everything around it down." </p><p><em>Taylor is a Reporter at IGN. You can follow her on Twitter </em><a href="https://twitter.com/TayNixster" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>@TayNixster.</em></a></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Call Of Duty Patch Notes Reveal Bug Fixes, Changes, Weapon Tuning, And More]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-patch-notes-reveal-bug-fixes-changes-weapon-tuning-and-more/1100-6523440/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/call-of-duty-patch-notes-reveal-bug-fixes-changes-weapon-tuning-and-more.870687/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-patch-notes-reveal-bug-fixes-changes-weapon-tuning-and-more/1100-6523440/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6523440">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>The newest patches for <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/call-of-duty-modern-warfare-iii/" data-ref-id="5000-597446">Call of Duty: Modern Warfare III</a> and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/call-of-duty-warzone/" data-ref-id="5000-572198">Warzone</a> have arrived, ushering in the latest changes to the popular multiplayer shooters.</p><p>Starting with Modern Warfare III, players can expect a variety of bug fixes and a new feature. In particular, players can now preview equipment skins from the in-game store. Bugs related to tracked challenges and the customization menu have been fixed, too.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="1590508000" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6463699,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Modern%20Warfare%20III%2C%20Warzone%2C%20%26%20Warzone%20Mobile%20-%20Cross%20Progression%20Trailer&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:37,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/modern-warfare-iii-warzone-warzone-mobile-cross-progression-trailer\/2300-6463699\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6463699\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6463699\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6463699\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6463699&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;Publisher Asset&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4276766-33.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/G4Jzi50z.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1711034580,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="G4Jzi50z" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> Modern Warfare III, Warzone, &amp; Warzone Mobile - Cross Progression Trailer</p>
      </div>
<p>On the Derail map, this newest patch fixes an issue that allowed players to access the blue train car when they should not have been able to. For the Enhanced Vision Goggles field upgrade, players no longer need to unequip the goggles when the battery dies. Instead, player vision is blurred.</p><p>There are weapon changes, too. The DG-58 LSW machine gun has its hand-damage multipliers reduced from 1.1x to 1x. The COR-45 handgun has now been fixed so players cannot fire faster than intended.</p><p>For Warzone, weapon prestige camos are now supported for Modern Warfare II weapons. There are bug fixes, too. In particular, players previously could not enter a vehicle when using the biometric scanner, but now they can. The Call of Duty Endowment challenge has been fixed, too, to address snapshot grenade issues.</p><p>You can see the full patch notes for Warzone and Modern Warfare III below, as shared by Activision on the <a href="https://www.callofduty.com/patchnotes/2024/04/call-of-duty-modern-warfare-iii-season-3-patch-notes" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Call of Duty patch notes website.</a></p><h2>Call of Duty: Warzone patch notes</h2><h2>PROGRESSION</h2><ul><li>Weapon Prestige Camos can now be unlocked for MWII Weapons.</li></ul><h2>WEAPONS</h2><h4>MARKSMAN RIFLES</h4><p>WEAPON</p><h3>LOCKWOOD MK2 (MWII)</h3><ul><li><b>JAK Wardens Conversion Kit</b><ul><li>Resolved an issue causing incompatible Attachments to remain equipped in the Gunsmith.</li></ul></li></ul><h4>HANDGUNS</h4><p>WEAPON</p><h3>COR-45</h3><ul><li>Implemented measures to prevent exploits that allow firing faster than intended.</li></ul><h4>» ATTACHMENTS «</h4><ul><li>Adjusted Pros and Cons for multiple Optic Attachments to reflect their true statistics.  <ul><li>Corio Enforcer Optic</li><li>Dragon’s Eye Optic</li><li>KR Marauder 9 Riser</li></ul></li></ul><h2>BUG FIXES</h2><ul><li>Fixed an issue preventing the Call of Duty Endowment challenge to track 20 operators using a Snapshot Grenade from tracking properly.</li></ul><ul><li>Fixed an issue allowing players to enter a vehicle while using the Biometric Scanner.</li></ul><h3>Call of Duty: Modern Warfare 3 multiplayer patch notes</h3><h3>UIX</h3><ul><li>Equipment Skins can now be previewed in the Store.</li><li>Bug Fixes  <ul><li>Tracked Challenges widget now accurately reflects progress toward Weapon Prestige Camos.</li><li>Locked Calling Cards earned via the current Season’s Battle Pass are now displayed in the Customization menu.</li><li>Locked/Unlocked filter for Calling Cards in the Customization menu now functions as expected.</li><li>Restored functionality of the Select / Deselect All button in the Quick Play menu.</li><li>EMP HUD effects no longer persist upon Wheelson-HS destruction via Stormender.</li></ul></li></ul><h3>GAMEPLAY</h3><ul><li>Resolved an issue causing Akimbo Weapons to be given less reserve ammo than intended following a map infiltration sequence.</li></ul><h3>PROGRESSION</h3><ul><li>Weapon Prestige Camos can now be unlocked for MWII Weapons.</li></ul><h3>MAPS</h3><ul><li>Derail  <ul><li>Added collision to prevent an exploit that allowed players to get in the blue train car near the Crossing area.</li></ul></li></ul><h3>MODES</h3><ul><li>Arcade  <ul><li>EOD Padding no longer reduces incoming explosive damage by power Weapons.</li></ul></li><li>Infected  <ul><li>Blank Perk icons are no longer shown on the HUD upon spawning as a survivor.</li></ul></li><li>One in the Chamber  <ul><li>Weapon Match Stats section of the After-Action Report is no longer empty upon completing a match.</li></ul></li></ul><h3>WEAPONS &amp; ATTACHMENTS</h3><p>Light Machine Guns</p><ul><li>DG-58 LSW  <ul><li>Decreased neck, torso, arm, and hand damage multipliers from 1.1x to 1x.</li></ul></li></ul><p>Marksman Rifles</p><ul><li>Lockwood Mk2  <ul><li>JAK Wardens Conversion Kit  <ul><li>Resolved an issue causing incompatible Attachments to remain equipped in the Gunsmith.</li></ul></li></ul></li></ul><p>Handguns</p><ul><li>COR-45  <ul><li>Implemented measures to prevent exploits that allow firing faster than intended.</li></ul></li></ul><p>Attachments</p><ul><li>Adjusted Pros and Cons for multiple Optic Attachments to reflect their true statistics.  <ul><li>Corio Enforcer Optic</li><li>Dragon’s Eye Optic</li><li>KR Marauder 9 Riser</li></ul></li></ul><h3>PERKS</h3><ul><li>High-Gain Antenna (Gear)  <ul><li>Addressed an issue causing Equipment detected by allies with Signal Jammer not to appear indicated on the compass.</li></ul></li></ul><h3>EQUIPMENT</h3><ul><li>Scatter Mine (Tactical)  <ul><li>In Hardcore mode, players equipped with EOD Padding are no longer immune to stun effects.</li></ul></li></ul><h3>FIELD UPGRADES</h3><ul><li>Enhanced Vision Goggles  <ul><li>Player is no longer forced to unequip upon a dead battery, instead, vision is blurred until the goggles are manually removed.</li></ul></li></ul>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[10 Best Final Fantasy XIV seasonal events, ranked]]></title>
            <link>https://www.destructoid.com/best-ffxiv-seasonal-events-schedule/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=best-ffxiv-seasonal-events-schedule</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/10-best-final-fantasy-xiv-seasonal-events-ranked.870681/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.destructoid.com/best-ffxiv-seasonal-events-schedule/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=best-ffxiv-seasonal-events-schedule<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p data-characters="360" data-injectable="true" data-video="true">After more than a decade of celebrating Eorzea,<em> Final Fantasy XIV</em> has accumulated a lengthy calendar of recurring, limited-time events and a few that may be worth timing your sub renewals around. While they aren’t all bangers, with some <em>FFXIV</em> events more akin to an in-universe Fyre Festival, there’s far more good than bad on the yearly schedule. </p> <p data-characters="343" data-current-count="343" data-injectable="false">If you’re trying to prioritize which celebrations to hit, I’ve got a few favorites as personal picks for a top 10 list of best <em>Final Fantasy XIV</em> seasonal events. Some are for lore reasons, others are for glam or exclusivity. Regardless, it’s a place for Warriors of Light to begin planning out their own <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/ffxiv-event-calendar-seasonal-ongoing-and-announced/"><em>FFXIV </em>event calendar</a>.</p> <h2 data-injectable="false">10. The Maiden’s Rhapsody</h2> <figure data-wp-context="{ &quot;core&quot;: 				{ &quot;image&quot;: 					{   &quot;imageLoaded&quot;: false, 						&quot;initialized&quot;: false, 						&quot;lightboxEnabled&quot;: false, 						&quot;hideAnimationEnabled&quot;: false, 						&quot;preloadInitialized&quot;: false, 						&quot;lightboxAnimation&quot;: &quot;zoom&quot;, 						&quot;imageUploadedSrc&quot;: &quot;https://www.destructoid.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/FFXIV-FF14-FFXI-FF11-Crossover-Event.png&quot;, 						&quot;imageCurrentSrc&quot;: &quot;&quot;, 						&quot;targetWidth&quot;: &quot;2563&quot;, 						&quot;targetHeight&quot;: &quot;1455&quot;, 						&quot;scaleAttr&quot;: &quot;&quot;, 						&quot;dialogLabel&quot;: &quot;Enlarged image&quot; 					} 				} 			}" data-wp-interactive="" data-current-count="643" data-injectable="true"><figcaption>Memoro de la Ŝtono (Screenshot by Destructoid)</figcaption> <div data-wp-body="" data-wp-bind--role="selectors.core.image.roleAttribute" data-wp-bind--aria-label="selectors.core.image.dialogLabel" data-wp-class--initialized="context.core.image.initialized" data-wp-class--active="context.core.image.lightboxEnabled" data-wp-class--hideanimationenabled="context.core.image.hideAnimationEnabled" data-wp-bind--aria-modal="selectors.core.image.ariaModal" data-wp-effect="effects.core.image.initLightbox" data-wp-on--keydown="actions.core.image.handleKeydown" data-wp-on--touchstart="actions.core.image.handleTouchStart" data-wp-on--touchmove="actions.core.image.handleTouchMove" data-wp-on--touchend="actions.core.image.handleTouchEnd" data-wp-on--click="actions.core.image.hideLightbox" tabindex="-1"> <p> <figure><figcaption>Memoro de la Ŝtono (Screenshot by Destructoid)</figcaption></figure> </p> <p> <figure><figcaption>Memoro de la Ŝtono (Screenshot by Destructoid)</figcaption></figure> </p>  </div></figure>
 <p data-characters="375" data-current-count="375" data-injectable="false">While <em>FFXIV’s</em> Version 1.0 disaster launch remains talked about to this day, there’s a better, happier origin story for <em>Final Fantasy’s</em> roots in the MMO space thanks to <em>Final Fantasy XI</em>. In honor of that legacy, the <em>FFXIV </em>event for its older online sibling, The Maiden’s Rhapsody, revisits the<em> Final Fantasy XI: Rhapsodies of Vana’diel</em> scenario. </p> <p data-characters="450" data-current-count="825" data-injectable="true">The <em>FFXI </em>questline bookends Vana’diel’s story with chief priestess Iroha, and in the <em>FFXIV </em>collaboration event, we learn more about her adventures and how she stumbled into Eorzea. You aren’t going to stuff over a decade’s worth of history from the eleventh game into a brief crossover, but it’s packed with nods to the classic MMO that make it a poignant, even nostalgic, event for those both familiar and unfamiliar. </p>
 <p data-characters="238" data-current-count="238" data-injectable="false">It’s not often this one rolls around, so check it out when you see The Maiden’s Rhapsody pop up on the<em> FFXIV</em> schedule. If not for the beautiful ode to online<em> Final Fantasy</em> of yore, then at least do it for the Amatsu gear set. </p> <h2 data-injectable="false">9. A Nocturne for Heroes</h2> <figure data-current-count="538" data-injectable="true"><figcaption>Great Value Noctis. (Screenshot by Destructoid)</figcaption></figure>
 <p data-characters="340" data-current-count="340" data-injectable="false">Alright, for the sake of honesty — I don’t<em> like </em>this event or the tasks involved. Noctis desperately needs that <em>Dawntrail</em> facelift, he looks a little too much like just some Hyur wearing the ‘fit. That said, I love the horrendous car mount, the Regalia Type-G, that <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/ffxiv-ffxv-crossover-event-returns-february-28-with-regaila-car-mou/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>FFXIV’s </em>A Nocturne for Heroes</a> crossover event rewards.</p> <p data-characters="387" data-current-count="727" data-injectable="true">Regardless of how you or I feel about <em>Final Fantasy XV</em> and its bizarre we-have-Noctis-at-home NPC, the mount is a neat, limited-time ride that seats you and three friends. It could really use an obnoxious horn for full effect, but the Regalia and the other <em>FFXV</em>-inspired goodies (Noctis glamour and Orchestrion rolls) make for a fairly generous affair as far as <em>FFXIV’s</em> events go. </p>
 <h2 data-injectable="false">8. Make it Rain Campaign</h2> <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"><figcaption>The /Gratuity emote. (Screenshot by Destructoid)</figcaption></figure> <p data-characters="117" data-current-count="417" data-injectable="true">There has never been a better time to monotonously slap the Cuff-a-Cur machine than during the Make it Rain campaign.</p>
 <p data-characters="413" data-current-count="413" data-injectable="true">There’s one other event on this list that’s probably more efficient for grinding MGP, but I won’t say no to another opportunity. With every year’s celebration of the<em> FFXIV</em> Gold Saucer, the mini-game hub gets a +50% increase to MGP rewards earned through the usual activities. The event also discounts some items that typically cost way more in MGP, so you can make the most of your gains. </p>
 <p data-characters="469" data-current-count="469" data-injectable="true">Even if not for the MGP grinding, it’s a favorite of mine just for the exclusive rewards. I’ve regularly used the Show Left and Show Right emotes to celebrate friends’ in-game achievements for the last couple of years now, and the event also introduced another beloved hairstyle, the Rainmaker. Ask your post-<em>Stormblood </em>era friends about how annoying it was they missed out on that one, until Square Enix mercifully added the up-do again years later. </p>
 <h2 data-injectable="false">7. The Path Infernal</h2> <figure data-wp-context="{ &quot;core&quot;: 				{ &quot;image&quot;: 					{   &quot;imageLoaded&quot;: false, 						&quot;initialized&quot;: false, 						&quot;lightboxEnabled&quot;: false, 						&quot;hideAnimationEnabled&quot;: false, 						&quot;preloadInitialized&quot;: false, 						&quot;lightboxAnimation&quot;: &quot;zoom&quot;, 						&quot;imageUploadedSrc&quot;: &quot;https://www.destructoid.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/FFXIV_FF14_FFXVI_Crossover_Collab_Event_Torgal_Minion.png&quot;, 						&quot;imageCurrentSrc&quot;: &quot;&quot;, 						&quot;targetWidth&quot;: &quot;1920&quot;, 						&quot;targetHeight&quot;: &quot;1080&quot;, 						&quot;scaleAttr&quot;: &quot;&quot;, 						&quot;dialogLabel&quot;: &quot;Enlarged image&quot; 					} 				} 			}" data-wp-interactive="" data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"><figcaption>A catgirl’s best friend. (Screenshot by Destructoid)</figcaption> <div data-wp-body="" data-wp-bind--role="selectors.core.image.roleAttribute" data-wp-bind--aria-label="selectors.core.image.dialogLabel" data-wp-class--initialized="context.core.image.initialized" data-wp-class--active="context.core.image.lightboxEnabled" data-wp-class--hideanimationenabled="context.core.image.hideAnimationEnabled" data-wp-bind--aria-modal="selectors.core.image.ariaModal" data-wp-effect="effects.core.image.initLightbox" data-wp-on--keydown="actions.core.image.handleKeydown" data-wp-on--touchstart="actions.core.image.handleTouchStart" data-wp-on--touchmove="actions.core.image.handleTouchMove" data-wp-on--touchend="actions.core.image.handleTouchEnd" data-wp-on--click="actions.core.image.hideLightbox" tabindex="-1"> <p> <figure><figcaption>A catgirl’s best friend. (Screenshot by Destructoid)</figcaption></figure> </p> <p> <figure><figcaption>A catgirl’s best friend. (Screenshot by Destructoid)</figcaption></figure> </p>  </div></figure> <p data-characters="465" data-current-count="765" data-injectable="true">It’s another event I’m not super keen on the activity or in-universe explainers (like <em>FFXV</em>), but I can’t deny I was among those sprinting to complete the questline on day one for the rewards. The Path Infernal is <em>FFXIV’s </em>crossover with <em>Final Fantasy XVI,</em> and not only does it give you Torgal as a big ole boy to use a mount, but it also rewards a tiny, sweet baby Torgal as a minion. That’s two good boys for maybe a half-hour of work.</p>
 <p data-characters="317" data-current-count="317" data-injectable="false">There’s also the Clive glamour set, and it’s cool and all, but it doesn’t get much better than giving my catgirl two dog best friends. Honestly, I’m not even sure I could tell you the plot of the whole thing. I remember more from the <em>FFXI </em>crossover, but that little guy follows me everywhere. </p> <h2 data-injectable="false">6. Yo-Kai Watch: Gather One, Gather All!</h2> <figure data-wp-context="{ &quot;core&quot;: 				{ &quot;image&quot;: 					{   &quot;imageLoaded&quot;: false, 						&quot;initialized&quot;: false, 						&quot;lightboxEnabled&quot;: false, 						&quot;hideAnimationEnabled&quot;: false, 						&quot;preloadInitialized&quot;: false, 						&quot;lightboxAnimation&quot;: &quot;zoom&quot;, 						&quot;imageUploadedSrc&quot;: &quot;https://www.destructoid.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/FFXIV_Yokai_Watch_Event_Mount.png&quot;, 						&quot;imageCurrentSrc&quot;: &quot;&quot;, 						&quot;targetWidth&quot;: &quot;1920&quot;, 						&quot;targetHeight&quot;: &quot;1080&quot;, 						&quot;scaleAttr&quot;: &quot;&quot;, 						&quot;dialogLabel&quot;: &quot;Enlarged image&quot; 					} 				} 			}" data-wp-interactive="" data-current-count="617" data-injectable="true"><figcaption>I don’t go here, but I love Jibanyan. (Screenshot by Destructoid)</figcaption> <div data-wp-body="" data-wp-bind--role="selectors.core.image.roleAttribute" data-wp-bind--aria-label="selectors.core.image.dialogLabel" data-wp-class--initialized="context.core.image.initialized" data-wp-class--active="context.core.image.lightboxEnabled" data-wp-class--hideanimationenabled="context.core.image.hideAnimationEnabled" data-wp-bind--aria-modal="selectors.core.image.ariaModal" data-wp-effect="effects.core.image.initLightbox" data-wp-on--keydown="actions.core.image.handleKeydown" data-wp-on--touchstart="actions.core.image.handleTouchStart" data-wp-on--touchmove="actions.core.image.handleTouchMove" data-wp-on--touchend="actions.core.image.handleTouchEnd" data-wp-on--click="actions.core.image.hideLightbox" tabindex="-1"> <p> <figure><figcaption>I don’t go here, but I love Jibanyan. (Screenshot by Destructoid)</figcaption></figure> </p> <p> <figure><figcaption>I don’t go here, but I love Jibanyan. (Screenshot by Destructoid)</figcaption></figure> </p>  </div></figure>
 <p data-characters="389" data-current-count="389" data-injectable="false">Depending on when you ask me, the <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/how-to-get-every-ffxiv-yokai-watch-reward/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>FFXIV</em> and <em>Yo-Kai Watch</em> </a>collaboration event is either the bane of my existence, or it’s the coolest crossover the game has ever had. Since I’m done with it, and only had to grab the new Framer’s Kit this time around in <em>Endwalker</em>, I’ve got a more tame response. It’s good; it’s not my favorite event, but it’s good.</p> <p data-characters="400" data-current-count="789" data-injectable="true">Before the days of an abundance of rampaging Blue Mages, I ground out its original offerings and<em> hated</em> it. In hindsight, I didn’t have to go that damn hard, and offering so many glamour weapons, minions, and mounts from one seasonal event is not <em>FFXIV’s</em> usual affair. It’s definitely one of the things that make the<em> FFXV </em>and<em> Yo-Kai Watch</em> events better than they would be otherwise. </p>
 <p data-characters="452" data-current-count="452" data-injectable="true">Ultimately, if you’re like me and all done or you just don’t care, it’s still a benefit. The hordes of folks always FATE-grinding in the event zones is nice if you’re working on older Relic weapons or even just achievement hunting. I managed to clean up the last of my <em>Heavensward</em> relic checklist thanks to this round of participants, and I’m hoping it’ll return again in <em>Dawntrail</em> with weapons for Sage and Reaper. </p>
 <h2 data-injectable="false">5. Moonfire Faire</h2> <figure data-wp-context="{ &quot;core&quot;: 				{ &quot;image&quot;: 					{   &quot;imageLoaded&quot;: false, 						&quot;initialized&quot;: false, 						&quot;lightboxEnabled&quot;: false, 						&quot;hideAnimationEnabled&quot;: false, 						&quot;preloadInitialized&quot;: false, 						&quot;lightboxAnimation&quot;: &quot;zoom&quot;, 						&quot;imageUploadedSrc&quot;: &quot;https://www.destructoid.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/FFXIV_Moonfire_Faire_2023.png&quot;, 						&quot;imageCurrentSrc&quot;: &quot;&quot;, 						&quot;targetWidth&quot;: &quot;1980&quot;, 						&quot;targetHeight&quot;: &quot;963&quot;, 						&quot;scaleAttr&quot;: &quot;&quot;, 						&quot;dialogLabel&quot;: &quot;Enlarged image&quot; 					} 				} 			}" data-wp-interactive="" data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"><figcaption>This counts as flirting. (Screenshot by Destructoid)</figcaption> <div data-wp-body="" data-wp-bind--role="selectors.core.image.roleAttribute" data-wp-bind--aria-label="selectors.core.image.dialogLabel" data-wp-class--initialized="context.core.image.initialized" data-wp-class--active="context.core.image.lightboxEnabled" data-wp-class--hideanimationenabled="context.core.image.hideAnimationEnabled" data-wp-bind--aria-modal="selectors.core.image.ariaModal" data-wp-effect="effects.core.image.initLightbox" data-wp-on--keydown="actions.core.image.handleKeydown" data-wp-on--touchstart="actions.core.image.handleTouchStart" data-wp-on--touchmove="actions.core.image.handleTouchMove" data-wp-on--touchend="actions.core.image.handleTouchEnd" data-wp-on--click="actions.core.image.hideLightbox" tabindex="-1"> <p> <figure><figcaption>This counts as flirting. (Screenshot by Destructoid)</figcaption></figure> </p> <p> <figure><figcaption>This counts as flirting. (Screenshot by Destructoid)</figcaption></figure> </p>  </div></figure> <p data-characters="274" data-current-count="574" data-injectable="true">For someone who claims to hate jump puzzles so much, I sure spend a lot of time skulking about the Moonfire Faire. I’ve played FFXIV 2.0 since beta, but this one is among the few seasonal events that I’ve never missed thanks to a brief break or just forgetting. </p>
 <p data-characters="473" data-current-count="473" data-injectable="true">And while I do love suiting up in a swimsuit before loading into the cutscene where it’s the Scions versus God, I’m really all about the Moonfire Faire because of the Eorzean Nimble Warrior obstacle course. It first debuted in 2018, but ever since then, I’ve jumped at every opportunity to race friends and strangers to the top. Perhaps it’s the limited nature, but it’s the only puzzle like it in the game that doesn’t make me see red. </p>
 <p data-characters="275" data-current-count="275" data-injectable="false">Also, the 2023 Moonfire Faire, referenced in the image above, gave us Sicard and Emmanellain bickering on the side of the obstacle course. I don’t know how long I spent watching Emmanellain just hang there, wondering if Sicard would ever help him up (he doesn’t).</p> <h2 data-injectable="false">4. Starlight Celebration</h2> <figure data-wp-context="{ &quot;core&quot;: 				{ &quot;image&quot;: 					{   &quot;imageLoaded&quot;: false, 						&quot;initialized&quot;: false, 						&quot;lightboxEnabled&quot;: false, 						&quot;hideAnimationEnabled&quot;: false, 						&quot;preloadInitialized&quot;: false, 						&quot;lightboxAnimation&quot;: &quot;zoom&quot;, 						&quot;imageUploadedSrc&quot;: &quot;https://www.destructoid.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/FFXIV_Starlight_Festival_Event_Glamour_2023_2024_Seasonal.jpg&quot;, 						&quot;imageCurrentSrc&quot;: &quot;&quot;, 						&quot;targetWidth&quot;: &quot;1920&quot;, 						&quot;targetHeight&quot;: &quot;1147&quot;, 						&quot;scaleAttr&quot;: &quot;&quot;, 						&quot;dialogLabel&quot;: &quot;Enlarged image&quot; 					} 				} 			}" data-wp-interactive="" data-current-count="575" data-injectable="true"><figcaption>Ignore the cat ears, she’s a reindeer. (Screenshot by Destructoid)</figcaption> <div data-wp-body="" data-wp-bind--role="selectors.core.image.roleAttribute" data-wp-bind--aria-label="selectors.core.image.dialogLabel" data-wp-class--initialized="context.core.image.initialized" data-wp-class--active="context.core.image.lightboxEnabled" data-wp-class--hideanimationenabled="context.core.image.hideAnimationEnabled" data-wp-bind--aria-modal="selectors.core.image.ariaModal" data-wp-effect="effects.core.image.initLightbox" data-wp-on--keydown="actions.core.image.handleKeydown" data-wp-on--touchstart="actions.core.image.handleTouchStart" data-wp-on--touchmove="actions.core.image.handleTouchMove" data-wp-on--touchend="actions.core.image.handleTouchEnd" data-wp-on--click="actions.core.image.hideLightbox" tabindex="-1"> <p> <figure><figcaption>Ignore the cat ears, she’s a reindeer. (Screenshot by Destructoid)</figcaption></figure> </p> <p> <figure><figcaption>Ignore the cat ears, she’s a reindeer. (Screenshot by Destructoid)</figcaption></figure> </p>  </div></figure>
 <p data-characters="505" data-current-count="505" data-injectable="true"><em>Final Fantasy XIV’s </em>first expansion introducing the city-state of Ishgard ushered in an era of ‘peace’ with the conclusion of the Dragonsong War, and the nation’s citizens learning to live alongside dragonkind. But the war was just one front of the country’s real cruelty, and the Starlight Festival —<em> Final Fantasy’s</em> equivalent of the winter holidays — is borne from a handful of Temple Knights’ decision to ignore authority and do what they see as right. </p>
 <p data-characters="483" data-current-count="483" data-injectable="true">In an era of Eorzea long before our own and in the midst of war, all of the violence left a staggering amount of Ishgard’s children orphaned. While the Holy See forbade its knights from caring for them, some soldiers began hiding orphans in their oversized uniforms and sneaking them into their barracks. It kept the children safe during harsh months of deadly cold. Those who survived thanks to a brave few, celebrated the knights from then on with the Starlight Celebration. </p>
 <p data-characters="349" data-current-count="349" data-injectable="false">The seasonal event spends most of its time handing out Santa-inspired outfits or cutesy mounts, but the backstory still comes up in its yearly celebration. You can also find references to those involved in the Firmament questline and lore book series. It’s one of my favorite little lore tidbits that seems to pay off a little more every year.</p> <h2 data-injectable="false">3. All Saints’ Wake</h2> <figure data-wp-context="{ &quot;core&quot;: 				{ &quot;image&quot;: 					{   &quot;imageLoaded&quot;: false, 						&quot;initialized&quot;: false, 						&quot;lightboxEnabled&quot;: false, 						&quot;hideAnimationEnabled&quot;: false, 						&quot;preloadInitialized&quot;: false, 						&quot;lightboxAnimation&quot;: &quot;zoom&quot;, 						&quot;imageUploadedSrc&quot;: &quot;https://www.destructoid.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/FFXIV_All_Saints_Wake.png&quot;, 						&quot;imageCurrentSrc&quot;: &quot;&quot;, 						&quot;targetWidth&quot;: &quot;1893&quot;, 						&quot;targetHeight&quot;: &quot;1065&quot;, 						&quot;scaleAttr&quot;: &quot;&quot;, 						&quot;dialogLabel&quot;: &quot;Enlarged image&quot; 					} 				} 			}" data-wp-interactive="" data-current-count="649" data-injectable="true"><figcaption> (Screenshot by Destructoid)</figcaption> <div data-wp-body="" data-wp-bind--role="selectors.core.image.roleAttribute" data-wp-bind--aria-label="selectors.core.image.dialogLabel" data-wp-class--initialized="context.core.image.initialized" data-wp-class--active="context.core.image.lightboxEnabled" data-wp-class--hideanimationenabled="context.core.image.hideAnimationEnabled" data-wp-bind--aria-modal="selectors.core.image.ariaModal" data-wp-effect="effects.core.image.initLightbox" data-wp-on--keydown="actions.core.image.handleKeydown" data-wp-on--touchstart="actions.core.image.handleTouchStart" data-wp-on--touchmove="actions.core.image.handleTouchMove" data-wp-on--touchend="actions.core.image.handleTouchEnd" data-wp-on--click="actions.core.image.hideLightbox" tabindex="-1"> <p> <figure><figcaption> (Screenshot by Destructoid)</figcaption></figure> </p> <p> <figure><figcaption> (Screenshot by Destructoid)</figcaption></figure> </p>  </div></figure>
 <p data-characters="416" data-current-count="416" data-injectable="true">Halloween is my favorite real-life celebration, and that easily translates into<em> FFXIV </em>with the yearly All Saints’ Wake festivities. I’ve always enjoyed just about every mount, minion, glamour, and spooky-themed furnishing Square Enix releases for the occasion, but I’m mostly here for the opportunity to take <em>a lot</em> of screenshots of Estinien, Aymeric, and Y’shtola doing Hydaelyn-knows-what. </p>
 <p data-characters="417" data-current-count="417" data-injectable="true">If you’ve got no idea what I’m talking about, then, man, you’ve been missing out on what is arguably the best feature in this whole shindig. I’m only half-kidding, but the All Saints’ Wake celebration typically includes access to an instanced area, The Haunted Manor, where players can transform into their favorite <em>FFXIV</em> characters and control them just as they would their own avatar. </p>
 <p data-characters="250" data-current-count="250" data-injectable="false">Look, I’m not gonna make generalizations about everyone with the Gpose icon above their heads inside the Haunted Manor, but also, the NPC that transforms you is called “The Unsavory Imp.” There’s no good that comes from that. </p> <h2 id="h-2-the-moogle-treasure-trove" data-injectable="false">2. The Moogle Treasure Trove</h2> <figure data-wp-context="{ &quot;core&quot;: 				{ &quot;image&quot;: 					{   &quot;imageLoaded&quot;: false, 						&quot;initialized&quot;: false, 						&quot;lightboxEnabled&quot;: false, 						&quot;hideAnimationEnabled&quot;: false, 						&quot;preloadInitialized&quot;: false, 						&quot;lightboxAnimation&quot;: &quot;zoom&quot;, 						&quot;imageUploadedSrc&quot;: &quot;https://www.destructoid.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/FFXIV_Final_Fantasy_XIV_Moogle_Tomestone_Event_Farming_2023_Guide.png&quot;, 						&quot;imageCurrentSrc&quot;: &quot;&quot;, 						&quot;targetWidth&quot;: &quot;1200&quot;, 						&quot;targetHeight&quot;: &quot;675&quot;, 						&quot;scaleAttr&quot;: &quot;&quot;, 						&quot;dialogLabel&quot;: &quot;Enlarged image&quot; 					} 				} 			}" data-wp-interactive="" data-current-count="550" data-injectable="true"><figcaption> (Screenshot by Destructoid)</figcaption> <div data-wp-body="" data-wp-bind--role="selectors.core.image.roleAttribute" data-wp-bind--aria-label="selectors.core.image.dialogLabel" data-wp-class--initialized="context.core.image.initialized" data-wp-class--active="context.core.image.lightboxEnabled" data-wp-class--hideanimationenabled="context.core.image.hideAnimationEnabled" data-wp-bind--aria-modal="selectors.core.image.ariaModal" data-wp-effect="effects.core.image.initLightbox" data-wp-on--keydown="actions.core.image.handleKeydown" data-wp-on--touchstart="actions.core.image.handleTouchStart" data-wp-on--touchmove="actions.core.image.handleTouchMove" data-wp-on--touchend="actions.core.image.handleTouchEnd" data-wp-on--click="actions.core.image.hideLightbox" tabindex="-1"> <p> <figure><figcaption> (Screenshot by Destructoid)</figcaption></figure> </p> <p> <figure><figcaption> (Screenshot by Destructoid)</figcaption></figure> </p>  </div></figure>
 <p data-characters="404" data-current-count="404" data-injectable="true">The Moogle Treasure Trove is <em>FFXIV’s</em> usual filler activity between big patches, and every iteration brings a new, lengthy list of rewards that are (typically) a little harder to score. It’s a good time to avoid old Extreme Trial mount grinds and just earn the respective mount through here. Plus, there’s often an exclusive glam reward, like the Mameshiba Neckerchief or Inferno Jacket.</p>
 <p data-characters="496" data-current-count="496" data-injectable="true">All of that’s cool and all, but I’m just here for the MGP. “You should wait for the Moogle Treasure Trove event,” remains my guiding principle for Gold Saucer currency grinding. I know I wrote a whole guide on <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/best-way-to-get-mgp-ffxiv/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">farming MGP</a> without it, and it’s all solid advice, but I typically just wait for The Moogle Treasure Trove’s unlimited MGP Platinum Card rewards. It’s 50,000 MGP per card, and if you’re diligent, one cycle of this event can net millions. </p>
 <h2 data-injectable="false">1. The Rising</h2> <figure data-wp-context="{ &quot;core&quot;: 				{ &quot;image&quot;: 					{   &quot;imageLoaded&quot;: false, 						&quot;initialized&quot;: false, 						&quot;lightboxEnabled&quot;: false, 						&quot;hideAnimationEnabled&quot;: false, 						&quot;preloadInitialized&quot;: false, 						&quot;lightboxAnimation&quot;: &quot;zoom&quot;, 						&quot;imageUploadedSrc&quot;: &quot;https://www.destructoid.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/FFXIV_The_Rising_Wandering_Minstrel_Event.png&quot;, 						&quot;imageCurrentSrc&quot;: &quot;&quot;, 						&quot;targetWidth&quot;: &quot;2115&quot;, 						&quot;targetHeight&quot;: &quot;1190&quot;, 						&quot;scaleAttr&quot;: &quot;&quot;, 						&quot;dialogLabel&quot;: &quot;Enlarged image&quot; 					} 				} 			}" data-wp-interactive="" data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"><figcaption>(Screenshot by Destructoid)</figcaption> <div data-wp-body="" data-wp-bind--role="selectors.core.image.roleAttribute" data-wp-bind--aria-label="selectors.core.image.dialogLabel" data-wp-class--initialized="context.core.image.initialized" data-wp-class--active="context.core.image.lightboxEnabled" data-wp-class--hideanimationenabled="context.core.image.hideAnimationEnabled" data-wp-bind--aria-modal="selectors.core.image.ariaModal" data-wp-effect="effects.core.image.initLightbox" data-wp-on--keydown="actions.core.image.handleKeydown" data-wp-on--touchstart="actions.core.image.handleTouchStart" data-wp-on--touchmove="actions.core.image.handleTouchMove" data-wp-on--touchend="actions.core.image.handleTouchEnd" data-wp-on--click="actions.core.image.hideLightbox" tabindex="-1"> <p> <figure><figcaption>(Screenshot by Destructoid)</figcaption></figure> </p> <p> <figure><figcaption>(Screenshot by Destructoid)</figcaption></figure> </p>  </div></figure> <p data-characters="377" data-current-count="677" data-injectable="true">The Rising is<em> FFXIV’s</em> annual tribute to those lost in the Seventh Umbral Calamity; you know the one. It’s the big cutscene featuring the Battle of Cartenau, where Louisoix Leveilleur and countless others gave their lives to protect Eorzea from Dalamud’s cataclysmic collision with the continent. I’ve teared up every time I’ve watched that scene. </p>
 <p data-characters="504" data-current-count="504" data-injectable="true">And if there’s one thing to always know about me, it’s that I’m gonna cry. Just like the Starlight Festival and the <em>Final Fantasy XI</em> tribute, The Rising gets me sniffling and snotting. The 2022 and 2023 events, in particular, had me blubbering, as the Warrior of Light welcomed a brand new adventurer to Ul’dah, offering a more meta look at the beginning of someone else’s journey in the MMO. I laughed, I cried, and, more importantly, made that screenshot button work hard.</p>
 <blockquote data-current-count="493" data-injectable="true"> <div><p>Your life is a riddle, to bear gladness and grief,<br>‘Neath stars and through storms, the answers to seek.</p><p>Your footprints are threads, to be gathered and woven,<br>A song of dawn resplendent, dancing high to heavens.</p><p>From the embrace of the gods though mankind has been torn,<br>Upon winds eternal lives and memories are borne.</p><p>The future is unwritten, bring it rapture or sorrow,<br>Our journey shall continue, unto tomorrow and tomorrow.</p></div> <cite>The Wandering Minstrel in The Rising, 2022</cite></blockquote>
 <p data-characters="536" data-current-count="536" data-injectable="false">For me, The Rising gets personal as a chance to reflect on some of the special connections and friendships I’ve made thanks to more than a decade in <em>FFXIV</em>. It’s also a moment to think on how much I’ve changed since I started playing, how much my life has changed. The wink-wink nature of the Wandering Minstrel, Yoshida’s in-universe avatar, is often packing a thoughtful and poetic gut punch. As a Bard, he’s always got a new tale to share through song, plus a few words of wisdom for your next adventure.</p>

<hr>
<p><i data-stringify-type="italic"> Destructoid is supported by our audience. When you purchase through links on our site, we may earn a small affiliate commission.&nbsp;</i><i data-stringify-type="italic"><a href="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-stringify-link="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" data-sk="tooltip_parent">Learn more</a></i> </p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Some of Warzone’s most dominant players may have found their third in another champion]]></title>
            <link>https://www.destructoid.com/some-of-warzones-most-dominant-players-may-have-found-their-third-in-another-champion/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=some-of-warzones-most-dominant-players-may-have-found-their-third-in-another-champion</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/some-of-warzone%E2%80%99s-most-dominant-players-may-have-found-their-third-in-another-champion.870678/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.destructoid.com/some-of-warzones-most-dominant-players-may-have-found-their-third-in-another-champion/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=some-of-warzones-most-dominant-players-may-have-found-their-third-in-another-champion<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p data-characters="278" data-injectable="true" data-video="true">One trio – Shifty, DiazBiffle, and Sage – dominated <em>Warzone’s</em> competitive scene in 2023, until the departure of Sage earlier this year. The remaining duo might have already found their third though, adding one of the most decorated players in <em>Warzone</em> history. </p> <p data-characters="321" data-current-count="321" data-injectable="false">On April 11, Sage <a href="https://x.com/aqSage/status/1778275186455765345" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">stepped away</a> from OMiTGG and stopped competing in <em>Warzone</em>, leaving Shifty and DiazBiffle without a teammate despite previously winning the 2023 WSOW Global Final in dominant fashion. In Sage’s absence, the remaining duo went out and made a huge splash by landing Tommey as a potential replacement.</p> <p data-characters="397" data-current-count="718" data-injectable="true">Tommey is currently the <a href="https://warzoneearnings.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">highest-earning<em> Warzone</em> player of all time</a>, and previously spent 10 years as a professional <em>CoD </em>player. Last season, Tommey placed third at the 2023 WSOW Global Final, won the Stage 2 Final, and placed second in the Stage 1 Final. Looking at their stacked resumes, it should come as no surprise that this new squad found immediate success in its first official tournament. </p>
 <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"><figcaption>Image via Activision</figcaption></figure> <p data-characters="252" data-current-count="552" data-injectable="true">In the Oh Mama $30,000 tournament, the trio finished second and received an extra cash prize for getting the highest kills game. Ironically, the squad that came in first was Tommey’s former teammates Almxnd and Newbz, with replacement HisokaT42. </p>
 <p data-characters="426" data-current-count="426" data-injectable="false">This won’t be the last time these two stacked trios go head to head at the top of leaderboards, and it sets up a compelling rivalry moving forward. Based on previous years, the WSOW usually tends to start in June. If the competition uses the same format for 2024, and this new trio of Tommey, Biffle, and Shifty decide to stick it out, we could be in store for an electrifying head-to-head matchup on the biggest stage. </p>

<hr>
<p><i data-stringify-type="italic"> Destructoid is supported by our audience. When you purchase through links on our site, we may earn a small affiliate commission.&nbsp;</i><i data-stringify-type="italic"><a href="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-stringify-link="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" data-sk="tooltip_parent">Learn more</a></i> </p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hades 2: Moon Dust resource guide – What it does and how to get more]]></title>
            <link>https://www.destructoid.com/hades-2-moon-dust-resource-guide-what-it-does-and-how-to-get-more/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=hades-2-moon-dust-resource-guide-what-it-does-and-how-to-get-more</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hades-2-moon-dust-resource-guide-%E2%80%93-what-it-does-and-how-to-get-more.870675/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.destructoid.com/hades-2-moon-dust-resource-guide-what-it-does-and-how-to-get-more/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=hades-2-moon-dust-resource-guide-what-it-does-and-how-to-get-more<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p data-characters="401" data-injectable="true" data-video="true">As you progress through the Arcana system in <em>Hades 2</em>, you may want to <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/how-to-activate-arcana-xiii-the-centaur-in-hades-2/">get more out of certain Arcana</a>. While getting a single Death Defiance is nice, having more would be great, especially for some of the later, much more difficult levels. Thankfully, there is a way to do just that. Here’s a full guide on the Moon Dust resource in <em>Hades 2</em>, and how you can use it to get more out of your Arcana.</p> <h2 id="h-what-is-moon-dust-in-hades-2" data-injectable="false">What is Moon Dust in Hades 2?</h2> <p data-characters="388" data-current-count="388" data-injectable="false">Moon Dust is a resource unlocked via completing the Consecration of Ashes Incantation at the Incantation Cauldron. If this Incantation isn’t unlocked for you, you should progress through runs until it is mentioned by Hecate when fighting her. Once you unlock it and spend the resources, make your way to the Meditation location in the equipment room (where you select Arcana cards).</p> <figure data-current-count="688" data-injectable="true"><figcaption>Image via Destructoid.</figcaption></figure>
 <p data-characters="459" data-current-count="459" data-injectable="true">Here, you should see a new button you can press in the bottom-right of your screen to reveal Insights. Doing this changes the board and lets you upgrade individual Arcana using this Moon Dust resource. For example, upgrading The Titan Arcana card costs two Moon Dust, and increases the Max Life and Max Magick values from 20 to 30. Each Arcana card has a different Moon Dust cost, with later Arcana upgrades requiring additional resources alongside Moon Dust.</p>
 <h3 id="h-how-to-get-moon-dust" data-injectable="false">How to get Moon Dust</h3> <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"><figcaption>Image via Destructoid.</figcaption></figure> <p data-characters="758" data-current-count="1058" data-injectable="true">There are three main ways to get Moon Dust in <em>Hades 2</em>. The first, and easiest, is to <strong>visit the Wretched Broker</strong> in the Crossroads. Here, you can purchase one Moon Dust for 80 Bones, <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/how-to-farm-bones-in-hades-2/">which are earned either through</a> completing Locations with Bone rewards or by bringing weapons with Grave Thirst applied to them (refer to the Incanatation Gathering of Ancient Bones). Alongside the Wretched Broker, you can spend Obol Points with the <strong>Gold Rewards chest </strong>next to the Wretched Broker. Spending four Obol Points will grant eight Moon Dust in 80 Whiles. The final method won’t come until much later but is the <strong>Moonlit Essence from Shadow recipe</strong> in the Incantation Cauldron. This costs one Shadow and one Cinder but will grant five Moon Dust after eight Whiles.</p>
 <p data-characters="225" data-current-count="225" data-injectable="false">If you want to hard focus one of these, then focusing the Bones for the Wretched Broker is your best bet. It’ll also give you the chance to try out more of the weapon roster, and who doesn’t like a little variety?</p>

<hr>
<p><i data-stringify-type="italic"> Destructoid is supported by our audience. When you purchase through links on our site, we may earn a small affiliate commission.&nbsp;</i><i data-stringify-type="italic"><a href="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-stringify-link="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" data-sk="tooltip_parent">Learn more</a></i> </p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sony Names Two PlayStation CEOs, Says PS5 Growth Is Likely Over]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/sony-names-two-playstation-ceos-says-ps5-growth-is-likely-over/1100-6523439/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sony-names-two-playstation-ceos-says-ps5-growth-is-likely-over.870642/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/sony-names-two-playstation-ceos-says-ps5-growth-is-likely-over/1100-6523439/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6523439">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>The PS5 might be outselling its chief competitor, but it seems that its overall sales have slowed in recent months. In a <a href="https://www.irwebmeeting.com/sony/fast/20240514/qF9kBTC8/202403_4q_02_en/index.html" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">recent financial report</a>, Sony said that PS5 sales are down 29% year-over-year in the last fiscal quarter, and it further expects PS5 sales to decrease to 18 million for the fiscal year 2024.</p><p dir="ltr">Sony narrowly missed its revised PS5 sales target of 21 million units sold for fiscal year 2023, with 20.8 million units sold. Needless to say, this means that Sony expects PS5 sales to continue to slow, a stark contrast from the pandemic-era shortages that defined the early years of the console.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="1256077119" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6463815,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Sea%20of%20Thieves%20PlayStation%205%20Feature%20Overview%3A%20Official%20Trailer&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:39,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/sea-of-thieves-playstation-5-feature-overview-official-trailer\/2300-6463815\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6463815\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6463815\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6463815\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6463815&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;Publisher Asset&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4283344-33.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/hhTM5ccO.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1712238360,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="hhTM5ccO" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> Sea of Thieves PlayStation 5 Feature Overview: Official Trailer</p>
      </div>
<p dir="ltr">Overall, Sony said that cumulative PS5 sales reached 59.2 million units, with 4.5 million units coming in the last quarter. It also noted the success of Helldivers 2 on both PC and PS5, as it sold 12 million copies.</p><p dir="ltr">In addition, Sony recently named two PlayStation CEOs in the wake of Jim Ryan's departure. Hideaki Nishino and Hermen Hulst will serve as joint CEOs, with Nishino heading up Sony Interactive Entertainment's Platform Business Group and Hulst leading the Studio Business group. The former is responsible for technology, products, the platform experience, and third-party developer relations, while the latter is responsible for all PlayStation game content and film/TV adaptations.</p><p dir="ltr">In February of this year, PlayStation cut <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/playstation-cutting-900-jobs-in-video-game-industrys-latest-round-of-big-cuts/1100-6521383/">roughly 900 jobs</a> as part of the ongoing wave of mass layoffs in the gaming industry, resulting in the cancellation of multiple projects, including a Twisted Metal live-service game (which wasn't actually greenlit yet). Sony recently named the unlikely smash hit Helldivers 2 as the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/helldivers-2-is-fastest-selling-playstation-game-ever/1100-6523423/">fastest-selling PlayStation game</a> ever after changing course on the game's PSN account requirement, which triggered a wide backlash.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Hades II Digital Issue Is Now Live!]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gameinformer.com/digital-issue/2024/05/14/the-hades-ii-digital-issue-is-now-live</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-hades-ii-digital-issue-is-now-live.870639/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gameinformer.com/digital-issue/2024/05/14/the-hades-ii-digital-issue-is-now-live<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p>If you subscribe to the digital edition of <em>Game Informer</em>, you can now learn all about our trip to Supergiant for Hades II! Following the <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/cover-reveal/2024/05/06/cover-reveal-the-making-of-hades-ii">cover reveal</a> our digital issue is now live on <a href="http://www.gameinformer.com/magazine" target="_blank">web browsers</a>, <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/game-informer/id526096699?mt=8" target="_blank">iPad/iPhone</a>, and <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.gameinformer.tablet&amp;hl=en_US" target="_blank">Android devices</a>.</p>

<p>Alongside our 12-page Hades II cover story, you will also find big features on our trip to Wizards of the Coast to learn all about what is next for Dungeons &amp; Dragons, how Digital Eclipse is conserving video game history with its documentary video games, details from our trip to South Korea to play The First Descendant, a feature about tracking down and playing a thought-lost Star Wars arcade cabinet, a piece on the history and current state of Final Fantasy XI, and lots more! We've also got previews for The Rogue Prince of Persia, Super Monkey Ball Banana Rumble, Kingdom Come: Deliverance II, Monaci 2, Still Wakes the Deep, Tales of the Shire, and reviews for Stellar Blade, Eiyuden Chronicles: Hundred Heroes, Sand Land, TopSpin 2K5, Tales of Kenzera: Zau, Animal Well, and much more!</p>

<p>If you love print as much as we do, you can subscribe to the <em>physical</em> magazine:</p>

<p><a href="https://subscription.gameinformer.com/">Subscribe Now</a></p>

<p>You get 10 issues for $19.91, or two years and 20 issues for $34.99. Individual issues are also now available <a href="https://www.gamestop.com/search/?q=gi+magazine&amp;lang=default">for purchase at this link</a> or in any GameStop store.</p>

<p>You can download the apps to read the issue <a href="http://www.gameinformer.com/magazine" target="_blank">by following this link</a>.</p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Halo Composer Running For Congress 'Intends To Win' Because He's A 'Gamer']]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/halo-composer-marty-odonnell-bungie-congress-gamer-win-1851476437</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/halo-composer-running-for-congress-intends-to-win-because-hes-a-gamer.870624/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/halo-composer-marty-odonnell-bungie-congress-gamer-win-1851476437<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>A few months ago, former Bungie composer Marty O’Donnell <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/destiny-halo-composer-marty-odonnell-nevada-congress-1851305880&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/destiny-halo-composer-marty-odonnell-nevada-congress-1851305880">announced he was running for Congress</a></span>. And in a new interview, the <em>Halo </em>and <em>Destiny</em> composer says he’ll succeed because he’s a “gamer” and also because, making <em>Halo 2</em> was harder than governing a nation. </p><div data-video-id="196917" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Halo’s Joseph Morgan On The Joys Of Halo Co-Op" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="96" data-playlist="196917,196909,195840" data-current="196917"><div><p>Halo’s Joseph Morgan On The Joys Of Halo Co-Op</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196917/196917_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196917/196917_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196917/196917_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196917/196917_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/22473.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><p> O’Donnell—<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/how-halo-and-destinys-composer-got-fired-from-bungie-1728943410&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/how-halo-and-destinys-composer-got-fired-from-bungie-1728943410">who was fired from Bungie in 2014</a></span>, leading to a lawsuit against the company—announced his campaign for the U.S. House of Representatives in March of this year. He’s running for in Nevada’s third congressional district as a Republican, challenging the current Democratic incumbent Susie Lee. Since his announcement, he’s done what you’d expect from a conservative politician, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://twitter.com/MartyTheElder/status/1764445788556665041&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://twitter.com/MartyTheElder/status/1764445788556665041" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">including blaming all our problems</a></span> on big government, “undocumented” immigrants, and a lack of <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://martyforcongress.vote/martys-platform/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://martyforcongress.vote/martys-platform/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">“old-fashioned family values.”</a></span> But don’t worry, he’s also keeping up with another important political tradition: providing bad and weird quotes in interviews.</p><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.theepochtimes.com/us/halo-composer-policy-maven-former-treasurer-among-gop-hopefuls-in-competitive-district-5648185&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.theepochtimes.com/us/halo-composer-policy-maven-former-treasurer-among-gop-hopefuls-in-competitive-district-5648185" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">In a recent interview with <em>The</em> <em>Epoch Times</em></a></span>, O’Donnell explained that even though his Democratic opponent has far more money and resources than him, he’s not giving up because he’s a gamer. </p><p> “I’m a gamer, so I intend to win,” said O’Donnell. “And I’m not going to lose because somebody thinks they can spend more money than me, because they can’t.” </p><h2 id="h1834"><a id=""></a>I’m a little bit Reagan, and I’m a little bit rock n’ roll</h2><p>Elsewhere in the interview, the former <em>Halo </em>composer said that as a young child, he loved music (he always wanted to be a “rock star”) and...conservative politics.  <br></p><p> “I sort of split my interests when I was 9 years old,” said the composer. “I was like, Ronald Reagan on one hand, and Paul McCartney on the other hand.” </p><p>As for why he—a musician with no political experience—should be elected to Congress, O’Donnell suggested that the government needs fewer lawyers and more people from different backgrounds.</p><p>“You don’t want 10 engineers making the game. You want an engineer, an artist, an animator, a composer, a writer, a designer—you want people who just approach the world differently,” explained O’Donnell. “You don’t want all designers. You don’t want all composers. They would be horrible.”</p><p>He then added: “Most of the time, you only want one composer.” Hmm.</p><p>Finally, O’Donnell suggested that what’s happening in the US government right now is nothing compared to his time making an Xbox-exclusive sci-fi shooter video game. </p><p> “What I see happening in Congress is like a walk in the park compared to making <em>Halo 2</em>.”</p><p>&nbsp; .<br></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>