<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 16:20:52 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Big Phasmophobia Update Introduces Point Hope and Speeds Up Leveling]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/phasmophobia-update-point-hope</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/big-phasmophobia-update-introduces-point-hope-and-speeds-up-leveling.910833/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/phasmophobia-update-point-hope<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Kinetic Games has released a new&nbsp;<em>Phasmophobia&nbsp;</em>update, and this one's got enough to offer that the devs have officially made it the 0.10 update, meaning future roadmap updates will have higher version numbers.</p>
<p>Earlier this year, Kinetic released the&nbsp;<em>Phasmophobia&nbsp;</em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/phasmophobia-roadmap-2024">roadmap</a>, in which the studio promised additions like new tasks, new player models, and new ghost models, plus lots more.</p>
<p>While this update doesn't contain much of what was promised for version 0.10, it does bring an entirely new map in the form of Point Hope, a vertiginous lighthouse with ten floors and twelve rooms to explore.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/phasmophobia-update-0.10-eventide-point-hope.jpg?itok=auWMUHKA 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/phasmophobia-update-0.10-eventide-point-hope.jpg?itok=kD_GFRp_ 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Abandon Hope, all ye who enter here.</figcaption></figure><p>You'll be able to unlock Point Hope at level 15, and thanks to some of the new changes to leveling this update brings, it shouldn't take you quite as long to get there.</p>
<p>Kinetic Games says it's lowered the required experience to reach level 100 "by around 10%", which should speed up the leveling experience. Additionally, you can now "level up to 9999 for each prestige" if you really, really love playing&nbsp;<em>Phasmophobia</em>.</p>
<p>Tons of other changes have also been implemented, including technical optimizations that have "drastically improved the performance of several areas of the game", according to Kinetic.</p>
<p>You can read the full&nbsp;<em>Phasmophobia&nbsp;</em>update 0.10 <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/739630/view/6215608421522854557" rel="noopener" target="_blank">patch notes here</a>. Sadly, they don't make any mention of the long-delayed&nbsp;<em>Phasmophobia&nbsp;</em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/phasmophobia-console-delay-halloween">console release</a>, but hopefully, we'll hear more about that sooner rather than later.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/phasmophobia-update-0.10-eventide-dark-room.jpg?itok=3yh_lrVY 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/phasmophobia-update-0.10-eventide-dark-room.jpg?itok=Z4ereUXc 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Playing&nbsp;<em>Phasmophobia&nbsp;</em>should feel a little better now thanks to Kinetic's technical improvements.</figcaption></figure><p>If you've yet to play&nbsp;<em>Phasmophobia</em>, it's a multiplayer ghost-hunting horror game in which you and your buddies must explore haunted locations to gather evidence of ghostly activity.</p>
<p>Different ghosts require different equipment and strategies to track, so you'll have to alter your approach to make sure that you deal with whatever spirit is haunting the place you're investigating.</p>
<p><i>Phasmophobia&nbsp;</i>is available right now <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/739630/Phasmophobia/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor">on PC via Steam</a>. It's also due to come to PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X|S at some point in the future.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Broke Signal Badlands is a pocket Fallout RPG for weird western dice-addled mystics]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/broke-signal-badlands-is-a-pocket-fallout-rpg-for-weird-western-dice-addled-mystics</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/broke-signal-badlands-is-a-pocket-fallout-rpg-for-weird-western-dice-addled-mystics.910830/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/broke-signal-badlands-is-a-pocket-fallout-rpg-for-weird-western-dice-addled-mystics<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
  

        <p>The road to Enlightenment is paved with cacti</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/20240625125537_1.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Forward Instinct</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
It's hotter than the inside of a horse here, so what better time to play an RPG about driving randomly through the desert in search of enlightenment. The RPG in question is <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/broke-signal-badlands-a-world-of-desert-adventure">Broke Signal Badlands: A World of Desert Adventure</a>, and yes, that's a very upbeat subtitle for a game in which you can perish after getting your hand stuck in the door of an abandoned Fonts Museum, or while yanking cacti out of your foot. There are gunfights, too, with dice serving as bullets, but so far, I've only managed to die of pathetic human error and clumsiness. Consider me unenlightened, but enthused.

</p><!--more-->
<p>
Coming this year to <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2432490/Broke_Signal_Badlands_A_World_of_Desert_Adventure/">Steam</a> with an older version already for sale on <a href="https://forwardinstinct.itch.io/broke-signal-badlands">Itch</a>, Broke Signal Badlands casts you as a line man (a telephone repair engineer, I think) who has abruptly decided to steal the company truck and go on a mystical roadtrip. Over the course of the subsequent hour or two, you'll WASDrive across a tilted 2D map painted in glaring shades of hazard yellow and Vimto purple, investigating landmarks such as forgotten mines and dealing with fleeting pop-up events such as hitchhikers.  
</p>
<p>
I'm not entirely sure which technology or medium or period the visual direction is channelling, but I like it. The map reminds me of both the original <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/fallout">Fallout</a>'s overworld and the pulp comic stylings of last year's <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-fabulous-fear-machine-out-today-is-a-strategy-game-of-engrossing-evil">The Fabulous Fear Machine</a>. The HUD is interestingly abrasive: scratchy illustrations of events and quests materialise slowly from the bottom up, as though slithering out of the belly of a fax machine. This invests the accompanying text with a peculiar mixture of suspense and irritation, as you either tap your cactus-punctured foot waiting for the full scene to reveal itself, or shrink back at the thought of seeing the horrors described. The writing itself is as sparing and dry as the bones of a cable repairguy who went looking for himself on the barrens and suffered a mortal wound while tidying up tumbleweeds after dark (yes, this is one of the quests).
</p>
<figure data-count="2" role="group">
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/20240625125017_1.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
</figure>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/20240625125459_1.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
</figure>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Forward Instinct</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>
The weird western premise and vignette-driven structure obviously recall <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/kentucky-route-zero">Kentucky Route Zero</a>, but rather than being an experimental episodic adventure like KRZ, Broke Signal Badlands is a shortform pen-and-paper-style <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-rpgs">RPG</a> in the vein of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/world-of-horror">World Of Horror</a>. Again, the game is a search for enlightenment. How does one become enlightened? By Mad Maxing your stats, apparently. 
</p>
<p>
There are three - Guile, which describes how crafty and underhand you are, Strength, which describes how likely you are to fall and hurt yourself while scaling a mesa, and Attunement, which describes both your level of empathy and your sensitivity to stuff like passing UFOs. Each point you plunk into a stat gives you a die you can roll to complete or fail an event or quest. You'll need plenty of Guile, for example, if you're going to sneak into the back of that Fonts Museum. More Guile than me, anyway. 

</p><p>If you can level each stat all the way to six, you'll pierce the veil of ignorance and emerge from the badlands a more complete and rounded being. More likely, you will injure yourself repeatedly, with each injury reducing the number of quest actions you can perform each day. When that number falls to zero, it's game over.
</p>
<p>
Broke Signal Badlands is apparently based on real-life trips to the Mojave - some of the illustrations look like they were created using photographs from those journeys. I do have to ask whether developers Forward Instinct found enlightenment in the process, and whether this game is the result? If you like the atmosphere, but would prefer to play something with more lavish writing, I recommend <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/where-the-water-tastes-like-wine">Where The Water Tastes Like Wine</a>.
</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Still Wakes the Deep is a horror gem that won’t get out of my head]]></title>
            <link>https://www.polygon.com/reviews/24185081/still-wakes-the-deep-review-narrative-platform-horror-game</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/still-wakes-the-deep-is-a-horror-gem-that-won%E2%80%99t-get-out-of-my-head.910827/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.polygon.com/reviews/24185081/still-wakes-the-deep-review-narrative-platform-horror-game<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  <p id="2u5cg9">The best horror games stick around long after credits have rolled, squirming in and tickling the back of your brain. <em>Still Wakes the Deep</em> has stuck around in my noggin, provoking questions that I know I will never have the answers to. There are plenty of familiar elements in <em>Still Wakes the Deep</em>, and in less deft hands, it could come off as derivative or redundant. But the atmosphere, the characters, and the restraint exercised by developer The Chinese Room all come together to create a special four-hour experience that I can’t forget.</p>
<p id="OmTf8b"><em>Still Wakes the Deep</em> takes place on a Scottish oil rig in 1975. The protagonist, Caz McLeary, is dodging an assault charge by taking a position here. The game gives us a little bit of exposition via a letter from Caz’s wife, and then we’re off to meet some of Caz’s co-workers. There’s a whole crew of boisterous blue-collar workers here, but we only get a couple of quick conversations with most of them before shit hits the fan. The voice acting is superb and very Scottish, so it might be worth turning on subtitles (if you aren’t familiar with Scottish accents) to catch the intricacies of these conversations.</p>
<p id="QjXWa1">A greedy manager insists the oil rig drill down into something that feels “off” to the workers, and something ancient awakens. Some crew members die, others are injured, and some are trapped under wreckage or in a diving bell. The early game is a very industrial horror experience, and Caz’s electrical skills are essential to try and salvage things. It’s chaotic, but the crew guesses at first that it was an air pocket or some similar, mundane catastrophe. They’ll soon be proven wrong, but the crew’s initial reactions set a tone of fear very well.</p>
  <figure>
  <span>
    
    <span data-original="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25504437/ss_6b6426f6742e20dfa2e05f8ad2af0f4136699507.jpg">
      
        <picture data-cid="site/picture_element-1719331206_5358_13788" data-cdata="{&quot;asset_id&quot;:25504437,&quot;ratio&quot;:&quot;*&quot;}">
  


  <source srcset="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/pQpLOSlzeeqKVYs3f2O782QXiDQ=/0x0:1920x1080/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:1920x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25504437/ss_6b6426f6742e20dfa2e05f8ad2af0f4136699507.jpg 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/JpC4fUGrYpezI3NZs3zG2duUVLA=/0x0:1920x1080/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:1920x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25504437/ss_6b6426f6742e20dfa2e05f8ad2af0f4136699507.jpg 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/RCY2lZJFYt5Fr9S6-TbmbTREOYk=/0x0:1920x1080/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:1920x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25504437/ss_6b6426f6742e20dfa2e05f8ad2af0f4136699507.jpg 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cz-L05H0DRo84XOrSxEr65VRd98=/0x0:1920x1080/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:1920x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25504437/ss_6b6426f6742e20dfa2e05f8ad2af0f4136699507.jpg 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_NwGE12d4upLgg87Xsq1pN8AV44=/0x0:1920x1080/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:1920x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25504437/ss_6b6426f6742e20dfa2e05f8ad2af0f4136699507.jpg 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/N-VSzztgIOa_KwD--XnoFP0Zwxk=/0x0:1920x1080/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:1920x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25504437/ss_6b6426f6742e20dfa2e05f8ad2af0f4136699507.jpg 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/S_RgQjeNpZ-2h8JihxnWvaeWhjU=/0x0:1920x1080/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:1920x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25504437/ss_6b6426f6742e20dfa2e05f8ad2af0f4136699507.jpg 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/10i7z2gzx2FG0su348lIouFGXQs=/0x0:1920x1080/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:1920x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25504437/ss_6b6426f6742e20dfa2e05f8ad2af0f4136699507.jpg 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/t4u-yxdlKm19JTsG9DsGJ7VDS6M=/0x0:1920x1080/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:1920x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25504437/ss_6b6426f6742e20dfa2e05f8ad2af0f4136699507.jpg 1920w" sizes="(min-width: 1221px) 846px, (min-width: 880px) calc(100vw - 334px), 100vw" type="image/webp">




</picture>

      
    </span>
    
  </span>
  
    <span>
      
      
        <cite>Image: The Chinese Room/Secret Mode</cite>
      
    </span>
  
</figure>


<p id="7TRu7N">From here, Caz is tasked with trying to help as many of his colleagues survive as possible. One early scene that sticks with me is of a rookie diver, stuck in a diving bell, screaming incoherently. His partner, distraught with grief and guilt, is trying to get him out. At the time, this seemed like the morally right thing to do, but those primal howls gave me the unsettling feeling that freeing him was the wrong choice. Sure enough, whatever emerged from the drill began writhing and climbing up the oil rig, claiming and corrupting any workers it could reach.</p>
<p id="vCHHFK">This is where <em>Still Wakes the Deep</em> really shines. My corrupted co-workers become my biggest obstacle. They’re out of their minds with pain and fear, and their bipedal forms twist and contort into something unrecognizable. The monster designs are deeply unnerving, and The Chinese Room did a fantastic job at allowing them to pursue and menace Caz while never giving the player a full look at them. Being around the supernatural creature from the depths or the monsters it produces obscures Caz’s vision; a colorful oil-like substance dances around the colors of his perception. </p>
<p id="SOdJ7s">It would have been very easy for <em>Still Wakes the Deep</em> to overplay its hand and end up being lost in the crowded genre of hallway horror. Stop me if you’ve heard this one before: A troubled man flees the consequences of his actions, only to find himself ensnared in a supernatural nightmare. Add in memories of a sobbing spouse and a protagonist desperate for immersion, and you’ve got a narrative going. But The Chinese Room strategically refuses to provide the player with all the answers they want. </p>
<p id="VkdQuJ">It’s easy to imagine a weaker presentation, where Caz stumbles across diary entries explaining a cult taking root on the oil rig, rituals to summon the antagonistic force, and definitive answers to his (and the player’s) questions. These scenes might be sprinkled with gratuitous gore and cheap jump scares. Instead, I walked away from <em>Still Wakes the Deep</em> feeling like I had experienced a carefully honed story. I still have questions, but that feels intentional; it’s proof that in horror, less is more.</p>
  <figure>
  <span>
    
    <span data-original="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25504439/ss_9f14421cbaa945a22c303454042a81c68c892498.jpg">
      
        <picture data-cid="site/picture_element-1719331206_4990_13789" data-cdata="{&quot;asset_id&quot;:25504439,&quot;ratio&quot;:&quot;*&quot;}">
  


  <source srcset="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ABnHdtTXid1LY3jJV3OdoJVz1hA=/0x0:4487x2524/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:4487x2524):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25504439/ss_9f14421cbaa945a22c303454042a81c68c892498.jpg 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NxvkmUI3th1VcYVRxOqGc26jt2c=/0x0:4487x2524/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:4487x2524):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25504439/ss_9f14421cbaa945a22c303454042a81c68c892498.jpg 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/w15D6ah1W84IhXzpJ1m2WZ891jM=/0x0:4487x2524/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:4487x2524):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25504439/ss_9f14421cbaa945a22c303454042a81c68c892498.jpg 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-V0qwITmGmcAKVr12qRXD9nSGzU=/0x0:4487x2524/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:4487x2524):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25504439/ss_9f14421cbaa945a22c303454042a81c68c892498.jpg 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NLocm9FKSGg9Me0qhZXl8fwXYG0=/0x0:4487x2524/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:4487x2524):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25504439/ss_9f14421cbaa945a22c303454042a81c68c892498.jpg 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/vPRUBq30MJn8-gvpzi_Nt4AA5Os=/0x0:4487x2524/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:4487x2524):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25504439/ss_9f14421cbaa945a22c303454042a81c68c892498.jpg 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/jg3GjdLjFvyk9gsCe0sETuml4pU=/0x0:4487x2524/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:4487x2524):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25504439/ss_9f14421cbaa945a22c303454042a81c68c892498.jpg 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Pl6r2wFYuh3CJTt-NbpjtUpiBCo=/0x0:4487x2524/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:4487x2524):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25504439/ss_9f14421cbaa945a22c303454042a81c68c892498.jpg 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/MturnL-_3vXVNQZ6Y3Aqu6MYQwE=/0x0:4487x2524/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:4487x2524):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25504439/ss_9f14421cbaa945a22c303454042a81c68c892498.jpg 1920w" sizes="(min-width: 1221px) 846px, (min-width: 880px) calc(100vw - 334px), 100vw" type="image/webp">




</picture>

      
    </span>
    
  </span>
  
    <span>
      
      
        <cite>Image: The Chinese Room/Secret Mode</cite>
      
    </span>
  
</figure>


<p id="YYMWlm">It’s a shame that the platforming doesn’t hit quite as well. It’s very functional; Caz has to make his way through the oil rig, trying to find a way out. The creature from the depths is growing up over the rig, breaking the structure down. Once safe corridors flood, Caz must swim through dark and claustrophobic hallways. Former colleagues stalk critical junctures, weeping and wailing. But my journey feels like I’m on rails; unlike a <em>Dead Space</em> or a <em>Prey</em> where I’m exploring a structure, <em>Still Wakes the Deep</em> feels like it’s guiding me along a predetermined course. </p>
<p id="VoXaR3">There are points where this works really well, as you can watch the supernatural organism grow and evolve its way across the oil rig. Other times, that structure feels clumsy. For instance, stumbling across a platforming sequence where each jump is marked by a big splash of yellow paint feels a bit awkward. One thing I enjoyed is Caz’s blunt reaction to each subsequent bit of bad news he gets; after being ordered around by NPCs in a hundred other horror games, I appreciated Caz calling his colleagues out for bossing him around. It’s also deeply relatable to watch Caz nearly fall to his death and curse up a storm.</p>
<p id="V401dv">Indeed, I started <em>Still Wakes the Deep</em> hating Caz, but by the end of the game, he had won me over. The finale was a complete gut punch, and for the first time in a while, I sobbed over the conclusion of a story. It’s not necessarily a bummer ending — I’ll spare you the details — but it is an emotional one. Each individual element of <em>Still Wakes the Deep</em> has been done before, but they’re brought together marvelously here, and the end result is a horror classic.</p>
<p id="0TuEmh"><small><em>Still Wakes the Deep</em></small><small> was released on June 18 on PlayStation 5, Windows PC, and Xbox Series X. The game was reviewed on PC using Xbox Game Pass. Vox Media has affiliate partnerships. These do not influence editorial content, though Vox Media may earn commissions for products purchased via affiliate links. You can find </small><a href="https://www.polygon.com/pages/ethics-statement"><small>additional information about Polygon’s ethics policy here</small></a><small>.</small></p>


  
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Modern Warfare 3's New Mode Is A Mashup Of GoldenEye And Minecraft And It Looks Wild]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/mw3-bit-party-pixel-big-head-mode-mid-season-4-update-1851559314</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/modern-warfare-3s-new-mode-is-a-mashup-of-goldeneye-and-minecraft-and-it-looks-wild.910824/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/mw3-bit-party-pixel-big-head-mode-mid-season-4-update-1851559314<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>For its mid-season update, which drops on June 26, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/games/call-of-duty-modern-warfare-iii&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/games/call-of-duty-modern-warfare-iii"><em>Call of Duty: Modern Warfare III</em></a></span> is getting a new playlist called Bit Party. As the name might suggest, Bit Party pixelates a popular map from <em>MW3</em> and makes everything look far more whimsical than it usually does. The modifier asks players to keep a cool head as their own pixelated one continues to grow proportional to their success.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196049" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="This Modern Warfare 3 Gameplay Feature Spices Up A Weak Campaign" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="134" data-playlist="196049,196653,196909" data-current="196049"><div><p>This Modern Warfare 3 Gameplay Feature Spices Up A Weak Campaign</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196049/196049_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196049/196049_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196049/196049_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196049/196049_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21580.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>In Bit Party, players will be dropped into Bitvela, a play on the Favela map <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/modern-warfare-3-mw3-2023-multiplayer-maps-1851017710&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/modern-warfare-3-mw3-2023-multiplayer-maps-1851017710">brought over from 2009’s <em>Modern Warfare 2</em></a></span>, not the more recent map of the same name in 2022’s <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/call-of-duty-modern-warfare-2-ii-infinity-ward-campaign-1849695247&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/call-of-duty-modern-warfare-2-ii-infinity-ward-campaign-1849695247"><em>Modern Warfare II</em></a></span>. I’m sorry I’m just not gonna let go of how <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/call-of-duty-modern-warfare-3-2-mw-sequel-1850430147&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/call-of-duty-modern-warfare-3-2-mw-sequel-1850430147">stupid a naming convention</a></span> <em>Call of Duty </em>has deployed of late. Anyways, Bitvela looks like a really cute and pixelated version of the classic map, and as usual it will be able to host 12 players in variants of popular 6v6 modes.<br></p><p>Though the majority of the player models will remain semi-realistic, their heads will balloon in size as you rack up kills and only dying will reset it. There are only three possible head sizes: small, medium, and large. Think of this fun little playlist as <em>MW3</em>’s own neat homage to Big Head mode in <em>Goldeneye</em>, where you could input a cheat code to make your friends’ heads bigger, making it that much simpler to line up headshots.</p><p>Even though having a big head makes you an easier target, the benefit to slaying so hard that it <em>literally </em>goes to your head is that the size of your dome also amplifies your score. For example, holding an objective in Hardpoint with a bigger head will net you and your team more points. The same goes for capturing a flag in Domination, collecting a tag in Kill Confirmed, or just getting a kill in good ol’ fashioned Team Deathmatch.</p><p>Bit Party will be available to play in <em>MW3</em> beginning June 26, and will run until July 3 as part of a “Retro Warfare” event. Additionally, players will be able to shop for a pack on <em>MW3</em>’s store called the 8-Bit Bliz bundle, which will give them access to pixelated versions of the protagonists of the <em>Modern Warfare </em>series, including Ghost, Soap MacTavish, Captain Price, and Farah.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Project Loki officially titled SUPERVIVE, open beta set for late 2024]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/06/project-loki-officially-titled-supervive-open-beta-set-for-late-2024</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/project-loki-officially-titled-supervive-open-beta-set-for-late-2024.910821/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/06/project-loki-officially-titled-supervive-open-beta-set-for-late-2024<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Public playtest to run from June 27 to July 4.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><em><a title="Games > SUPERVIVE [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/supervive">Project Loki</a></em>, the free-to-play competitive squad-based hero <a title="Genres > Battle Royale [41 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/battle-royale">battle royale</a>, is officially titled <em>SUPERVIVE</em> and an open beta is planned for late 2024, developer <a title="Companies > Theorycraft Games [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/theorycraft-games">Theorycraft Games</a> announced. A public playtest will also run from June 27 to July 4, with registration available <a href="https://playsupervive.com/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">here</a>. <span id="more-894751"></span></p><p>“We left the security of our AAA jobs and founded Theorycraft to make a big bet on ourselves, to see if we could make the deepest games in the world, and to develop in a new way—out in the open with real players from day one,” said Theorycraft CEO Joe Tung in a press release. “It’s been a wild ride to get to this point and we are proud to present <em>SUPERVIVE</em> as our first shot across the bow. We’re beyond grateful for our existing community and are super excited to welcome in new players!”</p><div id="carousel_894752"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Theorycraft Games:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>SUPERVIVE</em> is a free-to-play competitive, squad-based, hero battle royale. In a single session of <em>SUPERVIVE</em>, you’ll team-up in groups of four and dive into a huge world in the sky with the goal of being the last team standing as the playspace grows smaller due to an encroaching, deadly storm.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>To win, your squad will drop on a vast, expansive map to kill monsters and pursue a wide variety of map objectives. Doing so will grant you levels, rare powers, and equipment, which you can use to your advantage in defeating enemy teams. Along the way, you’ll find unique powers and equipment, dream up crazy strategies, and outplay other teams in sprawling, free-flowing combat.</p><p><em>SUPERVIVE</em> is a <a title="Genres > Free-to-Play [281 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/free-to-play">free-to-play game</a> with cosmetic unlocks – no pay-for-power, ever.</p><p><strong>Combat Meets Chaos</strong></p><p>Key differences between <em>SUPERVIVE</em> and other games include:</p><ul><li>A wide array of open-ended powers, items, abilities, and environmental interactions—bounce off jumpads, build walls, glide through abysses, punch trees, ride trains, combine powers in unique ways, and more.</li><li>Gliding and aerial combat with instant-KO “spikes” when players are hit over the abyss mid-glide.</li><li>Low time-to-kill, allowing for highly-lethal, 1vN playmaking.</li><li>In <em>SUPERVIVE</em>, massive comebacks are a more regular occurrence, ensuring players aren’t out until they’re out thanks to innovative comeback mechanics like:<ul><li>You can revive downed teammates while still fighting.</li><li>“Deathbox resurrections” where you can bring back a dead ally using their deathbox (as long as nobody interrupts you)</li><li>A full-squad revive at resurrection beacons (no tags needed).</li><li>The “most wanted” power-up that revives your squad if you stay alive long enough (or get enough kills) while your position is broadcast to the lobby.</li></ul></li></ul><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li>Main mode: SQUADS—10 teams per lobby, 40 players total, four players per squad. About 20 minutes per game session.<ul><li><em>SUPERVIVE</em> also supports duos and four-versus-four deathmatch.</li></ul></li><li>Over 15 hunters are currently available during playtests with more in development for launch.<ul><li>Each hunter has a primary fire, four abilities, and a passive.</li><li>Hunters are unlocked through regular play—as players progress in their Hunter’s Journey pass, they’ll be able to select any hunter to unlock at various level milestones.</li><li>There are no hard “roles” in <em>SUPERVIVE</em> or mandated team compositions—all hunters can output reasonable amounts of damage and can win a one-versus-one with some skill.</li><li>There are three major hunter archetypes:<ul><li>Fighters, who tend to deal the most damage with low-to-medium utility.</li><li>Protectors, who deal moderate damage with supportive team abilities.</li><li>Controllers, who deal moderate damage and have disruptive, space-controlling abilities.</li></ul></li></ul></li><li>Map-based objectives and storm shifts.<ul><li>Every game has a chance to roll a random “storm shift” that mutates that game’s variables—like bullet trains, which places three high-speed, lethal trains on the map; nomadic storm, which moves the available playspace across large distances; and more!</li><li>Unique, biome-specific monsters and bosses spawn at different times throughout the match, each dropping a unique power or game-changing ability.</li><li>Explore a wide and varied world in the sky where many different biomes have been stitched together.</li></ul></li><li>Over 50 unique powers.<ul><li><em>SUPERVIVE</em> features a wide array of unique, open-ended powers ranging from passive benefits, to special abilities, to placeable fortifications, to combat-augmenting skills. Some examples</li></ul></li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch the announcement trailer and a new developer diary below. View a set of screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/supervive/june-25-2024/">at the gallery</a>. Visit the official website <a href="https://playsupervive.com/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">here</a>.</p><h2><span>Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="SUPERVIVE - Announce Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/50cymlhI368?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><span>Developer Diary</span></h2><p><iframe title="SUPERVIVE - Developer Diary: June 2024" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/A5BshUFhLaw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How To Get Better At Playing Elden Ring And Shadow Of The Erdtree If You're Bad At Souls-Likes]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/how-to-get-better-at-playing-elden-ring-and-shadow-of-the-erdtree/1100-6524469/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/how-to-get-better-at-playing-elden-ring-and-shadow-of-the-erdtree-if-youre-bad-at-souls-likes.910818/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/how-to-get-better-at-playing-elden-ring-and-shadow-of-the-erdtree/1100-6524469/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6524469">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>With the release of its <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-bosses-gameplay-and-everything-we-know/1100-6522484/" data-ref-id="1100-6522484">Shadow of the Erdtree</a> expansion, Elden Ring is once again one a must-play game. If you missed out on it when it first launched in 2022 and you're considering picking it up, you might feel apprehensive when you hear how tough the game is. Fret not, because in a new video, GameSpot is ready to show you how you can survive and thrive in The Lands Between.</p><p>First off, if there's one golden rule with Elden Ring and other Souls-like games, it's that you need to be patient. Be Patient Pete--be the Tarnished warrior who approaches every battle with a wary nature and who waits for an opening. As GameSpot's Devante Chisolm explains in the video, treat every encounter like a conversation: one where you can respond to a question with a perfectly timed attack when you have the chance to speak.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="1238277460" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6464476,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;How%20To%20Be%20Good%20At%20Elden%20Ring%20%28If%20You%27re%20Bad%20At%20Souls%20Games%29&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:689,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/how-to-be-good-at-elden-ring-if-youre-bad-at-souls-games\/2300-6464476\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464476\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464476\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464476\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6464476&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6464476,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6524469&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;elden-ring&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;action,role-playing&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;xbox-one,pc,playstation-4,xbox-series-x,playstation-5&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;bandai-namco-games,from-software&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6464476},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6464476\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;GameSpot&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1823\/18237490\/4324234-eldentips_site.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/mwdAs59T.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1719258120,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="mwdAs59T" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> How To Be Good At Elden Ring (If You're Bad At Souls Games)</p>
      </div>
<p>There are a few other tips to help you out--or you can check GameSpot's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/elden-ring-guides-hub-classes-summons-and-more/1100-6501032/">Elden Ring and Shadow of the Erdtree guides hub</a> for more in-depth walkthroughs--like embracing growth through failure, using your free will to say "nope" to fights, and over-leveling your character to stand a better chance against some tough opponents. Did we mention that you should over-level your character? You should definitely over-level your character: we cannot stress this enough.</p><p>Throw in some helpful gameplay assists like summoning friends or AI companions to give you a helping hand, and you'll be on the right path toward becoming an Elden Lord.</p><p>"With all that Shadow of the Erdtree offers to accompany what exists in the Lands Between, the story of Elden Ring now feels complete and its world whole, and it's a staggering achievement," Tamoor Hussain wrote in GameSpot's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-dlc-review-kill-them-with-kindness/1900-6418243/">Elden Ring: Shadow of the Erdtree review</a>. "It's dark fantasy done masterfully; rich in detail and intricate in its construction; a place that feels dangerous and cruel, filled with memorable characters, fascinating rules, mind-bending concepts, and competing ideologies."</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/108490194306897153177?rel=author">Darryn Bonthuys</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Warhammer 40k: Darktide Secrets of the Machine God Update Brings New Mission and More]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/warhammer-40k-darktide-secrets-of-machine-god-update</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/warhammer-40k-darktide-secrets-of-the-machine-god-update-brings-new-mission-and-more.910791/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/warhammer-40k-darktide-secrets-of-machine-god-update<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Fatshark has released the&nbsp;<em>Warhammer 40k: Darktide&nbsp;</em>Secrets of the Machine God update, and it contains a new mission for you to try out, plus new weapons and more.</p>
<p>The patch is live on Steam right now, and it'll be going live on other platforms "shortly" as well, so if you're playing on Xbox or you've got the game via the Microsoft Store, you shouldn't have too much longer to wait.</p>
<p>First up, the new Clandestium Gloriana mission (which Fatshark says was "previously mentioned as Atelium Foundryplex Omega V"), will take you into the depths of Tertium to reawaken an Adeptus Mechanicus facility. It's got a new "variable end event" to increase its replayability as well.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/warhammer-40k-darktide-secrets-of-the-machine-god-new-mission.jpg?itok=_JXKU1aF 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/warhammer-40k-darktide-secrets-of-the-machine-god-new-mission.jpg?itok=yXE23V70 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>This land serves as the backdrop for your new&nbsp;<em>Warhammer 40k: Darktide&nbsp;</em>mission.</figcaption></figure><p>New weapons have also been added, with the Ogryn class getting its first two-handed weapon in the form of the Pickaxe. If you've ever felt like Ogryn melee attacks lack a certain heft, this weapon should do a lot to redress the balance.</p>
<p>Naturally, a number of quality-of-life improvements and gameplay tweaks have also been implemented. Several missions have been changed according to community feedback, and&nbsp;<em>Darktide</em>'s crosshair has undergone some changes to make it a more reliable tool as well.</p>
<p>That's all in addition to a ton of bug fixes and minor improvements that work diligently behind the scenes to (hopefully) make your&nbsp;<em>Darktide&nbsp;</em>experience a more pleasant one, if such a thing can be said about this miserable hive city.</p>

<p>If you want to know everything that's new, you can take a look at the full&nbsp;<em>Warhammer 40k: Darktide&nbsp;</em>Secrets of the Machine God patch notes <a href="https://forums.fatsharkgames.com/t/secrets-of-the-machine-god-out-now-pt-1/96131" rel="noopener" target="_blank">right here</a>....and <a href="https://forums.fatsharkgames.com/t/secrets-of-the-machine-god-out-now-pt-2/96132" rel="noopener" target="_blank">here as well</a>. The notes were so long Fatshark split them into two posts, so I hope you like reading patch notes!</p>
<p><em>Warhammer 40k: Darktide&nbsp;</em>is a co-op first-person shooter set in the hive city of Tertium. Newly conscripted to the Emperor's Inquisition, you must assist Explicator Zola in containing the forces of Nurgle and ensuring they don't overrun Tertium.</p>
<p>Gameplay-wise, the game is quite similar to Fatshark's&nbsp;<em>Vermintide</em>, although the&nbsp;<em>40k&nbsp;</em>setting means everything's much less fantasy-inflected and much more grungy and industrial. If you loved&nbsp;<em>Vermintide</em>, though, you'll almost certainly like this too, and there's <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/warhammer-40000-darktide-2024-plans">lots more on the way</a> for the devoted faithful.</p>
<p>You can check out&nbsp;<em>Warhammer 40k: Darktide&nbsp;</em>right now on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1361210/Warhammer_40000_Darktide/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="noopener" target="_blank">PC via Steam</a> or the <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-us/games/store/warhammer-40-000-darktide/9nt3wc6rkbvq" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Microsoft Store</a>, as well as on Xbox Series X|S. Stay tuned for more.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fallout: New Vegas Villain Tease For Season 2 Raises All Sorts Of Questions]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/fallout-season-2-amazon-tv-mr-house-new-vegas-1851559169</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fallout-new-vegas-villain-tease-for-season-2-raises-all-sorts-of-questions.910785/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/fallout-season-2-amazon-tv-mr-house-new-vegas-1851559169<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="51913a19fc785e84298cfd7a0581ba34" data-recommend-id="image://51913a19fc785e84298cfd7a0581ba34" data-format="jpg" data-width="1280" data-height="734" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Mr. house sits at a table" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Mr. house sits at a table" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Amazon</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="51913a19fc785e84298cfd7a0581ba34" data-recommend-id="image://51913a19fc785e84298cfd7a0581ba34" data-format="jpg" data-width="1280" data-height="734" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Mr. house sits at a table" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>The <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/fallout-show-amazon-review-1851400505&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/fallout-show-amazon-review-1851400505"><em>Fallout</em> series</a></span> from Amazon isn’t done teasing <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/fallout-new-vegas-things-never-say-fan-bethesda-xbox-1851467599&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/fallout-new-vegas-things-never-say-fan-bethesda-xbox-1851467599">fans</a></span> over the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/fallout-new-vegas-timeline-canon-todd-howard-1851416601&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/fallout-new-vegas-timeline-canon-todd-howard-1851416601">potential canonicity</a></span> of Obsidian’s beloved <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/review-fallout-new-vegas-5670346&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/review-fallout-new-vegas-5670346"><em>New Vegas</em></a></span>. After constant questions about whether that game even existed in the show’s world (which were pretty definitively answered by the first season’s final episode), the second season is gearing up to bring <em>New Vegas </em>into the fold in a big way. That includes revealing that <em>New Vegas</em>’s big bad, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/fallout-new-vegas-elon-musk-mod-mr-house-ai-pc-twitter-1850686612&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/fallout-new-vegas-elon-musk-mod-mr-house-ai-pc-twitter-1850686612">Mr. House</a></span>, will play a role. Of course, that only raises more questions about what is and isn’t canon.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196903" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Why Fallout: New Vegas Is Still Canon After The TV Show" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="189" data-playlist="196903,196452,196805" data-current="196903"><div><p>Why Fallout: New Vegas Is Still Canon After The TV Show</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196903/196903_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196903/196903_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196903/196903_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196903/196903_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/22460.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>The news comes from a <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://variety.com/2024/tv/news/fallout-season-1-finale-explainer-1236044450/#article-comments&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://variety.com/2024/tv/news/fallout-season-1-finale-explainer-1236044450/#article-comments" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Variety</em></a></span> interview with showrunners and series creators Graham Wagner and Geneva Robertson-Dworet. In the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=x8Q0Ch50lNU&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=x8Q0Ch50lNU" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">video interview</a></span>, Wagner states that Las Vegas is Robert House’s town and that Mr. House “will be involved” in the second season. Robert House runs New Vegas in the game and is an integral part of any story in the setting. Since New Vegas appears in the final shot of season one, we know the second season will feature the iconic location in a big way. If Mr. House is involved, it means that the show will likely need to make one particular ending of <em>New Vegas </em>canon: the one in which the player sides with Mr. House in the conflict for the Hoover Dam. </p><figure id="" data-id="2e030e9ee75574b0a3971b39eba50b98" data-recommend-id="image://2e030e9ee75574b0a3971b39eba50b98" data-format="jpg" data-width="1278" data-height="717" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Mr. House appears on a computer screen" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Mr. House appears on a computer screen" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Bethesda</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="2e030e9ee75574b0a3971b39eba50b98" data-recommend-id="image://2e030e9ee75574b0a3971b39eba50b98" data-format="jpg" data-width="1278" data-height="717" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Mr. House appears on a computer screen" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>This ending establishes that Mr. House will continue to rule New Vegas in the years following the game, with the city described as a despotic vision of pre-war glory in which the streets are “orderly, efficient, cold.” However, if the show takes the same storytelling approach in season two as it did in season one, there is another option. Mr. House could appear in flashbacks, further revealing the machinations that led to the apocalypse in the first place. If the show takes the flashback route, it could feature Mr. House while continuing to play coy about the specific events of<em> New Vegas</em> to keep each player’s ending equally canonical, for now.</p><p>Whichever ending of the game the show chooses to go with (if any in particular), it still won’t answer the question of what happened to New Vegas after the game. The show takes place 15 years after <em>New Vegas</em>,<em> </em>and in that glimpse we get of it in the first season’s final moments, we see it as a ruined city bereft of its signature lights and splendor. What happened in those 15 years remains a mystery the second season will likely dig into, and whether in flashback or not, Mr. House is sure to play a big role in revealing the answers.</p><p>.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Still Hasn’t Officially Complained About Palworld]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-no-complaints-palworld/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-still-hasn%E2%80%99t-officially-complained-about-palworld.910782/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-no-complaints-palworld/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>In January, shortly after the sensational ‘Palworld’ was released, Nintendo announced that it was investigating the game for any signs of plagiarism. Later, Nintendo’s president, Shuntaro Furukawa, said that the company would ‘take appropriate action’ if their IP had been infringed upon. Nintendo has long been known as a stalwart company where copyright issues are concerned, but it has been confirmed that six months after Palworld was released, Nintendo has yet to make an official complaint.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-perhaps-it-s-fine">Perhaps It’s Fine</h2>



<p>In many ways, Palworld was a flash in the pan. It blew up overnight, with millions of players flooding the game, which was being presented online as ‘Pokémon with guns’. In Palworld, players are charged with exploring a vast open world, collecting and upgrading ‘Pals’, crafting items, and building bases. It was a monumental success when it was released in January, soaring up the charts and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/palworld-growth-emergency-epic-meeting/">prompting emergency meetings at Epic</a> Games because it threatened to bring down the servers hosting it.</p>



<p>Despite Nintendo’s claims that it was <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-pokemon-company-says-they-will-investigate-palworld-for-ip-infringement/">launching an investigation into Palworl</a>d just days after it blew up, it seems as though nothing has come of it. Pocket Pair, the developer behind Palworld, confirmed recently that no complaints have been received and no legal proceedings have been kicked off, suggesting that all is well between Nintendo and Palworld.</p>



<p>Speaking to Game File’s Stephen Totilo, Takuro Mizobe, <a href="https://www.gamefile.news/p/palworld-pocketpair-takuro-mizobe-interview" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">the head at Pocket Pair, said</a>:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>Nintendo and the Pokémon Company didn’t say anything to us. Of course I love Pokémon and respect it. I grew up with it, in my generation.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Palworld has suffered a fall from grace since dominating the charts six months ago. It hit an all-time peak player count of around 2.1 million users on Steam but now averages around 18,000 peak players per month. It has also dropped off entirely on streaming and content platforms – but that’s the lifecycle of most games.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/stellar-blade-sells-estimated-1-million-units-dlc-sequel-under-review/">Stellar Blade sold 1 million copies</a>, and sign up to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/newsletter/">receive our newsletter</a>.</p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lara Croft is Coming to Dead by Daylight July 16, 2024]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/lara-croft-is-coming-to-dead-by-daylight-july-16-2024/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/lara-croft-is-coming-to-dead-by-daylight-july-16-2024.910779/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/lara-croft-is-coming-to-dead-by-daylight-july-16-2024/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>In <a href="https://x.com/DeadbyDaylight/status/1805617622970511468" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a new post</a> via X, the Dead by Daylight account officially confirmed that Lara Croft will be the next survivor and release on July 16, 2024.</p>



<p>The developers elaborated on Croft’s perks in the full <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/deadbydaylight/comments/1do8343/810_ptb/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">PTB patch notes</a> released today. Lara Croft will include the Finesse, Hardened, and Specialist perks.</p>



<p>Finesse will make Croft’s fast vaults 20 percent faster. Hardened can allow Croft to reveal the Killer’s aura instead of screaming. Finally, the Specialist perk introduces a token system that can lower the maximum required generator progress.</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>Today’s patch notes also detail some balancing changes coming to The Knight, The Singularity, maps, and more. Fortunately, that does include some extensive bug fixes.</p>



<p>Earlier this month, Dead by Daylight developer Behaviour Interactive revealed it would <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dead-by-daylight-dev-layoffs/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">face new layoffs</a> affecting nearly 100 employees. However, Dead by Daylight continues to expand with impressive new updates and collaborations.</p>



<p>In May, fans also got a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/heres-a-first-look-at-dead-by-daylight-universe-game-project-t/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">first look at Project T</a>, which is set in the Dead by Daylight universe.</p>



<p>Besides Dead by Daylight, Lara Croft has previously seen other collaborations such as the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tomb-raider-pack-cod/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Call of Duty Tomb Raider pack</a> from last year. </p>



<p>More recently, there’s a lot of traction around Tomb Raider adaptations. A <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tomb-raider-live-action-show-coming-amazon-prime-video/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">live-action series</a> is coming to Amazon Prime Video. Animated series The Legend of Lara Croft is also coming in October 2024, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hayley-atwell-lara-croft-netflix/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">featuring Hayley Atwell</a> as Croft.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more of the latest Insider Gaming news, you can read about THQ Nordic announcing a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/disney-epic-mickey-rebrushed-is-coming-september-2024/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">September release date</a> for Disney Epic Mickey: Rebrushed, and sign up to receive <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/newsletter/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">our official newsletter</a>.</p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PlayStation 5 Exclusive Stellar Blade Sells 1 Million Copies]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/playstation-5-exclusive-stellar-blade-sells-1-million-copies</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/playstation-5-exclusive-stellar-blade-sells-1-million-copies.910776/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/playstation-5-exclusive-stellar-blade-sells-1-million-copies<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>PlayStation 5 action game <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/stellar-blade">Stellar Blade</a> has sold more than one million copies, developer Shift Up has announced.</p><p>As reported by <a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/stellar-blade-studio-is-looking-at-a-pc-version-but-cant-comment-due-to-its-contractual-relationship/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">VGC</a>, the studio hosted a Stellar Blade presentation where it revealed that estimates now suggested the game had sold upwards of the one million mark. That number may grow even more if Shift Up releases a PC version, something it is "currently looking at" but is unsure on as a result of a "contractual relationship," likely with PlayStation owner Sony.</p><p>Shift Up also reiterated prior comments that <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/stellar-blade-developer-shift-up-considering-a-sequel">it's considering releasing more downloadable content and even a sequel to Stellar Blade</a>. A photo mode coming in August, further outfits for protagonist Eve coming in October, and more are already announced for the game, though Shift Up did tease a big collaboration at the end of 2024.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div><h3>Stellar Blade Screenshots</h3></div></output><p>The one million sales will likely make a sequel more likely, giving fans who enjoyed the game more hope, but an official announcement is likely still very far away as Stellar Blade only launched on April 26, 2024.</p><p>Its sci-fi action and adventure took <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/stellar-blade-was-inspired-by-a-taxi-driver-strike-along-with-alita-battle-angel-and-80s-90s-sci-fi">inspiration from Alita: Battle Angel, 80s and 90s science fiction, and a taxi driver strike</a> according to director Kim Hyung Tae. Its already enjoyed a handful of post-launch updates too, <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/stellar-blade-update-1003-adds-new-boss-challenge-new-outfits-and-more">including one which added a boss challenge, new outfits, and more</a>.</p><p><a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/stellar-blade-review">In our 7/10 review</a>, IGN said: "Stellar Blade is great in all of the most important ways for an action game, but dull characters, a lackluster story, and several frustrating elements of its role playing game mechanics prevent it from soaring along with the best of the genre."</p><p><em>Ryan Dinsdale is an IGN freelance reporter. He'll talk about The Witcher all day.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EA Sports Reveals the Toughest Places to Play in College Football 25]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/college-football-25-toughest-places-to-play</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ea-sports-reveals-the-toughest-places-to-play-in-college-football-25.910770/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/college-football-25-toughest-places-to-play<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>As the release date for <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/college-football-25">College Football 25</a> inches closer, EA Sports has released new information on the game. Specifically, the publisher has provided information on the toughest places to play. </p><p>As part of its weeklong plan to reveal new details about College Football 25, EA Sports <a href="https://www.ea.com/games/ea-sports-college-football/college-football-25/news/college-football-25-rankings-week-showcase?utm_campaign=cf25_pub_na_ic_ic_twt_rankings&amp;utm_source=twitter&amp;utm_medium=social&amp;cid=80567&amp;ts=1719327319382" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">shared a list</a> of the top 25 stadiums that will make it difficult for away teams to emerge victorious. Some factors used to determine this list included  "historical stats" such as home winning percentage, attendance for home games, active home winning streaks, and team prestige. Some stadiums that made the final cut include Penn State's Beaver Stadium, LSU's Tiger Stadium, and Texas A&amp;M's<strong> </strong>Kyle Field. The complete list of the top 25 toughest places to play will be listed below in this article. </p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div><h3>College Football 25 - Gameplay Deep Dive Screenshots</h3></div></output><p>Alongside this list of the toughest places to play, to up the ante of home-field advantage and make winning road games challenging, EA Sports <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/college-football-25-gameplay-deep-dive-provides-first-look-at-campus-iq-wear-tear-system-and-more">previously confirmed</a> that Stadium Pulse Meter, a feature first debuted in NCAA Football 06, will return in College Football 25. The Stadium Pulse meter will measure the crowd's noise and cause distractions for the opposing team, such as the screen shaking and making it hard to read plays and preview the play you selected in the huddle. </p><p>Yet, Stadium Pulse and a list of the most difficult places to play is only scratching the surface of what EA Sports promises to feature in College Football 25 and attempt to replicate that atmosphere of watching your favorite college football team play. The publisher previously confirmed 169 themes, such as the Penn State Whiteout game, in addition to over 200 chants, including Florida State's war chant and tomahawk chop. </p><p>College Football 25 will <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ea-sports-college-football-25-release-date">be released on July 19</a> for PS5 and Xbox Series X/S. For more, check out <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/college-football-25-preview-more-than-just-a-madden-clone">our hands-on preview</a> of College Football 25, where I explain why it is more than just a clone of the Madden NFL football games.</p><h2><u><strong>College Football 25's Toughest Places to Play (Ranked)</strong></u></h2><ol data-cy="list"><li>Kyle Field - (Texas A&amp;M University)</li><li>Bryant-Denny Stadium - (University of Alabama)</li><li>Tiger Stadium - (LSU)</li><li>Ohio Stadium - (Ohio State University)</li><li>Sanford Stadium - (University of Georgia)</li><li>Beaver Stadium - (Penn State University)</li><li>Camp Randall Stadium - (University of Wisconsin)</li><li>Gaylord Family Oklahoma Memorial Stadium - (University of Oklahoma)</li><li>Doak S. Campbell Stadium - (Florida State University)</li><li>Ben Hill Griffin Stadium - (University of Florida)</li><li>Autzen Stadium - (University of<strong> </strong>Oregon)</li><li>Memorial Stadium - (Clemson University)</li><li>Neyland Stadium - (University of Tennessee)</li><li>Jordan-Hare Stadium - (Auburn University)</li><li>Williams-Brice Stadium - (University of South Carolina)</li><li>Michigan Stadium - (University of Michigan)</li><li>Lane Stadium - (Virginia Tech University)</li><li>Rice-Eccles Stadium - (University of Utah)</li><li>Darrell K. Royal - Texas Memorial Stadium (University of Texas)</li><li>Kinnick Stadium - (University of Iowa)</li><li>Notre Dame Stadium - (University of Notre Dame)</li><li>Spartan Stadium - (Michigan State University)</li><li>Donald W. Reynolds Razorback Stadium - (University of Arkansas)</li><li>Albertsons Stadium - (Boise State University)</li><li>Davis Wade Stadium - (Mississippi State Univeristy)</li></ol><p><em>Taylor is a Reporter at IGN. You can follow her on Twitter </em><a href="https://twitter.com/TayNixster" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>@TayNixster.</em></a></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Best Power Banks for Switch Are Back on Sale For a Limited Time in the UK]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/best-power-bank-steam-deck-switch-back-on-sale-for-a-limited-time-updated-new-uk</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-best-power-banks-for-switch-are-back-on-sale-for-a-limited-time-in-the-uk.910767/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/best-power-bank-steam-deck-switch-back-on-sale-for-a-limited-time-updated-new-uk<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">These are unbelievable affordable.</h2></div><div><section><p>The perfect power bank to use with your Steam Deck or Nintendo Switch is back on sale in the UK right now. We are, of course, talking about the INIU 140W 27000mAh Fast Charging Portable Charger, available on Amazon for just <a href="https://zdcs.link/AdVgp" target="_blank">£37.98 right now (see here)</a>. Ensure you use the listed voucher (35% off) and promo code 995LXLXE to get the full discount. The last time we saw a discount like this, it sold out before the end of the day, so act fast!</p><div><div id="201881"><p><h3>INIU Power Bank, 27000mAh 140W Portable Charger</h3></p><div><p>Use listed 35% voucher and redeem promo code to secure the discount.</p></div></div><div id="202397"><p><h3>INIU Power Bank, 22.5W 10000mAh</h3></p><div><p>Use listed 35% voucher and redeem promo code to secure the discount.</p></div></div></div><p>This incredibly affordable INIU power bank is ideal for portable gaming systems like the <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/steam-deck-oled-review">Steam Deck</a> or the <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-switch-oled-review">Switch</a>. It boasts super-fast charging capabilities, a robust battery capacity, and a sleek design. It's our favourite pick for portable gaming, and well worth it at such a discounted price. But if you're after something just that bit smaller and easier to use, then consider the <a href="https://zdcs.link/qkJNp" target="_blank">INIU Power Bank, 22.5W 10000mAh for £10.82</a> with the listed voucher and code ORS5THPD. That's a crazy good price, and well worth considering for the Switch or your smartphone, especially if you're traveling soon.</p><p>Taking your Steam Deck or Switch on the go is undeniably convenient. We've all experienced that sinking feeling—you leave the house in a rush, grabbing your phone or Nintendo Switch on the way out, only to find it lifeless when you try to power it up. If only we had remembered to bring a power bank. </p><p>You'll need a top cable that's a bit longer to go with your new portable charger, so consider grabbing a 2M, <a href="https://zdcs.link/Bd18M?_ga=1195960001.1647009307" target="_blank">100w USB-C cable 2 pack from UGREEN for £5.94</a> (it usually goes for £10 so that's a serious saving as well). If you don't need as much wattage, consider the Anker 310 60W USB C Cable, available on <a href="https://zdcs.link/rdwem" target="_blank">Amazon for just £4.49</a>. However, if you're purchasing power solutions for your Steam Deck, remember it requires at least 40W to charge properly—don't say we didn't warn you!</p><p>These power banks are lifesavers, so grab one and never be caught with a dead phone or gaming system again. Plus, with games like <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/god-of-war-ragnarok-pc-release-officially-confirmed-state-of-play-2024">God of War: Ragnarok coming to Steam soon</a>, there are going to be some graphically intensive games to check out which will zap your power fast--best come prepared. For more gaming and everyday deals, follow <a href="https://x.com/IGNUKDeals" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@IGNUKDeals</a> on Twitter/X.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><h2>Can I Take a Power Bank on an Airplane?</h2><p>You are permitted to bring a power bank on the plane, but there are specific regulations you must follow. Each power bank must have a maximum capacity of no more than 100 Wh or 27,000 mAh. Additionally, each passenger is allowed to carry up to two power banks, each adhering to the 100 Wh limit. You must also carry your power bank in your hand luggage. But, it's also worth bearing in mind that each airline or country could have different regulations that you will have to adhere to, so it's always worth double checking before you arrive to the airport.</p><p>Robert Anderson is a deals expert and Commerce Editor for IGN. You can follow him <a href="https://twitter.com/robertliam21" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@robertliam21</a> on Twitter.</p></section><div><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Jun 25, 2024 2:45 pm</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Midnight Murder Club Revealed from Knockout City Developers]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/midnight-murder-club-revealed-from-knockout-city-developers</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/midnight-murder-club-revealed-from-knockout-city-developers.910764/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/midnight-murder-club-revealed-from-knockout-city-developers<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Velan Studios wants to play hide-and-seek with you...</h2></div><section><p>Velan Studios, makers of Knockout City, Mario Kart Live: Home Circuit, and Hot Wheels Rift Rally, has announced Midnight Murder Club, a new six-player first-person hide-and-seek multiplayer party game where all you'll have in order to survive against other players are a flashlight, a revolver, and your wits. It's due out on PC via Steam in Fall 2024.</p><p>Midnight Murder Club is planning four game modes for launch: a traditional Deathmatch (in regular or 2v2v2 team variants); Free For All, which values deadliness above all else; Hunter/Hunted, in which two players become Hunters and try to prevent the rest from locating and burning four hidden effigies; and Thief in the Night, where teams of two try to steal more valuables than the other duos.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div><h3>Midnight Murder Club - First Screenshots</h3></div></output><p>“With Midnight Murder Club, we started with a simple game jam idea of a shooter in the dark and we quickly realized that we had something unique,” said game director Eric Feurstein. “By playing with light, dark and sound, we’re able to offer a riveting gameplay experience that keeps players’ adrenaline pumping. Playing in pitch darkness is an immediately novel experience where you’re scared to turn your flashlight on for fear that someone will see it, but also don’t want to turn it off for fear of losing your way.</p><p><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2698870" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Wishlist</a> Midnight Murder Club on Steam if you're interested, and don't miss IGN's reviews of the aforementioned <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/knockout-city-review">Knockout City</a> and <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/mario-kart-live-home-circuit-review">Mario Kart Live: Home Circuit</a>.</p><p><em>Ryan McCaffrey is IGN's executive editor of previews and host of both IGN's weekly Xbox show, </em><a href="https://www.ign.com/watch/unlocked">Podcast Unlocked</a><em>, as well as our monthly(-ish) interview show, </em><a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2016/02/04/ign-unfiltered-every-episode-ever">IGN Unfiltered</a><em>. He's a North Jersey guy, so it's "Taylor ham," not "pork roll." Debate it with him on Twitter at </em><a href="https://twitter.com/DMC_Ryan" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>@DMC_Ryan</em></a><em>.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A Game That Lets You Fight Back Against The Indignity Of Waiting]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/while-waiting-demo-steam</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/a-game-that-lets-you-fight-back-against-the-indignity-of-waiting.910749/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://aftermath.site/while-waiting-demo-steam<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Owning my own business and working from home, I don’t actually wait for stuff that much anymore. If anything, I have the opposite problem: tasks and responsibilities are constantly flying at my head while I shout, “Aah, wait a minute!” at them. But if you have not made the same terrible life choices as me, the demo of upcoming game <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2449160/While_Waiting/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>While Waiting</em></a> might be your speed.</p><p><em>While Waiting</em>’s demo has been out since <a href="https://x.com/PlayOptillusion/status/1764783113815671252" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">March</a>, but I checked it out after seeing some folks talking about it online over the weekend. The demo features 10 levels from developer Optillusion’s full game, where you control a character across various ages as they wait for stuff: a bus to come, the rain to stop, someone to get out of the bathroom, their boss to finish a presentation. You have the option to simply wait, standing there until the thing you want to happen happens, but you can also get up to trouble, guided by vague in-game achievements like “percussive maintenance” and “Watch out!”&nbsp;</p><div><figure><p><iframe title="While Waiting - Official Trailer | Day of the Devs 2024" width="710" height="399" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/FBsxzuL4YK0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></figure></div><p>One of my favorite levels was about waiting for a game to download. You’re faced with a familiar on-screen screen of several simultaneous downloads, and an indicator that your internet connection is low. The downloads crawl along, so I did all the things I do when faced with that situation on Steam: I turned the internet on and off, paused and un-paused the downloads, and set them up to download one after the other before getting impatient and trying to force them all to happen at the same time again. Like every level in <em>While Waiting</em>, there’s stuff you can do that isn’t immediately clear, which I discovered by clicking around. It was such a familiar, relatable situation, and such a unique feeling to have the feelings I usually have <em>around</em> a game inside a game instead.</p><p>Another favorite level for me, for personal reasons, was waiting for the bathroom. I’m a trans man, so I am intimately familiar with the uncomfortable situation of waiting for a bathroom stall when there’s a free urinal. In real life, I pass this time by doing the “you go ahead” gesture at men, combined with a choreography I’ve perfected of trying to pretend I have to poop (justifying my wait for the stall) but not so urgently that I cause a scene. In <em>While Waiting</em>, I wandered over to the urinal, only to be confronted by the fact that–just like in real life–I couldn’t figure out if I could pee in it.&nbsp;(In the game, it appears your character actually has to poop, as suggested by an uncomfortably hilarious image of an upturned can of Spam.)</p><p>Given how many possible tasks each level presents, it seems like the game <em>wants </em>you to mess around while waiting, but I like the idea of just standing there, even if I never actually succeeded at doing it. In real life, you don’t–or, I hope you don’t–respond to the interminable wait for your luggage on the airport carousel by hurling everyone’s bags around the terminal. Some of the secrets you can get up to strain the bounds of credulity, painting <em>While Waiting</em>’s world as much wackier than its initial mundane premise might suggest. I am dour and un-fun, so I’d love to see more levels where you’re actually constrained by reality, though I understand what a bad game that would make when stretched over hours. But despite my desire for everything to be tediously literal, it was delightful to discover little secrets in <em>While Waiting</em>’s scenes, creating interesting events and revelling in throwing destructive tantrums.</p><p>There’s a bit of <em>Untitled Goose Game</em> in <em>While Waiting</em>’s self-created chaos and mysterious tasks, but without the excuse of “hey, I’m a goose!”, you really just get to let your worst impulses come out. There’s no release date yet, but <em>While Waiting</em> promises over 100 levels to cause a scene in when we get a full release.</p></div><div><h2>Stay in touch</h2><p>Sign up for our free newsletter</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Epic Mickey: Rebrushed Release Date Revealed for September]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/epic-mickey-rebrushed-release-date</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/epic-mickey-rebrushed-release-date-revealed-for-september.910725/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/epic-mickey-rebrushed-release-date<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>THQ Nordic and developer Purple Lamp have announced the&nbsp;<em>Epic Mickey: Rebrushed&nbsp;</em>release date, and the reworked 3D platformer is on its way to modern systems this fall.</p>
<p>The game, which was originally revealed <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/nintendo-direct-partner-showcase-january-2023-recap-find-all-news-and-announcements">during this February's Nintendo Partner Direct</a>, will arrive across PC, PlayStation, Xbox, and Nintendo Switch on September 24th, publisher THQ Nordic <a href="https://x.com/THQNordic/status/1805596997509886405" rel="noopener" target="_blank">announced earlier today</a>.</p>
<p>As well as revealing the release date, the publisher also unveiled a shiny&nbsp;<em>Epic Mickey: Rebrushed&nbsp;</em>Collector's Edition, which is available for pre-order right now and which contains some extra goodies for you to enjoy.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/epic-mickey-rebrushed-release-date-statues.jpg?itok=MOwifZm- 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/epic-mickey-rebrushed-release-date-statues.jpg?itok=0thVc11i 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Epic Mickey: Rebrushed&nbsp;</em>is a full rework of the 2010 Wii platformer.</figcaption></figure><p>Said Collector's Edition contains a number of extra goodies, including an 11-inch Mickey Mouse statue, an Oswald keychain, and a vintage Mickey Mouse sign, as well as several postcards and a collector's steelbook case.</p>
<p>You can also look forward to special in-game costumes and 24 hours' worth of early access to the game <a href="https://epicmickey.thqnordic.com/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">if you pre-order</a>, although you'll also get those bonuses if you pre-order the standard version.</p>
<p>To reveal the release date and also preview the collector's edition, THQ Nordic also released a video starring none other than&nbsp;<em>Epic Mickey&nbsp;</em>creative director Warren Spector, a legend who's also known for his work on&nbsp;<em>Deus Ex</em>.&nbsp;</p>

<p>If you're not familiar with&nbsp;<em>Epic Mickey: Rebrushed</em>, it's a remake of 2010's&nbsp;<em>Epic Mickey</em>&nbsp;that features reworked visuals and gameplay.</p>
<p>Built on Unreal Engine 5 instead of the original's Gamebryo engine, <i>Epic Mickey: Rebrushed&nbsp;</i>not only revamps the graphics of the original game, but also gives Mickey a few new moves, including a ground pounds, a dash, and a sprint.</p>
<p><em>Rebrushed&nbsp;</em>will tell the same story as the original game, one in which Mickey must delve into Wasteland, a world filled with forgotten Disney characters, and decide its fate with the aid of his magical brush.</p>
<p><em>Epic Mickey: Rebrushed&nbsp;</em>arrives on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1522160/Disney_Epic_Mickey_Rebrushed/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="noopener" target="_blank">PC via Steam</a>, as well as <a href="https://store.playstation.com/concept/10008074" rel="noopener" target="_blank">PlayStation</a>, <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/disney-epic-mickey-rebrushed/9nhf463jc2hl" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Xbox</a>, and <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/en-gb/Games/Nintendo-Switch-games/Disney-Epic-Mickey-Rebrushed-2523455.html" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Nintendo Switch</a>, on September 24th. Stay tuned for more on this one.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tomb Raider's Lara Croft coming to Dead by Daylight]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/tomb-raiders-lara-croft-coming-to-dead-by-daylight</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/tomb-raiders-lara-croft-coming-to-dead-by-daylight.910722/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/tomb-raiders-lara-croft-coming-to-dead-by-daylight<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>



            <p>
As if she hasn't been through enough already, Tomb Raider's Lara Croft is now set to join Dead by Daylight as a Survivor.
</p>
<p>
"Lara Croft has survived expeditions few would dare attempt, locked eyes with death and lived to tell the tale... Now, she must face yet again a dark adventure shrouded in Fog," the Dead by Daylight team teased, noting that while this may be her first foray into horror, she has certainly seen things many of us can only imagine during her own global escapades. Remember when she took down a tyrannosaurus rex?!
</p>
<p>
The Lara heading to Dead by Daylight is from the Survivor trilogy, specifically the 2013 reboot (see image above). However, while she has her jade necklace and tank top, she does not have her bow and pistols, meaning she will have to find other ways to survive the fog. 
</p>
<figure>
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<figcaption>Dead by Daylight meets Dungeons &amp; Dragons.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jLYEPAHt4PI" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>
"Her unwavering tenacity, wealth of survival expertise, and bravery are represented with three unique Perks to balance the scales in her favour," the Dead by Daylight team explains.
</p>
<p>
Lara is set to make her Dead by Daylight debut next month, on 16th July, as part of the game's Tomb Raider chapter. Ahead of that date, those wanting to put Lara through her paces sooner rather than later can take part in the limited-time public test-build on Steam, which is available now.
</p>
<p>
"With her experiences and skill set, Lara Croft perfectly embodies the characteristics needed to survive in The Fog and is right at home in the world of Dead by Daylight alongside other iconic characters. Though she may be well-prepared for the Trials ahead, in the Entity's twisted world, the future is never promised," Behaviour close.
</p>
<p>
Elsewhere in the news, the Dead by Daylight team recently announced a new 2v8 mode, as well as an update on spin-off titles, and a tease of a new Castlevania chapter coming later this year. 
</p>
<p>
You can check out <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/dead-by-daylight-adding-dungeons-dragons-and-castlevania-chapters-this-year">everything shown during last month's Dead by Daylight anniversary stream here</a>.

</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Epic Mickey Rebrushed To Release This September on PC and Consoles]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/epic-mickey-rebrushed-release-date/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/epic-mickey-rebrushed-to-release-this-september-on-pc-and-consoles.910719/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/epic-mickey-rebrushed-release-date/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Epic Mickey Rebrushed, the remake of the first entry in the series created by Deux Ex series creator <a href="https://wccftech.com/interview-warren-spector-system-shock-3-deus-ex-trilogy/">Warren Spector</a>'s Junction Point Studio, is launching this September on PC and consoles.</p>
<p>The game developed by Purple Lamp will be released on September 24th, 2024, on PC, PlayStation 5, PlayStation 4, Xbox Series X, Xbox Series S, Xbox One, and Nintendo Switch, as announced by a new trailer shared today. The game's standard and Collector's Editions are also available for pre-order now, the latter giving access to a special costume pack as well as 24-hour early access to the game, which won't be available on PC.</p>
<p><iframe title="Disney Epic Mickey: Rebrushed | Release Date Reveal | Collector’s Edition Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/M3UPoTalv4A?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Epic Mickey Rebrushed reimagines the original game developed by Junction Point Studio with improved visuals and some tweaks, such as new movement skills like dash, ground pound, and sprinting. Despite the gameplay tweaks, the game promises to be a faithful remake that will see players accompany Mickey Mouse in the Wasteland, a realm of forgotten Disney characters like Oswald the Rabbit, Walt Disney's first unlucky creation who was eventually replaced by Mickey Mouse in 1928.</p>
<p>Epic Mickey Rebrushed launches on PC, PlayStation 5, PlayStation 4, Xbox Series X, Xbox Series S, Xbox One, and Nintendo Switch on September 23rd, 2024.</p>

				

			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Where To Find Elden Ring: Shadow Of The Erdtree's Fire Knight Greatsword]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-shadow-erdtree-fire-knight-greatsword-1851558987</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/where-to-find-elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtrees-fire-knight-greatsword.910716/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-shadow-erdtree-fire-knight-greatsword-1851558987<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>The Fire Knight’s Greatsword is a Colossal Sword found in <em>Elden Ring</em>’s <em>Shadow of the Erdtree</em> expansion. This powerful armament not only looks intriguing, but can also deal some hefty damage to your foes, making it a sought-after armament for those interested in hitting baddies with slow but hard attacks.<br></p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="195502" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="The Most Sought After Elden Ring Sword Has A Storied History" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="307" data-playlist="195502,195624,196742" data-current="195502"><div><p>The Most Sought After Elden Ring Sword Has A Storied History</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195502/195502_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195502/195502_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195502/195502_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195502/195502_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/20979.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>Here’s what you need to know about the Fire Knight’s Greatsword and where to find it.</p><h2 id="h120448"><a id=""></a><strong>Fire Knight’s Greatsword stats and features</strong></h2><p>The Fire Knight’s Greatsword has a weight of 16.0 and requires the following stats to wield:</p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li>STR - 22</li><li>DEX - 18</li><li>FAI - 12</li></ul><p>The weapon comes equipped with Ash of War: Stamp. This Ash of War puts you in a stance that can prevent recoil from most attacks. You can follow this up with a heavy attack to perform a devastating upward slash that looks as cool as it sounds.</p><p>The Fire Knight’s Greatsword can be upgraded to +25 with standard Smithing Stones.</p><h2 id="h120449"><a id=""></a><strong>Fire Knight’s Greatsword item description</strong></h2><p>The Fire Knight’s Greatsword’s item description reads:</p><p>“Greatsword of the Fire Knights. A long, slender blade that undulates like fire. Blessed with a flame incantation. Further flame imbuement will amplify the effect and greatly increase the armament’s power.”</p><h2 id="h120450"><a id=""></a><strong>Where to find the Fire Knight’s Greatsword</strong></h2><p>You can find the Fire Knight’s Greatsword by defeating Fire Knights who are wielding, well, the Fire Knight’s Greatsword. These can be found in various locations throughout the Shadow Keep legacy dungeon in Scadu Altus.</p><p>To easily farm this, play through Shadow Keep until you reach an area with one of these sword-wielding Fire Knights on the left and a large staircase going down on the right. Walk down the staircase and open the shortcut back to the Main Gate Plaza Site of Grace.</p><figure id="" data-id="31b08799cd61fd49dbc025a2be8ef60b" data-recommend-id="image://31b08799cd61fd49dbc025a2be8ef60b" data-format="jpg" data-width="3840" data-height="2160" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A map showing the location of the Fire Knight Greatsword." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A map showing the location of the Fire Knight Greatsword." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->FromSoftware / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="31b08799cd61fd49dbc025a2be8ef60b" data-recommend-id="image://31b08799cd61fd49dbc025a2be8ef60b" data-format="jpg" data-width="3840" data-height="2160" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A map showing the location of the Fire Knight Greatsword." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Now you can quickly reach this Fire Knight using the shortcut, fast traveling back to the Main Gate Plaza Site of Grace to reset the encounter as many times as you need. Additionally, you can use a Silver-Pickled Fowl Foot to improve your chances of having the weapon drop.<br></p><p>Regardless of what you do, you may find yourself grinding for this for a while. Keep it up, though, and eventually you can claim the Fire Knight’s Greatsword for yourself.<br></p><p>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GTA Online: Bottom Dollar Bounties Update Out Now — Here’s What It Does]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/gta-online-bottom-dollar-bounties-update-out-now-heres-what-it-does</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gta-online-bottom-dollar-bounties-update-out-now-%E2%80%94-here%E2%80%99s-what-it-does.910713/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/gta-online-bottom-dollar-bounties-update-out-now-heres-what-it-does<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p><a href="https://www.ign.com/games/grand-theft-auto-online">GTA Online</a>’s big summer 2024 update, called Bottom Dollar Bounties, is out now across PlayStation 5, PlayStation 4, Xbox Series X and S, Xbox One, and PC alongside the release of patch 1.69 for Grand Theft Auto 5.</p><p>Players assume the role of “the new lead dog” for Bottom Dollar Bail Enforcement, and work with notorious bounty hunter Maude Eccles’ daughter, junior assistant bounty hunter Jenette, to take down targets.</p><p>Elsewhere, LSPD officer Vincent Effenburger provides new off-the-books Dispatch Work. New rides include three new Law Enforcement vehicles, below, new Drift Tuning upgrades for select vehicles, as well as new tools and props in the Creator.</p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Declasse Impaler SZ Cruiser</li><li>Bravado Greenwood Cruiser</li><li>Bravado Dorado Cruiser</li></ul><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div><h3>GTA Online: Bottom Dollar Bounties Screenshots</h3></div></output><p>The other new vehicles are the Enus Paragon S (Sports), the Bollokan Envisage (Sports), the Übermacht Niobe (Sports), the Annis Euros X32 (Coupe), the Invetero Coquette D1 (Sports Classic) and the Declasse Yosemite 1500 (Off-Road).</p><p>Today’s update also brings increased base GTA$ payouts for many activities, including Open Wheel Races, Taxi Work, A Superyacht Life, Lowriders Missions, Operation Paper Trail, Casino Story Missions, Gerald’s Last Play, Madrazo’s Dispatch Services, Premium Deluxe Repo Work, and Project Overthrow. Solo players also benefit from an increased timer when taking on Gunrunning and Biker Sell Missions.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>Rockstar teased further updates coming later this summer, including Martin Madrazo providing daily bounties. You’ll also be able to ride a Pegassi Pizza Boy scooter and help Pizza This... deliver pizzas around Los Santos. Expect an Independence Day event, a Halloween trip to North Yankton’s Ludendorff Cemetery, an “exciting new multi-stage head-to-head mode”, a new community Heist Challenge, and more coming to the game.</p><p>The GTA Online summer 2024 update comes amid increased excitement around <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/grand-theft-auto-vi"><u>GTA 6</u></a>. So far Rockstar has dropped a solitary, <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/gta-6-trailer-has-already-surpassed-grand-theft-auto-5s-reveal-with-more-than-100-million-views"><u>record-breaking trailer</u></a> for the game, due out fall 2025 on PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X and S. Rockstar is yet to detail its plan for GTA 6’s version of GTA Online, or say what becomes of the existing GTA Online once GTA 6 comes out. Until then, however, GTA Online remains hugely popular, bringing in hundreds of millions of dollars for parent company Take-Two each quarter.</p><h2>GTA 5 Title Update 1.69 Patch Notes (PS5 / PS4 / Xbox Series X|S / Xbox One / PC)</h2><blockquote data-theme="light"></blockquote><p><strong>[June 25, 2024] - New Content in Grand Theft Auto Online</strong></p><p>The Bottom Dollar Bounties update adds a new Bail Enforcement business property, new Dispatch Work in Freemode, new Vehicles, and a range of Creator additions as well as overall experience improvements.</p><p><strong>Bail Enforcement Office</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Purchasing this business provides new ways for players to earn money through bounty hunting</li><li>Bail Enforcement Office owners can hunt down new bounty targets, securing them alive to be processed or eliminated and delivered to the Los Santos County Coroner Office</li><li>Each day a Most Wanted target will be identified with a large bounty on their head. Three other standard targets will become available every hour.</li><li>Secured bounty targets are processed over time in the Bail Enforcement Office’s holding cell. Upon completion, cash will be added to the player’s wallet.</li><li>Bail Enforcement Office owners can purchase Agents that can be sent out to complete their own work, adding cash to the owner’s safe upon completion<ul data-cy="list"><li>Agents will also reduce the amount of time taken to process secured bounty targets</li></ul></li><li>The Bail Enforcement Office can be customized with a range of styles and includes a bounty transporter van, which can be upgraded with Armor Plating and used in Freemode</li><li>This property comes with new Awards as well as Career Progress Challenges on PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X|S consoles</li></ul><p><strong>Dispatch Work</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Players that own a Law Enforcement personal vehicle can access a new range of Freemode Dispatch Work provided by Vincent</li><li>While driving an owned Law Enforcement personal vehicle in Freemode, players can request Dispatch Work from Vincent directly or wait until Vincent contacts them</li><li>Players can find applicable Law Enforcement Vehicles on Warstock Cache &amp; Carry</li><li>Dispatch Work cannot be accessed when part of an Organization or Motorcycle Club</li></ul><p><strong>Vehicles</strong></p><p>Nine new vehicles have been added:</p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Enus Paragon S (Sports) – With Imani Tech</li><li>Bollokan Envisage (Sports) – With Imani Tech</li><li>Übermacht Niobe (Sports) – With HSW Upgrade (PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X|S only)</li><li>Annis Euros X32 (Coupe) – With HSW Upgrade (PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X|S only)</li><li>Invetero Coquette D1 (Sports Classic)</li><li>Declasse Yosemite 1500 (Off-Road)</li><li>Declasse Impaler SZ Cruiser (Emergency) – Law Enforcement Vehicle</li><li>Bravado Dorado Cruiser (Emergency) – Law Enforcement Vehicle</li><li>Bravado Greenwood Cruiser (Emergency) – Law Enforcement Vehicle</li></ul><p>Three existing vehicles are also receiving custom Drift Tuning upgrades, these can be applied to personal vehicles inside the LS Car Meet:</p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Vulcar Nebula Turbo (Sports Classic)<ul data-cy="list"><li>This vehicle is again available for sale on the Southern San Andreas Super Autos website</li></ul></li><li>Übermacht Cypher (Sports)</li><li>Übermacht Sentinel Widebody (Sports)</li></ul><p><strong>Economy Updates</strong></p><p>Base GTA$ payout rates for the following content have been increased:</p><ul data-cy="list"><li>A Superyacht Life (Contact Missions)</li><li>Lamar’s Lowriders (Contact Missions)</li><li>Operation Paper Trail (Contact Missions)</li><li>Casino Story (Contact Missions)</li><li>Gerald’s Last Play (Contact Missions)</li><li>Madrazo Dispatch Services (Contact Missions)</li><li>Premium Deluxe Repo Work (Contact Missions)</li><li>Project Overthrow (Contact Missions)</li><li>Open Wheel Races (Races)</li><li>Taxi Work (Freemode)</li></ul><p><strong>Cosmetics</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>150+ pieces of male clothing and accessories have been added to clothing stores</li><li>200+ pieces of female clothing and accessories have been added to clothing stores</li></ul><p><strong>Experience Improvements</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Several business Sell Missions have had their timers increased by 50% when launched solo:<ul data-cy="list"><li>All Biker businesses</li><li>Bunker business</li></ul></li><li>The armor values of the Sparrow and RM-10 Bombushka have been increased by 50%</li><li>Players’ snack inventories are now fully restocked upon launching Contact missions and Heists from lobbies</li><li>The button prompts upon failing a mission have been updated</li><li>Drag Races can now be played over a series of rounds</li><li>Multiple texts and emails sent to players have been spaced out over longer periods of time or removed</li><li>Players can now move an owned Avenger between their Hangar and Facility storage via the Interaction Menu</li><li>The minimum player count required to launch the Assault on Cayo Perico mode has been increased from 4 to 8 players</li><li>An advanced options menu has been added to the Race Lobby Menu, containing many of the least used race options</li><li>The Music Locker Strobes section of the Interaction Menu has been moved to the Pause Menu</li><li>The Nightclub and Office Garage menus have been divided into separate sub menus when requesting vehicles from the Mechanic</li><li>The rank requirement for purchasing properties has been removed</li><li>A new starting grid option has been added when playing races in a series, sorting players based on their positions in the previous race</li><li>A link to the Community Guidelines has been added to the Welcome screen and other select alert screens</li><li>Custom Arena War vehicle names are now only visible to the local player</li></ul><p><strong>GTA+ Updates</strong></p><p><strong>The Vinewood Club App</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>GTA+ Members have access to a new phone app, which grants a range of features:<ul data-cy="list"><li>Claiming the earnings from owned business safes remotely</li><li>Purchasing ammo without paying a convenience charge</li><li>Requesting and purchasing Car Club vehicles has been moved to this app</li></ul></li></ul><p><strong>The Vinewood Club Garage Vehicle Workshop</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>A Vehicle Workshop has been added to the Vinewood Club Garage, allowing players to modify their stored vehicles at an exclusive 10% discount</li></ul><p><strong>Creator Updates</strong></p><p>Several updates have been added to the Creator as part of this update</p><p><strong>Drag and Drift Race Creators</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Players with an LS Car Meet membership can now create their own Drag and Drift races inside the Creator</li></ul><p><strong>General</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Ambient weather options are now implemented when players take a photo for their created mode</li><li>The RUNE Zhaba is now available as an Off-Road vehicle option in the Creator</li></ul><p><strong>Race Creator</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Additional units have been added to the Race Creator, these are placed scenarios that can consist of people and vehicles<ul data-cy="list"><li>People:<ul data-cy="list"><li>Race crowds of 1–5 people, previously only larger crowds were available</li><li>A photographer taking photos of the race</li></ul></li><li>Vehicles:<ul data-cy="list"><li>Lowrider vehicle using hydraulics</li><li>A car doing a donut</li><li>A car doing a burnout</li></ul></li></ul></li><li>The existing race crowd units can now stand in a range of different poses</li><li>Race crowds can now be triggered to cheer and wave when a player gets close</li><li>When testing a Race, players can choose which checkpoint to start testing from</li><li>Flaming barrel props can now have their color changed</li><li>Players can now preview different audio tracks while in the Race Creator</li></ul><p><strong>Prop Additions</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Additional small stunt track props have been added</li><li>Additional track smoothing props have been added</li><li>Road paddle props have been added</li></ul><p><strong>Fixes</strong></p><p>The Bottom Dollar Bounties update brings a range of fixes to various issues</p><p><strong>Game Stability and Performance</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Fixed multiple crashes and issues affecting stability that occurred in GTAV</li></ul><p><strong>Matchmaking and Networking</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Fixed multiple issues that affected network stability in GTA Online</li></ul><p><strong>Content</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in destroyed Signal Jammer collectibles being tracked incorrectly</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in players not unlocking the Skull Santa finish for the Special Carbine upon winning five games of Entourage (Festive Remix)</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in players not being able to start Lowriders missions after completing them on a different character</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in players not being unable to drop cargo during Special Cargo Sell Missions</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in players not being able to progress after completing VIP Contract prep mission – Data Recovery</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in players being unable to progress through Casino Work – Best Laid Plans shortly after launching</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in unowned vehicles appearing in the personal vehicle space of Salvage Yards</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in players having access to their owned weapons when playing Short Trips – Seed Capital</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in enemy blips not appearing during The McTony Robbery – Sonar Equipment mission</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in players being unable to launch Tow Truck Service missions</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in players being unable to progress when playing A Superyacht Life – Icebreaker</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in planes falling to the floor during Air Race countdowns</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in other players’ Kosatkas interfering with the Cargo Ship during The Cargo Ship Robbery</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in players getting stuck in an air vent during The Cluckin’ Bell Farm Raid – Concealed Weapons</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in players being unable to swap inventories during The Cluckin’ Bell Farm Raid – Concealed Weapons</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in players respawning outside of the factory during The Cluckin’ Bell Raid – Scene of the Crime</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in players being unable to progress through The Cayo Perico Heist Finale when the leader has died</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in players transforming into a land vehicle during a flying section of Transform Races</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in players coming to an immediate stop upon passing a checkpoint during Transform Races</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in the race countdown not starting during Transform Races</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in players being unable to access the Interaction Menu during The Pacific Standard Job – Convoy</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in players being unable to progress after leaving Mason’s apartment during Operation Paper Trail – Intelligence</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in P Moss taking off without players inside the Avenger during Operation Overthrow – Unconventional Warfare</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in players not being able to finish The Podium Robbery – Scope Out</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in players being unable to request personal vehicles during LSA Operation – Direct Action</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in players being unable to lose their wanted level during The Doomsday Heist – Setup: Server Farm</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in hacking minigames being more difficult when playing on ultrawide screen setups</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in Hao’s Special Works Time Trial not appearing for players that haven’t completed it</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in players being unable to send photos to Pavel during The Cayo Perico Heist – Scope Out</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in the mission not progressing after delivering the two lowriders back to Lamar during Lowriders – Peace Offerings</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in incorrect prompts to leave the Avenger appearing when entering an owned Thruster during Project Overthrow – Reporting for Duty</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in players being unable to obtain the VIP pass during The Duggan Robbery – VIP Pass</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in players being unable to send photos to Jamal during The Gangbanger Robbery – Scope Out</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in players leaving their F-160 Raiju during Project Overthrow – On Parade</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in players being unable to pick up snowballs during Snowball Fight Deathmatches</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in players getting stuck when interacting with Street Dealers</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in players being unable to complete Terrorbyte Client Job – Robbery in Progress</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in weapons given during Hot Swap Deathmatches not persisting when returning to Freemode</li></ul><p><strong>Properties</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in stolen vehicles disappearing after completing a successful Salvage Yard Robbery</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in the roulette game inside The Diamond Casino getting stuck</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted players’ Tow Truck disappearing from the Salvage Yard</li><li>Fixed an issue that prevented players from entering an Auto Shop with no vehicle slots remaining</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in CEOs being unable to enter their Agency while an Executive Search is active</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in players becoming stuck when attempting to enter a Nightclub in a vehicle</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in players not entering their Acid Lab when selecting “enter with nearby friends and crew” inside the Freakshop</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in players not sitting up from their Agency office chair</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in players being unable to interact with the Drone Station inside Arcades</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in players getting stuck after interacting with the Shiny Wasabi Kitty Claw machine inside an Arcade</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in the Auto Shop 5% discount not being applied to Wheel Type and Wheel Color</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in players being unable to mod personal vehicles inside their Auto Shop</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in vehicles colliding with each other when multiple players were modding vehicles in the same Auto Shop</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in players being unable to leave their Motorcycle Club Clubhouse on a personal vehicle</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in players being unable to interact with the laptop inside their Bunker</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in players getting stuck when leaving Hao’s Special Works inside the LS Car Meet</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in players’ personal vehicles becoming invisible when leaving the Test Track inside the LS Car Meet</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in players spawning far away when leaving the LS Car Meet</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in personal vehicle blips not appearing on the map when another player is test driving a vehicle inside the LS Car Meet</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in players being unable to get a makeover inside the Spa of their Diamond Casino Penthouse</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in players being able to move while using the Place Decorations Menu inside their Diamond Casino Penthouse</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in players getting stuck when attempting to enter their Diamond Casino Penthouse from Freemode</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in the Acid Lab not appearing inside the Freakshop</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in the Tow Truck not appearing inside the Salvage Yard after purchase</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in players being unexpectedly kicked out when driving another player’s vehicle in the LS Car Meet Test Track</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in players not being registered as a CEO or MC Leader after purchasing an Office or Motorcycle Clubhouse for the first time</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in players being unable to access their Nightclub PC</li></ul><p><strong>Vehicles</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in BMX bikes behaving differently when bunny hopping</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in incorrect speeds being displayed during Highest Speed Freemode Events</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in players being unable to request their Avenger in Freemode</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in Suspension mods not being available for the Karin Asterope GZ</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in custom license plates for vehicles claimed from the Salvage Yard not persisting</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in players not being able to see the tracers of the F-160 Raiju’s cannons</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in the camera clipping through the Avenger when modding a vehicle inside</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in players with no owned garages losing their personal vehicle</li><li>The Declasse Impaler SZ’s vehicle class has been updated from Sedan to Muscle</li></ul><p><strong>Miscellaneous</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in players losing ammo when joining a new session</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in players being unable to change gears during Drag Races when using alternative control types</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in players being unable to access the Cockpit Access settings for the Avenger in the Interaction Menu</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in players being unable to swap outfits via the Interaction Menu when wearing full body outfits</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in event exclusive weapon liveries that had been previously earned being unavailable</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in players gaining negative amounts of body armor when purchasing from Ammunation</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in the Snowball Launcher weapon being unusable when on a Motorcycle</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in players being unable to use snacks or equip armor via the weapon wheel</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in players being unable to add Stunt Races to a Playlist</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in players being able to see under the map when spectating a player in their Kosatka</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in players being unable to use the default name “An Organization” when creating an Organization for the first time</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in SFX previews not playing when editing clips in the Rockstar Editor</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in TVs in owned apartments not showing anything</li></ul><p><strong>PlayStation Specific</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in players being unable to accept invites to GTA Online after purchasing PlayStation Plus with GTAV running</li></ul><p><strong>Xbox Specific</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in the Xbox keyboard continuously appearing after editing an owned garage tooltip</li></ul><p><strong>PC Specific</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Fixed numerous issues relating to stability and security</li></ul><p><strong>PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X|S Only</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in GTA+ alerts triggering during a Race and bringing the player’s vehicle to a sudden stop.</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in players getting stuck when moving vehicles via the Vehicle Organization Menu</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in GTA+ Members being unable to enter The Vinewood Club Garage with their personal vehicle when part of an Organization or Motorcycle Club</li></ul><p><strong>Creator</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in conflicting button inputs when using the Override Position Menu on PC</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in Trap to Activate options under Arena props not being able to be toggled when placed</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in Trailer Units being unable to be placed</li><li>Fixed an issue that resulted in players getting stuck when testing a King of the Hill mode</li></ul><p><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon Is Giving Away 15 Free Games For Prime Day 2024]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/amazon-prime-free-games-prime-day-2024/1100-6524480/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/amazon-is-giving-away-15-free-games-for-prime-day-2024.910707/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/amazon-prime-free-games-prime-day-2024/1100-6524480/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6524480">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/amazon-prime-day-deals/">Amazon Prime Day</a> will officially be held <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/when-is-amazon-prime-day-2024/1100-6524467/" data-ref-id="1100-6524467">July 16-17</a>, and to celebrate, Prime Gaming is giving away a bunch of great games leading up to the event. From now until July 11, Amazon will gradually unlock 15 free PC games. The lineup includes an all-time classic Star Wars game, a modern stealth classic, Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles, a pair of gunslinging action games set in the Wild West, and more. </p><p>Several games are already available, and you can grab the multiplayer subterfuge game <strong>Deceive Inc.</strong>, try out some puzzling adventures in <strong>Tearstone: Thieves of the Heart</strong>, take on the stock market in <strong>The Invisible Hand</strong>, and fill some bandits with lead in <strong>Call of Juarez</strong>.</p><p>On June 27, you can check out 2D open-world exploration in <strong>Forager</strong>, look for an ace up your sleeve in <strong>Card Shark</strong>, survive against zombie hordes in <strong>Heaven Dust 2</strong>, and prepare yourself for some fast-paced action in <strong>Soulstice</strong>. Other highlights this month include the underrated assassination sandbox of <strong>Hitman Absolution</strong>, the radical beat-'em-up action of <strong>Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles: Shredder's Revenge</strong>, and<strong> Star Wars: Knights of the Old Republic 2</strong>, a fantastic sequel to a brilliant RPG.</p><p>Once you claim the free games from Prime Gaming, they are yours to keep forever--even if your subscription expires. If you aren't a member, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/prime/pipeline/signup?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" rel="nofollow ">you can sign up for Amazon Prime</a> for even just one month to take advantage of the subscription and score some great freebies. You can see the full list below for everything that'll be available for the next couple of weeks.</p><h2>Prime Gaming free games for Amazon Prime Day 2024</h2><h3>Now available</h3><ul><li>Deceive Inc.</li><li>Tearstone: Thieves of the Heart</li><li>The Invisible Hand</li><li>Call of Juarez</li></ul><h3>June 27</h3><ul><li>Forager</li><li>Card Shark</li><li>Heaven Dust 2</li><li>Soulstice</li></ul><h3>July 3</h3><ul><li>Wall World</li><li>Hitman Absolution</li><li>Call of Juarez: Bound in Blood</li></ul><h3>July 11</h3><ul><li>Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles: Shredder's Revenge</li><li>Star Wars: Knights of the Old Republic 2</li><li>Alex Kidd in Miracle World DX</li><li>Samurai Bringer</li></ul><div data-embed-type="pinbox" data-ref-id="4304">  <ul>                              <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/lord-of-the-rings-4k-blu-ray-box-set-amazon-preorder/1100-6524366/">Lord Of The Rings 4K Blu-Ray Steelbook Collection Is Back In Print, Preorders Live At Amazon</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/official-xbox-controllers-get-significant-discounts-at-amazon-and-walmart/1100-6524341/">Official Xbox Controllers Get Significant Discounts At Amazon And Walmart</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/zelda-links-awakening-is-back-in-stock-for-40-at-amazon/1100-6511630/">Get Ready For Zelda: Echoes Of Wisdom With This Great Link's Awakening Deal</a></li>                          <li>         <span>+ Show More Best Gaming &amp; Tech Deals This Week Links (2)</span>       </li>          <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/save-big-on-nintendo-switch-joy-con-controllers-at-amazon-and-walmart/1100-6523566/">Save Big On Nintendo Switch Joy-Con Controllers At Amazon And Walmart</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/inside-out-2-fans-should-check-out-the-new-lego-mood-cube-set/1100-6524400/">Inside Out 2 Fans Should Check Out The New Lego Mood Cube Set</a></li>   </ul> </div>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/108490194306897153177?rel=author">Darryn Bonthuys</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This New Game Is Hide-And-Seek With A Deadly Twist, Including Flamethrowers And Bear Traps]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/this-new-game-is-hide-and-seek-with-a-deadly-twist-including-flamethrowers-and-bear-traps/1100-6524486/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/this-new-game-is-hide-and-seek-with-a-deadly-twist-including-flamethrowers-and-bear-traps.910704/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/this-new-game-is-hide-and-seek-with-a-deadly-twist-including-flamethrowers-and-bear-traps/1100-6524486/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6524486">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Velan Studios, the team behind Knockout City and Mario Kart Live: Home Circuit, has announced its next game--and it is completely different. Midnight Murder Club is a six-player first-person hide-and-seek game where players begin with only a revolver and flashlight as they try to survive the night.</p><p>The entire game is played in an old Victorian mission, Wormwood Manor, in pitch black darkness. "The only light you'll ever see will come from you or your opponents," Velan Studios <a href="https://www.velanstudios.com/post/midnight-murder-club-hide-seek-and-shoot-in-the-dark" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">said in a blog post</a>.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5HRu6wQpHN0" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/5HRu6wQpHN0" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>With a flashlight and a revolver, players have a simple goal: survive all night.</p><p>"It's a high-stakes game of hide, seek, and shoot in the dark. Listen carefully for footsteps echoing down the corridors, voices crying out in the shadows, and the telltale creak of a door slowly opening behind you," Velan Studios said.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4324522-mmc.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4324522" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4324522-mmc.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4324522"></a><figcaption>Introducing Midnight Murder Club</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4324522-mmc.jpg"></figure><figure data-embed-type="gallery" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4324523-mmc1.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4324524-mmc2.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4324523,1300-4324524" data-resize-urls="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1179/11799911/4324523-mmc1.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1179/11799911/4324524-mmc2.jpg"><p>Gallery</p>     <img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4324523-mmc1.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4324524-mmc2.jpg"></figure><p>As players explore the manor and its many rooms, they'll find things like a flame thrower to immolate enemies and an electrified bear trap to catch foes. There is also a Tommy gun that players can acquire to get the edge. Velan Studios says Midnight Murder Club also has a variety of modes, including team deathmatch and objective-based modes. More details will be announced later. </p><p>Midnight Murder Club is targeting a release this fall on PC. Fans can <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2698870/Midnight_Murder_Club/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">wishlist it on Steam now.</a></p><p>Velan Studios was founded by the brothers Guha and Karthik Bala, who founded Vicarious Visions before that. Velan Studios worked with Nintendo on Mario Kart Live: Home Circuit and then partnered with EA on the "dodgebrawl" game Knockout City. Velan later split off from EA, but Knockout City <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/knockout-citys-closure-is-part-of-a-painful-truth-of-the-games-industry-studio-says/1100-6511390/" data-ref-id="1100-6511390">couldn't attract or retain a big enough audience and its official servers closed in 2023.</a></p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Double Fine and Undead Labs vets launch experimental web game studio]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/production/double-fine-and-undead-labs-vets-launch-experimental-web-game-studio</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/double-fine-and-undead-labs-vets-launch-experimental-web-game-studio.910698/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/production/double-fine-and-undead-labs-vets-launch-experimental-web-game-studio<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Industry veterans Brandon Dillon and Richard Foge have launched a new studio called 2weeks to rapidly create experimental projects for the open web.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Dillon previously spent over six years at Oculus, most recently as the company's product management director. Prior to that he served as the technical director on </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Grim Fandango Remastered</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and product lead on </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Hack 'n' Slash</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> at Double Fine.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Foge spent four years at Possibility Space, which was </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/-distributed-studio-possibility-space-abruptly-shut-down-by-prytania-media">shuttered by co-founder Jeff Strain earlier this year</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. He also worked at </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>State of Decay</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> developer Undead Labs for almost a decade as design director.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The pair explained their core development pillars are rapid prototyping, experimentation, and transparency. "Our goal is to whip up small, experimental prototypes at lightning speed and ship them straight to you on the open web," they added in a press release.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Why the web? Because we want to get games in your hands fast. No app installations. No high-end devices required–just pure gaming joy for everyone as quick as we can serve it up."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Dillon and Foge say it's an approach that will let them test "wild" ideas that don't work in a traditional model and share them with players much earlier. They'll also be able so solicit direct feedback so they can quickly improve their experimental platter.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Several studios founded by industry veterans dedicated to shipping smaller games faster have surfaced in 2024. These include companies like </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/production/why-the-former-borderlands-boss-is-betting-big-on-uefn-development">Barnyard Games</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, which are prioritizing development on user generated content platforms like Unreal Engine for </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Fortnite</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">2weeks' debut release is strategic title called </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Homestretch Bet </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">that combines the "thrill of horse racing with the strategy of Texas Hold 'Em." Players must bet on their favorite horse based on their stats and the luck of the draw as the race unfolds.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The studio intends to keep fan in the loop by way of newsletter that will roll out regularly. Those eager to see 2weeks' development philosophy in action can </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://homestretchbet.com/">try Homestretch Bet right here</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author(s)</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">News Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer news editor Chris Kerr is an award-winning journalist and reporter with over a decade of experience in the game industry. His byline has appeared in notable print and digital publications including Edge, Stuff, Wireframe, International Business Times, and&nbsp;</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="http://pocketgamer.biz/">PocketGamer.biz</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. Throughout his career, Chris has covered major industry events including GDC, PAX Australia, Gamescom, Paris Games Week, and Develop Brighton. He has featured on the judging panel at The Develop Star Awards on multiple occasions and appeared on BBC Radio 5 Live to discuss breaking news.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Midnight Society ousts co-founder Dr Disrespect over 'allegation']]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/midnight-society-ousts-co-founder-dr-disrespect-over-allegation-</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/midnight-society-ousts-co-founder-dr-disrespect-over-allegation.910695/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/midnight-society-ousts-co-founder-dr-disrespect-over-allegation-<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="captioned-content"><p><span>Image via Dr Disrespect / YouTube</span></p></div><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Midnight Society co-founder Guy Beahm, better known as Dr Disrespect, has been ousted from the studio after company leadership become aware of "an allegation" against the popular streamer.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The studio was founded by a group of industry veterans including former Call of Duty lead Robert Bowling. It's currently working on a multiplayer 'vertical extraction shooter' and has scaled to over 50 employees.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"On Friday evening we became aware of an allegation against one of our co-founder’s Guy Beahm aka Dr Disrespect. We assumed his innocence and began speaking with parties involved. And in order to maintain our principles and standards as a studio and individuals, we needed to act," </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://x.com/12am/status/1805341504086622355">reads a statement shared by Midnight Society on X</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"For this reason, we are terminating our relationship with Guy Beahm immediately. While these facts are difficult to hear and even more difficult to accept, it is our duty to act with dignity on behalf of all individuals involved, especially the fifty-five developers and families we have employed along with our community of players."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Beahm was previously a mainstay on Twitch, but was banned from the streaming platform in 2020 without explanation. </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/6/23/24183875/dr-disrespect-twitch-ban-explanation">A recent report from The Verge</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> published on June 23, 2024, alleges that ban was the result of messages sent by Beahm to a minor via (now defunct) Twitch messaging tool Whispers.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">One former Twitch employee claims Beahm attempted to arrange a meeting with that person at TwitchCon. Those comments appear to </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://x.com/evoli/status/1804309358106546676">corroborate an X post from Cody Conners</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, a former member of Twitch's strategic partnerships team, which states "he got banned because got caught sexting a minor in the then existing Twitch whispers product. He was trying to meet up with her at TwitchCon. The powers that be could read in plain text."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Conners didn't specifically name Beahm, but The Verge understands he was the subject of the post.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://x.com/DrDisrespect/status/1804577136998776878">Beahm denied those allegations in an X post on June 22</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. "Listen, I'm obviously tied to legal obligations from the settlement with Twitch but I just need to say what I can say since this is the fucking internet," he wrote. "I didn’t do anything wrong, all this has been probed and settled, nothing illegal, no wrongdoing was found, and I was paid."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The streamer sued Twitch over his ban in 2020 before eventually settling over a year later. At that time, Beahm said "I have resolved my legal dispute with Twitch. No party admits to any wrongdoing.”</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author(s)</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">News Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer news editor Chris Kerr is an award-winning journalist and reporter with over a decade of experience in the game industry. His byline has appeared in notable print and digital publications including Edge, Stuff, Wireframe, International Business Times, and&nbsp;</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="http://pocketgamer.biz/">PocketGamer.biz</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. Throughout his career, Chris has covered major industry events including GDC, PAX Australia, Gamescom, Paris Games Week, and Develop Brighton. He has featured on the judging panel at The Develop Star Awards on multiple occasions and appeared on BBC Radio 5 Live to discuss breaking news.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Atari 50 Expansion Adds Over 30 Games And New Timelines This October]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gameinformer.com/2024/06/25/atari-50-expansion-adds-over-30-games-and-new-timelines-this-october</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/atari-50-expansion-adds-over-30-games-and-new-timelines-this-october.910692/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gameinformer.com/2024/06/25/atari-50-expansion-adds-over-30-games-and-new-timelines-this-october<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p>Atari 50: The Anniversary Celebration is already a fantastic history lesson and playable compilation of Atari’s heyday, but it’s about to become even more comprehensive. The 2022 interactive documentary is getting an expansion that adds new timelines and 39 games.</p>

<p>This new version of the game is called Atari 50: The Anniversary Celebration Expanded Edition, and it arrives on October 25. It will be released as DLC to Atari 50 owners and as a standalone title, both digitally and physically. Developer Digital Eclipse (which Atari <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/2023/10/31/atari-to-acquire-retro-game-restorer-digital-eclipse">acquired</a> in 2023) is bolstering the compilation with two new timelines.</p>

<p>First is "The Wider World of Atari", which features 19 playable games and eight video segments. Topics discussed include Pong creator Al Acorn discussing the birth of Breakout, a spotlight on artist Evelyn Soto, who helped create Atari’s "Fuji" logo, and a deep dive into Stern Electronics’ Berzerk.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The second timeline is called "The First Console War" and includes 20 playable games. It features six video segments and focuses on the rivalry between the Atari 2600 and Mattel’s Intellivision, with interviews from former Intellivision game director Don Daglow, Activision’s David Crane and Garry Kitchen, M Network programmer Jne Terjung, and more. This timeline also features playable M Network games (which, for the unaware, were Mattel-produced games for the 2600) and rare Atari 2600 and 5200 prototypes.&nbsp;</p>












<article data-embed-button="image_browser_uploader" data-entity-embed-display="view_mode:file.body_default_rendered" data-entity-embed-display-settings="{&quot;link_url&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;link_target&quot;:0,&quot;link_original&quot;:0,&quot;image_source&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;embed_source&quot;:0,&quot;image_caption&quot;:&quot;Atari 50: The Anniversary Celebration Expanded Edition Steelbook Version (Switch only)&quot;,&quot;embed_caption&quot;:0,&quot;content_warning&quot;:0}" data-entity-type="file" data-entity-uuid="20851c28-4193-41a7-a891-87a50b2a3bc9" data-langcode="en">



<p>Atari 50: The Anniversary Celebration Expanded Edition Steelbook Version (Switch only)</p>

</article><p>Atari 50: The Anniversary Celebration Expanded Edition will be available for PlayStation and Xbox consoles, Switch, and PC. The standalone standard edition costs $39.99. The physical Switch version is getting an exclusive Steelbook version for $49.99 and includes extras like a replica of Al Acorn's business card, Atari 2600 art cards, and miniature arcade marquee signs (as seen in the graphic above). Atari did not reveal how much the add-on will cost for existing Atari 50 owners.&nbsp;</p>

<p>For more on the collection, read our glowing review of the original game <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/review/atari-50-the-anniversary-celebration/a-half-century-of-gaming-history-stuffed-into-an">here</a>. Be sure to also listen to our interview with current Atari CEO Wade Rosen on this episode of <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/2023/09/22/90-minutes-with-atari-ceo-wade-rosen-all-things-nintendo">All Things Nintendo</a>.</p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>