<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 20:41:07 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Treating Blue Prince Like A Daily Crossword Has Cracked It Wide Open]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/treating-blue-prince-like-a-daily-crossword-has-cracked-it-wide-open/1100-6531243/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/treating-blue-prince-like-a-daily-crossword-has-cracked-it-wide-open.1178052/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/treating-blue-prince-like-a-daily-crossword-has-cracked-it-wide-open/1100-6531243/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6531243">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Blue Prince is one of the greatest games of the moment, and the roguelike puzzler has encouraged a lot of discussion about the best possible way to make sense of its confounding nature. Considering the ever-changing halls of its setting, I understand how one could come to their own conclusion on how to best <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/blue-prince-guides-hub/1100-6530716/">resolve its countless mysteries</a>. I happen to have my own method, and it's been working wonders for me. You see, I've been treating Blue Prince less and less like a roguelike, where you are expected to cycle through runs ad nauseam, and more like the daily crosswords that often fill my days. Though the two might seem quite distant, I'd argue there are more than enough similarities to warrant the parallels, and so far, the approach seems to be a real winner.</p><p dir="ltr">Let me first set the stage, though. Blue Prince, which tasks players with exploring the constantly shifting rooms of a manor in search of a hidden 46th one, has quickly become the game du jour since it was released earlier this year and for good reason: It's an utterly enthralling experience with <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/2024s-best-games-let-me-figure-it-out/1100-6528592/">layers upon layers of mysteries</a> to unspool. And since it has ensnared just about everyone I've seen pick it up--in both positive and negative ways--I have been drowning in well-reasoned criticisms of its mechanics as well as rapturous acclaim over its novelty. I've similarly bumped up against some frustrating walls that I found particularly hard to break through, but the thing that has really changed how I play Blue Prince, and simultaneously increased my enjoyment of it, was this much-needed shift in perspective that has been incredibly illuminating.</p><p dir="ltr">I promise you, Blue Prince has not in fact rotted my brain. I do have a case here, even if it may sound like gibberish externalized outside of my head for the first time. First and foremost, I've found that some of the folks who have bristled against Blue Prince (a perfectly fine reaction, <a href="https://www.pastemagazine.com/games/blue-prince/no-you-dont-have-to-play-blue-prince-or-any-other-game" rel="nofollow ">not everything is for everyone</a>!) have seemed to try and brute force their way through the game. Alternatively, I've been taking it at what can only be described as a near-glacial pace. I get on the game and do a handful of runs--maybe two or three at a time--that prioritize room discovery and pushing forward on a single thread until there's some turn or new discovery that further cracks the game's facade. Sometimes it's as simple as a new note to turn over in the quietest moments of my day, and sometimes it's making a perspective-shifting find that <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/platanoranger.bsky.social/post/3lmxw4kqgc22m" rel="nofollow ">melts my brain</a>.</p><p dir="ltr">Personally, this methodology lets me jot down notes and be more deliberate about where I focus my dwindling brain power (I'm so tired, guys) and avoid being overwhelmed by the sheer scope of Blue Prince and ultimately being turned off by it. I know people whose playthroughs are trending towards a hundred hours if they aren't already north of that, and the community is jointly trying to solve some of its meta puzzles not unlike last year's mystery-laden platformer <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/animal-well-review-going-deeper/1900-6418225/">Animal Well</a>. Consider this approach my attempt at protecting my own peace and secondarily prolonging my satisfaction with Blue Prince so that I don't sour on it before it gets too good.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/123/1239113/4485423-blueprince.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4485423" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/123/1239113/4485423-blueprince.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4485423"></a><figcaption>Blue Prince's magnifying glass</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/123/1239113/4485423-blueprince.jpeg"></figure><p dir="ltr">However there's more to this comparison than just my peace of mind, and I'd seriously note the similarities between the two if you're still doubtful. Both Blue Prince and a crossword take place on a grid. The former may present itself as a first-person puzzle game, but this feels like the first of Blue Prince's many tricks it revels in playing on the player. Open up the in-game map and you are treated not to a revelatory illustration or document, but an empty grid, not unlike a crossword. Not to give too much away, but it's also probably best thought of as that when pursuing some of Blue Prince's later and more enigmatic threads.</p><p dir="ltr">Moreover, despite the rigidity of the grid, the exact contents of the puzzles are constantly shifting. At the start of each run in Blue Prince, the manor effectively resets, and it's on the player to draft the next room from a randomly picked "hand" of cards. Every day, the crossword sometimes has different dimensions (especially when drawing a distinction between the weekday and weekends), features new blanks, and the shape of these blanks and white spaces could form an intriguing shape meant to clue players into a unifying theme. Both leverage visual motifs and more explicitly laid breadcrumbs to trick the player into accidentally solving a larger puzzle by picking away at smaller ones nested within the former.</p><p dir="ltr">To that end, clues in an especially devious crossword will often be in concert with one another. Like inside jokes, you don't entirely get one without the others, but cracking even one seems to suddenly give you the language or cipher to piece together another. Blue Prince functions in a pretty similar way, leading the player by the hand to disparate elements, like rooms with mechanics that don't initially present as things that interact with one another or tools that might not logically function the way you think they would. Though it may initially confound, Blue Prince asks you to put these components together to unlock the next step in the grander scheme of things. "How do I ensure I get x tool to find y clue in z room reliably when the placement of each of these elements is randomly generated?"</p><p dir="ltr">I don't know, maybe by taking the exact thing I'm describing--the combination of tools and mechanics in sometimes esoteric ways--and considering the bigger picture to manipulate the game in your favor. There are coat checks everywhere for those with eyes to see. And when you hit that serendipitous "aha" moment where the puzzles, both big and small, click into place, the satisfaction of that sequence tugs the player ever deeper into the tide, whether that be into another of Blue Prince's layers or just another sophistically crafted crossword.</p><p>My appreciation of the daily crossword, a thing that I do damn near all the time thanks to brilliant games like <a href="https://www.puzzmo.com/today" rel="nofollow ">Puzzmo</a>, almost appears to have trained me for a title like Blue Prince, which seems delighted to play with and remix some of its tenets into something both new and vaguely familiar. Thewholething is a puzzle. Its construction, its contents, and the logic behind their placements. They're so uncannily similar I'd be surprised if the game didn't take some kind of inspiration from the renowned and timeless classic. And maybe along the way, Blue Prince picked up a thing or two that'll turn it into a classic in its own right in due time. For now though, I'm really relishing taking it a thread and a handful of days at a time, and am feeling all the better for it.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WoW One-Button Rotation Tool Will Basically Play The Game For You]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/wow-one-button-rotation-tool-will-basically-play-the-game-for-you/1100-6531244/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/wow-one-button-rotation-tool-will-basically-play-the-game-for-you.1178049/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/wow-one-button-rotation-tool-will-basically-play-the-game-for-you/1100-6531244/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6531244">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Blizzard continues to bake features and capabilities into <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/world-of-warcraft/" data-ref-id="5000-3919">World of Warcraft</a> previously relegated to third-party add-ons, but it's going a step further with the newly announced Rotation Assist option coming in the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/best-mmorpgs/2900-5436/" data-ref-id="2900-5436">MMORPG's</a> next patch.</p><p dir="ltr">As announced by WoW game director Ion Hazzikostas in a new episode of the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-hqJ210XWeU" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">WoWCast</a>, the new optional UI feature is coming as part of WoW's 11.1.7 update. It will make it so the game's UI will display which ability a player should use next to deal optimal damage, mimicking the functionality of the popular add-on Hekili Priority Helper. According to WoW add-on manager Curse Forge, Hekili has been downloaded more than 56 million times.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-hqJ210XWeU" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/-hqJ210XWeU" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p dir="ltr">However, WoW's Rotation Assist tool will actually go even further beyond add-ons like Hekili by having an option to simplify WoW's gameplay into a single button, one that will serve as an "auto rotation" that will automatically use the next optimal ability.</p><p dir="ltr">There will be some penalty to using the single-button rotation option in the form of a small global cooldown penalty. The longer wait to cycle between abilities means those using it will perform worse than a skilled player doing the same rotation without assistance, but it's still a huge change for Blizzard's 20-year-old MMO. Hazzikostas said the option of the single-button rotation is being added for accessibility purposes, as well as for those who don't care about playing the game at a high-level or learning their class.</p><p dir="ltr">"We want to make sure this is for accessibility purposes," Hazzikostas said. "That it's there for people who maybe, honestly, aren't interested in the gameplay of mastering their spec. They want to explore Azeroth and experience the story, and mechanics get in the way of that sometimes. This should be for them. Ideally, this is not a tool where someone is being told by their raid leader to stop trying to DPS manually and just turn on the one button mode to meet some DPS check. That we want to give you the tools to go through that organic progression naturally."</p><p dir="ltr">The announcement of the Rotation Assist feature comes as part of larger discussion between Hazzikostas, WoW content creator Dratnos, and Team Liquid guild leader Max about Blizzard's philosophy when it comes to add-ons, expanding the base capabilities of WoW's UI, and how the game is designed around some of the information only add-ons can currently provide.</p><p dir="ltr">Hazzikostas said while he doesn't have any specific dates, the team is also looking at building a DPS meter (the most popular WoW add-on by a large margin, he said) into the base UI, as well as improvements to nameplates and more raid encounter information, like a timeline of upcoming boss abilities.</p><p dir="ltr">"We are looking at all the places where players are saying, 'You need this WeakAura, you need this add-on to be competitive', and asking ourselves, 'How do we change our game to make that not the case?'"</p><p dir="ltr">It's a path Blizzard has already been on for several years, starting with a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/wow-dragonflight-players-have-a-few-notes-on-the-games-ui-overhaul/1100-6508658/" data-ref-id="1100-6508658">customizable UI overhaul in WoW's Dragonflight expansion</a> and most <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/wow-april-22-update-will-finally-offer-an-easy-alternative-to-a-critical-ui-add-on/1100-6530701/" data-ref-id="1100-6530701">recently with the introduction of the Cooldown Manager</a> to the game's base UI, a replacement for the popular add-on WeakAuras.</p><p dir="ltr">At the end of the video, Hazzikostas made clear none of Blizzard's decisions were set in stone going forward on the subject of add-ons and that it's listening to the community for its feedback However, he also laid out Blizzard's current philosophy on how it's approaching add-ons going forward.</p><p dir="ltr">"Our sense is that for many players, the feeling that they have to download and use certain add-ons in order to play the game competitively, isn't really part of what's attractive about the game or healthy in the long run," Hazzikostas said. "So if we can pull things back to a place where add-ons are available for those who want to use them, but people aren't feeling pressured by their groups, by just the natural demands of competition and not wanting to lose out to someone who is using more advantages, that's going to be the healthier route in the long run."</p><p dir="ltr">WoW's 11.1.7 patch does not have a release date but will be available for testing on the game's public test realm later this week. Meanwhile, if you want to see what happens when a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/heres-what-happens-when-you-install-3703-wow-classic-add-ons-at-once/1100-6528652/" data-ref-id="1100-6528652">WoW Classic player installs every available add-on at once</a>, well, you've been warned.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The ZD-0+ Excellence Is As Close To A Perfect Controller As I’ve Gotten]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/zd-0-excellence-review-controller-gaming-xbox-perfect</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-zd-0-excellence-is-as-close-to-a-perfect-controller-as-i%E2%80%99ve-gotten.1178043/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://aftermath.site/zd-0-excellence-review-controller-gaming-xbox-perfect<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure><figcaption><span><p>As close to perfection as I have gotten.</p>
</span></figcaption></figure></div><div><p>Being picky with controllers can be hell. It would be great if I could be satisfied with simply going to Best Buy and getting some mass produced shit off the shelf, but I’m not built like that. This has condemned me to an eternal search for my Forever Controller, one built to last and easy to repair. This led me to import a Chinese controller called the ZD-0+ Excellence, a totally modular controller that checked off all my criteria and came closer to perfection than any before it, just as the American economy is set to implode.&nbsp;</p><p>Before moving on, it’s worth elaborating on exactly what my criteria are for a good controller. For starters, it has to use at least Hall Effect or the newer TMR modules for its sticks– I refuse to invest good money in a controller that’s going to turn to shit from stick drift in a few years.&nbsp;</p><figure><figcaption>"Fight For Me"? Thanks, I will ZD-0+</figcaption></figure><p>The second requirement is programmable back paddles. These make complex inputs that require you to move your hand between multiple face buttons while using the right analogue stick easier. At this point these should simply be standardized across the industry, with a minimum or two and upwards of six. I have written extensively about performing <a href="https://aftermath.site/i-modded-my-ps5-controller-and-you-can-too" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">aftermarket mods for my PS5 controllers</a>, but if we’re being honest with ourselves, nobody should have to do that.&nbsp;</p><p>The third requirement is build quality and performance. I’ve had many controllers simply turn to garbage over the years, even when the sticks are good on paper. Squeaky triggers, sticky buttons, the list goes on. I despise spending good money just to generate e-waste, and I have seen many an Xbox Elite and Scuf controller eat it, making them unsalvageable unless you know how to solder. An easy way around this is to make the entire controller modular, like the stick modules on the Dualsense Edge, although both the Edge and its modules are wildly overpriced, and the sticks inside those modules are old technology.</p><p>Lastly, I need a controller where the sticks are symmetrical. This is slightly harder to find, as the default layout for high-performance controllers skews towards the traditional Xbox layout, but there are controllers that almost fit the bill, like the 8BitDo Pro 2 (which only has two rear buttons). But I want something better than that. I want an Xbox Elite controller for half the price with better sticks, modular parts, lightning fast performance and a layout I prefer.&nbsp;</p><h2>Taobao importing</h2><figure><figcaption>That sure does look a lot like an Elite controller. I also hear the Scuff paddles fit right in there.</figcaption></figure><p>The ZD-0+ Excellence is all of the above things and more. I first heard about it via a mutual friend who had heard rave reviews of it via the Discord for <a href="http://gamepadla.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Gamepadla</a>, a site devoted to testing the input latency of gamepads and a fantastic resource for <a href="https://gamepadla.com/soft.pdl" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">open source tools for that purpose.</a></p><p>When I first saw reports about the ZD-0+ Excellence, the controller was only available in the States via Aliexpress. That was fine, but I wanted to get several of the modules that mod it to be symmetrical, similar to the PS5. The modules were slightly expensive, so I decided to purchase from Taobao via a proxy buying site, which hires a shipping agent to ship it to you. This turned out to be way more trouble than it was worth. The tariff situation meant that the controller got snagged in customs and spent several weeks lingering there. When it finally did arrive, it was sealed by big neon green tape informing me that US Customs had inspected it. Had I waited about a week, US-facing distributor GadgetHyper would have had it for sale domestically for a reasonable price (they seem like they <a href="http://gadgethyper.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">still have it in stock</a> for what I paid for it, as of writing this blog), but I was nervous and the escalating economic situation forced my hand. This concern was warranted, as the cost of the controller has shot up from roughly $90 to $180 on Aliexpress since then.&nbsp;</p><p>Though the controller comes in plain black and white, I decided to go with a clear transparent blue model that is aggressively more gamery, as well as several other modules, accessories and face buttons. All of this together was still less than the MSRP of Xbox Elite Series 2.</p><h2>How it feels</h2><div><figure><p><iframe title="Reviewing the ZD O+ Excellent!!! A Modular PC Controller with ALL the Features!" width="710" height="399" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/7WXoCWG-eHA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></figure></div><p><em>Old Man Rob’s initial review, which is fantastic at showing the basic functionality of the device, although it had some pushback on Reddit and the comments.&nbsp;</em></p><p>The second I held the ZD-0+ Excellence I knew I was in love. It had that premium heft and shape that I associated with the Elite series. Even as stock, the controller feels excellent: the real paddles are where they should be, magnetically held in place. The triggers and shoulder buttons feel responsive, and the controller comes with built-in toggles very similar to the Xbox Elite to switch the triggers to clicky short throws, which I enjoy far more than I expected. There’s also an additional layer of shoulder buttons to the side of the shoulders and triggers that fall organically where the index fingers are. I have not gotten too obsessed with programming these, but this gives you far more options than most people will ever need.</p><p>The modularity of the controller is a joy. I’ve had to painfully convert a Dualsense before, and the experience was not for the faint of heart. But on the ZD-0+ the front shell just pops off, revealing a few easy-to-remove hex screws. Converting the controller from Xbox (asymmetrical) stick layout to PlayStation was as simple as swapping in a new module and a face plate. On top of this, they also sell different accessories like various stick lengths as well as different modular faceplates for the d-pad. I generally prefer a symmetrical layout with a polygonal Xbox Elite style D-pad, but the accessories give you a lot of options, including a cursed “3 stick” layout.&nbsp;</p><div><figure><p><iframe title="Installing TMR Modules on the ZD O+ Excellent!" width="710" height="399" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Xgn9Id5quBw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></figure></div><p><em>Old Man Rob’s follow-up review, upon installing the TMR modules</em>, <em>which solved many of his issues.</em></p><h2>Modularity</h2><figure><figcaption>Modules are held together by a few screws. This makes the modules easy to replace, and easier to fix without tearing the controller apart.</figcaption></figure><p>Not only does the company offer multiple stick types (traditional ALPS, Hall Effect, TMR), they also offer multiple types of competing TMR sticks. This is only something that hardcore controller nerds have to contend with, but I went with “Jinful” because I had heard good things (a friend went with K-Silver and apparently got a lemon). The modules are, as of this writing, 10 dollars and not too difficult to take apart. Every test I have seen seems to indicate that the TMR modules outperform the stock Hall Effects by a country mile. It also appears to be possible to swap marginally better TMR sticks into the PCB and shell of the modules, provided you are good at soldering and desoldering. Knowing that you can do this without tearing apart and potentially ruining an $80-$100 dollar controller is deeply valuable. On top of this, user <a href="https://oshwhub.com/meki/zhi-dong-o-mu-kuai" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Meki has already created an open source PCB</a> specifically to be compatible with standard stick pinouts, like the kind used in Xbox, Playstation and Switch controllers. I’m so happy that this controller not only has easy solutions for stick drift, but potentially for improvements in stick technology down the line.</p><div><figure><p><iframe title="噂通りの最強コントローラー？徹底的に検証した結果【ZD O Plus、ZD O+ Excellence、ゲームパッド】" width="710" height="399" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/AguZG2JW67I?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></figure></div><p><em>If you would like to watch a Japanese YouTuber show off this controller for an hour, here you go.</em></p><p>Different button options are also on the table. The default tactile buttons in the controller I got feel quite good, far better than most controllers. Both the D-Pad as well as the default face buttons use surface mount variants of mouse switches, the kind usually used on the side clicks of the mouse (specifically HCNHK blues, having disassembled the module). There is also an optional module that has optical mouse switches, which many people contend are superior and longer lasting. Based on how they look, they appear to be these ones made by a company called <a href="https://www.globalsources.com/Micro-miniature-switch/microswitch-1197920464p.htm" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Raesha</a>, which I have heard mixed things about from true mouse perverts, but are still better than many controller buttons on the market.&nbsp;</p><div><figure><p><iframe title="ZD-O plus Excellenceの色んな右スティックを検証、一番良いスティックはこれだ【コントローラー、ゲームパッドレビュー】" width="710" height="399" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6geh12jnc8A?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></figure></div><p><em>Above: Here’s the same YouTuber just talking about just the stick modules.</em></p><p>If all of this is above your head, just know that these are generally serious parts that will last a while and be inexpensive to replace or repair if they ever fail. Given that the reason I stop using many controllers is “the buttons just feel super shitty now,” that catapults the ZD-0+ Excellence to the top of my list. In addition to this, the back paddles appear to be compatible with ones offered by brands like Scuff, which I plan on investigating because I have bigger hands and the stock paddles are just a hair too small for me personally. My controller also features RGB lighting, which I immediately turned off, and gyroscopic controls, which I don’t need but could imagine being useful if I ever got super into <em>Splatoon </em>again.</p><figure><figcaption>I wanted to go symmetrical so I went big on the accessories, although I wish they just sold a model that was symmetrical with TMR sticks stock.</figcaption></figure><p>It is absolutely crucial to properly calibrate your controller, and on the ZD-O+ that is even more important due to the modularity of its design. Different stick modules will perform differently. Calibration is done internally by pressing the triangle button in the middle, up and “A” at the same time, spinning the sticks three times, then hitting the triggers three times and pressing the middle triangle button again. <a href="https://hardwaretester.com/gamepad" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Hardwaretester</a> is very useful for this as it will give you a sense of the circularity of your controller. By default the right stick seems to have more of a square deadzone, which I understand many players prefer particularly when it comes to FPSes. But if you want a more traditional circular deadzone you are going to need to make some deadzone adjustments in the app.&nbsp;</p><h2><strong>Some hiccoughs</strong></h2><p>The ZD-0+ 's companion app is not the worst I’ve ever used, but when I first bought the controller it was exclusively in Chinese. By default this is still the case, although this week they updated it with additional languages. I have an iPhone, and so had to search “<a href="https://apps.apple.com/cn/app/%E8%87%B4%E5%8A%A8%E6%B8%B8%E6%88%8F%E5%9C%B0%E5%B8%A6/id6738748371" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">搜索 致动游戏地带</a>” on the iOS store, although apparently it’s not available in every country unless you use a VPN. There’s also a version on <a href="https://testflight.apple.com/join/1TfFssXB" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">testflight </a>as far as I know, and you can download an Android version <a href="https://www.zd2015.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">on their website</a>. There is no desktop or web app for this controller, just iOS and Android, which is by far my biggest pet peeve, although once you connect it to your phone the process is pretty seamless. Though the trigger buttons can be programmed without the app, the app allows you to program extensive inputs on the fly, which is clutch for PC gaming. I pray for a world where every button in your house can be programmed to do basically anything if you’re committed and perverted enough.&nbsp;</p><p>The largest failing of the ZD-0+ appears to be its wireless connectivity. It seems to poll at a maximum of about 250-260Hz according to community testing as well as my own and has middling jitter even with the included dongle. If you are like me and basically only use your controller wired, then that’s functionally a non-issue, but I hope that either updated firmware or an improved dongle can fix whatever is causing this, because this is otherwise as close to a perfect controller that I have ever seen. I have never been less mad at an input device, which is impressive given that since the manual is in Chinese I have to look up a YouTuber’s video every time I need to change something.</p><h2><strong>On China and the future</strong></h2><div><figure><p><iframe title="The Death of Affordable Computing | Tariffs Impact &amp; Investigation" width="710" height="399" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/1W_mSOS1Qts?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></figure></div><p>On some level, many of my hurdles with this controller stem from the fact that it feels like it wasn’t aimed at me. I only learned about it because I’m in a Discord devoted to testing controllers and someone raved about it. Many Americans like to humor ourselves and think that China tailors its products closely to US tastes, and while this has been true in the past more and more of the best deals out there in hardware are made with the Chinese domestic market in mind. In the peripheral space this is clearly true if you look at the explosion in good, affordable Hall Effect keyboards. More broadly, just look at Chinese EVs, which are so far ahead of American domestic offerings that they’re functionally impossible for most people here to own. We are not the center of the world, and rarely are we the center of innovation as much of our money and productive capacity has shifted towards the task of creating endless AI garbage.</p><p>As I write this, the United States is on a path to economic self immolation. If nothing changes and Trump doesn’t buckle or get overthrown in some treat-based version of January 6th, it’s going to be catastrophic for everyone. Everything is getting expensive for no coherent reason and container ships have more or less halted entirely. Watching this car crash in slow motion has made the prospect of writing about hardware difficult. How do you cover the tech space in the face of “<a href="https://youtu.be/1W_mSOS1Qts?si=ypnWnXm7CyABNlKH" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The Death of Affordable Computing</a>,” as Gamer’s Nexus called their three-hour long documentary? How can you assess the value of an object if you don’t know what it’ll cost or if it will be available tomorrow? Does the task itself become frivolous given how many industries are poised to collapse? Or does it become more relevant to talk about as it becomes clear that we have radically overestimated the degree to which China actually needs us?&nbsp;</p><p>Even if we all survive geopolitically, it does not change the fact that American hardware companies are thoroughly washed. I could never conceive of Logitech or Razer putting out a product so innovative or reasonable for anywhere close to this price and without some gargantuan caveat. No Western company would ever think to make a product so thoroughly repairable, modular, and anti-obsolescence. The ZD-0+ Excellence is a tinkerer’s dream, S-tier in repairability, close to the quality of an Elite for half the price and compatible with already existing parts on the market. It’s Taobao excellence, a potential Forever Controller, the dream of a thousand Reddit posters and Discord lurkers. Though it has real flaws that need to be addressed and other controllers may beat it in individual metrics, it is so close to being perfect that it hurts to think about. I am so happy I purchased it when it was reasonable to do so. And if you’re already in China or a country they export to that’s sane, like Canada, that almost perfect controller can still be yours for a song.</p></div><div><h2>Stay in touch</h2><p>Sign up for our free newsletter</p></div><div><h2><span>More from Aftermath</span></h2><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/all">See all posts<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="#000" stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round"><path d="M5 12h13m-6-7 7 7-7 7"></path></svg></a></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Epic Games Won’t Stop AI Generated Thumbnails On Fortnite, Says Gen AI Will Become “More And More Difficult To Detect”]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/epic-games-wont-stop-ai-generated-thumbnails-on-fortnite-says-gen-ai-will-become-more-and-more-difficult-to-detect/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/epic-games-won%E2%80%99t-stop-ai-generated-thumbnails-on-fortnite-says-gen-ai-will-become-%E2%80%9Cmore-and-more-difficult-to-detect%E2%80%9D.1178037/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/epic-games-wont-stop-ai-generated-thumbnails-on-fortnite-says-gen-ai-will-become-more-and-more-difficult-to-detect/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Epic Games project management director Dan Walsh confirms that Epic won't be making the effort to stop Fortnite creators from using AI-generated thumbnails, due in part because Walsh believes that generated AI content will "<em>become more and more difficult to detect</em>."</p>
<p>In an interview with <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JDZYR0gEsfg">Mustard Plays</a> (spotted by <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/fortnite-wont-police-ai-generated-thumbnail-images-and-epic-games-says-detecting-them-will-likely-become-impossible">Eurogamer</a>), Walsh and executive vice president Sax Persson were both insistent that Epic itself wouldn't be using generative AI in its own creations such as Fortnite skins, but that when it comes to user's content, Epics' concerns are more geared towards whether the content is "<em>compliant with [its] rules</em>," rather than being concerned with how the users made that content.</p>
<p>"<em>From our perspective, for moderation, thumbnails - like, we don't really care what tool you use to make your thumbnails,</em>" Walsh said. "<em>All we care about is whether or not it's compliant with our rules</em>."</p>
<p>"<em>I think to some degree AI is going to become more and more difficult to detect</em>," Walsh continued. "<em>It's not going to stand out as a unique thing, it's just going to be another tool that people are using to create things.</em>"</p>
<p>"<em>So trying to look for that specifically is going to become increasingly difficult to the point where it's probably going to become unenforceable. We're really just focused on - 'does this asset comply with our rules, yes or no?', not 'what tool did you use to make this asset'?</em>"</p>
<p>Generative AI is becoming more prevalent across the industry, with every major company and creator trying to figure out where it fits, if it does, in their process. <a href="https://wccftech.com/larian-studios-boss-doesnt-think-gen-ai-will-replace-game-creators/">Larian Studio boss Swen Vincke</a> recently commented that, in his view, generative AI might be able to make the "<em>baseline</em>" of what people can make go up, but it won't replace artists, and that if you tried to use generative AI for everything, you won't have a competitive advantage.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shovel Knight Dig for PS5, Xbox Series, and Xbox One launches May 15 alongside ‘Wicked Wishes’ update]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/shovel-knight-dig-for-ps5-xbox-series-and-xbox-one-launches-may-15-alongside-wicked-wishes-update</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/shovel-knight-dig-for-ps5-xbox-series-and-xbox-one-launches-may-15-alongside-%E2%80%98wicked-wishes%E2%80%99-update.1178031/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/shovel-knight-dig-for-ps5-xbox-series-and-xbox-one-launches-may-15-alongside-wicked-wishes-update<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>The <a title="Platforms > PS5 [9,388 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [7,135 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, and <a title="Platforms > Xbox One [13,945 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a> versions of <em><a title="Games > Shovel Knight Dig [6 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/shovel-knight-dig">Shovel Knight Dig</a></em> will launch on May 15 alongside the “Wicked Wishes” update for existing platforms, publisher <a title="Companies > Yacht Club Games [44 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/yacht-club-games">Yacht Club Games</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Nitrome [8 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/nitrome">Nitrome</a> <a href="https://www.yachtclubgames.com/blog/shovel-knight-dig-tunnels-onto-xbox-and-playstation-5-on-may-15th/" target="_blank">announced</a>. <span id="more-959124"></span></p><p><em>Shovel Knight</em> first launched for <a title="Platforms > Switch [17,035 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>, <a title="Platforms > PC [23,048 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1416050/Shovel_Knight_Dig/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a>, and Apple <a title="Platforms > Arcade [377 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/arcade">Arcade</a> on September 23, 2022.</p><p>The PlayStation 5 and <a title="Platforms > Xbox [25,881 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox">Xbox</a> versions will include the base game and all previously released expansions, including  “Wicked Wishes.” This final update will add new bosses, quests, secrets, and game-changing upgrades.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Yacht Club Games:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>When Drill Knight and his dastardly digging crew blast apart Shovel Knight’s peaceful campsite and steal his loot, he grabs his trusty Shovel Blade and starts tunneling after them!</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Meet new friends and foes, visit strange lands, and outfit yourself in your quest to keep the entire land from collapsing underfoot! Jump, slash, and dig your way down an ever-changing chasm of mystery in <em>Shovel Knight Dig</em>, an all-new <em>Shovel Knight</em> <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,249 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a>!</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li>An all-new presentation featuring a new <em>Shovel Knight</em> story! When Drill Knight and his dastardly digging crew blast apart Shovel Knight’s peaceful campsite and steal his loot, he grabs his trusty Shovel Blade and starts tunneling after them!</li><li>The first <em>Shovel Knight</em> adventure in glorious high color pixel graphics and sound. Fluid animation, scaling, rotation, and parallax create the most convincing <em>Shovel Knight</em> world yet!</li><li>Every adventure is different! <em>Shovel Knight Dig</em> levels have been meticulously crafted, then stitched together using proprietary generation techniques for infinite replayability.</li><li>Jump, slash, and dig your way in an all-new direction—down! Rely on your trusty Shovel Drop, then dig through huge swaths of dirt with all-new Speed Shovel mechanics.</li><li>Grow in power and wealth as you descend into the depths of the earth. Emerge with untold riches to outfit Shovel Knight further, unlocking permanent items and upgrades to your Shoveling equipment.</li><li>New Knights, new characters, and new enemies abound, but fear not! <em>Shovel Knight Dig</em> features <em>Shovel Knight</em>‘s signature storytelling, humor, and maybe even some familiar faces.</li><li>Another pulse-pounding soundtrack in a new style by astonishing virtuoso Jake Kaufman!</li><li>The first collaboration between Yacht Club Games and Nitrome, pixel masters!</li><li>Using your <em>Shovel Knight</em> series amiibo allows you to call upon a familiar fairy friend to keep you company on your adventure.</li></ul><p><strong>“<a title="Series > Fate [66 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/series/fate">Fate</a> &amp; Fortune”</strong></p><p>Something truly evil must be brewing down in the well, and it’s up to Shovel Knight and Black Knight to uncover the true Knightmare and put a stop to it! Once you’ve completed the base game, Knightmare Mode will unlock, adding a whole new level of challenge</p><p><strong>“Wicked Wishes”</strong></p><p>Your new adventure begins as you step into Hoofman’s Guild Hall – a secret hideout where elite quest-seekers and their illustrious patrons converge. Climb the ranks within the guild by undertaking their thrilling challenges. Collect powerful Relics and buffs, face new bosses and enemies, and unravel the mysteries encircling the impeccably dressed horse and his top adventurer, the Guildarch. But be careful what you wish for, wicked consequences await you in the well.</p></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Shovel Knight Dig - PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series Release Date Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_EHdY7UBE8M?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Popular Accessory Manufacturer JSAUX Reveals Switch 2 Gear, Including Grip Cases]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/popular-accessory-manufacturer-jsaux-reveals-switch-2-gear-including-grip-cases/1100-6531232/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/popular-accessory-manufacturer-jsaux-reveals-switch-2-gear-including-grip-cases.1178028/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/popular-accessory-manufacturer-jsaux-reveals-switch-2-gear-including-grip-cases/1100-6531232/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6531232">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Nintendo Switch 2 preorders sold out shortly after going live on April 24, with millions vying for a spot in line to snag the limited inventory. It’s shaping up to be another success for Nintendo, but because the console is quite expensive at $450, accessories like screen protectors and carrying cases are going to be more important than ever before. You’ll find a long list of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-first-party-accessories-will-be-more-expensive-than-originally-announced/1100-6530965/" data-ref-id="1100-6530965">official Nintendo accessories</a>, though you can save a few bucks by opting for the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/stores/page/832B1743-E051-4166-BC5E-7ED09ED9EA02&amp;tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">JSAUX lineup</a>. The brand made a name for itself crafting popular (and highly reviewed) accessories for Steam Deck, and these Switch 2 accessories look just as impressive.</p><p>If you’re not looking to spend a bunch of cash after dropping $450 on a console, at least take a look at the affordable JSAUX screen protectors. You’ll find <a href="https://www.amazon.com/JSAUX-Anti-Glare-Protector-Nintendo-Resistant/dp/B0DSHQ192C?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Anti-Glare Tempered Glass Screen Protectors (2-Pack)</a> for just $10 (was $16), though the standard <a href="https://www.amazon.com/JSAUX-Tempered-Protector-Nintendo-Resistant/dp/B0DW8WQ8L2?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Tempered Glass Screen Protectors (3-Pack)</a> is a bit more affordable at $8 (was $10). Both are smudge-resistant and protect your screen from scrapes and scratches--though the anti-glare model might be a better choice if you’re worried about playing outdoors.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1702/17023653/4485256-mixcollage-30-apr-2025-09-46-am-4174.png" data-ref-id="1300-4485256" data-ratio="0.563" data-width="1000" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1702/17023653/4485256-mixcollage-30-apr-2025-09-46-am-4174.png" data-ref-id="1300-4485256"></a><figcaption>JSAUX Switch 2 accessories</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1702/17023653/4485256-mixcollage-30-apr-2025-09-46-am-4174.png"></figure><figure data-embed-type="gallery" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1702/17023653/4485257-61jbfk32e0l._ac_sl1500.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1702/17023653/4485258-71kf5agmjml._ac_sl1500.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1702/17023653/4485259-812l5pe6z9l._ac_sl1500.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1702/17023653/4485260-71ka7jf4gol._sl1500.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1702/17023653/4485261-71te97pg21l._ac_sl1500.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1702/17023653/4485262-71fzhlh76l._ac_sl1500.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1702/17023653/4485263-61dxp1votsl._ac_sl1500.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4485257,1300-4485258,1300-4485259,1300-4485260,1300-4485261,1300-4485262,1300-4485263" data-resize-urls="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1702/17023653/4485257-61jbfk32e0l._ac_sl1500.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1702/17023653/4485258-71kf5agmjml._ac_sl1500.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1702/17023653/4485259-812l5pe6z9l._ac_sl1500.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1702/17023653/4485260-71ka7jf4gol._sl1500.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1702/17023653/4485261-71te97pg21l._ac_sl1500.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1702/17023653/4485262-71fzhlh76l._ac_sl1500.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1702/17023653/4485263-61dxp1votsl._ac_sl1500.jpg"><p>Gallery</p>     <img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1702/17023653/4485257-61jbfk32e0l._ac_sl1500.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1702/17023653/4485258-71kf5agmjml._ac_sl1500.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1702/17023653/4485259-812l5pe6z9l._ac_sl1500.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1702/17023653/4485260-71ka7jf4gol._sl1500.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1702/17023653/4485261-71te97pg21l._ac_sl1500.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1702/17023653/4485262-71fzhlh76l._ac_sl1500.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1702/17023653/4485263-61dxp1votsl._ac_sl1500.jpg"></figure><p>A few Switch 2 carrying cases are up for grabs, too. The <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Carrying-Compatible-Nintendo-Protective-Portable-Accessories/dp/B0DSGDH1XY?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Hard Shell Carrying Case (15 Card Slots)</a> is one of the largest, offering space for a few accessories and up to 15 game cards. Other options include the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Protective-Compatible-Nintendo-Dustproof-Travel-Carry-Protection/dp/B0F2G8PFVY?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Slim Hard Shell Carrying Case</a> for $17 (was $26) and the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/JSAUX-Carrying-Compatible-Nintendo-Protective/dp/B0F2DSY1S7?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Ultra Slim Carrying Case</a> for $19 (was $22). For an ultra-portable option, check out the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/JSAUX-Accessories-Shock-Absorption-Anti-Scratch-Design-Black/dp/B0F1TR36ND?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Protective Case + Enhanced Grip</a>. Though it’s not a carrying case, its hard shell design will protect it from all sorts of damage, and it’s even built with ergonomic grips to make handheld gaming more comfortable.</p><p>JSAUX has plenty of other Switch 2 gear available at Amazon, which we've collected in the list below.</p><h2>JSAUX Switch 2 Accessories</h2><ul><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/JSAUX-Anti-Glare-Protector-Nintendo-Resistant/dp/B0DSHQ192C?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">2-Pack Anti-Glare Tempered Glass Screen Protector</a> -- $10 (<del>$16</del>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/JSAUX-Tempered-Protector-Nintendo-Resistant/dp/B0DW8WQ8L2?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">3-Pack Tempered Glass Screen Protector</a> -- $8 (<del>$10</del>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Carrying-Compatible-Nintendo-Protective-Portable-Accessories/dp/B0DSGDH1XY?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Hard Shell Carrying Case (15 Card Slots)</a> -- $18 (<del>$26</del>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/JSAUX-Accessories-Shock-Absorption-Anti-Scratch-Design-Black/dp/B0F1TR36ND?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Protective Case + Enhanced Grip</a> -- $16 (<del>$20</del>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/JSAUX-Protective-Transparent-Controller-Scratch-Resistant/dp/B0F244GFNF?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Protective Case for Joy-Con 2</a> -- $14 (<del>$17</del>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/JSAUX-Protective-Accessories-Compatible-Controller/dp/B0F1YLC6G3?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Dockable Case + Joy-Con 2 Case</a> -- $20 (<del>$23</del>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Protective-Compatible-Nintendo-Dustproof-Travel-Carry-Protection/dp/B0F2G8PFVY?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Slim Hard Shell Carrying Case (10 Card Slots)</a> -- $17 (<del>$26</del>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/JSAUX-Carrying-Compatible-Nintendo-Protective/dp/B0F2DSY1S7?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Ultra Slim Carrying Case (Orange and Blue)</a> -- $19 (<del>$22</del>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/JSAUX-Designed-Nintendo-Ergonomic-Comfortable/dp/B0F2QWMW81?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Thumb Grips (Black)</a> -- $13</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/JSAUX-Designed-Nintendo-Ergonomic-Comfortable/dp/B0F2QWQLZQ?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Thumb Grips (Orange and Blue)</a> -- $13</li></ul><p>If you're looking for more Switch 2 accessories, be sure to check out <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-first-party-accessories-will-be-more-expensive-than-originally-announced/1100-6530965/" data-ref-id="1100-6530965">Nintendo's official Switch 2 accessories</a> that are available for preorder. <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gamestop-is-releasing-budget-friendly-switch-2-accessories/1100-6531016/" data-ref-id="1100-6531016">GameStop is also selling its own Switch 2 accessories</a>, while several <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/save-on-nintendo-switch-2-screen-protectors-and-carrying-cases-at-amazon/1100-6531093/" data-ref-id="1100-6531093">screen protectors and carrying cases</a> from various other third-party manufacturers are discounted at Amazon. Be sure to also check <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-preorder-guide-mario-kart-world-bundle/1100-6530531/" data-ref-id="1100-6530531">our Switch 2 preorder guide</a> for information on the new console, its accessories, and all the Switch 2 games available for preorder.</p><hr><div data-embed-type="pinbox" data-ref-id="4304">  <ul>                              <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-preorder-all-launch-games-buy-amazon-walmart-best-buy-target/1100-6531115/">All The Nintendo Switch 2 Games You Can Preorder Now</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/studio-ghibli-movies-limited-edition-steelbook-blu-ray-best-deals-amazon-walmart/1100-6530746/">Studio Ghibli Movies With Collectible Steelbooks Are Available For Cheap</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/8bitdo-best-controllers-amazon-restocks-tariffs/2900-6514/">8BitDo Halts US Shipments Due To Tariffs, But You Can Get Great Controller Deals (For Now)</a></li>                          <li>         <span>+ Show More More Gaming, Tech, and Entertainment Deals &amp; Preorders Links (5)</span>       </li>          <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/you-wont-find-switch-2-consoles-on-amazon-but-you-can-get-games-gear/1100-6531143/">You Won't Find Switch 2 Consoles On Amazon, But You Can Get Games &amp; Gear</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-preorder-guide-mario-kart-world-bundle/1100-6530531/">Nintendo Switch 2 Preorders Sold Out - Games &amp; Accessories Available</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-pro-controller-preorders-are-available-now/1100-6530558/">Nintendo Switch 2 Pro Controller Preorders Are Available Now</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/final-fantasy-x-magic-the-gathering-card-preorders-restocked-at-walmart/2900-6271/">Final Fantasy X Magic: The Gathering Card Preorders Restocked At Walmart</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/middle-earth-6-film-4k-blu-ray-collection-is-over-50-off-at-amazon/1100-6529053/">Middle-earth 6-Film 4K Blu-Ray Collection Is Over 50% Off At Amazon</a></li>   </ul> </div>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/105566936584242225941?rel=author">Jon Bitner</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EA Abandons One Of The Longest-Running Racing Franchises After 25 Years]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/ea-collin-mcrae-rally-race-wrc-dirt-codemasters-ending-1851778534</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ea-abandons-one-of-the-longest-running-racing-franchises-after-25-years.1178007/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/ea-collin-mcrae-rally-race-wrc-dirt-codemasters-ending-1851778534<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="155cba206b80b8212932ee491b02e406" data-recommend-id="image://155cba206b80b8212932ee491b02e406" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Codemasters / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="155cba206b80b8212932ee491b02e406" data-recommend-id="image://155cba206b80b8212932ee491b02e406" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>Earlier today racing game developer <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/dirt-bodycount-developer-codemasters-shifts-exclusivel-5903412&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/dirt-bodycount-developer-codemasters-shifts-exclusivel-5903412">Codemasters</a></span> announced that it was no longer developing any future dirt rally racing games, ending a 25-year run that started back in 1998. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196663" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="The Top 10 Most Played Games On Steam Deck: February 2024 Edition" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="429" data-playlist="196663,196049,196653" data-current="196663"><div><p>The Top 10 Most Played Games On Steam Deck: February 2024 Edition</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196663/196663_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196663/196663_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196663/196663_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196663/196663_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/22220.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>On April 30, Codemasters—a UK studio that specializes in racing games and was bought by EA in 2021— <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.ea.com/games/ea-sports-wrc/wrc-24/news/wrc-development-update&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.ea.com/games/ea-sports-wrc/wrc-24/news/wrc-development-update" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">posted an update on its official website</a></span> announcing that it would no longer release new updates or expansions for 2023's <em>EA Sports WRC</em> rally racing game. This game acted as a successor to the <em>Dirt </em>series, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Colin_McRae_Rally_and_Dirt&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Colin_McRae_Rally_and_Dirt" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">which itself had connections to the studio’s earlier <em>Colin McRae Rally</em> franchise</a></span> that started all the way back on the original PlayStation. But the more disappointing news for fans is that Codemasters is done making rally games altogether. </p><p>As announced in the Wednesday update, Codemasters is “pausing” all current development on future dirt racing rally games, effectively killing the <em>Dirt/Colin McRae </em>rally franchise after two decades and 10+ entries. The last entry in the <em>Dirt </em>franchise,<em> </em><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/games/dirt-5-year-one-edition?_gl=1*170ur3a*_ga*MTc0MjY2NTg1OS4xNzQwMzc1OTc4*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTc0NjAyMjg5NS41OC4xLjE3NDYwMzc2NTQuNjAuMC4w&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/games/dirt-5-year-one-edition?_gl=1*170ur3a*_ga*MTc0MjY2NTg1OS4xNzQwMzc1OTc4*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTc0NjAyMjg5NS41OC4xLjE3NDYwMzc2NTQuNjAuMC4w"><em>Dirt 5</em>, launched in 2020</a></span>.  <em>Kotaku </em>has reached out to EA for more information. </p><p>“For now, we are pausing development plans on future rally titles,” explained Codemasters. “Our [World Rally Championship] partnership was a culmination of sorts for our Codemasters journey with off-road racing, spanning decades through titles like <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/games/colin-mcrae-rally?_gl=1*1yt714s*_ga*MTc0MjY2NTg1OS4xNzQwMzc1OTc4*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTc0NjAyMjg5NS41OC4xLjE3NDYwMzc2NTQuNjAuMC4w&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/games/colin-mcrae-rally?_gl=1*1yt714s*_ga*MTc0MjY2NTg1OS4xNzQwMzc1OTc4*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTc0NjAyMjg5NS41OC4xLjE3NDYwMzc2NTQuNjAuMC4w"><em>Colin McRae Rally</em></a></span>, and <em>Dirt</em>. We’ve provided a home for every rally enthusiast, striving tirelessly to push the boundaries and deliver the exhilarating thrill of driving on the ragged edge. We’ve brought together incredibly talented racing developers, worked with some of the sport’s icons, and had the opportunity to share our love of rallying. Thank you to all the fans who have and continue to be part of our rally journey.”</p><p>The studio promised fans that EA Sports <em>WRC </em>will continue to be “available” to new and existing players, so thankfully it doesn’t sound like the team’s last rally game will be delisted and shut down anytime soon. Still, it’s a shame to see the studio stepping away from rally racing after nearly 30 years of excellent games in a genre that is often ignored by other studios and publishers.</p><p>Codemasters will continue to develop other racing games, like EA’s yearly <em>F1 </em>series and possibly (hopefully) future entries in the track racer franchise <em>Grid</em>. </p><p> .<br></p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Diablo 4's Battle Pass Overhaul Isn't Going Over Well]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/diablo-4-battle-pass-overhaul-isnt-going-over-well/1100-6531240/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/diablo-4s-battle-pass-overhaul-isnt-going-over-well.1178004/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/diablo-4-battle-pass-overhaul-isnt-going-over-well/1100-6531240/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6531240">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/diablo-4-season-8-patch-notes-introduce-endgame-boss-overhaul/1100-6531150/" data-ref-id="1100-6531150">Diablo 4 Season 8</a> is now live, and players have some complaints about the game's newly revamped battle pass, ranging from far fewer rewards to how it offers less premium currency.</p><p dir="ltr">In addition to overhauling <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/how-diablo-4-season-8-is-making-endgame-bosses-stronger-simpler-to-access-and-more-rewarding/1100-6530970/" data-ref-id="1100-6530970">Diablo 4's endgame bosses for Season 8</a>, Blizzard additionally <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/diablo-4-battle-pass-is-getting-a-major-rework-for-season-8/1100-6530937/" data-ref-id="1100-6530937">reworked the game's battle pass system</a> into a new one called The Reliquary. In the new system, certain types of rewards (like weapons or mount-related items) are each broken out into their own, separate Reliquary reward track, and players don't have to unlock rewards in order.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="819660577" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6465918,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Diablo%204%20x%20Berserk%20%7C%20Official%20Full%20Animated%20Reveal%20Trailer&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:103,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/diablo-4-x-berserk-official-full-animated-reveal-trailer\/2300-6465918\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465918\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465918\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465918\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6465918&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6465918,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6531240&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;diablo-iv&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;action,role-playing&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;pc,playstation-4,xbox-one,xbox-series-x,playstation-5&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;blizzard-entertainment,activision&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;franchise&quot;:&quot;diablo&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;franchiseRoot&quot;:&quot;diablo&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6465918},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6465918\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;Publisher Asset&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4480322-11.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/ns7P3qSm.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1745328480,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="ns7P3qSm" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> Diablo 4 x Berserk | Official Full Animated Reveal Trailer</p>
      </div>
<p dir="ltr">Individual Reliquaries vary in price but cost less than the game's old 90-tier battle pass, though they can all be bought together for the same $10 price as previous battle passes. Rewards can also be chosen in any order by spending tokens, rather than having to grind through potentially dozens of levels for a player to reach a particular reward that interests them. As in previous seasons, there are still free seasonal rewards for those who don't want to pay but still participate in the season, this time in the form of this season's Belial's Return Reliquary.</p><p dir="ltr">While being able to specifically purchase particular types of cosmetics and unlock specific rewards first is nice, the number of rewards on offer in total is far less than Diablo 4's old battle passes, something that has not gone unnoticed by players.</p><p dir="ltr">However, it's the removal of 500 Platinum (the game's premium currency used to purchase the battle pass and in-game shop cosmetics) from the battle pass that is causing the most outrage. In previous seasons, Diablo 4's premium battle pass awarded 700 Platinum. That was still 300 short of being able to purchase next season's battle pass, as in many other live-service games, and a controversy in and of itself. Diablo 4 Season 8's battle pass now only offers 200 Platinum in total.</p><p dir="ltr">One of the most popular posts on the Diablo 4 subreddit currently is one comparing the old battle pass to the new one from user <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/diablo4/comments/1kav4ce/reliquaries_are_a_massive_downgrade_born_from/?rdt=47498" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">ITheDarkitect</a>, who breaks down the differences between free and premium rewards offered under previous seasons and in Season 8. They note how the new premium Reliquary doesn't offer any emotes, headstones, titles, or emblems like previous battle passes, as well as the loss of additional Platinum for those who buy the premium version.</p><p dir="ltr">"The massive downgrade, especially the 500 Platinum cut, and the supposed 'freedom of choice' that pretends to make it better, don't surprise me at all," ITheDarkitect writes. "I'll spend my money somewhere else."</p><p dir="ltr">What changes Blizzard may make in the future is unclear, but it doesn't seem Blizzard is likely to make dramatic changes to Reliquaries in Season 8. The new system will be used for <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/heres-everything-diablo-4-and-immortals-berserk-crossover-entails/1100-6530989/" data-ref-id="1100-6530989">Diablo 4's upcoming crossover with Berserk starting on May 6</a> and last until the end of the season.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Planet Coaster 2’s updated roadmap includes security guards, Sci-Fi theme and more]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/04/30/planet-coaster-2s-updated-roadmap-includes-security-guards-sci-fi-theme-and-more/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/planet-coaster-2%E2%80%99s-updated-roadmap-includes-security-guards-sci-fi-theme-and-more.1177986/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/04/30/planet-coaster-2s-updated-roadmap-includes-security-guards-sci-fi-theme-and-more/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Frontier has now previewed what’s next for their latest theme park management game, Planet Coaster 2, with a new roadmap for May and June.</p>
<p>Arriving on 29th May is Update 5, which will include fan requested features like security guards and expanded colour customisations. The Sci-Fi theme will also return, while there’s two de-themed coasters that will allow for greater customisation alongside the returning Vector – Return Mk 2, and the maps from Act 3 of the career will be available in Sandbox mode.</p>



<p>Looking further ahead to June, Update 6 will bring Souvenir Shops and On-Ride Photos that will be sold at those shops (at no doubt extortionate prices!). There will be more stock coasters and the returning Coriolis ride, and then more ongoing stability and performance enhancements. Another returning theme is also teased, with Frontier saying that “It’s a real fairy tale come true.”</p>
<p>Planet Coaster 2 launched at the tail end of 2024, Frontier looking to find new ways to expand on their popular theme park game with a fresh release, instead of bolting on features with DLC and patches. In particular, they added new water park areas with water slides, wide plaza areas and more, though fans initially complained that it felt like a step back in terms of the number of themes and certain features, and some bugginess. Frontier has steadily worked to add more to the game since then, resolving key complaints and generally making improvements, and it seems that it’s kicking into gear with the next few updates.</p>

<p>In <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/11/19/planet-coaster-2-review/">our Planet Coaster 2 review</a>, Dom said, “Frontier’s park-building sequel is a vibe, it is a mood, and it is sunshine wrapped in a very bright bow. Minor control frustrations aside, it’s the best theme park builder out there, with impressively deep customisation, beautifully detailed visuals and the ability to make hours of your life melt away.”</p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4D4KX_yYnPg">Frontier Unlocked</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Assassin’s Creed Shadows Shares Year One Roadmap (and There’s No Mention of Multiplayer)]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/assassins-creed-shadows-shares-year-one-roadmap-and-theres-no-mention-of-multiplayer/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/assassin%E2%80%99s-creed-shadows-shares-year-one-roadmap-and-there%E2%80%99s-no-mention-of-multiplayer.1177983/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/assassins-creed-shadows-shares-year-one-roadmap-and-theres-no-mention-of-multiplayer/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Earlier today, some users <a href="https://wccftech.com/assassins-creed-shadows-multiplayer/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">found references to multiplayer modes in Assassin's Creed Shadows</a>, reigniting a rumor that <a href="https://wccftech.com/assassins-creed-shadows-is-reportedly-getting-a-co-op-mode-post-launch/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">circulated even before the game's launch</a>.</p>
<p>However, this afternoon, Ubisoft Quebec shared the full year-one roadmap, and there's no mention at all of any multiplayer modes. They may be keeping it a secret until a later announcement, but I wouldn't count on it. On the other hand, here's what is definitely coming to Assassin's Creed Shadows in the next twelve months:</p>
<ul>
<li>The first update will land in a week from today, on May 6. It will add a new story quest titled 'The Works of Luis Frois', a Codex update, and some quality of life improvements.</li>
<li>In late May, Ubisoft Quebec plans to release another sizable update featuring a special collaboration with another franchise. Moreover, the patch will introduce new parkour interactions requested by the community, including height-gaining back flips, fully re-animated height-gaining side flips, and a brand-new parkour move called the Vertical Ledge Jump. This move allows both playable characters to jump and grab onto canopies and lower overhangs—a move that's particularly handy when wall running isn't an option.</li>
<li>In June, another story drop is coming to Assassin's Creed Shadows. That includes a new story quest and a new ally for the League. Moreover, the developers will add the Alarm System to the open world, new difficulty settings, and several immersion options like toggles for weapon glints during combat, black-and-white-and-red ability filters, target assassination celebration effects, and stealth outlines. Lastly, players will be able to toggle their headgear during dialogues and cutscenes.</li>
</ul>
<p><iframe title="[ESRB] Assassin's Creed Shadows: Year 1 Roadmap Update" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/KhsxtWjyxo4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Throughout the rest of 2025, Assassin's Creed Shadows will be updated with the New Game Plus mode, new story drops, more quality-of-life enhancements, more special collaborations, more Codex updates, Animus content and rewards, and, of course, the <a href="https://wccftech.com/assassins-creed-shadows-first-dlc-is-called-claws-of-awaji-will-bring-10-hours-of-new-content/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Claws of Awaji expansion</a> that will introduce a new region with over 10 hours of content. As a reminder, Claws of Awaji is free for anyone who pre-ordered the game, while pricing for everyone else still needs to be communicated.</p>
<p>Assassin's Creed Shadows <a href="https://wccftech.com/assassins-creed-shadows-has-surpassed-3-million-players/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">has done very well for Ubisoft</a>, largely keeping the publisher afloat during its restructuring, which culminated in <a href="https://wccftech.com/ubisoft-forms-new-subsidiary-based-on-the-assassins-creed-far-cry-and-rainbow-six-and-franchises/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a new subsidiary</a> whose sole purpose is to control the Assassin's Creed, Far Cry, and Rainbow Six IPs.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Quietly Made A Big Change To The Nintendo Switch eShop]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/slop-nintendo-switch-eshop-best-seller-firmware-update-1851778523</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-quietly-made-a-big-change-to-the-nintendo-switch-eshop.1177974/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/slop-nintendo-switch-eshop-best-seller-firmware-update-1851778523<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p> The Nintendo Switch received a major firmware update today that paves the way for its integration with the Switch 2 and institutes a less than stellar new regime of virtual game sharing. But firmware version 20.0.0 also made some other equally notable but less advertised changes, including a major shift to how Nintendo ranks best-selling games in the eShop. The result could have big ramifications for how games are discovered on one of the biggest console install-bases in history, and could help alleviate <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/nintendo-eshop-switch-slop-clones-unpacking-scam-ai-art-1851722248&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/nintendo-eshop-switch-slop-clones-unpacking-scam-ai-art-1851722248">some of the platform’s “slop” problem</a></span>. <br></p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="195670" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="This Stylish Noir-Punk Side-Scroller Is Like Celeste With Guns" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="184" data-playlist="195670,194644,196773" data-current="195670"><div><p>This Stylish Noir-Punk Side-Scroller Is Like Celeste With Guns</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195670/195670_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195670/195670_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195670/195670_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195670/195670_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21167.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>Prior to Wednesday’s update, the “Best Sellers” section of the eShop covered the last 14 days and was arranged by total downloads. Now, however, the list is arranged by total revenue a game has generated from just the last three days. The shift was <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3X6nDoGNfPc&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3X6nDoGNfPc" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">spotted by <em>GVG</em></a></span> and documented at length on YouTube. “Hell has frozen over, folks, and Nintendo has massively changed chart discoverability with the latest Switch eShop OS update—in such a way that makes it clear that it’ll also carry through to the Switch 2,” game discoverability expert <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://lnkd.in/gPRBN5P5&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://lnkd.in/gPRBN5P5" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Simon Carless</a></span> posted <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:7323333696051150848/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:7323333696051150848/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">on LinkedIn</a></span> following the news. <br></p><p>While there’s s still an option to revert to the previous view, the eShop now defaults to ranking games by revenue rather than individual units sold. Carless speculates that could stop companies from trying to game the charts by running steep discounts to gin up downloads, an incentive structure that led to lots of shovelware crowding out better quality games on the best sellers list. But he adds that it will also make it harder for cheaper games, including lots of smaller indie titles, to compete for high-ranking slots against pricier blockbusters. </p><p>So what does this change look like in practice? Just about every game in the best seller list, with the exception of <em>Minecraft</em>, is different than it was a couple days ago, according to <em>GVG</em>’s comparison. The chart heavily favors games that aren’t on sale and Nintendo games in particular, with seven of the top 12 being first-party releases. The deals list has similarly been skewed away from just the games that are the most discounted, now heavily featuring those that are both heavily discounted and selling well. I had to scroll for a bit before stumbling on an obvious shovelware cash grab like <em>I Am Busy Digging A Hole</em>, an asset-flip sim aimed at capitalizing on the success of the similarly titled <em>A Game About Digging A Hole</em> which is only on Steam at the moment.</p><p>Unfortunately, on the best seller list at least, you have to toggle over to the “download only” list before you start to see lots of smaller indie games, though even those are dominated by existing winners. The <em>Gloomhaven</em>-inspired party RPG <em>Sunderfolk</em> was the only recently released game in the top 10 when I looked today. As <em>GVG </em>mentions in its video, the eShop change has gone a long way to pushing “slop” off of the discoverability pages, but it’s also done the same to many indie releases. Also the storefront is still incredibly sluggish and loads like molasses. The Switch 2 version can’t come soon enough.</p><p>What else could Nintendo do to improve store browsing in the meantime? Some developers have suggested a new browser tab purely for curated picks. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.pushtotalk.gg/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.pushtotalk.gg/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Push to Talk</em></a></span>’s Ryan Rigney recommended a new and trending section that takes into account the eShop’s own wishlisting system and other users’ activity on the store, similar to how Valve seemingly does it on Steam. Any new options would be better than none at all, though it’s interesting to see Nintendo tinkering more with the eShop now than it has in almost the entirety of the Switch’s existence (people also have strong feelings about <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.ign.com/articles/rip-orange-eshop-nintendo-fans-bid-farewell-to-iconic-switch-color&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/rip-orange-eshop-nintendo-fans-bid-farewell-to-iconic-switch-color" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">the move from orange to red</a></span>). </p><p>“Thanks to the system’s performance capabilities, Nintendo eShop on Switch 2 has been improved and runs smoothly even when displaying a large number of games,” Nintendo’s developers said earlier this month. “We believe the act of finding the game you want to play is itself part of the game system experience.” They’ve promised better speed, overall performance, and a new “Game Finds” feature for more easily scrolling through images and videos on the Switch 2's eShop, though it doesn’t sound like any of those improvements will be trickling back down to the older hardware. </p><p>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Assassin's Creed Shadows Roadmap Includes Free Updates Driven by Community Feedback and DLC Details]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/assassins-creed-shadows-roadmap-includes-free-updates-driven-by-community-feedback-and-dlc-details</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/assassins-creed-shadows-roadmap-includes-free-updates-driven-by-community-feedback-and-dlc-details.1177971/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/assassins-creed-shadows-roadmap-includes-free-updates-driven-by-community-feedback-and-dlc-details<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Ubisoft has outlined its plans for the first year of post-launch content for <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/assassins-creed-shadows"><u>Assassin’s Creed Shadows</u></a>, including promises to add features like new game+, more difficulty settings, additional story content, and more.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The Assassin’s Creed company detailed all of its plans for 2025 in a four-and-a-half-minute roadmap update video published today. It’s a brief but enlightening video with a specific schedule for May and June as the team behind the latest stealth-action entry plots out how it will keep fans coming back with free updates throughout the year.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/04/30/assassins-creed-shadows-post-launch-roadmap-1746033627143.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Assassin's Creed Shadows post-launch roadmap. Image courtesy of Ubisoft.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The drops begin soon with The Works of Luis Frois, the first of a few free story add-ons, which is set to drop in early May. It’ll be accompanied by a Codex update and a few quality-of-life improvements, with relatively substantial parkour additions and a photo mode update also set to arrive next month. These adjustments and more are part of what Ubisoft says is a continued effort to listen to its community and take their feedback into consideration for future Assassin’s Creed Shadows updates.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Your feedback has been a core focus of the team throughout development, and that’s not stopping now that Shadows is released,” community developer Daniel St. Germain explained in today’s video. “Regular title updates are coming, each with impactful additions – and changes – based on your feedback and requests, with some bug fixes to continue refining the experience across all platforms.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The next free Assassin’s Creed Shadows story drop will follow in June, as will more challenging difficulty settings, gameplay immersion options, an open-world alarm system, and an option to keep headgear on or off during cutscenes. These are worthwhile changes that players are already looking to see included, but more features, such as new game+ support, additional story drops, special collaborations, and more, are expected to arrive before the year is out.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The biggest item on the post-launch roadmap is the first proper Assassin’s Creed Shadows DLC expansion, Claws of Awaji, which drops at an unspecified point later in the year. It’s said to include new content, such as the Bo staff weapon and a new region for Naoe and Yasuke to explore, across its 10-hour journey. Pricing details have yet to be revealed, though it will at least be free for those who pre-ordered Assassin’s Creed Shadows before its launch last month.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Assassin’s Creed Shadows arrived for PC, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series X and S on March 20 and finally takes Ubisoft’s long-running stealth series to Feudal Japan. Its leap of faith managed to land it among <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-best-video-games-of-2025-so-far"><u>our list of the best games of 2025 so far</u></a> while also emerging as <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/assassins-creed-shadows-was-the-best-selling-game-in-the-us-for-march"><u>the best-selling game of last month</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Michael Cripe is a freelance contributor with IGN. He's best known for his work at sites like The Pitch, The Escapist, and OnlySP. Be sure to give him a follow on Bluesky (@mikecripe.bsky.social) and Twitter (@MikeCripe).</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tomodachi Life: Living The Dream Release Window, Trailer, And Everything We Know]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/tomodachi-life-living-the-dream-release-date-story-trailer/1100-6531217/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/tomodachi-life-living-the-dream-release-window-trailer-and-everything-we-know.1177968/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/tomodachi-life-living-the-dream-release-date-story-trailer/1100-6531217/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6531217">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">Nintendo may be keeping its release calendar for 2026 under wraps for now, but the company already has a couple of big games lined up for next year, including <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/tomodachi-life-living-the-dream/" data-ref-id="5000-670016">Tomodachi Life: Living the Dream</a>. The highly anticipated follow-up to the hit 3DS game, Living the Dream is a quirky life sim in which players create Miis and watch the humorous interactions they have as they live out their daily lives as part of an island community.</p><p dir="ltr">Nintendo will undoubtedly have a lot more to share about the game as we get closer to its release, but in the meantime, here's everything we know about Tomodachi Life: Living the Dream so far.</p><h2 dir="ltr" id="When_will_Tomodachi_Life__Living_The_Dream_be_released_">When will Tomodachi Life: Living The Dream be released?</h2><p dir="ltr">Nintendo has yet to pin down a firm release date for Tomodachi Life: Living the Dream, but the company has confirmed the game will launch sometime in 2026.</p><h2 dir="ltr" id="What_platforms_is_Tomodachi_Life__Living_The_Dream_on_">What platforms is Tomodachi Life: Living The Dream on?</h2><p dir="ltr">At the moment, Nintendo has only confirmed that Tomodachi Life: Living the Dream will be released for the original Switch. The company has not yet said anything about a potential Nintendo Switch 2 Edition of the game.</p><p dir="ltr">Considering that several other upcoming Switch 1 titles (such as <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/metroid-prime-4-beyond/" data-ref-id="5000-465595">Metroid Prime 4: Beyond</a> and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/pokemon-legends-z-a/" data-ref-id="5000-619901">Pokemon Legends: Z-A</a>) will be cross-gen, it's possible this could also apply to Tomodachi Life. However, nothing has been confirmed as of yet. At the very least, the game should be playable on Switch 2 through backwards compatibility.</p><h2 dir="ltr" id="Preorder_Tomodachi_Life__Living_The_Dream">Preorder Tomodachi Life: Living The Dream</h2><p dir="ltr">With its release date still a ways off, retailers have not yet begun taking preorders for Tomodachi Life: Living the Dream.</p><h2 dir="ltr" id="Price">Price</h2><p dir="ltr">Nintendo has not yet announced how much Tomodachi Life: Living the Dream will cost. While most first-party Switch 1 titles typically retail for $60, it remains to be seen if that will be the case for Tomodachi Life as well.</p><h2 dir="ltr" id="Trailer">Trailer</h2><div tabindex="0" data-id="1586745752" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6465829,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Tomodachi%20Life%3A%20Living%20the%20Dream%20%E2%80%93%20Official%20Reveal%20Trailer&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:67,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:false,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/tomodachi-life-living-the-dream-official-reveal-trailer\/2300-6465829\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465829\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465829\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465829\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6465829&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6465829,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6531217&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;tomodachi-life-living-the-dream&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;simulation&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;nintendo-switch&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;nintendo&quot;,&quot;franchise&quot;:&quot;tomodachi-life&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;franchiseRoot&quot;:&quot;tomodachi-life&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6465829},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6465829\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;Publisher Asset&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4466463-88.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/BOlf2No5.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1743085620,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="BOlf2No5" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle" data-embed-type="video" data-ref-id="2300-6465829" data-src="/videos/tomodachi-life-living-the-dream-official-reveal-trailer/2300-6465829/" data-width="100%" data-height="100%" data-video-start="0"><div><p>Tomodachi Life: Living the Dream – Official Reveal Trailer</p><div><p>         Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?       </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!       </p></div></div><p>       Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.     </p><p>       This video has an invalid file format.     </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div><p dir="ltr">Nintendo shared the first trailer for Tomodachi Life: Living the Dream at the end of its <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/nintendo-direct-march-2025-all-the-biggest-announcements/2900-6377/">March 2025 Nintendo Direct</a> presentation.</p><p dir="ltr">The video begins with a slow pan over a peaceful shoreline, where we see one beachgoing Mii casually toot while asleep on a beach chair. The trailer then showcases a handful of different Miis going about their daily lives on the island, from an elderly man breakdancing in front of a crowd to a pair of characters angrily throwing items at each other during a heated argument.</p><h2 dir="ltr" id="Tomodachi_Life_gameplay_details">Tomodachi Life gameplay details</h2><p dir="ltr">Tomodachi Life: Living the Dream marks the third installment in Nintendo's quirky life-sim series, and while many details about the game are still up in the air, it appears the series' hallmark gameplay and humor are intact.</p><p dir="ltr">In past installments, players would create (or import) Mii characters and have them live together on an island community, watching as the Miis went about their day-to-day lives. They could work part-time jobs, take strolls along the beach, and visit each other’s apartments, which often resulted in humorous interactions.</p><p dir="ltr">In contrast to Tomodachi Life for 3DS, where each Mii occupied a different apartment in one shared building, it appears the Miis in Living the Dream will live in their own small houses. A clothing store and supermarket can also be spotted in the background of the announcement trailer, hinting that players will still be able to purchase outfits and meals for the Miis. However, it remains to be seen if the Miis can still get married and have children.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Outer Worlds 2: Release Window, Story, And Everything We Know]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-outer-worlds-2-release-date-story-trailer/1100-6531213/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-outer-worlds-2-release-window-story-and-everything-we-know.1177965/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-outer-worlds-2-release-date-story-trailer/1100-6531213/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6531213">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/the-outer-worlds-2/">The Outer Worlds 2</a>, the sequel to Obsidian's comedic sci-fi RPG, is set to release later this year. Obsidian's second major release of 2025 following Avowed, The Outer Worlds 2 has been pitched as a bigger and better version of the original, expanding the scope of the game while adding in more ways to approach situations. Obsidian RPGs are well known for giving you a variety of ways to solve a problem, and The Outer Worlds 2 seems to be continuing that tradition.</p><p dir="ltr">While The Outer Worlds 2 still hasn't been fully revealed by Microsoft, with just a release window for later this year, it has been confirmed that the second half of Xbox's June showcase will be a deep dive on The Outer Worlds 2, likely giving a release date and more information about the RPG.</p><div data-embed-type="toc"><p><span><strong>Table of Contents</strong> [<a data-toggle="collapse" href="#toc_list">hide</a>]</span></p><ul id="toc_list"><li><a href="#When_will_The_Outer_Worlds_2_be_released_">When will The Outer Worlds 2 be released?</a></li><li><a href="#The_Outer_Worlds_2_announcement_trailer">The Outer Worlds 2 announcement trailer</a></li><li><a href="#The_Outer_Worlds_2_platforms">The Outer Worlds 2 platforms</a></li><li><a href="#The_Outer_Worlds_2_story__setting__and_characters">The Outer Worlds 2 story, setting, and characters</a></li><li><a href="#The_Outer_Worlds_2_gameplay">The Outer Worlds 2 gameplay</a></li><li><a href="#The_Outer_Worlds_2_development_news">The Outer Worlds 2 development news</a></li></ul></div><h2 dir="ltr" id="When_will_The_Outer_Worlds_2_be_released_">When will The Outer Worlds 2 be released?</h2><p dir="ltr">The Outer Worlds 2 currently has a release window of 2025. Microsoft is likely announcing a more exact date at the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/xbox-games-showcase-announced-for-june-8-heres-what-to-expect/1100-6530713/">Xbox June showcase</a>, where The Outer Worlds 2 will be the main focus of a Direct following the showcase. While we don't know when the release will fall, we do at least know it won't be prior to that June showcase.</p><h2 dir="ltr" id="The_Outer_Worlds_2_announcement_trailer">The Outer Worlds 2 announcement trailer</h2><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=I_rvTE-3S4c" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/I_rvTE-3S4c" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p dir="ltr">The Outer Worlds 2 announcement trailer was released in 2019, featuring only a CG cutscene. At The Game Awards in 2024, a second trailer was released, showing off the gameplay of The Outer Worlds 2, along with the 2025 release window. The trailer itself shows a decent amount of gameplay, from normal shooting to invisible sneaking and high-octane explosions, but it doesn't focus on the narrative of The Outer Worlds too much. Instead, it focuses on the fact that Obsidian has made a number of highly regarded sequels in the past, like Star Wars: Knights of the Old Republic 2 and Fallout: New Vegas.</p><h2 dir="ltr" id="The_Outer_Worlds_2_platforms">The Outer Worlds 2 platforms</h2><p dir="ltr">The Outer Worlds 2 is releasing on Xbox Series X|S, PlayStation 5, and PC. As an Xbox Game Studios title, it will be available on Game Pass for both console and PC at launch, alongside the option to purchase it at full price. At the time of writing, The Outer Worlds 2 has not been confirmed to be releasing on the Nintendo Switch 2, although Xbox has expressed interest in <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/switch-2-reveal-doesnt-make-microsoft-nervous-about-its-own-next-gen-plans-phil-spencer-says/1100-6530893/">supporting the Switch 2</a> and the first game did come to the Nintendo Switch.</p><h2 dir="ltr" id="The_Outer_Worlds_2_story__setting__and_characters">The Outer Worlds 2 story, setting, and characters</h2><p dir="ltr">While most story details have yet to be revealed, the <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1449110/The_Outer_Worlds_2/" rel="nofollow ">Steam page</a> for The Outer Worlds 2 does have the basic premise. You play as the Earth Directorate agent, tasked with uncovering the source of devastating rifts in Arcadia. The Arcadia colonies are currently in a war as the Protectorate's rule is challenged by rebels. Oddly enough, the outsider with government authority trying to solve a massive problem is very similar to the pitch for Avowed, although the way the narrative shakes out over the course of the game will likely be different.</p><p dir="ltr">While more details haven't been shared just yet, the Steam page also confirms the return of companions and emphasizes player choice when it comes to how you tackle quests, both in the main story and side quests.</p><h2 dir="ltr" id="The_Outer_Worlds_2_gameplay">The Outer Worlds 2 gameplay</h2><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4484992-theouterworlds22.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4484992" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4484992-theouterworlds22.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4484992"></a><figcaption>The Outer Worlds 2 will feature a variety of sci-fi weaponry.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4484992-theouterworlds22.jpg"></figure><p>The Outer Worlds 2 appears to have feature gameplay similar to the original, but refined. As shown in a gameplay video (via <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LhDvnM3wBaQ">IGN</a>), it's a first-person RPG, where--depending on how you like to play--you will be shooting, sneaking, and stabbing your way through enemies in combat encounters. If you have played the original, Avowed, or Fallout 4, you have a pretty good idea of how combat can flow. You will also be looting--both enemies and chests--gathering materials, valuables, and new gear.</p><p dir="ltr">That's just combat of course, as you will also spend a decent amount of time talking to NPCs. How these conversations go depends on your build, letting you play anyone from a charismatic smooth-talker to an intimidating brute. You can also use food and drugs to give stat boosts, letting you appear to be charming, even if you aren't. There will also be plenty of main missions, side quests, and companion missions, if it's similar to the first game.</p><h2 dir="ltr" id="The_Outer_Worlds_2_development_news">The Outer Worlds 2 development news</h2><p>Development news has been fairly light for The Outer Worlds 2 since its reveal in 2019. After that, there was a trailer at The Game Awards 2024, and a few gameplay videos have been released in the time since. However, The Outer Worlds 2 is getting a deep dive at the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/xbox-games-showcase-announced-for-june-8-heres-what-to-expect/1100-6530713/">Xbox Games Showcase</a> on June 8, with a Direct focus entirely on the game after the main showcase. Xbox has done a couple of these single-game presentations after the main show in recent years, typically spending 20-30 minutes deep-diving into the game and interviewing developers. That is likely the next time news about the game will be revealed, including a release date.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Assassin’s Creed Shadows year one roadmap detailed]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/04/30/assassins-creed-shadows-year-one-roadmap-detailed/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/assassin%E2%80%99s-creed-shadows-year-one-roadmap-detailed.1177947/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/04/30/assassins-creed-shadows-year-one-roadmap-detailed/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Ubisoft has revealed what players should expect in the first year of Assassin’s Creed Shadows, with the studio releasing the year one roadmap for the game. Included in the first year are free missions called Story Drops, the first expansion called the Claws of Awaji, New Game+, and further updates to Assassin’s Creed Shadows gameplay mechanics.</p>
<p><iframe title="Assassin's Creed Shadows: Year 1 Roadmap Update" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/1LLB-WNvQEQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>The Claws of Awaji expansion, which will be available at no additional cost to those who pre-ordered Assassin’s Creed Shadows, will add the island of Awaji and continues the story of both Yasuke and Naoe following the epilogue of the main questline. Naoe will be getting a new weapon with that being the Bo Staff, which can be used to fight the new enemies that will be added to the game. Both characters will be getting additional abilities too.</p>
<p>Another new addition to Assassin’s Creed Shadows will be story drops, free quests that expand upon the backstories of various characters. These story drops will also add new abilities and new activities in the world. The first of these story drops will be “The Works of Luis Frois”, which will focus on the Jesuit scholar whose works had documented a lot of the Sengoku era of Japan. This story drop will be added in early made.</p>
<p>From a gameplay standpoint, the parkour system in Assassin’s Creed Shadows will be optimised and new interactions will be brought in. These include height-gaining back-ejects, reanimated height-gaining side-ejects, and a vertical ledge jumps so characters can grab on to awnings and low overhangs. There will be more parkour improvements added through the year. The photo mode will be improved too, with new poses, expressions, filters, stickers and ambient music. In June, the second community feedback update will be rolled out which will allow players to toggle headgear being visible in cutscenes, giving the option to disable weapon glints and stealth outlines, black-and-white and red ability filters, and assassination celebration effects. The alarm system will be expanded to the open world as well.</p>


<p>In our Assassin’s Creed Shadows review, Adrian said, <em>“Fans of Assassin’s Creed have waited an era or two for a series entry that lets you be a ninja and explore Feudal Japan. Thankfully, the wait has been absolutely worth it. Assassin’s Creed Shadows is an astonishing achievement. Vast, impossibly detailed, immaculately researched, and enormously fun, Shadows is easily one of the best games in this storied franchise.”</em></p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://www.ubisoft.com/en-gb/game/assassins-creed/news/3rJiU861lAyWTYpvH3cfmY">Ubisoft</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jack Black's Minecraft Chicken Song Just Broke A Billboard Charts Record]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/jack-black-minecraft-lava-chicken-song-billboard-record-1851778515</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/jack-blacks-minecraft-chicken-song-just-broke-a-billboard-charts-record.1177944/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/jack-black-minecraft-lava-chicken-song-billboard-record-1851778515<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="b078c0e5c8d03e23c131c51146eb66ac" data-recommend-id="image://b078c0e5c8d03e23c131c51146eb66ac" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->WB / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="b078c0e5c8d03e23c131c51146eb66ac" data-recommend-id="image://b078c0e5c8d03e23c131c51146eb66ac" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/minecraft-movie-creeper-milk-blue-dye-fda-safe-children-1851777905&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/minecraft-movie-creeper-milk-blue-dye-fda-safe-children-1851777905"><em>A Minecraft Movie</em></a></span><em> </em>is a <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/minecraft-movie-half-a-billion-550-million-box-office-1851776110&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/minecraft-movie-half-a-billion-550-million-box-office-1851776110">box office juggernaut</a></span> and has convinced loads of kids and teenagers to go out to the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/minecraft-movie-chicken-jockey-meme-chaos-block-party-1851778197?_gl=1*1vn9ipg*_ga*MTc0MjY2NTg1OS4xNzQwMzc1OTc4*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTc0NjAyMjM1My41Ni4xLjE3NDYwMjQzOTguMzkuMC4w&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/minecraft-movie-chicken-jockey-meme-chaos-block-party-1851778197?_gl=1*1vn9ipg*_ga*MTc0MjY2NTg1OS4xNzQwMzc1OTc4*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTc0NjAyMjM1My41Ni4xLjE3NDYwMjQzOTguMzkuMC4w">movies again (and cause chaos)</a></span>. And a song from the the live-action adaptation of the hit video game has set a new record: it’s the shortest track to ever make it on the Billboard Hot 100 chart. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="197547" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="The Ultimate Beginner’s Guide to Oblivion Remastered: Potions, Guilds, and Free Housing" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="156" data-playlist="197547,197544,197541" data-current="197547"><div><p>The Ultimate Beginner’s Guide to Oblivion Remastered: Potions, Guilds, and Free Housing</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197547/197547_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197547/197547_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197547/197547_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"></video></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>Earlier this month, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/minecraft-movie-creeper-milk-blue-dye-fda-safe-children-1851777905&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/minecraft-movie-creeper-milk-blue-dye-fda-safe-children-1851777905"><em>A Minecraft Movie</em></a></span> starring Jack Black and Jason Momoa hit theaters to mostly negative reviews. While the film’s (<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/minecraft-movie-unfinished-cgi-jack-black-leak-screens-1851774855&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/minecraft-movie-unfinished-cgi-jack-black-leak-screens-1851774855">finished</a></span>) CG effects look great, the movie is a mostly boring adventure <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/minecraft-movie-review-bad-jack-black-kids-movie-steve-1851775345&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/minecraft-movie-review-bad-jack-black-kids-movie-steve-1851775345">made worse by Jack Black</a></span> deciding that yelling and spitting out slang is the same as acting. And another thing Jack Black does a lot of in the <em>Minecraft </em>movie is sing songs. Many of these songs are short and not very memorable. But one about really hot chicken has turned out to be a bit of a hit. </p><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.billboard.com/lists/jack-black-minecraft-song-steves-lava-chicken-hot-100-record/34-steves-lava-chicken-jack-black/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.billboard.com/lists/jack-black-minecraft-song-steves-lava-chicken-hot-100-record/34-steves-lava-chicken-jack-black/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">On April 28, <em>Billboard </em>posted an article</a></span> explaining that the song “Steve’s Lava Chicken” had charted on the upcoming May 3 version of the Hot 100 chart. The song debuted at 78 out of 100, which is pretty impressive considering its just 34 seconds long. That’s so short that it’s set a new record for shortest track to chart on the Hot 100. Previously, that record was held by Kid Cudi’s 2020 song “Beautiful Trip” which was just 37 seconds long. </p><p>Meanwhile, “Steve’s Lava Chicken” has also cracked the top 10 on the Hot Rock Songs chart. Black’s previous big video game song, “Peaches” from the<em> </em><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/super-mario-bros-movie-review-chris-pratt-jack-black-1850309488?_gl=1*v41jl5*_ga*MTc0MjY2NTg1OS4xNzQwMzc1OTc4*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTc0NjAyMjM1My41Ni4xLjE3NDYwMjQzOTguMzkuMC4w&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/super-mario-bros-movie-review-chris-pratt-jack-black-1850309488?_gl=1*v41jl5*_ga*MTc0MjY2NTg1OS4xNzQwMzc1OTc4*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTc0NjAyMjM1My41Ni4xLjE3NDYwMjQzOTguMzkuMC4w"><em>The Super Mario Bros. Movie</em></a></span>, was an even bigger hit for the actor. In April 2023 it reached the 56 spot on the Hot 100 list. Will “Steve’s Lava Chicken” be able to beat that high point? Probably not. Which is fine by me. “<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/peaches-bowser-mario-movie-jack-black-remix-rap-1851081104?_gl=1*v41jl5*_ga*MTc0MjY2NTg1OS4xNzQwMzc1OTc4*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTc0NjAyMjM1My41Ni4xLjE3NDYwMjQzOTguMzkuMC4w&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/peaches-bowser-mario-movie-jack-black-remix-rap-1851081104?_gl=1*v41jl5*_ga*MTc0MjY2NTg1OS4xNzQwMzc1OTc4*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTc0NjAyMjM1My41Ni4xLjE3NDYwMjQzOTguMzkuMC4w">Peaches” is much better. In fact, it’s basically the only good thing to come out of that movie</a></span>. </p><p> .<br></p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[One Of The Most Viral Games Ever, Flappy Bird, Has Returned With "No Web3 Elements"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/one-of-the-most-viral-games-ever-flappy-bird-has-returned-with-no-web3-elements/1100-6531239/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/one-of-the-most-viral-games-ever-flappy-bird-has-returned-with-no-web3-elements.1177935/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/one-of-the-most-viral-games-ever-flappy-bird-has-returned-with-no-web3-elements/1100-6531239/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6531239">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Flappy Bird, one of the most viral games ever that became massively popular before being delisted by its creator, has returned. There are some key things to know, however, that could give you pause about jumping back in.</p><p>This new version of Flappy Bird comes from The Flappy Bird Foundation Group and was not produced in partnership with series designer Dong Nguyen. The game's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/flappy-bird-studio-addresses-criticism-but-ignores-the-games-biggest-controversy/1100-6526576/" data-ref-id="1100-6526576">announcement in 2024</a> was mired in controversy surrounding cryptocurrency concerns. In the announcement of the new game's launch, the developer said there are "no Web3 elements," despite the company's background in that area.</p><p>Flappy Bird can now be downloaded on Android devices from the Epic Games Store. There is no word yet on if it's also coming to iOS, or if the planned PC edition is still coming, but the developer said more news is on the way.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ftbTah7oqj4" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/ftbTah7oqj4" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>The new Flappy Bird has two modes: Classic and Quest. In Classic, players do what they did 10 years ago, which is tap the screen to make the bird jump to avoid pipes for as long as possible. Quest mode, meanwhile, features levels with set goals, with new content added "regularly."</p><p>Flappy Bird makes money through in-app purchases that remove ads. Players can also buy special helmets that allow players to revive themselves.</p><p>Nguyen originally removed the game in 2014 because he thought it became "an addictive product," which ran counter to his belief that it should be played in short bursts.</p><p>"I think it has become a problem. To solve that problem, it's best to take down Flappy Bird. It's gone forever," <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2014/02/creator-cites-addictiveness-discomfort-in-pulling-down-flappy-bird/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">he said at the time.</a></p><p>Nguyen is not involved with the new Flappy Bird and apparently made no money of its return. That's because, <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2024/09/how-crypto-bros-wrested-flappy-bird-from-its-creator/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Ars Technica reports</a>, a company called Gametech Holdings filed a "notice of opposition" against Nguyen in late 2013. After Nguyen did not respond to the notice, the US Patent &amp; Trademark Office canceled his trademark, which gave Gametech the opportunity to acquire it.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[May 2025’s PS Plus Monthly Games features Balatro, boomer shooting & dinos]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/04/30/may-2025s-ps-plus-monthly-games-features-balatro-boomer-shooting-dinos/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/may-2025%E2%80%99s-ps-plus-monthly-games-features-balatro-boomer-shooting-dinos.1177890/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/04/30/may-2025s-ps-plus-monthly-games-features-balatro-boomer-shooting-dinos/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>The <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/ps-plus">PlayStation Plus</a> monthly games for May 2025 have been announced and it’s a pretty good month, featuring tons of dinosaurs, a great boomer shooter, and the Poker-inspired card dealing phenomenon that is Balatro.</p>
<p><span>What are the PS Plus May 2025 games?</span></p>


<p>The following three games will be available from the first Tuesday of the month, which will be 6th May – no kidding – and they will be available until 2nd June.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/ark-survival-ascended">Ark: Survival Ascended</a> | PS5</strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/warhammer-40000-boltgun">Warhammer 40,000: Boltgun</a> | PS5, PS4</strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/balatro">Balatro</a> | PS5, PS4</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>Considering that it’s a celebrated Game of the Year contender and nominee from last year, Balatro is likely the biggest included here. The game is a roguelike that takes inspiration from Poker hands, asking you to play card combos in order to generate high scores, while collecting Joker cards that add multipliers, boosters and other effects as you play. It’s hugely addictive and was <strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/12/19/game-of-the-year-2024-best-independent/">an easy winner for our Best Independent Game award in 2024</a>. </strong>Through 2025, it’s reached even more people as more awards have rolled in, and that attention has led to some interesting collaborations with much bigger budget games.</p>
<p><iframe title="Balatro - Short Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9agt18c_V1U?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>An then there’s Warhammer 40,000: Boltgun. Before Space Marine 2 dropped into our laps last year, this was probably up there as the latest and greatest 40K shooter, leaning into the “Boomer Shooter” fad with retro graphics and retro FPS gameplay to match. In <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2023/05/23/warhammer-40k-boltgun-review/">our Boltgun review</a>, Dom said, “The commitment to ‘the bit’ means that Warhammer 40,000: Boltgun stays true to its old-school shooter roots, with very little signposting, apart from the occasional spot of yellow marking to show you can climb up through an area. Otherwise, you’re left to your own devices. The same goes for storytelling, which extends to your servitor’s asides, short loading screen introductions to each area and the occasional cutscene. It doesn’t hurt it, but there were times where I yearned for a little more explanation.”</p>


<p>Rounding out this month’s selection is Ark: Survival Ascended, the current gen revamp of Ark: Survival Evolved within Unreal Engine 5. This remaster fully implements Unreal Engine’s Lumen lighting, Nanite mesh rendering, and all the other new technologies, while Studio Wildcard has gradually reimplemented all of the DLC maps from the original game over the course of the last year and a half – it’s still in Early Access with the final map planned for release in October. It hasn’t had the smoothest launch or reception, but the game has an enduring popularity regardless. Dinos, am I right?</p>
<h2>Can you still get the April 2025 PS Plus games?</h2>
<p>Yes! You’ve got until Monday 5th May March to claim your PS Plus games, which include:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong><a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-gb/concept/10003485">RoboCop: Rogue City</a> | PS5&nbsp;</strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-gb/concept/10002719">The Texas Chain Saw Massacre</a> | PS5, PS4</strong></li>
<li><a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-gb/product/EP0700-CUSA09923_00-DSHACKERSMEMORY1/"><strong>Digimon Story: Cyber Sleuth – Hacker’s Memory</strong></a><strong> | PS4&nbsp;</strong></li>
</ul>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2025/04/30/playstation-plus-monthly-games-for-may-ark-survival-ascended-balatro-warhammer-40000-boltgun/">PS Blog</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Evil Dead: The Game is getting delisted]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/04/30/evil-dead-the-game-is-getting-delisted/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/evil-dead-the-game-is-getting-delisted.1177887/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/04/30/evil-dead-the-game-is-getting-delisted/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Evil Dead: The Game is being delisted from digital storefronts, Saber Interactive has announced. The statement the company has released follows the disappearance of the game from the <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-gb/games/evil-dead-the-game/">PlayStation Store,</a> among others. Those who own the game will not need to worry about servers being shut down, as it has been made clear that the servers for Evil Dead: The Game will remain online.</p>
<p><iframe title="Evil Dead: The Game - Launch Trailer | PS5 &amp; PS4 Games" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/LiZqKiamYSs?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>In a statement on Steam, Saber Interactive said, <em>“We can confirm we’ve begun the process of removing the game from digital storefronts. Anyone who has purchased the game will still be able to play it as we plan to keep our servers online for everyone. We want to extend a sincere thank you to our community, to those who have been part of the game from the very beginning, and those who have recently joined us. We appreciate all of your support.”</em></p>
<p>The delisting of Evil Dead: The Game comes just shy of three years from the game’s launch date of May 13th, 2022, when it released for PC, PS5, PS4, Xbox Series XS, Xbox One, and Nintendo Switch. The game is an asymmetrical multiplayer game where four players face off against a number of villains controlled by another player. In our <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2022/05/16/evil-dead-the-game-review/">Evil Dead: The Game Review</a>, Jim said, <em>“Evil Dead fans will love the amount of fan service on offer here, from the painstaking recreation of movie locations to Bruce Campbell’s goofy one-liners. However, when it comes to raw entertainment value, there’s an imbalance between the forces of good and evil. Playing as the survivors can be fun with friends but lacks the fun or variety of being an evildoer.”</em></p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1493750/view/501697399294526021?l=english">Steam</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Codemasters Shows Off F1 25 Gameplay, Confirms WRC Games Are On Pause]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/codemasters-shows-off-f1-25-gameplay-confirms-wrc-games-are-on-pause/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/codemasters-shows-off-f1-25-gameplay-confirms-wrc-games-are-on-pause.1177884/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/codemasters-shows-off-f1-25-gameplay-confirms-wrc-games-are-on-pause/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>EA studio Codemasters had two major announcements for players, one to do with the WRC and DiRT games, and the other with <a href="https://wccftech.com/f1-25-announced-for-may-30-launch-pc-requirements-released/">F1 25</a>.</p>
<p>F1 25 fans get the 'good news' end of the deal, with Codemasters showing off the first gameplay for F1 25, highlighting the reversed tracks, the improvements players will enjoy in F1 25 due to <span data-olk-copy-source="MessageBody">LIDAR scanning</span>, and all the little details in these tracks being rebuilt to really add that extra layer of realism for players keen to jump behind the wheel.</p>
<p>WRC and DiRT fans aren't as lucky, with the confirmation that the 2024 season expansion for EA Sports WRC 2023 is the last expansion from the team, and Codemasters is officially pausing development on future rally racing titles.</p>
<p>"<em>After releasing EA SPORTS WRC in 2023, the 2024 season, including the recently released Hard Chargers Content pack, will be our last expansion. For now, we are pausing development plans on future rally titles. Rest assured, EA SPORTS WRC will continue to be available for existing and new players,</em>" Codemasters wrote in a <a href="https://www.ea.com/games/ea-sports-wrc/wrc-24/news/wrc-development-update">blog post</a> on the EA Sports WRC website.</p>
<p>"<em>Our WRC partnership was a culmination of sorts for our Codemasters journey with off-road racing, spanning decades through titles like Colin McRae Rally, and DiRT. We've provided a home for every rally enthusiast, striving tirelessly to push the boundaries and deliver the exhilarating thrill of driving on the ragged edge...Thank you to all the fans who have and continue to be part of our rally journey.</em>"</p>
<p>Back to F1 25, the new gameplay trailer showcases four of the five updated circuits and digs into the improvements made in this iteration.</p>
<p>"<em><span data-olk-copy-source="MessageBody">The tech behind LIDAR gives players unprecedented levels of detail, bringing them closer to each race weekend,</span></em>" creative director at Codemasters Gavin Cooper said in a press release. "<em><span data-olk-copy-source="MessageBody">Also, we’ve carefully selected the three reverse circuits to provide a unique and engaging experience for our players that feels polished, authentic, and fun. The process includes reworking DRS zones, retraining AI, recalibrating sector boundaries, repositioning the starting grid and pit lanes, and more, delivering new thrills and</span></em> <em>challenges</em>."</p>
<p><iframe title="F1 25 First Look at Gameplay" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/smwFJlL9wCU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>F1 25 will arrive on PS5, Xbox Series X/S and PC this coming May 30, 2025.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fortnite dev thinks bans on generated AI art will eventually become "unenforceable"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/fortnite-dev-thinks-bans-on-generated-ai-art-will-eventually-become-unenforceable</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fortnite-dev-thinks-bans-on-generated-ai-art-will-eventually-become-unenforceable.1177881/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/fortnite-dev-thinks-bans-on-generated-ai-art-will-eventually-become-unenforceable<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>"It's not going to stand out as a unique thing"</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Epic Games</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Ding ding, it is AI-slop-alypse-O-Clock. Time for another helping of doom-ridden commentary upon the technologies that are busily scraping and remaking all the wit, lore and gibberish accumulated over 30 blessed years of the internet. Here's a cut from <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JDZYR0gEsfg">a Mustard Plays interview</a> with Fortnite product management director Dan Walsh, in which he comments upon the issue of Fortnite players using latter-day generative AI tools to conjure up thumbnail images for their profiles. 
</p>
<p>
While Epic aren't, Walsh says, about to use any genAI when creating their own assets such as character models for Fortnite, they don't really care if players do, as long as the resulting images don't break any rules around graphic violence or similar. Beyond that, Walsh argues that generated images are becoming so tricky to spot that the idea of banning their usage in a game like Fortnite is impractical. Hmmm.</p> <!--more-->
<p>Here's the quote in full, via <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/fortnite-wont-police-ai-generated-thumbnail-images-and-epic-games-says-detecting-them-will-likely-become-impossible">Eurogamer</a>:
</p>
<blockquote><p>
 "From our perspective, for moderation, thumbnails - like, we don't really care what tool you use to make your thumbnails. All we care about is whether or not it's compliant with our rules. I think to some degree AI is going to become more and more difficult to detect. It's not going to stand out as a unique thing, it's just going to be another tool that people are using to create things. So trying to look for that specifically is going to become increasingly difficult to the point where it's probably going to become unenforceable. We're really just focused on - 'does this asset comply with our rules, yes or no?', not 'what tool did you use to make this asset'?" 
</p></blockquote>
<p>
It's perhaps focussing on the trees, not the wood, but I'm struck by Walsh's suggestion that genAI stuff at large is becoming impossible to detect, inasmuch as it rests on the idea that genAI art currently looks a certain way, that genAI is a kind of artstyle with specific hallmarks. In amongst all the gloom of the genAI industry's impact at the level of livelihoods, energy consumption and conceptions of creativity or culture, I find it endlessly interesting to grapple with what, right now, is considered a symptom or stigma of AI generation. 
</p>
<p>
The obvious signs are outright errors - characters having too many fingers, or objects with reversed proportions. There's also a bottomless seam of syrupy or sparkly genAI material that is evidently born of the understanding that "artistic" means expensive-looking. The goalposts move continually, however, and I do worry that certain creative works are getting misidentified in the urgency to identify the regurgitations. 
</p>
<p>
Works of photorealism, for example, a tradition now heavily associated with fancy computing technology. Or simply projects that wear their inspirations so openly and honestly that they can be falsely interpreted as automatic pastiche. I'm uneasy about the association of genAI with obvious errors - there are plenty of digital artists who make deliberate usage of incorrectness, blemishes, and uncanny disorder. There are plenty of artists who work with more "innocent" forms of generation. Experimental art in general is at risk of being mislabelled because it is supposed to seem counterintuitive, or perverse. 
</p>
<p>
To care about art in the current era of vociferously oversold generated art is to be lumbered with the maintenance of a personal Turing Test methodology that must be continually updated as the genAI tools themselves change. Inasmuch as there's anything positive or "fun" about having billion-dollar image-scramblers dumped on us by a collection of big corporations in need of double-digit growth, it's being obliged to engage more closely with all sorts of artistic traditions, so as to sort the human-crafted stuff from the bot fabulations.</p>
<p>Anyway, this probably should have been a proper editorial. I started writing a news piece and got carried away. It happens! What do you look for when you're trying to identify a piece of AI-generated art? Do you think that certain image generation tools have particular visual hallmarks?

</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sony Announces PlayStation Plus Monthly Games for May 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/sony-announces-playstation-plus-monthly-games-for-may-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sony-announces-playstation-plus-monthly-games-for-may-2025.1177869/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/sony-announces-playstation-plus-monthly-games-for-may-2025<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Balatro, Ark, and Warhammer 40,000.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Sony has announced the PlayStation Plus monthly games for May 2025.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As revealed in a post on the <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2025/04/30/playstation-plus-monthly-games-for-may-ark-survival-ascended-balatro-warhammer-40000-boltgun/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">PlayStation Blog</a>, PS Plus members can download Ark: Survival Ascended, Balatro, and Warhammer 40,000: Boltgun for free from May 6 to June 2.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s worth noting that Until Dawn, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/rumored-may-2025-free-ps-plus-game-ties-in-with-a-hollywood-movie-release">which was rumored to be a May PS Plus game</a>, is not on the list.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Here’s the official blurb on each game, courtesy of Sony:</p><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>Ark: Survival Ascended | PS5</strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Are you ready to form a tribe, tame and breed hundreds of species of dinosaurs and other primeval creatures, explore, craft, build, and fight your way to the top of the food-chain? Your new world awaits in this survival sim, reimagined from the ground-up with Unreal Engine 5, with high-end graphic features, advanced physics systems and quality of life revamps in every area. Ark: Survival Ascended includes access to all of Ark’s worlds, including Scorched Earth, Aberration, Extinction, Ark Genesis Part 1, Ark Genesis Part 2, and more. The game supports public online multiplayer for up to 70 players, private-session multiplayer for up to 8 players, and local split-screen for 2 players.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>Balatro | PS5, PS4 </strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">In this poker-inspired roguelike deck builder, it’s all creating powerful synergies and winning big. Play illegal poker hands, discover game-changing jokers and trigger outrageous combos in this roguelike strategy experience. Combine valid poker hands with unique joker cards in order to create varied synergies and builds. Earn enough chips to beat devious blinds, all while uncovering hidden bonus hands and decks as you progress. You’re going to need every edge you can get in order to reach the boss blind, beat the final ante and secure victory.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>Warhammer 40,000: Boltgun | PS5, PS4 </strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Load up your Boltgun and plunge into battle headfirst! Experience a perfect blend of Warhammer 40,000, classic, frenetic FPS gameplay and the stylish visuals of your favourite 90’s retro shooters. Play a battle-hardened Space Marine on a perilous mission across the galaxy, as they battle against the Chaos Space Marines and daemons of Chaos. In glorious boomer shooter style, unleash your devastating Space Marine arsenal as you blast through an explosion of sprites, pixels and blood. Run, jump and charge across huge levels to shoot, shred and slice the worst heretics across the galaxy!</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Meanwhile, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/sony-pulls-first-party-ps3-games-resistance-fall-of-man-and-resistance-2-from-ps5-and-ps4-as-part-of-big-ps-plus-clearout"><u>22 games are set to be pulled from the PlayStation Plus library next month</u></a>, including <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/grand-theft-auto-v"><u>Grand Theft Auto 5</u></a>, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/payday-2"><u>Payday 2</u></a>: Crimewave Edition, and the last playable versions of first-party titles <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/resistance-fall-of-man"><u>Resistance: Fall of Man</u></a> and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/resistance-2"><u>Resistance 2</u></a>. As a result, Resistance: Fall of Man and Resistance 2 will now completely disappear for modern consoles.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>