<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 17:47:54 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What’s Up With The Petanks In Clair Obscur: Expedition 33?]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/clair-obscur-expedition-33-catch-fight-beat-petanks-1851779185</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/what%E2%80%99s-up-with-the-petanks-in-clair-obscur-expedition-33.1181388/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/clair-obscur-expedition-33-catch-fight-beat-petanks-1851779185<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>You might’ve noticed among all the giant hammer-wielding, blade-swinging, death-dealing hate-puppets out there in the Paintress’ domain that there’s one enemy that absolutely, positively, categorically does not want the smoke from you at any point. And that’s these little cracked orbs on legs that take off like they’re trying to win the Boston marathon when you get within striking range. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="197551" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Minecraft Movie Song Sets Record as Shortest Track Ever on Billboard Hot 100" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="121" data-playlist="197551,197550,197547" data-current="197551"><div><p>Minecraft Movie Song Sets Record as Shortest Track Ever on Billboard Hot 100</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197551/197551_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197551/197551_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197551/197551_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/23075.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>They’re called Petanks, undoubtedly named after the classic French game where you try to get your balls as close as possible to get the best score.</p><p><strong>Read More:</strong> <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/clair-obscur-expedition-33-attack-jar-light-resin-1851778839&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/clair-obscur-expedition-33-attack-jar-light-resin-1851778839">Should You Attack Jar In <em>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</em>?</a></span></p><p>You might be wondering if and how exactly to catch and compromise these little bastards to a permanent end, and we’re here to tell you that you can and you will, long as you know what you’re up against. </p><p>1. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;#chase&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="#chase">The chase</a></span><br>2. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;#battle&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="#battle">The battle</a></span></p><hr><h2 id="h837034"><a id="chase"></a>The chase</h2><p>So, obviously, the main problem is actually getting the damn things to stop moving long enough to actually catch, since they take off when you’re just inside attack range.<em> Clair Obscur</em> ain’t Plague Tale, though; <strong>there’s no stealthy way to get this done</strong>. <strong>What you’re actually trying to do with these guys is herd them onto a very specific metal plate nearby glowing the same color as the Petank</strong>. </p><p><strong>Read More:</strong> <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/clair-obscur-expedition-33-lune-stains-skills-burn-1851778480&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/clair-obscur-expedition-33-lune-stains-skills-burn-1851778480">A Beginner’s Guide To Mastering Lune In <em>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</em></a></span></p><div><p>That metal spot will freeze them in place long enough to attack. However, that plate can be further away than you think, so if you see a Petank, before you even think of getting this show on the road, clear out every enemy wandering the immediate area. They’ll never put the plate outside of one of the cramped connective doors/spaces/hallways/corridors in the world, so you just need to clean up in proximity. You’ll likely discover the plate while wandering around, just keep its location in mind. </p><p>When the coast is clear, you’re not so much trying to chase the Petank onto the plate as herd it there. Petanks have a fixed route/grid they’ll run in, with specific stopping points. Your job is to simply run them down those lines towards the plate. Once they’re on there, get all healed up, and get ready for a fight.</p></div><h2 id="h837035"><a id="battle"></a>The battle</h2><p><strong>When a battle starts with these guys, your first instinct might be to Free Aim at the big glowy weakspot in the center of the orb. That would be a waste of AP; it’s not a weakspo</strong>t. And you definitely don’t have AP to waste: With only two exceptions, you have three turns total to beat this thing, after which it’ll flee and <strong>you’ll need to either rest at a flag or reload a save to bring it back</strong>. </p><p><strong>Read MOre:</strong> <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/clair-obscur-33-gustave-best-skills-lumiere-overdrive-1851777694&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/clair-obscur-33-gustave-best-skills-lumiere-overdrive-1851777694">A Beginner’s Guide To Mastering Gustave In <em>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</em></a></span></p><p>In addition, each Petank you find has its own specific gimmick/strategy involved. And sure, you can go ahead and try and suss that out with some trial and error. Or, you can just go through this handy list we made for you right here because, idk, we love you or something.</p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li><strong>Ancient Sanctuary Petank (Act I)</strong>: Starts shielded, gains 6 shields each turn, 9 on turn 3</li><li><strong>Esquie’s Nest Petank (Act I)</strong>: High defense; must be broken to do real damage</li><li><strong>Stone Wave Cliffs Petank (Act I)</strong>: Summons Nevrons each turn; only takes damage when no other enemies are on the field</li><li><strong>Forgotten Battlefield Petank (Act II)</strong>: Applies Exhaust (no AP gained)</li><li><strong>Sirene Petank (Act II)</strong>: Must be killed within 2 turns</li><li><strong>Monolith Petank (Act II)</strong>: Extremely slow, but extremely high defense, cannot Break.</li></ul><p>In addition, there’s a secret Chromatic Petank on the eastern part of the Overworld/Continent maps that you can only get to once Esquie learns how to fly. His gimmick is that he summons other Petanks, and if they’re allowed to escape, they heal the Chromatic one. That fight is rough, ngl.</p><p>Still, once you know the gimmick, it’s just a matter of doing the damage, which you have a lot of leeway to figure out with your current loadout. </p><div><p><strong>Read More: </strong><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/clair-obscur-expedition-33-tips-pictos-stains-stances-1851777496&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/clair-obscur-expedition-33-tips-pictos-stains-stances-1851777496">8 Things To Know Before Starting <em>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</em></a></span></p><p>The reward for all your hard work is typically a nice combo pack of Colours of Lumina or Chroma Catalysts, the stuff the Curator needs to upgrade your weaponry and give your team more Lumina points. Considering how tough it is to come by that stuff out in the world, especially at higher levels, yeah, this little detour is almost always worth it. </p></div><p>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tinkerlands launches in Early Access on May 23]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/05/tinkerlands-launches-in-early-access-on-may-23</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/tinkerlands-launches-in-early-access-on-may-23.1181382/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/05/tinkerlands-launches-in-early-access-on-may-23<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Explore, craft, and fight your way on uncharted islands.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><em><a title="Games > Tinkerlands" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/tinkerlands">Tinkerlands</a></em> will launch in Early Access for <a title="Platforms > PC [23,065 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2617700/Tinkerlands/" target="_blank">Steam</a> on May 23, publisher <a title="Companies > HypeTrain Digital [21 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/hypetrain-digital">HypeTrain Digital</a> and developers <a title="Companies > CodeManu [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/codemanu">CodeManu</a> and endless Coffee announced. <span id="more-962899"></span></p><p>The Early Access release will be playable in both single-player and <a title="Genres > Multiplayer [494 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer">multiplayer</a>, and feature a large main island, three major islands, and multiple minor islands to discover, as well as more than 10 unique bosses, a class system and events that change the state of islands, various side activities, and over 2,000 items and objects.</p><p>The game is expected to remain in Early Access for six to eight months, but that can change depending on user feedback. The full release will add one to three major islands, additional minor islands, new gameplay systems, endgame content, expanded <a title="Genres > Crafting [33 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/crafting">crafting</a> and exploration, expanded NPC interactions, and additional language support.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via HypeTrain Digital:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>In <em>Tinkerlands</em>, players find themselves stranded on an island. They must craft, scavenge equipment, build a town for fellow survivors, and face various dangers in this mysterious world!</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Explore the Islands</strong> – The islands are full of things to explore. <a title="Companies > Enhance [31 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/enhance">Enhance</a> your character’s strength by discovering loot and crafting weapons and gear.</li><li><strong>Build a Town</strong> – Establish a community where diverse characters can join and assist you throughout your <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,253 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a>.</li><li><strong>Craft and Find Loot</strong> – Collect resources from the island’s environment and vanquish monsters to craft formidable weapons—or less powerful ones, if that’s your preference.</li><li><strong>Fantasy Allowed</strong> – These islands harbor magic, peculiar creatures, and even things that defy the laws of physics. Let your imagination run wild!</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer.</p><h2><span>Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Tinkerlands - Release Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ivkaa0fCRPQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jackbox Party Pack 11's First Revealed Game Is Suspectives]]></title>
            <link>https://gameinformer.com/2025/05/05/jackbox-party-pack-11s-first-revealed-game-is-suspectives</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/jackbox-party-pack-11s-first-revealed-game-is-suspectives.1181379/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://gameinformer.com/2025/05/05/jackbox-party-pack-11s-first-revealed-game-is-suspectives<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text" typeof="schema:Article"><p>Jackbox Party Pack 11 is coming at some vague point later this Fall, and up until today, its inclusions were also vague. Suspectives is the first game revealed for the new pack and you can check out the trailer for it below.</p>

<p><iframe allow="autoplay" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/YT3BXNBp-xE" width="640"></iframe></p>

<p>The game takes inspiration from party games like <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mafia_(party_game)">Mafia</a> or <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Werewolves_Within">Werewolves Within</a> where one player is a secret criminal and the others must deduce who it is. This is done by players sharing personal anecdotes about themselves and then those details become part of the investigation process.</p>

<p>According to the press release for the new game, "Suspectives is a detective-themed social deduction game where players work together to uncover the secret criminal hiding among them. The only clues left behind? Facts that players share about themselves. Suspectives turns players’ quirky personal details into the key evidence for solving a crime. Players must put each other in the hot seat to determine if the evidence stacks up against them."</p>

<p>The game is designed for 4-8 players and rounds can be played in about 10-15 minutes. As mentioned previously, The Jackbox Party Pack 11 is coming later this year.</p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gears Of War Makes Its PlayStation Debut This Summer]]></title>
            <link>https://gameinformer.com/2025/05/05/gears-of-war-makes-its-playstation-debut-this-summer</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gears-of-war-makes-its-playstation-debut-this-summer.1181376/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://gameinformer.com/2025/05/05/gears-of-war-makes-its-playstation-debut-this-summer<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p>We’ve seen more and more Xbox first-party franchises launching on PlayStation over the last year or so, and arguably Microsoft’s second-biggest exclusive franchise is next in line. Gears of War is finally making its debut on Sony platforms in the form of a remaster dubbed Gears of War: Reloaded.</p>

<p>Reloaded, which is also coming to Xbox, is billed as the definitive version of the original Gears of War, first released in 2006. It has been natively optimized for modern platforms, boasting a 4K resolution and support for 120 frames per second gameplay. Multiplayer includes cross-play across all platforms, and a Microsoft account is not required for online play (most relevant for PS players). The game also features cross-progression, letting you carry campaign and multiplayer progress across multiple platforms.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Content-wise, Reloaded includes everything included in the previous remaster, <a href="https://gameinformer.com/games/gears_of_war_ultimate_edition/b/xboxone/archive/2015/08/26/restored-beauty.aspx">Gears of War: Ultimate Edition</a>. That includes all post-launch DLC, the bonus campaign act, all multiplayer maps/modes, and the complete roster of characters and cosmetics unlockable through progression.&nbsp;</p>












<article data-embed-button="image_browser_uploader" data-entity-embed-display="view_mode:file.body_default_rendered" data-entity-embed-display-settings="{&quot;link_url&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;link_target&quot;:0,&quot;link_original&quot;:1,&quot;image_source&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;embed_source&quot;:0,&quot;image_caption&quot;:&quot;Click to enlarge&quot;,&quot;embed_caption&quot;:0,&quot;content_warning&quot;:0}" data-entity-type="file" data-entity-uuid="b06c9fd7-4a0b-4930-9867-18ff3179ad79" data-langcode="en"><a data-featherlight="image" href="">
</a>





<p>Click to enlarge</p>

</article><p>Here’s the complete list of Reloaded’s features:</p>

<ul><li>4K resolution</li>
	<li>60 FPS in campaign</li>
	<li>120 FPS in multiplayer</li>
	<li>High Dynamic Range (HDR)</li>
	<li>Dolby Vision &amp; 7.1.4 Dolby Atmos</li>
	<li>7.1.4 3D Spatial Audio</li>
	<li>Variable Refresh Rate (VRR)</li>
	<li>4K assets and remastered textures</li>
	<li>Enhanced post-processing visual effects</li>
	<li>Improved shadows and reflections</li>
	<li>Super resolution with improved anti-aliasing</li>
	<li>Zero loading screens during campaign</li>
</ul><p>Gears of War: Reloaded will be released on August 26 for PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X/S, and PC (via Steam). It will cost $39.99 and will be available on Game Pass at launch for Ultimate and PC Game Pass subscribers. Furthermore, Reloaded will be a free upgrade to players who already purchased Gears of War: Ultimate Edition before today’s announcement.&nbsp;</p>

<p>If you’re new to Gears of War, Reloaded seems like a great way to get acquainted ahead of its upcoming prequel, Gears of War: E-Day. You can read about the announcement of that title from last year’s Xbox Games Showcase <a href="https://gameinformer.com/xbox-showcase/2024/06/09/gears-of-war-e-day-is-a-prequel-set-14-years-before-the-first-game">here</a>.&nbsp;</p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gears of War Hits PS5 for the First Time With Gears of War: Reloaded]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/gears-of-war-reloaded-announced</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gears-of-war-hits-ps5-for-the-first-time-with-gears-of-war-reloaded.1181370/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/gears-of-war-reloaded-announced<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Microsoft has announced&nbsp;<em>Gears of War: Reloaded</em>, a remastered version of the seminal 2006 third-person shooter, and it marks the third-person shooter series' debut on PS5.</p>

<p>Per an Xbox <a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2025/05/05/gears-of-war-reloaded-release-date/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">announcement</a>,&nbsp;<em>Gears of War: Reloaded&nbsp;</em>lands on PC, Xbox Series X|S, and PS5 on August 26th. It's a "faithfully remastered and natively optimized" version of the original&nbsp;<em>Gears of War</em>, which is to say it's essentially a new version of 2015's&nbsp;<em>Gears of War: Ultimate Edition</em>.</p>

<p>You can expect all the usual current-gen bells and whistles: 120fps and 4K support, cross-play and cross-progression, and all of the original game's DLC, including the bonus Campaign act and "a full roster of classic characters and cosmetics unlockable through progression".</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/gears-of-war-reloaded-characters.jpg?itok=-aSlhzbk 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/gears-of-war-reloaded-characters.jpg?itok=1DxFY8Hf 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Gears of War: Reloaded&nbsp;</em>is another&nbsp;<em>Gears of War&nbsp;</em>remaster, and it's coming your way in August.</figcaption></figure><p><em>Gears of War: Reloaded&nbsp;</em>is a co-development effort between longtime&nbsp;<em>Gears&nbsp;</em>stewards The Coalition, British outfit Sumo Interactive (who recently <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/sumo-group-layoffs-refocus" rel="nofollow">made the move to predominantly partner-based work like this</a>), and support studio Disbelief.</p>

<p>It'll support two-player campaign co-op play, as well as up to eight players in multiplayer modes, all of which can be enjoyed across different platforms. Signing into a Microsoft account also allows you to enjoy cross-progression, so you can pick up where you left off on any platform.</p>

<p>Thanks to the Xbox Series X|S and PS5's SSDs, you can also enjoy a campaign with "zero loading screens", according to Microsoft, as well as a host of visual improvements like enhanced post-processing and better shadows.</p>

<p>If you already bought&nbsp;<em>Gears of War: Ultimate Edition</em>, don't worry; you'll be getting this one as a free upgrade, although you can't rush out and buy the game now, because that only applies to purchases made before 4pm UTC today (which is about twenty minutes ago at time of writing).</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/gears-of-war-reloaded-baird-cole.jpg?itok=bBzqAd7s 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/gears-of-war-reloaded-baird-cole.jpg?itok=Ywi-PP_8 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>You'll get&nbsp;<em>Gears of War: Reloaded&nbsp;</em>for free if you bought&nbsp;<em>Ultimate Edition</em>.</figcaption></figure><p><em>Gears of War: Reloaded&nbsp;</em>launches for <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2523720/Gears_of_War_Reloaded/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC</a>, <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/concept/10008829" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PlayStation 5</a>, and Xbox Series X|S on August 26th. It'll cost you $40, unless you already own&nbsp;<em>Ultimate Edition</em>, but it'll also be on PC Game Pass and Game Pass Ultimate on day one.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Microsoft announces a Gears of War remaster – and it’s coming to PlayStation, too]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/661169/gears-of-war-reloaded-remaster-release-date</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/microsoft-announces-a-gears-of-war-remaster-%E2%80%93-and-it%E2%80%99s-coming-to-playstation-too.1181367/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/news/661169/gears-of-war-reloaded-remaster-release-date<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/jay-peters">Jay Peters</a> <span>is a news editor covering technology, gaming, and more. He joined The Verge in 2019 after nearly two years at Techmeme.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Microsoft <a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2025/05/05/gears-of-war-reloaded-release-date/">just announced</a> <em>Gears of War: Reloaded</em>, a remaster of the original game that’s launching on August 26th for Xbox Series X / S, PlayStation, and PC for $39.99. </p><p>“<em>Gears of War: Reloaded</em> is a celebration of one of gaming’s most iconic franchises,” according to <a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2025/05/05/gears-of-war-reloaded-release-date/">an Xbox Wire blog post</a>. “Featuring 4K resolution, 120 FPS support, and the ultimate multiplayer experience with cross-progression and cross-play, across all platforms, this is the definitive way to experience the game that started it all.”</p><p>The game will have the “full breadth of content from the <em>Gears of War: Ultimate Edition</em>” and “players will gain immediate access to all post-launch downloadable content at no additional cost,” including “the bonus Campaign act, all multiplayer maps and modes, and a full roster of classic characters and cosmetics unlockable through progression.”</p><p><em>Gears of War: Reloaded</em> will have two-player co-op for the campaign and 8-player multiplayer. And if you owned <em>Gears of War: Ultimate Edition</em> ahead of Monday’s announcement at 12PM ET, you’ll get <em>Reloaded</em> as a free upgrade.</p><p>Last year, Microsoft announced a new game in the series, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/24172052/gears-6-xbox-summer-game-fest-trailer"><em>Gears of War: E-Day</em></a>, which doesn’t yet have a release date. </p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fallout 1 & 2 Source Code Still Exists, Despite Orders To Destroy It]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/fallout-source-code-saved-interplay-cain-order-destroy-1851779159</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fallout-1-2-source-code-still-exists-despite-orders-to-destroy-it.1181361/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/fallout-source-code-saved-interplay-cain-order-destroy-1851779159<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>The original source code for <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/fallout-3-van-buren-cancellation-tim-cain-1851550786&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/fallout-3-van-buren-cancellation-tim-cain-1851550786">Interplay’s <em>Fallout </em>and its sequel <em>Fallout 2</em></a></span> was thought lost and destroyed. But it turns out that at least one person defied orders from the studio and saved the source code behind two of the most popular PC RPGs ever made. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196903" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Why Fallout: New Vegas Is Still Canon After The TV Show" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="189" data-playlist="196903,196411,196055" data-current="196903"><div><p>Why Fallout: New Vegas Is Still Canon After The TV Show</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196903/196903_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196903/196903_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196903/196903_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196903/196903_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/22460.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/destroy-everything-you-have-on-fallouts-development-interplay-told-creator&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/destroy-everything-you-have-on-fallouts-development-interplay-told-creator" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">In April, <em>Fallout </em>creator Tim Cain explained</a></span> that when he left Interplay in 1998 he was ordered to destroy any game assets or code he was holding onto that didn’t belong to him. This included the source code for the OG <em>Fallout</em>. Cain complied, which made it awkward when Interplay called a few years later asking if he had <em>Fallout’s </em>source code still. He thought it was a trap; turns out, Interplay had actually lost the code for it and <em>Fallout 2</em>. And <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/tim-cain-fallout-obsidian-lgbtq-pride-month-gay-history-1850501928&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/tim-cain-fallout-obsidian-lgbtq-pride-month-gay-history-1850501928">Cain</a></span> had assumed that due to Interplay’s “destroy it all” policy, the source code for the old RPGs were lost and destroyed. Thankfully, that’s not the case. </p><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.videogamer.com/news/fallout-1-fallout-2-source-code-isnt-actually-not-lost-reveals-former-interplay-founder/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.videogamer.com/news/fallout-1-fallout-2-source-code-isnt-actually-not-lost-reveals-former-interplay-founder/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">On May 5, <em>Videogamer </em>reported</a></span> that it had heard from Interplay founder and game designer Rebecca Heineman that she had the source code for both <em>Fallout </em>and its sequel, as well as many other Interplay classics. She started preserving every Interplay game after working on the studio’s <em>10 Year Anthology: Classic Collection </em>and realizing how poorly the company’s past work was being saved for the future. </p><p> “I made it a quest to snapshot everything and archive it on CD-ROMs,” Heineman explained. “When I left Interplay in 1995, I had copies of every game we did. No exceptions. When I did MacPlay, which existed beyond my tenure at Interplay, every game we ported, I snapshotted. It included <em>Fallout 1 </em>and <em>2.</em>” </p><p>Heineman confirmed to <em>Videogamer </em>that Cain’s comments about Interplay demanding all employees who leave the studio destroy all assets or face possible “litigation” in the future was true. She just didn’t follow those orders. And while she doesn’t have Caine’s lost and destroyed design docs and notes, she does have the source code for <em>Fallout </em>and <em>Fallout 2</em> safely secured on a high quality Blu-Ray disc.</p><p> “Interplay had a reputation of threatening ex-employees with litigation if they were ‘poached’, and if they had assets taken home,” she told the outlet. “However, they had no legal leg to stand on which was why a suit was never filed on anyone. [If] they did have a legal leg to stand on, I would have been sued into last week.”</p><p>As for why Heineman hasn’t released the code to the internet, she says that could only happen with permission from Bethesda (now the owners of <em>Fallout</em>) as they are still selling <em>Fallout </em>and <em>Fallout 2</em> today. </p><p>“I need expressed permission to release, despite the source code being pretty much obsolete,” said Heineman. “I [haven’t] gotten around to asking them. They are on my list.” She is a busy woman, working on bringing back MacPlay and porting more games to Mac. But hopefully, when she does ask, Bethesda is cool with her sharing these important pieces of game history online. </p><p> .<br></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Last Of Us Fans Are Divided On The Show’s Ellie And Dina Romance]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/last-us-dina-ellie-romance-sex-scene-pregnant-episode-4-1851779166</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-last-of-us-fans-are-divided-on-the-show%E2%80%99s-ellie-and-dina-romance.1181355/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/last-us-dina-ellie-romance-sex-scene-pregnant-episode-4-1851779166<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>After four agonizing weeks of waiting, Dina and Ellie finally consummated their relationship in <em>The Last of Us </em><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/last-us-season-2-episode-4-dina-ellie-isaac-seraphite-1851779062&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/last-us-season-2-episode-4-dina-ellie-isaac-seraphite-1851779062">during this week’s episode</a></span>. The <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/last-of-us-season-2-hbo-max-show-review-joel-ellie-abby-1851774661&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/last-of-us-season-2-hbo-max-show-review-joel-ellie-abby-1851774661">live-action adaptation</a></span> has taken a few creative liberties with the girl’s love story, and that meant rather than starting the game out in a relationship, it baited the audience with a month-long “will they/won’t they?” arc. But now that they’ve confessed their feelings and decided to live a life of mutual domesticity with a kid on the way, the reaction has been somewhat mixed. Like most criticism laid at the show’s feet, it has to do with how showrunner Craig Mazin has chosen to change the storyline up for the show compared to the game on which it’s based.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="195618" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Unboxing The Baldur’s Gate 3 Collector’s Edition" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="376" data-playlist="195618,197551,197550" data-current="195618"><div><p>Unboxing The Baldur’s Gate 3 Collector’s Edition</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195618/195618_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195618/195618_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195618/195618_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195618/195618_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21110.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>In <em>The Last of Us Part II</em>, Dina and Ellie’s relationship begins in much happier circumstances. This is before <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/last-of-us-hbo-max-show-joel-death-abby-kills-reaction-1851777068&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/last-of-us-hbo-max-show-joel-death-abby-kills-reaction-1851777068">Joel’s death at the hands of Abby</a></span>, and so it’s not heightened by the explosive life-or-death circumstances seen in the show. The two’s budding romance is pretty much conflict-free for the first several hours of the game. Dina is a ride-or-die, ready to help Ellie cross state lines for her revenge tour in Seattle, and most of their time together on the first day in the city is about getting to know each other better in this new romantic context. The first time there’s real tension between the girls is when Dina reveals that she is pregnant with her ex-boyfriend Jesse’s baby. By this point, they’ve been traveling for weeks to reach the city, and Dina suspected she was pregnant for at least some of the trip. Ellie is furious at her for keeping this information from her, saying that they could have turned around and gotten her back home, going as far as to call her a “burden” in a fit of anger.</p><p>The two reconcile the next morning, but the scene illustrates how Ellie’s violent conquest is distorting everything else in her life. She’s concerned for Dina, but frustrated at how this development threatens to derail her revenge. Ellie comes off as boorish and dismissive of her girlfriend’s condition, and it stings hearing something so callous come out of her mouth in the heat of the moment. Compare that to the show’s take on this reveal:</p><p>Ellie is jazzed about being a parent in HBO’s version of the scene. Some fans similarly share the excitement of the mothers-to-be. Part of this is no doubt because viewers have been waiting for weeks for these two to seal the deal, but Ellie actor Bella Ramsey’s humorous “I’m gonna be a dad” line has become its own meme. It’s a sweet scene, and cuteness is enough to win over most people’s hearts.</p><p>But isn’t it all a little too perfect? That’s the argument some <em>Last of Us </em>fans are making, looking at the scenes side-by-side.</p><blockquote data-type="BlockQuote"><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.tiktok.com/@ackvvrman/video/7500789433646484766&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.tiktok.com/@ackvvrman/video/7500789433646484766" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">TikTok</a></span> user tambor wrote, “I’m trying real hard to defend the show and understand their choices, but why is Ellie so joyous after Joel’s death?”</p><p>“I know everybody’s gonna love this change because it’s funny, but them removing all of the conflict and relationship development and combining it into one happy-go-lucky fairytale moment is annoying,” TikTok user char said in the comments.</p><p>“I didn’t like this change [because] it was one of the stepping stones of Ellie losing herself to revenge,” TikTok user Invader wrote. “I hope they can still flesh this out correctly.”</p></blockquote><p>Part of me reads this as another example of the show being scared to let its leads be unlikeable. The adaptation has taken a lot of the thornier aspects of the original story out to endear viewers to characters like Abby and Joel. The second season was forthcoming with Abby’s motivations, seemingly in an effort to help viewers warm up to her after the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/last-of-us-part-2-abby-laura-bailey-threats-grounded-1851222035&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/last-of-us-part-2-abby-laura-bailey-threats-grounded-1851222035">ludicrous backlash</a></span> toward her when <em>The Last of Us Part II </em>launched. The show also <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/last-of-us-tlou-hbo-show-finale-joel-lies-ellie-part-ii-1850209559&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/last-of-us-tlou-hbo-show-finale-joel-lies-ellie-part-ii-1850209559">bent over backwards to justify Joel’s violent actions</a></span> in season one, so this isn’t a recent tonal shift for HBO’s recreation. Ellie’s curt reaction to Dina’s pregnancy is hardly the most reprehensible thing she’ll do before she leaves Seattle, but if the show’s already pulling its punches on this, it doesn’t bode well for how down-and-dirty it’s going to be when things get much, much worse for our funky little lesbian.</p><p>If nothing else, the show needed a little bit of levity after the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/last-of-us-tv-season-2-episode-joel-abby-death-reaction-1851777264&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/last-of-us-tv-season-2-episode-joel-abby-death-reaction-1851777264">brutal past couple of weeks</a></span>. Enjoy the happy gay moms while you can, viewers. Shit’s gonna hit the fan again real quick.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Destiny 2 Lawsuit Continues As Judge Rejects Bungie's Use Of YouTube Videos And Wikis]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/destiny-2-lawsuit-continues-as-judge-rejects-bungies-use-of-youtube-videos-and-wikis/1100-6531315/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/destiny-2-lawsuit-continues-as-judge-rejects-bungies-use-of-youtube-videos-and-wikis.1181352/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/destiny-2-lawsuit-continues-as-judge-rejects-bungies-use-of-youtube-videos-and-wikis/1100-6531315/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6531315">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>A lawsuit filed against Bungie alleging the developer used copyrighted ideas in <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/destiny-2/" data-ref-id="5000-463450">Destiny 2</a> just got more complicated, as a federal judge has rejected Bungie's attempt to have the case dismissed and ruled that evidence submitted by Bungie in the form of fan-made YouTube videos and wiki pages aren't acceptable.</p><p dir="ltr">The lawsuit filed by author Matthew Kelsey Martineau in late 2024 accuses Bungie of allegedly copying various ideas from their work, including Destiny 2's Red Legion faction and other elements like a giant celestial object hovering over Earth.</p><p dir="ltr">Bungie sought to have the case dismissed but has run into a strange problem. Many of the ideas Martineau cited as being accused of copyright, specifically Destiny 2's original Red War campaign and its Curse of Osiris campaign, haven't been playable for years. They've been removed from Destiny 2 as part of Bungie's "vaulting" process that sees the developer occasionally <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/destiny-2-vault-of-glass-is-returning-but-old-cont/1100-6478197/" data-ref-id="1100-6478197">remove older content</a> from the game. That led to <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/bungie-lawsuit-had-to-cite-destiny-2-fan-videos-because-in-game-content-no-longer-exists/1100-6529709/" data-ref-id="1100-6529709">Bungie including YouTube lore videos in its motion to dismiss the case</a> (like a one a 10-hour-long <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zzBmOeYmN_M" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">"Complete Story of Destiny" video</a> from YouTuber My Name is Byf) as well as wiki pages from <a href="https://www.destinypedia.com/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Destinypedia</a> in order to show the differences between Destiny 2 and Martineau's work.</p><p dir="ltr">In a declaration included as part of Bungie's attempt to dismiss the case, Destiny 2 game director Tyson Green explained that the Red War and Curse of Osiris campaigns "can no longer run because their outdated code is incompatible with Destiny 2's underlying operational framework," hence the studio's use of YouTube videos and wiki pages.</p><p dir="ltr">"As a result, Bungie cannot feasibly provide the Court with the original Destiny 2 game as it existed in 2017, including the accused 'Red War' and 'Curse of Osiris' campaigns, in any operable or reviewable form," Green said. "Nor will Bungie be able to produce the accused campaigns in operable or reviewable form if this matter proceeds to formal discovery."</p><p dir="ltr">That is, however, what's happening. The judge overseeing the case said there is sufficient evidence to proceed with the copyright infringement case and that it will not consider YouTube videos and wiki pages as acceptable on Bungie's part, as they originate from a third-party and their "authenticity" has not been established. The judge also stated that the cases Bungie cited in its motion to dismiss are not applicable to this specific case, and that the case "would require a much more complicated side-by-side analysis than those conducted in the caselaw cited by Defendant."</p><p dir="ltr">Bungie will reveal <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/destiny-2-the-edge-of-fate-reveal-announced-for-next-month/1100-6530898/" data-ref-id="1100-6530898">Destiny 2's next expansion, The Edge of Fate</a>, during an upcoming livestream on May 6. Meanwhile, Bungie's new game, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/marathon/" data-ref-id="5000-589442">Marathon</a>, recently held a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/marathon-alpha-update-allows-players-to-talk-about-the-game/1100-6530975/" data-ref-id="1100-6530975">closed Alpha test</a> and is slated to <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/bungies-marathon-releases-in-september-on-same-day-as-another-big-game/1100-6530810/" data-ref-id="1100-6530810">release on September 23</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gears of War: Reloaded Launches on PC, PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X|S This Summer With Full Cross-Progression and Cross-Platform Multiplayer]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/gears-of-war-reloaded-launches-on-pc-playstation-5-xbox-series-xs-this-summer-with-full-cross-progression-and-cross-platform-multiplayer/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gears-of-war-reloaded-launches-on-pc-playstation-5-xbox-series-x-s-this-summer-with-full-cross-progression-and-cross-platform-multiplayer.1181325/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/gears-of-war-reloaded-launches-on-pc-playstation-5-xbox-series-xs-this-summer-with-full-cross-progression-and-cross-platform-multiplayer/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Gears of War: Reloaded, a remaster of the first entry in the series, will launch this summer on PC and consoles, marking the classic third-person shooter series' debut on PlayStation consoles.</p>
<p>The remaster, which was announced today with a new post on the official <a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2025/05/05/gears-of-war-reloaded-release-date/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Xbox website</a>, is being developed by The Coalition in partnership with Sumo Interactive and Disbelief, and will be the most complete version of the game, featuring all the content included in the Gears of War: Ultimate Edition such as the main campaign, all post-launch DLC such as the bonus Campaign act, all multiplayer maps and modes, and a roster of classic characters and cosmetics that can be unlocked through progression.</p>
<p>Besides featuring all this content, Gears of War: Reloaded will enhance the original experience on all platforms with 4K resolution support, 60 FPS gameplay in the campaign and 120 FPS gameplay in multiplayer, HDR support, VRR support, enhanced post-processing visual effects, improved shadows and reflections, super resolution with improved antialiasing and zero loading screens during the Campaign. No matter which system the game is played on, signing with a Microsoft account unlocks full cross-platform functionality, enabling cross-progression and cross-platform multiplayer, including the ability to send invites to players across all systems. Cross-platform multiplayer will still be available even without a Microsoft account.</p>
<figure>
<div>

<div>
		
		
		<p><span>2 of 9</span>
	</p></div></div>
</figure>


<p>Gears of War: Reloaded launches on August 25th on PC, PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X, and Xbox Series S. Those who purchased the Ultimate Edition before today's announcement will receive the remaster as a free upgrade. The game will also be available as part of the Xbox Game Pass Ultimate and PC Game Pass libraries at launch.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch 2 May Have a Hard Time Running Unreal Engine 5 Full Set of Features; Fortnite Is a Good Indication of What to Expect]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-running-unreal-engine-5-features-trouble/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-switch-2-may-have-a-hard-time-running-unreal-engine-5-full-set-of-features-fortnite-is-a-good-indication-of-what-to-expect.1181319/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-running-unreal-engine-5-features-trouble/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The Nintendo Switch 2 will support the full set of Unreal Engine 5 features, but the hardware will likely have trouble running all of them simultaneously.</p>
<p>Replying to a supporter's question during the latest episode of their weekly podcast, the tech experts at Digital Foundry commented on how the soon-to-be-released new Nintendo system will handle games powered by the Unreal Engine 5 using features like Nanite, Lumen, and Virtual Shadow Maps. While it's obviously impossible to say for sure at this time, chances are high that games powered by the engine will likely be unable to use all the above features at the same time, not even targeting 30 FPS with significant compromises in terms of resolution, image quality, and performance. Recently, we have seen the PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X struggle to run UE5-powered games using all three features, and the Nintendo Switch 2 would struggle even more, considering its hardware.</p>
<p>All the above, however, doesn't mean that we won't see Unreal Engine 5-powered games using these features on Nintendo Switch 2, only not all of them at the same time. According to Digital Foundry, how Fortnite runs on the system is a good indication of what should be expected on the console for UE5 games. The popular battle royale game was shown running at 60 FPS, but without Lumen, which has proven to be highly demanding in a test conducted by the tech experts featuring The Matrix Awakens demo<a href="https://wccftech.com/unreal-engine-5-4-the-matrix-awakens-cpu-gpu-performance-improvements/"> ported to the latest public version of the engine</a> running on comparable PC hardware with an Ampere architecture GPU. With Lumen, the demo ran poorly even at low resolution, and with NVIDIA DLSS in Performance mode, the feature is the prime candidate, together with the demanding Virtual Shadow Maps, that will be cut or heavily cut down to achieve acceptable performance.</p>
<p><iframe title="DF Direct Weekly #212: Big Xbox Price Hikes, Doom The Dark Ages Path Tracing, Far Cry 4 60FPS!" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/FTAW38VTIJQ?start=6242&amp;feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>While the system may struggle with the complete set of Unreal Engine 5 features, the Nintendo Switch 2 handles Cyberpunk 2077 rather well, so there's a solid chance the system will be pushed beyond expectations once developers get more comfortable developing games for it. We won't have to wait much longer to finally see what the system will be capable of, as it finally launches worldwide on June 5th.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gears of War Getting New Remaster, Coming To Xbox And PS5 This Summer]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/gears-of-war-1-reloaded-remaster-ps5-xbox-pc-summer-1851779167</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gears-of-war-getting-new-remaster-coming-to-xbox-and-ps5-this-summer.1181316/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/gears-of-war-1-reloaded-remaster-ps5-xbox-pc-summer-1851779167<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Xbox announced today that a new remaster of the original <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/xbox-gears-of-war-e-day-gears-6-ending-storyline-2025-1851528933&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/xbox-gears-of-war-e-day-gears-6-ending-storyline-2025-1851528933"><em>Gears of War</em></a></span>, first released on Xbox 360 in 2006, will be launching on Xbox Series X/S, PC, and for the first time in the franchise’s history, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/PlayStation/status/1919422008451813547&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/PlayStation/status/1919422008451813547" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">PlayStation</a></span> in August.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="195928" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="How Alan Wake 2 Builds Upon The 'Remedy-Verse'" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="190" data-playlist="195928,195922,196917" data-current="195928"><div><p>How Alan Wake 2 Builds Upon The 'Remedy-Verse'</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195928/195928_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195928/195928_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195928/195928_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195928/195928_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21446.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>On May 5, Xbox revealed <em>Gears of War: Reloaded, </em>a fresh remaster of the first game in the beloved third-person cover-shooter series, featuring chainsaws, big men, and lots of grubby monsters. The newly-announced remaster will support a 4K resolution, 120 FPS multiplayer, 60 FPS campaign, crossplay, and cross-progression across all platforms. </p><p><em>Gears of War: Reloaded </em>will launch on August 26 on PS5, Xbox Series X/S, Game Pass, and PC. The new <em>Gears </em>remaster will cost $40, but in splendid news, if you already own the last <em>Gears of War </em>remaster—<em>Gears of War Ultimate Edition</em>—you’ll get a free code for <em>Reloaded</em>. It will also be available free on day one for all Game Pass Ultimate and Game Pass PC subscribers. </p><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2025/05/05/gears-of-war-reloaded-release-date/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2025/05/05/gears-of-war-reloaded-release-date/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">In an official blog post on Xbox Wire</a></span>, Microsoft explained the <em>Gears of War: Reloaded </em>is being developed by The Coalition—the studio that’s been charge of the franchise since 2015—with some help from external teams at Sumo Digital and Disbelief. </p><p><em>Gears of War: Reloaded </em>will include all of the content featured in the 2015 <em>Ultimate Edition, </em>featuring all post-launch DLC including the bonus Campaign chapter, all multiplayer maps, and a full roster of classic <em>Gears</em> characters to choose from when playing online. <em>Reloaded </em>will support full co-op and competitive crossplay without an Xbox account, though if you do link your account you’ll be able to jump between all platforms, including PS5, while keeping your progress.</p><p>In June 2024, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/gears-of-war-e-day-trailer-marcus-dom-xbox-sgf-showcase-1851528894?_gl=1*1pnov8o*_ga*NzE0NzM5NTc5LjE3Mjk4Njg5MzU.*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*czE3NDY0NTc0MjIkbzM1NSRnMSR0MTc0NjQ2MjgxNiRqNDgkbDAkaDA.&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/gears-of-war-e-day-trailer-marcus-dom-xbox-sgf-showcase-1851528894?_gl=1*1pnov8o*_ga*NzE0NzM5NTc5LjE3Mjk4Njg5MzU.*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*czE3NDY0NTc0MjIkbzM1NSRnMSR0MTc0NjQ2MjgxNiRqNDgkbDAkaDA.">Xbox and The Coalition announced the next mainline <em>Gears of War</em> game was going to be a prequel</a></span> set during E-Day and would show us how Marcus and Dom met. That game doesn’t have a release date yet. Despite the prequel, The Coalition promises it isn’t done with the characters and storylines seen in <em>Gears 4 </em>and <em>Gears 5. </em></p><p>Last year, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/microsoft-is-reportedly-considering-bringing-gears-of-war-to-playstation/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/microsoft-is-reportedly-considering-bringing-gears-of-war-to-playstation/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">it was reported</a></span>&nbsp;that Xbox had been discussing the possibility of bringing the<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/gears-of-war-xbox-360-split-screen-local-coop-nostalgia-1850753479&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/gears-of-war-xbox-360-split-screen-local-coop-nostalgia-1850753479"> <em>Gears of War</em></a></span> franchise to PlayStation. We’ve already seen other big name Xbox franchises, like <em>Forza Horizon 5,</em> make the leap to PS5 this year. Now the question is: When does <em>Halo </em>make that jump? </p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gears of War: Reloaded announced for PS5, Xbox Series, and PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/05/gears-of-war-reloaded-announced-for-ps5-xbox-series-and-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gears-of-war-reloaded-announced-for-ps5-xbox-series-and-pc.1181307/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/05/gears-of-war-reloaded-announced-for-ps5-xbox-series-and-pc<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>Gears of War: Reloaded</em> is a celebration of one of gaming’s most iconic franchises. Featuring 4K resolution, 120 frames per second support, and the ultimate multiplayer experience with cross-progression and cross-play, across all platforms, this is the definitive way to experience the game that started it all.</p><p>As we approach the 20th anniversary of <em>Gears of War</em> in 2026, we’re reflecting on what this franchise means. It’s about the stories we’ve told, the friendships we’ve built, and the unforgettable moments we’ve shared together. With <em>Gears of War: Reloaded</em>, we’re opening that door to more players than ever.</p><p><strong>A Modern Classic Goes Multiplatform</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Originally released in 2006, <em>Gears of War: Reloaded</em> brings the full experience forward once again—enhanced for the latest hardware across multiple platforms, introducing the <em>Gears of War</em> franchise to a new generation of players.</p><p>Developed by The Coalition in partnership with Sumo Interactive and Disbelief, <em>Gears of War: Reloaded</em> launches August 26, 2025, for $39.99 SRP on <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [7,145 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series X|S</a>, Xbox PC, Xbox Cloud Gaming, PlayStation 5, and Steam, and arrives on day one with Game Pass Ultimate or PC Game Pass. Play on Xbox Series X|S and Xbox PC with Xbox Play Anywhere.</p><p><em>Gears of War: Reloaded</em> includes the full breadth of content from the <em>Gears of War: Ultimate Edition</em>, delivering the most complete version of the original game to date. Players will gain immediate access to all post-launch downloadable content at no additional cost—this includes the bonus Campaign act, all multiplayer maps and modes, and a full roster of classic characters and cosmetics unlockable through progression.</p><p><strong>Built for Brotherhood</strong></p><p><em>Gears of War: Reloaded</em> is built for shared play—whether you’re teaming up in split-screen or jumping online. The Campaign supports two-player <a title="Genres > Co-Op [259 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer/co-op">cooperative</a> play, and Versus <a title="Genres > Multiplayer [494 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer">Multiplayer</a> allows up to eight players. With cross-play across all platforms, you and your friends can squad up no matter where you play—no Microsoft account required.</p><p>However, signing in with a Microsoft account unlocks full cross-platform functionality. It enables cross-progression, so your Campaign and multiplayer progress carries across devices. It also allows you to send invites and play with friends across platforms—like Xbox to <a title="Platforms > PlayStation [47,514 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation">PlayStation</a> or Steam to Xbox.</p><p><strong>Precision Performance on Every Platform</strong></p><p>No matter where you play, <em>Gears of War: Reloaded</em> has been re-engineered to look and feel incredible. Players can expect:</p><ul><li>4K resolution</li><li>60 frames per second in Campaign</li><li>120 frames per second in Multiplayer</li><li>High Dynamic Range (HDR)</li><li>Dolby Vision and 7.1.4 Dolby Atmos</li><li>7.1.4 3D Spatial Audio</li><li>Variable Refresh Rate (VRR)</li><li>4K assets and remastered textures</li><li><a title="Companies > Enhance [31 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/enhance">Enhance</a>d post-processing visual effects</li><li>Improved shadows and reflections</li><li>Super resolution with improved anti-aliasing</li><li>Zero loading screens during Campaign</li></ul><p>From faster frame rates to deeper visual fidelity, every detail has been tuned to bring the original game into the present with clarity, smoothness, and immersion that matches the power of today’s hardware.</p><p>And wherever you play, we’re meeting you there with the best version possible. <em>Gears of War: Reloaded</em> includes platform-specific features that make the most of the hardware you already own to deliver a world-class <em>Gears of War</em> experience—faithful to the original, optimized for today, and made for everyone.</p><p><strong>For Xbox Fans, A Thank You</strong></p><p>As a token of our gratitude to longtime fans, <em>Gears of War: Reloaded</em> will be a free upgrade for players who purchased the digital version of <em>Gears of War: Ultimate Edition</em> prior to today’s announcement. (Must have purchased a digital version of <em>Gears of War: Ultimate Edition</em> prior to 16:00 UTC on May 5, 2025. A code for <em>Gears of War: Reloaded</em> will be delivered prior to launch of the game via a direct message to eligible Xbox accounts.)</p><p>And for Game Pass Ultimate and PC Game Pass members, <em>Gears of War: Reloaded</em> will be available as part of the Game Pass library at launch.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gears Of War: Reloaded Remaster Coming This August To Xbox, PlayStation, and PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gears-of-war-reloaded-remaster-coming-this-august-to-xbox-playstation-and-pc/1100-6531314/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gears-of-war-reloaded-remaster-coming-this-august-to-xbox-playstation-and-pc.1181304/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gears-of-war-reloaded-remaster-coming-this-august-to-xbox-playstation-and-pc/1100-6531314/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6531314">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>A new remaster of the original Gears is on the way, as Microsoft has announced Gears of War: Reloaded for Xbox Series X|S, PS5, and Steam. It's coming to Game Pass on day one for Ultimate subscribers. This is just the latest remaster from Microsoft, following the successful debut of Oblivion Remastered in April.</p><p>Gears of War: Reloaded arrives on August 26 for $40, and it'll also be available to stream via Xbox Cloud Gaming. The game supports cross-play and cross-progression on all platforms. Anyone who already owns the digital version of Gears of War: Ultimate Edition will get Reloaded for free.</p><p>Reloaded features 4K resolution 120fps support, and multiplayer. "This is the definitive way to experience the game that started it all," Microsoft said.</p><p>"As we approach the 20th anniversary of Gears of War in 2026, we're reflecting on what this franchise means. It's about the stories we've told, the friendships we've built, and the unforgettable moments we've shared together. With Gears of War: Reloaded, we're opening that door to more players than ever," Microsoft said.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4487802-gow_reloaded_2ndroom.png" data-ref-id="1300-4487802" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="3840" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4487802-gow_reloaded_2ndroom.png" data-ref-id="1300-4487802"></a><figcaption>Gears of War: Reloaded arrives in August.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4487802-gow_reloaded_2ndroom.png"></figure><figure data-embed-type="gallery" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4487803-gow_reloaded_4k_screenshot_01.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4487804-gow_reloaded_4k_screenshot_04.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4487805-gow_reloaded_4k_screenshot_05.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4487806-gow_reloaded_4k_screenshot_08.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4487807-gow_reloaded_4k_screenshot_10.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4487808-gow_reloaded_embry.png" data-ref-id="1300-4487803,1300-4487804,1300-4487805,1300-4487806,1300-4487807,1300-4487808" data-resize-urls="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1179/11799911/4487803-gow_reloaded_4k_screenshot_01.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1179/11799911/4487804-gow_reloaded_4k_screenshot_04.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1179/11799911/4487805-gow_reloaded_4k_screenshot_05.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1179/11799911/4487806-gow_reloaded_4k_screenshot_08.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1179/11799911/4487807-gow_reloaded_4k_screenshot_10.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1179/11799911/4487808-gow_reloaded_embry.png"><p>Gallery</p>     <img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4487803-gow_reloaded_4k_screenshot_01.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4487804-gow_reloaded_4k_screenshot_04.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4487805-gow_reloaded_4k_screenshot_05.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4487806-gow_reloaded_4k_screenshot_08.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4487807-gow_reloaded_4k_screenshot_10.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4487808-gow_reloaded_embry.png"></figure><p>The Reloaded package includes everything from Gears of War: Ultimate Edition, which launched in 2015 and was itself a remaster of the 2006 original Gears of War game. This includes the base game with all post-launch expansions, covering multiplayer maps and modes, characters, and cosmetics.</p><p>Reloaded supports local split-screen or online for, with two-player co-op for the campaign and up to eight players in multiplayer. A Microsoft account is not required to play, but <em>is</em> required to unlock "full cross-platform functionality" in terms of enabling cross-progression.</p><p>Here is a rundown of what to expect in terms of performance improvements for Gears of War: Reloaded, as written by Microsoft.</p><ul><li>4K resolution</li><li>60 FPS in Campaign</li><li>120 FPS in Multiplayer</li><li>High Dynamic Range (HDR)</li><li>Dolby Vision &amp; 7.1.4 Dolby Atmos</li><li>7.1.4 3D Spatial Audio</li><li>Variable Refresh Rate (VRR)</li><li>4K assets and remastered textures</li><li>Enhanced post-processing visual effects</li><li>Improved shadows and reflections</li><li>Super resolution with improved anti-aliasing</li><li>Zero loading screens during Campaign</li></ul><p>"From faster frame rates to deeper visual fidelity, every detail has been tuned to bring the original game into the present with clarity, smoothness, and immersion that matches the power of today's hardware," Microsoft said.</p><p>The Coalition, Sumo Interactive, and Disbelief are developing Gears of War: Reloaded.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Next Assassin's Creed Shadows Update Announced, Adds New Story Mission And Fixes A Deer Problem]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/next-assassins-creed-shadows-update-announced-adds-new-story-mission-and-fixes-a-deer-problem/1100-6531312/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/next-assassins-creed-shadows-update-announced-adds-new-story-mission-and-fixes-a-deer-problem.1181298/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/next-assassins-creed-shadows-update-announced-adds-new-story-mission-and-fixes-a-deer-problem/1100-6531312/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6531312">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Ubisoft has announced the next major update for Assassin's Creed Shadows, and it's coming soon. Title update 1.0.4 arrives on Tuesday, May 6, and it adds a new free quest and numerous bug fixes.</p><p>The update adds a story pack called "The Works of Luis Frois." Players can visit Azuchi to find Luis, a Jesuit priest, who has a mission for you. Players must complete the "Path he Walks" mission to start the new story chapter.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="894320102" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6465770,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Assassin%27s%20Creed%20Shadows%20-%20Official%20Cinematic%20Launch%20Trailer&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:69,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/assassins-creed-shadows-official-cinematic-launch-trailer\/2300-6465770\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465770\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465770\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465770\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6465770&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6465770,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6531312&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;assassins-creed-shadows&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;action,adventure&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;pc,xbox-series-x,playstation-5,macintosh&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;ubisoft&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;franchise&quot;:&quot;assassins-creed&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;franchiseRoot&quot;:&quot;assassins-creed&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6465770},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6465770\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;Publisher Asset&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4458854-11.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/LiqOnt8M.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1741871400,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="LiqOnt8M" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> Assassin's Creed Shadows - Official Cinematic Launch Trailer</p>
      </div>
<p>The patch also reduces an issue that could cause too many deer to spawn near roads, which in turn led them to run into harm's way. "Oh dear, watch out!" Ubisoft said in the <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/assassinscreed/comments/1kfcep2/ac_shadows_title_update_104_release_notes/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">patch notes</a>.</p><p>Players can also expect improvements for animation and visual issues, along with multiple fixes for the game's Photo Mode. What's more, the new update addresses crashing and stability issues.</p><p>Also notable in this update is the introduction of character bios in the Codex database. Ubisoft said this should help players "<span>keep track of the many allies and foes you will meet throughout your journey in Japan."</span></p><p>The 1.0.4. update for Assassin's Creed Shadows varies in size by platform. On PS5, it's 4.67 GB, but on Xbox Series X|S it's a whopping 20 GB. On Steam, the update is 8.5 GB. The patch officially arrives on May 6 at 7 AM PT / 10 AM ET.</p><h2><strong>Patch Sizes</strong></h2><ul><li>PS5: 4.67 GB</li><li>XBS: 20 GB</li><li>MAC: ~9 GB</li><li>PC: 17 GB</li><li>Steam: 8.5 GB</li></ul><h2>Patch Highlights</h2><p><em>As written by Ubisoft</em></p><h3>New Free Story Pack: The Works of Luis Frois</h3><p>An encounter with Luis Frois at a Jesuit Mission turns into an opportunity to help an old friend. Retrieve lost notes, protect Lady Satoko and learn more about the Jesuits in this new Free Story Pack playable with both Naoe or Yasuke.</p><p>To meet with Luis Frois and start the quest arc, head to Azuchi. Luis will be located south of the Merchants’ Quarters. The quest will be available upon completing "The Path he Walks," in Yasuke's Board.</p><h3>Codex Update: Character Entries</h3><p>As requested by many, we have added character bios in the Codex database to help you keep track of the many allies and foes you will meet throughout your journey in Japan.</p><h3>LIST OF BUG FIXES</h3><h4>General</h4><ul><li>Fixed an issue when pressing "Go to board" for "Complete Yasuke's personal journey" does not redirect the player to Yasuke's quest board.</li><li>Fixed an issue where some trinkets could not be accessed in the Forge.</li><li>Fixed some issues where visual customization could not be applied to certain weapons.</li><li>Fixed a visual issue with the Red Bull trinket swapping between Yasuke and Naoe.</li><li>Addressed several AI issues.</li><li>Addressed several audio issues.</li></ul><h4>World</h4><ul><li>All props near an altar or a religion building will now be static, preventing any destruction.</li><li>Fixed an issue where too many deer spawning and running on main roads. Oh dear, watch out!</li><li>Merchants will no longer offer multiple instances of the same item in shops.</li><li>Fixed an issue where buying and equipping head gear would kick you from the merchant menu.</li></ul><h4>Quests</h4><ul><li>Fixed an issue where in the quest “Astray”, players could not talk To Nakamura Tadashige.</li><li>NOTE: Players will need to step away from Nakamura Tadashige (+500 meters) and then come back to speak with them.</li><li>Fixed an issue where Nagato would sometimes not follow the correct path in the prologue during the "Fight of the Kakushiba Ikki" quest.</li><li>Fixed an issue where Momochi Sandayu does not attack during the objective "Kill the Soldier" in the "Fight of the Kakushiba Ikki" quest.</li><li>Fixed an issue where Nagato would despawn after a save/load during the quest "The Onryo Samurai".</li><li>A prompt will now properly appear to Observe during the objective "Reach a high place to observe the Onryo Samurai" in the quest "The Onryo Samurai".</li><li>Addressed an issue with enemy NPCs fighting each other after talking to Shotei during "Against the Koga-ryu".</li><li>Fixed an issue where Tokubei would start attacking anyone that enters conflict with the player during the "Confront Tokubei" objective of "Losing Hand" quest.</li><li>Fixed an issue where quest directions do not match the quest location during the "Meet Katsuhime" objective of "Against the Koga-ryu" quest.</li><li>Addressed an issue where Yasuke would recover all of his health upon receiving a killing blow from Marume Nagayoshi during the duel from "Nobutsaha's Students".</li></ul><h4>Stealth</h4><ul><li>Fixed an issue where Improved Ground Assassination (Assassin passive skill) would not work properly.</li><li>Fixed an issue where Assassinations would not remove any health from knocked-out enemies.</li><li>Fixed an issue where, after performing a Double Assassination, Naoe could not swap weapons if she was using the Katana as primary weapon.</li><li>Fixed an issue with Yasuke’s Brutal Assassination not triggering at a certain distance with NPCs.</li><li>Fixed Guaranteed Assassination not working with the kunai.</li><li>Fixed an issue where Naoe could use smoke bombs to trigger Guaranteed Assassination opportunities on bosses.</li><li>Fixed an issue where crouching during a Sprint Dodge would increase the speed of the crouch state.</li><li>Fixed an issue where Naoe had a delay when crouching after moving while aiming a tool.</li><li>Fixed an issue where corner cover camera would not always trigger.</li><li>Fixed an issue with alarm bells respawning after cutscenes. Please don't ring. Please don't ring. Please don't ring.</li></ul><h4>Combat</h4><ul><li>Adjusted the Igan Sunset Tanto perk (i.e. slow down time on Escape Strike) to prevent endless slow-down when using Escape Strike repeatedly.</li><li>The perk now works as follows: “Slow down time after Escape Strike interrupts enemies”</li><li>Fixed an issue with the Snake Bite ability (Kusarigama) costing more than one chunk of adrenaline. Two fangs. But one bite.</li><li>Fixed an issue where the "Crescent Strike” ability (Naginata) did not deal any damage on its first hit.</li><li>Fixed various issues with perks not functioning correctly.</li><li>Fixed an issue where letters displayed on screen would not automatically close when the player would enter conflict. Listen I’m just trying to read here.</li><li>Fixed an issue where Naoe cannot dodge if she first attacks the Ashigaru Swordsman with a posture attack during "Fight of the Kakushiba Ikki" quest.</li><li>Fixed an issue where the ability wheel would still display the abilities from the previously equipped weapon when being unarmed.</li></ul><h3>Visuals &amp; Graphics</h3><ul><li>Fixed several animation, visual or misplacement issues.</li><li>Fixed various rendering issues.</li></ul><h3>UI &amp; HUD</h3><ul><li>Addressed various UI/HUD issues.</li><li>Addressed localization issues.</li><li>Fixed an issue with the tutorial explaining how to use boats. How do you row this thing?</li><li>Fixed an issue where the four targets of the Pirate Alliance were not aligned on the Objective Board.</li><li>Fixed an issue where the drop-down list is missing for "Text Color" and "Background Color" options in the Captions menu.</li></ul><h3>Photo Mode</h3><ul><li>Fixed various visual issues with Photo Mode.</li><li>Fixed an issue where the last known position visual effect remained visible in Photo Mode.</li><li>Fixed an issue where the Codex Orbs remained present in Photo Mode.</li><li>Fixed an issue where the vignette effect size increases when decreasing the value in Photo Mode.</li></ul><h3>Hideout</h3><ul><li>Fixed an issue where the blacksmith was missing from the hideout. I must upgrade my weapons!</li><li>Fixed an issue where some trinkets could not be accessed in the Forge.</li></ul><h3>Stability &amp; Performances</h3><ul><li>Addressed various crashing and stability issues.</li></ul><h3>Platform-Specific issues</h3><h4>Xbox</h4><ul><li>Fixed an issue where the "Balanced" mode was missing in the Performance options.</li></ul><h4>PC</h4><ul><li>VRAM usage is now added to the performance overlay when using the benchmark tool.</li><li>Improved description in the Scalability options to better reflect the impact on CPU and GPU.</li><li>Addressed an issue with conflicting bindings for mouse &amp; keyboard on PC.</li><li>Fixed an issue where the VRAM meter doesn't accurately update the VRAM usage when settings are individually changed.</li><li>Addressed an issue with PC using Photo Mode with the Ultra-wide screen settings.</li></ul><h3>STEAMDECK</h3><ul><li>Addressed an issue where there was a heavy loss of FPS in the opening animation before arriving at the Animus HUB (memories).</li></ul><h3>MacOS</h3><ul><li>Fixed an issue where the resolution options are all "Custom" when the game is in windowed mode on macOS.</li><li>VRAM usage added to the performance overlay.</li><li>Addressed an issue with the PS5® DUALSENSE® controller lightbar not emitting the correct light on macOS.</li></ul>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bugnie’s Attempt At Dismissing Copyright Lawsuit Denied By Court Due To Bungie’s Inability To Provide Vaulted Destiny 2 Content As Evidence]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/bugnie-attempt-at-dismissing-copyright-lawsuit-denied-by-court-due-bungies-inability-to-provide-vaulted-destiny-2-content-as-evidence/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/bugnie%E2%80%99s-attempt-at-dismissing-copyright-lawsuit-denied-by-court-due-to-bungie%E2%80%99s-inability-to-provide-vaulted-destiny-2-content-as-evidence.1181268/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/bugnie-attempt-at-dismissing-copyright-lawsuit-denied-by-court-due-bungies-inability-to-provide-vaulted-destiny-2-content-as-evidence/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p><a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/author-sues-bungie-for-copyright-infringement-over-destiny-2s-story">Last year</a>, writer Matthew Kelsey Martineau filed a copyright infringement lawsuit against Bungie, claiming that the studio had stolen his work to create the story for Destiny 2.</p>
<p>Martineau claimed that Destiny 2's Red Legion was pulled straight from his work, which was published on WordPress in 2013 and 2014. Bungie responded with a motion to dismiss the case, saying (per <a href="https://thegamepost.com/bungie-pushes-back-destiny-2-red-war-lawsuit/">TheGamePost</a>) that Martineau's claim "<em>failed to plausibly allege that Bungie copied constituent elements of Plaintiff's work that are original, and, specifically, that the Complaint fails to plausibly allege factual copying by Bungie and that the works incorporated by reference into the Complaint are not substantially similar as a matter of law</em>."</p>
<p>Demonstrating that has become an issue, however, as <a href="https://thegamepost.com/court-denies-bungie-dismiss-destiny-2-red-war-lawsuit-youtube-wiki/">TheGamePost</a> reports that the court denied Bungie's dismissal claim because Bungie cannot provide the court with the original content from Destiny 2 to demonstrate the differences between Bungie and Martineau's work. Bungie can't provide the court with Destiny 2's original content because it was <a href="https://wccftech.com/destiny-2-content-removed-vault-beyond-light-november/">vaulted</a>, and it's now incompatible with the modern-day version of Destiny 2.</p>
<p>Bungie game director Tyson Green described why Bungie can't provide the game's original content, clarifying that "<em>the 'Red War' and 'Curse of Osiris' legacy builds can no longer run because their outdated code is incompatible with Destiny 2's underlying operational framework, which has evolved considerably since the 'Red War' and 'Curse of Osiris' campaigns were retired</em>."</p>
<p>Unfortunately for Bungie, Green's statement wasn't enough for Judge Susie Morgan, who won't accept YouTube videos of the game's original content or wikis as admissible evidence.</p>
<p>"<em>While Plaintiff does reference Destiny 2 in his complaint</em>," Judge Morgan's dismissal decision reads, "<em>he does not reference the YouTube videos containing Destiny 2 game footage, the Destinypedia pages, or the Tyson declaration.</em>"</p>
<p>Judge Morgan acknowledged that this is an extremely complicated copyright case and not typical compared to previous examples of copyright infringement, which also seems to be part of why the case is moving forward at all.</p>
<p>Vaulting content has never been popular with Destiny players, and while Bungie certainly has its reasons for doing so, those decisions are seemingly coming back to bite them in more ways than just facing the ire of players.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Modded Grand Theft Auto V Enhanced Edition Makes the Wait for GTA VI a Little Easier With Its Stunning Visuals]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/modded-grand-theft-auto-v-enhanced-edition-stunning-gta-vi/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/modded-grand-theft-auto-v-enhanced-edition-makes-the-wait-for-gta-vi-a-little-easier-with-its-stunning-visuals.1181265/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/modded-grand-theft-auto-v-enhanced-edition-stunning-gta-vi/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Grand Theft Auto V Enhanced Edition is undoubtedly the best-looking version of the open-world game developed by Rockstar Games, but this doesn't stop modders from taking the game's visuals to the next level.</p>
<p>A new 4K resolution video shared by Digital Dreams shows the latest version of the fifth entry in the series by Rockstar Games running with mods such as <a href="https://www.patreon.com/crxhvrd/home" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CoreFx</a> and <a href="https://www.patreon.com/posts/lively-world-for-124497674">Lively World</a>, two known graphics and immersion improvement mods released for the original version of the game that were later ported to the Enhanced Edition. Needless to say, the two mods introduce noticeable enhancements that can make players forget the game initially released over a decade ago and possibly make the wait for the next entry in the series more bearable.</p>
<p><iframe title="[4K100] GTA 5 Enhanced: modded CoreFX - Lively World BeyondallLimits RTX5090 RAYTRACING Graphics" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/juHYo9QMU54?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Fans of the Rockstar Games series will have to make do with Grand Theft Auto V Enhanced Edition for a while longer to experience the best the series has to offer, as Grand Theft Auto VI will not release as initially scheduled. <a href="https://wccftech.com/grand-theft-auto-vi-launches-may-26/">Last week</a>, Rockstar confirmed the game will now release on May 26th, 2026, on PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X|S, as the studio requires additional development time to deliver the level of quality fans expect. While the public was only informed of the delay last week, the fact that the game would slip to 2026 was known for a while at Rockstar Games, due in part to <a href="https://wccftech.com/grand-theft-auto-vi-reportedly-had-no-chance-of-releasing-in-2025-for-months-due-in-part-to-a-real-desire-to-avoid-crunch/">a real desire to avoid crunch</a>, which is commendable.</p>
<p>Grand Theft Auto V Enhanced Edition is now available on PC. You can learn more about how this new version of the game breathes new life into the popular open-world game by checking out Alessio's analysis.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Sues Accessory Maker Who Flaunted Console Mockup At The Height Of Switch Leaks]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/switch-2-accessory-genki-nintendo-lawsuit-leak-ces-2025-1851779140</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-sues-accessory-maker-who-flaunted-console-mockup-at-the-height-of-switch-leaks.1181262/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/switch-2-accessory-genki-nintendo-lawsuit-leak-ces-2025-1851779140<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>A very strange thing happened earlier this year, prior to Nintendo officially revealing the Switch 2: A small accessory maker, Genki, brought a mockup of the mysterious <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/nintendo-switch-2-rumors-genki-ces-2025-official-1851736830&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/nintendo-switch-2-rumors-genki-ces-2025-official-1851736830">new console to CES 2025 and flaunted it</a></span> on the show floor, suggesting to press that the 3D printed replica was accurate and based on early access to an actual Switch 2. The stunt happened just as Switch 2 leaks were hitting a fever pitch and Nintendo is now suing Genki over it. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="194644" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="The Week In Games: Return To Hyrule" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="165" data-playlist="194644,196181,196230" data-current="194644"><div><p>The Week In Games: Return To Hyrule</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/194644/194644_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/194644/194644_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/194644/194644_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/194644/194644_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/20101.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>A <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.scribd.com/document/856896674/NinteNintendo-Files-Lawsuit-Against-Genki-Over-Unauthorized-Switch-2-Mockups-and-Trademark-Use-at-CES-2025ndo-Lawsuit-Against-Genki-Switch-2-Mockups-C#from_embed&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.scribd.com/document/856896674/NinteNintendo-Files-Lawsuit-Against-Genki-Over-Unauthorized-Switch-2-Mockups-and-Trademark-Use-at-CES-2025ndo-Lawsuit-Against-Genki-Switch-2-Mockups-C#from_embed" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">lawsuit filed on May 2</a></span> in the U.S. District Court for the Central District of California accuses Genki of trademark infringement, unfair competition, and false advertising,<em> </em><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://thegamepost.com/nintendo-lawsuit-against-genki-switch-2-mockups-ces-2025/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://thegamepost.com/nintendo-lawsuit-against-genki-switch-2-mockups-ces-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>The Game Post</em> reported</a></span> over the weekend. Nintendo specifically targets video ads for Switch 2 accessories that Genki released in April claiming day-one compatibility with the un-released hardware. </p><p>“Either Defendant is not in possession of a genuine console and thus cannot claim compatibility with enough certainty to make its advertising claims in good faith, or Defendant unlawfully or illicitly obtained an authentic Nintendo Switch 2, or proprietary technical information about the Nintendo Switch 2, prior to the console’s release to the public,” the complaint alleges.</p><p>Genki has remained undeterred in the face of the lawsuit, and plans to continue showing off its Switch 2 merchandize at upcoming events, like this week’s PAX East convention in Boston. “You may have seen that Nintendo recently filed a lawsuit against us,” it wrote in a statement <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/GenkiThings/status/1918852177046737231&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/GenkiThings/status/1918852177046737231" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">on May 3</a></span>. “We’re taking it seriously and working with legal counsel to respond thoughtfully.”<br></p><p>It continued:</p><blockquote data-type="BlockQuote"><p>What we can say is this: Genki has always been an independent company focused on building innovative gaming accessories for the community we love. We’re proud of the work we’ve done, and we stand by the quality and originality of our products.  While we can’t comment in detail, we’re continuing preparations to fulfill orders and showcase our newest products at PAX East this week.  We’re grateful for the overwhelming support we’ve received so far. We’ll share more when we can, but for now, we’re staying focused on doing what we do best: building gear for gamers.</p></blockquote><p>It’s unclear if Nintendo still would have targeted Genki for its subsequent Switch 2 marketing campaign if it hadn’t pulled the CES stunt accompanied by a detailed render of the Switch 2 <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/GamingLeaksAndRumours/comments/1hwa2qa/genki_releases_video_showing_full_unit_switch_2/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GamingLeaksAndRumours/comments/1hwa2qa/genki_releases_video_showing_full_unit_switch_2/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">posted in a video on its website</a></span>. While the accessory maker was at first happy to talk about its Switch 2 mockup to <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/8/24339396/nintendo-switch-2-genki-ces-2025&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/8/24339396/nintendo-switch-2-genki-ces-2025" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>The Verge</em></a></span>, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.ign.com/articles/i-didnt-expect-this-much-media-attention-we-saw-genkis-ces-nintendo-switch-2-mockup-heres-what-they-had-to-say&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/i-didnt-expect-this-much-media-attention-we-saw-genkis-ces-nintendo-switch-2-mockup-heres-what-they-had-to-say" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>IGN</em></a></span>, and others, allowing footage of it to go viral on social media, Genki later changed its tune after Nintendo’s lawyers reportedly made their displeasure known. </p><p>A <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://thegamepost.com/nintendo-lawyers-genki-switch-2-mockup-ces-2025/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://thegamepost.com/nintendo-lawyers-genki-switch-2-mockup-ces-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">French journalist reported</a></span> being told that Genki’s CES booth had been visited by the Nintendo reps after the Switch 2 replica blew up online. Genki later told <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.sankei.com/article/20250110-XHI3U6QWZ5CZ7IFGTGUGJUVH4A/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.sankei.com/article/20250110-XHI3U6QWZ5CZ7IFGTGUGJUVH4A/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">a Japanese publication</a></span> that the 3D printed mockup was based on internet leaks and not access to an actual Switch 2. “The gaming hardware that Genki is claiming to be Nintendo hardware at CES is unofficial and was not provided to the company by Nintendo,” the company said at the time, but Genki continued to try and draft off the attention. “Genki ninjas infiltrate Nintendo Kyoto HQ, the company <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/GenkiThings/status/1881325842187637044&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/GenkiThings/status/1881325842187637044" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">posted on January 20</a></span>. </p><p>It was a whole mess, but a funny one when it turned out that the Genki replica was basically accurate to the finished model Nintendo <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/switch-2-reveal-trailer-date-nintendo-mario-kart-9-1851739487&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/switch-2-reveal-trailer-date-nintendo-mario-kart-9-1851739487">revealed just weeks later</a></span>. Of course, whether that was because it actually did have an early Switch 2, or because of the widespread leaks from <em>others</em> who had access, remains unclear. Either way, Nintendo is clearly not laughing. The company is demanding Genki “destroy” any products or ads that used its trademark, turn over any profits from related sales, and cease this kind of behavior in the future. </p><p><em>Update 5/5/2025 12:21 p.m. ET: Added more information about Genki’s pre-announcement Switch 2 marketing. </em></p><p><em>.</em></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Get A Massive Discount On Apple's Newest Mac Mini At Amazon]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/get-a-massive-discount-on-apples-newest-mac-mini-at-amazon/1100-6531310/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/get-a-massive-discount-on-apples-newest-mac-mini-at-amazon.1181259/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/get-a-massive-discount-on-apples-newest-mac-mini-at-amazon/1100-6531310/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-main">

      
                    
  
              <header id="masthead"><nav></nav></header>      
                            <div id="site-wrapper" role="main">
          <div id="default-content">
        
          <p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p>
  
    <article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6531310">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>The <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DLBTPDCS?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">2024 Mac Mini</a> just hit its <strong>lowest price ever at $490.84 (was $599)</strong>. This is the latest model of Apple’s popular computer, though a newer edition is expected to be announced later this year. Amazon’s massive price cut is worth checking out, however, as the 2024 Mac Mini is a premium computer packed with excellent hardware--making it a wonderful companion for young professionals and students. It'll even suffice for a bit of light gaming. Amazon is not listing an end date for the discount--head over to the retailer soon if you're interested.</p><div title="6531310 - Mac Mini Lowest Price Ever" data-embed-type="buylink" data-ref-id="3469" data-template="4" data-size="buylink__listicle" data-title="6531310 - Mac Mini Lowest Price Ever" data-collection="">             <h2>                    <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DLBTPDCS?tag=gamespot-promos-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/dp\/B0DLBTPDCS?tag=gamespot-promos-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DLBTPDCS?tag=gamespot-promos-20">Apple 2024 Mac Mini</a>       </h2>                                   <h3>                      <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DLBTPDCS?tag=gamespot-promos-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/dp\/B0DLBTPDCS?tag=gamespot-promos-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DLBTPDCS?tag=gamespot-promos-20">$490.84 (was $599)</a>         </h3>                                                                                                                      <div><p><span>Don’t let its small size fool you--this is a powerful little device. Clocking in at just 5 inches by 5 inches, it packs an M4 chip with a 10-core CPU and a 10-core GPU (more than enough for all sorts of daily computing tasks). It also includes 16GB Unified Memory and 256GB SSD. You’ll have plenty of options when it comes to connectivity, thanks to ports for Thunderbolt, HDMI, Ethernet, and USB-C. There’s also a 3.5mm input for headphones.</span></p></div>                      </div><p>Along with impressive hardware, the Mac Mini is designed to work with all your favorite programs. Microsoft Word, Excel, and other Microsoft 365 apps work flawlessly on Mac Mini, and if you’re using an iPhone, you’ll find added functionality between the two devices. It’s an impressive little device, and it’s only become more enticing at this new price point.</p><p>Not sold on this exact model? A few other Mac Minis are discounted right now:</p><h2>More Mac Mini Deals</h2><ul><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DLBX4B1K?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Mac Mini (M4, 16GB Memory, 512GB SSD)</a> -- $743 (<del>$799</del>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DLBV145M?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Mac Mini (M4, 24GB Memory, 512GB SSD)</a> -- $929 (<del>$999</del>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DLBVHSLD?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Mac Mini (M4 Pro, 24GB Memory, 512GB SSD)</a> -- $1,230.54 (<del>$1,399</del>)</li></ul><p>The Mac Mini is a perennial favorite with shoppers, thanks to its tiny footprint and oversized power. And because it comes from Apple, it’s all but guaranteed to be reliable, ensuring you have a computing companion for years to come.</p><p>The <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-2025-MacBook-13-inch-Laptop/dp/B0DZD9S5GC?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Apple 2025 MacBook Air (13-Inch)</a> is on sale alongside the Mac Mini. Featuring a Liquid Retina Display for vibrant images, 16GB Memory, 256GB SSD, and the M4 chip, it’s a solid choice now that it’s on sale for $849 (was $999). This deal is just a bit shy of its lowest ever price of $836.71.</p><div data-embed-type="pinbox" data-ref-id="4304">  <ul>                              <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/lego-store-star-wars-day-sale-2025-jango-fett-ucs-starship-free-lego-sets/1100-6530872/">Lego Star Wars Day Sale Is Live - Get Two Free Sets With Jango Fett's UCS Starship</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-preorder-all-launch-games-buy-amazon-walmart-best-buy-target/1100-6531115/">All The Nintendo Switch 2 Games You Can Preorder Now</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/studio-ghibli-movies-limited-edition-steelbook-blu-ray-best-deals-amazon-walmart/1100-6530746/">Studio Ghibli Movies With Collectible Steelbooks Are Available For Cheap</a></li>                          <li>         <span>+ Show More More Gaming, Tech, and Entertainment Deals &amp; Preorders Links (5)</span>       </li>          <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/8bitdo-best-controllers-amazon-restocks-tariffs/2900-6514/">8BitDo Halts US Shipments Due To Tariffs, But You Can Get Great Controller Deals (For Now)</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/you-wont-find-switch-2-consoles-on-amazon-but-you-can-get-games-gear/1100-6531143/">You Won't Find Switch 2 Consoles On Amazon, But You Can Get Games &amp; Gear</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-preorder-guide-mario-kart-world-bundle/1100-6530531/">Nintendo Switch 2 Preorders Sold Out - Games &amp; Accessories Available</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-pro-controller-preorders-are-available-now/1100-6530558/">Nintendo Switch 2 Pro Controller Preorders Are Available Now</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/final-fantasy-x-magic-the-gathering-card-preorders-restocked-at-walmart/2900-6271/">Final Fantasy X Magic: The Gathering Card Preorders Restocked At Walmart</a></li>   </ul> </div>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/105566936584242225941?rel=author">Jon Bitner</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article>

    
  

</div>
                      <meta itemprop="seamless-content-list-items" data-list-items="[{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529223&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/batman-beyond-complete-series-blu-ray-amazon-deal\/1100-6529223\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6521901&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/legos-3d-recreation-of-the-starry-night-is-on-sale-for-a-great-price-at-amazon\/1100-6521901\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6531308&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/x-men-the-manga-remastered-get-both-512-page-books-for-cheap-at-amazon\/1100-6531308\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526375&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/apple-airpods-best-deals-available-now\/1100-6526375\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6531234&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/dragons-dogma-2-dead-rising-deluxe-remake-and-more-capcom-games-on-sale-at-amazon\/1100-6531234\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6531170&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/legos-new-sunny-bouquet-is-a-perfect-mothers-day-gift-idea\/1100-6531170\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6527851&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/get-18-batman-animated-movies-on-blu-ray-for-only-45-for-a-limited-time\/1100-6527851\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6527044&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/nex-playground-an-xbox-kinect-style-console-is-on-sale-for-amazon-gaming-week\/1100-6527044\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6531228&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/teenage-mutant-ninja-turtles-splintered-fate-collectors-deluxe-edition-amazon-preorder\/1100-6531228\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6531189&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/elder-scrolls-6-should-probably-focus-on-choices-over-stats-original-oblivion-dev-says\/1100-6531189\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6531184&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/gamestop-actively-investigating-switch-2-forced-bundling-reports\/1100-6531184\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6531185&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/nier-director-yoko-taro-says-ai-will-make-all-game-creators-unemployed\/1100-6531185\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6531190&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/the-last-of-us-gets-a-heartbreaking-update-to-its-intro-sequence\/1100-6531190\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6531114&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/genshin-impacts-charlotte-tilbury-collab-is-as-gorgeous-as-the-character-it-celebrates\/1100-6531114\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6531180&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/a-minecraft-movie-getting-a-theatrical-block-party-edition-inviting-viewers-to-basically-go-wild\/1100-6531180\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6531191&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/youll-never-guess-who-the-next-cod-operator-might-be\/1100-6531191\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6531204&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/cyberpunk-2077-on-switch-2-is-best-way-to-experience-the-game-on-the-go-says-dev\/1100-6531204\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6531203&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/vera-bradleys-star-wars-day-collection-includes-stylish-backpacks-handbags\/1100-6531203\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6531200&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/apex-legends-studio-cancels-two-incubation-projects-lays-off-staff-amid-big-ea-shakeup\/1100-6531200\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6531216&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/nintendo-switch-system-update-now-live-adds-virtual-game-cards-switch-2-compatibility-and-more\/1100-6531216\/&quot;}]">
            </div>
              
    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 New Mod Allows Easy Configuration of Additional Graphics Settings for Better Visuals and Performance]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/clair-obscur-expedition-33-mod-additional-graphics-settings/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/clair-obscur-expedition-33-new-mod-allows-easy-configuration-of-additional-graphics-settings-for-better-visuals-and-performance.1181244/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/clair-obscur-expedition-33-mod-additional-graphics-settings/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>A new Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 mod now available for download allows users to easily tweak additional graphics settings not available in-game without modifying engine configuration files directly.</p>
<p>The Expedition 33 - Unreal Config tool, created by Bighead and now available on <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/clairobscurexpedition33/mods/119?tab=description" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nexus Mods</a>, is a very handy tool that creates and configures engine configuration files for the game, allowing users to tweak additional graphics settings not available in-game to achieve better visuals, performance, or both. The tool, which is compatible with both the Steam and the Xbox Game Pass versions of the game, also comes with some built-in presets that can be selected as a base configuration to help users tweak these settings.</p>
<p>Though plenty of mods have been developed for the game, Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 is absolutely enjoyable in its vanilla form, as it is one of the best role-playing games released in the past few years. With an incredibly compelling story, a charming cast of endearing characters, and excellent gameplay, the debut game from Sandfall Interactive is well worth experiencing, as I highlighted in my <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/clair-obscur-expedition-33-dont-fear-the-paintress/">review.</a></p>
<p><em>Before launch, Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 looked like a solid yet safe role-playing game, but Sandfall Interactive’s debut shattered expectations in the best possible way. With a gripping story, a beautifully written cast of characters, and engaging gameplay that breathes new life into familiar mechanics, the game is a journey that leaves a lasting mark on both the mind and the heart.</em></p>
<p>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 is now available on PC, PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X, and Xbox Series S worldwide.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Call Of Duty 2025 Could Lock Limited-Time Modes Behind Battle Pass - Report]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-2025-could-lock-limited-time-modes-behind-battle-pass-report/1100-6531311/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/call-of-duty-2025-could-lock-limited-time-modes-behind-battle-pass-report.1181238/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-2025-could-lock-limited-time-modes-behind-battle-pass-report/1100-6531311/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6531311">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">There might be a major shakeup to how limited-time modes work with <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-2025-everything-we-know-about-rumored-black-ops-2-sequel/1100-6529073/">Call of Duty 2025</a> (which is still unannounced). A new report states that only players who have purchased a battle pass for the FPS will have access to modes tied <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/cod-black-ops-6-squid-game-event-includes-red-light-green-light-operator-bundles-and-rewards/2900-6100/#1">to special events, like the Squid Game collaboration</a> earlier this year.</p><p dir="ltr"><a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1KC9Qz9edHJyjR5XCMy5slTzprus4SFSrq3CtSqnkEYc/edit?tab=t.0" rel="nofollow ">Call of Duty insider "The Ghost of Hope"</a> wrote <a href="https://x.com/TheGhostOfHope/status/1919060883696722210" rel="nofollow ">on X</a> that Activision is looking to "have more seasonal LTMs," but they will be locked behind the battle pass. Currently, all Call of Duty players have access to these events and modes, though people can buy a premium track pass to earn items and skins if they want. Apparently, this report states those premium tracks wouldn't exist starting with Call of Duty 2025. Instead, those rewards would be mixed into the battle pass.</p><div data-embed-type="tweet" data-src="https://x.com/TheGhostOfHope/status/1919060883696722210" data-has-image="true"><blockquote data-conversation="none" data-mce-disable-toolbar="true"><div dir="ltr"><p>EXCLUSIVE: Activision/Treyarch are currently planning to make changes to the Battle Pass with the release of Black Ops 7 (2025). </p><p>Black Ops 7 will reportedly have more seasonal LTM’s and some of them would be considered “higher value” with unique rewards and different game… <a href="https://t.co/Kw61ia4XMu" rel="nofollow ">pic.twitter.com/Kw61ia4XMu</a></p></div>  — Hope (@TheGhostOfHope) <a href="https://twitter.com/TheGhostOfHope/status/1919060883696722210?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">May 4, 2025</a></blockquote>              </div><p dir="ltr">That would mean the supposed value of a battle pass would increase, but for people who don't pay, their experience would seemingly decrease since they can't play special events. For instance, if this change was implemented, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/cod-black-ops-6-and-warzone-season-3-reloaded-adds-4-20-events-and-major-updates-to-verdansk/2900-6513/#2">the current High Art event featuring Seth Rogen</a> would be locked behind the battle pass paywall. Right now it's accessible to everyone.</p><p dir="ltr">Last month, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-2025-leak-suggests-a-black-ops-2-sequel-and-tranzit-return/1100-6530848/">a leak suggested Call of Duty 2025 will be Black Ops 7</a>, featuring a story that follows up Black Ops 2 and brings back Woods and Mason. This campaign is rumored to have four-player co-op and an open-world map. In addition, the leak noted Treyarch is behind the next installment of the blockbuster FPS franchise. <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-2025-will-be-black-ops-2-sequel-report/1100-6520054/">Reports of a Black Ops 2 sequel first surfaced</a> back in late 2023.</p><p dir="ltr">Recently, Warzone saw <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-just-hit-a-2025-record-on-steam-following-verdansks-return-to-warzone/1100-6530610/">the return of Verdansk, propelling Call of Duty to see a record of concurrent players on Steam</a> for this year so far. <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cod-black-ops-6-and-warzone-season-3-reloaded-start-date-and-details/1100-6531027/">Black Ops 6 and Warzone Season 3 Reloaded</a> just started to kick off May. The update introduced three new multiplayer maps: Haven, Signal, and Blazetown. For more, check out GameSpot's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-multiplayer-review/1900-6418309/">Black Ops 6 multiplayer review</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trump Launches A Surprise Attack On Anime]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/trump-hollywood-movie-tariff-anime-studio-ghibli-1851779131</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/trump-launches-a-surprise-attack-on-anime.1181223/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/trump-hollywood-movie-tariff-anime-studio-ghibli-1851779131<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>President Trump is telling people to buy <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://nypost.com/2025/05/04/us-news/trump-doubles-down-on-attacking-cheap-chinese-imports/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://nypost.com/2025/05/04/us-news/trump-doubles-down-on-attacking-cheap-chinese-imports/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">fewer Barbie dolls</a></span>. The Xbox Series X <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/microsoft-xbox-series-x-s-price-increase-may-2025-1851778615&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/microsoft-xbox-series-x-s-price-increase-may-2025-1851778615">is now $100 more expensive</a></span> than it was a month ago. And now even anime is threatened by the administration’s ongoing trade war. Trump recently threatened 100 percent tariffs on all foreign-made movies like <em>Avengers: Doomsday</em> and <em>Chainsaw Man</em>, resulting in two familiar reactions: “What the heck?!” and “Oh no.”</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="194664" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Disney's New Post-Apocalyptic Anime Proves The Mouse Has Good Taste" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="162" data-playlist="194664,194741,197551" data-current="194664"><div><p>Disney's New Post-Apocalyptic Anime Proves The Mouse Has Good Taste</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/194664/194664_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/194664/194664_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/194664/194664_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/194664/194664_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/20130.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>“The Movie Industry in America is DYING a very fast death,” Trump <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/114452117143235155&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/114452117143235155" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">posted on social media on Sunday</a></span>. He blamed other countries for offering financial incentives encouraging productions to film overseas and called it a national security threat.</p><p>“Therefore, I am authorizing the Department of Commerce, and the United States Trade Representative, to immediately begin the process of instituting a 100% Tariff on any and all Movies coming into our Country that are produced in Foreign Lands,” he wrote. “WE WANT MOVIES MADE IN AMERICA, AGAIN!”</p><p>Uh, how would that work? Imports are normally taxed at ports of entry based on the prices of the goods. How would that apply to movies distributed at the box office and over streaming platforms? Nobody seems quite sure, and like lots of half-cocked plans fired off on social media, this could be another Trump nothing burger. Actual businesses don’t have the luxury of gambling like that, however.</p><p><em>Reuters</em> <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.reuters.com/business/media-telecom/trump-announces-100-tariff-movies-produced-outside-us-2025-05-04/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.reuters.com/business/media-telecom/trump-announces-100-tariff-movies-produced-outside-us-2025-05-04/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">reported</a></span> that Hollywood execs were scrambling last night to figure out what the hell was going on. Disney, Warner Bros. Discovery, Paramount, and other entertainment companies saw their stock prices go down on Monday. The policy as outlined would also hit anime. This year alone sees the releases of <em>Mobile Suit Gundam GQuuuuuuX: Beginning</em>, <em>Demon Slayer: Kimetsu no Yaiba Infinity Castle</em>, and <em>Chainsaw Man – The Movie: Reze Arc</em> in theaters, as well as re-releases of several older movies like <em>Spirited Away</em>. </p><p>“Japanese films, such as those by Studio Ghibli, directed by Hayao Miyazaki, are also popular in the U.S. If Trump imposes film tariffs, it will limit Americans’ opportunities to see these foreign films,” <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://mainichi.jp/articles/20250505/k00/00m/030/067000c&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://mainichi.jp/articles/20250505/k00/00m/030/067000c" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">one Japanese media outlet reported today</a></span>. It’s unclear how this would impact shows and feature-length content on streaming services like Crunchyroll, but they would seemingly also be tariffed in some way unless Trump backtracks. </p><p>One irony to the surprise announcement is that a very vocal contingent of Trump’s online support <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/DAIHIME_SAMA/status/1919186935756583141&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/DAIHIME_SAMA/status/1919186935756583141" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">comes from self-professed anime fans</a></span>. We’ll have to see how they react to this latest betrayal. </p><p>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Thunderbolts' Success Shows Just How Big A Minecraft Movie Was]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/thunderbolts-success-shows-just-how-big-a-minecraft-movie-was/1100-6531306/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/thunderbolts-success-shows-just-how-big-a-minecraft-movie-was.1181214/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/thunderbolts-success-shows-just-how-big-a-minecraft-movie-was/1100-6531306/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6531306">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>A Minecraft Movie continues to soar at the box office, climbing above $870 million after about a month in theaters. This weekend, it faced new competition from Marvel's Thunderbolts* movie, and here's how the two films compared for their opening weekends in the US and globally.</p><p>Thunderbolts* made $76 million in the US for its opening weekend from May 2-4.  For comparison, A Minecraft Movie debuted on April 4 and made $162.7 million worldwide over its first weekend in the US alone. This past weekend was A Minecraft Movie's fifth weekend in theaters, and it made $13.7 million in the US. Movie theaters held "block party" screenings of the movie this weekend, during which <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/a-minecraft-movie-getting-a-theatrical-block-party-edition-inviting-viewers-to-basically-go-wild/1100-6531180/" data-ref-id="1100-6531180">attendees were encouraged to go wild.</a></p><p>Thunderbolts* made $162.1 million worldwide for its opening weekend, compared to $301 million for A Minecraft Movie.</p><p>According to <a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/movies/movie-news/thunderbolts-box-office-solid-opening-1236206794/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">The Hollywood Reporter</a>, $76 million in the US for Thunderbolts* was "slightly ahead" of expectations, with the report noting that Thunderbolts* featuring relatively lesser-known characters might have factored in to the movie's performance so far.</p><p>Thunderbolts* reportedly had a production budget of $180 million, compared to <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/04/06/business/a-minecraft-movie-box-office.html" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">$150 million for A Minecraft Movie.</a></p><p>A Minecraft Movie is the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/highest-grossing-video-game-movies-of-all-time/2900-3968/" data-ref-id="2900-3968">No. 2 highest-grossing video game movie of all time</a>, only trailing The Super Mario Bros. Movie ($1.3 billion). Another video game movie is currently in theaters, too, as Sony's Until Dawn movie has now earned <a href="https://www.boxofficemojo.com/title/tt30955489/?ref_=bo_se_r_1" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">$34.8 million worldwide</a> against a reported $15 million budget.</p><p>Unsurprisingly, Warner Bros. is reportedly <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/a-minecraft-movie-2-sounds-like-a-sure-thing/1100-6530854/" data-ref-id="1100-6530854">close to announcing A Minecraft Movie 2.</a></p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>