<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 07:49:35 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Final Fantasy Producer Talks Turn-Based Combat Viability, Final Fantasy XVI Learnings and More]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/final-fantasy-producer-talks-turn-based-combat-viability/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/final-fantasy-producer-talks-turn-based-combat-viability-final-fantasy-xvi-learnings-and-more.1241223/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Final Fantasy producer, director, and designer Naoki Yoshida <a href="https://www.animenewsnetwork.com/interview/2025-07-08/final-fantasy-xvi-producer-on-the-series-future/.226405" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">was interviewed by Anime News Network</a> at last week's Anime Expo 2025 in Los Angeles, California. One of the first questions was about the viability of turn-based combat for future installments in the series. It was Yoshida himself who infamously <a href="https://wccftech.com/final-fantasy-xvi-producer-says-realistic-graphics-and-turn-based-combat-dont-fit/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">said</a> that, as the visuals get more realistic, it is increasingly challenging for some gamers to stomach turn-based combat without feeling a dissonance. That's one of the reasons Final Fantasy XVI went with action combat only, angering some fans in the process.</p>



<p>After the <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/clair-obscur-expedition-33-dont-fear-the-paintress/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">incredible success of Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</a>, which does feature turn-based combat (albeit spiced up with real time elements), did Yoshida change his mind? Not quite, based on his answer, though he did not exclude the possibility that the next Final Fantasy might have turn-based combat.</p>



<p><em>With this question of turn-based versus action, it tends to isolate the gameplay to just the battle system. That doesn't take into account what kind of game the creators want to deliver to players. For example, based on a certain graphical quality we want to present to our players, or the narrative we want to deliver to our players, it relates to how we set up the game's systems around it. This includes the battle system, game design, and gameplay feel. It's not a clear-cut answer, whether it will become all turn-based, or if it's going to become more action-based. I'm not necessarily going to be on Final Fantasy 17, so we also don't want to obstruct or limit our future director or whomever will be producing the games like 17 or even 18. We don't want to put them on a rail.</em></p>



<p>Yoshida was chosen as the producer of Final Fantasy XVI after <a href="https://wccftech.com/final-fantasy-xiv-naoki-yoshida-interview/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">his excellent work as director of Final Fantasy XIV</a>. What did he learn during the development of the single player game?</p>



<p><em>There's a lot, but if I were to pick one, we were able to learn how to produce a high-end video game. There were a lot of learning points through that, and I feel like we gleaned a lot of know-how through the process. I want to challenge myself or apply to future works on how we can swiftly produce something of high quality and minimize the development period without lowering the quality.</em></p>



<p>Yoshida then said that he and his Final Fantasy XIV already have plans up to version 10.0 (the game is currently at version 7.0 with the Dawntrail expansion). Lastly, he expressed the desire to make a new online game based on a brand-new intellectual property at some point, and he added he doesn't feel anywhere near his retirement (he's currently 52).</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/final-fantasy-producer-talks-turn-based-combat-viability/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Krafton slings dirt at fired Subnautica 2 execs, who then declare a lawsuit]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/07/11/krafton-slings-dirt-at-fired-subnautica-2-execs-who-then-declare-a-lawsuit/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/krafton-slings-dirt-at-fired-subnautica-2-execs-who-then-declare-a-lawsuit.1241217/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>The fallout from <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/07/02/krafton-replaces-subnautica-2-studio-co-founders-effective-immediately/">Krafton’s firing of Unknown Worlds founders and execs</a> last week and <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/07/10/subnautica-2-delayed-to-2026-just-a-week-after-krafton-fired-studio-co-founders/">the delay of Subnautica 2</a> has already been pretty wild and messy, but the publisher has now rolled up its sleeves and stepped down into the mud wrestling pits to try and restore its reputation and honour in this situation. In response, studio founder Charlie Cleveland has announced a lawsuit against Krafton.</p>
<p>In a statement posted as a pop-up on the Krafton website – in and of itself a pretty wild way to deliver such a message – Krafton accuses studio founders Charlie Cleveland and Max McGuire of effectively abandoning <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/subnautica-2">Subnautica 2’s</a> development to focus on other projects – including <a href="https://www.abyssal.co/nutmeg-mistletoe">an independent movie by Cleveland with a podcast and… uh… AI-generated movie posters</a> – despite repeated requests by Krafton for them to return to work. With the game originally expected to reach Early Access in early 2024, it’s already significantly delayed, and Krafton claim that it is significantly lacking in content for even this stage.</p>


<p>Additionally, Krafton states that 90% of the $250 million payout would have been reserved for studio executives Cleveland, McGuire and former CEO Ted Gill. Importantly, Krafton now state that for the rest of the Unknown Worlds team, they “reaffirm our commitment to provide the rewards they were promised.”</p>
<p><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/jasonschreier.bsky.social/post/3ltmkisws4c2w">Per Bloomberg’s Jason Schreier</a>, the purchase agreement would mean there’s $25 million to be divided between roughly 40 employees from a team of 100. It’s also still tied to revenue targets.</p>
<p>Making such strong accusations is very significant, because it opens Krafton up to libel and defamation lawsuits. Given the strong community pushback at the publisher, it’s clear they felt they had no choice but to air some dirty laundry.</p>

<p><a href="https://old.reddit.com/r/subnautica/comments/1lwsxco/lawsuit_a_community_update_from_charlie/">Charlie Cleveland’s rebuttal</a> states that they “know in our souls that the game is ready for Early Access”, echoing his statement from last week, and denies that they would have taken 90% of the $250 million bonus for themselves, stating that “Historically we’ve always shared our profits with the team and did the same when we sold the studio. You can be damned sure we’ll continue with the earnout/bonus as well.”</p>
<p>Most significantly, he announces that they are suing Krafton: “We’ve now filed a lawsuit against Krafton: the details should eventually become (at least mostly) public – you all deserve the full story.”</p>
<p>It’s all an abject mess, and will leave gamers unsure of who to believe. The Subnautica subreddit, for example, seems to still be wholly backing the studio founders, while there’s more doubt in more general gaming subreddits, especially with Cleveland’s movie projects coming to light.</p>
<p>One of the most important things to remember is the the vast majority of the work and the employees are unchanged by this ugly spat. For their sake, maybe it’s best to take a step back and wait for more information to surface before making a conclusion. Sure, remove a wishlisting for the game if you want, but also be open to this project still being good and developed by those with the best of intentions.</p>
<p>Here is Krafton’s full statement:</p>
<p><em>To Our 12 Million Fellow Subnauts,</em></p>
<h3><em><strong>Inevitable Leadership Change Driven by Project Abandonment–Despite Holding 90% of Earnout for Themselves</strong></em></h3>
<p><em>First and foremost, we sincerely thank you for your continued support, passion, and unwavering dedication to Subnautica. We wish to provide clarity on the recent leadership changes at Unknown Worlds, a creative studio under KRAFTON.</em></p>
<p><em><strong>Background of Leadership Change&nbsp;</strong></em></p>
<p><em>KRAFTON deeply values Subnautica’s unique creativity and immersive world-building. To provide fans with even better gaming experiences, we acquired Unknown Worlds, fully committed to supporting Subnautica’s future success. We collaborated closely with the studio’s leadership, who were central to the creation of the original Subnautica, to foster the optimal environment for a successful Subnautica 2.</em></p>
<p><em>Specifically, in addition to the initial $500 million purchase price, we allocated approximately 90% of the up to $250 million earn-out compensation to the three former executives, with the expectation that they would demonstrate leadership and active involvement in the development of Subnautica 2.</em></p>
<p><em>However, regrettably, the former leadership abandoned the responsibilities entrusted to them. Subnautica 2 was originally planned for an Early Access launch in early 2024, but the timeline has since been significantly delayed. KRAFTON made multiple requests to Charlie and Max to resume their roles as Game Director and Technical Director, respectively, but both declined to do so. In particular, following the failure of Moonbreaker, KRAFTON asked Charlie to devote himself to the development of Subnautica 2. However, instead of participating in the game development, he chose to focus on a personal film project.</em></p>
<p><em>KRAFTON believes that the absence of core leadership has resulted in repeated confusion in direction and significant delays in the overall project schedule. The current Early Access version also falls short in terms of content volume. We are deeply disappointed by the former leadership’s conduct, and above all, we feel a profound sense of betrayal by their failure to honor the trust placed in them by our fans.</em></p>
<p><em><strong>KRAFTON’s Full Support for the Dedicated Development Team&nbsp;</strong></em></p>
<p><em>To uphold our commitment to provide you with the best possible gaming experience, we made the difficult yet necessary decision to change the executive leadership. Subnautica 2 has been and continues to be actively developed by a dedicated core team who share genuine passion, accountability, and commitment to the game. We deeply respect their expertise and creativity and will continue to provide full and unwavering support, enabling them to focus solely on delivering the exceptional game you deserve.</em></p>
<p><em><strong>KRAFTON’s Commitment to its Promises in Rewarding Employees&nbsp;</strong></em></p>
<p><em>Additionally, KRAFTON has committed to fair and equitable compensation for all remaining Unknown Worlds employees who have continuously and tirelessly contributed to Subnautica 2’s development. We believe that the dedication and effort of this team are at the very heart of Subnautica’s ongoing evolution, and we reaffirm our commitment to provide the rewards they were promised.</em></p>
<p><em>Fans will always remain at the center of every decision we make at KRAFTON. Moving forward, we promise transparent communication and continued efforts to sustainably develop and expand the beloved Subnautica universe.</em></p>
<p><em><strong>Honoring your trust and expectations is a core tenet at KRAFTON. We are committed to repaying your patience with an even more refined and exceptional gaming experience.</strong></em></p>
<p>And Charlie Cleveland’s rebuttal</p>
<p><em>Hello everyone,</em></p>
<p><em>It continues to be an explosive and surreal time for the Subnautica team and community. None of this is what we wanted. But we truly appreciate the amazing support we’ve gotten from everyone. It means a lot to us, especially now.</em></p>
<p><em>As I wrote last week, we know in our souls that the game is ready for Early Access – that’s just how we roll. And we’d like nothing more than for you to play it (game devs <strong>live</strong> for this). But it’s not currently under our control.</em></p>
<p><em>We’ve now filed a lawsuit against Krafton: the details should eventually become (at least mostly) public – you all deserve the full story. Suing a multi-billion dollar company in a painful, public and possibly protracted way was certainly not on my bucket list. But this needs to be made right. Subnautica has been my life’s work and I would never willingly abandon it or the amazing team that has poured their hearts into it.</em></p>
<p><em>As for the earnout, the idea that Max, Ted and I wanted to keep it all for ourselves is totally untrue. I’m in this industry because I love it, not for riches. Historically we’ve always shared our profits with the team and did the same when we sold the studio. You can be damned sure we’ll continue with the earnout/bonus as well. They deserve it for all their incredible work trying to get this great game into your hands.</em></p>
<p><em>Stay tuned.</em></p>
<p><em>-Charlie</em></p>

<p>Sources: Krafton, <a href="https://old.reddit.com/r/subnautica/comments/1lwsxco/lawsuit_a_community_update_from_charlie/">Reddit</a></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/07/11/krafton-slings-dirt-at-fired-subnautica-2-execs-who-then-declare-a-lawsuit/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Atelier Ryza Secret Trilogy Deluxe Pack Announced For Switch 2 And Switch]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/07/atelier-ryza-secret-trilogy-deluxe-pack-announced-for-switch-2-and-switch</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/atelier-ryza-secret-trilogy-deluxe-pack-announced-for-switch-2-and-switch.1241205/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Here's a teaser trailer</p>
</section></header><section>

<p>If you need more of the <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/atelier_yumia_the_alchemist_of_memories_and_the_envisioned_land">Atelier</a> series in your life, Koei Tecmo has today announced it will be releasing the <strong>Atelier Ryza Secret Trilogy Deluxe pack</strong> digitally for the Switch 2, original Switch, PlayStation and Steam platform.</p>
<p>This "definitive collection" trilogy will be arriving at some point in <strong>2025</strong> and will come with new content – including new playable characters and new story elements for each of the three titles.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"The most comprehensive iteration of the "Secret" series to date, with brand-new content that includes a new story and more playable characters!"</p></blockquote><blockquote>
</blockquote>
<p>The games included are <strong>Atelier Ryza: Ever Darkness &amp; the Secret Hideout DX</strong>, <strong>Atelier Ryza 2 Lost Legends &amp; the Secret Fairy DX</strong> and <strong>Atelier Ryza 3: Alchemist of the End &amp; the Secret Key DX</strong>.</p>
<p>Koei Tecmo has also announced it will be hosting a "special livestream" for this package, which will air on <strong>4th August 2025</strong>. This broadcast will "reveal further details and new footage" although the program will "only be available in Japanese". A <a href="https://atelier.games/secretdx/us/?utm_source=youtube&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=TeaserUS&amp;utm_id=Caption">teaser website has been launched</a> as well.</p>
<p>Earlier this week, Koei Tecmo also teamed up with Bandai Namco and the <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/wiiu/tekken_tag_tournament_2">Tekken</a> team for a special collabration event.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:183911,185033,182820,184930 @ 1752216572 -->
<p>When we find out more, we'll let you know. Would you be interested in this pack? <em>Tell us in the comments.</em></p></section></article><div><p>Liam is a news writer and reviewer across Hookshot Media. He's been writing about games for more than 15 years and is a lifelong fan of many iconic video game characters.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Liam_Doolan"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/liamdoolan.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Liam_Doolan');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/07/atelier-ryza-secret-trilogy-deluxe-pack-announced-for-switch-2-and-switch]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Inti Creates Unveils New "Paper Craft" 2D Action Game For Switch 2, Out October]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/07/inti-creates-unveils-new-paper-craft-2d-action-game-for-switch-2-out-october</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/inti-creates-unveils-new-paper-craft-2d-action-game-for-switch-2-out-october.1241190/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>It's also on the way to the Switch</p>
</section></header><section>

<p>Following <strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/07/azure-striker-gunvolt-trilogy-enhanced-announced-for-switch">Azure Gunvolt Trilogy Enhanced</a></strong> getting confirmed for a worldwide release yesterday, Inti Creates has now lifted the lid on its 30th anniversary project <strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/majogami">Majogami</a></strong>.</p>
<p>It will be coming to the Switch and Switch 2 on <strong>30th October 2025</strong> and is described as a new paper craft "2D action experience". You can see the official premiere in the video above, and below this is some PR to go with it.</p>
<p>The game stars a young woman named Shiroha who must cut through the horrors of a bizarre world after her father is turned into paper.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Paper craft character action. Majogami stars Shiroha, a young woman who has lost her memory, who travels alongside Shiori, her father who has been turned to paper. With her katana, "Kamikiri", in hand, she travels through a bizarre world and cuts through the horrors she finds there in this 2D character action platformer.</p>
<p>Players take control of Shiroha who can move and attack instantly with her "Setsuna" ability, taking out enemies without missing a beat.</p>
<p>Along her journey, Shiroha will collect cards imbued with her memories called Recarte, and face off against the diverse Majogami, divine "Craft Witches" who control the world. These Majogami, with twisted hearts and powerful magic, stand in Shiroha's way as she tries to escape their domain. In addition to her Setsuna attack, she can rely on Shiori's defense sigils and the power of the guardians she meets, the Astrals, to transform herself into new fighting forms.<br>
By defeating these Majogami, Shiroha can slowly regain her memories of both her and Shiori's life, deepening their bonds and revealing her story.</p>
<p>Experience the touching family story and see Shiroha's determination to make it through this twisted world to the end.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This title will be available digitally on the Switch 2 for <strong>$39.99 USD</strong> (or the regional equivalent), or you can grab it on the Switch for <strong>$34.99</strong>. A physical release has also been confirmed for Japan. Here's a look at the box art design:</p>
<figure><a title="Majogami" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/df23ab50e2694/majogami.large.jpg"></a></figure>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:179317 @ 1752217784 -->
<p>What are your first impressions of this upcoming release? <em>Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section></article><div><p>Liam is a news writer and reviewer across Hookshot Media. He's been writing about games for more than 15 years and is a lifelong fan of many iconic video game characters.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Liam_Doolan"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/liamdoolan.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Liam_Doolan');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/07/inti-creates-unveils-new-paper-craft-2d-action-game-for-switch-2-out-october]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Inti Creates announces 2D action platformer Majogami for Switch 2, Switch, PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/07/inti-creates-announces-2d-action-platformer-majogami-for-switch-2-switch-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/inti-creates-announces-2d-action-platformer-majogami-for-switch-2-switch-pc.1241163/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch-2">Switch 2</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Switch 2 and Switch versions due out on October 30.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Inti Creates [250 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/inti-creates">Inti Creates</a> has announced <em><a title="Games > Majogami" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/majogami">Majogami</a></em>, a 2D action <a title="Genres > Platformer [706 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/platformer">platformer</a> coming to <a title="Platforms > Switch 2 [234 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch-2">Switch 2</a> and <a title="Platforms > Switch [17,334 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a> on October 30, followed by <a title="Platforms > PC [23,650 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via Steam at a later date. The Switch 2 version will be priced at $39.99, while the Switch version will be priced at $34.99. <span id="more-978203"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Inti Creates:</p><blockquote><p><strong>■ About <em>Majogami</em></strong></p><p><em>Majogami</em> stars Shiroha, a young woman who has lost her memory, who travels alongside Shiori, her father who has been turned to paper. With her katana, “Kamikiri,”&nbsp; in hand, she travels through a bizarre world and cuts through the <a title="Genres > Horror [659 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/horror">horror</a>s she finds there in this 2D character action platformer.</p><p>Players take control of Shiroha who can move and attack instantly with her “Setsuna” ability, taking out enemies without missing a beat.</p><p>Along her journey, Shiroha will collect cards imbued with her memories called Recarte, and face off against the diverse Majogami, divine “Craft Witches” who control the world.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>The Craft Witches, with twisted hearts and powerful magic, stand in Shiroha’s way as she tries to escape their domain. In addition to her Setsuna attack, she can rely on Shiori’s defense sigils and the power of the guardians she meets, the Astrals, to transform herself into new fighting forms.</p><p>By defeating these Craft Witches, Shiroha will slowly regain memories of both her and Shiori’s life, deepening their bonds and revealing her story.</p><p><strong>■ Story</strong></p><p>Shiroha awakens in Orchesgra, a world of illusions and nightmares, with no memory of her past. After meeting “Shiori”, a sheet of paper who calls himself her father, the two set off to make their escape from the twisted land.</p><p>Standing in their way are those known as “Majogami”, or Craft Witches. Shiroha must defeat them if she wishes to escape and get her memories back.<br>But once she has them, what fate awaits her…?</p><p>“‘Tis a tale of a lonesome girl. Her journey is long, her outlook uncertain.”</p><p><strong>■ <a title="Companies > Experience [212 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/experience">Experience</a> a strange and unique world!</strong></p><p>In a brand new setting created by INTI CREATES art director Yuji <a title="Companies > Natsume [122 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/natsume">Natsume</a>*, Majogami combines paper craft and dark visuals in the world, characters, and game design.</p><p>Be immersed in the lush setting and artwork as you delve into the <a title="Genres > Action [2,864 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action game</a>play.”</p><p>*Main character and art designer for <em>Bloodstained: Curse of the Moon</em> and the <em>Blaster <a title="Companies > Mas [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/mas">Mas</a>ter Zero</em> series. Main heroine designer for <em>Mighty No. 9</em>.</p></blockquote><div id="carousel_978241"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div><blockquote><p><strong>■ “Setsuna” brings unprecedented speed and freedom to combat!</strong></p><p>Use Setsuna to dive fearlessly at powerful enemies to slice them up quickly!</p><p>With a single button press, summon a unique Japanese-inspired effect as you slice your foe in two. Not only a mere attack, Setsuna will allow you move to areas you wouldn’t otherwise, as well as allow you to dodge attacks when timed correctly.</p><p>Master Setsuna, and you’ll experience satisfying combat like no other.</p><p><strong>■ “Astralize” with the power of song!</strong></p><p>With the energy you charge using Setsuna, you’ll be able to transform Shiroha by borrowing the power of the gods known as Astrals.<br>A lush animation accompanies these powerful transformations as Shiroha powers up.</p><p><strong>■ A Rich Story with a Colorful Cast</strong></p><p>The Craft Witches standing in your way each have a unique and charming design.</p><p>Each sporting their own “obsession”, these witches will make the fight a tough one for Shiroha, showing off their prowess with a full-screen animation.<br>You’ll also unlock new sub-stories that reveal more about the lives of Shiori and other characters’ pasts beyond the main story.</p><p><strong>■ Gameplay Introduction</strong></p><p><strong>Basic Attacks</strong></p><p>Shiroha can unleash various attacks with her katana, Kamikiri.</p><p><strong>Setsuna</strong></p><p>A quick approach slashing attack against a single target.</p><p>Should the attack defeat the enemy, you can follow-up with a Piercing Jump.</p><p><strong>Triple Setsuna</strong></p><p>You can charge up Setsuna to turn it into a three-part attack.</p><p>It takes some time, but the resulting attack will gain special properties that pierce enemy defenses.</p><p><strong>Slash</strong></p><p>Useful attacks with great range that can be performed quickly.</p><p>A single attack has low damage, but recharges your resources.</p></blockquote><p>Watch the announcement trailer below. View the first screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/majogami/july-10-2025/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="魔女ガミ －The Witch of Luludidea－ 第一弾紹介映像" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/BIttiV9n06Y?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/07/inti-creates-announces-2d-action-platformer-majogami-for-switch-2-switch-pc]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Company Of Heroes Collection Adds Cross-Platform Multiplayer On Switch]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/07/company-of-heroes-collection-adds-cross-platform-multiplayer-on-switch</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/company-of-heroes-collection-adds-cross-platform-multiplayer-on-switch.1241157/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Reporting for duty</p>
</section></header><section>

<p>The multiplayer component wasn't in the <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/company_of_heroes_collection">Company of Heroes Collection</a> when it arrived on the Switch in 2023, but it's now here.</p>
<p>After promising to add this in as a post-launch update, Feral Interactive has now patched in online "cross-platform multiplayer" in the latest game update. This will allow you to fight online in "up to four player online skirmishes". Here's the <a href="https://x.com/feralgames/status/1943249112641548782">announcement in full via social media</a>:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"Atten-shun! Online, cross-platform multiplayer has arrived for the Company of Heroes Collection on Nintendo Switch! Update today and take the fight online in up to four player online skirmishes. Battle your buddies across the world be they on Switch or mobile!"</p></blockquote><blockquote>
</blockquote>
<p>When Company of Heroes Collection originally launched on Switch, we mentioned how "incomplete" the game felt without multiplayer, so it's great to see the team has finally delivered it.</p>
<p>Feral Interactive also recently confirmed <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/grid_autosport">GRID Autosport</a> is now playable on Switch 2 thanks to a recent system firmware update.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/switch-eshop/related-articles:155975,184230 @ 1752217249 -->
<p>Will you be returning to the Company of Heroes Collection to check out multiplayer on Switch? <em>Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section></article><div><p>Liam is a news writer and reviewer across Hookshot Media. He's been writing about games for more than 15 years and is a lifelong fan of many iconic video game characters.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Liam_Doolan"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/liamdoolan.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Liam_Doolan');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/07/company-of-heroes-collection-adds-cross-platform-multiplayer-on-switch]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Puella Magi Madoka Magica: Magia Exedra for PC launches July 17]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/07/puella-magi-madoka-magica-magia-exedra-for-pc-launches-july-17</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/puella-magi-madoka-magica-magia-exedra-for-pc-launches-july-17.1241151/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/mobile/smartphone">Smartphone</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Game data linkable between PC and mobile.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Genres > Free-to-Play [412 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/free-to-play">Free-to-play</a> <a title="Genres > RPG [17,409 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg">RPG</a> <em><a title="Games > Puella Magi Madoka Magica: Magia Exedra [4 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/puella-magi-madoka-magica-magia-exedra">Puella Magi Madoka Magica: Magia Exedra</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > PC [23,650 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2987800/Madoka_Magica_Magia_Exedra/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> on July 17, publisher <a title="Companies > Aniplex [286 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sony-group-corporation/sony-music-entertainment-japan/aniplex">Aniplex</a> and developers <a title="Companies > Pokelabo [8 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/gree/pokelabo">Pokelabo</a> and <a title="Companies > f4samurai [15 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/f4samurai">f4samurai</a> <a href="https://madoka-exedra.com/news/?id=67325" target="_blank">announced</a>. <span id="more-978208"></span></p><p><em>Puella Magi Madoka Magica: Magia Exedra</em> for iOS via <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/madoka-magica-magia-exedra/id6480402391" target="_blank">App Store</a> and Android via <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.aniplex.magia.exedra.en" target="_blank">Google Play</a> on March 27. Game data can be linked between the PC and mobile versions.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2987800/Madoka_Magica_Magia_Exedra/" target="_blank">Steam page</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Characters from the hit anime series<em> Puella Magi Madoka Magica</em> come together!</p><p>Featuring an all-new story setting and characters from the original ideas of Gekidan Inu Curry (Doroinu), experience the <a title="Genres > Action [2,864 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a> alongside Magical Girl memories in this battle RPG!</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Now go. Unveil the memories of these Magical Girls.</p><p><strong>Enter a Realm of Magical Memories! </strong></p><p>A place where the memories of Magical Girls illuminate the dark…</p><p>The Lighthouse.</p><p>Now a girl who’s lost everything has wandered into its sanctum.</p><p>Who am I…?</p><p>How did I get here…?</p><p>She will relive key moments of countless Magical Girls by opening windows into their memories…</p><p>Trusting she’ll one day find her own lost light of remembrance.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Dive into the World of <em>Puella Magi Madoka Magica</em> Fully Recreated in 3D</strong>&nbsp;– Magical Girls from throughout the series will appear as you <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,392 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a> through various stories, including scenarios from the anime <em>Puella Magi Madoka Magica</em> and the <em>Magia Record: Puella Magi Madoka Magica Side Story</em> mobile game!</li><li><strong>Explore Labyrinths on a Witch Hunt</strong>&nbsp;– Guide characters through treacherous Witch Labyrinths to collect the light of Magical Girl memories, items, and more! Navigate unique challenges and stage designs devised by the bewitching bosses that await within!</li><li><strong>Command the Battlefield with a Tap</strong>&nbsp;– Form a team of up to five Magical Girls and use simple command selections to turn the tide of victory! Magical Girls have varying types, allowing you to form teams strategically! Battle features include the break system where using the right element allows you to wear down enemy break gauges and apply additional effects! Jump into intense, strategic battles against Witches and their minions!</li></ul><p><strong>Staff </strong></p><ul><li><strong>Planning and Distribution:</strong> Aniplex Inc.</li><li><strong>Development:</strong> Pokelabo, Inc. / f4samurai, Inc.</li><li><strong><a title="Genres > Management [30 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/management">Management</a>:</strong> Pokelabo, Inc.</li></ul><p><strong>Voice Cast&nbsp;</strong><br>Ai Nonaka, Aoi Yuki, Ayane Sakura, Chiwa Saito, Emiri Kato, Eri Kitamura, Kaori Mizuhashi, Manaka Iwami, Momo Asakura, Shiina Natsukawa, Sora Amamiya, Yui Ogura, and many more!</p></blockquote></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/07/puella-magi-madoka-magica-magia-exedra-for-pc-launches-july-17]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vocaloid Sensation Hatsune Miku Scores A Switch eShop Sequel Later This Month]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/07/vocaloid-sensation-hatsune-miku-scores-a-switch-eshop-sequel-later-this-month</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/vocaloid-sensation-hatsune-miku-scores-a-switch-eshop-sequel-later-this-month.1241136/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Reunite with the virtual idol in her latest puzzle game</p>
</section></header><section>

<p>Hatsune Miku's puzzle and Picross-inspired title is getting a sequel officially titled <strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/hatsune_miku_logic_paint_splus">Hatsune Miku Logic Paint S+</a></strong>. It's releasing for the Switch later this month on <strong>23rd July 2025</strong>.</p>
<p>This "official sequel" to the virtual idol's original game features over 1000+ puzzles (that is "nearly 3 times as many as the original) to solve, while Hatsune Miku or one of the other Piapro Characters "cheers you along". It will be priced at <strong>$14.99 USD</strong> (or your regional equivalent).</p>
<p>Here's some additional PR from Komodo and Crypton Future Media, along with some screenshots:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Play 10x10, 15x15, or 20x20 standard puzzles, or go for the 75x75 Special puzzles! You can even take the ultimate test of your skills, and try the 100x100 special puzzles. Solving puzzles unlocks illustrations, songs, and all new in Logic Paint S+ character costumes and room decorations.</p>
<p>Collect costumes to dress up Hatsune Miku and friends, and decorations to fill out a fun room for them to hang out in!</p>
</blockquote>

<p>In some related news, three new paid DLC packs are now available for <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/fitness_boxing_feat_hatsune_miku">Fitness Boxing feat. HATSUNE MIKU</a>, where you can duck, jab and punch your way to fitness in classic Fitness Boxing Mode, or brand new Miku Exercise mode.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/switch-eshop/related-articles:112455 @ 1752219885 -->
<p>Have you played any of Hatsune Miku's games on Switch? <em>Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section></article><div><p>Liam is a news writer and reviewer across Hookshot Media. He's been writing about games for more than 15 years and is a lifelong fan of many iconic video game characters.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Liam_Doolan"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/liamdoolan.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Liam_Doolan');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/07/vocaloid-sensation-hatsune-miku-scores-a-switch-eshop-sequel-later-this-month]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This Is Not A ‘Stop Killing Games’ Explainer, I Just Think It’s Interesting]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/stop-killing-games-petition-eu-pirate-software-ross-scott</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/this-is-not-a-%E2%80%98stop-killing-games%E2%80%99-explainer-i-just-think-it%E2%80%99s-interesting.1241133/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>In case you don't know--and people not knowing is going to be part of this!--for the past year or so <a href="https://www.stopkillinggames.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a petition has been floating around asking the European Union to step in and consider forcing video game publishers and studios to 'Stop Killing Games'</a>.</p><p>While some of the language involved has been questionable--the words "consumer movement"<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gamergate" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> are a huge red flag when it comes to video games</a>, and the subject line is pretty dramatic--what's actually being asked is fairly reasonable! The petition,<a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2022/oct/26/iphone-usb-c-lightning-connectors-apple-eu-rules" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> which is seeking to have the EU consider roughly the same common sense enforcement that led Apple to adopt USB-C</a>, ultimately wants every multiplayer game to ship with the ability for fans to take over running its servers if a company decides to cease official support.</p><p>A good idea, and one that we can all get behind. Which a lot of folks already have; despite slowing through 2024 the petition recently passed the threshold for consideration by the EU, bringing it back into the news cycle. But for the past couple weeks, almost every time I've seen this petition mentioned, and especially on places like social media, it's been through the weirdest lenses. It feels like it's been almost impossible for anyone to simply cover this normally, because from the get-go it's been linked with <em>YouTuber drama</em>, something I would usually rather gnaw my own arm off before engaging with.</p><p>For example: I landed on the front page of Reddit yesterday and was greeted very close to the top by this:</p><p>Believe it or not, that's about 'Stop Killing Games'. You wouldn't know it unless you were on top of YouTuber drama though, because 'Pirate Software' spoke out against the petition,<a href="https://www.si.com/esports/news/pirate-software-leaves-off-brand-games-as-stop-killing-games-reaches-goal" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> and was then rounded upon by other channels, and then other people tried to lay blame for the campaign stalling through 2024, and I simply cannot bring myself to type any more about this</a>. Instead, I'm going to let my former colleague Ethan Gach <a href="https://kotaku.com/stop-killing-games-accursed-farms-piratesoftware-eu-1851785707" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">summarise</a>:</p><blockquote><p>The resurgence began with a new video from Accursed Farms two weeks ago titled, “The end of Stop Killing Games.” In it, Scott laid out why he thought the initiative has run out of steam and was failing, laying no small part of the blame at the feet of fellow YouTuber Jason “Thor” Hall, a former Blizzard developer more commonly known by his indie studio pseudonym Pirate Software. Scott accused Hall of leveraging the latter’s big viewership to misinterpret and spread falsehoods about the “Stop Killing Games” initiative, in part by casting it as naïve and unworkable in the modern gaming landscape where always-online and server-centric releases are flopping all the time.</p><span><blockquote></blockquote></span></blockquote><p>Exhausting. I did see some straight-faced news stories about the petition's success, but almost every time that news was<a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/stop-killing-games-eu-petition-tops-12m-signatories-prompting-response-from-video-games-europe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> accompanied</a> by a<a href="https://www.engadget.com/gaming/the-stop-killing-games-initiative-has-hit-a-major-milestone-but-the-fights-just-begun-190431644.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> response</a> from publisher groups that was as predictable and self-serving as you'd expect, providing quotes and explanations that often had nothing to do with what was actually being proposed. For the most part, this campaign has lived and died on social media and video platforms.</p><p>In one way, this was to be expected. The movement was begun and led by a prominent YouTuber, Ross Scott, so some degree of that platform's culture was always bound to bleed into the fabric. But the extent to which it’s dominated the whole movement has been utterly fascinating to me. Whatever I think about drama (something YouTube culture is built on to an extent), it clearly hasn't had a negative effect; the petition now has over 300,000 more signatures than it needs, which should hopefully account for whatever percentage of the first one million will be wiped out for being ineligible (you have to live in the EU for this to count, for example, and you can bet a lot of Americans clicked "sign" anyway).</p><p>It's weird, then, but also extremely interesting! This is a <em>real thing</em>, aiming for a positive outcome through genuine, legislative means, a process you would normally expect to see driven by lobbyists and opportunistic politicians and any media outlet they'd want to get in front of. To see it instead live and breathe on YouTube, becoming something driven entirely by the people it will most directly benefit, is extremely cool. It's rare to see a positive democratic outcome in 2025, so (provided this actually leads somewhere) let's cherish them when and where we can, even if people had to feast on some <em>drama </em>to get there.</p></div><div><h2>Stay in touch</h2><p>Sign up for our free newsletter</p></div><div><h2><span>More from Aftermath</span></h2><div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/outlier-best-mens-pants-indestructible-pants"><h3>All My Pants Are From Outlier Because They Appear To Live Forever</h3></a><p>Outlier makes pants that will survive the abuse of several presidential administrations.</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/plushie-lawsuit-emotional-support-chicken-nuggets-what-do-you-meme"><h3>Plushie Maker Suing Over ‘Emotional Support Chicken Nuggets’</h3></a><p>It’s a pretty standard copyright and trademark infringement case, despite being about stuffed chicken nuggets.</p></div></div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/all">See all posts<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="#000" stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round"><path d="M5 12h13m-6-7 7 7-7 7"></path></svg></a></div></div><br/><br/>https://aftermath.site/stop-killing-games-petition-eu-pirate-software-ross-scott]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Prime Day 2025 - Big Discounts On iPhones, iPads, Apple Watches, & More]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/prime-day-2025-big-discounts-on-iphones-ipads-apple-watches-more/1100-6532970/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/prime-day-2025-big-discounts-on-iphones-ipads-apple-watches-more.1241124/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6532970">

            
            
    


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Apple products are typically among the best hardware you can own, with products like iPhones and iPads supported with software updates for many years-- but that quality comes at a premium price. Fortunately, thanks to Amazon's Prime Day 2025 sale, there are numerous discounts to take advantage of on Apple's latest and best products. We've gathered up the best deals below, with everything from <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DNT2X82Q?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">iPhones</a>, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DZB3KNML?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">iPads</a>, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CH23FR7P?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Macbooks</a>, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DGVWYRT8?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Apple Watches</a>, and <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0D1XD1ZV3?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">AirPods Pro 2</a> earbuds available. The sale runs through July 11, so check out the discounts while you can.</p><p>Many of these deals are offered through the Amazon Renewed Premium program. These are products that are almost brand-new, and while they may have a few cosmetic flaws, such as scratches or dings, they'll still function as intended. Each gadget comes with all the benefits of Amazon customer service and offers up to 90-day returns. Note that some of these discounts are only available to <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/prime/pipeline/signup?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Amazon Prime members</a>, so you'll need to sign up or have an active subscription to get the best deals.</p><p>You'll find more deals on electronics, video games, Blu-rays, and beyond at <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/phoenix-cms/articles/form?id=6533048/">GameSpot's Prime Day Deals Hub</a>, or you can browse the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/primeday?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">full sale lineup at Amazon</a>.</p><div title="6532970 -- Prime Day Apple Products Renewed Deals" data-embed-type="buylink" data-ref-id="3826" data-template="4" data-size="buylink__listicle" data-title="6532970 -- Prime Day Apple Products Renewed Deals" data-collection="">                                                                     <div>             <h2>                    <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0D1XD1ZV3?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/dp\/B0D1XD1ZV3?tag=gamespot-primeday-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0D1XD1ZV3?tag=gamespot-primeday-20">AirPods Pro 2</a>       </h2>                                   <h3>                      <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0D1XD1ZV3?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/dp\/B0D1XD1ZV3?tag=gamespot-primeday-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0D1XD1ZV3?tag=gamespot-primeday-20">$160 (was $253)</a>         </h3>                                                                                                                      <div><p>One of the very best wireless earphones on the market, the AirPods Pro 2 offer excellent audio quality and noise cancellation. I have a pair of these that I use at a <em>very loud </em>gym, and they do a top-notch job at drowning out my facility's terrible soundtrack so that I can properly listen to Dethklok during sessions. These come with a charging case and have an absurdly strong battery life, so you can use them on the go for a lengthy amount of time before you need to recharge. They also use a USB-C connection, so topping the battery up is fairly simple.</p><p>The other great thing about these earphones is that they can sync up seamlessly with your Apple devices and other hardware with Bluetooth functionality, like a TV. They're also quite comfortable with their silicone ear-tips, but you'll probably want to look for something from the sports department if you're planning to go for a jog as heavy movement can make them sit awkwardly. Still, if you're in the market for a comfortable set of earphones that can pump high-quality audio into your ear canals, these are some of the best on the market right now.</p><ul><li><a href="http://www.amazon.com/dp/B0D1XD1ZV3?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Apple AirPods Pro 2 Wireless Earbuds</a> -- $160 (<del>$253</del>)</li></ul></div>                      </div>                                                                     <div>             <h2>                    <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DZB3KNML?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/dp\/B0DZB3KNML?tag=gamespot-primeday-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DZB3KNML?tag=gamespot-primeday-20">iPad Air with M3 (11 and 13 inch models)</a>       </h2>                                                                                                                         <div><p>What's the best iPad for your use? Apple has several options, and the iPad Air hits that sweet spot for power and affordability. It's better than your standard iPad--but still overshadowed by the iPad Pro--and it offers rock-solid performance in a compact form factor.</p><p>The M3 model has a sharp display and a sturdy aluminum design, so you can run a wide variety of apps on it and games. It's available in several colors, and depending on your needs, you can pick up 11-inch or 13-inch versions of the tablet. Overall, expect a solid battery life, above-average speakers, and strong performance. It also supports USB-C, adding to its appeal.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DZB3KNML?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">iPad Air 11-inch (128GB, Wi-Fi, Blue)</a> -- $539 (<strike>$600</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DZ9MYHSG?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">iPad Air 11-inch (128GB,Wi-Fi, Purple)</a> -- $539 <strike>($600</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DZ9RR9SM?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">iPad Air 11-inch (128GB, Wi-Fi, Space Grey)</a> -- $539 (<strike>$600</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DZ9VW4D5?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">iPad Air 11-inch (128GB, Wi-Fi, Starlight)</a> -- $539 (<strike>$600</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DZ75N9KQ?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">iPad Air 11-inch (256GB, Wi-Fi + Cellular, Blue)</a> -- $730 (<strike>$849</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DZ75N6K4?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">iPad Air 11-inch (512GB, Wi-Fi + Cellular, Blue)</a> -- $930 (<strike>$1,049</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DZ757MX5?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">iPad Air 11-inch (512GB, Wi-Fi + Cellular, Purple)</a> -- $930 (<strike>$1,049</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DZ75JPVR?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">iPad Air 11-inch (512GB, Wi-Fi + Cellular, Space Gray)</a> -- $930 (<strike>$1,049</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DZ74JDMV?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">iPad Air 11-inch (512GB, Wi-Fi, Blue)</a> -- $780 (<strike>$899</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DZ74G4WC?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">iPad Air 11-inch (512GB, Wi-Fi, Purple)</a> -- $780 (<strike>$899</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DZ75DNYQ?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">iPad Air 11-inch (1TB, Wi-Fi + Cellular, Starlight)</a> -- $780 (<strike>$1,249</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DZ74CF3K?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">iPad Air 11-inch (1TB, Wi-Fi, Blue)</a> -- $980 (<strike>$1,099</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DZ75MMQK?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">iPad Air 11-inch (1TB, Wi-Fi, Purple)</a> -- $980 (<strike>$1,099</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DZ74CJBR?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">iPad Air 11-inch (1TB, Wi-Fi, Space Gray)</a> -- $980 (<strike>$1,099</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DZ73TF31?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">iPad Air 11-inch (1TB, Wi-Fi, Starlight)</a> -- $980 (<strike>$1,099</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DZ74L7CP?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">iPad Air 13-inch (256GB, Wi-Fi, Purple)</a> -- $780 (<strike>$899</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DZ76P9SL?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">iPad Air 13-inch (512GB, Wi-Fi + Cellular, Blue)</a> -- $1,129 (<strike>$1,249</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DZ76Q6XH?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">iPad Air 13-inch (1TB, Wi-Fi + Cellular, Blue)</a> -- $1,330 (<strike>$1,449</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DZ73TSDW?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">iPad Air 13-inch (1TB, Wi-Fi + Cellular, Purple)</a> -- $1,330 (<strike>$1,449</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DZ7433F5?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">iPad Air 13-inch (1TB, Wi-Fi + Cellular, Space Gray)</a> -- $1,330 (<strike>$1,449</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DZ7347KC?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">iPad Air 13-inch (1TB, Wi-Fi, Space Gray)</a> -- $1,180 (<strike>$1,299</strike>)</li></ul></div>                      </div>                                                                     <div>             <h2>                    <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DK3WJTNQ?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/dp\/B0DK3WJTNQ?tag=gamespot-primeday-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DK3WJTNQ?tag=gamespot-primeday-20">iPad Mini A17 Pro</a>       </h2>                                                                                                                         <div><p>The iPad Mini has set a high bar in the tiny tablet category, as this portable powerhouse is surprisingly nimble thanks to the A17 Pro chip inside of it. Released last year, it's a really nice tablet to carry around thanks to its form factor, and the hardware inside has basically future-proofed it for several years. It has a great battery life, USB-C, and it feels great thanks to its recycled aluminum design. It might be a little too small to use as a work device, but as a multimedia hub--or even a handheld gaming console if you combine it with the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/razers-kishi-v3-pro-xl-controller-turns-your-ipad-pro-into-a-giant-handheld/1100-6532399/">Razer Kishi V3 Pro</a>--it's worth looking at.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DK3WJTNQ?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">iPad mini 8.3-inch (128GB, Wi-Fi + Cellular, Blue)</a> -- $530 (<strike>$649</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DK3WBMBR?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">iPad mini 8.3-inch (128GB , Wi-Fi + Cellular, Purple)</a> -- $530 (<strike>$649</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DK3Y4DY8?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">iPad mini 8.3-inch (128GB, Wi-Fi + Cellular, Starlight)</a> -- $530 (<strike>$649</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DK3YF38G?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">iPad mini 8.3-inch (128GB, Wi-Fi, Blue)</a> -- $530 (<strike>$649</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DKL298QX?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">iPad mini 8.3-inch (128GB, Wi-Fi, Blue)</a> -- $380 (<strike>$499</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DKKRLVR4?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">iPad mini 8.3-inch (128GB, Wi-Fi, Purple)</a> -- $439 (<strike>$499</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DKKM2KW3?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">iPad mini 8.3-inch (128GB, Wi-Fi, Space Gray)</a> -- $439 (<strike>$499</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DKKWFML9?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">iPad mini 8.3-inch (128GB, Wi-Fi, Starlight)</a> -- $439 (<strike>$499</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DK3Z3JY1?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">iPad mini 8.3-inch (256GB, Wi-Fi + Cellular, Blue)</a> -- $630 (<strike>$749</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DK3WP3NX?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">iPad mini 8.3-inch (256GB, Wi-Fi + Cellular, Purple)</a> -- $630 (<strike>$749</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DK3XYFX2?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">iPad mini 8.3-inch (512GB, Wi-Fi + Cellular, Blue)</a> -- $830 (<strike>$949</strike>)</li></ul></div>                      </div>                                                                                                                                          <div>             <h2>                    <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CSVG1668?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/dp\/B0CSVG1668?tag=gamespot-primeday-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CSVG1668?tag=gamespot-primeday-20">Apple Watch Ultra 2</a>       </h2>                                                                                                                         <div><p>Admittedly, the Apple Watch Ultra 2 only offers minor refinements when compared to previous iterations. However, if you're new to this tech, it might seem revolutionary as you're getting a large 3,000-nit display, amazing clarity on the screen, and an upgraded processor. It has a rugged design as well, so it can stand up to the pressure of the great outdoors, and with its rock-solid battery life, it can stay operational for even the toughest treks.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CSVG1668?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Apple Watch Ultra 2 [GPS + Cellular 49mm, Rugged Titanium Case &amp; Blue Alpine Loop]</a> -- $650 (<strike>$700</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CSVJ7BRX?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Apple Watch Ultra 2 [GPS + Cellular 49mm, Rugged Titanium Case &amp; Blue Alpine Loop]</a> -- $650 (<strike>$700</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CSVB9C5G?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Apple Watch Ultra 2 [GPS + Cellular 49mm, Rugged Titanium Case &amp; Blue Ocean Band]</a> -- $650 (<strike>$700</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CSVL1GS9?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Apple Watch Ultra 2 [GPS + Cellular 49mm, Rugged Titanium Case &amp; Blue/Black Trail Loop]</a> -- $650 (<strike>$700</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CSTGJVKF?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Apple Watch Ultra 2 [GPS + Cellular 49mm, Rugged Titanium Case &amp; Blue/Black Trail Loop]</a> -- $650 (<strike>$700</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CSVCDCPP?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Apple Watch Ultra 2 [GPS + Cellular 49mm, Rugged Titanium Case &amp; Green/Grey Trail Loop]</a> -- $650 (<strike>$700</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CSTFM519?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Apple Watch Ultra 2 [GPS + Cellular 49mm, Rugged Titanium Case &amp; Green/Grey Trail Loop]</a> -- $650 (<strike>$700</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CSVJ5W27?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Apple Watch Ultra 2 [GPS + Cellular 49mm, Rugged Titanium Case &amp; Indigo Alpine Loop]</a> -- $650 (<strike>$700</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CSVG2GM8?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Apple Watch Ultra 2 [GPS + Cellular 49mm, Rugged Titanium Case &amp; Indigo Alpine Loop]</a> -- $650 (<strike>$700</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CSTGZT4Y?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Apple Watch Ultra 2 [GPS + Cellular 49mm, Rugged Titanium Case &amp; Indigo Alpine Loop]</a> -- $650 (<strike>$700</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CSVMM8LR?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Apple Watch Ultra 2 [GPS + Cellular 49mm, Rugged Titanium Case &amp; Olive Alpine Loop]</a> -- $650 (<strike>$700</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CSV8JVJP?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Apple Watch Ultra 2 [GPS + Cellular 49mm, Rugged Titanium Case &amp; Olive Alpine Loop]</a> -- $650 (<strike>$700</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CSVGDV7Q?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Apple Watch Ultra 2 [GPS + Cellular 49mm, Rugged Titanium Case &amp; Olive Alpine Loop]</a> -- $650 (<strike>$700</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CSTHHVBM?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Apple Watch Ultra 2 [GPS + Cellular 49mm, Rugged Titanium Case &amp; Orange Ocean Band]</a> -- $650 (<strike>$700</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CSVGK51Y?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Apple Watch Ultra 2 [GPS + Cellular 49mm, Rugged Titanium Case &amp; Orange/Beige Trail Loop]</a> -- $650 (<strike>$700</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CSVMMBRM?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Apple Watch Ultra 2 [GPS + Cellular 49mm, Rugged Titanium Case &amp; Orange/Beige Trail Loop]</a> -- $650 (<strike>$700</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CSTGYWZZ?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Apple Watch Ultra 2 [GPS + Cellular 49mm, Rugged Titanium Case &amp; White Ocean Band]</a> -- $650 (<strike>$700</strike>)</li></ul></div>                      </div>                                                                                                                                          <div>             <h2>                    <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DNT2X82Q?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/dp\/B0DNT2X82Q?tag=gamespot-primeday-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DNT2X82Q?tag=gamespot-primeday-20">Unlocked iPhone 16 + 15 (Amazon Renewed)</a>       </h2>                                                                                                                         <div><p>Finally, you can also save big on some of Apple's best iPhone models. We're at a point where smartphone design is largely iterative, but if you haven't upgraded for quite a few years, then there's a lot to love about these models. Each one has a powerful camera for photography and video--the recent 28 Years Later was shot on iPhone 15 Pro Max smartphones--a battery that can last for days, and enough hardware power under the hood to handle a wide variety of apps.</p><p>Each numbered model has improved on its predecessor, but the big thing to consider here is what type of iPhone you want at the end of the day. Your regular iPhone is still an excellent workhorse device, but if you want a little more grunt for your creative pursuits or your gaming hobbies, then you'll want to look at the Pro models. These offer bigger screens, batteries, and lenses for the camera, with the Pro Max being the overall best--and thus more expensive--option in all of these categories.</p><p>These are also all Renewed Premium devices, so they'll look brand-new when you get them as they've barely been used.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DNT2X82Q?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">iPhone 16 Pro 256GB Black Titanium - Unlocked (Renewed Premium)</a> -- $828.74 (<strike>$979</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DNTC3HXX?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">iPhone 16 Pro 256GB Desert Titanium - Unlocked (Renewed Premium)</a> -- $816 (<strike>$979</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DNTDQTYC?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">iPhone 16 Pro 256GB Natural Titanium - Unlocked (Renewed Premium)</a> -- $823.15 (<strike>$979</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DNT8MWWK?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">iPhone 16 Pro 256GB White Titanium - Unlocked (Renewed Premium)</a> -- $827.89 (<strike>$999</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DNT53LJG?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">iPhone 16 Pro 512GB Black Titanium - Unlocked (Renewed Premium)</a> -- $935 (<strike>$1,199</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DNTB894F?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">iPhone 16 Pro 512GB Desert Titanium - Unlocked (Renewed Premium)</a> -- $935 (<strike>$1,199</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DNTBWNBL?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">iPhone 16 Pro 512GB Natural Titanium - Unlocked (Renewed Premium)</a> -- $891.65 (<strike>$1,049</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DNT9HYXL?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">iPhone 16 Pro 512GB White Titanium - Unlocked (Renewed Premium)</a> -- $935 (<strike>$1,199</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CRJ1HCCP?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">iPhone 15 Pro Max 1TB Black Titanium - Unlocked (Renewed Premium)</a> -- $849.15 (<strike>$999</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CRJQ3CPC?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">iPhone 15 Pro Max 1TB Blue Titanium - Unlocked (Renewed Premium)</a> -- $833 (<strike>$999</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CRJNYVYT?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">iPhone 15 Pro Max 1TB Natural Titanium - Unlocked (Renewed Premium)</a> -- $849.15 (<strike>$999</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CRJXJS12?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">iPhone 15 Pro Max 1TB White Titanium - Unlocked (Renewed Premium)</a> -- $849.15 (<strike>$999</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CRJJBBPY?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">iPhone 15 Pro Max 256GB Black Titanium - Unlocked (Renewed Premium)</a> -- $714 ($<strike>899</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CRJSBN5M?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">iPhone 15 Pro Max 256GB Natural Titanium - Unlocked (Renewed Premium)</a> -- $764.15 (<strike>$899</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CRJTPR6T?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">iPhone 15 Pro Max 256GB White Titanium - Unlocked (Renewed Premium)</a> -- $747 (<strike>$899</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CRJXCL61?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">iPhone 15 Pro Max 512GB Black Titanium - Unlocked (Renewed Premium)</a> -- $773.47 (<strike>$949</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CRJ3HN3X?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">iPhone 15 Pro Max 512GB Blue Titanium - Unlocked (Renewed Premium)</a> -- $806.65 (<strike>$949</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CRJK7V6D?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">iPhone 15 Pro Max 512GB Natural Titanium - Unlocked (Renewed Premium)</a> -- $765 (<strike>$949</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CRJP4H1M?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">iPhone 15 Pro Max 512GB White Titanium - Unlocked (Renewed Premium)</a> -- $790.43 (<strike>$949</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0BY77JM8T?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">iPhone SE 3rd Gen 64GB Starlight - Unlocked (Renewed Premium)</a> -- $194 (<strike>$260</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0BYLN65JD?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">iPhone 14 128GB Blue - Unlocked (Renewed Premium)</a> -- $371 (<strike>$449</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0BN733951?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">iPhone 14 128GB Blue - Unlocked (Renewed)</a> -- $322.38 (<strike>$389</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0BYL93774?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">iPhone 14 128GB Midnight - Unlocked (Renewed Premium)</a> -- $381.39 (<strike>$449</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0BYLLR7QZ?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">iPhone 14 128GB Purple - Unlocked (Renewed Premium)</a> -- $381.65 (<strike>$449</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0BYL97GJ9?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">iPhone 14 256GB Purple - Unlocked (Renewed Premium)</a> -- $407.15 (<strike>$479</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0BYL2LTSJ?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">iPhone 14 512GB Blue - Unlocked (Renewed Premium)</a> -- $458.15 (<strike>$539</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0BGQKY8S9?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">iPhone 13 128GB Midnight - Unlocked (Renewed Premium)</a> -- $317.92 (<strike>$399</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08PP5MSVB?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">iPhone 12 64GB Black - Fully Unlocked (Renewed)</a> -- $194 (<strike>$249</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B09JFNTCLX?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">iPhone 12 64GB Black - Unlocked (Renewed Premium)</a> -- $234.34 (<strike>$289</strike>)</li></ul></div>                      </div>   </div><h2>Shop all Prime Day Deals at Amazon</h2><p>tk</p><div data-embed-type="pinbox" data-ref-id="4304">  <ul>                              <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-criterion-collection-best-movie-deals-amazon-blu-ray-sale/1100-6532794/">The Criterion Collection 50% Off Movie Sale - Here Are The Best Deals</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/little-nightmares-3-preorder-guide-amazon-exclusive-edition-bonuses-release-date/1100-6532712/">Little Nightmares 3 Amazon-Exclusive Mirror Edition Is Up For Preorder</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/legos-first-visual-history-for-adults-is-60-off-in-early-prime-day-deal/1100-6532717/">Lego's First Visual History For Adults Is 60% Off In Early Prime Day Deal</a></li>                          <li>         <span>+ Show More More Gaming, Tech, and Entertainment Deals &amp; Preorders Links (5)</span>       </li>          <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/rune-factory-guardians-of-azuma-earth-dancer-limited-edition-nintendo-switch-2-restock/1100-6526172/">Amazon Restocks Rune Factory: Guardians Of Azuma Earth Dancer Edition</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/all-four-discontinued-donkey-kong-lego-sets-restocked-at-amazon/1100-6532560/">All Four Discontinued Donkey Kong Lego Sets Restocked At Amazon</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/death-stranding-2-on-the-beach-collector-edition-launch-buying-guide/1100-6530003/">Death Stranding 2 Collector's Edition Is In Stock Ahead Of Tomorrow's Launch</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/donkey-kong-bananza-preorder-nintendo-switch-2/1100-6530595/">Donkey Kong Bananza Game &amp; Amiibo Bundle Available At Walmart</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/marvel-spider-man-magic-the-gathering-trading-card-restock-amazon-preorder/1100-6529819/">Marvel's Spider-Man Magic: The Gathering Preorders Restocked At Amazon</a></li>   </ul> </div>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/prime-day-2025-big-discounts-on-iphones-ipads-apple-watches-more/1100-6532970/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ghost of Yotei State of Play July 2025: Everything Revealed]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/ghost-of-yotei-state-of-play-july-2025-everything-revealed</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ghost-of-yotei-state-of-play-july-2025-everything-revealed.1241118/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Sony and Sucker Punch Productions just wrapped up their July 2025 <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/ghost-of-yotei"><u>Ghost of Yōtei</u></a> State of Play, showcasing a better look at its world, combat, and new modes ahead of its release date this fall.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cgM6poO2JmY" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>20-minute gameplay presentation</u></a>, hosted by creative directors Jason Connell and Nate Fox, arrived today to help showcase how Atsu’s journey will be both familiar and new for players who enjoyed 2020’s Ghost of Tsushima. Any way you cut it, the Ghost of Yōtei State of Play is the closest look at one of the PlayStation 5’s biggest games of the year that we’ve seen yet.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">For those who missed out on the State of Play, IGN took the time to gather all of the highlights for you right here. You can check out everything revealed during the presentation below while we wait for more updates ahead of Ghost of Yōtei’s October 2, 2025, release date.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><h2 data-cy="title2">The Sights and Sounds of Ezo</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Ghost of Yōtei focuses on Atsu as she seeks revenge against the Yōtei Six at any cost. It's a bloody journey that has led Atsu's enemies to fear her, with many worried that she is a legendary Onyro spirit come to life. Ghost of Yōtei fuels its journey of vengeance in a completely new way, allowing players to flash back to its protagonist's younger years with the simple press of a button.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Traveling throughout Ezo means encountering a land far different from the war-torn island of Tsushima. Beautiful in its own right, Ghost of Yōtei's new map encourages players to experience Atsu's journey how they please, with Sucker Punch going as far as to say the adventure "focuses on player freedom more than any game" it has ever made. One example of this newfound player freedom can be found in the Clue System, which can lead the player in new directions. While some information gained during an interrogation may see Atsu travel to snowy mountaintops that hide hidden attackers, another may take her to a village ravaged by fire and an army of samurai.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Sucker Punch wants players to choose to focus on combat, exploration, story, or whatever it is that satisfies their quest. However, one recommended way to see all Ezo has to offer involves simply using a spyglass and walking toward whatever catches your eye.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Exploring a 1603 Japan means finding familiar points of interest, such as new Bamboo Strike challenges and even more Hot Springs to relax in, but players can also look forward to taking out difficult fights as a bounty hunter, too. There are also Altars of Reflection, which unlock new abilities for Atsu that will no doubt aid her on her journey.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><h2 data-cy="title2">Ghost of Yōtei Combat Get an Upgrade</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">With a hefty price on Atsu's head, players will need to utilize an arsenal of new tools and weapons. While it looks like fans will have plenty of opportunities for standard sword encounters, some new blades will help spice things up. Highlights include the weapons like the katana and spear as well as the more unconvential kusarigama chain blade, the lengthy odachi, and even dual swords. Each offers specific advantages in battle depending on the circumstances, with all weapons featuring upgrades to utilize, too.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Ranged combat, meanwhile, will see Atsu primarily using two tools: a bow and a gun. The Ghost of Yōtei gameplay showed off a glimpse at how the latter can be used to quickly take out a distant enemy at the cost of stealth. In other words, Atsu comes with a few more tools than Ghost of Tsushima's Jin did, and she's got no reservations when it comes to using them to take out the Yōtei Six.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In between combat encounters and brushes with death, players can allow Atsu to rest under the stars. Here, you can cook food, play music, and even meet up with allies while taking in all Ezo's skies have to offer. With these changes also comes a replacement for the standard journal that is known as Atsu's Wolf Pack. Sucker Punch calls the menu system a "more character-driven way of managing allies and vendors" met during Atsu's journey. It's a straightforward way to see who might have something to offer, and it's wrapped up with art for each face you meet.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Where Ghost of Tsushima approached its connection to nature in one way, Ghost of Yōtei appears like it may depend the connection players have with the world around them. One way it will do this involves a new wolf companion who, as shown during the State of Play, can tear out an enemy's throat during combat. Traveling through a field of flowers, meanwhile, can give your character a boost while riding on your horse. Sucker Punch also showed off a first look at what appears to be a dense customization system for Atsu's armor as well as the ability to disarm enemies with enough well-timed attacks.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Ghost of Yotei State of Play July 2025 - Screenshots</h3></div></output><h2 data-cy="title2">Kurosawa Mode Returns Alongside New Immersive Options</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Kurosawa Mode, a black-and-white omage to legenadary director Akira Kurosawa, makes its return after fans fell in love with it in Ghost of Tsushima. It's a sign not only that Sucker Punch is happy with the response it received the first time around but that the team remains influenced by some of the prominent artists in the genre.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">This influence can also be felt in two additional modes: Miike Mode and Watanabe Mode. As some movie fans might have guessed, the former takes after 13 Assassins director Takashi Miike, moving the camera in closer with more blood and more mud. The latter, meanwhile, brings in the work of Samurai Champloo anime director Shinichirō Watanabe by featuring original lo-fi beats that back moments of exploration and combat.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Other highlights from the Ghost of Yōtei State of Play include a first look at photo mode as well as options for Standard English audio, Subtitled English audio, and Samurai Cinema, which features fully voice acted Japanese dialogue with English subtitles.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Ghost of Yōtei launches October 2, 2025, for PS5. As a last-minute surprise, Sucker Punch promised that special edition Ghost of Yōtei PS5 consoles and unique DualSense controllers will also be available at launch. For more details while we wait to see more, you can check out everything else we know about Ghost of Yōtei <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ghost-of-yotei-release-date-gameplay-story-latest-news"><u>here</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Michael Cripe is a freelance contributor with IGN. He's best known for his work at sites like The Pitch, The Escapist, and OnlySP. Be sure to give him a follow on Bluesky (@mikecripe.bsky.social) and Twitter (@MikeCripe).</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/ghost-of-yotei-state-of-play-july-2025-everything-revealed]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Yu-Gi-Oh! Early Days Collection Drops to Just $19.99 for Amazon Prime Day]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/yu-gi-oh-early-days-collection-nintendo-switch-amazon-prime-day-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/yu-gi-oh-early-days-collection-drops-to-just-19-99-for-amazon-prime-day.1241115/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">A great collection of 14 games. </h2></p><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Amazon Prime Day ends tomorrow, but there are plenty of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/amazon-prime-day-2025-sale-top-deals-live">amazing deals</a> still in stock. We've seen price cuts on hundreds of popular <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-4k-uhd-blu-ray-deals-amazon-prime-day-2025">movies</a>, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/amazon-buy-two-get-one-free-book-sale-prime-day-2025">books</a>, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-lego-set-deals-for-prime-day-2025">toys</a>, and of course, games. The Yu-Gi-Oh! Early Days Collection for the Nintendo Switch is certainly a standout here. Right now, you can pick it up for $19.99, a nice 60% off the original price of $49.99.</p><p id="yu-gi-oh-early-days-collection"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Yu-Gi-Oh! Early Days Collection">Yu-Gi-Oh! Early Days Collection Is 60% Off for Prime Day</h2></p><div catalogid="5955769b-2ea8-46c6-8214-ebe3be2242ff" id="225076"><div id="225076" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Yu-Gi-Oh! Early Days Collection</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">The Yu-Gi-Oh! Early Days collection just released this past February. It's a compilation of 14 retro games based on the globally popular trading card game. Here are the games you get in the bundle, many of which are available in the West for the first time with this release:</p><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Yu-Gi-Oh! Duel Monsters (GameBoy, 1998)</strong></li><li><strong>Yu-Gi-Oh! Duel Monsters II: Dark Duel Stories (GameBoy, GBC, 1999)</strong></li><li><strong>Yu-Gi-Oh! Monster Capsule (GameBoy, GBC, 2000)</strong></li><li><strong>Yu-Gi-Oh! Dark Duel Stories (GBC, 2000)</strong></li><li><strong>Yu-Gi-Oh! Duel Monsters 4: Battle of the Great Duelist (GBC, 2000)</strong></li><li><strong>Yu-Gi-Oh! Dungeon Dice Monsters (GBA, 2001)</strong></li><li><strong>Yu-Gi-Oh! The Eternal Duelist Soul (GBA, 2001)</strong></li><li><strong>Yu-Gi-Oh! Duel Monsters 6 Expert 2 (GBA, 2001)</strong></li><li><strong>Yu-Gi-Oh! The Sacred Cards (GBA, 2002)</strong></li><li><strong>Yu-Gi-Oh! Reshef of Destruction (GBA 2003)</strong></li><li><strong>Yu-Gi-Oh! Worldwide Edition: Stairway to the Destined Duel (GBA, 2003)</strong></li><li><strong>Yu-Gi-Oh! World Championship Tournament 2004 (GBA, 2004)</strong></li><li><strong>Yu-Gi-Oh! Destiny Board Traveler (GBA, 2004)</strong></li><li><strong>Yu-Gi-Oh! 7 Trials to Glory: World Championship Tournament 2005 (GBA, 2004)</strong></li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph">Did you know there were this many Yu-Gi-Oh! games? Me neither. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/yu-gi-oh-the-sacred-cards">The Sacred Cards</a> on the GameBoy Advance is the only one I've played, and it's actually a pretty fun digital version of the popular card game that has you playthrough the early days (well would you look at that) of the anime. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Aside from this great collection of classic handheld games, you have the chance to get one of two exclusive pack-in bonus cards. The Quarter Century Secret Rare versions of <a href="https://zdcs.link/9wRxVN?object_uuid=5a78f3e7-9851-4c5f-9a53-b025dc234dbb&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Harpie's Feather Duster</a> with alternate arts are classic cards longtime fans will be familiar with. </p></div><p id="featured-in-this-article"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Featured in this article">More Nintendo Switch Games on Sale During Prime Day</h2></p><p data-cy="paragraph">There are tons of other physical <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-amazon-prime-day-switch-game-deals-2025">Nintendo Switch games available with new Prime Day deal prices.</a> The <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/final-fantasy-i-vi-pixel-remaster-collection-deal-playstation-nintendo-switch-prime-day-2025">Final Fantasy Pixel Remaster I-VI Collection</a> was extremely hard to attain when it first released, and I would absolutely be picking one up if I hadn't already imported a Japanese copy. </p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Myles Obenza is a freelance writer for IGN. Follow him on Bluesky </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/mylesobenza.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>@mylesobenza.bsky.social</em></a><em>.</em></p></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Jul 10, 2025 10:26 pm</p></div></div><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/yu-gi-oh-early-days-collection-nintendo-switch-amazon-prime-day-2025]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Heartworm launches July 31]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/07/heartworm-launches-july-31</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/heartworm-launches-july-31.1241112/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Retro-inspired survival horror game dated.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Retro-inspired <a title="Genres > Survival [435 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/survival">survival</a> <a title="Genres > Horror [659 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/horror">horror game</a> <em><a title="Games > Heartworm [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/heartworm">Heartworm</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > PC [23,650 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1257030/Heartworm/" target="_blank">Steam</a> on July 31, publisher <a title="Companies > DreadXP [14 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/dreadxp">DreadXP</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Vincent Adinolfi [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/vincent-adinolfi">Vincent Adinolfi</a> announced. <span id="more-978201"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1257030/Heartworm/" target="_blank">Steam page</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Pass through the threshold and enter a world born of memories. Defend yourself with a camera while solving death’s mysteries in a reverent evolution of 90s survival horror, integrating both fixed cameras and over the shoulder perspectives.</p><p><strong>Story</strong></p><p>Sam, unable to move on from the death of her beloved grandfather, falls down an internet rabbit hole chasing the promise of reuniting with him.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Following the lead of a mysterious forum, she finds herself at a supposedly supernatural house in the mountain, hoping to make contact with the other side.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li>A journey through grief and loss within retro-inspired atmospheric environments..</li><li>Four-to-six hours of gameplay with multiple endings.</li><li>Both pre-rendered and in-game cutscenes.</li><li>A focus on exploration with classic puzzles, and limited combat using a camera as a weapon.</li><li>A modern control scheme with third-person over-the-shoulder aiming and optional classic tank controls.</li><li>Optional pixelation and retro effects calling back to the first 3D console era for a more authentic experience.</li><li>A haunting original soundtrack.</li></ul><p><a title="Companies > Experience [212 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/experience">Experience</a> a psychologically-focused narrative love letter to late 90s genre staples <em><a title="Companies > Sile" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sile">Sile</a>nt Hill</em> and <em>Resident Evil</em>.</p></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Heartworm | Release Date Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/t-ckqEK89Ws?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/07/heartworm-launches-july-31]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Borderlands 4 – Vex gameplay overview and character short]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/07/borderlands-4-vex-gameplay-overview-and-character-short</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/borderlands-4-%E2%80%93-vex-gameplay-overview-and-character-short.1241109/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch-2">Switch 2</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Witness Vex's destructive Phase energy in action.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > 2K [666 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/take-two-interactive-software/2k">2K</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Gearbox Software [243 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/the-gearbox-entertainment-company/gearbox-software">Gearbox Software</a> have released a Vex gameplay overview and character short for <em><a title="Games > Borderlands 4 [8 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/borderlands-4">Borderlands 4</a></em>. <span id="more-978204"></span></p><p>Here are the latest details, via 2K:</p><blockquote><p>In the Vex Gameplay Overview, you can witness Vex’s destructive Phase energy in action, whether she’s blasting enemies to bits with elemental orbs, summoning an entourage of aggressive Phase Clones, or letting her adorable (and deadly) feline Phase Phamiliar, aptly named Trouble, tear the opposition limb from limb.</p><p>You can also watch Vex’s new Character Short “Purple Friday,” featuring Vex’s retelling of the bloody events that set her down the path to becoming a Vault Hunter and how she obtained her powers.</p></blockquote><p><em>Borderlands 4</em> is due out for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [9,884 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [7,516 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [23,650 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1285190/Borderlands_4/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> and <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/p/borderlands-4" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Epic Games Store</a> on September 12, followed by <a title="Platforms > Switch 2 [234 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch-2">Switch 2</a> later in 2025.</p><p>Watch the trailer below.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <h2><span>Gameplay Overview: Vex</span></h2><p><iframe title="Borderlands 4 - Official Gameplay Overview - Vex" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/LzC0TYyH6nk?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><span>Gameplay Overview: Vex</span></h2><p><iframe title="Borderlands 4 - Official Gameplay Overview - Vex" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/LzC0TYyH6nk?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/07/borderlands-4-vex-gameplay-overview-and-character-short]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Unlocked iPhones Are Hundreds Of Dollars Off At Amazon For Prime Day]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/unlocked-iphones-are-hundreds-of-dollars-off-at-amazon-for-prime-day/1100-6532971/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/unlocked-iphones-are-hundreds-of-dollars-off-at-amazon-for-prime-day.1241106/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="default-content">
        
          <p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p>
  
    <article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6532971">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>If you're looking to upgrade your iPhone, several professionally refurbished models are on sale during Amazon's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/phoenix-cms/articles/form?id=6533048/">Prime Day 2025 sale</a>, which ends July 11. Each of the discounted iPhones is certified through the Amazon Renewed Premium program. While these are pre-owned, they're all in full working order, usually just a step away from brand-new in quality. According to Amazon, each item has been professionally inspected, tested, and cleaned by professionals, and there are "no visible cosmetic imperfections" when the item is held at arm's length. The only real loss here is the box, as Amazon will instead ship these iPhones out in generic packaging. Products are also eligible for a replacement or refund within 90 days. Note that these deals are only available to <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/prime/pipeline/signup?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Amazon Prime members</a>, so you'll need an active subscription to get the lowest price.</p><p>The upshot of choosing one of the refurbished models listed below is that they're all unlocked, meaning you can use them with your current service provider or take them with you if you decide to switch to a different company in the future. As for the discounted iPhones, there are a variety of models on sale here, though <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DNT2X82Q?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">the iPhone Pro 16 is the best of the bunch</a>, and you can grab one for as low was $816 (was $979). To be fair, smartphone design is very iterative these days, so even the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CRJ1HCCP?tag=gamespot-primeday-20&amp;th=1" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">iPhone 15 Pro Max</a> or <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0BYL93774?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">iPhone 14</a> are still worth picking up while they're discounted, especially if you haven't upgraded in a while. iPhone Pro and Pro Max models offer more power, better batteries, larger screens, and enhanced cameras compared to the standard models. There's also the larger Pro Max comes down to size mainly, with the Pro Max offering Apple's best hardware of the year on a larger scale.</p><p>These iPhone discounts will only be available during Prime Day, which runs until July 11, so grab them while you can. You'll find more deals on electronics, video games, Blu-rays, and beyond at <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/phoenix-cms/articles/form?id=6533048/">GameSpot's Prime Day Deals Hub</a>, or you can browse the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/primeday?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">full sale lineup at Amazon</a>.</p><div title="6532971 - Unlocked iPhones - Amazon Renewed P (Prime Day)" data-embed-type="buylink" data-ref-id="3827" data-template="4" data-size="buylink__listicle" data-title="6532971 - Unlocked iPhones - Amazon Renewed P (Prime Day)" data-collection="">             <h2>                    <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0BY77JM8T?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/dp\/B0BY77JM8T?tag=gamespot-primeday-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0BY77JM8T?tag=gamespot-primeday-20">iPhone SE 3rd Gen</a>       </h2>                                   <h3>                      <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0BY77JM8T?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/dp\/B0BY77JM8T?tag=gamespot-primeday-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0BY77JM8T?tag=gamespot-primeday-20">$194 (was $260)</a>         </h3>                                                                                                                      <p>Is the iPhone SE outclassed by Apple's other devices? Absolutely. But is it still some of your best bang-for-buck value? Double-yes. This is the perfect first smartphone, especially if you want to gift your kids with something that you can use to stay in touch with them and not worry about breaking the bank. For its size and price it has an above-average screen, decent battery-life, and TouchID for added security, as well as an adequate camera. </p>                      </div><h2>Shop all Prime Day Deals at Amazon</h2><hr><div data-embed-type="pinbox" data-ref-id="4304">  <ul>                              <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-criterion-collection-best-movie-deals-amazon-blu-ray-sale/1100-6532794/">The Criterion Collection 50% Off Movie Sale - Here Are The Best Deals</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/little-nightmares-3-preorder-guide-amazon-exclusive-edition-bonuses-release-date/1100-6532712/">Little Nightmares 3 Amazon-Exclusive Mirror Edition Is Up For Preorder</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/legos-first-visual-history-for-adults-is-60-off-in-early-prime-day-deal/1100-6532717/">Lego's First Visual History For Adults Is 60% Off In Early Prime Day Deal</a></li>                          <li>         <span>+ Show More More Gaming, Tech, and Entertainment Deals &amp; Preorders Links (5)</span>       </li>          <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/rune-factory-guardians-of-azuma-earth-dancer-limited-edition-nintendo-switch-2-restock/1100-6526172/">Amazon Restocks Rune Factory: Guardians Of Azuma Earth Dancer Edition</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/all-four-discontinued-donkey-kong-lego-sets-restocked-at-amazon/1100-6532560/">All Four Discontinued Donkey Kong Lego Sets Restocked At Amazon</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/death-stranding-2-on-the-beach-collector-edition-launch-buying-guide/1100-6530003/">Death Stranding 2 Collector's Edition Is In Stock Ahead Of Tomorrow's Launch</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/donkey-kong-bananza-preorder-nintendo-switch-2/1100-6530595/">Donkey Kong Bananza Game &amp; Amiibo Bundle Available At Walmart</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/marvel-spider-man-magic-the-gathering-trading-card-restock-amazon-preorder/1100-6529819/">Marvel's Spider-Man Magic: The Gathering Preorders Restocked At Amazon</a></li>   </ul> </div>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article>

    
  

</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/unlocked-iphones-are-hundreds-of-dollars-off-at-amazon-for-prime-day/1100-6532971/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokémon Anime Voice Actor James Carter Cathcart Passes Away]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/07/pokemon-anime-voice-actor-james-carter-cathcart-passes-away</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pok%C3%A9mon-anime-voice-actor-james-carter-cathcart-passes-away.1241091/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>He voiced multiple iconic characters</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure><a title="Pokémon" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/85dda83b216f8/pokemon.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: The Pokémon Company</em></figcaption></figure><p>Pokémon fans and the voice acting community are this week mourning the loss of James Carter Cathcart, who has passed away at the age of 71.</p>
<p>Cathcart was known for not only voicing characters like Gary Oak, but also Professor Oak and Team Rocket's James and Meowth later in his career. He also worked on other series like Yu-Gi-Oh! (Weevil Underwood) and Sonic the Hedgehog (Vector).</p>
<p>Voice actor Erica Schroeder <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DL7dvZ8OAmN/?igsh=MWR6MHU0c2c4eXAxNQ%3D%3D">confirmed his passing on social media</a>, noting how he was "one of the most joyful, exuberant, kind-hearted and talented souls" and a master of the "pen, piano and microphone".</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"Rest in peace dear sweet man. I will miss you. The community will miss you. The world will miss you. One of the most joyful, exuberant, kind-hearted and talented souls no longer walks with us. James Carter Cathcart you were one of a kind, a gentle, beautiful, playful genius and I was happy to call you my friend.<br>
Master of the pen, piano and microphone. Friend to many. Loving father and husband. Thank you for your gifts."</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The Pokémon community has taken to social media to pay its respects with messages like the following being shared to honour Cathcart's life and career:</p>


<p>Cathcart called time on his voice acting career in 2023 after he was diagnosed with throat cancer, but was still able to lend his voice to the original Pokémon series’ finale, which aired in the same year.</p>
<p>On behalf of the community here at Nintendo Life, we extend our deepest sympathies to James' family and friends.</p>

<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/pokemon/related-articles:184872,170155 @ 1752217345 --></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://kotaku.com/pokemon-james-carther-cathcart-dies-meowth-gary-oak-1851786041" rel="noopener" href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-james-carther-cathcart-dies-meowth-gary-oak-1851786041">kotaku.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/pokemon/related-info/4c60441fe7a879ce1dc5cb98ba327381 @ 1752218070 --></div></article><div><p>Liam is a news writer and reviewer across Hookshot Media. He's been writing about games for more than 15 years and is a lifelong fan of many iconic video game characters.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Liam_Doolan"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/liamdoolan.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Liam_Doolan');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/07/pokemon-anime-voice-actor-james-carter-cathcart-passes-away]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dbrand says its new Switch 2 Joy-Con grips fix the detachment issue]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/704767/dbrand-switch-2-killswitch-joy-con-lock-grip-detachment-fixed</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dbrand-says-its-new-switch-2-joy-con-grips-fix-the-detachment-issue.1241076/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/jay-peters">Jay Peters</a> <span>is a news editor covering technology, gaming, and more. He joined The Verge in 2019 after nearly two years at Techmeme.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>After recently admitting that it had a “spectacularly terrible response” to Joy-Con grip detachment complaints with its Killswitch Nintendo Switch 2 case, Dbrand <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/dbrand/comments/1lwrl9q/joycon_detachment_update_part_3_we_fixed_it/">has some good news</a>: it says its redesigned Joy-Con grips fix the issue <em>and</em> the company will be able to mass produce them.</p><p>Dbrand had already promised it would be replacing the grips for everyone, and now we know that the replacement will be the redesign instead of a refined version of what’s already available. Here’s a video from Dbrand showing the Joy-Con not detaching while being held from the Joy-Con with the updated grips.</p><p>In addition to the modification to the Joy-Con grips — which Dbrand is calling Joy-Lock — the company says it will be sending out silicone friction pads to place on the Killswitch adapter for Nintendo’s dock to address “the issue of one-handed undocking on our Dock Adapter” and keep the adapter “snugly seated” on the dock.</p><p>By “early next week,” Dbrand says it will “share a production schedule that outlines when you’ll be able to claim your free Joy-Lock replacements, and when you can expect them to ship.” New production and any unshipped orders will include the Joy-Lock Grips and have the silicone friction pads preinstalled on the Dock Adapter.</p><p>In June, some users of the original Killswitch Switch 2 case found that if they held the console primarily by a Joy-Con while the case and grips were on, the controller <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/dbrand/comments/1lgav3g/i_love_my_killswitch_2_buttttttt/">would pop off</a> and the console would drop down. Probably not what you want to have happen to your brand-new Nintendo console.</p><p>Dbrand published a <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/dbrand/comments/1lhvtyw/killswitch_joycon_detachment_update/">lengthy post</a> about the issue where it argued that “nobody routinely holds their Switch 2 like this” and that Joy-Con detachment only happens if you hold the console in a very specific way. But many users compared that response to when Steve Jobs told people running into iPhone 4 reception issues to <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2010/TECH/mobile/06/25/iphone.problems.response/index.html">“just avoid holding it that way.”</a></p><p>The company soon after published <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/dbrand/comments/1ljlhwy/joycon_detachment_update_part_2_were_fixing_it/">a mea culpa post</a> where it said that “you should be allowed to hold it however the fuck you want, without detachment occurring” and outlined how it was working on two potential fixes: a slightly tweaked version of the original grip and the one with a bigger redesign.</p></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/news/704767/dbrand-switch-2-killswitch-joy-con-lock-grip-detachment-fixed]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ghost Of Yōtei Drops Predecessor's Samurai Combat To Make Atsu A Walking Arsenal]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ghost-of-yotei-drops-predecessors-samurai-combat-to-make-atsu-a-walking-arsenal/1100-6533101/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ghost-of-y%C5%8Dtei-drops-predecessors-samurai-combat-to-make-atsu-a-walking-arsenal.1241067/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6533101">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">As seen in the latest <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ghost-of-yotei-focused-state-of-play-start-time-how-to-watch-and-what-to-expect/1100-6533023/" data-ref-id="1100-6533023">State of Play</a>, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/ghost-of-yotei/" data-ref-id="5000-645132">Ghost of Yōtei</a> is changing things up when it comes to combat, opting to give protagonist Atsu far more tools and weapons than <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/ghost-of-tsushima/" data-ref-id="5000-474583">Ghost of Tsushima</a>'s Jin.</p><p dir="ltr">The State of Play gameplay deep dive describes Atsu as "no samurai or ninja" but a "lone wolf mercenary." The way she fights reflects this. Unlike Jin--who only relied on a few weapons to engage enemies in announced duels or assassinate foes from the shadows--Atsu can easily wade into open combat armed with a katana, spear, kusarigama, ōdachi, and dual swords, and then also wield a half bow, longbow, teppo, kunai, bombs, and blinding powder.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="1449791283" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6466057,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Ghost%20of%20Yotei%20-%20State%20of%20Play%20Announcement%20Trailer&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:57,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/ghost-of-yotei-state-of-play-announcement-trailer\/2300-6466057\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466057\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466057\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466057\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6466057&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;Publisher Asset&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4507239-11.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/8y1tth1k.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1749075900,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="8y1tth1k" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> Ghost of Yotei - State of Play Announcement Trailer</p>
      </div>
<p dir="ltr">The gameplay revealed a rock-paper-scissors system to Atsu's arsenal, describing certain weapons as hard counters to specific threats--the ōdachi is especially useful for dealing with large enemies, for example, and the dual swords trump spear-wielders. Tsushima had a similar system, but it centered around <em>stances</em>, not weapons. Jin could change his stance and how he held his katana in a fight, with different stances being more adept for handling certain foes.</p><p dir="ltr">It's still unclear whether Yōtei's new weapon system is a complete replacement for Tsushima's stance system, but they do seem to embody similar roles in gameplay, so it seems likely.</p><p dir="ltr">Along with all the new weapons, Atsu can also disarm foes and ally with other characters, including a mysterious wolf that accompanies her on her mission of revenge. We didn't see much of this in action, so it's not immediately clear how inviting allies along affects gameplay.</p><p dir="ltr">Presumably, we'll get another showcase that dives into Atsu's skills and tools when it comes to stealth, as well as what gameplay with allies looks like. But even if we don't, we don't have to wait all that long to see the full game in action. Ghost of Yōtei is set to launch for PlayStation 5 on October 2.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ghost-of-yotei-drops-predecessors-samurai-combat-to-make-atsu-a-walking-arsenal/1100-6533101/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Subnautica 2 Publisher Krafton Blames Leads for Delay in Statement, Saying They 'Abandoned Responsibilities']]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/subnautica-2-publisher-krafton-blames-leads-for-delay-in-statement-saying-they-abandoned-responsibilities</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/subnautica-2-publisher-krafton-blames-leads-for-delay-in-statement-saying-they-abandoned-responsibilities.1241055/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Per Krafton, the three removed executives allegedly would have been eligible for 90% of the $250 million bonus promised to staff.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">The ongoing drama around Subnautica 2's delay and its team's upheaval continues, with the company Krafton issuing a lengthy public statement today accusing the studio's leaders of having "abandoned responsibilities" on the game, alleging they focused on personal projects rather than fulfilling their contracted roles and suggesting the game's delay is their fault.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In the published statement sent to press, which we've reprinted in full below, Krafton claims it made "multiple requests" to Unknown Worlds founders Charlie Cleveland and Max McGuire to resume their responsibilities as game director and technical director respectively, but claims they both declined. "In particular, following the failure of Moonbreaker, KRAFTON asked Charlie to devote himself to the development of Subnautica 2. However, instead of participating in the game development, he chose to focus on a personal film project," the statement reads. "KRAFTON believes that the absence of core leadership has resulted in repeated confusion in direction and significant delays in the overall project schedule."</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Krafton also makes reference to a reported $250 million bonus that was promised to the development team, which would have paid out just a few months from now if it hit revenue targets. Per Krafton, 90% of this bonus was intended to go directly to Cleveland, McGuire, and former CEO Ted Gill prior to their removal from the project.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The statement concludes with Krafton promising "fair and equitable compensation for all remaining Unknown Worlds employees...and we reaffirm our commitment to provide the rewards they were promised."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The full content of the statement is as follows:</p><blockquote>To Our 12 Million Fellow Subnauts,</blockquote><blockquote>— <strong> Inevitable Leadership Change Driven by Project Abandonment–Despite Holding 90% of Earnout for Themselves</strong></blockquote><blockquote>First and foremost, we sincerely thank you for your continued support, passion, and unwavering dedication to Subnautica. We wish to provide clarity on the recent leadership changes at Unknown Worlds, a creative studio under KRAFTON.</blockquote><blockquote><strong>Background of Leadership Change</strong></blockquote><blockquote>KRAFTON deeply values Subnautica’s unique creativity and immersive world-building. To provide fans with even better gaming experiences, we acquired Unknown Worlds, fully committed to supporting Subnautica’s future success. We collaborated closely with the studio’s leadership, who were central to the creation of the original Subnautica, to foster the optimal environment for a successful Subnautica 2.</blockquote><blockquote>Specifically, in addition to the initial $500 million purchase price, we allocated approximately 90% of the up to $250 million earn-out compensation to the three former executives, with the expectation that they would demonstrate leadership and active involvement in the development of Subnautica 2.</blockquote><blockquote>However, regrettably, the former leadership abandoned the responsibilities entrusted to them. Subnautica 2 was originally planned for an Early Access launch in early 2024, but the timeline has since been significantly delayed. KRAFTON made multiple requests to Charlie and Max to resume their roles as Game Director and Technical Director, respectively, but both declined to do so. In particular, following the failure of Moonbreaker, KRAFTON asked Charlie to devote himself to the development of Subnautica 2. However, instead of participating in the game development, he chose to focus on a personal film project.</blockquote><blockquote>KRAFTON believes that the absence of core leadership has resulted in repeated confusion in direction and significant delays in the overall project schedule.</blockquote><blockquote>The current Early Access version also falls short in terms of content volume.</blockquote><blockquote>We are deeply disappointed by the former leadership’s conduct, and above all, we feel a profound sense of betrayal by their failure to honor the trust placed in them by our fans.</blockquote><blockquote><strong>KRAFTON’s Full Support for the Dedicated Development Team</strong></blockquote><blockquote>To uphold our commitment to provide you with the best possible gaming experience, we made the difficult yet necessary decision to change the executive leadership. Subnautica 2 has been and continues to be actively developed by a dedicated core team who share genuine passion, accountability, and commitment to the game. We deeply respect their expertise and creativity and will continue to provide full and unwavering support, enabling them to focus solely on delivering the exceptional game you deserve.</blockquote><blockquote><strong>KRAFTON’s Commitment to its Promises in Rewarding Employees</strong></blockquote><blockquote>Additionally, KRAFTON has committed to fair and equitable compensation for all remaining Unknown Worlds employees who have continuously and tirelessly contributed to Subnautica 2’s development. We believe that the dedication and effort of this team are at the very heart of Subnautica’s ongoing evolution, and we reaffirm our commitment to provide the rewards they were promised.</blockquote><blockquote>Fans will always remain at the center of every decision we make at KRAFTON. Moving forward, we promise transparent communication and continued efforts to sustainably develop and expand the beloved Subnautica universe.</blockquote><blockquote>Honoring your trust and expectations is a core tenet at KRAFTON. We are committed to repaying your patience with an even more refined and exceptional gaming experience.</blockquote><p data-cy="paragraph">Subnautica 2's <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/subnautica-2-developers-entire-leadership-team-replaced-in-shock-move-krafton-said-will-bring-renewed-energy-and-momentum">entire leadership team was replaced last week</a> with former Striking Distance CEO Steve Papoutsis by owner Krafton, and the game was delayed to 2026. The replacement came as a "shock" to Cleveland, who <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ousted-subnautica-2-developer-breaks-silence-after-shock-removal-to-find-that-im-no-longer-able-to-work-at-the-company-i-started-stings">claimed in a Reddit post shortly after his removal</a> that Subnautica 2 was "ready for early release", that the decision was "in Krafton's hands," and saying the decision to remove him and the other leaders "stings."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">This was followed by a <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/more-drama-in-the-murky-world-of-subnautica-2-as-official-delay-confirmation-comes-hot-on-the-heels-of-damaging-report-into-now-unlikely-250m-bonus">Bloomberg report</a> that alleged this decision was made just before the $250 million bonus was scheduled to be paid out to the team, with staff expecting bonuses ranging from hundreds of thousands of dollars to seven figures that they were now concerned they would not see. In a statement to IGN at the time, Krafton claimed the delay was a response to playtester feedback, and had nothing to do with "any contractual or financial considerations." In response to the removal of the three members of leadership and concerns about the denial of promised bonuses to staff, <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/subnautica/comments/1lvyc7f/do_not_buy_subnautica_2/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">fans have begun organizing boycotts of the game on social media</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Rebekah Valentine is a senior reporter for IGN. You can find her posting on BlueSky @duckvalentine.bsky.social. Got a story tip? Send it to rvalentine@ign.com.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/subnautica-2-publisher-krafton-blames-leads-for-delay-in-statement-saying-they-abandoned-responsibilities]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Here's How Trump's Cuts To Arts And Science Funding Have Affected Video Games]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/heres-how-trumps-cuts-to-arts-and-science-funding-have-affected-video-games/1100-6533100/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/heres-how-trumps-cuts-to-arts-and-science-funding-have-affected-video-games.1241052/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6533100">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Through its first seven months, the Trump Administration has made massive cuts to public spending that have affected nearly every area of American life, from weather reporting and disaster response to arts funding. Video games are no exception.</p><p>The administration's sweeping cuts have halted game preservation programs, virtual reality projects, and even game-related public health research. A report from <a dir="ltr" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/trump-funding-cuts-devastate-video-game-research-and-development" rel="noreferrer nofollow ">Game Developer</a> details some of the efforts affected by the lost funding, from the University of Washington's Game Research Group, which launched in 2024 to "improve the accessibility of critical video games in cultural heritage institutions for educational purposes," to a grant for a program at Arizona State University helping latinx students develop games about climate change.</p><p dir="ltr">Some projects had their funding removed just as they were about to complete. Rabindra Ratan, an associate professor at Michigan State, was developing a program to "reduce issues of Zoom fatigue and other types of gender and race inequities in the games industry related to virtual meetings." A $1.6 million grant from the National Science Foundation's Future of Work program enabled Ratan's work, but the Trump administration rescinded the grant earlier this year, preventing Ratan and his team from accessing the $200,000 they needed to complete the project.</p><p dir="ltr">Ratan and his crew had built a virtual meeting space, designed to be an effective alternative to Zoom. The platform is still accessible by the public, and Ratan intends to publicize more of the program's findings, but it will remain unfinished for the foreseeable future.</p><p dir="ltr">Other multi-media projects, like the virtual reality game Paccha, have been affected on multiple fronts. Paccha lets players explore the Peruvian Andes as a student archeologist. The loss of funding has halted collaborations with the San Antonio Museum of Art and with inhabitants and workers in the village of Hualcayan, where the game is set. The developers are now hunting for new places to get funding.</p><p dir="ltr">The video game industry helps drive technological development, exploration, and experimentation, Ratan said, so the cuts could have an impact that reaches beyond the games industry.</p><p dir="ltr">"By limiting research in this industry, it is limiting science as a whole," Ratan said. "There's a slightly more direct negative consequence here in hindering progress in the games industry, namely being that progress in the games industry leads to other industries."</p><p dir="ltr">You can read the full report at <a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/trump-funding-cuts-devastate-video-game-research-and-development" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Game Developer</a>, which goes into more detail about affected projects.</p><p dir="ltr">In other federal government news, the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fbi-seizes-prominent-nintendo-switch-piracy-site/1100-6533098/" data-ref-id="1100-6533098">FBI has seized a Nintendo Switch piracy site,</a> underlining the company's efforts against piracy.</p><p dir="ltr"><em>Image: Courtesy of The Strong, Rochester, New York</em></p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/heres-how-trumps-cuts-to-arts-and-science-funding-have-affected-video-games/1100-6533100/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sucker Punch Announces Ghost of Yōtei PlayStation 5 Bundles, Controllers, And Console Covers]]></title>
            <link>https://gameinformer.com/2025/07/10/sucker-punch-announces-ghost-of-yotei-playstation-5-bundles-controllers-and-console</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sucker-punch-announces-ghost-of-y%C5%8Dtei-playstation-5-bundles-controllers-and-console-covers.1241040/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p>Ghost of Yōtei is one of our most anticipated games of the year. <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/2025/07/10/ghost-of-yotei-has-new-director-modes-inspired-by-miike-and-watanabe-and-lots-lots-more">Thanks to today's State of Play livestream</a>, we learned a lot more about the game, including its new combat, its beautiful open world, its new director modes, and much more. The game looks like something special, and Sony is seemingly on the same page, opting to release two limited edition PlayStation 5 consoles on the same day as the game.</p><p height="360" width="640" url="https://www.youtube.com/embed/cgM6poO2JmY"><iframe width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/cgM6poO2JmY" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay" allowfullscreen="true">&nbsp;</iframe></p><p>There are two versions of the console. One has a white base with gold design across it, mimicking a Japanese art practice known as kintsugi, where cracked pottery is repaired with lacquer and gold, highlighting the fact that it shattered. It mirrors Atsu's onryō mask, which has seemingly undergone the same process. The bundle also includes a controller with a similar design. If the gold isn't to your taste, there's a white and black version instead, which is meant to mimic Sumi-e, an art style defined by brush strokes of black ink.</p><p>These bundles will include the disc drive version of the console along with a digital copy of Ghost of Yōtei Standard Edition, complete with pre-order content, an in-game mask, and seven PSN avatars of Atsu and each of the Yōtei Six.</p><p>If you already own a PlayStation 5 but still like the design, you can instead purchase console covers for the slim or pro models, which will be available on&nbsp;<a href="http://direct.playstation.com/">direct.playstation.com</a>. The covers, however, are not available for the base model PS5, and if you want the black covers, you'll have to buy a whole new console. Meanwhile, both versions of the controller will be available as a standalone purchase.</p><p>The PS5 bundles, controllers, console covers, and Ghost of Yōtei will all be available on October 2, later this year.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://gameinformer.com/2025/07/10/sucker-punch-announces-ghost-of-yotei-playstation-5-bundles-controllers-and-console]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ghost of Yōtei's gorgeous gameplay deep dive reveals refined combat, lo-fi beats mode, and more]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/ghost-of-yoteis-gorgeous-gameplay-deep-dive-reveals-refined-combat-lo-fi-beats-mode-and-more</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ghost-of-y%C5%8Dteis-gorgeous-gameplay-deep-dive-reveals-refined-combat-lo-fi-beats-mode-and-more.1241037/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>Ahead of October's release.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Sucker Punch/Sony</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
<a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/ghost-of-tsushima">Ghost of Tsushima</a>'s gorgeous PlayStation 5 sequel <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/ghost-of-yotei">Ghost of Yōtei</a> is inching ever-closer to release, and ahead of its October arrival, developer Sucker Punch has <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cgM6poO2JmY">shared its best look yet</a> at what the revenge-soaked open-world action-adventure will bring - including, it turns out, a lo-fi beats mode for a more soothing saunter through Ezo.
</p>
<p>
Ghost of Yōtei, of course, features a brand-new protagonist in Atsu, a "lone wolf mercenary" so single-minded in her mission to punish the Yōtei Six - the ruthless gang who slaughtered her family - she's believed to an Onryō (a Japanese spirit of vengeance) by the local people.
</p>
<p>
Atsu returns to Ezo after 16 years in the south as Sucker Punch's deep dive begins, travelling back to her childhood home in order to put the spirits of her family to rest. Here, she can revisit the "cherished times" of her youth, switching between the past and present at the push of a button, before venturing out across the stunning world in her relentless quest for blood.
</p>
<!-- code from Primis - Eurogamer.net - eurogamer.net -->
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<!-- code from Primis -->
<p>
And with each victory Atsu secures against the Yōtei Six, the more her renown grows, increasing the bounty on her head and leading to encounters with deadlier foes. But Atsu can also take on bounties of her own in order to make money and fuel her quest. Which brings us nicely onto Ghost of Yōtei's expanded combat.
</p>
<p>
Atsu can wield a katana, spear, kusarigama, odachi, or dual swords (and can switch between them on the fly) with each being uniquely effective against particular enemies. The odachi, for instance, is best used against massive enemies, and when opponents switch weapons, players will need to do the same in order to adapt - unleashing their dual swords, say, to better counter spears. All weapons feature their own upgrades to discover and master, and Atsu has access to ranged abilities too, including throwing weapons such as bombs and blinding powder.
</p>
<p>
As to how players can find themselves in these sorts of sticky situations, Sucker Punch says Ghost of Yōtei is more focused on player freedom than any of its other games, and there's a clue system - based on interrogating enemies and collecting new mission cards - that can take players everywhere from snow-covered heights to a landscape scarred by fire. But there's seemingly ample space for players to simply grab their spyglass, pick a point of interest, and forge their own path across Ezo, taking in its golden fields, shimmering lakes, swaying trees, and endless valleys of fallings leaves and rising mist.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Ghost of Yōtei - State of Play Gameplay Deep Dive | PS5 Games" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/cgM6poO2JmY?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Ghost of Yōtei - State of Play Gameplay Deep Dive | PS5 Games</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/cgM6poO2JmY?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/cgM6poO2JmY?autoplay=1" title="Ghost of Yōtei - State of Play Gameplay Deep Dive | PS5 Games">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Ghost of Yōtei - gameplay deep dive. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cgM6poO2JmY" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
Players might, for instance, stumble across Altars of Reflection. These provide Atsu with fresh inspiration and unlock new abilities - such as Perfect Parry and Disarm Counter - that'll help her on the journey ahead. Alternatively, players can buy travellers maps from a cartographer if they'd prefer to focus on forward momentum rather than languid exploration. Either way, they've the option to set up camp under the stars throughout their adventure, resting up, play shamisen, cooking, and preparing for the fight ahead. Camping also brings important characters and upgrades straight to players, replacing Ghost of Tsushima's journal with a system said to provide a "more character-driven way of managing allies and vendors", so you "don't have to leave where you're exploring, [because] the game comes to you".
</p>
<p>
Elsewhere in Sucker Punch's deep dive, there was talk about customisation and finding the right combination of armour, charms, and gear that works for different play-styles, be that the stealthy approach or a more melee-focused one. And of course armour and weapon appearances can be customised too, meaning you'll be able to look your best as you crank out Ghost of Yōtei's returning photo mode.
</p>
<p>
That's not the only returning feature, however; it's once again possible to select a Japanese voice track with full lip sync and subtitles from the beginning, if you want a more authentic representation of the samurai movies Sucker Punch's series is inspired by. And you can go even further with the returning Kurasowa mode, which emulates the legendary film director's movies with a distinctive black and white palette, film grain, audio filters, and increased wind.
</p>
<p>
Kurasowa isn't the only Japanese movie director being represented this time though. There's a new mode taking its cue from Ichi the Killer and Audition director Takashi Miike that puts the camera closer during combat for a "more intense, raw experience" that also features increased mud and blood splatter. Alternatively, you can opt for the mode created in conjunction with Cowboy Bebop director Shinichirō Watanabe. This is where the lo-fi beats come in, switching out Ghost of Tsushima's usual music in favour of more relaxed tunes created by Watanabe that play during exploration and combat.
</p>
<p>
And that's pretty much all we're getting for now. Ghost of Yōtei launches for PS5 on 2nd October, and it'll arrive alongside a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/two-limited-edition-ghost-of-yotei-ps5-bundles-with-designs-rooted-in-traditional-japanese-art-announced">newly announced limited edition console and controller</a>.
</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/ghost-of-yoteis-gorgeous-gameplay-deep-dive-reveals-refined-combat-lo-fi-beats-mode-and-more]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sucker Punch Dives Into New Ghost Of Yotei Gameplay Details, Reveals Limited Edition PS5 Consoles And Controllers]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/sucker-punch-ghost-of-yotei-gameplay-new-limited-edition-ps5-consoles-controllers/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sucker-punch-dives-into-new-ghost-of-yotei-gameplay-details-reveals-limited-edition-ps5-consoles-and-controllers.1241004/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Sucker Punch's creative directors, Nate Fox and Jason Connell, narrated a <a href="https://wccftech.com/ghost-of-yotei-july-state-of-play-gameplay-deep-dive/">State of Play</a> presentation today, dedicated entirely to Ghost of Yotei, which is due to release on PS5 and PS5 Pro this coming October 2, 2025. The presentation also revealed <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2025/07/10/first-look-ps5-ghost-of-yotei-limited-edition-console-designs/">two new limited edition PS5 consoles and matching controllers</a> for players to grab that will both release alongside the game in October.</p>



<p>The showcase delved into the game's gameplay, specifically focusing on exploration and combat, as well as showing off returning, and new game modes for players to experience the story. Kurosawa mode, for example, is back, and Sucker Punch is still striving to make playing Ghost of Yotei as close to playing an interactive classic samurai film as it was with Ghost of Tsushima. </p>



<p>To that end, Sucker Punch is also adding two new gameplay modes also named after Japanese directors Shinichirō Watanabe and Takashi Miike. The former adds a lo-fi soundtrack crafted by Watanabe himself that will play while you explore the game world. The latter brings the camera in closer to Atsu, and increases the amount of blood and mud splatter you see on screen. And of course, Kurosawa mode makes everything appear black and white, to emulate his famous films.</p>



<p>You'll also be able to play the game with full Japanese voice acting, and thankfully, with proper tracking from characters when choosing to play with Japanese voices. While Ghost of Tsushima also had Japanese voice acting available, characters' mouths still moved as if they were speaking their lines in English. It's a relief that Sucker Punch has not repeated this mistake with Ghost of Yotei. </p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Ghost of Yōtei - State of Play Gameplay Deep Dive | PS5 Games" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/cgM6poO2JmY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>Gameplay-wise, there are a few notable changes from Ghost of Tsushima, though at the same time it looks fairly familiar. Atsu's expanded arsenal of weapons, for example, have seemingly replaced the different stances you would switch between in Ghost of Tsushima. Atsu is able to wield a single katana, dual katanas, a very large katana called an odachi, a spear, and a kurisagama. She also has a few ranged options, such as throwable kunai, a bow and arrow, and a rifle. </p>



<p>You can switch from one weapon to another on the fly, just like you could switch stances in Ghost of Tsushima, with different weapons being better suited for different situations, depending on the type of enemy you're up against. A large enemy, for example, is best handled with the odachi. If you're facing someone with a spear, then Sucker Punch recommends swapping to dual swords.</p>



<p>Sucker Punch also stressed that Atsu is not like Jin. She's not a samurai and is not bound by any moral code. She's a mercenary on a path for revenge, with the goal of killing a group of warriors known as the Yotei Six, who brutally murdered her family. She'll use whatever she can to gain the upper hand on her path, including disarming her enemies entirely. However, if you're not careful, you can also be disarmed, which adds a significant wrinkle and a bit of a new challenge to combat that's not in Ghost of Tsushima. </p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Ghost of Yōtei - Limited Edition PS5 Bundles &amp; Accessories" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/tpy0vfXXnd8?start=1&amp;feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>The biggest gameplay changes and evolutions seem to be in the game's exploration, as both Fox and Connell stress that Ghost of Yotei is not looking to rush you through anything. You pick up clues towards quests and where to go next through a card system that helps you keep track of everything. </p>



<p>You'll also be able to stop and camp out in the wilderness to cook yourself a meal and rest along your journey, and it is while you're camping out that you'll meet new NPCs who appear as travellers asking you to share your fire. These NPCs are vendors and characters you can come back to who can potentially have a quest to give you, a specific weapon upgrade, or lead you to unlocking a unique ability.</p>



<p>These companions also include the wolf that debuted alongside Atsu, who also helps her in combat. It's unclear if the other companions you'll meet along the journey can join you in combat. There are also new kinds of side quests, like bounty hunting, that you can do to earn some cash along your journey. Atsu will also have a bounty on her head as you play, which will increase the more your legend grows.</p>



<p>Regarding her legend, beyond the fact that Atsu is on a path of revenge, the one area the presentation didn't dive into was the game's story. We did get a cool look at how you can swap between the past and the present when returning to Atsu's home, showing how it was before and after her family was attacked, but it wasn't clear if that's a feature you can use anywhere in your journey, or if it is limited to the area of her family's home.</p>



<p>Overall, the presentation showed that Sucker Punch is on track to deliver a stunning follow-up to Ghost of Tsushima with Ghost of Yotei, that is somehow more colorful and cinematic this time around. Hopefully, the final game can live up to expectations when it arrives this October.</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/sucker-punch-ghost-of-yotei-gameplay-new-limited-edition-ps5-consoles-controllers/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Some Switch 2 accessories and upgraded games are on sale for Prime Day]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/tech/704317/amazon-prime-day-best-nintendo-switch-2-accessories-game-deals-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/some-switch-2-accessories-and-upgraded-games-are-on-sale-for-prime-day.1240998/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="__next"><p><a href="#content"><span>Skip to main content</span></a></p><nav aria-label="Sticky Nav"></nav><div><main id="content"><article><div><div><div><p><span><ul><li><a href="https://www.theverge.com/tech">Tech</a></li></ul></span></p></div><div><p>Some of our favorite screen protectors, cases, and upgraded Switch titles are discounted during Prime Day.</p></div></div><div><p>Some of our favorite screen protectors, cases, and upgraded Switch titles are discounted during Prime Day.</p><div><p><span><time datetime="2025-07-10T21:30:00+00:00">Jul 10, 2025, 9:30 PM UTC</time></span></p></div></div></div><div><div><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/cameron-faulkner">Cameron Faulkner</a> <span>is an editor covering deals and commerce. He joined in 2018, and served as commerce editor at Polygon until May 2025.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>The <a href="https://www.theverge.com/nintendo/686603/nintendo-switch-2-review">Nintendo Switch 2</a> is <em>not </em>discounted for <a href="https://www.theverge.com/tech/689359/amazon-prime-day-tech-deals-guide-2025">Prime Day</a>. Just getting that out of the way. The fastest-selling console ever came out on June 5th, and only <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/701385/amazon-nintendo-switch-2-listings">just hit Amazon’s storefront</a> for reservation a couple of days ago. Nevertheless, I thought it’d be fun to share some Prime Day deals I found on Switch 2 accessories and games that have been patched to run better on the new console. Whether you already have a Switch 2 or you’ll be getting one soon, there are some great money-saving opportunities below (ones that I wish I had a couple of weeks ago).</p><div><div data-product-filter=""><p><span>$<!-- -->30</span></p><div><p>This hard case has a soft touch and a slim fit, and includes a flap that can hold up to 12 cartridges as it protects the console’s screen.</p></div></div><div data-product-filter=""><p><span>$<!-- -->25</span></p><div><p>The official Nintendo Switch 2 webcam is expensive, so we suggest getting this cheaper Logitech 1080p model instead.</p></div></div><div data-product-filter=""><p><span>$<!-- -->10</span></p><div><p>For when you want to wire in when you’re on-the-go (and away from the dock), I can verify that this model works with the Switch 2.</p></div></div><div data-product-filter=""><p><span>$<!-- -->63</span></p><div><p>For something cheaper — and in some ways better — than Nintendo’s official Pro controller, there’s 8BitDo’s Ultimate 2, which works with the original Switch and Switch 2.</p></div></div><div data-product-filter=""><p><span>$<!-- -->50</span></p><div><p>While I haven’t tried it yet, many report that the Switch 2 works nearly perfectly with this model. I say “nearly” because apparently the exposed Joy-Con 2 pins rub against the controller a bit, which may worry some.</p></div></div><div data-product-filter=""><p><span>$<!-- -->95</span></p><div><p>While its 100W top charging speed is overkill for the Switch 2, this 25,000mAh battery contains multiple recharges for the console, as well as some of your other gadgets.</p></div></div><div data-product-filter=""><p><span>$<!-- -->8</span></p><div><p>You really should protect your Switch 2’s screen. These glossy glass covers are easy to install, and let the full glow of the screen shine through.</p></div></div><div data-product-filter=""><p><span>$<!-- -->12</span></p><div><p>While equally protective as glossy protectors, these anti-glare matte covers tone down reflections, but in doing so, they slightly tone down how vibrant colors appear.</p></div></div><div data-product-filter=""><p><span>$<!-- -->40</span></p><div><p><em>Splatoon 3</em> is one of a handful of original Switch games to get a free update that drastically enhances visual quality as well as frame rate. It’s the way the game was always meant to be experienced.</p></div></div><div data-product-filter=""><p><span>$<!-- -->40</span></p><div><p>2017’s <em>Super Mario Odyssey</em> is timeless, even more so with the Switch 2 update that makes the game run at higher resolution with HDR enabled.</p></div></div></div><div><form><div><h2>Verge Deals</h2><p><span>Sign up for Verge Deals to get deals on products we’ve tested sent to your inbox weekly.</span></p></div></form></div></div></div></article></main></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/tech/704317/amazon-prime-day-best-nintendo-switch-2-accessories-game-deals-2025]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ghost of Yotei – State of Play ‘Gameplay Deep Dive’, PlayStation 5 Limited Edition consoles announced]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/07/ghost-of-yotei-state-of-play-gameplay-deep-dive-playstation-5-limited-edition-consoles-announced</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ghost-of-yotei-%E2%80%93-state-of-play-%E2%80%98gameplay-deep-dive%E2%80%99-playstation-5-limited-edition-consoles-announced.1240986/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Over 20 minutes of new footage.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Sony Interactive Entertainment [5,024 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sony-group-corporation/sony-interactive-entertainment">Sony Interactive Entertainment</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Sucker Punch Productions [152 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sony-group-corporation/sony-interactive-entertainment/sucker-punch-productions">Sucker Punch Productions</a> shared 20 minutes of gameplay for <a title="Games > Ghost of Yotei [4 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/ghost-of-yotei">Ghost of Yotei</a>, as well as <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2025/07/10/first-look-ps5-ghost-of-yotei-limited-edition-console-designs/" target="_blank">announced</a> two <a title="Platforms > PS5 [9,884 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a> <em>Ghost of Yotei</em> Limited Edition bundles, during a dedicated State of Play broadcast. The console covers and the DualSense controllers included with the bundles will also be available as separate purchases. <span id="more-978196"></span></p><p>Here are the details:</p><blockquote><p><strong>■ Console Bundles</strong></p><p>The PlayStation 5 Console – <em>Ghost of Yotei</em> Gold Limited Edition Bundle will be available globally, and is inspired by the Japanese art form, kintsugi, a traditional process to repair broken ceramics with lacquer and gold. The design captures the essence and aesthetic of kintsugi, symbolizing beauty in imperfection and mirroring Atsu’s own personal journey of healing and resilience amidst the adversities she’ll face along the way.</p><p>The PlayStation 5 Console – <em>Ghost of Yotei</em> Black Limited Edition Bundle will be exclusively available at direct.playstation.com*. This version draws inspiration from another Japanese traditional art form, Sumi-e, which is the use of black ink on paintings. Expressing the landmarks of Ezo through bold black brush strokes, this design captures the essence of the land’s beauty and mystery, while echoing Atsu’s inner struggle and journey towards redemption.</p><p>Both bundles come with a matching DualSense wireless controller, featuring a striking silhouette of Atsu on the DualSense touchpad.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>We’re proud of these fantastic designs from the teams at Sucker Punch, which were made in close collaboration with the design team at Sony Interactive Entertainment. Sucker Punch shared with us why they decided to pursue these unique forms of art:</p><p>“Our inspiration for this design came straight from one of the core aspects within the game: a deep focus on exploration,” said&nbsp;<em>Ghost of Yotei</em> creative director Jason Connell. “This includes the hand-drawn icons Atsu marks on her map, a kintsugi-style effect pulled from her Ghost mask, and brushstrokes reminiscent of her Sumi-e paintings. The towering Mount Yotei is included at the center of the console design to pull it all together, and Atsu is spotlighted on the DualSense controller. Each of these elements were thoughtfully woven into both the console and controller designs.”</p><p>The PlayStation 5 Console – <em>Ghost of Yotei</em> Limited Edition Bundles include a limited edition PlayStation 5 console with disc drive, matching DualSense wireless controller, and a digital copy of <em>Ghost of Yotei</em> Standard Edition that includes pre-order content, featuring a unique in-game mask, as well as a set of seven PSN avatars featuring concept art of Atsu and each member of the Yotei Six.</p><p><strong>■ Accessories</strong></p><p>If you already own a PlayStation 5 (model group – slim) or PlayStation 5 Pro console, we have great news for you, too. You’ll be able to purchase Console Covers for PlayStation 5 (model group – slim) and PlayStation 5 Pro – <em>Ghost of Yotei</em> Gold Limited Edition—directly from <a title="Platforms > PlayStation [48,002 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation">PlayStation</a> where direct.playstation.com is available* and in limited quantities in other regions through select online retailers. Both console covers feature the same kintsugi inspired designs and maker’s seal found on The PlayStation 5 Console – <em>Ghost of Yotei</em> Gold Limited Edition Bundle.</p><p>Both designs of the DualSense Wireless Controller – <em>Ghost of Yotei</em> Limited Edition will also be available as a standalone purchase.</p><p>We recognize the importance of capturing the essence from which <em>Ghost of Yotei</em> draws its inspiration, and we hope players deeply feel this influence through these designs as they experience the game. We can’t wait for you to follow the wind again and experience Atsu’s journey when <em>Ghost of Yotei</em> releases on October 2.</p><p><strong>■&nbsp;<em>Ghost of Yotei</em> Limited Edition Bundle and Accessories Purchase Information</strong></p><p><strong><em>Ghost of Yotei</em> Gold Limited Edition PlayStation 5 Console Bundle and Accessories</strong></p><ul><li>PlayStation 5 Console – <em>Ghost of Yotei</em> Gold Limited Edition Bundle<ul><li>Available globally at select retailers and <a href="https://direct.playstation.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PlayStation Direct</a>.</li></ul></li><li>PlayStation 5 (model group – slim) Console Covers – <em>Ghost of Yotei</em> Gold Limited Edition<ul><li>Available at <a href="https://direct.playstation.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PlayStation Direct</a>&nbsp;and select retailers outside of these regions.</li></ul></li><li>PlayStation 5 Pro Console Covers – <em>Ghost of Yotei</em> Gold Limited Edition<ul><li>Available at <a href="https://direct.playstation.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PlayStation Direct</a> and select retailers outside of these regions</li></ul></li><li>DualSense Wireless Controller – <em>Ghost of Yotei</em> Gold Limited Edition<ul><li>Available globally at select retailers and <a href="https://direct.playstation.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PlayStation Direct</a>.</li></ul></li></ul><p><strong><em>Ghost of Yotei</em> Black Limited Edition PlayStation 5 Console Bundle and DualSense Wireless Controller</strong></p><ul><li>PlayStation 5 Console – <em>Ghost of Yotei</em> Black Limited Edition Bundle<ul><li>Available exclusively at <a href="https://direct.playstation.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PlayStation Direct</a>.</li></ul></li><li>DualSense Wireless Controller – <em>Ghost of Yotei</em> Black Limited Edition<ul><li>Available at <a href="https://direct.playstation.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PlayStation Direct</a>. Also available at select retailers in Japan.</li></ul></li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch the State of Play and a trailer for the console bundles below.</p><h2><span>State of Play</span></h2><p><iframe title="Ghost of Yōtei - State of Play Gameplay Deep Dive | PS5 Games" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/cgM6poO2JmY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><span>Limited Edition Bundles and Accessories Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Ghost of Yōtei - Limited Edition PS5 Bundles &amp; Accessories" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/tpy0vfXXnd8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/07/ghost-of-yotei-state-of-play-gameplay-deep-dive-playstation-5-limited-edition-consoles-announced]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>