<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 15:44:22 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Monster Hunter Wilds Open Beta Extended After PSN Outage]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/monster-hunter-wilds-open-beta-extended</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/monster-hunter-wilds-open-beta-extended-after-psn-outage.1104948/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/monster-hunter-wilds-open-beta-extended<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Capcom has announced that the upcoming second week of February's&nbsp;<em>Monster Hunter Wilds&nbsp;</em>open beta will be extended thanks to a recent PSN outage that saw many unable to log into PlayStation's online services.</p>

<p>In a <a href="https://x.com/monsterhunter/status/1888907040879485237" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">message</a> on X, Capcom says the open beta period, which is <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/second-monster-hunter-wilds-open-beta" rel="nofollow">set to begin on February 13th</a> (or 14th depending on your timezone), will be extended by 24 hours. That means it'll now be coming to an end on either February 17th or 18th, again dependent on timezone.</p>

<p>If you're a PC or Xbox player, don't worry; the open beta has been extended across all platforms, so even if you weren't directly affected by the outage, you'll still be able to enjoy the game for an extra day.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/monster-hunter-wilds-open-beta-extended-fleeing.jpg?itok=IrkoceCC 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/monster-hunter-wilds-open-beta-extended-fleeing.jpg?itok=DgdAHT5k 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Monster Hunter Wilds</em>' open beta has been extended by a day.</figcaption></figure><p>As well as the extension itself, Capcom has also <a href="https://x.com/monsterhunter/status/1888907223285256244" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">confirmed</a> that the rewards you'll get for participating in the open beta will remain available for the additional day, so you don't need to miss out on those.</p>

<p>The PSN outage to which Capcom is referring <a href="https://www.techradar.com/news/live/playstation-network-outage-february-2025-live" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">began on Friday evening</a> (Eastern time) and was resolved the following day, meaning PSN was unavailable for around a 24-hour period.</p>

<p>Sony hasn't revealed the reason behind the outage, simply putting it down to an "operational issue" in an apologetic <a href="https://x.com/AskPlayStation/status/1888454556125708758" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">message on X</a>.</p>

<p>If you're a PlayStation Plus member, then you'll be getting an extra five days of subscription by way of apology. Non-PS Plus members don't get anything, but it looks like it doesn't matter which tier you're subscribed to, at least.</p>




<p>As for&nbsp;<em>Monster Hunter Wilds</em>, it's the upcoming next major installment in the&nbsp;<em>Monster Hunter&nbsp;</em>series. The game will see you sally forth into the Forbidden Lands to investigate rumors of a mysterious monster attacking villages.</p>

<p>Along the way, you will, of course, hunt and kill plenty of monsters, collecting unique gear and discovering a deep ecosystem as you go.</p>

<p><em>Monster Hunter Wilds&nbsp;</em>launches for <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2246340/Monster_Hunter_Wilds/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC</a>, <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-us/games/monster-hunter-wilds/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PS5</a>, and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/monster-hunter-wilds/9NMT6XFN0LVD" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Xbox Series X|S</a> on February 28th. You can check out our <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/monster-hunter-wilds-preview-wildly-impressive" rel="nofollow">preview of the game here</a> to find out how it's shaping up.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sony Gives Out Free PS Plus Days But Fails To Explain Mysterious PlayStation Network Outage]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/psn-down-outage-why-free-ps-plus-gift-sony-ps5-1851759274</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sony-gives-out-free-ps-plus-days-but-fails-to-explain-mysterious-playstation-network-outage.1104945/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/psn-down-outage-why-free-ps-plus-gift-sony-ps5-1851759274<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="5471f10c07ec8088ee2fb43f4c6d7aee" data-recommend-id="image://5471f10c07ec8088ee2fb43f4c6d7aee" data-format="jpg" data-width="1088" data-height="612" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A Helldiver holds up a flag to celebrate. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A Helldiver holds up a flag to celebrate. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Arrowhead Game Studios</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="5471f10c07ec8088ee2fb43f4c6d7aee" data-recommend-id="image://5471f10c07ec8088ee2fb43f4c6d7aee" data-format="jpg" data-width="1088" data-height="612" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A Helldiver holds up a flag to celebrate. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>The PlayStation Network <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/psn-playstation-network-login-servers-error-login-ps5-1851758731&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/psn-playstation-network-login-servers-error-login-ps5-1851758731">has been back up and running</a></span> for a bit now, after a major outage took PlayStation 5 and PS4's online features offline for roughly 24 hours at the end of last week. To make up for the extended downtime, Sony is  offering every  paying PS Plus member a small but free extension of their existing subscription.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="197298" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Live Forever in the Universe of 'New World: Aeternum'" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="108" data-playlist="197298,197284,197260" data-current="197298"><div><p>Live Forever in the Universe of 'New World: Aeternum'</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"></video></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>“We apologize for the inconvenience and thank the community for their patience,” Sony <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/AskPlayStation/status/1888454556125708758&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/AskPlayStation/status/1888454556125708758" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">posted</a></span> on X on February 9, the morning after PSN came back online. “All PlayStation Plus members will automatically receive an additional 5 days of service.” It appears this make-good should be added  directly to players’ accounts and push back their renewal dates by nearly a week. </p><p>It’s a nice little gesture but it still doesn’t address why PSN suffered one of the longest outages in the service’s history over the weekend. The pervasiveness of the problems, across multiple continents and PSN features like accounts and the PlayStation Store, seemed to point to some sort of significant malfunction.</p><h2 id="h650814"><a id=""></a>Why was PSN down for 24 hours?</h2><p>Sony’s explanation for what happened is strangely brief and vague. “Network services have fully recovered from an operational issue,” the company <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/AskPlayStation/status/1888454556125708758&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/AskPlayStation/status/1888454556125708758" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">posted</a></span> on February 9. There was no further detail about what that operational issue was or whether it might pop back up at some point.</p><p>Sony’s description of the issues prior to solving them was similarly limited. “We are aware some users might be currently experiencing issues with PSN,” is all the company wrote for the 24 hours that PSN was down, as thousands of players <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/psn-down-playstation-network-outage-reactions-ps5-1851758856&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/psn-down-playstation-network-outage-reactions-ps5-1851758856">aired their frustrations and demanded more information</a></span> across social media and Reddit. Imagine Netflix being down for an entire day with an explanation that basically amounted to, “Well that was weird, but hey we’re back!”</p><p>Because the duration of the interrupted service recalled the infamous PSN outage of 2011 which arose from a malicious hack, some fans were worried that something similar might have happened this time as well, even taking the step of preemptively changing their PSN login information in case their accounts had been compromised. Fortunately, that doesn’t appear to have been the case this time around. Hopefully, the outage remains a blip and PlayStation Network service continues without future problems. </p><p>.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Take-Two CEO Talks GTA 6 Not Coming To PC At Launch]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/take-two-ceo-talks-gta-6-not-coming-to-pc-at-launch/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/take-two-ceo-talks-gta-6-not-coming-to-pc-at-launch.1104942/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/take-two-ceo-talks-gta-6-not-coming-to-pc-at-launch/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Grand Theft Auto (GTA 6) is likely coming to PC, it’s just a matter of when. In a new interview with IGN, Take-Two CEO Strauss Zelnick was asked about the game coming to the platform and the decision to not launch on what he calls an “important part” of the business.</p>



<p>In the <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/take-two-boss-unconcerned-by-plummeting-ps5-and-xbox-sales-insists-gta-6-will-cause-a-meaningful-uptick-in-console-sales-in-2025?utm_source=threads,twitter" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">interview</a>, Zelnick says, usually, Take-Two’s strategy has not been to release on all platforms at once. Instead, he says, it would start with a console or two before branching out. With GTA 6, that plan appears to be no different as there is a focus on moving more PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series systems with the game’s release.</p>



<p>“When you have a big title in the market and we have many of them coming, historically that has sold consoles,” Zelnick said while also mentioning that it’s not always the case to not release on all platforms at once. He pointed to Civilization 7 as an example of a full multi-platform release that includes PC and Nintendo Switch.</p>



<h6 id="h-podcast-gta-6-still-on-track-for-2025-insider-gaming-weekly-podcast">PODCAST: <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/gta-6-still-on-track-for-2025-insider-gaming-weekly-podcast/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">GTA 6 Still On Track For 2025: Insider Gaming Weekly Podcast</a></h6>



<p>Regarding PC launches, specifically, Zelnick says that the company knows how big the market it. According to the Take-Two boss, PC versions of a game can result in up to 40% of a game’s total sales.  It’s not something that’s lost on him.</p>



<p>“We have seen PC become a much more and more important part of what used to be a console business, and I wouldn’t be surprised to see that trend continue,” he said. </p>



<p>GTA 6 is currently scheduled to launch this fall on PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X|S. The latest update on the game still being on track  sent Take-Two <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/take-two-stock-hits-all-time-high-after-gta-6-update/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">stock to an all-time high</a>.</p>



<p>When do you think GTA 6 will come to PC? Let us know in the comments or on our new&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/resistance-4-was-pitched-by-insomniac-but-playstation-turned-it-down/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Sony turning down the Resistance 4&nbsp;pitch</a>.&nbsp;Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Monster Hunter Wilds Open Beta Week Extended Due To PSN Outage]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/monster-hunter-wilds-open-beta-week-extended-due-to-psn-outage/1100-6529350/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/monster-hunter-wilds-open-beta-week-extended-due-to-psn-outage.1104936/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/monster-hunter-wilds-open-beta-week-extended-due-to-psn-outage/1100-6529350/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529350">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Capcom has announced that it is extending the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/next-monster-hunter-wilds-open-beta-features-flagship-monster/1100-6529269/" data-ref-id="1100-6529269">second open beta test</a> for Monster Hunter Wilds on all platforms as a result of PlayStation Network being down this past weekend.</p><p>In a statement, Capcom said, "Hunters, we're pleased to confirm that due to the PlayStation Network outage that occurred during the first week of OBT2, we're extending the second week of OBT2 by +24 hours on all platforms!"</p><p>The second weekend of the open beta test will start at the normal time, February 13 at 7 PM PT / 10 PM ET. However, the open beta's end time has been extended by a full 24 hours, meaning that it will now ends on February 18 at 6:59 PM PT / 9:59 PM ET.</p><div data-embed-type="tweet" data-src="https://x.com/monsterhunter/status/1888907040879485237?s=46" data-has-image="true"><blockquote data-conversation="none" data-mce-disable-toolbar="true"><p dir="ltr">Hunters, we're pleased to confirm that due to the PlayStation Network outage that occurred during the first week of OBT2, we're extending the second week of OBT2 by +24 hours on all platforms!<br>New period:<br>Feb. 13, 7pm PT / Feb. 14, 3am GMT – Feb. 17, 6:59 pm PT / Feb. 18, 2:59… <a href="https://t.co/i0jTHjYHyx" rel="nofollow ">pic.twitter.com/i0jTHjYHyx</a></p>  — Monster Hunter (@monsterhunter) <a href="https://twitter.com/monsterhunter/status/1888907040879485237?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 10, 2025</a></blockquote>              </div><p>This upcoming session will have the same content as the session this past weekend. Players will be able to hunt game's flagship monster the Arkveld, also known as the White Wraith.</p><p>Players will also be able to access the training area, as well as create a private lobbies in order to hunt with specific people. Online single player mode will be available too, which allows players to play solo without joining a lobby.</p><p>Characters created in the open beta tests can be carried over to the full version of the game once it releases on February 28, 2025 for PC, PS5, and Xbox Series X|S. There will be a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/monster-hunter-wilds-console-details-revealed-ps5-pro-support-will-be-in-day-one-patch/1100-6528576/" data-ref-id="1100-6528576">day-one patch to implement PS5 Pro support</a>, and for more on the PC version, be sure to check out the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/monster-hunter-wilds-gets-pc-benchmark-tool-see-how-your-system-stacks-up/1100-6529248/" data-ref-id="1100-6529248">new system-benchmark test first</a>.</p><p>Last Friday, February 7, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/psn-is-down/1100-6529341/" data-ref-id="1100-6529341">PSN went down for nearly 24 hours</a> and Sony stated that it was due to an "operational issue." For compensation, Sony gave all PlayStation Plus members an additional five days of service.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/115776530127739146123?rel=author">George Yang</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bubble Ghost Remake Reimagines a Retro Platforming Classic in March]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/bubble-ghost-remake-release-date</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/bubble-ghost-remake-reimagines-a-retro-platforming-classic-in-march.1104915/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/bubble-ghost-remake-release-date<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Developer Nakama Game Studio and publisher SelectaPlay have announced a release date for&nbsp;<em>Bubble Ghost Remake</em>, a reimagined version of the cult classic 1987 platformer.</p>

<p>Launching on March 27th,&nbsp;<em>Bubble Ghost Remake&nbsp;</em>offers a "reimagined, visually captivating gameplay experience" largely based on the 1987 original, although it'll also boast a host of new features to bring it up to speed with modern gaming standards.</p>

<p>These features include new game modes, boss battles, and collectibles, as well as "many more surprises". It sounds like you'll have to play&nbsp;<em>Bubble Ghost Remake&nbsp;</em>yourself if you want to find out what those surprises are.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/bubble-ghost-remake-release-date-level.jpg?itok=ILBGCzH0 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/bubble-ghost-remake-release-date-level.jpg?itok=yLkhiMU1 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Bubble Ghost Remake&nbsp;</em>offers a fresh take on a classic platformer.</figcaption></figure><p><em>Bubble Ghost Remake</em>'s Story mode will offer over 40 levels to play through, each of which promise "hours of entertainment and challenge", according to the developers.</p>

<p>If you don't fancy playing through the game with its narrative trappings intact, you can instead opt for the Arcade mode, and Challenge and Speedrun modes are available if you're the kind of person who likes to test themselves to their limits.</p>

<p>These aren't the aforementioned surprises, though; Nakama Game Studio promises further game modes you can unlock "for an even more thrilling gameplay experience".</p>

<p>Naturally, the game will feature revamped graphics and sound when compared to its bleepy-bloopy 80s counterpart, and you can also look forward to in-game achievements, so if you're playing the Switch version, you don't have to miss out on that sweet dopamine hit.</p>




<p>As well as the digital versions, <i>Bubble Ghost Remake&nbsp;</i>will also be available as a physical release. In North America, you'll be able to get the standard version, but there's also an EU-exclusive Collector's Edition for Switch that packs in some extra goodies.</p>

<p>These include the game itself (of course), as well as a prequel comic, a soundtrack CD, a "selection of stickers", and a special standee. If you love yourself some&nbsp;<em>Bubble Ghost</em>, you'll want to plump for that.</p>

<p><em>Bubble Ghost Remake&nbsp;</em>launches for <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2412240/Bubble_Ghost_Remake/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC</a> and <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/en-gb/Games/Nintendo-Switch-download-software/Bubble-Ghost-Remake-2702820.html" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Nintendo Switch</a> on March 27th. Stay tuned for more.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dawn of War and Company of Heroes Developer Relic Shares Future Plans]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/relic-entertainment-future-plans</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dawn-of-war-and-company-of-heroes-developer-relic-shares-future-plans.1104912/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/relic-entertainment-future-plans<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Relic Entertainment, the studio behind games like&nbsp;<em>Warhammer 40k: Dawn of War&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>Company of Heroes</em>, has announced its plans for the future, and while they're rather vague on the whole, there are some interesting tidbits to pore over.</p>

<p>In a press release, Relic, which <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/sega-relic-entertainment-layoffs" rel="nofollow">became independent</a> after being sold off by Sega in March last year (sustaining a <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/relic-entertainment-layoffs" rel="nofollow">number of layoffs</a> into the bargain), says it's identified three key pillars for its strategy when it comes to the studio's future.</p>

<p>Pillar one involves "deepening commitment to existing titles", which means providing updates and continuing support for Relic's existing games. At the moment, the company is actively supporting strategy titles&nbsp;<em>Company of Heroes 3&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>Age of Empires 4</em>.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/relic-entertainment-future-plans-company-of-heroes-3-battle.jpg?itok=UzEe6FaP 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/relic-entertainment-future-plans-company-of-heroes-3-battle.jpg?itok=eAMsoasP 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Relic will continue supporting&nbsp;<em>Company of Heroes 3</em>, but it has plans for new games too.</figcaption></figure><p>Relic's second major new pillar is titled "independent development, creative experiences", and it involves the developer branching out into "smaller-scope, in-house games", as well as "continuing to develop the larger, complex strategy titles" for which it's known.</p>

<p>Finally - and perhaps most interestingly - Relic says it wants to "reimagin[e] classics", finding ways to "bring [its] classic titles to modern audiences". This could entail "re-releases, remasters, or brand-new franchise experiences" that capture the originals' "spirit" while appealing to new players as well.</p>

<p>Relic CEO Justin Dowdeswell says the studio's new direction marks "a significant milestone", and that he's "confident" Relic will be able to deliver "innovative, high-quality games that resonate with players around the world".</p>

<p>Unfortunately, Relic doesn't commit to announcing exactly what any of the aforementioned games might be, so we don't know just how far away from that tantalizing&nbsp;<em>Dawn of War&nbsp;</em>remaster we might be. Let's hope it's just around the corner, eh?</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/warhammer-40k-dawn-of-war-relic.jpg?itok=Z7ptPWPo 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/warhammer-40k-dawn-of-war-relic.jpg?itok=DC8CvpIq 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Let's hope that&nbsp;<em>Dawn of War&nbsp;</em>remaster is just around the corner.</figcaption></figure><p>If you were worried that Relic's independence from Sega meant it wouldn't be able to create its large-scale RTS games anymore, then it looks like you won't need to worry about that. We'll just be getting some extra experiments on the side.</p>

<p>What this means for Relic in a broader sense remains to be seen, though. Stay tuned for more on this and all other things Relic-related.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This Week at Remap]]></title>
            <link>https://remapradio.com/articles/this-week-at-remap-57/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/this-week-at-remap.1104909/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://remapradio.com/articles/this-week-at-remap-57/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
			<div>
					
					
					

					<article>
	
	<div>
		<p>I'm writing this introduction before the Super Bowl has happened, but if you'll recall, one of my annual traditions is having my oldest daughter bet on the coin flip. She had a multi-year run of taking an L, before making a huge recovery last year. We're hoping, much like the Kansas City Chiefs, to repeat. So I'm just putting the correct degenerate energy into the world that my child will choose wisely.</p><p>-pk, who is writing in advance so he can take a half day on Monday, because he took a half day for his birthday and in total, that's a full day!</p><hr><figure></figure><ul><li><strong>PODCAST: </strong><em>Remap Interview</em> – It's nice to chat with other folks running independent media outlets, so when <em>Rascal</em> reached out about a podcast to help promote their pledge drive, I said yes, even though I know [checks notes] nothing about tabletop RPGs. Fortunately, Cado came along for the ride.</li><li><strong>STREAM:</strong> <em>Civilization VII</em> – Can Cado and Rob build an empire, one stream at a time? Surely, it can't go any better/worse than their attempts at racing teams.</li><li><strong>STREAM:</strong> <em>PS1 Horror Demo Disc</em> — Well, it turns out there's a meta narrative on that disc—and we intend to see it to the end. Come find out what's hiding.</li><li><strong>PODCAST: </strong><em>Remap Radio</em> – It feels so good to be back to numbers. Also, I can talk about the time that I've spent playing <em>Avowed, </em>a game that finally got me to fully figure out (successfully!) getting my PC streaming to both my PC and Steam Deck, depending on whether the Steam Deck is docked. It's beautiful.</li><li><strong>ARTICLE: </strong><em>Letter Series</em> – Time to start talking about turning 41 next year.</li></ul><p><em>If you have any support issues, send details on the issue to </em><a href="https://remapradio.com/r/53613e2c?m=c2a53baa-518b-4385-90e8-62545232c3f6"><em><u>support@remapradio.com</u></em></a><em>.</em></p>
		<p><em>Patrick Klepek (he/him) is an editor at Remap. In another life, he worked on horror movie sets, but instead, he also runs&nbsp;<a href="https://crossplay.news/?ref=remap.ghost.io" rel="noreferrer"><em>Crossplay</em></a>, a newsletter about parenting and video games. You can follow him on&nbsp;<a href="https://www.twitter.com/patrickklepek?ref=remap.ghost.io" rel="noreferrer"><em>Twitter</em></a>,&nbsp;<a href="https://www.threads.net/@patrickklepek?ref=remap.ghost.io" rel="noreferrer"><em>Threads</em></a>,&nbsp;<a href="https://mastodon.social/@patrickklepek?ref=remap.ghost.io" rel="noreferrer"><em>Mastodon</em></a>, and&nbsp;<a href="https://bsky.app/profile/patrickklepek.bsky.social?ref=remap.ghost.io" rel="noreferrer"><em>Bluesky</em></a>.</em></p>
			</div>
</article>

				</div>
			<div id="notifications">
	<p>You’ve successfully subscribed to Remap</p>
	<p>Welcome back! You’ve successfully signed in.</p>
	<p>Great! You’ve successfully signed up.</p>
	<p>Success! Your email is updated.</p>
	<p>Your link has expired</p>
	<p>Success! Check your email for magic link to sign-in.</p>
</div>
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bubble Ghost Remake launches March 27]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/02/bubble-ghost-remake-launches-march-27</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/bubble-ghost-remake-launches-march-27.1104906/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/02/bubble-ghost-remake-launches-march-27<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Guide a little ghost and his bubble through an enchanted mansion.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Side-scrolling <a title="Genres > Platformer [609 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/platformer">platformer</a> remake <em><a title="Games > Bubble Ghost Remake" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/bubble-ghost-remake">Bubble Ghost Remake</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > Switch [16,626 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a> and <a title="Platforms > PC [22,305 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2412240/Bubble_Ghost_Remake/" target="_blank">Steam</a> on March 27, publisher <a title="Companies > Selecta Play [10 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/selecta-play">Selecta Play</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Nakama Game Studio" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/nakama-game-studio">Nakama Game Studio</a> announced. A physical standard edition for North America and Europe, as well as a Collector’s Edition for Europe, will also be available at participating retailers. <span id="more-942957"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Selecta Play:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>In the old castle of the renowned inventor Heinrich Von Schinker, in northern England, Heinrich’s spirit returns as a small ghost.</p><p>Alongside a mysterious bubble that he can move with gentle blows, he must face his own out-of-control inventions and fierce wild animals.</p><p>Guiding the bubble to freedom is his only goal.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Challenge Your Skills</strong> – Overcome levels filled with dangers and puzzles that will test your abilities. With addictive gameplay and devilish difficulty, your only goal is to protect the bubble at all costs.</li><li><strong>Defeat Epic Bosses</strong> – Face fierce bosses that will make you sweat. Only the most skilled will emerge victorious.</li><li><strong>Relive the Original Classic</strong> – Enjoy the full remaster of the 90s game, with 36 original levels recreated with completely renewed art.</li><li><strong>Compete for Glory</strong> – Perfect your times in speedrun mode and submit your results online to secure your place in the prestigious Hall of Fame.</li></ul><p><strong>More Features</strong></p><ul><li>Enjoy an <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,031 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a> with over 40 levels filled with skill and clever puzzles.</li><li>Three difficulty levels tailored to your playstyle.</li><li>Completely revamped graphics and sound that bring the magical world of the castle to life.</li><li>Dive deep into Heinrich’s story by finding hidden collectibles throughout the castle chambers.</li><li>Upload your scores and compare them with the best players worldwide in the online ranking.</li><li>Discover secret rooms, alternative endings, and unlock challenging in-game achievements.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Bubble Ghost - Official launch date trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/YyKfdHMryC8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dragon Quest 12: Series Creator Yuji Horii Offers A Small, But Important Update]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/dragon-quest-12-series-creator-yuji-horii-offers-a-small-but-important-update/1100-6529347/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dragon-quest-12-series-creator-yuji-horii-offers-a-small-but-important-update.1104903/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/dragon-quest-12-series-creator-yuji-horii-offers-a-small-but-important-update/1100-6529347/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-main">

      
                    
  
              <header id="masthead"><nav></nav></header>      
                            <div id="site-wrapper" role="main">
          <div id="default-content">
        
          <p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p>
  
    <article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529347">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">Square Enix hasn't forgotten about Dragon Quest XII: The Flames of Fate. In fact, series creator Yuji Horii reportedly confirmed that the company is working hard on the RPG over the weekend, with the hope that more info will be dished out piece by piece.</p><p dir="ltr"><a href="https://automaton-media.com/en/news/dragon-quest-12-is-still-fully-in-development-new-information-to-be-revealed-little-by-little-says-series-creator/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Automaton</a> states that Horii chatted about Dragon Quest XII with his radio show group <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wfikAAlgNsw&amp;embeds_referring_euri=https%3A%2F%2Fautomaton-media.com%2F&amp;source_ve_path=MjM4NTE">KosoKoso Hōsō Kyoku on YouTube</a>. That's when Horii reportedly made it clear his team has been toiling away at the RPG. <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/dragon-quest-12-the-flames-of-fate-announced/1100-6492022/" data-ref-id="1100-6492022">Dragon Quest XII was revealed almost four years ago</a> at this point, with minimal official updates since that time. For instance, no platforms have been announced.</p><div tabindex="0" data-id="1465379454" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6455352,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Dragon%20Quest%2012%3A%20The%20Flames%20Of%20Fate%20-%20Official%20Title%20Reveal%20Trailer&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:54,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:false,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/dragon-quest-12-the-flames-of-fate-official-title-reveal-trailer\/2300-6455352\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6455352\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6455352\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6455352\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6455352&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;Publisher Asset&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/3836152-223213.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/mt-rv-v1.gamespot.com\/vr\/2021\/05\/27\/650341\/trailer_dq12_700,1000,1800,2500,3200,4000,master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;adaptive_dash&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/mt-rv-v1.gamespot.com\/vr\/2021\/05\/27\/650341\/trailer_dq12_700,1000,1800,2500,3200,4000,master.mpd&quot;,&quot;adaptive_hd&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/mt-rv-v1.gamespot.com\/vr\/2021\/05\/27\/650341\/trailer_dq12_4000,master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;adaptive_high&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/mt-rv-v1.gamespot.com\/vr\/2021\/05\/27\/650341\/trailer_dq12_2500,master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;adaptive_low&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/mt-rv-v1.gamespot.com\/vr\/2021\/05\/27\/650341\/trailer_dq12_700,master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;adaptive_restricted&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/mt-rv-v1.gamespot.com\/vr\/2021\/05\/27\/650341\/trailer_dq12_700,1000,1800,2500,master.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1622144340,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="8gr2f7VK" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle" data-embed-type="video" data-ref-id="2300-6455352" data-src="/videos/dragon-quest-12-the-flames-of-fate-official-title-reveal-trailer/2300-6455352/" data-width="100%" data-height="100%" data-video-start="0"><div><p>Dragon Quest 12: The Flames Of Fate - Official Title Reveal Trailer</p><div><p>         Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?       </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!       </p></div></div><p>       Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.     </p><p>       This video has an invalid file format.     </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div><p dir="ltr">However, in April 2024, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/dragon-quest-producer-steps-down-due-to-repeated-delays-of-next-mainline-title-report/1100-6522431/" data-ref-id="1100-6522431">producer Yu Miyake reportedly stepped down from working on Dragon Quest XII at Square Enix</a> because of repeated delays for the RPG. This caused some public concerns about the development of the game.</p><p dir="ltr">The last mainline entry in the RPG franchise was Dragon Quest XI: Echoes of an Elusive Age in 2017 (though the worldwide release was 2018). Square Enix did launch <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/dragon-quest-iii-hd-2d-remake-review-history-repeats/1900-6418319/">Dragon Quest III: HD-2D Remake</a> this past November, with <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/dragon-quest-12-hd-2d-remake-announced-dq3-release-date-confirmed/1100-6524357/">the first two games getting the same treatment sometime this year</a>.</p><p>For more, GameSpot has <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/20-years-ago-square-and-enix-teamed-up-to-create-an-rpg-powerhouse/1100-6512882/">chronicled the history of Square and Enix joining forces in the early 2000s</a>, which led to the formation of an RPG powerhouse. The merger brought Final Fantasy and Dragon Quest under the same roof.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article>

    
  

</div>
                      <meta itemprop="seamless-content-list-items" data-list-items="[{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6476419&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/free-games-epic-games-store\/1100-6476419\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529213&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/elgato-popular-audio-mixing-software-is-getting-big-upgrade\/1100-6529213\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529214&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/nintendo-switch-breaks-13-year-sales-record\/1100-6529214\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529212&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/atari-revisits-an-arcade-classic-with-breakout-beyond\/1100-6529212\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529216&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/yes-metroid-prime-4-is-still-coming-out-in-2025\/1100-6529216\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529219&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/switch-2-joy-con-rumored-mouse-feature-is-definitely-intriguing-civ-dev-says\/1100-6529219\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529226&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/helldivers-2-players-can-now-dig-their-way-out-of-trouble-with-a-shovel\/1100-6529226\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529222&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/hogwarts-legacy-how-to-download-and-use-mods\/1100-6529222\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529091&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/playstation-plus-essential-free-games-for-february-2025\/1100-6529091\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529225&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/fallout-new-vegas-writer-is-back-at-obsidian-but-dont-get-your-hopes-up\/1100-6529225\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6522984&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-launch-deals-save-15-on-pc-steelbook-for-ps5-and-more\/1100-6522984\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529229&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/mlb-the-show-25-revamps-road-to-the-show-adds-high-school-and-college-ball\/1100-6529229\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529227&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/mlb-the-show-25-limited-edition-is-up-for-preorder-includes-topps-baseball-card\/1100-6529227\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529224&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/the-last-of-us-season-2-introduces-another-brand-new-character-unique-to-the-show\/1100-6529224\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529230&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/activision-raises-2-6-million-for-los-angeles-fire-relief-efforts-via-call-of-duty-dlc-and-more\/1100-6529230\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6527183&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/terrifier-3s-very-strange-collectors-box-set-is-available-now-at-amazon\/1100-6527183\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529231&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/former-usps-worker-stole-over-100000-worth-of-pokemon-cards-and-other-memorabilia\/1100-6529231\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529240&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/the-united-kingdom-wont-change-its-laws-to-address-games-going-offline\/1100-6529240\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529243&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/new-battlefield-game-releasing-by-march-2026\/1100-6529243\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529209&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/wwe-2k25-like-cody-rhodes-explores-what-comes-after-you-finish-the-story\/1100-6529209\/&quot;}]">
            </div>
              
    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GTA 6 PC version teased by Take-Two boss, acknowledges platform's growing importance]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/gta-6-pc-version-teased-by-take-two-boss-acknowledges-platforms-growing-importance</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gta-6-pc-version-teased-by-take-two-boss-acknowledges-platforms-growing-importance.1104900/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/gta-6-pc-version-teased-by-take-two-boss-acknowledges-platforms-growing-importance<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div>
        

        <p>"I wouldn't be surprised to see that trend continue."</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Steam-Grand-Theft-Auto-VI-Trailer-1-1-9-screenshot.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Rockstar / Steam / Eurogamer</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Take-Two boss Strauss Zelnick has discussed the growing importance of the PC market, though stopped short of outright confirming <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/gta-6-everything-we-know-so-far-9357">GTA 6</a> will be heading to PC.</p>
<p>GTA 6 is currently slated for PS5 and Xbox Series X/S, but there's been no mention of a PC release so far. That's surprising in 2025, when big releases are often released simultaneously across all three platforms, or at least follow up soon with PC.</p>
<p>Speaking to <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/take-two-boss-unconcerned-by-plummeting-ps5-and-xbox-sales-insists-gta-6-will-cause-a-meaningful-uptick-in-console-sales-in-2025?utm_source=threads,twitter">IGN</a>, Zelnick teased a PC release of GTA 6 will be on the way, but the company tends not to "go across all platforms simultaneously".</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Grand Theft Auto VI Trailer 1" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/QdBZY2fkU-0?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Grand Theft Auto VI Trailer 1</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/QdBZY2fkU-0?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/QdBZY2fkU-0?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Grand Theft Auto 6's first trailer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QdBZY2fkU-0" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>"So with Civ 7 it's available on console and PC and Switch right away," Zelnick said, making comparison with Firaxis' recently launched Civilization 7. "With regard to others in our lineup, we don't always go across all platforms simultaneously. Historically, Rockstar has started with some platforms and then historically moved to other platforms."</p>
<p>Interestingly, Zelnick admitted that the PC version of a multiplatform game can generate 40 percent of overall sales. As a result, the PC platform is growing in importance.</p>
<p>"We have seen PC become a much more important part of what used to be a console business, and I wouldn't be surprised to see that trend continue," he said.</p>
<p>Still, the focus for GTA 6 for now are the console releases, which Zelnick expects to boost console sales in response.</p>
<p>"When you have a big title in the market and we have many of them coming, historically that has sold consoles," Zelnick said.</p>
<p>"And I think that will happen this year. I don't think tariffs are going to be our friend, but I think there will be a meaningful uptick in console sales in calendar '25 because of the release schedule, not just coming from us, but coming from others. So I'm not concerned about that [console sales falling]. I think the trend that you'd want to focus on is this increasing share of the market that is reflected in PC."</p>
<p>So why no PC release for GTA 6 at present? As Zelnick noted, Rockstar has traditionally started with console releases in the past: <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/grand-theft-auto-v">GTA 5</a>, for instance, released in September 2013 while the PC version (initially aiming for simultaneous release) was delayed until April 2015.</p>
<p>Rockstar also has a torrid history with modders, including the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/who-spilled-hot-coffee">infamous Hot Coffee mod</a>.</p>
<p>Just last month, the company <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/rockstar-shuts-down-ambitious-mod-that-put-gta-4s-liberty-city-in-grand-theft-auto-5">shut down an ambitious mod that put a playable version of GTA 4's Liberty City inside GTA 5</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch 2 Units May Already Be in the Hands of Some; Console Could Be Priced at Around $350 – Rumor]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-units-out-priced-350/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-switch-2-units-may-already-be-in-the-hands-of-some-console-could-be-priced-at-around-350-%E2%80%93-rumor.1104894/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-units-out-priced-350/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The Nintendo Switch 2 could already be in the hands of some users, according to some new online reports.</p>
<p>As reported on Bluesky by Necro Felipe, the same user on the Xiaohongshu forums who shared the console's CAD model <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-design-pictures-specs/">a few months back</a> claims to have obtained a real Nintendo Switch 2 unit, most likely via illegal means. If this is true, we should expect more information on the system to surface online before the April 2nd Direct and the hands-on events that will be held worldwide in the coming months.</p>
<blockquote data-bluesky-uri="at://did:plc:5uw2zrybj37wnkkc5ku4fxyu/app.bsky.feed.post/3lht5vqyzlp2x" data-bluesky-cid="bafyreia2unbnwu4mqgh2dve44seg5vprp5hrle7hjgbjia2bdaqryv4voa">
<p lang="pt">Usuário que compartilhou o modelo CAD do Switch 2 anteriormente no fórum Xiaohongshu afirma que obteve um Switch 2 real agora (provavelmente de forma ilegal)</p>
<p>Ele avisa aos interessados por acessórios que o contate para testes com o aparelho</p>
<p>(thx Kysen)</p>
<p><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:5uw2zrybj37wnkkc5ku4fxyu/post/3lht5vqyzlp2x?ref_src=embed">[image or embed]</a></p>
<p>— Necro Felipe • Universo Nintendo (<a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:5uw2zrybj37wnkkc5ku4fxyu?ref_src=embed">@necro.universonintendo.com</a>) <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:5uw2zrybj37wnkkc5ku4fxyu/post/3lht5vqyzlp2x?ref_src=embed">February 10, 2025 at 1:37 PM</a></p></blockquote>

<p>Among the many things we still don't know about the Nintendo Switch 2 is how much the system will cost, as the Japanese company has not said much on the matter yet other than the fact that they are considering multiple factors for the system's price, including inflation, exchange rate and the price range that consumers expect for Nintendo products. As reported by <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/02/rumour-placeholder-retail-listing-suggests-switch-2-price-might-be-cheaper-than-expected">Nintendo Life</a>, according to two images showing Costco Canada's backend product listing and a printed sign with an obvious misspelling recently shared on the <a href="https://famiboards.com/threads/future-nintendo-hardware-technology-speculation-discussion-st-new-staff-post-please-read.55/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Famiiboards forums</a>, the console could cost 499 Canadian dollars, around 350 US dollars, which would be an excellent price for the system, although a direct conversion may not be very accurate, looking at the current Switch pricing in different regions.</p>
<p>The Nintendo Switch 2 will launch later this year worldwide. As already mentioned, the next look at the system will come during a dedicated Nintendo Direct scheduled for<a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-officially-revealed-with-a-new-trailer-dedicated-direct-confirmed-for-april/"> April 2nd.</a></p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[When is Steam Next Fest 2025 and When Does The Next Fest Sale Start?]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/when-is-steam-next-fest-2025-details/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/when-is-steam-next-fest-2025-and-when-does-the-next-fest-sale-start.1104888/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/when-is-steam-next-fest-2025-details/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Steam Next Fest is one of the most exciting events for PC players. It’s an event that lasts more than a week, with developers worldwide (both big and small) bringing their upcoming games to an eager audience. It happens three times a year, and the next Steam Next Fest is set to take place between February and March 2025.</p>



<p>At the Steam Next Fest event, you’ll get your hands on exclusive demos, check out developer livestreams, and offer critical feedback on developing titles, all within Steam.</p>



<p>So, when is Steam Next Fest 2025 and when does the killer sale that accompanies Next Fest kick-off?</p>



<p>Read on to find out.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-steam-next-fest-2025-dates">Steam Next Fest 2025 Dates</h2>



<p><strong>The first Steam Next Fest of 2025 will take place between February 24 and March 3. This is known as the Steam Next Fest: February Edition.</strong> Following that, the second Steam Next Fest 2025 event will land between June 9 – 16. These events will be accompanied by regular sales and other themed, limited-time events.</p>



<p>The third and final Steam Next Fest 2025 event is yet to be revealed, but 2024’s ‘winter edition’ landed in October, so perhaps we’ll see the same thing unravel this year.</p>



<h2 id="h-what-is-steam-next-fest">What is Steam Next Fest?</h2>



<p>Steam Next Fest is a legendary showcase of some of the most highly anticipated – or unheard of – games on PC. It’s a one-stop-shop for PC gamers worldwide who want to connect with indie developers to find out which hidden gems are being released soon on PC.</p>



<p>Developers both solo and major will prepare exclusive demos and trial products for Steam Next Fest, and many will offer special promotions for those wishlisting or pre-ordering their game during the event.</p>



<p>It’s also a good time to buy games on PC – <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/next-steam-sale-steam-sale-dates/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the Steam Next Fest sale</a> runs parallel to the demo showcase.</p>



<p>From February 24 at 10 AM PST to March 3, you’ll be able to explore hundreds of games, connecting with developers on Steam like never before and offering key feedback on their emerging titles. </p>



<p>The most popular <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/steam-next-fest-june-2024-10-games-you-need-to-check-out/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Steam Next Fest 2024 games</a> and demos included:</p>



<ul>
<li>Delta Force</li>



<li>Supervive</li>



<li>The Precinct</li>



<li>Sand</li>



<li>Permafrost</li>



<li>Commandos: Origins</li>



<li>Incantation</li>
</ul>



<h2 id="h-best-games-at-steam-next-fest-2025">Best Games at Steam Next Fest 2025</h2>



<p>The full suite of games being showcased at the Steam Next Fest 2025 is yet to be revealed. Stop back here when the showcase is live to get the full scope of what’s worth playing at Steam Next Fest: February Edition.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that </p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Spooked by the 2011 PSN Hack, Some PlayStation Customers Want Sony to Say Exactly What Went Wrong With PSN Over the Weekend]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/spooked-by-the-2011-psn-hack-some-playstation-customers-want-sony-to-say-exactly-what-went-wrong-with-psn-over-the-weekend</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/spooked-by-the-2011-psn-hack-some-playstation-customers-want-sony-to-say-exactly-what-went-wrong-with-psn-over-the-weekend.1104885/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/spooked-by-the-2011-psn-hack-some-playstation-customers-want-sony-to-say-exactly-what-went-wrong-with-psn-over-the-weekend<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Sony has said the 24-hour outage that <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/is-psn-down-february-2025">knocked out PlayStation Network</a> over the weekend was due to an “operational issue.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In a <a href="https://x.com/AskPlayStation/status/1888454556125708758" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">tweet</a> confirming the recovery of its network services, Sony apologized for the downtime and thanked the PlayStation community for its patience. As a make-good, it’s giving all PlayStation Plus members an additional five days of service.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">However, some PlayStation customers are demanding more information on the cause of the downtime beyond the vague “operational issue,” and have pointed to the high-profile PSN data breach of 2011 that saw personal details from approximately 77 million accounts compromised.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/02/10/gettyimages-2197511020-1739195956853.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">The PSN hack of 2011 is still fresh in the memory of some gamers. Photo by Nikos Pekiaridis/NurPhoto via Getty Images.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">“Given what happened in 2011 we need to know if we need to call our banks for new credit cards and need identity protection services,” one social media user said in response to Sony’s statement.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Sweet, but can you also tell us what happened and how you’ll be working to avoid it in the future?” another asked.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Your lack of transparency is disturbing,” said another.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Some are also calling on Sony to outline the measures it’s taking to prevent similar “operational issues” from knocking out PSN in the future.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">PSN going offline not only affected online gaming but single-player games that require either authentication with a server or a constant internet connection. Embattled U.S. retailer GameStop tweeted a joke at Sony’s expense while PSN was offline, saying “bet y’all want physical copies now.” But this joke was met with ridicule across social media, as users pointed out the declining shop chain’s penchant for selling products other than video games these days.</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr">Yeah let me go to my local GameStop and grab some physical ga- <a href="https://t.co/zpCn71rF5t" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://t.co/zpCn71rF5t</a> <a href="https://t.co/W1J9ECChUE" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/W1J9ECChUE</a></p>— 「WOKEN ELMA SIMP」 (@WOKENJJT) <a href="https://twitter.com/WOKENJJT/status/1888309913514123362?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">February 8, 2025</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">Some third-party publishers whose games were affected have announced extensions to in-game events or limited-time modes. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/monster-hunter-wilds-beta-gets-extra-24-hours-after-psn-outage">Capcom just announced an extension to the next Monster Hunter Wilds beta test</a> after last weekend’s was cut short by the PSN issue. EA was forced to extend FC 25's most hardcore multiplayer event, too.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Sony is yet to expand on the PSN downtime beyond two single tweets: one to acknoledge PSN was offline, another to say it was back up with the vague explanation and compensation. Clearly, some customers want further communication from the company.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[As Civilization 7 Dataminers Discover Reference to the Atomic Age, Firaxis Says 'We're Excited for Where This Is Going']]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/as-civilization-7-dataminers-discover-reference-to-the-atomic-age-firaxis-says-were-excited-for-where-this-is-going</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/as-civilization-7-dataminers-discover-reference-to-the-atomic-age-firaxis-says-were-excited-for-where-this-is-going.1104879/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/as-civilization-7-dataminers-discover-reference-to-the-atomic-age-firaxis-says-were-excited-for-where-this-is-going<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/sid-meiers-civilization-vii">Civilization 7</a> dataminers have unearthed evidence to suggest the game is set to receive a fourth, unannounced Age — and developer Firaxis has teased its plans in an interview with IGN.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">A full campaign in Civilization 7 is one that goes through all three Ages: Antiquity, Exploration, and Modern. Once the Age is completed, all players (and any AI opponents) experience an Age Transition simultaneously. During an Age Transition, three things happen: you select a new civilization from the new Age to represent your empire, you choose which Legacies you want to retain in the new Age, and the game world evolves. The Civilization games have never had such a system.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Based on the unit types and victory conditions currently in-game, the Modern Age ends before the Cold War. In an interview with IGN, Civilization 7 lead designer Ed Beach confirmed this timeline, explaining how Firaxis settled on ending the current version of the game at the conclusion of World War 2.</p><div id="best-civ-7-leaders" data-cy="tierlist-view-trigger"><p><h3 data-cy="title3">Best Civ 7 Leaders</h3><h3>Best Civ 7 Leaders</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">“We spent a lot of time looking at the ebbs and flows of history,” Beach said. “Once we knew that our game would benefit by breaking it up into chapters, obviously the first thing we ask ourselves is, ‘well, when does a chapter start and when does a chapter end?’ And our senior historian on the project, Andrew Johnson, was working very closely with me, comes from a study of Southeast Asian history. My tendencies are way too focused on Western history, but he's very good at making sure that we're looking at the whole picture worldwide. But we did notice that all the big empires of antiquity, it wasn't just the Roman Empire, but even the big empires over in China and India crumbled under outside pressure in the rough same time period, the 300 to 500 common era time period that Rome was being challenged. Those big empires face challenges across the world.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“So we're like, okay, that's a great ending chapter for the first block of our game or what we're going to call the Age. So that's where Antiquity ends. And so we started looking for other places where the other chapters should end. The transition from Exploration to Modern is all about those big monarchies that were established, especially in places like Europe being challenged by people's revolutions, like the French Revolution or the American Revolution. There were a lot of revolutions in Europe in the 1840s as well. So that felt like a good grounding point. And then the nations emerging from it, the Americas and the French and so forth, could be in the Modern Age that follows.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Then we looked for where's the next big shakeup worldwide in history, and it was the World Wars. We had to feel like there was a big pivot in history in 1945 essentially after the World Wars. Especially because we have new gameplay systems that can be unique for each Age, so we can change the rules of diplomacy or the rules of warfare, which commanders you have access to, whenever we change Ages, we need to make sure that those breaks have enough conformity to what happened in real life that they make sense to us.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“So yeah, we very deliberately did not push into the Cold War time period because that is one that just felt very different than the rest of the Modern Age. It just sort of dips its toes in the Cold War, like you've identified with the thermonuclear device being the one that ends the military victory path there.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The inevitable follow-up question is, of course, whether Firaxis plans to expand Civilization 7 down the line with the addition of a fourth Age where players may, perhaps, go to space, land on the moon, and get to play with up to day units.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Executive producer Dennis Shirk wouldn’t confirm this outright, but did tease the developer’s future plans.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“You can imagine the possibilities with this, honestly,” Shirk said. “The way that the design team set it up so that each age is chockfull of systems, visuals, units, Civs, all specific to that age, and what you could do with that and where you could take it… we can't talk about the specifics. We can just talk about it in generalities. We're excited for where this is going to go.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Hot on the heels of this tease, Civilization 7 players have already datamined the game, which is available in advanced access to those who paid more, and found reference to the Atomic Age.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/civ/comments/1ikk193/so_according_to_the_asset_cloudenv_in_the/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Redditor ManByTheRiver11</a> revealed mention of unannounced leaders, civilizations, and word of the Atomic Age. New leaders and civs are of course expected, given Firaxis’ DLC strategy for previous games in the series. And this Atomic Age would certainly fit the bill with where Civ 7 currently ends and Shirk’s tease in our interview.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In the shorter term, Firaxis is working on addressing various community complaints that have led to a ‘mixed’ user review rating on Steam. In an interview with IGN ahead of the release of its third quarter financial results, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/take-two-boss-says-legacy-civilization-audience-will-eventually-come-around-on-civilization-7-amid-mixed-steam-user-reviews">Take-Two CEO Strauss Zelnick acknowledged that Civilization 7 had received some negative reviews from press and players</a>, but insisted that the “legacy Civ audience” will come around the more they play, and called Civilization 7’s early performance “very encouraging.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Looking for tips to help you take over the world? Check out our guide to completing <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/civilization-7/How_to_Win:_Civ_7_Victory_Types">every Civ 7 victory</a>, our run down of the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/civilization-7/Biggest_Civ_7_Changes_for_Civ_6_Players">biggest Civ 7 changes for Civ 6 players</a>, and the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/civilization-7/14_Civ_7_Mistakes_to_Avoid">14 crucial Civ 7 mistakes to avoid</a>. We’ve also got explanations on all the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/civilization-7/Civ_7_Map_Settings">Civ 7 map types</a> and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/civilization-7/Civ_7_Map_Settings">difficulty settings</a> so you know what you’re getting into.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kentum demo now available for PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/02/kentum-demo-now-available-for-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/kentum-demo-now-available-for-pc.1104876/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/02/kentum-demo-now-available-for-pc<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Play the opening hours of the game.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Tlon Industries [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/tlon-industries">Tlon Industries</a> has released a demo for <a title="Genres > Side-Scrolling [896 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/side-scrolling">side-scrolling</a> base-building <a title="Genres > Survival [372 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/survival">survival game</a> <em><a title="Games > Kentum [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/kentum">Kentum</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > PC [22,305 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2165140/Kentum/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a>. <span id="more-942921"></span></p><p>The demo features the opening hours of the game, allowing players to explore its first region, craft machines, decorate their base, and more.</p><p>“<em>Kentum</em> is a complex, systems-heavy game, so we wanted to ensure that the demo is hefty enough to let players really get a sense of the <em>Kentum</em>‘s scope,” said Tlon Industries game director Roque Rey in a press release. “Of course, the final game will contain A LOT more content, with new regions to explore, creatures to encounter, modules to expand your base, and gear to wear. <em>Kentum</em> is a very expressionistic, open-ended game, so we want to ensure players can survive the post apocalypse their own way!”</p><p>Here is an overview of the game and demo, via Tlon Industries:</p><blockquote><p><em>Kentum</em> places players in the role of a man awakening from a very, very long nap. After 7,000 years in suspended animation, he awakens to find himself seemingly the last man on earth. With no one else to rely on, you must scour for resources and use advanced technology to create your own home base to sustain your survival.</p><p>This demo lets players go through the opening hours of <em>Kentum</em>, exploring its first region. While the demo contains plenty of machines to craft and base decorations, far more awaits in the full game, which includes fauna machines, drones and advanced optimization options.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><em>Kentum</em> lets players explore post-post-apocalyptic landscapes with dynamically changing climates and seasons full of unknown forms of flora and fauna. From trash mountains to desolate ruins, each area is filled with secrets to discover and challenges to overcome – like extreme weather and low gravity. Gather resources, fight newly evolved predators, harvest life-forms, and adapt to the hazardous, ever-changing world of 10,000 AD!</p><p>With no civilization you need to ensure that your house is more than a home; it must also be a factory. You’ll have to craft new automatization machinery and creatively combine your findings to optimize your own self-regulating habitat. Create your own farms, craft coal and ingots, build claws and conveyor belts. And don’t forget to decorate the place, as increasingly complex pipelines could be an eyesore. After all, this is the one environment you have control over, so you might as well make it personal to you!</p></blockquote><p><em>Kentum</em> is due out for PlayStation 5, Xbox Series, and PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2165140/Kentum/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> in 2025.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SEC confirms Roblox part of 'active and ongoing' investigation]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/sec-confirms-active-and-ongoing-investigation-into-roblox</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sec-confirms-roblox-part-of-active-and-ongoing-investigation.1104870/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/sec-confirms-active-and-ongoing-investigation-into-roblox<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Roblox is part of an active investigation being conducted by U.S. regulator the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC).</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-02-07/sec-confirms-game-service-roblox-part-of-active-investigation">As reported by Bloomberg</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, the SEC confirmed Roblox is involved in an "active and ongoing investigation" but refused to elaborate further.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Responding to a Freedom of Information Act request, the SEC said providing additional information could "harm to the ongoing enforcement proceeding."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Bloomberg has been unable to learn more about the investigation. Roblox owner Roblox Corp has yet to respond to a request for comment from Bloomberg, while the SEC declined to provide more context.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Roblox is no stranger to headlines. The platform, which allows users to build and play video game experiences, has faced heavy criticism over a perceived lack of child protections.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/roblox-adds-more-parental-overwatch-to-its-revamped-child-safety-procedures">Roblox Corp rolled out new safety measures in November 2024</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> to protect younger players. Prior to that, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.bloomberg.com/features/2024-roblox-pedophile-problem/">Bloomberg reported</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> that employees at the company were concerned it wasn't taking adequate steps to combat predatory behaviour targeting children.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">A number of current and former Roblox staffers told Bloomberg that catching predators had become a "Sisyphean task."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">At the time, Roblox Corp told Game Developer it "protects users of all ages on the platform" and claimed Bloomberg's report contained "glaring mischaracterizations."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Bloomberg, however, wasn't alone in raising the issue. In October 2024, Hindenburg Research claimed Roblox Corp had </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/roblox-report-inflated-user-numbers-child-predator-presence-investors">lied about player metrics and downplayed the presence of predators on its platform</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"The company has cut moderation costs in an attempt to appease Wall Street, while endangering kids with a platform that exposes them to illicit content and facilitates pedophilia at scale," claimed the report.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Once again, Roblox Corp rejected those allegations and claimed Hindenburg's report was inaccurate.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer has reached out to Roblox Corp for comment.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">News Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer news editor Chris Kerr is an award-winning journalist and reporter with over a decade of experience in the game industry. His byline has appeared in notable print and digital publications including Edge, Stuff, Wireframe, International Business Times, and&nbsp;</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="http://pocketgamer.biz/">PocketGamer.biz</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. Throughout his career, Chris has covered major industry events including GDC, PAX Australia, Gamescom, Paris Games Week, and Develop Brighton. He has featured on the judging panel at The Develop Star Awards on multiple occasions and appeared on BBC Radio 5 Live to discuss breaking news.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Civilization 7 VR Version Announced for Meta Quest 3, Coming in Spring]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/civilization-7-vr-spring-meta-quest</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/civilization-7-vr-version-announced-for-meta-quest-3-coming-in-spring.1104849/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/civilization-7-vr-spring-meta-quest<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Firaxis and Meta have announced that&nbsp;<em>Civilization 7&nbsp;</em>is coming to VR, with a version of the upcoming 4X grand strategy game heading to Meta Quest 3 and 3S devices in spring.</p>

<p>The game is available to wishlist in VR form right now, and it marks the first time the&nbsp;<em>Civilization&nbsp;</em>series has been available in VR. Naturally, the VR version of the game will feature a redesigned interface, too.</p>

<p><em>Civilization 7 - VR&nbsp;</em>revolves around something the developers are calling the Command Table, which is a sort of zoomed-out view of the action that makes everything look as though you're playing it as a tabletop game.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/civilization-7-vr-command-table.jpg?itok=v9zRev6f 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/civilization-7-vr-command-table.jpg?itok=0XJKTp4q 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Civilization 7&nbsp;</em>will look a little different in VR.</figcaption></figure><p>World leaders will stand around the Command Table, reacting when you make decisions like forging alliances with them or declaring war on their nations.</p>

<p>You'll also be able to "bring the Command Table into your surroundings with dynamic mixed reality", according to Meta, so it sounds like you'll be able to superimpose&nbsp;<em>Civilization 7&nbsp;</em>into the real world if you so desire.</p>

<p>The VR version of the game will support solo play and multiplayer for you and up to three others, although they will need to be playing the Meta Quest version of the game; you won't be able to play this one with regular&nbsp;<em>Civilization 7&nbsp;</em>players, unfortunately.</p>

<p>You can check out the announcement trailer for&nbsp;<em>Civilization 7 - VR&nbsp;</em>right here. It's set for a spring 2025 release, although no more specific release date has been revealed yet.</p>




<p>Elsewhere in&nbsp;<em>Civilization 7&nbsp;</em>news, the non-VR version of the game launched into its advanced access period last week and immediately <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/civilization-7-early-access-mixed-reviews-50k-players" rel="nofollow">met with criticism from players</a>, who highlighted its user interface and a perceived paucity of game features as particular sticking points.</p>

<p>Following those criticisms, Firaxis <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/civilization-7-ui-problems-fixes-coming" rel="nofollow">promised to fix players' problems</a> with&nbsp;<em>Civilization 7</em>, highlighting three areas to address (namely UI, community-requested features, and polish) without committing to specific timings.</p>

<p><em>Civilization 7&nbsp;</em>is due out on February 11th for <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1295660/Sid_Meiers_Civilization_VII/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC</a>, <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-gb/games/sid-meier-s-civilization-vii/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PlayStation</a>, <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/sid-meiers-civilization-vii-for-xbox-series-xs/9N23HJHSC6BL" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Xbox</a>, and <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/us/store/products/sid-meiers-civilization-vii-switch/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Nintendo Switch</a>. The VR version arrives in spring for <a href="https://www.meta.com/experiences/sid-meiers-civilization-vii-vr/5781689118524197/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Meta Quest 3 and 3S</a>.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marvel Rivals Has Its Own Section on Disney Plus]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-section-disney-plus/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/marvel-rivals-has-its-own-section-on-disney-plus.1104843/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-section-disney-plus/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Disney Plus users have spotted a dedicated section for Marvel Rivals on the streaming platform.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Spotted by <a href="https://x.com/CultureCrave/status/1888862600244699555" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Culture Crave</a> (via <a href="https://www.thegamer.com/marvel-rivals-own-disney-plus-section/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">TheGamer</a>), the new category on Disney Plus has been titled “Featuring Characters from Marvel Rivals”. It includes three movies: Captain America: Civil War, Thor: Ragnarok, and Doctor Strange: The Multiverse of Madness.&nbsp;</p>



<p>These three Disney movies feature a massive chunk of the Marvel Rivals roster but not all the heroes and villains. Civil War features characters like Captain America, Spider-Man, Iron Man, Black Panther, and Black Widow. Ragnarok features Thor, Loki, Hulk, and Hela. Lastly, the Multiverse of Madness has other characters from the roster, including Doctor Strange, Scarlet Witch, and Mr. Fantastic.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Marvel Rivals promotion on <span>the</span> streaming platform might help the game gain more traction; however, it has been doing pretty well since its release. The hero-shooter quickly became popular with its big roster, familiar faces, and exciting gameplay. It managed to soar on the Steam charts and has retained its position as one of the platform’s <a href="https://steamdb.info/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">top 10 most-played games</a>, according to SteamDB.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Players might soon see categories like “Movies and TV shows based on Marvel Rivals game” on Disney Plus. We already know that a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-comic-book-april-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">comic book</a> is in the works, and there’s a chance we could get other adaptations, too.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In other news, Ninja thinks Marvel Rivals <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/overwatch-dead-ninja-marvel-rivals/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">has killed Overwatch</a>. Also, the developers <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-fake-leaks/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">allegedly hide fake heroes</a> in the files to catch leakers. What are your thoughts on Disney Plus having a section for Marvel Rivals?&nbsp;Let us know in the comments or on our new&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read&nbsp;about<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/valve-reveals-advertising-rules-for-steam-games/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> Valve’s advertising rules for Steam games</a>.&nbsp;Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bleach: Rebirth of Souls character trailer – Nnoitra Gilga]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/02/bleach-rebirth-of-souls-character-trailer-nnoitra-gilga</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/bleach-rebirth-of-souls-character-trailer-%E2%80%93-nnoitra-gilga.1104840/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/02/bleach-rebirth-of-souls-character-trailer-nnoitra-gilga<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>The Quinta Espada.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Bandai Namco Entertainment [6,638 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/bandai-namco-entertainment">Bandai Namco</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Tamsoft [314 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/tamsoft">Tamsoft</a> have released a new character trailer for fighting <a title="Genres > Action [2,471 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action game</a> <em><a title="Games > Bleach: Rebirth of Souls [33 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/bleach-rebirth-of-souls">Bleach: Rebirth of Souls</a></em> highlighting playable fighter Nnoitra Gilga. <span id="more-941837"></span></p><p>According to his description, Gilga is obsessed with strength and aims to become the strongest, using frontal attacks and relying on his Hierro to destroy his opponents.</p><p><em>Bleach: Rebirth of Souls</em> is due out for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,803 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [6,671 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,684 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [22,305 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1689620/BLEACH_Rebirth_of_Souls/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> on March 21.</p><p>Watch the trailer below.</p><h2><span>Character Trailer: Nnoitra Gilga</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><iframe title="BLEACH Rebirth of Souls — Nnoitra Gilga Character trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/BieqWlJgYoE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe title="「BLEACH Rebirth of Souls」キャラクタームービー #29｜ノイトラ・ジルガ" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/qoL7R5nqAsM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Relic Entertainment announces future plans – updates and DLC, small- and large-scale titles, and re-imaginings]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/02/relic-entertainment-announces-future-plans-updates-and-dlc-small-and-large-scale-titles-and-re-imaginings</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/relic-entertainment-announces-future-plans-%E2%80%93-updates-and-dlc-small-and-large-scale-titles-and-re-imaginings.1104837/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/02/relic-entertainment-announces-future-plans-updates-and-dlc-small-and-large-scale-titles-and-re-imaginings<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
        </ul>

    
    <p><span>Company of Heroes developer poised for continued growth and innovation.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><em>Company of Heroes</em> and <em><a title="Series > Warhammer [42 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/series/warhammer">Warhammer</a> 40,000: Dawn of War</em> series developer <a title="Companies > Relic Entertainment [22 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sega/relic-entertainment">Relic Entertainment</a> has announced its plans for the future following <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2024/03/sega-sells-relic-entertainment-lays-off-240-staff-across-european-studios">its split</a> from former parent company <a title="Companies > SEGA [2,652 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sega">SEGA</a> in March 2024. <span id="more-942910"></span></p><p>The company’s plans include:</p><blockquote><ul><li><strong>Deepening Commitment to <a title="Companies > Exis [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/exis">Exis</a>ting Titles</strong> – Relic will continue to provide robust support for its acclaimed titles, including <em><a title="Games > Company of Heroes 3 [7 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/company-of-heroes-3">Company of Heroes 3</a></em> which just announced a new downloadable content and a major update. Relic is committed to ongoing updates, and community engagement to ensure a thriving and long-lasting experience for players.</li><li><strong>Independent Development, Creative <a title="Companies > Experience [210 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/experience">Experience</a>s</strong> – Recognizing the power of creativity and innovation, Relic will actively pursue the development and publishing of smaller-scope, in-house games, while also continuing to develop the larger, complex strategy titles the studio is renowned for. This will allow the studio to explore new genres and gameplay experiences and continue fostering a culture of experimentation and artistic expression.</li><li><strong>Re-Imagining Classics</strong> – Drawing upon its rich catalog of beloved games, Relic will explore opportunities to bring these classic titles to modern audiences. This may include re-releases, remasters, or brand-new franchise experiences that capture the spirit of the originals while appealing to a new generation of players.</li></ul></blockquote><p>“Relic Entertainment has always been a studio defined by its resilience and passion for creating unforgettable gaming experiences,” said Relic Entertainment CEO Justin Dowdeswell in a press release. “This new chapter marks a significant milestone for us. By embracing independence and focusing on our core strengths, we are confident in our ability to deliver innovative, high-quality games that will resonate with players around the world. The future of Relic Entertainment is bright, and we are excited to embark on this new journey.”</p><!-- AD: content -->
        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Company of Heroes developer Relic to build for the future with smaller titles and classic revivals]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/company-of-heroes-developer-relic-to-build-for-the-future-with-smaller-titles-and-classic-revivals</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/company-of-heroes-developer-relic-to-build-for-the-future-with-smaller-titles-and-classic-revivals.1104834/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/company-of-heroes-developer-relic-to-build-for-the-future-with-smaller-titles-and-classic-revivals<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="captioned-content" data-testid="featured-image"><p><span>Image via Relic Entertainment</span></p></div><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Company of Heroes developer Relic Entertainment is implementing a new business strategy after </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/sega-sells-off-relic-entertainment-will-axe-240-jobs">gaining independence from Sega</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The Canadian studio will now focus on three key areas by deepening its commitment to existing titles, developing and publishing "smaller-scope" games, and reimagining classic franchises.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Relic said it will maintain support for major titles such as </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Company of Heroes 3 </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">while continuing to develop the larger, more complex strategy titles that have become its bread and butter.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">It hopes those more robust projects will give it the freedom to explore new genres and experiences through in-house projects that are smaller in scale.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Relic also intends to "explore opportunities" to bring some of its classic titles to modern audiences by working on remasters, re-releases, or entirely new projects that "capture the spirit of the originals."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Notably, Relic CEO Justin Dowdeswell said the company will continue to invest in its workforce and said the new chapter represents a "significant milestone for the studio."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"By embracing independence and focusing on our core strengths, we are confident in our ability to deliver innovative, high-quality games that will resonate with players around the world. The future of Relic Entertainment is bright, and we are excited to embark on this new journey," he added.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Relic CEO insists new strategy won't place more jobs at risk">Relic CEO insists new strategy won't place more jobs at risk</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Speaking to Game Developer about the new strategy, Dowdeswell insisted the pivot won't lead to redundancies and said the company is on "much better footing" after </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/relic-is-laying-off-41-staff-after-independence-from-sega">making layoffs following its split from Sega in 2024</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Our new approach allows us to service our business needs while being in a strong position to react to opportunities in the market," he added.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">When asked how Relic will choose which classic titles to revive, Dowdeswell said the decision will be a "multifactored process" involving conversations with external partners. It will also be dependent on internal resources and other projects that are in development.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">When it comes to the more experimental projects Relic intends to develop, Dowdeswell said the hope is to bring them to market in under two years.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"We're looking to operate with smaller teams on shorter timeframes, which means likely getting a game in market roughly in the 1-2 year range," he continued. "Budget costs will vary depending on scope, but these titles will have a notably smaller budget than the big Relic RTS games we will continue to work on."</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">News Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer news editor Chris Kerr is an award-winning journalist and reporter with over a decade of experience in the game industry. His byline has appeared in notable print and digital publications including Edge, Stuff, Wireframe, International Business Times, and&nbsp;</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="http://pocketgamer.biz/">PocketGamer.biz</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. Throughout his career, Chris has covered major industry events including GDC, PAX Australia, Gamescom, Paris Games Week, and Develop Brighton. He has featured on the judging panel at The Develop Star Awards on multiple occasions and appeared on BBC Radio 5 Live to discuss breaking news.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Grand Theft Auto VI Could Lose Over 40% of Sales Skipping PC Release This Year; Game Will Meaningfully Drive Console Sales]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/grand-theft-auto-vi-skipping-pc-lose-40-sales/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/grand-theft-auto-vi-could-lose-over-40-of-sales-skipping-pc-release-this-year-game-will-meaningfully-drive-console-sales.1104822/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/grand-theft-auto-vi-skipping-pc-lose-40-sales/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Grand Theft Auto VI skipping PC at launch could result in over 40% sales, according to Take-Two's CEO Strauss Zelnick.</p>
<p>Speaking with <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/take-two-boss-unconcerned-by-plummeting-ps5-and-xbox-sales-insists-gta-6-will-cause-a-meaningful-uptick-in-console-sales-in-2025">IGN</a> ahead of the publisher's <a href="https://wccftech.com/grand-theft-auto-vi-is-still-scheduled-to-release-this-fall-take-two-full-expects-to-support-the-nintendo-switch-2/">recent financial results</a> about the game skipping PC at launch, Zelnick essentially said that the highly-anticipated game will unsurprisingly eventually release on PC, highlighting that, historically, Rockstar has started with some platforms before moving on to others, so even a game as anticipated as the next entry in the popular series is not going to break this trend.</p>
<p>Still, PC sales make up a large amount of total sales for almost every multiplatform game, and it won't be any different for Grand Theft Auto VI, as, according to the Take-Two CEO, the PC version of any multiplatform game can generate over 40% of overall sales. On the other hand, launching on PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X and S only is likely to drive console sales out of the current slump, as Zelnick believes this is what is going to happen this year with the release not only of GTA VI but of other games as well, even in the United States despite tariffs not making things any easier.</p>
<p>Grand Theft Auto VI is launching this Fall on PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X|S worldwide. However, the game's ambitious scope could cause a delay, which wouldn't be the first for Rockstar Games.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nvidia’s RTX 5090 power connectors are melting]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/609207/nvidia-rtx-5090-power-connector-melting-burning-issues</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nvidia%E2%80%99s-rtx-5090-power-connectors-are-melting.1104819/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/news/609207/nvidia-rtx-5090-power-connector-melting-burning-issues<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Ah shit, here we go again. Two owners of Nvidia’s new RTX 5090 Founders Edition GPUs have reported melted power connectors and damage to their PSUs. The images look identical to reports of <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/10/25/23422349/nvidia-rtx-4090-power-cables-connectors-melting-burning">RTX 4090 power cables burning</a> or melting from two years ago. <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/11/18/23466974/nvidia-rtx-4090-power-cable-12vhpwr-melt-burn-plugged-in">Nvidia blamed</a> the issue on people not properly plugging the 12VHPWR power connection in fully and the PCI standards body <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/12/1/23488276/nvidia-12vhpwr-cable-16-pin-pci-sig-response">blamed Nvidia</a>.</p><p><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/nvidia/comments/1ilhfk0/rtx_5090fe_molten_12vhpwr/">A Reddit poster</a> upgraded from an RTX 4090 to an RTX 5090 and noticed “a burning smell playing <em>Battlefield 5</em>,” before turning off their PC and finding the damage. The images show burnt plastic at both the PSU end of the power connector and the part that connects directly to the GPU. The cable is one from <a href="https://www.moddiy.com/products/ATX-3.0-PCIe-5.0-600W-12VHPWR-16-Pin-to-16-Pin-PCIE-Gen-5-Power-Cable.html">MODDIY</a>, a popular manufacturer of custom cables, and the poster claims it was “securely fastened and clicked on both sides (GPU and PSU).”</p><p>While it’s tempting to blame the MODDIY cable, Spanish <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Nw7HaVRUN9k">YouTuber Toro Tocho</a> has experienced the same burnt cable (both at the GPU and PSU ends) with an RTX 5090 Founders Edition while using a cable supplied by PSU manufacturer FSP. Plastic has also melted into the PCIe 5.0 power connector on the power supply.</p><p>Nvidia originally introduced the 12VHPWR power connector on its RTX 40-series GPUs, and power supplies also debuted to support the new standard. The RTX 4090 Founders Edition was able to draw 450 watts over the 12VHPWR connector, while the new RTX 5090 draws up to 575 watts over a cable that’s rated up to 600 watts. After early issues with RTX 4090 connectors melting, PCI-SIG, the standards organization responsible for the 12VHPWR connector, has now updated it to a new 12V-2x6 connector on the GPU side and in some cases the PSU side, too.</p><p>The 12V-2x6 connector has shorter sensing pins and longer conductor terminals, to improve reliability. “This might not sound like a huge difference, but it matters in ensuring that the power cable has been properly connected to whatever device is going to be pulling power from your system’s power supply,” <a href="https://go.corsair.com/c/482924/490888/8513?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.corsair.com%2Fuk%2Fen%2Fexplorer%2Fdiy-builder%2Fpower-supply-units%2Fevolving-standards-12vhpwr-and-12v-2x6%2F%3F" rel="sponsored">explains Corsair</a>.</p><p>Nvidia uses the 12V-2x6 connector on its RTX 50-series GPUs, but you can still use existing 12VHPWR cables. “To be clear, this is not a new cable, it is an updated change to the pins in the socket, which is referred to as 12V-2x6,” says Corsair. PSU manufacturers like Corsair and MSI have adopted colored pins on their 12VHPWR cables so that if you can still see the yellow or grey pins it means the connector isn’t seated properly.</p><p>While Intel and AMD are both members of the PCI-SIG group that helped develop the 12VHPWR power connector, only Nvidia has adopted the standard so far. Even AMD’s upcoming <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/6/24336246/amd-radeon-rx-9070-series-rdna-4-fsr-4-ces-2025">Radeon RX 9070-series</a> are using existing 8-pin PCIe connections instead. AMD even suggested the 12VHPWR connector was a fire hazard in late 2022, when the company’s gaming marketing director Sasa Marinkovic <a href="https://x.com/SasaMarinkovic/status/1593243804538372096?">tweeted</a> “Stay safe this holiday season” alongside a picture of 8-pin connectors.</p><p>12VHPWR has been <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Y36LMS5y34A">branded a “dumpster fire,</a>” thanks to design oversights that make it relatively easy for end users to not properly connect the cable securely. Cablemod was also <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/2/8/24029465/after-74500-in-damage-cablemod-is-fully-recalling-its-nvidia-12vhpwr-gpu-power-adapters">forced to recall</a> its 12VHPWR GPU power adapters last year after reports of melted adapters.</p><p>We’ve reached out to Nvidia to comment on these latest reports of RTX 5090 power connector issues, but the company did not respond in time for publication.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Valve Bans Forced In-Game Ads From All Steam Titles]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/valve-steam-adverts-ads-ban-free-to-play-1851759164</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/valve-bans-forced-in-game-ads-from-all-steam-titles.1104816/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/valve-steam-adverts-ads-ban-free-to-play-1851759164<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>If you, like most people on Earth, a frequent mobile gamer, you’ll be all-too aware of the bane of in-game ads. Because the freemium model proves by far the most successful way to release games on telephones, you pay by sitting through agonizing ads with fake countdown timers, ‘x’ buttons that don’t close anything, and faux-interactivity designed to trick you into tapping through to the store. Valve has now made it abundantly clear that anything like this on their PC store means an instant ban.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="194341" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="The Top Ten Most Played Games On Steam Deck: March 2023 Edition" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="219" data-playlist="194341,194651,196447" data-current="194341"><div><p>The Top Ten Most Played Games On Steam Deck: March 2023 Edition</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/194341/194341_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/194341/194341_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/194341/194341_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/194341/194341_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/19799.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>As <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.gamingonlinux.com/2025/02/valve-ban-advertising-based-business-models-on-steam-no-forced-adverts-like-in-mobile-games/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.gamingonlinux.com/2025/02/valve-ban-advertising-based-business-models-on-steam-no-forced-adverts-like-in-mobile-games/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">spotted by <em>GamingOnLinux</em></a></span>, Valve’s encyclopedic Steamworks Documentation has been updated to make much more clear that it refuses to sell any game that relies on in-game advertising for its business model. That means no games can require players to watch ads to be able to play, nor hide any elements of a game behind a commercial. And it goes further, banning the use of viewing ads to gain in-game advantages, rewards, or time.</p><p>“Developers should not utilize paid advertising as a business model in their game,” <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://partner.steamgames.com/doc/marketing/advertising&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://partner.steamgames.com/doc/marketing/advertising" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">say Valve’s instructions</a></span>, “such as requiring players to watch or otherwise engage with advertising in order to play, or gating gameplay behind advertising. If your game’s business model relies on advertising on other platforms, you will need to remove those elements before shipping on Steam.” The company suggests switching to an up-front payment, or keeping the game “free” but keeping upgrades as paid DLC. The rules then say,</p><blockquote data-type="BlockQuote"><p>Developers should not use advertising as a way to provide value to players, such as giving players a reward for watching or engaging with advertising in their game.</p></blockquote><p>For people who never play games on mobile, these might seem quite bizarre things to need to rule out: while video games have, for decades, included in-game ads (or even existed to <em>be </em>advertising), gatekeeping actual play behind commercials has only been a very occasional, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/nba-2k-just-keeps-putting-unskippable-ads-in-a-60-vide-1845443416&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/nba-2k-just-keeps-putting-unskippable-ads-in-a-60-vide-1845443416">very egregious matter</a></span>. On mobile, it’s the norm.</p><p>If you’ve played a match-3, or a merger game, or any number of mock-RTS games, you’ll be very familiar with the requirement to sit through 30 seconds of a puzzle game being played infuriatingly badly, or a flashing icon begging you to tap on an army unit, or the most extraordinarily high-quality CG animation promoting a game that plays like it was made on a VIC-20. A tiny circle counts down from 30 seconds, after which the advert doesn’t end, and then it cuts to a new screen with a new timer, replaced by an ‘x’ so tiny that if you don’t tap it with a tungsten needle it’ll take you to the store page. After all that, you’ve now got enough imaginary energy to take two more turns at the game you wish you were allowed to enjoy.</p><p>This is, however, extraordinarily profitable, and while you and I might scream into the void that we just want to pay $5 to own the game outright, the moment you put a price on an unknown mobile game it’s doomed to obscurity. And while Steam may not have been plagued by the same issues, it makes a lot of sense for Valve to make these rules clear for those hoping to just port their game and business model over to PC, wholesale.</p><p>If anything, it’s very surprising that this isn’t already a fire that needs putting out, rather than some preventative measures. The mobile market proves that are squillions of people who are content to sit through countless ads to play games, so you’d think there would have already been a bigger push to see if the same could happen with PC’s free-to-play audiences. Small mercies, I guess.</p><p>Valve makes clear companies <em>can</em> still advertise in games. Those awkward billboards and real-world brand cosmetics are still fine to include, although Steam does stipulate that these must not be “disruptive” and are “appropriate within the context of the game.”</p><p>It’s worth noting this does also block previous gross behavior we’ve seen from the biggest names, the likes of 2K, filling basketball games with unskippable ads and so on.</p><p><strong>Updated: 10/02/2025, 10:13 a.m. ET:</strong> The wording of the post has been slightly adjusted to make clear this was already a rule, but made much more prominent in a new update.</p><p>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Take-Two Boss Unconcerned by Plummeting PS5 and Xbox Sales, Insists GTA 6 Will Cause 'A Meaningful Uptick in Console Sales' in 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/take-two-boss-unconcerned-by-plummeting-ps5-and-xbox-sales-insists-gta-6-will-cause-a-meaningful-uptick-in-console-sales-in-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/take-two-boss-unconcerned-by-plummeting-ps5-and-xbox-sales-insists-gta-6-will-cause-a-meaningful-uptick-in-console-sales-in-2025.1104813/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/take-two-boss-unconcerned-by-plummeting-ps5-and-xbox-sales-insists-gta-6-will-cause-a-meaningful-uptick-in-console-sales-in-2025<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/grand-theft-auto-vi">Grand Theft Auto 6</a> is set to launch fall 2025 on PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X and S only, leaving one platform in particular out in the cold: PC.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s an omission in keeping with developer Rockstar’s playbook for its previous games, but in 2025 feels outdated. And, given the increasing importance of the PC for a multiplatform game’s success, is GTA 6’s no-show on PC a missed opportunity or even a mistake?</p><p data-cy="paragraph">IGN put that question to Take-Two boss Strauss Zelnick ahead of the company’s recent financial results, and in his response he teased GTA 6’s <em>eventual</em> release on PC.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“So with Civ 7 it's available on console and PC and Switch right away,” Zelnick said of Firaxis' recently launched Civilization 7. “With regard to others in our lineup, we don't always go across all platforms simultaneously. Historically, Rockstar has started with some platforms and then historically moved to other platforms.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Rockstar fans have noted the studio's historical reluctance to release other past games on PC day-and-date with console, as well as its fraught relationship with the modding community over the years. Still, some had hoped that a game as big as GTA 6 could be a turning point for the studio's PC gaming attitude.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Big Rockstar titles tend to get to PC eventually, but the question of how long PC gamers will have to wait for what could end up being one of the biggest games ever remains. Given GTA 6’s fall 2025 release window, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/gta-6-release-date-still-set-for-fall-2025-take-two-ceo-insists-we-feel-really-good-about-it">which Take-Two is still confident in</a>, it seems likely PC players won’t get to play the game until 2026 at the earliest.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In December 2023, a former developer at Rockstar <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ex-rockstar-dev-tries-to-explain-why-gta-6-is-coming-to-pc-after-ps5-and-xbox-series-x-and-s"><u>attempted to explain why GTA 6 is coming to PC after it hits PS5 and Xbox Series X and S</u></a>, and called on PC gamers to give the studio the “benefit of the doubt” over its controversial launch plans.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">But how big of a missed opportunity could skipping PC for GTA 6’s launch be? Zelnick told IGN that the PC version of a multiplatform game can generate 40% of overall sales, or even more with certain games.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">That stat came as part of a discussion about the current console generation, which has seen sales of the PS5 and Xbox Series X and S — the two consoles GTA 6 launches on later this year — plummet. While Nintendo has the Switch 2 waiting in the wings, neither Sony nor Microsoft have announced their next-gen consoles. How long before the industry needs the PlayStation 6 and whatever Xbox is next?</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Zelnick pointed to the PC platform as growing in importance, even as console sales fall, while publishers wait for Sony and Microsoft’s next moves.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“We have seen PC become a much more and more important part of what used to be a console business, and I wouldn't be surprised to see that trend continue,” he said. “Of course, there will be a new console generation.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In any case, according to Zelnick, the release of GTA 6, which is expected to be the biggest entertainment launch of all time, will drive console sales as fans jump into the current generation for the first time in order to play the game.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“When you have a big title in the market and we have many of them coming, historically that has sold consoles,” Zelnick said.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“And I think that will happen this year. I don't think tariffs are going to be our friend, but I think there will be a meaningful uptick in console sales in calendar 25 because of the release schedule, not just coming from us, but coming from others. So I'm not concerned about that [console sales falling]. I think the trend that you'd want to focus on is this increasing share of the market that is reflected in PC.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Indeed, many see the PlayStation 5 Pro as a future 'GTA 6 machine,' in the hopes it will be the best platform to play the game when it comes out. However, tech experts believe <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/will-ps5-pro-run-gta-6-at-4k60-probably-not-say-the-experts">the PS5 Pro probably won't run GTA 6 at 4K60</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Talks Switch 2 Demand And Gives Small Update On Pricing]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-talks-switch-2-demand-and-gives-small-update-on-pricing/1100-6529342/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-talks-switch-2-demand-and-gives-small-update-on-pricing.1104810/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-talks-switch-2-demand-and-gives-small-update-on-pricing/1100-6529342/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529342">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Some new details about Nintendo's plans for the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/switch-2-release-date-specs-display-price/1100-6520278/" data-ref-id="1100-6520278">Switch 2 launch</a> have been revealed in the company's latest earnings briefing, with president Shuntaro Furukawa revealing that Nintendo is preparing for a high level of demand for the new console. The executive also discussed Nintendo's philosophy regarding pricing for the Switch 2 and confirmed there are no plans right now for a Switch price cut.</p><p>While answering shareholders' questions about the launch, Furukawa revealed that Nintendo is anticipating a high level of demand for the new console. "As of now, we are taking the risk and proceeding with production to meet as large a demand as possible," Furukawa said, adding that Nintendo would be estimating the initial demand for the console based off the reaction to its <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/now-we-know-exactly-when-switch-2-nintendo-direct-is-happening/1100-6529256/" data-ref-id="1100-6529256">April 4 Switch 2 Nintendo Direct</a>, as well as the response to its hands-on <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/heres-how-to-try-the-switch-2-before-its-released/1100-6528849/" data-ref-id="1100-6528849">Switch 2 Experience events</a>.</p><p>Nintendo is also making preparations in case it needs to quickly ramp up production of the consoles, as was the case when the original Nintendo Switch experienced supply issues in 2020. "As was true with Nintendo Switch, we believe it will not be easy to rapidly increase production capacity," Furukawa said. "So based on our prior experience, we are making preparations to be able to respond as quickly as possible."</p><div tabindex="0" data-id="641707132" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6465596,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Nintendo%20Switch%202%20%E2%80%93%20Official%20First%20Look%20Reveal%20Trailer&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:141,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:false,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/nintendo-switch-2-official-first-look-reveal-trailer\/2300-6465596\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465596\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465596\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465596\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6465596&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6465596,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6529342&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;nintendo-switch-2&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6465596},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6465596\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;Publisher Asset&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4428695-11.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/LOUrtQRx.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1737037800,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="LOUrtQRx" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle" data-embed-type="video" data-ref-id="2300-6465596" data-src="/videos/nintendo-switch-2-official-first-look-reveal-trailer/2300-6465596/" data-width="100%" data-height="100%" data-video-start="0"><div><p>Nintendo Switch 2 – Official First Look Reveal Trailer</p><div><p>         Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?       </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!       </p></div></div><p>       Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.     </p><p>       This video has an invalid file format.     </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div><p>The company seems well-positioned to meet demand this time around, with an <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-could-sell-20-million-units-in-first-year-analyst-says/1100-6528856/" data-ref-id="1100-6528856">industry analyst revealing</a> that Nintendo has lined up a supply chain to avoid another chip shortage. Nintendo has also said that having sufficient supply is a key part of its <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-is-making-preparations-to-discourage-potential-switch-2-scalpers/1100-6529220/" data-ref-id="1100-6529220">strategy to discourage scalpers</a>--although it has run into a different issue with scalpers, with people attempting to <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/people-are-selling-non-transferable-switch-2-experience-tickets-on-ebay/1100-6529103/" data-ref-id="1100-6529103">sell off their non-transferable Switch 2 Experience tickets</a> on eBay.</p><p>The earnings call also included a question about the Switch 2's pricing. While Nintendo hasn't revealed a price or even a ballpark range for the Switch 2, Furukawa has explained some of the factors the company has to consider when it comes to pricing. As well as inflation and exchange rates, which Furukawa notes have "changed significantly" since the original Switch released in 2017, it also needs to "consider the price range that consumers expect for Nintendo products."</p><p>"I cannot tell you a specific price for Nintendo Switch 2 at this time, but we are taking various factors into account," Furukawa said, adding that the company has no plans to change the price of the original Nintendo Switch hardware.</p><p>While Nintendo is staying tight-lipped on the price, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/these-analysts-expect-the-switch-2-will-launch-for-400/1100-6529255/" data-ref-id="1100-6529255">analysts have estimated</a> that the console will cost around $400. The original Nintendo Switch launched for $300 in 2017, though when adjusted for inflation is equivalent to around $388, making a $400 price point for the Switch 2 closer to its predecessor than it first appears.</p><p>Until we get more information about the Switch 2 in the April 4 Nintendo Direct, check out <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/switch-2-release-date-specs-display-price/1100-6520278/" data-ref-id="1100-6520278">everything we currently know</a> about the upcoming console.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jotunnslayer is a stylish bullet heaven that could become your next obsession]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/02/10/jotunnslayer-hordes-of-hel-early-access-review/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/jotunnslayer-is-a-stylish-bullet-heaven-that-could-become-your-next-obsession.1104801/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/02/10/jotunnslayer-hordes-of-hel-early-access-review/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Vampire Survivors has become a genuine cultural phenomenon by this point and continues to add to this legacy with extra characters, tie-ins and more content for startlingly low prices. Perhaps more obvious than this, though, is the legion of clones and impersonators it has spawned in the emerging ‘bullet heaven’ genre. For those who follow new releases on Steam in particular it seems like a new one is announced and/or released every couple of days. The genre as a whole is in real risk of oversaturation and most examples disappear without much fanfare. Occasionally a new one brings something to the table, such as the fun Karate Survivor and the Diablo-like Halls of Torment. Jotunnslayer: Hordes of Hel stays relatively faithful to the established bullet heaven formula, but adds a level of graphical polish that stands out.</p>
<p><iframe title="Jotunnslayer: Hordes of Hel | Early Access Launch Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/cF16KwbeXuQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>In its Early Access form, there isn’t a vast amount of content in Jotunnslayer just, so it’s a little early to judge how satisfying the full game will be. In fact, I’d probably go so far as to say that you are paying for an extended demo with the promise of a fully fleshed out experience – something that is becoming a familiar story with Early Access titles. There are two maps and four characters, with four gods that offer boons in a style similar to Hades. The devs have a clear roadmap laid out for the full release which will increase the number of characters, skills, maps, and gods.</p>



<p>At the start of the game you have a choice of either melee Berserker or the midrange magic user Seeress, with Revenant (archer) and Flame Sister (magic user) unlocked as you progress. Each class has their own set of skills and unique level-ups to choose from, whilst all can benefit from the different Divine boons. At present Thor, Freya, Loki, and Odin are available and they each offer active skills and passive power-ups. Thor is all about strength and thunder spells, whilst Loki offers poison attacks and the potential for more pickups. As you might expect, these are randomly offered with every playthrough being different. There is clear potential for some powerful builds here and the fusion of Hades and Vampire Survivors is a fantastic idea.</p>

<p>Rather than room navigation of Hades, however, you fight on static maps which are far more contained than the sprawling levels in Vampire Survivors. Each run has more of an actual point than many Bullet Heaven games, with a randomised selection of miniquests to complete in order to unlock the run boss. The bosses are massive and intimidating foes that will challenge your builds and use of skills to the max. Initial runs on Easy take only 10 minutes, with the increasing difficulty levels also increasing the duration. As always, level ups and skills are restricted to the specific playthrough but you can upgrade your characters and Gods in the skill tree between runs to receive permanent improvements.</p>

<p>Jotunnslayer is perhaps the best looking Bullet Heaven game I’ve played and the core game is just as addictive and enjoyable as the genre’s best. What is needed, however is more content as the progression just isn’t rewarding enough to keep you playing right now, and the jump in difficulty requires a fair amount of grinding. I will definitely return to the game as more is added, but don’t feel compelled to complete everything that is here just yet. A very promising start and one to keep an eye on for the full release.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Valve Reveals Advertising Rules for Steam Games]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/valve-reveals-advertising-rules-for-steam-games/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/valve-reveals-advertising-rules-for-steam-games.1104798/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/valve-reveals-advertising-rules-for-steam-games/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Valve has a new dedicated page that explains what types of advertisements are supported and not supported on Steam.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Steam has always had these advertising rules. However, recently, a <a href="https://partner.steamgames.com/doc/marketing/advertising" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">new page</a> spotted by <a href="https://www.gamingonlinux.com/2025/02/valve-ban-advertising-based-business-models-on-steam-no-forced-adverts-like-in-mobile-games/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Gaming on Linux</a> has appeared to explain these rules and clarify that the platform doesn’t contain paid advertising or models. The page also explains what constitutes “advertising” in a game, what types of ads developers can implement, and what advertisements shouldn’t be in the game.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 id="h-what-types-of-ads-are-allowed-on-steam">What types of ads are allowed on Steam?</h2>



<p>Steam allows ads with product placement, which includes “real brands, products, personalities, etc., as part of gameplay.” This advertising is accepted when it does not disrupt anything and matches the context of the game—for example, sponsor logos in sports games like football, Formula 1, and more.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Cross-promotions are also allowed, such as promoting bundles, sale events, and more. Players can also include other Steam products or products/brands outside of Steam; however, it’s not allowed “to charge other developers to participate in a bundle or to sell access to a sale page or other page on Steam.” Lastly, developers can also run paid advertising campaigns to increase traffic to their Steam product pages.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 id="h-what-types-of-ads-are-not-allowed-on-steam">What types of ads are not allowed on Steam?</h2>



<p>Coming to the ads that will lead to your game being banned on Steam. Devs are not allowed to “utilize paid advertising as a business model in their game,” meaning you can’t entice players into watching ads to play or gate gameplay behind it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If the game’s business model depends on advertising, the developers must remove those elements before releasing it on Steam. They can also create a single-purchase “paid app” or use microtransactions and DLCs by making the game free to play.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Moreover, the wrong use of advertising, such as creating value for the player, will not be allowed. This means developers can’t put rewards or unique content behind ads on Steam games. Lastly, developers cannot “charge other developers for access to Steam features. These include sale pages, bundles, store pages, franchise pages, etc.”</p>



<p>In other news, Steam now warns players <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/steam-warning-buying-abandoned-early-access/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">before they purchase an “abandoned” game</a>. Also, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/wreckfest-2-early-access-release-date/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Wreckfest 2 is arriving</a> on the platform on March 20. What are your thoughts on Valve’s advertising rules for Steam games? Let us know in the comments or on our new&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/what-should-battlefield-6-take-from-battlefield-5/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">what Battlefield 6 should learn from the previous instalment</a>.&nbsp;Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Roblox under investigation by the US Securities and Exchange Commission]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/roblox-under-investigation-by-the-us-securities-and-exchange-commission</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/roblox-under-investigation-by-the-us-securities-and-exchange-commission.1104795/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/roblox-under-investigation-by-the-us-securities-and-exchange-commission<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Screenshot-2025-02-10-at-12.53.30.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Roblox / US SEC / Eurogamer</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>The US Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) has launched an investigation into Roblox.</p>
<p>As reported by <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-02-07/sec-confirms-game-service-roblox-part-of-active-investigation">Bloomberg</a>, while the investigation is ongoing, the exact focus of the SEC's probing remains unclear. The commission did however acknowledge the investigation was active, and said it could not currently share full details to ensure there was "no harm to the ongoing enforcement proceeding".</p>
<p>The SEC was established after the 1929 Wall Street crash in a bid to protect American citizens from market manipulation. It requires public companies to submit quarterly and annual reports, as well as investigate possible violations of the securities laws.</p>
<figure><div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div><figcaption>Xbox Developer Direct - four promising games also coming to PlayStation.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=afaO_AuPw0o" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>"We have confirmed with Division of Enforcement staff that there are responsive emails between Enforcement staff referencing Roblox and that these emails are a part of an active and ongoing investigation," an SEC spokesperson told Bloomberg, via a Freedom of Information request: </p>
<p>Bloomberg suggests - though it is not confirmed - that the investigation may pertain to November's report that <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/damning-roblox-report-claims-company-inflates-player-numbers-to-investors-by-as-much-as-42">Roblox misled investors by falsely reporting player numbers, and has highlighted yet more examples of inappropriate - and allegedly, illegal - content being shared via the platform</a>.</p>
<p>In response to November's report, Roblox said at the time that it "rejects" its findings and pointed to previously-released details of its efforts to try and combat inappropriate content. It also stressed that it had previously acknowledged that "fraud and unauthorised access to [its] platform may contribute, from time to time, to an overstatement of DAUs".</p>
<p><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/roblox-shares-drop-by-20-as-platform-misses-target-active-users">Roblox shares dropped by 20 percent last week</a> after the platform's reported daily active users fell short of analysts' estimates.</p>
<p>For the fourth quarter (ending 31st December), the number of daily active users fell by four percent to 85.3 million compared to the previous quarter. Wall Street analysts had forecasted 88.4 million. Overall player engagement also declined by 9.7 percent in the same period to 18.7bn hours.</p>
<p>Eurogamer has contacted Roblox for comment.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Steam's overlords still think in-game ads are fine as long as they're "appropriate"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/steams-overlords-still-think-in-game-ads-are-fine-as-long-as-theyre-appropriate</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/steams-overlords-still-think-in-game-ads-are-fine-as-long-as-theyre-appropriate.1104792/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/steams-overlords-still-think-in-game-ads-are-fine-as-long-as-theyre-appropriate<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div>
  

        <p>And I still have an unhealthy fascination with the practice of adding ads to games</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/energizer.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>The Drum</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Cheery mom-and-pop computer game business Valve have created a new Steamworks page for their policy about in-game adverts and advertising in general, with a troubleshooter's list of dos and don'ts for developers.</p>
<p>As Graham pointed out to me just now, Valve's handling of such things hasn't really changed over the past few years, but I can't pass up the opportunity to chew the fat a little about the intriguingly murky, slippery-slope business of turning your virtual world into an ad platform. Also, I had already written this article by the time he pointed that out to me, and I can't bear to send all my precious words to the abyss.</p><!--more-->
<p>Briefly, Valve say it's fine to feature ads inside games if it's "appropriate within the context of the game". Not fine: the use of paid advertising as a business model, as with ports of mobile games that make you watch an advert to unlock stuff, or that dole out rewards for willingly filling your eyes with footage of, say, crypto investors pitching a new wellness diet. If your game makes use of such strategies on other platforms, explain Valve, you will need to strip them out before selling them on Steam. They suggest switching to a single-purchase model or free-to-play with microtransactions instead.</p>
<p>The <a href="https://partner.steamgames.com/doc/marketing/advertising">Steamworks Documentation post</a> in question - spotted by <a href="https://www.gamingonlinux.com/2025/02/valve-ban-advertising-based-business-models-on-steam-no-forced-adverts-like-in-mobile-games/">GamingOnLinux</a> - is quite cut-and-dried on the surface, but ambiguity predictably sneaks in as you start to thrash out the use-case scenarios for a store that gets thousands of new releases a year. Here's what it says about in-game ads being fine as long as they fit the context.</p>
<blockquote><p>"Games may contain real brands, products, personalities, etc as part of gameplay, provided such portrayals are not disruptive and are appropriate within the context of the game. For example, a racing game might feature real life sponsor logos on its race cars, or a skateboard game might include characters wearing real-world brands. Note that all developers must obtain the relevant permission and/or licenses for any copyrighted content contained in their games."</p></blockquote>
<p>There's an interesting tradition of product placement within games, ranging from signboards for pirate sim <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/overboard">Overboard</a>! in the otherwise galleon-deficient G-Police, to <a href="https://www.wired.com/2008/10/obama-campaign/">Obama campaign ads in Burnout Paradise</a>. You can definitely make the case for ads forming a believable aspect of the setting, but even when it's credible, I can't help but ponder what might have been sacrificed in order to meet the client spec. Publishers have, unsurprisingly, expressed qualified approval for the idea. Last year, EA's Andrew Wilson <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/ea-are-thinking-about-inserting-adverts-into-games-but-dont-worry-itll-be-very-thoughtful">promised</a> that any such future measures undertaken by the Battlefield publisher would be "very thoughtful".</p><p>Among the more egregious examples of noxious in-game advertising is the original <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/alan-wake">Alan Wake</a>, would you believe. Alan might sporadically style himself an arthouse novelist, but he's not above <a href="https://kotaku.com/alan-wake-remastered-is-ditching-the-energizer-batterie-1847658945">flying the flag for Verizon and Energizer</a>. Examples of doing it right include the recent reality TV sim <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/the-crush-house">The Crush House</a>, in which you play both the producer and target audience of adverts for other Devolver games.</p>
<p>The Steamworks page adds that "cross-promotional activities on Steam, such as bundles, sale events, and more" are OK-dokey as well. Under what's not allowed, meanwhile, we find the following:</p>
<blockquote><p>"Developers should not utilize paid advertising as a business model in their game, such as requiring players to watch or otherwise engage with advertising in order to play, or gating gameplay behind advertising. If your game's business model relies on advertising on other platforms, you will need to remove those elements before shipping on Steam. Some options you could consider include switching to a single purchase "paid app," or making your game free to play with optional upgrades sold via Microtransactions or Downloadable Content (DLC)."</p></blockquote>
<p>While mandatory ad-watching tends to be associated with mobile, console and PC publishers have tried it too. 2K <a href="https://stevivor.com/news/nba-2k21-inserts-unskippable-ads-pre-game-loading-screens/">once added unskippable ads to NBA 2K21</a>, for instance, rolling them back after an outcry.</p>
<p>The post further comments that devs "should not use advertising as a way to provide value to players, such as giving players a reward for watching or engaging with advertising in their game".</p>
<p>With my shitpost hat firmly jammed down around my devil's advocate horns, I feel that weaving an advert into a setting that absolutely doesn't support adverts would be a thrilling designer's challenge. "Perhaps it deserves a gamejam", I impishly say aloud to myself, smiling at the torch-waving hordes of Steam users outside my window. Here's some homework for the comments: how would you advertise, say, Papa Johns in The Lord Of The Rings? It shouldn't be that tricky, really, given that the Orcs are <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dY4V3UUY95A">already familiar with the concept of menus</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>