<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 10:36:53 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[People Can Fly confirmed as Gears of War: E-Day co-developers]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/01/28/people-can-fly-confirmed-as-gears-of-war-e-day-co-developers/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/people-can-fly-confirmed-as-gears-of-war-e-day-co-developers.1093506/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/01/28/people-can-fly-confirmed-as-gears-of-war-e-day-co-developers/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>People Can Fly has revealed that they are a co-development partner for <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/gears-of-war-e-day">Gears of War: E-Day</a>, working alongside series leads The Coalition on the prequel third person shooter.</p>
<p>The Polish studio has historic ties to the franchise, having been a co-development partner to Epic Games through the original Gears of War trilogy, before then becoming lead developer on <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2013/03/18/gears-of-war-judgment-review-xbox-360/">Gears of War: Judgment</a>.</p>
<p><iframe title="Gears of War: E-Day | Official Announce Trailer (In-Engine)" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/12m0bw1W_tk?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>Gears of War: E-Day will be a prequel to the series as a whole, set 14 years before the original and depicting the events of Emergence Day, where the Locust suddenly emerged from below the cities of Sera. Not only that, but it’s an origin story for the series’ most popular protagonist, Marcus Fenix, and his long-standing friendship with Dom, from the Pendulum Wars.</p>
<p>CEO Sebastian Wojciechowski said, “Returning to collaborate on the next chapter of this legendary saga is both a privilege and an exciting opportunity to build upon the intense, visceral action and rich storytelling that fans have come to love. We are deeply grateful for our partners’ trust and support on this journey.”</p>

<p>Guillaume Barry, Development Director at PCF added, “Our team at People Can Fly, made up of dedicated Gears of War fans, is pouring everything we have into creating an experience that will exceed expectations. While we can’t share more just yet, we’re eager for the day when we can show all the exciting things we’ve been working on.”</p>
<p>This announcement will be a boost for the studio, which has had a difficult time of late. In December, <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/12/11/people-can-fly-suspend-project-and-layoff-120-employees/">they laid off 120 employees</a> from a headcount of around 700, reduced their self-publishing strategy and scaled back on several projects. As a publicly listed company on the Warsaw Stock Exchange, being able to announce a steady gig like Gears of War: E-Day will no doubt be a boost to their profile – there was a healthy bump yesterday, though<a href="https://www.google.com/finance/quote/PCF:WSE?window=MAX"> the stock’s trend has been downward since 2021</a>.</p>
<p>That said, their partnership with Microsoft was already known, having <a href="https://www.techpowerup.com/310133/people-can-fly-selected-to-make-project-maverick-for-microsoft">confirmed work on a game codenamed Project Maverick back in 2023</a>. This was already expected to be a Gears of War project, given those historic ties, but has now been made clear.</p>
<p>The one thing that <em>isn’t</em> clear is what this means for a Gears of War: E-Day release window. The game was <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/06/09/gears-of-war-e-day-revealed-prequel-to-the-original-series/">announced during the Xbox Games Showcase in June 2024</a>, but has no release date announced and was absent from the Developer_Direct stream last week.</p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://peoplecanfly.com/partnership-announcement/">People Can Fly</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Conspiracy was briefly afoot in the Marvel Rivals community following NetEase hero plant rumours]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/conspiracy-was-briefly-afoot-in-the-marvel-rivals-community-following-netease-hero-plant-rumours</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/conspiracy-was-briefly-afoot-in-the-marvel-rivals-community-following-netease-hero-plant-rumours.1093503/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/conspiracy-was-briefly-afoot-in-the-marvel-rivals-community-following-netease-hero-plant-rumours<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div>
  

        <p>The tragedy of Paste Pot Pete</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/marvel-rivals-heroes-on-cliff.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Rock Paper Shotgun/NetEase Games</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>The <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/marvel-rivals">Marvel Rivals</a> community was briefly awash with rumours than publisher NetEase were playing 4D chess with their hero-loving hearts last week, according to a new report by Michael Cripe for <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/marvel-rivals-fans-fear-netease-is-planting-fake-hero-leaks-to-throw-off-dataminers-but-whats-really-going-on">Ian Games</a> The rumours began in a Discord for the team <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/genres/shooter">shooter</a> named Marvel Rivals Leaks, where user Keone speculated that NetEase were seeding fake information on upcoming heroes for dataminers to find.</p>
<!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="The Fantastic Four Join Marvel Rivals!" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Xg2ea9O95bA?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>The Fantastic Four Join Marvel Rivals!</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Xg2ea9O95bA?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/Xg2ea9O95bA?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Xg2ea9O95bA" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>"It has come to our attention that the devs have set up fake characters to catch leakers," wrote Keone in the Discord. "Not only the ones in the code - but potentially inside sources too". They then gave a list of previously rumoured heroes they now believed were "very likely fake", including Quicksilver, Professor X, and Paste Pot Pete, who I hadn't heard of until now and suddenly I have a renewed interested in Marvel.</p>
<p>The Discord, says the report, had previously found some success catching heroes before their official announcement, such as the Fantastic Four. The rumour gained some traction before reaching datamining group X0XLeak, who weren't so convinced. "Could they be intended troll by NetEase? I guess,” an X0XLeak spokesninja told IGN. "Would it make sense, in my opinion? No. The way I see it, they could have made it way easier if their goal was to troll us.” They also posted <a href="https://x.com/zvis_ceral/status/1882561140049269227">an X thread</a> as evidence that the rumoured-then-unrumoured heroes existed in the game's code, thoroughly re-rumouring them once again. From IGN's report:</p>
<blockquote><p>X0X’s matfacio told IGN that, if NetEase had truly tucked away bait to trick leakers in this way, it would need to know exactly how dataminers are rummaging through the Marvel Rivals backend, explaining: “I think it would require reverse engineering a reverse engineer.”</p>
<p>The existence of new, hidden hero names in Marvel Rivals doesn’t totally poor cold water on the idea that the developers are attempting to mislead, but some believe the studio would have to go through a lot of trouble — likely more trouble than it’s worth — just to keep the more dedicated fans on their toes.</p></blockquote>
<p>That "trouble" includes things like datamined voice line events and gameplay tags, which some community members reckoned represented <a href="https://x.com/RivalsInfo/status/1882535375387697271">far too much work</a> to be part of an elaborate hoax. Keone did end up amending their initial stance, saying that their post spread beyond their control before they could make edits.</p><p>"The primary assumption from the main leakers (separate from me, the ones who have most info) now is that the ‘plants’ are in fact still real. And the developers did not intend for us to find them," Keone says. "That's why I edited the original post and since deleted it, and have worked to help clear up confusion surrounding it."</p>
<p>Please do have a read of the report in full for all the details and context. I don't play Marvel Rivals myself, but I found this one interesting since - while it's somewhat of a well-seasoned nothing burger - it's fundamentally just a group of passionate players wanting to share the excitement of getting new toys to play with. Hell, <em>I'm </em>excited about Paste Pot Pete and I haven't watched a Marvel film since X-Men 2, nor played a videogame in 15 years.</p>
<p>"A server that started small to spread information has now become a cornerstone of information across the entire community, and sometimes we can misinterpret things or make mistakes," Keone told IGN. "We're a group of people working hard to find and share information, and there's never malice behind what we post. We'll work hard to make sure things don't spread like wildfire again unless it's been verified first, and are grateful for everything we've been able to share thus far."</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[All Sniper Elite Resistance Propaganda Posters—All Locations Guide]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/sniper-elite-resistance-propaganda-posters-locations-guide/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/all-sniper-elite-resistance-propaganda-posters%E2%80%94all-locations-guide.1093500/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/sniper-elite-resistance-propaganda-posters-locations-guide/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Many secrets lurk throughout Sniper Elite Resistance, including Propaganda Posters to track down. Although optional, they serve a great benefit if you find each one in Resistance, and I’ve pinpointed the location of each Poster in the main Campaign.</p>



<p>The sheer scale of <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/sniper-elite-resistance-review/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Sniper Elite Resistance</a>‘s levels means there’s a lot to do. On top of main objectives and optional side tasks, you can do specific actions related to the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/sniper-elite-resistance-trophy-guide-all-achievements-trophies/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Trophies and Achievements</a> list and also track down the countless Collectibles most levels contain.</p>



<p>One of the most important though—other than Workbenches—are Propaganda Posters. This guide has the location of each Propaganda Poster, where to find them, and what they do in Sniper Elite Resistance.</p>



<h2 id="h-what-do-propaganda-posters-do-in-sniper-elite-resistance">What Do Propaganda Posters Do in Sniper Elite Resistance?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Fresh gameplay awaits. Image by Insider Gaming</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Obtaining Propaganda Posters unlocks special Propaganda Challenges in Sniper Elite Resistance.</strong></p>



<p>You can see different gameplay options on <a href="https://sniperelite.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Sniper Elite Resistance</a>‘s main menu. You’ve got the Campaign, Invasion, and Multiplayer, and it also mentions Propaganda Challenges. When you start Resistance, the Propaganda Challenge sub-menu looks uninviting and unreceptive.</p>



<p>This is because all seven challenges are locked from the get-go. <strong>You must find a Poster hidden in seven of the nine levels</strong> in the entire <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/full-sniper-elite-resistance-mission-list/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Resistance Mission List</a>. Each one unlocks a brand-new challenge, but they can be serious time sappers to locate. This is where I step in to save your day.</p>



<h2 id="h-every-propaganda-poster-location-in-sniper-elite-resistance">Every Propaganda Poster Location in Sniper Elite Resistance</h2>



<p><strong>I’ve provided my location on each mission’s map below, and this is where the Sniper Elite Resistance Propaganda Poster is.</strong></p>



<p>Each Poster has a <strong>distinct gloss and shine</strong> which makes it obvious it’s the Collectible. Posters are scattered throughout the levels, but only a specific one is needed. If you want to skip the text, head to my player marker on the map screenshot to quickly and easily find the Posters.</p>



<h3 id="h-dead-drop-propaganda-poster-location">Dead Drop Propaganda Poster Location</h3>



<figure>
<figure><figcaption>Dead Drop Poster. Image by Insider Gaming</figcaption></figure>



<figure><figcaption>Map Location. Image by Insider Gaming</figcaption></figure>
</figure>



<p>Start the level, carry on forward, follow the natural path to the castle, and get to the broken stone bridge. Take the wooden bridge to the left of it that takes you to the river, and <strong>break the planks covering the underground doorway</strong>. Head inside, move ahead, and lockpick the door ahead. Climb the ladder, lock pick the door directly in front of you once you get to the top, and the Poster is on the right on some stairs.</p>



<h3 id="h-sonderzuge-sabotage-propaganda-poster-location">Sonderzüge Sabotage Propaganda Poster Location</h3>



<figure>
<figure><figcaption>Sonderzüge Sabotage Poster. Image by Insider Gaming</figcaption></figure>



<figure><figcaption>Map Location. Image by Insider Gaming</figcaption></figure>
</figure>



<p>The Poster is on the building right next to the “<strong>Find the missing Resistance Cell” Optional Objective</strong>. Simply, head to this location, and go to my marker on the Map Location screenshot above. You can’t miss the Propaganda Poster.</p>



<h3 id="h-collision-course-propaganda-poster-location">Collision Course Propaganda Poster Location</h3>



<figure>
<figure><figcaption>Collision Course Poster. Image by Insider Gaming</figcaption></figure>



<figure><figcaption>Map Location. Image by Insider Gaming</figcaption></figure>
</figure>



<p>Make your way through Collision Course until you reach the train tracks—you can’t miss them. I’m giving you the fastest route to the Poster, <strong>but it is a dangerous one</strong>. If you follow the tracks across the bridge, you <strong>unfortunately come face-on with a tank</strong>. Either take it out or run past it. Follow the tracks around the curved track, and the Poster is on a tunnel’s wall on the right-hand side.</p>



<h3 id="h-devil-s-cauldron-propaganda-poster-location">Devil’s Cauldron Propaganda Poster Location</h3>



<figure>
<figure><figcaption>Devil’s Cauldron Poster. Image by Insider Gaming</figcaption></figure>



<figure><figcaption>Map Location. Image by Insider Gaming</figcaption></figure>
</figure>



<p>Another simple Poster to find in Devil’s Cauldron. Go to my map marker indicated above. It’s a relatively easy path to get there, and the Propaganda Poster is on the <strong>side of a church with a big watch tower at the top</strong>—fixed with a zip line.</p>



<h3 id="h-assault-on-fort-rouge-propaganda-poster-location">Assault On Fort Rouge Propaganda Poster Location</h3>



<figure>
<figure><figcaption>Assault On Fort Rouge Poster. Image by Insider Gaming</figcaption></figure>



<figure><figcaption>Map Location. Image by Insider Gaming</figcaption></figure>
</figure>



<p>This is probably the furthest Poster when it comes to travel distance from the start point. Cross the starting bridge, turn left, and go to the area I’ve highlighted. The Assault On Fort Rouge Poster is tucked away in alleys deep in the bottom-left corner of the level.</p>



<h3 id="h-lock-stock-and-barrels-propaganda-poster-location">Lock, Stock And Barrels Propaganda Poster Location</h3>



<figure>
<figure><figcaption>Lock, Stock And Barrels Poster. Image by Insider Gaming</figcaption></figure>



<figure><figcaption>Map Location. Image by Insider Gaming</figcaption></figure>
</figure>



<p>When Harry spawns, go forward, and immediately take the left path taking you <strong>down a hill and toward a wooden bridge crossing water</strong>. You can either go left or right, <strong>it doesn’t matter</strong>, as either one has Germans to get past. I went right, demonstrated my expert-killing skills (raising the alarm in the process), and went through an open wooden gate to the house the Poster is on. Use my reference point, as the <strong>Poster is hidden behind a decent amount of foliage</strong>.</p>



<h3 id="h-end-of-the-line-propaganda-poster-location">End Of The Line Propaganda Poster Location</h3>



<figure>
<figure><figcaption>End of the Line Poster. Image by Insider Gaming</figcaption></figure>



<figure><figcaption>Map Location. Image by Insider Gaming</figcaption></figure>
</figure>



<p>This Poster gave the most trouble of all, despite the fact all Posters are found near the beginning of the level. I searched everywhere, but it was <strong>sneakily hidden at the top of a ladder!</strong> From the default starting location, head down the ladder on the left taking you to the East side of the level. You should be in the train yard now, and there’s a big, open hangar. Either climb the ladder on the side of the building, or head inside and go up a flight of stairs, and head to the platform that takes you outside. The seventh and final Poster is on the side of the wall.  </p>



<hr>



<p>You should now have all seven Sniper Elite Resistance Propaganda Posters and access to every Propaganda Challenge. Good luck trying to get Gold on every mini-mission, it’s not easy! Let me know how you get on and if you’re chasing all Collectibles.</p>



<p>Plan your time with Sniper Elite Resistance carefully as I’ve also whipped up a handy explainer on <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-long-is-sniper-elite-resistance-game-length/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">how long Resistance is, and the game’s length</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch 2 hands-on invites sent out to lucky few]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-switch-2-hands-on-invites-sent-out-to-lucky-few</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-switch-2-hands-on-invites-sent-out-to-lucky-few.1093494/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-switch-2-hands-on-invites-sent-out-to-lucky-few<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/nintendo-switch-2-joy-cons-magnets_XXp1zAT.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Nintendo / Eurogamer</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Invitations for <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-announces-switch-2-public-hands-on-tour">Nintendo's Switch 2 hands-on events</a> have been sent out to fans who previously applied to try the hotly-anticipated upcoming hardware.
</p>
<p>
If that's you, well, it's worth checking your email inbox and spam folder now.
</p>
<p>
Posting on social media, numerous fans have included screenshots of their successful entries in Nintendo's ticket sweepstake.
</p>
<blockquote data-bluesky-cid="bafyreifp7qyuqqpg4xhwdu7kxf2vl3ds73voeyovxxl52i5koc3jsqpaoq" data-bluesky-uri="at://did:plc:3wbjkpovnrjg5jzpvan33wto/app.bsky.feed.post/3lgrb4yt2es2b">— TheAllergyGirl  🎃🏳️‍⚧️ (<a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:3wbjkpovnrjg5jzpvan33wto?ref_src=embed">@thealogian.bsky.social</a>) <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:3wbjkpovnrjg5jzpvan33wto/post/3lgrb4yt2es2b?ref_src=embed">January 28, 2025 at 1:04 AM</a></blockquote><p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span></p><p>
Of course, not everyone got an invite. Nintendo appears to have notified unsuccessful applicants, too.
</p> <div>

<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>
The <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/its-official-nintendo-switch-2-revealed-after-months-of-waiting">Nintendo Switch 2</a> World Tour will visit London between 11th and 13th April, shortly after the event series kicks off on 4th April in Paris, before visiting other European capital cities such as Berlin, Madrid and Amsterdam.
</p>
<p>Attendees are <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/switch-2-hands-on-registration-now-open-in-europe-and-youll-get-up-to-four-hours-play-time">expected to get around four hours with Switch 2</a> - and presumably will be able to try the new Mario Kart.</p>
<p>
A second version will simultaneously tour North America, with dates in New York, Los Angeles, Dallas and Toronto.
</p>
<figure><div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div><figcaption>Nintendo Switch 2 and Mario Kart 9 have been revealed - but questions remain.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UyPgPcxLlIk" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
The tour is currently set to conclude on 1st June in Seoul, after visiting Tokyo and Melbourne, though further dates in Hong Kong and Taipei are expected.
</p>
<p>
Nintendo is yet to say when exactly Switch 2 will be released - but could it be around then, as the tour concludes?
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[STALKER 2: Heart of Chornobyl Patch 1.1.4 Fixes Performance Degradation and More]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/stalker-2-heart-of-chornobyl-patch-1-1-4-fixes-performance-degradation-and-more/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/stalker-2-heart-of-chornobyl-patch-1-1-4-fixes-performance-degradation-and-more.1093488/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/stalker-2-heart-of-chornobyl-patch-1-1-4-fixes-performance-degradation-and-more/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Yesterday, GSC Game World <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1643320/view/533214336538117150" target="_blank" rel="noopener">released</a> the first new patch of 2025 for STALKER 2: Heart of Chornobyl, updating the game to version 1.1.4. This patch aims to fix existing issues, such as the performance degradation that occurred when shooting and/or aiming while on a save with long playtime.</p>
<p>Here's the full changelog shared by the developer:</p>
<ul>
<li>Fixed crashes and freeze on shaders compilation</li>
<li>Fixed memory leak occurred at Rostok location</li>
<li>Fixed performance degradation when shooting/aiming on saves with long playtime</li>
<li>Implemented fixes that should solve the problem causing saves to be lost on Xbox</li>
<li>Fixed a random crash related to UI animations.</li>
</ul>
<p>STALKER 2: Heart of Chornobyl launched in late November after a long and problematic development process that was interrupted by war, hacks, and an office fire, among other things. While still rough around the edges, the game managed to be a proper follow-up to the first game, as I outlined <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/stalker-2-heart-of-chornobyl-the-anomaly-never-changes/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">in the review</a>:</p>
<p><em>STALKER 2: Heart of Chornobyl is a worthy successor of the original in every regard, good and bad. The vision is the same: an uncompromising game that will often frustrate you, but also offers a unique experience that can hardly be found anywhere else. It's the classic example where the total is more than the mere sum of its parts. Bugs and balance issues are still very much an issue, but they shouldn't stand in your way of playing, especially if you're willing to wait a while for developers and modders to fix them. If you enjoy open world games and shooters and don't mind a challenge, there's no reason for you to pass up on this game.</em></p>
<p>Since then, the team has been hard at work at ironing out some of those issues, like with today's patch. There's undoubtedly more work to do, but GSC Game World is willing to go for it. Their post-launch roadmap also <a href="https://wccftech.com/stalker-2-is-getting-hardware-rt-cross-platform-mods-and-multiplayer-post-launch/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">includes</a> the release of official modding tools, the addition of multiplayer, the support for hardware ray tracing, not to mention at least two expansions promised to owners of the Ultimate Edition/Season Pass.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bulletstorm and Painkiller devs People Can Fly to co-develop Gears of War: E-Day, following spate of layoffs and cancellations last year]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/bulletstorm-and-painkiller-devs-people-can-fly-to-co-develop-gears-of-war-e-day-following-spate-of-layoffs-and-cancellations-last-year</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/bulletstorm-and-painkiller-devs-people-can-fly-to-co-develop-gears-of-war-e-day-following-spate-of-layoffs-and-cancellations-last-year.1093485/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/bulletstorm-and-painkiller-devs-people-can-fly-to-co-develop-gears-of-war-e-day-following-spate-of-layoffs-and-cancellations-last-year<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/gears-of-war-e-day-marcus-dom.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>The Coalition</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/painkiller">Painkiller</a>, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/bulletstorm">Bulletstorm</a>, and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/outriders">Outriders</a> studio People Can Fly will be co-developing <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/gears-of-war-e-day">Gears Of War: E-Day</a>, the upcoming <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/genres/shooter-first-person">shooter</a> in the long-running series of games about large men doing large violence at large bugs from behind medium walls. This is good news! People Can Fly have a pedigree for serving chunky gun chutney with a smile. They've also worked extensively on the series before, notably Judgement Day. E-Day itself is aiming to have a <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/gears-e-day-devs-promise-return-to-horror-from-the-original-games">pronounced horror slant</a>, with the 'Emergence Day' of the title referring to the insectoid Locust's first visit above ground.  </p>
<!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Gears of War: E-Day | Official Announce Trailer (In-Engine)" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/12m0bw1W_tk?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Gears of War: E-Day | Official Announce Trailer (In-Engine)</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/12m0bw1W_tk?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/12m0bw1W_tk?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=12m0bw1W_tk" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>This is good news, also, because last year was a fraught one for People Can Fly. Back in January, we learned from an email obtained by Kotaku that the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/people-can-fly-and-black-forest-games-hit-by-layoffs-according-to-sources-and-leaked-emails">Polish studio were laying off 30 people</a>, alongside 20 people being moved from an unannounced Square Enix project named Gemini. They cancelled another project - <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/bulletstorm-and-outriders-studio-have-cancelled-development-on-a-co-op-action-rpg">a co-op action RPG named Project Dagger</a> - in April. Last December, they <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/bulletstorm-and-painkiller-devs-people-can-fly-let-over-120-people-go-and-suspend-or-downsize-projects">parted wallets with a further 120 workers</a>, shelved one project, and downsized another. "We are redoubling our efforts with new work for hire engagements and focusing on the development of a single independent game," said chief executive officer Sebastian Wojciechowski at the time.</p>
<p>I've enjoyed every People Can Fly game I've played, including Outriders - an excellent shooter, albeit one buried under a clumpy mountain of pre-peed live service cat litter. As for E-Day, it's primed to be a soft series reboot of sorts. "Gears of War: E-Day is not just our next major game; it’s a return to what makes Gears of War games special and authentic," said The Coalition studio head Mike Crump in a <a href="https://peoplecanfly.com/partnership-announcement/">press release</a>. "We’re pleased to be partnering with the talented folks at People Can Fly who have been a part of our franchise’s legacy for so long.”</p><p>Gears Of War has always been an interesting series to me because it initially got my - and I imagine a lot of other people's - attention <a href="https://youtu.be/wy8LRlS1SCc">through an emotional beat in a trailer</a> that never really found its analogue in the actual games themselves. I sort of get the sense that's what E-Day is aiming for, especially if the strains of Mad World in the above teaser are any indication. I haven't kept up with the series all that closely over the years though, so I'm not sure how often they milk that song in marketing. I imagine it's probably a lot now I think about it. Either way, It's been long enough that I could absolutely go for some big man chainsaw misery. Perhaps in 2025, though no confirmation on that.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Helldivers 2 creative director takes sabbatical, promises to start Arrowhead's next game on return]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/helldivers-2-creative-director-takes-sabbatical-promises-to-start-arrowheads-next-game-on-return</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/helldivers-2-creative-director-takes-sabbatical-promises-to-start-arrowheads-next-game-on-return.1093482/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/helldivers-2-creative-director-takes-sabbatical-promises-to-start-arrowheads-next-game-on-return<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div>
        

        <p>After 11 years on the series.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Helldivers-2---Omens-of-Tyranny-_-PS5-%26-PC-Games-1-25-screenshot-(1).png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Arrowhead</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/helldivers-2">Helldivers 2</a> creative director Johan Pilestedt is taking a sabbatical after 11 years on the series, and will start developer Arrowhead's next game on his return.</p>
<p>Helldivers 2 released early last year, but as Pilestedt noted in a social media post, he's been "living it since early 2016", while development of the first game began in 2013.</p>
<p>"11 years of working 'around the clock' on the same IP has made me set aside family, friends and my lovely wife... and myself," he wrote.</p>
<p>"I am going to take some time now to redeem what was lost from all of those that supported me for over a decade."</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Helldivers 2 - Omens of Tyranny | PS5 &amp; PC Games" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Zk0XkX0U_m0?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Helldivers 2 - Omens of Tyranny | PS5 &amp; PC Games</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Zk0XkX0U_m0?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/Zk0XkX0U_m0?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Helldivers 2 - Omens of Tyranny | PS5 &amp; PC Games<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Zk0XkX0U_m0" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>Of course, support on Helldivers 2 will continue while he's away, considering it's proven such a success - it <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/helldivers-2-has-performed-well-ahead-of-expectations-and-topped-more-than-8m-sales">topped 8m sales in March</a> and was <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/helldivers-2-is-now-playstations-biggest-steam-launch-ever">PlayStation's biggest ever launch on Steam</a>.</p>
<p>Arrowhead did recently come under fire, however, for the<a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/helldivers-2-developers-respond-to-criticism-of-killzone-2-crossover-cost"> high cost of its Killzone 2 collaboration</a>, which the studio then gifted to players for free.</p>
<p>"When I'm back - I will start working on the next Arrowhead game," Pilestedt added. That will likely be a long way off, but it's exciting to consider what could be next for the studio.</p>
<div>
<div data-domain="twitter.com"><blockquote><div dir="ltr" lang="en"><p>Hey everyone!</p><p>I am gonna do a sabbatical for a while!</p><p>I know a lot of you are going to think "por qué?" - well, while you have enjoyed <a href="https://twitter.com/helldivers2?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@helldivers2</a> for almost a year, I have been living it since early 2016, and with <a href="https://twitter.com/HelldiversGame?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@HelldiversGame</a> - its since 2013.</p><p>11 years of working "around…</p></div>— Pilestedt (@Pilestedt) <a href="https://twitter.com/Pilestedt/status/1884015181895983223?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 27, 2025</a></blockquote></div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>

<p>Until then, there's the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/helldivers-2-developer-will-be-involved-in-film-adaptation-but-not-as-much-as-you-may-have-hoped">newly announced Helldivers film adaptation</a>. Pilestedt confirmed Arrowhead will be involved, but in a limited capacity as he acknowledged the development team are "not Hollywood people".</p>
<p>Further, Arrowhead CEO Shams Jorjani joked he wants as "many A-list actors as possible" to be in the film, but only if "they all get killed violently immediately".</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Neptunia Riders VS Dogoos Review]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/01/28/neptunia-riders-vs-dogoos-review/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/neptunia-riders-vs-dogoos-review.1093470/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/01/28/neptunia-riders-vs-dogoos-review/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="gp-content-wrapper">

	<article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/Article">

		<meta itemprop="mainEntityOfPage" itemtype="https://schema.org/WebPage" itemscope="" content="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/01/28/neptunia-riders-vs-dogoos-review/">
		<meta itemprop="headline" content="Neptunia Riders VS Dogoos Review">			
		
		<meta itemprop="author" content="Miguel Moran">			
		<meta itemprop="datePublished" content="2025-01-28">
		<meta itemprop="dateModified" content="2025-01-28">
		
		
			
		
								
		
			

																		
		<div itemprop="text">
			
			<p>It’s hard out here for a <em>Hyperdimension Neptunia </em>fan, guys. Every year for what’s felt like a decade, a new game comes out that is tangentially related to this franchise, but never actually a proper sequel or continuation. There’s a lot to love about these anime girl proxies for video game consoles, but they’ve been stuck in a non-canonical limbo for far too long. At some points, this has produced gold – like when one of these spin-offs introduced an anime girl based on the <em>idea </em>of Touhou, or when another was secretly a tightly-crafted character-action crossover with my other favorite niche Japanese game series <em>Senran Kagura. </em>Unfortunately, far more often these <em>Neptunia </em>diversions end up being poorly polished and instantly forgettable. <em>Neptunia Riders VS Dogoos </em>falls hard into that category.</p>
<p><iframe title="Neptunia Riders VS Dogoos | Announcement Trailer | Steam®" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6K3hDTtHNX0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>First of all, don’t even look in the direction of this game if you aren’t already familiar with the <em>Hyperdimension Neptunia </em>series. The game throws you into Uzume and the Gamindustri Goddesses’ latest dilemma so swiftly that it feels more like a side-quest from a different game than its own standalone product.</p>


<p>Due to hastily explained shenanigans, hordes of jelly-shaped pup creatures called Dogoos are invading the realm, so our heroes hop onto some anime-as-hell motorcycles to round ’em all up before it’s too late. Every character, as usual, is incredibly silly and funny and charming. I’m sure if you hop into this blind you’ll get some joy out of Izumi’s straight-man act or Nep-nep’s almost Deadpool-level meta shenanigans. If the game were really fun, the context for these characters and their quest wouldn’t even matter.</p>


<p>That fun, however, is few and far between. <em>Neptunia Riders VS Dogoos </em>consists of five stages, each containing three levels that repeatedly task you with collecting every Dogoo you see – a mission that will take you barely two minutes to complete. In between the missions and the cutscene chatter, you can buy costume accessories and motorcycle upgrades, but it all feels so tepid when the actual gameplay is so short, so basic, and so repetitive.</p>
<p>There’s almost an arena car action angle to this game, but the lack of any mechanical depth or lengthier stages makes everything feel like the tutorial for a bigger game, or a mini-game you’d play in the latest Hoyoverse gacha game to earn some extra gems. The Dogoo collecting is just <em>okay. </em>Your motorcycle handles fine, and the game tries to spice things up by tossing different stage layouts at you and sprinkling a few Mario Kart-style debuff items in your way. Those short levels make it impossible for you to spend enough time in a stage for any of this to click or matter, though.</p>

<p>What hurts is that I don’t hate the idea of a motorcycle-focused Neptunia spinoff at all. If this had been more of a racing game, or a proper car-combat game, or even <em>Rocket League </em>with the cars swapped for motorcycles and the soccer balls swapped for Dogoos, I feel like it’d be golden. What’s here now is so barebones and basic, though, and you’ll have it all wrapped up in barely a couple of hours.</p>
<p>These <em>Neptunia side games</em> have established a pattern of moving on and re-doing everything from scratch in a whole new genre instead of ever building on what the previous game did. If they bucked that trend now, a follow-up to this game could be something special. There’s something here that die-hard fans might appreciate as it is now, but it’s so brief and half-baked. Plus, with how long it’s been since a meaningful entry in this series, I have a hard time believing there are very many die-hard fans left.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

			
		</div>

		
				
	<div id="gp-summary">
		<p>Summary</p><p>
		Neptunia Riders VS Dogoos is not the follow-up that Hyperdimension Neptunia fans want or deserve. There are specks of charm and fun to be had here, but you'll have to dig deep, and after just two or three hours of digging, it'll all be over.	</p></div>
		

	<div id="gp-review-results">

									<div id="gp-good-points">
						<p>Good</p>
						<ul>
														
								<li><i></i>Charming, goofy characters</li>
													</ul>
					</div>
				
									<div id="gp-bad-points">
						<p>Bad</p>
						<ul>
														
								<li><i></i>Barebones, barely there gameplay</li>
														
								<li><i></i>Over in just a couple hours</li>
														
								<li><i></i>Stages are short, simple and far too repetitive</li>
													</ul>
					</div>
							
			</div>

					
	
						
			
			

			
						
		<div>

			<h3>Related stories from TSA			
			</h3>
			
				
				
		</div>

	
		
					
 
	
	
				
	</article>

</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Split Fiction’s new trailer showcases its fantastical co-op action and some spectacular side content]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/01/28/split-fictions-new-trailer-showcases-its-fantastical-co-op-action-and-some-spectacular-side-content/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/split-fiction%E2%80%99s-new-trailer-showcases-its-fantastical-co-op-action-and-some-spectacular-side-content.1093461/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/01/28/split-fictions-new-trailer-showcases-its-fantastical-co-op-action-and-some-spectacular-side-content/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Josef Fares’ Hazelight Studios are arguably the masters of co-op action, and their latest, Split Fiction, is looking like something pretty special. Excitingly, we’re now barely six weeks away from its launch, and just to make sure we keep up that level of excitement, the team have dropped a brand new trailer, showing off more of the co-op action, and some of the extremely varied gameplay styles we’re going to get to enjoy together.</p>
<p><iframe title="Split Fiction | Official Co-op Gameplay Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/0TlySOphMuo?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>The game centres on Mio and Zoe – named for Fares’ daughters – each of which are authors of different genres of fiction. Drawn into their own works, the levels and overarching story are half science fiction and half fantasy, making this an exciting amalgam of the two.</p>
<p>This latest trailer shows off more of the levels, with the first centring on gravity, set within a futuristic cyberpunk city. There’s giant mechs to fight, and some cool gravity tethering action here, as well as some Ghostrunner-esque motorbike sections that look absolutely awesome.</p>
<p>Next up, we get to see a fantasy level, with the two characters gaining the ability to shapeshift into different creatures, becoming a huge ape-like monster, or a fast-moving water-dweller, while you collaborate to make it to the end of the level. If you’ve played <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2021/03/24/it-takes-two-review/">It Takes Two</a> you’ll have an understanding of the wild and varied types of gameplay we’re likely to come across, and this only cements our excitement. It’s little surprise that the game made it into the top ten of our <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/01/10/our-most-wanted-games-of-2025-10-to-6/">Most Wanted for 2025</a>.</p>

<p>As the trailer closes out, Fares shows off some of the additional content that’s going to be available here, with side quest portals opening up at various points to take you into a new world, with another new gameplay style. While you won’t have to play these to advance the story, it looks like you won’t want to miss out on it.</p>
<p>Split Fiction will launch on March 6, 2025 for PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X|S and PC via Steam, Epic Games Store and the EA app. Players can also invite a friend to play with them for free on any platform (Crossplay on PS, Xbox &amp; PC) with the Friend’s Pass.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Next God of War Game Is Reportedly Centered Around Egyptian Mythology]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/next-god-of-war-game-is-reportedly-centered-around-egyptian-mythology/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/next-god-of-war-game-is-reportedly-centered-around-egyptian-mythology.1093431/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/next-god-of-war-game-is-reportedly-centered-around-egyptian-mythology/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>The next God of War game could be making its way to Egypt. According to a report from DanielRPK (<a href="https://www.patreon.com/posts/120905575?utm_campaign=postshare_creator&amp;utm_content=android_share" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">paywall</a>), Sony is casting currently casting for Middle Eastern Actors for a new game.</p>



<p>“Sony is casting Middle Eastern actors for an unknown AAA game, which is likely to be the next God of War that explores Egyptian mythology,” the report says.</p>



<p>It’s important to note that this information hasn’t been confirmed or independently verified by Insider Gaming. Until that happens, please take this news with a grain of salt.</p>



<h6 id="h-podcast-xbox-developers-direct-us-insider-gaming-weekly-podcast">PODCAST<strong>:&nbsp;</strong><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-developers-direct-us-insider-gaming-weekly-podcast/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Xbox Developers Direct Us: Insider Gaming Weekly Podcast</a></h6>



<p>Moving to Egyptian mythology wouldn’t be surprising should it happen. The God of War saga began in Greek mythology before shifting to Norse for the modern games. Moving to a new pantheon would make sense for next era of the franchise. </p>



<p>As far as Egyptian specifically, it’s been mentioned in the past (h/t <a href="https://thegamepost.com/sony-new-god-of-war-game-egyptian-mythology/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">The Game Post</a>) that Sony Santa Monica originally considered centering the game around Egyptian mythology for the 2018 revival before settling on Norse.</p>



<p>“I think the first pitch I gave was that we wouldn’t even know what was happening,” creative director <a href="https://youtu.be/ra_R-K_IoUc?si=Exzp3X0DfFld-6pZ&amp;t=1192" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Cory Barlog said</a>. “So i t was Kratos walking through the desert—because we were, in my mind, still doing Egypt initially—wind, sand blowing all over the place as he’s kind of crawling through and then kind of stands up over a dune and checks out this really fantastic ancient city.”</p>



<p>What do you think about Egypt and its lore being the focus of the next God of War game? Let us know down below, and join more discussions in the official&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, check out the official <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/wwe-2k25-cover-officially-revealed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">cover and reveal trailer</a> for WWE 2K25. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Put Your Ones Up For The WWE 2K25 Cover Star Reveal]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/put-your-ones-up-for-the-wwe-2k25-cover-star-reveal/1100-6529047/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/put-your-ones-up-for-the-wwe-2k25-cover-star-reveal.1093404/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/put-your-ones-up-for-the-wwe-2k25-cover-star-reveal/1100-6529047/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529047">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/wwe-2k25/" data-ref-id="5000-656808">WWE 2K25</a> is on the way, and tonight during WWE Raw on Netflix, the official cover star was revealed. If you've followed the teases, you may have already figured it out, but now it's official: Roman Reigns will be featured on the cover of WWE 2K25.</p><p dir="ltr">Reigns had one of the biggest years of his career in 2024. After 1,316 days as WWE Champion, he finally dropped the title to Cody Rhodes at WrestleMania 40. For months, he was off-screen, as his cousin Solo Sikoa had disowned him post-defeat from their familial faction, The Bloodline, and claimed the role of leader for himself.</p><p dir="ltr">Reigns returned at SummerSlam to reclaim his spot as the "Tribal Chief" to a chorus of massive cheers from the crowd. Turning face but still keeping a harder edge to his character than Rhodes' purer Face That Runs The Place role, Reigns has re-emerged as the fan-favorite good guy the company once spent years failing to create.</p><p dir="ltr">For now, the cover star news is all we have to go on regarding WWE 2K25, but stick around, as we expect to share more soon on this year's wrestling sim. If the WWE 2K24 schedule is any sort of indication, we can expect to see this year's game launch a few weeks ahead of WrestleMania, which would slot it into a March launch some time.</p><p dir="ltr">In my <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/wwe-2k24-review-long-term-booking/1900-6418191/">WWE 2K24 review</a>, I wrote, "As both WWE and the wider format of pro wrestling live through a new golden age, it's fortuitous timing for fans that this year's game is so great. While the MTX-heavy mode feels tacked on like a publisher mandate, there are thankfully several other modes that each feel like they deserve to be played for many months ahead, making them the true centerpieces of your personal WWE universe."</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/111003174123010839883?rel=author">Mark Delaney</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WWE 2K25 Cover Officially Revealed]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/wwe-2k25-cover-officially-revealed/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/wwe-2k25-cover-officially-revealed.1093395/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/wwe-2k25-cover-officially-revealed/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>The WWE 2K25 cover has been officially revealed. As expected from the first tease earlier this month, Roman Reigns will grace the cover of the Standard edition of the game.</p>



<p>The Undertaker will feature on the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/wwe-2k25-deadman-edition-undertaker/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Deadman Edition</a> while the entire Bloodline will be included on the Bloodline edition of the game.</p>



<h6 id="h-podcast-nbsp-xbox-developers-direct-us-insider-gaming-weekly-podcast">PODCAST<strong>:&nbsp;</strong><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-developers-direct-us-insider-gaming-weekly-podcast/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Xbox Developers Direct Us: Insider Gaming Weekly Podcast</a></h6>



<p>This is the second time Reigns will be featured on the game’s base cover, and the first time as the only wrestler. Both he and Becky Lynch were on the cover of WWE 2K20 back in 2019. This time around, however, he’s joined by his “Wiseman” Paul Heyman just outside of the ring.</p>



<p>You can check out the Standard Edition covers and the first trailer for the game, below.</p>



<figure><video controls="" poster="https://insider-gaming.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/WWECover.jpg" src="https://insider-gaming.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/j67CT_7BMS6aQJsk.mp4"></video></figure>



<p>With the cover finally shown, all that’s left is for the full reveal of the game. Luckily, fans won’t have to wait long as full details on the game will be announced on Tuesday, January 28.</p>



<p>Insider Gaming will have full coverage of the reveal, including modes, features, and more.</p>



<p>What do you think of Roman Reigns being the cover athlete for WWE 2K25? Let us know down below, and join more discussions in the official&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read about what studio is <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/people-can-fly-is-co-developing-gears-of-war-e-day/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">working with The Coalition</a> on Gears of War: E-Day, and the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/phoenix-labs-layoffs-closure/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">latest studio to hold layoffs</a> and possibly close.&nbsp;And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gears of War: E-Day: People Can Fly Announced as Co-Developers]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/gears-of-war-e-day-people-can-fly-announced-as-co-developers</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gears-of-war-e-day-people-can-fly-announced-as-co-developers.1093383/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/gears-of-war-e-day-people-can-fly-announced-as-co-developers<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Poland-based game studio People Can Fly has been announced as the co-developer of the upcoming Gears of War: E-Day alongside The Coalition.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In a <a href="https://peoplecanfly.com/partnership-announcement/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">press release</a> People Can Fly says it is "honored to return to the world of Gears of War[.]" The studio previously served as the lead developer of Gears of War: Judgment after co-developing Gears of War 1-3. "Returning to collaborate on the next chapter of this ligendary saga is both a privilege and an exciting opportunity to build upon the intense, visceral action and rich storytelling that fans have come to love."</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/next-gears-of-war-game-officially-revealed-at-xbox-showcase-2024">Gears of War: E-Day was announced</a> at last year's Xbox Showcase and is set to be a prequel to the original trilogy starring younger versions of characters like Marcus Fenix and Dom Santiago. And yes, the original actors will be <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/gears-of-war-e-day-will-feature-marcus-and-doms-original-voice-actors">returning to reprise their roles</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The game will cover the origins of the Locust invasion on Emergence Day. In a sit down with IGN, Brand Director Nicole Fawcette and Creative Director Matt Searcy said that the goal is to <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/gears-e-day-devs-promise-return-to-horror-from-the-original-games">focus on the horror elements</a> from the original trilogy. "What if the ground opened up and monsters came out? Yeah, it's set on a fictional, other planet, but there are very human reactions and stories we get to tell," Searcy tells IGN. "To do that, we need to be able to tell a story that feels like a horror story."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">People Can Fly was founded in 2002 and became known for games like Bullestorm and Painkiller. Epic Games acquired the studio in 2007, briefly renaming the studio Epic Games Poland, before the company spun off independently under its old name and logo.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Gears of War: E-Day will be the studio's next major game after the launch of Outriders in 2021. Be sure to check out our op-ed on why Gears of War needs to <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/gears-of-war-e-day-needs-to-rediscover-the-series-summer-blockbuster-sense-of-fun">rediscover its blockbuster levels</a> of entertainment again with E-Day.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Matt Kim is IGN's Senior Features Editor.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dauntless and Fae Farm studio Phoenix Labs lays off "majority" of employees]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/dauntless-and-fae-farm-studio-phoenix-labs-lays-off-majority-of-employees</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dauntless-and-fae-farm-studio-phoenix-labs-lays-off-majority-of-employees.1093368/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/dauntless-and-fae-farm-studio-phoenix-labs-lays-off-majority-of-employees<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div>
        

        <p>As part of "unfortunate but necessary changes to our operations".</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/dauntless-fae-farm-crop.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Phoenix Labs/Eurogamer</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Dauntless and Fae Farm developer Phoenix Labs has announced another round of layoffs - its fourth since May 2023 - this time affecting the "majority" of staff at the studio.
</p>
<p>
Phoenix Labs enjoyed early success with its first game, free-to-play Monster-Hunter-like Dauntless, and the studio released its second title, Fae Farm, in 2023. However, the developer has faced multiple rounds of layoffs since its acquisition by blockchain company Forte Labs in 2023, starting with job cuts impacting 9 percent of its workforce in May that year. A <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/fae-farm-developer-phoenix-labs-lays-off-34-staff">further 34 layoffs followed seven months later</a>, with an <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/fae-farm-developer-phoenix-labs-lays-off-staff-and-cancels-projects-in-significant-restructure">additional 140 jobs being cut</a> last May. And, unfortunately for employees, layoffs have continued into 2025.
</p>
<p>"Today is another difficult day at Phoenix Labs," the developer <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/phoenix-labs_activity-7289705935696969728-PaIL">wrote in a message posted to LinkedIn</a> on Monday. "We have made the tough decision to part ways with the majority of the studio as part of unfortunate but necessary changes to our operations."
</p>
<figure><div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div><figcaption>Newscast: Four promising Xbox games also coming to PlayStation.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=afaO_AuPw0o" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
We recognise and deeply appreciate the contributions of every individual impacted," it continued. "Their talent, dedication, and creativity have left an indelible mark on our company and our games... To our industry peers, we encourage you to reach out to these exceptional individuals - they are some of the best in the business."
</p>
<p>
As for Dauntless and Fae Farm, the studio says it'll share more on their fate "in the coming weeks", but notes its current focus is on "supporting those affected through this transition."
</p>
<p>
Phoenix Labs' announcement follows a devastating 2024 for the games industry - in which around 13000 employees are believed to have lost their jobs - and continues a January dogged by <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/microsoft-reportedly-makes-small-number-of-layoffs-across-divisions-including-gaming">further layoffs</a> and <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/two-weeks-into-2025-three-studios-are-already-closing-down">studio closures</a>. Ubisoft, for instance, announced it was <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/ubisoft-announces-studio-closure-as-it-lays-off-185-staff">cutting 185 jobs</a> this week, while Jar of Sparks - the studio founded by <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/halo-infinite">Halo Infinite</a> head of design Jerry Hook - confirmed it had <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/halo-infinite-head-of-designs-netease-studio-halting-work-on-first-game-as-it-searches-for-new-publisher">laid off "all" its team</a> earlier this month. Last year, Chris Dring shared his thoughts with Eurogamer on <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/what-is-going-on-with-the-video-games-industry">why these layoffs are happening</a>.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Another Big Day For Layoffs In Another Big Year For Layoffs]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/ubisoft-phoenix-labs-layoffs-studio-closure-far-cry-dauntless</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/another-big-day-for-layoffs-in-another-big-year-for-layoffs.1093365/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://aftermath.site/ubisoft-phoenix-labs-layoffs-studio-closure-far-cry-dauntless<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>I don’t believe any serious person really thought 2025 would magically be different <a href="https://variety.com/2025/gaming/news/video-game-layoffs-2024-report-gdc-1236277739/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">from 2024</a> in terms of video game industry layoffs, but if you are one of those people, I’m sorry. Today Ubisoft let nearly 200 workers go, closing yet another studio in the process, and <em>Dauntless </em>developer Phoenix Labs functionally turned to ash.</p><p>Ubisoft continued its valiant quest to “enhance operational efficiency and maximize value creation,” whatever that means, by <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/ubisoft-reportedly-discussing-buyout-options-with-tencent" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">laying off 185 workers</a>, including the team at Ubisoft Leamington, which assisted on games like <em>Star Wars Outlaws</em>, <em>The Division</em>, and <em>Far Cry 5</em>. The company has also begun “targeted restructurings” at Ubisoft Düsseldorf, Ubisoft Stockholm, and Ubisoft Reflections. This follows two other studio closures in Osaka and San Francisco<a href="https://aftermath.site/ubisoft-xdefiant-shutdown-studio-closure-layoffs" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> just last month</a> on the back of <em>XDefiant</em>'s shutdown, as well as the decision to “ramp down” production in Sydney – all of which resulted in nearly 300 layoffs.</p><p>Since late last year, rumors have swirled of a potential buyout from Tencent, which currently owns nine percent of Ubisoft. However, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/deals/ubisoft-shareholders-talks-over-possible-buyout-terms-sources-say-2024-12-06/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">according to Reuters</a>, Ubisoft has its sights set on a deal that would see the Guillemot family, which founded the company, retain control. Amid all of this, Ubisoft has faced “<a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ubisoft-admits-star-wars-outlaws-underperformed" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">softer than expected</a>” sales of blockbusters like <em>Star Wars Outlaws</em> and multiple employee walkouts over issues like <a href="https://aftermath.site/ubisoft-strike-france-pay-yves-guillemot" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">fair pay</a> and <a href="https://uniglobalunion.org/news/ubisoft-workers-strike-france/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">return-to-office mandates</a>.</p><p>Meanwhile, Phoenix Labs is against the ropes and a punch or two from going down, with the studio saying that the lion’s share of its workers are on the chopping block.</p><p>"Today is another difficult day at Phoenix Labs,” the company <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/phoenix-labs_activity-7289705935696969728-PaIL" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">wrote on LinkedIn</a>. “We have made the tough decision to part ways with the majority of the studio as part of unfortunate but necessary changes to our operations. We recognize and deeply appreciate the contributions of every individual impacted. Their talent, dedication, and creativity have left an indelible mark on our company and our games."</p><p>In 2023, Phoenix Labs was acquired by Forte Labs, a blockchain company. Last year, <a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/what-happens-when-a-secretive-blockchain-company-buys-your-game-studio" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Game Developer</a> reported that Forte cracked down on communication inside and outside of Phoenix Labs, going so far as to keep potential employees in the dark as to who actually owned the studio. That really smart and normal plan is evidently going well.</p><p>In <a href="https://publish.obsidian.md/vg-layoffs/Archive/2025" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">January alone</a>, we’ve seen layoffs at additional studios like <em>Godfall </em>developer <a href="https://www.resetera.com/threads/counterplay-games-godfall-hit-with-layoffs.832239/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Counterplay</a> – which may or may not still be open – <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/splash-damage-jobs-at-risk-following-transformers-reactivate-cancellation" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Splash Damage</a>, and <a href="https://www.enadglobal7.com/press-releases/eg7-undertakes-business-optimization-at-one-of-its-studios/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Piranha</a>.&nbsp;</p><p>As a result of <a href="https://aftermath.site/tiktok-ban-trump-bytedance" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">myriad concerns</a> with which you’re likely familiar, January has felt like it’s lasted a year, which if nothing else is less than two or three years. February, by virtue of having fewer days in it than January, can’t possibly feel longer. So that’s something, unless February somehow turns out to be even more grueling than January, in which case it isn’t.</p></div><div><h2>Stay in touch</h2><p>Sign up for our free newsletter</p></div><div><h2><span>More from Aftermath</span></h2><div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/escape-room-first-time"><h3>My First Escape Room Was Pretty Cool</h3></a><p>Please tell me everything about how you design them</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/oscars-emilia-perez-on-cinema-tim-heidecker"><h3>Stop Watching The Oscars</h3></a><p>They're bad, and you don't have to.</p></div></div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/all">See all posts<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="#000" stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round"><path d="M5 12h13m-6-7 7 7-7 7"></path></svg></a></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New FPGA-powered retro console re-creates the PlayStation, CD-ROM drive optional]]></title>
            <link>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/01/new-fpga-powered-retro-console-re-creates-the-playstation-one-cd-rom-drive-optional/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-fpga-powered-retro-console-re-creates-the-playstation-cd-rom-drive-optional.1093347/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/01/new-fpga-powered-retro-console-re-creates-the-playstation-one-cd-rom-drive-optional/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
          
          


<p>The console won't play original game discs natively, but Retro Remake offers an optional tray-loading CD drive in a separate "<a href="https://retroremake.co/products/superdock-preorder-deposit">SuperDock</a>" accessory; it also includes an internal M.2 drive for an SSD and four additional USB-A ports. Buyers will have to put $5 down on the SuperDock now and pay whatever the final cost ends up being when the console ships (Retro Remake claims to be targeting a price of roughly $40).</p>
<p>Like most Analogue consoles, the SuperStation uses an FPGA chip to emulate the original PlayStation's hardware rather than trying to emulate the console in software as most PC-based or Raspberry Pi-based retro consoles do. This has the benefit of reproducing all the quirks and oddities of the old hardware, making games run more accurately (and with lower input latency) than they do in software-based emulators.</p>
<p>But unlike most of Analogue's consoles, the SuperStation supports installing and running other FPGA "cores" to re-create other consoles (think of FPGA cores like you'd think of software emulators—generally, you're going to need a separate one for every console you want to emulate). The SuperStation is based on the established MiSTer platform, which already has <a href="https://mister-devel.github.io/MkDocs_MiSTer/cores/what/">a huge library of console and PC cores available</a>, including but not limited to the Nintendo 64 and Sega Saturn. Retro Remake also says that being based on the MiSTer platform makes the console "open source from day 1."</p>
<p>Analogue has its own competing open source library of FPGA cores, called <a href="https://www.analogue.co/developer">OpenFPGA</a>. But so far, the handheld Analogue Pocket is the only one of the company's consoles to support the initiative.</p>


          
                  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Switch-Exclusive Fantasy Life Sequel May Actually Be PS5-Bound]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/switch-exclusive-fantasy-life-sequel-may-actually-be-ps5-bound/1100-6529055/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/switch-exclusive-fantasy-life-sequel-may-actually-be-ps5-bound.1093344/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/switch-exclusive-fantasy-life-sequel-may-actually-be-ps5-bound/1100-6529055/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-main">

      
                    
  
              <header id="masthead"><nav></nav></header>      
                            <div id="site-wrapper" role="main">
          <div id="default-content">
        
          <p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p>
  
    <article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529055">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>When <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fantasy-life-i-the-girl-who-steals-times-new-trailer-shows-off-new-jobs-and-island-customization/1100-6519560/" data-ref-id="1100-6519560">Fantasy Life i: The Girl Who Steals Time</a> was unveiled by Level 5 in 2023, the game was originally announced as only going to Nintendo Switch. However, a new report suggests that The Girl Who Steals Time is also making the leap to Sony's PlayStation 5 and PlayStation 4.</p><p>Via <a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/level-5s-next-game-is-also-coming-to-playstation-according-to-a-sony-leak/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Video Games Chronicle</a>, Gematsu spotted <a href="https://x.com/gematsu/status/1883872387562946769" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">a PlayStation Store page</a> for The Girl Who Steals Time that listed April 23 as a release date for both the PS4 and PS5 versions. The page was subsequently removed, but a screencap was posted on Gematsu's X account.</p><div data-embed-type="tweet" data-src="https://twitter.com/gematsu/status/1883872387562946769" data-has-image="true"><blockquote data-conversation="none" data-mce-disable-toolbar="true"><p dir="ltr">A PlayStation Store page for FANTASY LIFE i: The Girl Who Steals Time was published before being quickly removed last night. It lists PS5 / PS4 versions, and an April 23 release date (or April 24—time zones). Currently only *officially* announced for Switch release in April. <a href="https://t.co/MlD0UIjOix" rel="nofollow ">pic.twitter.com/MlD0UIjOix</a></p>  — Gematsu (@gematsu) <a href="https://twitter.com/gematsu/status/1883872387562946769?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 27, 2025</a></blockquote>              </div><p>Fantasy Life i: The Girl Who Steals Time was announced as a 2023 title for Switch before it was subsequently delayed to 2024 and again to April of this year. Like its predecessor, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/fantasy-life-review/1900-6415904/" data-ref-id="1900-6415904">Fantasy Life</a>, The Girl Who Steals Time is a role-playing life simulation game. The new game also introduces a time travel element, as players will be able to customize a ruined island by going back one thousand years into the past while making changes that affect the present and future. Players can also assume up to 14 different jobs on the island, including farmer and artist.</p><p>Level 5 is also planning to release two other games this year, including <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/professor-layton-and-the-new-world-of-steam-gets-2025-release-window-and-new-trailer/1100-6519543/" data-ref-id="1100-6519543">Professor Layton and The New World of Steam</a> and Inazuma Eleven: Victory Road. Additionally, Level 5's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/videos/decapolice-playable-guide-trailer/2300-6462406/" data-ref-id="2300-6462406">Decapolice</a> is expected to follow in 2026.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article>

    
  

</div>
                      <meta itemprop="seamless-content-list-items" data-list-items="[{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6528927&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/save-on-thousands-of-pc-games-and-unlock-free-steam-keys-during-fanaticals-lunar-new-year-sale\/1100-6528927\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6528961&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/several-popular-gaming-subreddits-are-banning-content-pulled-from-x\/1100-6528961\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6528964&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/dragon-age-the-veilguard-had-far-fewer-players-than-ea-expected\/1100-6528964\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6528966&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/celeste-devs-next-project-earthblade-officially-canceled\/1100-6528966\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6524422&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/marvel-vs-capcom-fighting-collection-drops-to-30-for-playstation-and-switch\/1100-6524422\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6528820&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/fatal-fury-city-of-the-wolves-is-up-for-preorder-including-ps5-exclusive-deluxe-edition\/1100-6528820\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6528919&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/study-finds-majority-of-game-dev-companies-use-generative-ai-already-despite-worker-concerns\/1100-6528919\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6528921&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/why-switch-2-is-significantly-more-powerful-according-to-a-game-dev\/1100-6528921\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6528920&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/new-call-of-duty-dlc-benefits-la-wildfire-relief-efforts\/1100-6528920\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6528922&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/sonic-the-hedgehog-4-gets-march-2027-release-date\/1100-6528922\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6528924&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/you-can-now-build-a-cute-farm-with-hello-kitty-and-her-friends-in-minecraft\/1100-6528924\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6528925&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/microsoft-edge-now-features-this-popular-steam-like-feature\/1100-6528925\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6528932&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/netflix-is-raising-prices-again-as-it-discusses-vision-for-video-games\/1100-6528932\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6528916&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/guilty-gear-strive-nintendo-switch-edition-releases-this-week-preorders-available-now\/1100-6528916\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6528936&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/new-xbox-console-update-essentially-removes-external-storage-drive-limits\/1100-6528936\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6528939&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/mortal-kombat-1-adds-a-secret-fight-against-pink-floyd-kind-of\/1100-6528939\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6528937&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/death-stranding-2-crosses-new-development-milestone-as-deadpool-actor-finishes-scenes\/1100-6528937\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6528935&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/sign-up-for-new-sega-account-system-get-a-free-like-a-dragon-pirate-yakuza-costume\/1100-6528935\/&quot;}]">
            </div>
              
    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Alien Series Trailer Reminds Me We Need A New AVP Game]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/alien-earth-new-trailer-teaser-first-person-xenomorph-1851748814</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-alien-series-trailer-reminds-me-we-need-a-new-avp-game.1093320/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/alien-earth-new-trailer-teaser-first-person-xenomorph-1851748814<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="7c7f4479b4c93e2d045b88431a255a94" data-recommend-id="image://7c7f4479b4c93e2d045b88431a255a94" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->FX / Hulu</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="7c7f4479b4c93e2d045b88431a255a94" data-recommend-id="image://7c7f4479b4c93e2d045b88431a255a94" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p><em>Alien: Earth</em>, the upcoming FX series set in the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/predator-prey-2-badlands-secret-movie-animated-hulu-1851681811&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/predator-prey-2-badlands-secret-movie-animated-hulu-1851681811">expansive sci-fi universe</a></span>, is a show we don’t really know much about even though it’s set to arrive later this year. And the latest teaser doesn’t provide much new information, but it is really cool and has me hopeful for the series. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196406" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Why This Under-the-Radar AAA Title Is More Than Just A Far Cry Clone" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="102" data-playlist="196406,195358,195697" data-current="196406"><div><p>Why This Under-the-Radar AAA Title Is More Than Just A Far Cry Clone</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196406/196406_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196406/196406_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196406/196406_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196406/196406_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21954.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>On January 27, FX and Disney (yeah, remember they own the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/alien-movies-ranked-aliens-prometheus-predator-avp-1851621200&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/alien-movies-ranked-aliens-prometheus-predator-avp-1851621200"><em>Alien </em>franchise</a></span> now after buying Fox) released <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://youtu.be/62scKoepHwg&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://youtu.be/62scKoepHwg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">a new teaser</a></span> for this summer’s <em>Alien: Earth</em> series. In the teaser, we watch a Xenomorph creature break out of containment while on board a ship that appears to be crashing on, wait!...oh no...EARTH! Here’s the teaser: </p><p>Here’s the official synopsis for the show:</p><p> “When a mysterious space vessel crash-lands on Earth, a young woman (Sydney Chandler) and a ragtag group of tactical soldiers make a fateful discovery that puts them face-to-face with the planet’s greatest threat.” </p><p>That brief synopsis, like this new teaser and a past one <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://youtu.be/sgTBZmqrAIA&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://youtu.be/sgTBZmqrAIA" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">featuring a screaming alien monster</a></span>, don’t really tell us much beyond the fact that a Xenomorph is going to land on Earth and cause some problems. We do know that this new series will be set two years before the events of the original <em>Alien </em>movie. That places it in the year 2210, about 16 years after<em> Alien Covenant </em>and 22 years before <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/alien-romulus-movie-review-timeline-reddit-4dx-1851625237?_gl=1*m62cv6*_ga*MzQzNjkwNDM2LjE2NDY2NjQ1NzQ.*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczODAxMjMxMi4zMjguMS4xNzM4MDEzMzU1LjQ2LjAuMA..&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/alien-romulus-movie-review-timeline-reddit-4dx-1851625237?_gl=1*m62cv6*_ga*MzQzNjkwNDM2LjE2NDY2NjQ1NzQ.*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczODAxMjMxMi4zMjguMS4xNzM4MDEzMzU1LjQ2LjAuMA.."><em>Alien: Romulus</em></a></span><em>. </em></p><p>Watching that teaser again, all I can think about is how awesome a modern <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/games/aliens-versus-predator&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/games/aliens-versus-predator"><em>Alien Versus Predator</em></a></span><em> </em>game would be. Stalking people in high-fidelity 4K space stations as a nasty Xenomorph sounds great. At the very least, if I can’t get a new <em>AVP </em>game, let’s get some remasters of the original ones. Until then, I’ll just keep playing as the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://bsky.app/profile/zackzwiezen.com/post/3lcetgrevys2v&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://bsky.app/profile/zackzwiezen.com/post/3lcetgrevys2v" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Xenomorph in <em>Fortnite</em></a></span>. </p><p> .<br></p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Sims 1 & 2 reportedly getting PC re-releases this week]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/the-sims-1-2-reportedly-getting-pc-re-releases-this-week</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-sims-1-2-reportedly-getting-pc-re-releases-this-week.1093317/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/the-sims-1-2-reportedly-getting-pc-re-releases-this-week<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div>
        

        <p>As series' 25th anniversary looms.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/sims-1-2-montage.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Eurogamer</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
In just eight days time, <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/video-game-franchises/the-sims">The Sims</a> turns 25 - and EA is reportedly poised to re-release <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/the-sims">The Sims 1</a> &amp; 2 this week as part of the series' quarter-century celebrations. 
</p>
<p>
The Sims 1 &amp; 2 have, of course, long been unavailable in an official capacity, with the 25-year-old original never getting a digital release and its sequel's short-lived Ultimate Collection being yanked from Origin in 2018. That could be about to change, however. Kotaku, citing a "source familiar" with EA's plans, <a href="https://kotaku.com/sims-1-2-remaster-pc-buy-ea-maxis-steam-1851748658">reports</a> re-releases of The Sims 1 &amp; 2 will launch on PC later this week, with all their original expansions included. It's "unclear" if a console release is also coming.
</p>
<p>
Lending further credence to Kotaku's report are the handful of conspicuous teases EA has been sharing to coincide with the start of The Sims' Nostalgia Now week, which runs from 27th-31st January. The series' official website, for instance, now <a href="https://www.ea.com/en-gb/games/the-sims">features</a> a character from the original The Sims surrounded by <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/the-sims-2">The Sims 2</a>'s radial menu.
</p>
<figure><div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div><figcaption>Newscast: Four promising Xbox games also coming to PlayStation.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=afaO_AuPw0o" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
Similarly, the publisher has <a href="https://x.com/TheSims/status/1879218365430182064">posted</a> a short animation - accompanied by the phrase "BRB" - on social media. It features The Sims' iconic spinning Plumbob - initially surrounded by The Sims 2's radial menu, then superimposed on coloured squares reminiscent of The Sims 1's box art. 
</p><p>
Interestingly, the video then transitions to a scene resembling <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/the-sims-3">The Sims 3</a>'s loading screen. Kotaku's report doesn't mention the series' third outing, but fans were slightly stunned earlier this month when, with zero explanation or fanfare, it received its first (still mysterious) update in 15 years. If this means EA has been quietly tinkering under the hood to implement some much-needed stability and compatibility fixes, there'll be a lot of happy Sims players.
</p>
<p>
All of which is to say it could be an  exciting few days for The Sims fans, and that's before EA's big birthday blowout next week. Things kick off with a 25-hour livestream celebration of the series next Tuesday, 4th February, coinciding with the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-sims-4-marking-series-25th-anniversary-with-huge-free-update-adding-70-new-items">release a "huge" free 25th anniversary update for The Sims 4</a>, adding 70+ new items, a new limited-time event, and more.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sony reduces OLED burn-in fears with a three-year warranty on InZone monitors]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/27/24353227/sony-m10s-inzone-oled-burn-in-warranty</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sony-reduces-oled-burn-in-fears-with-a-three-year-warranty-on-inzone-monitors.1093302/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/27/24353227/sony-m10s-inzone-oled-burn-in-warranty<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Sony is upping the limited warranty on some InZone gaming monitors to three years and is <a href="https://www.sony.com/electronics/support/televisions-projectors-monitors/sdm-27q10s/articles/00350326">tossing in OLED burn-in coverage</a> for the 27-inch M10S. The company announced the additional coverage today after launching both the InZone M10S OLED and M9 II LED in <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/9/24/24253167/sony-inzone-gaming-monitor-m10s-480hz-oled">September</a> with only one-year limited warranties out of the box. Sony says other than that, the limited warranties remain as they were.</p><p>Manufacturers have long been averse to talking about burn-in or have outright categorized the phenomenon as “normal use,” denying warranty claims to fix it on various panel types. However, OLEDs have historically been more susceptible to burn-in, especially when used with many static images like those from a PC. In recent years, OLED has improved to be less sensitive to burn-ins.</p><div><p>Sony is the latest in a trend of manufacturers adding burn-in coverage. Alienware was one of the first to specifically include OLED burn-in within its three-year coverage on the <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/3/9/22966303/alienware-curved-aw3423dw-qd-oled-34-inch-quantum-dot-pc-gaming-monitor-hands-on">QD-OLED monitor launched in 2022</a>, and for its latest 27-inch 4K model <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/6/24335564/alienware-27-inch-4k-240hz-oled-price-date">coming this year</a>. And in 2023, The Verge’s Sean Hollister asked LG to <a href="https://www.theverge.com/22336413/lg-27gr95qe-b-oled-gaming-monitor-review#:~:text=Originally%2C%20LG%20wouldn%E2%80%99t%20confirm%20that%20to%20me.%20In%20fact%2C%20the%20company%20had%20originally%20reserved%20the%20right%20to%20reject%20warranty%20claims%20if%20this%20monitor%20experiences%20burn%2Din">explicitly warrant the company’s OLED monitors</a> against burn-in and they agreed and <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23827701/lg-oled-burn-in-warranty-two-desktop-monitor-windows">changed their verbiage</a>.</p></div><div><figcaption><em>A Samsung representative on this Best Buy product listing says the three-year warranty on the 32-inch Odyssey OLED G8 covers burn-in.</em></figcaption> <p><cite>Screenshot: The Verge</cite></p></div><p>Since then, companies like <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/2/7/24064465/asus-rog-msi-oled-monitor-warranty-burn-in-cover-expanded">MSI and Asus</a> have also pledged to cover OLED burn-in on some models, including <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/2/24334049/asus-samsung-msi-27-inch-4k-oled-240hz-monitors">their latest ones</a> (in some countries). It’s important to research the warranty included in the model you’re buying to determine whether burn-in coverage is included. For instance, Samsung’s website shows a general policy for its warranty that <a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/support/legal/LGL10000300/#standard-limited-warranty">excludes burn-ins</a>, however, an online rep <a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/questions/samsung-32-odyssey-oled-g8-g80sd-4k-uhd-240hz-0-03ms-smart-gaming-monitor-with-hdr-silver/6573686/question/2a8f4805-d47e-3416-9cec-dad034fbce5b#:~:text=OLED%20Safeguard%2B%20helps%20prevent%20burn,year%20warranty%20for%20this%20model">confirmed it does cover it on a 32-inch Odyssey OLED G8</a>. However, the company still <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/2/24334049/asus-samsung-msi-27-inch-4k-oled-240hz-monitors#:~:text=Samsung%20hasn%E2%80%99t%20confirmed%20its%20warranty%20situation%20for%20its%20latest%20G8%20model">hasn’t clarified</a> if burn-ins are covered for its latest 27-inch Odyssey OLED G8 gaming monitor.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I Love My NT Cutter Knife So Much]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/nt-cutter-japanese-utility-knife-best</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/i-love-my-nt-cutter-knife-so-much.1093296/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://aftermath.site/nt-cutter-japanese-utility-knife-best<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure><figcaption><span><p>The NT Cutter AD-2P. It costs basically nothing and I use it every day. Credit: NT Cutter.</p>
</span></figcaption></figure></div><div><p>As Aftermath’s resident hardware freak, my goal is to tell you about tools that I have bought and thoroughly enjoy. Sometimes, this process requires weeks of in depth testing and modification. Other times, it’s a pretty simple suggestion. Today is the latter: I love my NT Cutter cutting tool. It costs just over six dollars, is incredibly versatile, and I use it basically every single day. You should get one.</p><div><figure><p><iframe title="Tokyu Hands (Flagship store), Shibuya | Virtual Shopping Tokyo" width="710" height="399" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/IbpreAPHkio?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><figcaption>Here is an hour long tour of my favorite big chain in Japan. It's like I'm there. Skip to 10:49 for some pocket knives.</figcaption></figure></div><p>Of all the chain stores in Japan, the one I miss the most outside of combinis like Family Mart and Lawson is the DIY chain <a href="https://info.hands.net/en/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Hands</a>, formerly known as Tokyu Hands. For Americans, imagine if Michaels, The Container Store and the now defunct Bed Bath and Beyond fused and was seven stories tall.&nbsp; Imagine a building full of all the tiny, beautiful tools needed to make hyper detailed Gunpla and model trains, do woodworking, and cook. The one in Shibuya has a map that looks like it came out of <em>Metroid</em>. I daydream about it sometimes.&nbsp;</p><figure><figcaption>An NT Cutter Premium Evolution PMG series. I got this because I can't find my other knife and it costs slightly more. </figcaption></figure><p>I did not buy my NT Cutter at Hands, but going there does impress upon you how alienating and boring the experience of going into a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Category_killer" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">category killer</a> craft or hardware store can be in America. It also shows you, in case you could not guess, that Japan takes its knives and craft tools very seriously. This extends beyond kitchen knives&nbsp; to small pocket knives like kiridashi and razor blades. Japan takes this stuff so seriously that every time I look for a new tool I often add “Japanese” to the end the way people affix “reddit” to searches.&nbsp;</p><figure><figcaption>These things come apart easily. They're simple, convenient and made in Osaka.</figcaption></figure><p>This is how I came across the much beloved NT Cutter and Olfa brands, the latter of which actually invented the iconic snap-off razor blade. Both OLFA and NT Cutter’s entry level items are quite cheap online, at around six dollars as of this writing. Both brands offer knives in a variety of colors and shapes. They both feature a notch at the end for snapping off the blade when it gets dull and a clip for fitting into a pocket. OLFA is well loved and you can’t go wrong either way, but I find the NT Cutter PRO AD-2P to be quite handsome with its distinctive red dot. I use mine every single day of my life and just ordered more because I lost mine somewhere; backups are so cheap that it’s basically a rounding error for me.</p><div><figure><p><iframe title="Japanese Cutting Tools 🇯🇵 OLFA • NT Cutter" width="710" height="399" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/5mSQUv3d4HA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><figcaption>A comparison between various OLFA and NT Cutter tools. </figcaption></figure></div><p>This does not take anything away from American utility knives. X-ACTO makes a bunch of great tools, and I hear good things about Lenox. And for precision work like model crafting, I know a bunch of people who don’t even mess around with utility knives and go straight for medical scalpels. But for a tiny everyday cutting, the knife I go back to the most is my NT Cutter. I love that little guy so much.</p><figure><figcaption>As a total aside, NT-Cutter makes some kind of blade disposal pyramid that I really want now. Credit: NT Cutter.</figcaption></figure></div><div><h2>Stay in touch</h2><p>Sign up for our free newsletter</p></div><div><h2><span>More from Aftermath</span></h2><div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/ubisoft-phoenix-labs-layoffs-studio-closure-far-cry-dauntless"><h3>Another Big Day For Layoffs In Another Big Year For Layoffs</h3></a><p>Ubisoft is closing its third studio in two months, and Phoenix Labs is bidding farewell to "the majority" of its workforce</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/escape-room-first-time"><h3>My First Escape Room Was Pretty Cool</h3></a><p>Please tell me everything about how you design them</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/oscars-emilia-perez-on-cinema-tim-heidecker"><h3>Stop Watching The Oscars</h3></a><p>They're bad, and you don't have to.</p></div></div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/all">See all posts<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="#000" stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round"><path d="M5 12h13m-6-7 7 7-7 7"></path></svg></a></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Phoenix Labs, Fae Farm Developer Lays Off “Majority of the Studio”]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/phoenix-labs-fae-farm-developer-lays-off-majority-of-the-studio/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/phoenix-labs-fae-farm-developer-lays-off-%E2%80%9Cmajority-of-the-studio%E2%80%9D.1093281/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/phoenix-labs-fae-farm-developer-lays-off-majority-of-the-studio/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>It's been announced that Phoenix Labs, a small indie developer that created Fae Farm and Dauntless have now laid off the majority of the studio in an announcement made on LinkedIn. It's uncertain how many staff were still working at Phoenix Labs during this time, as they also had layoffs in May 2024, where over 100 staff were laid off, and all projects were canceled. This was so they could focus solely on Dauntless and Fae Farm. Below is the message left by the company on LinkedIn today.</p>
<p><em>"Today is another difficult day at Phoenix Labs. We have made the tough decision to part ways with the majority of the studio as part of unfortunate but necessary changes to our operations.&nbsp;</em></p>
<p><em>We recognize and deeply appreciate the contributions of every individual impacted. Their talent, dedication, and creativity have left an indelible mark on our company and our games.&nbsp;</em></p>
<p><em>We will share more details in the coming weeks about what this means for Dauntless and Fae Farm. For now, our focus is on supporting those affected through this transition.</em></p>
<p><em>To our industry peers, we encourage you to reach out to these exceptional individuals - they are some of the best in the business."&nbsp;</em></p>
<p>At the moment, the full number of layoffs hasn't been announced, and as the statement says, details regarding Dauntless and Fae Farm will be released in the coming weeks. However, the mention of them in the announcement gives a sense of foreboding and that the games are likely to lose support or Dauntless will be taken offline due to lack of resources or revenue. Of course, this is all speculation, and it could be that those games will continue to be worked on, with updates released in the future.</p>
<p>These layoffs come just two years after being acquired by the blockchain firm Forte Labs. The dealings that came with being acquired by a <a href="https://wccftech.com/garena-acquired-phoenix-labs-dauntless-now-eyeing-mobile-release/">blockchain firm</a> led to a lot of questions and tense environments within the company, such as the fact that they were told to keep the purchase a secret, with <a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/what-happens-when-a-secretive-blockchain-company-buys-your-game-studio" target="_blank" rel="noopener">former employees having to sign NDAs</a>.</p>
<p>After this happened, Dauntless launched on Steam but was immediately criticized by those who played it due to the in-app monetization and erasing any previous progress made by players thanks to the Awakening update. As a result of this update, Dauntless currently sits at "Overwhelmingly Negative" on Steam.</p>
<p><a href="https://wccftech.com/dauntless-hands-on-at-e3-2017/">Dauntless was fairly successful</a> when it was first released in 2019, with the game initially launching on the Epic Game Store, Xbox One, and PlayStation 4. It was a title funded and published by Epic Games. For the time, cross-platform functionality was a selling point of Dauntless. However, that is increasingly more common nowadays and is no longer a special feature for players to look out for.</p>
<p>Already, this month has seen a significant amount of layoffs, with <a href="https://wccftech.com/ubisoft-closes-uk-studio-lays-off-185-staff/">Ubisoft also laying off staff today</a> and closing one of their studios. It doesn't look like it'll be slowing down any time soon.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Orcs Must Die! Sequel Isn't Better Than The Last One, But Still Pretty Fun]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/orcs-must-die-deathtrap-4-game-pass-review-xbox-pc-ps5-1851748729</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-orcs-must-die-sequel-isnt-better-than-the-last-one-but-still-pretty-fun.1093272/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/orcs-must-die-deathtrap-4-game-pass-review-xbox-pc-ps5-1851748729<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Sometimes in our lives, we value consistency and affordability over anything else. This is why I continue to buy and eat Burger King’s cheap double cheeseburgers. I know what I’m getting, it’s not expensive, and it fills me up. The <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/orcs-must-die-2-the-kotaku-review-5929990&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/orcs-must-die-2-the-kotaku-review-5929990"><em>Orcs Must Die!</em> series</a></span>, launched in 2011, fills a similar role. The games are about killing thousands of orcs using traps, swords, and bows. They have never cost much, always been solid, and stuck pretty close to their straightforward, satisfying formula. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="195734" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="The Week In Games: What’s Coming Out Beyond Cyberpunk 2077: Phantom Liberty" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="157" data-playlist="195734,196411,195189" data-current="195734"><div><p>The Week In Games: What’s Coming Out Beyond Cyberpunk 2077: Phantom Liberty</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195734/195734_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195734/195734_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195734/195734_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195734/195734_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21246.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>But the latest game in the series, <em>Deathtrap</em>, does shake that recipe up. And while it’s not as <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/games/orcs-must-die-3&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/games/orcs-must-die-3">good previous games</a></span>, like a double cheeseburger missing ketchup, it still gets the job done and I still enjoy it.</p><p><em>Orcs Must Die! Deathtrap</em> is the fourth game in the series (<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/games/orcs-must-die-unchained?_gl=1*3mffup*_ga*NzE0NzM5NTc5LjE3Mjk4Njg5MzU.*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczODAwNzk2My4xNTIuMS4xNzM4MDEyMTE4LjQ0LjAuMA..&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/games/orcs-must-die-unchained?_gl=1*3mffup*_ga*NzE0NzM5NTc5LjE3Mjk4Njg5MzU.*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczODAwNzk2My4xNTIuMS4xNzM4MDEyMTE4LjQ0LjAuMA..">no, we don’t talk about that defunct free-to-play PvP spin-off)</a></span> and once again you play as a warrior who can kill orcs directly using various weapons or magic. And once again these orcs come in massive waves and funnel through maze-like maps that you can fill with deadly traps and barricades to create spots that kill all of them while you stand by and watch. In past games you completed levels in a set order and reached the end of the game that way.</p><p>However, this time around, the game is more like a roguelike and you end up replaying maps with randomly generated modifiers activated. You might have to deal with bigger enemies or you might be unable to revive co-op team members. Between waves of enemies you pick a randomly offered bonus or ability, like extra damage, which stays with you for the rest of that run. Runs are made up of two or more randomly generated missions and a harder boss fight featuring even more orcs and more places to put traps. Finishing runs earns you skulls that can be used to upgrade your traps or unlock new skills.</p><p>In theory, the random features should add to the replayablity of <em>Deathtrap</em>. But the problem is that, while in past games each new level led to a new map, here you end up playing on the same maps a lot. In fact, you’ll likely play on the same maps a few times during a co-op session. And that, coupled with the fact that you now have a limited number of barriers to place (which can change where orcs travel), means you’ll likely “solve” a map once and just more or less do that every time you play it again.</p><p>Sure, the modifiers can change that up a bit, but it does start to feel like a grind. And to actually to beat the game, you’ll need to do a lot of grinding to get all your traps boosted up and your skills maxed out. </p><p>Don’t get me wrong, <em>Orcs Must Die! Deathtrap</em> is still a good time with a friend, and building a giant kill-box filled with a dozen traps all firing at once to massacre a horde of orcs in seconds is still very satisfying. But I do hope that a future <em>Orcs Must Die!</em> sequel returns to the level-based formula while sprinkling some of the roguelike elements from this one on top. Like a good, cheap burger that’s not missing the ketchup and is also improved with some bacon or better cheese. </p><p><em>Orcs Must Die! Deathtrap </em>is out January 28 on Xbox Series X/S, PS5, and PC. It’s also available day one on Game Pass. </p><p> . </p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fae Farm And Dauntless Developer Lays Off Majority Of The Studio]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fae-farm-and-dauntless-developer-lays-off-majority-of-the-studio/1100-6529054/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fae-farm-and-dauntless-developer-lays-off-majority-of-the-studio.1093269/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fae-farm-and-dauntless-developer-lays-off-majority-of-the-studio/1100-6529054/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529054">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Phoenix Labs, the developer behind Fae Farm and Dauntless, has announced that has gone through another round of layoffs, which has impacted an unspecified but large portion of the studio.</p><p>"We have made the tough decision to part ways with the majority of the studio as part of unfortunate but necessary changes to our operations," Phoenix Lab explained in a <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/phoenix-labs_activity-7289705935696969728-PaIL/?utm_source=li_share&amp;utm_content=feedcontent&amp;utm_medium=g_dt_web&amp;utm_campaign=copy" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">statement on LinkedIn</a>. "We will share more details in the coming weeks about what this means for Dauntless and Fae Farm."</p><p>Phoenix Labs has already laid employees off through several rounds over the past few years. In 2023, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/dauntless-developer-is-the-latest-studio-to-suffer-significant-layoffs/1100-6513740/" data-ref-id="1100-6513740">Phoenix Labs let go of 9% of its employees</a> and then did <a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/phoenix-labs-lays-off-staff-cancels-games-studio-fate-unknown" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">another series of layoffs in 2024</a>, weeks before its next game was set to be announced. According to <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/kris-morness_everhaven-phoenix-labs-activity-7224446581071101952-nwK8?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=member_desktop" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">former Phoenix Labs employees</a>, it was an open-world sandbox game called Everhaven, which was supposed to be revealed during the PC Gaming Show on June 9, 2024 and enter early access sometime in September.</p><p>Phoenix Labs became independent in 2023 but then was quietly bought by Forte Labs, a <a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/what-happens-when-a-secretive-blockchain-company-buys-your-game-studio" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">blockchain company</a>. Dauntless, a Monster Hunter-like game, was first launched in 2019 for PS4, Xbox One, and PC via Epic Games Store. It finally came to Steam last month, but was <a href="https://gamerant.com/dauntless-review-bomb-controversy-why-monetization-awakening-update/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">heavily criticized for its new predatory monetization structure</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/115776530127739146123?rel=author">George Yang</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Your Friendly Neighborhood Spider-Man Is Greenlit For Season 3 Before Season 1 Premiere]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/your-friendly-neighborhood-spider-man-season-2-season-3-1851748696</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/your-friendly-neighborhood-spider-man-is-greenlit-for-season-3-before-season-1-premiere.1093248/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/your-friendly-neighborhood-spider-man-season-2-season-3-1851748696<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="cec8517283e32cd4a69925878852a5b9" data-recommend-id="image://cec8517283e32cd4a69925878852a5b9" data-format="jpg" data-width="1298" data-height="730" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Peter Parker in conversation" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Peter Parker in conversation" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Marvel</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="cec8517283e32cd4a69925878852a5b9" data-recommend-id="image://cec8517283e32cd4a69925878852a5b9" data-format="jpg" data-width="1298" data-height="730" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Peter Parker in conversation" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>When it comes to the upcoming animated series <em>Your Friendly Neighborhood Spider-Man</em>, it seems Marvel and Disney follow the philosophy expressed by rapper Common on his Grammy-nominated hit “The Light”: “It doesn’t take all day to recognize sunshine.” They don’t need the public’s reception to recognize they have a multi-season hit on their hands. Brad Winderbaum, Marvel Studios Head of Streaming, Television, and Animation, revealed in a recent interview with <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/TheMoviePodcast/status/1883619020441862369&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/TheMoviePodcast/status/1883619020441862369" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>The Movie Podcast</u></a></span> that not only is Marvel Studios’ first Spider-Man TV series ready for Season 2, but Season 3 has already been approved.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196053" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Stomp Your Foes &amp; Look Fly Doing It With This Marvel Snap Deck" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="138" data-playlist="196053,195896,194664" data-current="196053"><div><p>Stomp Your Foes &amp; Look Fly Doing It With This Marvel Snap Deck</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196053/196053_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196053/196053_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196053/196053_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196053/196053_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21582.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>Winderbaum attests that he’s read all of the scripts for Season 2, and the team behind the show is already “halfway through the animatics.” As for what happens beyond that, he confirms “we’re greenlit for through season 3, so in a couple weeks I’m going to hear [head writer Jeff Trammell’s] pitch for the third season.”</p><p>Given the fact that Disney+ original series can get cancelled after one season despite being one of the two <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/disney-the-acolyte-star-wars-amandla-stenberg-1851748400&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/disney-the-acolyte-star-wars-amandla-stenberg-1851748400">most streamed series</a></span> on the platform, renewing a series for two seasons before the public has even seen the first episode is a good sign they’re sitting on a goldmine. Last week we were introduced to some of the unique additions <em>Your Friendly Neighborhood Spider-Man</em> will introduce to Marvel fans, including <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/your-friendly-neighborhood-spider-man-marvel-venom-1851747418&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/your-friendly-neighborhood-spider-man-marvel-venom-1851747418">new variations</a></span> of traditional <em>Spider-Man</em> villains Rhino and Venom. While it’s been made explicitly clear that this series is not in the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/spiderman-disney-animated-cartoon-trailer-date-suit-1851730014&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/spiderman-disney-animated-cartoon-trailer-date-suit-1851730014">same MCU timeline</a></span> as Tom Holland’s Spidey, Hudson Thames, who voices the hero in both <em>What If?...</em> and <em>Your Friendly Neighborhood Spider-Man,</em> <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://screenrant.com/spider-man-mcu-your-friendly-neighborhood-crossover-tom-holland-hudson-thames/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://screenrant.com/spider-man-mcu-your-friendly-neighborhood-crossover-tom-holland-hudson-thames/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">told <em>ScreenRant</em></a></span> that he would love to do a live-action crossover:</p><p>“That is literally on my dream board to do that. So when this series happened, I was like, ‘Oh my God, it feels like almost that!’ So I would absolutely love to do that.”</p><p>We’ll see if <em>Your Friendly Neighborhood Spider-Man </em>can trap our attention in its web of animated thrills enough for three seasons when its first one debuts on January 29 on Disney+.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[It Sure Sounds Like Xbox Games Are Coming To Switch 2]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/it-sure-sounds-like-xbox-games-are-coming-to-switch-2/1100-6529052/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/it-sure-sounds-like-xbox-games-are-coming-to-switch-2.1093245/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/it-sure-sounds-like-xbox-games-are-coming-to-switch-2/1100-6529052/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529052">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">Microsoft Gaming CEO Phil Spencer expressed support for Nintendo--and hinted that Xbox games will be coming to the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/switch-2-release-date-specs-display-price/1100-6520278/">Nintendo Switch 2</a>--in a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mAl5yVpNc3o">recent interview with GamerTag Radio</a>.</p><p dir="ltr">"I want people to be able to experience the games that we build, the services that we offer, on as many devices as we can," Spencer said of Microsoft's push to put Xbox games on as many screens as possible.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mAl5yVpNc3o" data-width="854" data-height="480">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/mAl5yVpNc3o" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p dir="ltr">"We're really taking the approach of, 'We want people to be able to play Xbox on many different screens,'" Spencer said. "We're not gonna put walls up around where people can engage with the great games our studios are building, or where they can experience Xbox through different forms. Whether it's cloud [gaming], whether it's on PC, whether it's on handheld, whether it's on phones... I want everybody to be able to play on Xbox, and it does mean more of our games shipping on more platforms, not just on PlayStation. We love the work that we do with Nintendo, we love what we do with Valve on Steam, and that's what we're going to continue to do, we'll just continue to do more of it because what we learn is, 'Put the games first, make sure the games can be as great as they can.'"</p><p dir="ltr">Spencer said he wants players to choose the hardware that's right for them, and while he'd ultimately like to see that hardware be Microsoft-made, getting Microsoft's games in front of a wider audience is ultimately the more important goal. Spencer said that part of the reason for this is simply the level of success reached by games that are available on multiple platforms.</p><p dir="ltr">"I always applaud the moves that [Nintendo] makes," he declared, adding that he's "really looking forward to supporting [Nintendo] with the games that we have [at Xbox]." Spencer even said he personally congratulated Nintendo CEO Shuntaro Furukawa on the announcement of the Switch 2.</p><p dir="ltr">"I just think they're such an important part of this industry," Spencer said of the Japanese gaming giant. "Who would ever bet against the success of that team? I mean they are just masterful in what they do--Switch is a massive success--and I think Switch 2 will be as well."</p><p dir="ltr">"More and more, that's an important thing [as a player], that my save game travels to whatever screen I want to play on, that my community's always there, and I just think that should be an expectation for all of us: That the games we invest in are able to be played on any screen that we want to play them on."</p><p dir="ltr">"We love the experience on our own hardware, our own platform," Spencer said. "But our games will show up in more and more places, no doubt."</p><p dir="ltr">Microsoft is currently working on its own handheld gaming platform, but it's reportedly still <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/xbox-handheld-device-is-a-few-years-out-apparently/1100-6527758/">a few years away</a> from release. The publisher has already made several of its games available for the Switch, and it's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/halo-coming-to-switch-2-and-ps5-in-2025-alongside-gears-flight-sim-and-more-report/1100-6528744/" data-ref-id="1100-6528744">rumored that Halo: The Master Chief Collection will be coming</a> to the Switch 2.</p><p dir="ltr">Spencer also discussed other topics, like the lessons Microsoft learned from the launch of the Xbox 360, his favorite game of 2024 (<a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/metaphor-refantazio/">Metaphor: ReFantazio</a>), and handling player feedback.</p><p dir="ltr">"It's how I learn, it's how I stay balanced," Spencer said regarding the way he deals with critical feedback from Xbox users. "Getting out of my bubble of the people I see every day I think is critical."</p><p>The 26-minute interview can be watched in full on GamerTag Radio host <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mAl5yVpNc3o">Danny Peña's YouTube channel</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dying Light 10th Anniversary Q&A with Franchise Director Tymon Smektała]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/dying-light-10th-anniversary-qa-with-franchise-director-tymon-smektala/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dying-light-10th-anniversary-q-a-with-franchise-director-tymon-smekta%C5%82a.1093224/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/dying-light-10th-anniversary-qa-with-franchise-director-tymon-smektala/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Today, Techland <a href="https://wccftech.com/dying-light-the-beast-confirmed-for-this-summer-as-franchise-celebrates-10th-anniversary-with-new-roadmap/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced</a> several Dying Light news as part of the franchise's 10th anniversary. Events and updates are coming for both games, and the next title, <a href="https://wccftech.com/dying-light-the-beast-qa-techland-on-the-games-origins-the-return-of-kyle-crane-vehicles-and-more/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The Beast</a>, is landing this Summer. More unannounced projects are already in the works, and Techland is also preparing board games and a comic series.</p>
<p>To dive into all of that and much more, we had a nice, long chat with Dying Light Franchise Director Tymon Smektała. Keep scrolling to read the transcript; we've also embedded today's episode of the Dying to Know show for those who haven't watched it yet.</p>
<p><iframe title="Dying To Know — Celebrating 10 Years of Dying Light" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/CvqFjEILJao?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p><strong>We've read the press release, of course, but please give us an overview of the key announcements today.</strong></p>
<p><strong>Tymon Smektała:</strong> We are actually having a very special day today at Techland because it's the 10th anniversary of the release of the original Dying Light. It's a series with quite a long history. Not all the games are lucky enough and fortunate enough to be able to celebrate that.</p>
<p>In today's stream, we talk and reminisce a little bit about where we are with the franchise. The celebrations are basically packed with a lot of activations for fans. All of this starts today in both games. For Dying Light, we decided to go with a medley of the most liked, the most respected, and the favorite events from the history of that game. There's HyperMode, Super-Crane, all the stuff that players have come to love over those 10 years. Then next week, when we are at the same time celebrating the third anniversary of Dying Light 2, we'll start an anniversary celebration for that with a set of bounties, goals for players to achieve that will provide them with rewards that refer back to the whole series.</p>
<p>Of course, we want to use this as an opportunity for players to check out Dying Light if they haven't already done so. So, both games have cool promotions on all platforms. At the same time, we are also announcing that the series so far has reached 45 million players. It's something that we are very proud of. And we are also giving players a small update on our work forward for The Beast. We focus this period on the celebration of the anniversary, so we don't go into much detail regarding The Beast, but the stream will give players a very nice look behind the scenes on how we work on the game where we are. There will be some Easter eggs hidden for our community so they can discover that and see how the work progresses on the beast. We are also telling players that we have a couple of things planned outside of videogames, like board games. We are even announcing some new comic initiatives, but the main message is that Dying Light is celebrating its 10th anniversary as a series and that we feel strong about its future. We stick to our plan of growing the franchise and hope that one day, Dying Light will become the go-to zombie game for players.</p>
<p><strong>I also read that you're planning to release an update for the first game.</strong></p>
<p><strong>Tymon Smektała: </strong>That's part of the celebrations. Players will actually get two things from us. The first one is a kind of celebratory anniversary bundle where you can dress according to the occasion and also paint your buggy from Dying Light The Following in the same way. And yes, we are also preparing an update that will squeeze a little bit more from our graphics engine. It will also include the remastered soundtrack by Paweł Błaszczak. Don't expect a complete overhaul, but there will be a small update where we look at various areas of the game to try to squeeze a little bit more out of it, like increasing the resolution of textures here and there, improving the lighting, especially in dialogues, but it's a set of tweaks here and there that will just give the game a slightly nicer look.</p>
<p><strong>When is it coming?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Tymon Smektała: </strong>It will arrive soon. We're not revealing an exact date because this is basically a tech achievement to work with an engine that already has its years. So we didn't want to jump the gun too early, but it will happen very soon. We just want to make sure that when we announce the exact date, it will be delivered on that date. I think that's the best answer I can give you without kind of having to say, we missed the date for a few days, but it's going to happen soon.</p>
<figure><figcaption>'We are also preparing a Dying Light update that will squeeze a little bit more from our graphics engine. It will also include the remastered soundtrack by Pavo Bashak. Don't expect a complete overhaul, but there will be a small update where we look at various areas of the game to try to squeeze a little bit more out of it, like increasing the resolution of textures here and there, improving the lighting, especially in dialogues, but it's a set of tweaks here and there that will just give the game a slightly nicer look.'</figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>Looking at the new Dying Light roadmap that you put in the press release, you confirmed that The Beast is coming in the Summer. I guess you must be very close to finishing the game. Is it content complete yet? Is it just polishing at this point?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Tymon Smektała:</strong> Yes. One small thing that I said at today's anniversary is that we have basically finished recording the voice lines. We'll have all of them in the game within a few days. We are definitely in a stage where the game is complete, and we are just trying to look at all of its areas and polish as much as possible. I would say we are mostly focusing right now on general quality and seeing how we can improve the look at this particular location or this particular set of enemy animations. We are also at the stage of making a proper, final balance pass on everything, so it's shaping up to be a really nice experience. We still have a few playtest rounds ahead of us, so we'll see what will come from that, but I don't expect anything more than maybe another set of tweaks, pulling the knobs here and there to make sure that everything is ready for the launch.</p>
<p><strong>You said Summer, but that's three months. Could we narrow it down a bit more, like early Summer or late Summer?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Tymon Smektała:</strong> I don't want to answer that question. I think that at Techland, we have a history of being a little bit optimistic and saying days that we then had to move a little. Every developer has that. The game will definitely be released in the Summer, but you'll have to wait a little bit longer for the final date.</p>
<p><strong>Alessio Palumbo: Okay. I had to try. You're still working on Dying Light 2 as well, right?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Tymon Smektała:</strong> Yes, of course, absolutely. The roadmap also reveals our plans for this year. We are definitely sticking to the promise of supporting the game for five years. We are moving strong in the third year. I think we have found a rhythm that is comfortable both for us as developers and for our community. We have four big events each year. In every quarter of the year, there's a nice big event inside Dying Light 2, which brings new activities, new rewards, new cosmetic items, and at the same time, in between, we release slightly smaller updates.</p>
<p>New weapon types are coming. We plan to introduce a set of technical improvements mostly inspired by our work on The Beast. I would say we definitely managed to improve our tech for The Beast, so we plan to bring back some of those improvements to Dying Light 2 at some point this year. In the second half of next month, on February 19, we plan to release an update that will bring the Tower Raid. It's a co-op mode, which we worked on over the course of last year, but this time, it's going to stay as a permanent addition.</p>
<p>It's something quite unique for us. We created it as a response to players' requests and we plan to work on this and develop it further. We're waiting for feedback from our community. We are also introducing a set of improvements to our prologue and the initial hours of the game. We are making the story and player progression a little bit more seamless because we have realized that there are a couple of bumps, some tricky moments in the initial hours of the game. Since it still brings a lot of new players, we wanted to ease it out a little bit, make it more engaging and flowing more naturally for players.</p>
<p>We also plan to look again at and energize our content creators. As you know, Dying Light 2 is one of the unique games where we have released our tools for players to create their own maps and, at the same time, we made those maps easily accessible both on PC and consoles. I think there are maybe three, four, five games that really do it. We have some ideas on how we can direct and help our content creators to create premium content for the UGC part. When I say premium, of course, what I mean is high quality, not paid, because this is a part of the game that will stay absolutely free forever.</p>
<p>Going back to the Tower Raid, I think it's also worth noting that over the course of last year, we gave players access to it on two occasions for a few weeks. The goal was to treat it as an early access, open beta type of thing. We wanted to gather feedback and players' expectations. The permanent version of the Tower Raid will be an answer to that. It will be accessible from the main menu, so you don't have to be in the open world to access it.</p>
<p>Players will get to choose one of four characters with their own progression trees, skills and roles. Since it's a roguelite experience, it will change with each attempt, giving players access to different floors, different enemy combinations, sets of mutators, and so on. If they succeed, the loot they earn will then be usable in the classic open world part of Dying Light 2.</p>
<p><strong>What kind of co-op improvements are you making to the game outside of the Tower Raid mode?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Tymon Smektała:</strong> I would say those are mostly focused on technical stuff and making it easier for players to connect. Dying Light 2 was never intended or envisioned as a fully online game. We realized that we missed some features on the matchmaking front. It's a little bit harder, it takes a few too many steps to connect with your friends to create a group and play together. Post-launch, Dying Light 2 has received more and more content that supports, promotes, or is just fun to play with your friends or in co-op groups, so we wanted to make sure that players would be able to connect more easily. We also looked at the user interface to make sure that it's easier to understand what's happening to other players, where they are, and what kind of level they are.</p>
<p>We feel that this is something that we want to explore. We realized that we don't have as many things to play for players in co-op as probably would make that form of playing the game even more popular, so we'll be looking at this side of the game for any future ideas that we'll have.</p>
<figure><figcaption>'We feel that this is something that we want to explore. We realized that we don't have as many things to play for Dying Light 2 players in co-op as probably would make that form of playing the game even more popular, so we'll be looking at this side of the game for any future ideas that we'll have.</figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>You mentioned <a href="https://wccftech.com/dying-light-2-will-get-mod-tools-techland-looking-for-ways-to-deliver-mods-to-console-too/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Community Maps</a>. What kind of improvements are you going to make to that area of the game?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Tymon Smektała:</strong> I think they are already quite integrated and very accessible thanks to our partnership with mod.io, which delivers those super cool tools that make access to maps created by the community in a very easy way. We managed to have them available both on PC and consoles, and especially the consoles part is something that requires a little bit more effort. Not every developer is willing to go in that direction, but for us, it was very important to keep our community intact. The community maps are already available on PC and consoles, and the map creators have access to all of those players when they make their creations. Now, we are growing and improving our relations with the content creators, talking to them every day and trying to understand what kind of features they are missing and what kind of additional options, abilities, and opportunities they would like to have on the editor side.</p>
<p>We have a team that is trying to deliver that to them as quickly as possible. But at the same time, we realize that maybe we could help them a little by coming up with ideas and directions for what they create. Aside from a set of technical editor side tweaks that will make creating maps easier and also iron out some of the kinks that happen when you download the maps, we also want to support the most talented map creators specifically and individually to make sure that they are able to deliver their vision. This way, we hope that the maps that they will create will just get better.</p>
<p>We have had a lot of discussions with a lot of those people where they say, okay, we want to make this kind of map. We have this idea for it, but we were able to make it only up to this point because we are missing a feature or two to fully realize our vision. What we intend to do this year with Dying Light 2 mods is to get more intimate with those creators and deliver them the features that they need to fulfill their visions. For example, we have a map which is called Stadium. It is a set of sports events that use our mechanics. It's a great map, but when you start playing it, you quickly realize that it misses some features. There's a football match that you can try to play, with two goals and a ball, and you can play it with your friends, but then there's no mechanic that would allow you to count the score, so we talked to the content creator, and he told us that he didn't have the features needed to do this.</p>
<p>With this new approach, we'll look at a map with such potential and say, "Okay, let us help you, and we will deliver you a solution that will allow you to count the goals." That's just an example to present the mindset that we'll have for this year when working with the most talented map creators from the community.</p>
<p><strong>There are also new firearms and melee weapons on the way. Can you share something more about those?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Tymon Smektała:</strong> I think we don't want to kind of spoil the surprise, but definitely, this year will bring a number of new melee weapons and firearms. When you look at the roadmap and you see new firearms and new melee weapons, you can expect new items within the types that have already been established. And yes, we'll also add some new weapon types, both in the melee and the firearms sides, that we didn't have before.</p>
<p><strong>In general, are you happy with how <a href="https://wccftech.com/dying-light-2-reloaded-edition-qa-franchise-director-talks-firearms-10-new-hours-of-gameplay-and-more/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">firearms have been integrated into Dying Light 2</a>? Because I know that was a big sticking point.</strong></p>
<p><strong>Tymon Smektała:</strong> I think we have managed to do that in a way that makes sense both for us and for our community. We feel that our implementation achieves one thing, which is actually a challenge for a game like Dying Light, where one of the pillars is first-person melee combat. We chose this as something that makes us unique, standing out on the market.<br>
Of course, we still think of new ways we can develop it and what more we can do with it, but Dying Light is a game built on melee combat and bringing firearms to it is a design challenge about how you want to implement them into the game so they don't overpower your core gameplay mechanic, which is first person melee combat.</p>
<p>And I think we did actually a nice job on it with various design decisions on how often players get access to bullets. What's the value of one bullet? Does it make sense to use it in every situation? Maybe not. Then also, with additional mechanics that are well embedded into the worldbuilding where if you make noise, you wake up the zombies, making it always a double-edged sword. Then, it supports and builds up on our other gameplay pillar, which is parkour and being able to traverse with great agility. We created this loop where it's okay for you to use firearms, but you cannot stay in that place for long because the zombies will come and maybe when they do, you will have to use your parkour to run away or maybe even parkour to find a better shooting position.</p>
<p>Of course, we had firearms in the first game, so we have some experience in that regard. I think we'll be using both of those experiences in The Beast. I think the relation between melee weapons and firearms is even stronger in that game because the firearms are introduced to the player from the beginning. It's not like we did in Dying Light 2 where it was a game without firearms and only at some point did we add firearms to this already built mechanism. With The Beast, it was slightly easier because we knew from the start that, of course, we'd have firearms there. We are also increasing our range of firearms in that game. So far, we have mentioned that we'll have a grenade launcher. We have also shown a bit of flamethrower, and that's not all, as we have more announcements coming on that front.</p>
<p><strong>You also revealed that the franchise has a number of unannounced projects in the works.</strong></p>
<p><strong>Tymon Smektała:</strong> Yes, we wanted to use the anniversary occasion to affirm to our players that the future is bright, and we're definitely not stopping here. But we'll talk about those projects after the release of Dying Light The Beast because there's no denying that currently, our focus is on Dying Light the Beast and sticking to the support of Dying Light 2. So, we just wanted to give this little kind of heads-up to players that the future is bright, and we have ambitions for it.</p>
<p><strong>The franchise is going beyond games with board games and stuff like that, but did you look into TV or movie adaptations, which are increasingly active in the gaming industry? Was there ever anything that maybe could have happened or could still happen for the IP?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Tymon Smektała:</strong> Absolutely. We are still looking at all of our options here. As you can imagine, anything in this kind of glossy Hollywood area takes a little bit more time than the creation of a board game or a comic. So, we are still considering our options. Nothing to announce at this stage, but this is an area where we are constantly having conversations and discussions about trying different approaches and seeing what we can do. Definitely, our belief is that it has the potential to take off outside of games. I think that with 28 Years Later, we'll see a slight renaissance of the zombie setting in pop culture, and I think it makes a lot of sense for Dying Light to also be a part of it. But once again, there is nothing to announce at this moment.</p>
<p><strong>I guess you probably can't answer this, but I'm going to try anyway. A couple of years ago, you <a href="https://wccftech.com/dying-light-techland-fantasy-game-new-concept-art-climbing-huge-world/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">revealed</a> that Techland was working on another IP, a fantasy franchise. It's been a while since that new franchise has been discussed. Could you confirm if it's still being made?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Tymon Smektała:</strong> Well, my role is Dying Light franchise director. I will let my friends speak about their project. I can answer all the questions about Dying Light, but I will not steal the shine from my friends at Techland. So, nothing to comment on this topic.</p>
<p><strong>It's just that, while I love zombie games, I also dearly love fantasy. So, it's something I would love to see eventually.</strong></p>
<p><strong>Tymon Smektała:</strong> Same here.</p>
<p><strong>Finger crossed. Just a final question. The Nintendo Switch 2 has been <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-officially-revealed-with-a-new-trailer-dedicated-direct-confirmed-for-april/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced</a>, at long last. Are you looking into supporting it for Dying Light 2: Stay Human and/or The Beast? The first game was eventually released on the Switch.</strong></p>
<p><strong>Tymon Smektała:</strong> It's too early to comment on this because we have just basically learned the basics about the console, at least publicly. The only thing I can say right now is that I'm waiting for the orders on the Nintendo Switch 2 to open so I can secure my own version of it right away. But nothing to announce on this topic officially at this moment.</p>
<p><strong>OK, fair enough. Is there anything you'd like to add?&nbsp;</strong></p>
<p><strong>Tymon Smektała:</strong> I would like to say that it has really been an amazing journey for us and I think none of us at Techland realized that 10 years after releasing Dying Light we'd still be talking about the game and it would still be such a popular series which really left its mark the zombie genre in the open world survival horror genres. We really feel proud about our work on the game and the series, but we also understand that the series wouldn't be where it is today if not for our community and the players, 45 million of them who have spent their time with the Dying Light titles. So, if I may, I would like to thank all of our community and all the players who have enjoyed Dying Light over the years because we wouldn't be there without them. And it's a great honor to be able to deliver at least a slice of entertainment and fun to their lives. It's an honor for us. It's a pleasure for us and something that we are very grateful that this could happen.</p>
<p><strong>Thank you for your time.</strong></p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Long-Gone Classics The Sims 1 And 2 Are Finally Coming Back To PC]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/sims-1-2-remaster-pc-buy-ea-maxis-steam-1851748658</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/long-gone-classics-the-sims-1-and-2-are-finally-coming-back-to-pc.1093221/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/sims-1-2-remaster-pc-buy-ea-maxis-steam-1851748658<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="b5658fb35ddf996378f01f0919923cc8" data-recommend-id="image://b5658fb35ddf996378f01f0919923cc8" data-format="png" data-width="1065" data-height="600" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Sims characters prepare for the re-launch. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Sims characters prepare for the re-launch. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->EA / Mobygames</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="b5658fb35ddf996378f01f0919923cc8" data-recommend-id="image://b5658fb35ddf996378f01f0919923cc8" data-format="png" data-width="1065" data-height="600" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Sims characters prepare for the re-launch. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>Fans of <em>The Sims</em>&nbsp;<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://simscommunity.info/2025/01/27/sims-1-sims-2-rerelease-teaser/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://simscommunity.info/2025/01/27/sims-1-sims-2-rerelease-teaser/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">have their hopes up</a></span> that the original two games will finally be remastered for modern platforms after Electronic Arts cryptically teased them in a new 25th anniversary promo video. <em>Kotaku</em> understands that <em>The Sims 1</em> and <em>The Sims 2</em> will both be re-released on PC before the end of the month. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="194143" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="The Sims 4's Free Infant Update Can't Compare To The Growing Together Expansion" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="138" data-playlist="194143,195486,196653" data-current="194143"><div><p>The Sims 4's Free Infant Update Can't Compare To The Growing Together Expansion</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/194143/194143_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/194143/194143_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/194143/194143_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/194143/194143_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/19621.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>The teaser is part of Maxis Games’ and EA’s <em>Sims</em> <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/TheSims/status/1879218365430182064&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/TheSims/status/1879218365430182064" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">25th anniversary roadmap</a></span> teasing updates to <em>The Sims 4</em> and other surprises from now through early February. The first of these surprises today showed a <em>Sims 1</em> character and an interaction prompt wheel from <em>The Sims 2</em>. The games were previously teased <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/GamingLeaksAndRumours/comments/1i1frue/the_sims_1_2_and_3_might_be_rereleasing_for_the/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GamingLeaksAndRumours/comments/1i1frue/the_sims_1_2_and_3_might_be_rereleasing_for_the/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">via sound effects</a></span> in a “Behind the Sims” presentation earlier in the month, and when <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/SimMattically/status/1879209642108326097&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/SimMattically/status/1879209642108326097" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">official merchandise</a></span> also started making the rounds. </p><p>According to a source familiar with the plans, both games will be released digitally on PC later this week. They’re expected to arrive with all of their original expansion packs included, but it remains unclear if the legacy games will also make it to consoles at some point. </p><p><em>The Sims</em> released back in 2000 and it’s been <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/returning-to-the-sims-1-in-2023-is-a-weird-challenge-i-fully-recommend&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/returning-to-the-sims-1-in-2023-is-a-weird-challenge-i-fully-recommend" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">all but impossible to play</a></span> the Will Wright-designed game about managing the daily lives of semi-autonomous virtual avatars for years. The first<em> Sims </em>was a disc-only release, and<em> The Sims 2</em> was taken offline over a decade ago, with new digital copies only available to pre-existing owners briefly <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/thesims2/comments/15p5ktf/what_happened_to_the_sims_2_free_ultimate/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/thesims2/comments/15p5ktf/what_happened_to_the_sims_2_free_ultimate/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">via an Ultimate Collection on Origin</a></span> that was removed in 2014. </p><p>That’s around the time <em>The Sims 4 </em>was released. It’s still going strong nearly 11 years later as EA opts to keep updating the game with new content rather than release<em> The Sims 5</em>. But one thing you can’t do as easily in the current entry is kill Sims by trapping them in pools and taking the ladder away. That was a favorite <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://simscommunity.info/2025/01/27/sims-1-sims-2-rerelease-teaser/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://simscommunity.info/2025/01/27/sims-1-sims-2-rerelease-teaser/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pastime of OG fans, and the long-memed feature</a></span> seems likely to return in the remasters. <em>Sims </em>players will no doubt riot if it doesn’t. </p><p>.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>