<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 17:46:32 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Watch: Gamescom Opening Night Live 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/watch-gamescom-opening-night-live-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/watch-gamescom-opening-night-live-2025.1274103/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Geoff! Geoff! Geoff!</p>
</section></header><section>
<p>Two watch posts in one day? What is this madness?? With the <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/kirby-air-riders">Kirby Air Riders</a> Direct in the rear-view mirror, it's time to move on to the <em>second</em> showcase of the day: GamesCom Opening Night Live.</p>
<p>Yes, we are mere minutes away from the grand opening of the huge gaming expo, and <em>the</em> Geoff Keighley is back to guide us through an evening of news and announcements — some of which might even be for Switch and Switch 2.</p>
<p>The event kicks off at <strong>7pm BST / 11am PDT / 2pm EDT / 8pm CEST</strong> and promises roughly <em>two hours</em> of reveals. Those in for the long run can find the full showcase streamed on <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCHo_GVNoKNqfJx6zUGRd6YQ" rel="noopener">YouTube</a> and <a href="https://www.twitch.tv/gamescom" rel="noopener">Twitch</a>, or you can watch along with us via the feed below, so we can all have a natter in the meantime.</p>
<p>All of that is right around the corner, so make sure you're sitting comfortably, because it's almost Geoff o'clock!</p>

</section></article></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/watch-gamescom-opening-night-live-2025]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Asus has the new world’s fastest OLED monitor at 720Hz, and it’s dripping with style]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/761481/asus-720hz-gaming-monitor-rog-swift-oled-pg27aqwp-w</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/asus-has-the-new-world%E2%80%99s-fastest-oled-monitor-at-720hz-and-it%E2%80%99s-dripping-with-style.1274100/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>We might have a new king of esports gaming monitors — one with fewer compromises than usual. Asus has just announced <a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=1025X1701640&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Frog.asus.com%2Fus%2Farticles%2Fproduct-news%2Fmonitors-motherboards-and-more-everything-rog-announced-at-gamescom-2025%2F" rel="sponsored">the ROG Swift OLED PG27AQWP-W</a> at Gamescom 2025. Not only does it offer a 26.5-inch 2560 x 1440 QHD OLED screen at a blazing-fast 540Hz, it’s also a dual-mode panel that can switch to a practically unheard-of 720Hz refresh rate when you kick the graphics down to 1080p* resolution.</p><p>Asus may not technically have the fastest monitor ever made, as <a href="https://www.tomshardware.com/monitors/gaming-monitors/koorui-to-demo-the-worlds-first-750-hz-gaming-monitor-at-ces-tn-panel-device-gets-welcome-color-boost-with-the-latest-qd-film">both Koorui</a> and <a href="https://videocardz.com/newz/hkc-launches-worlds-first-750hz-gaming-monitor">HKC have announced</a> 750Hz 1080p monitors, but both of those have TN panels that won’t even begin to compete on color, brightness, and viewing angles. They’re from brands we don’t typically see in western countries, and neither lets you switch to higher resolution when you don’t need <em>all the speed</em>.</p><p>Meanwhile, the Asus isn’t just OLED — it’s a <em>tandem OLED</em> panel that should dramatically boost HDR brightness and allegedly improve lifespan. It’s also got a glossy coating that could make its colors even more vibrant and its blacks even blacker than OLED tech can already afford, assuming you’re not playing in a room with glare (though Asus claims the coating minimizes glare “even in bright rooms.”)</p><div><p>Here’s the part where I’d normally say “who needs 540Hz let alone 720Hz? <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/31/22911067/boe-500-hz-gaming-monitor-high-refresh-rate#:~:text=To%20put%20500Hz%20in%20context%2C">Have you done the math and seen the diminishing returns?</a>” Instead, I’m too busy gaping at Asus’ stunning new silver and translucent plastic design. Clear gadgets are <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23774468/clear-transparent-tech-gadgets-news-announcements-products">near and dear to my heart, after all</a>, and the skeletal silver really makes it stand out in a sea of black-framed panels.</p></div><p>Unfortunately, we don’t have pricing or a release date yet, and I suspect it’ll cost a pretty penny because Asus chose that groundbreaking panel and did all that work to set it apart. <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/623428/dell-alienware-oled-monitor-aw2725d-price-release-date">Seeing more OLED monitor prices come down to earth</a> would excite me even more than a new flagship like this.</p><p>Also, I would prefer a smaller stand to the huge three-blade propeller, but unfortunately, Asus does make you compromise to get that. The company’s also introducing a new ROG Strix OLED XG27AQWMG today with the same tandem OLED tech, but as you can see in the one-pager below, it’s a 280Hz panel that still relies on either HDMI 2.1 or DisplayPort 1.4’s DSC compression, rather than the flagship’s new DisplayPort 2.1a which boasts 80Gbps of bandwidth.</p><p>Both have Asus’ “Neo Proximity Sensor,” a relatively new feature it’s been adding to OLED panels, “to accurately measure the user’s distance to the monitor and automatically switch to a black screen when the user is away,” as an extra protection against burn-in. Asus also tends to offer a three-year warranty against OLED burn-in these days, and both LG Display and Samsung Display’s newer panels have many protections against it; as long as those protections aren’t over-aggressive, burn-in is no longer a reason I’d personally steer away.</p><p>Just know that other monitor makers will probably use the same 4th-gen WOLED tandem panel from LG Display, too. <a href="https://www.tweaktown.com/news/105695/sdc-teases-first-oled-gaming-monitor-with-gpu-busting-720hz-refresh-rate/index.html">SDC has already announced one</a>, and other brands might follow suit.</p><p><em>*If you’ve heard of 720Hz before, it’s probably because <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/753686/lg-display-540hz-oled-panel-720hz-mode">LG Display already announced the dual-mode 720Hz panel</a> that appears in this monitor.</em> <em>And if you’re wondering why we say 1080p rather than 720p <a href="https://x.com/tftcentral/status/1957848581760528587?s=46">as others are reporting</a>, it’s because we fact-checked with both Asus and LG Display that the panel is 1080p at 720Hz</em>. <em>We’ll let you know if we hear different.</em></p><div><p><span><strong>Follow topics and authors</strong> from this story to see more like this in your personalized homepage feed and to receive email updates.</span></p><ul><li id="follow-author-article_footer-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MzQz"><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span><span>Sean Hollister</span></span></span></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li></ul></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/news/761481/asus-720hz-gaming-monitor-rog-swift-oled-pg27aqwp-w]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Microsoft Announces Xbox Game Pass August 2025 Wave 2 Lineup]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/microsoft-announces-xbox-game-pass-august-2025-wave-2-lineup</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/microsoft-announces-xbox-game-pass-august-2025-wave-2-lineup.1274085/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Dragon Age: The Veilguard! Gears of War: Reloaded! More!</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Microsoft has announced Wave 2 of the Xbox Game Pass August 2025 lineup, which includes Dragon Age: The Veilguard, Gears of War: Reloaded, Persona 4 Golden, and more.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As revealed in a post on <a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2025/08/19/xbox-game-pass-august-2025-wave-2/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Xbox Wire</a>, Blacksmith Master (Game Preview) is available today, August 19, for PC via Game Pass Ultimate and PC Game Pass. This early access game allows you to manage your own medieval smithy, smelt resources into everything from swords to cooking pots, then fund upgrades to your forge.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Also available today is roguelite FPS Void/Breaker for PC, via Game Pass Ultimate and PC Game Pass. </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">On August 20, Goat Simulator Remaster joins Game Pass Standard, allowing you to do all sorts of things with goats (and also all sorts of other animals), now with shinier visuals and lots of DLC included. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The same day sees the beloved Persona 4 Golden arrive on Xbox Game Pass (Cloud, PC and Xbox Series X/S) for Game Pass Ultimate, PC Game Pass and Game Pass Standard subscribers.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">August 21 brings the day one launch via Game Pass of Herdling, the indie adventure where you take charge of a group of beasts that look rather like the banthas from Star Wars. Expect lots of dangers and obstacles to overcome in an alpine environment, rather than Tatooine.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The end of August brings the month's two biggest Game Pass additions, beginning with the day one launch of Gears of War: Reloaded on August 26 (Cloud, PC and Xbox Series X/S) for Game Pass Ultimate and PC Game Pass subscribers. This is the polished-up vrsion of the classic first Gears game, now with all post-launch content, multiplayer maps and cosmetics included. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Finally, on August 28, Dragon Age: The Veilguard (Cloud, PC, Xbox Series X/S) joins Microsoft's subscription service for Game Pass Ultimate and PC Game Pass members. Last year's blockbuster fantasy RPG proved divisive among fans, and arrives on Game Pass after previously appearing quickly after launch in PlayStation Plus, back in March.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Xbox Game Pass Wave 2 August 2025 lineup:</h2><ul data-cy="list"><li><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/blacksmith-master"><em><strong>Blacksmith Master</strong></em></a><em><strong> (Game Preview)</strong></em><strong> (PC) – August 19</strong><br>Game Pass Ultimate, PC Game Pass</li><li><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/voidbreaker"><em><strong>Void/Breaker</strong></em></a><strong> (PC) – August 19</strong><br>Game Pass Ultimate, PC Game Pass</li><li><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/goat-simulator-remastered"><em><strong>Goat Simulator Remastered</strong></em></a><strong> (Xbox Series X/S) – August 20</strong><br>Now with Game Pass Standard</li><li><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/persona-4-golden"><em><strong>Persona 4 Golden</strong></em></a><strong> (Cloud, Console, and PC) – August 20</strong><br>Game Pass Ultimate, PC Game Pass, Game Pass Standard</li><li><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/herdling"><em><strong>Herdling</strong></em></a><strong> (Cloud, Console, and PC) – August 21</strong><br>Game Pass Ultimate, PC Game Pass</li><li><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/gears-of-war-reloaded"><em><strong>Gears of War: Reloaded</strong></em></a><strong> (Cloud, PC, and Xbox Series X/S) – August 26</strong><br>Game Pass Ultimate, PC Game Pass</li><li><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/dragon-age-the-veilguard"><em><strong>Dragon Age: The Veilguard</strong></em></a><strong> (Cloud, PC, and Xbox Series X/S) – August 28</strong><br>Game Pass Ultimate, PC Game Pass
</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph">As ever, as Microsoft giveth, so it taketh away. Here are the titles set to leave Game Pass this month. Members can get a 20% discount to keep the games in their library.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Games leaving Xbox Game Pass on August 31:</h2><ul data-cy="list"><li>Ben 10 Power Trip (Cloud, Console, and PC)</li><li>Borderlands 3 (Cloud, Console, and PC)</li><li>Paw Patrol Mighty Pups Save Adventure Bay (Cloud, Console, and PC)</li><li>Sea of Stars (Cloud, Console, and PC)</li><li>This War of Mine: Final Cut (Cloud, Console, and PC)</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Tom Phillips is IGN's News Editor. You can reach Tom at tom_phillips@ign.com or find him on Bluesky </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/tomphillipseg.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@tomphillipseg.bsky.social</a></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/microsoft-announces-xbox-game-pass-august-2025-wave-2-lineup]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Helldivers 2 Is Officially Getting Halo: ODST Content, But Its First Legendary Warbond Is Going to Cost You]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/helldivers-2-is-officially-getting-halo-odst-content-but-its-first-legendary-warbond-is-going-to-cost-you</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/helldivers-2-is-officially-getting-halo-odst-content-but-its-first-legendary-warbond-is-going-to-cost-you.1274079/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Feet first into Helldivers.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s official: <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/helldivers-ii"><u>Helldivers 2</u></a> is getting a Legendary Warbond featuring weapons and cosmetics from <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/halo-3-odst"><u>Halo: ODST</u></a>, and its release date arrives in one week.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Arrowhead Game Studios announced the highly anticipated crossover news on social media today, revealing a first-look trailer for the Helldivers 2 Halo content that players will soon get their hands on. It’s a collaboration with Microsoft that arrives ahead of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/sony-published-helldivers-2-gets-shock-release-date-on-xbox-series-x-and-s"><u>the game’s launch on Xbox Series X/S August 26, 2025</u></a>, with the new Warbond tier and all of its ODST goodies set to drop that same day.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">A <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2O_9hwQ8jLw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>trailer for the Helldivers 2 Halo content</u></a> shows what some of the new content looks like in-game, but Microsoft made sure to offer more information in a new Xbox Wire <a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2025/08/19/helldivers-2-halo-odst-crossover-warbond-xbox-launch/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>blog post</u></a>. Players who pick up the Legendary Warbond will be treated to four weapons (three primary, one sidearm), four vehicle patterns, an armor passive, two player banners, two capes, one player title, and, of course, two armor sets that look like they were ripped straight out of Halo 3: ODST.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">You can see everything included in the Halo: ODST Legendary Warbond in the image below. As for that mysterious Feet First armor passive, players can expect a buff that allows them to make less noise when moving, become immune to leg injuries, and increase their discovery range by 30%.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/08/19/helldivers-2-halo-odst-warbond-1755617979176.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Helldivers 2 x Halo: ODST Legendary Warbond. Image courtesy of Arrowhead Game Studios.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Super Earth veterans will note that the Arrowhead is using the Halo crossover to introduce Legendary Warbonds as a completely new tier for its content packs. That means it’ll be more expensive, too, running players about 1,500 Super Credits (about $15). That’s up from the usual 1,000 Super Credits (about $10) players have come to expect with non-crossover packs, but Arrowhead says it will be worth the price of admission.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“The Legendary Warbond marks a brand-new tier in the Warbond lineup, and we’ve gone all-in to make sure it lives up to the name,” the studio said in a statement. “This one’s a tribute to a long-requested crossover, packed with details that fans will love to discover.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Arrowhead also clarifies that the new Premium Warbond Tokens, which also launch August 26, cannot be used to unlock the Helldivers 2 x Halo: ODST Legendary Warbond. Despite this, players seem to be taking the price announcement well.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>This isnt egregious. A lil pricey, but ultimately acceptable.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">“Fine. Collabs cost money,” one popular comment from a <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Helldivers/comments/1mui024/comment/n9ivdwi/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Reddit user said</u></a>. “This isnt egregious. A lil pricey, but ultimately acceptable.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Honestly, I was expecting it to be around 2000sc for a collab Warbond - 1500 is a nice surprise,” another <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Helldivers/comments/1mui024/comment/n9iwi53/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>comment added</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">A proper reveal for the Helldivers 2 x Halo: ODST Legendary Warbond follows a <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/helldivers-2-teases-halo-odst-crossover-ahead-of-xbox-release"><u>tease for the new content that was revealed last week</u></a>. With such a highly anticipated crossover finally making its way to all platforms, many expected to see Arrowhead take the opportunity to significantly increase its price.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Halo content in Helldivers 2 also follows the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/helldivers-2s-killzone-crossover-has-already-sparked-an-outcry-over-the-super-high-cost-of-items"><u>controversy surrounding the inclusion of Killzone content late last year</u></a>. While players were happy to see collaborations find their way into the game at the time, they were not happy with how it was handled.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Instead of delivering the Killzone content in the form of a traditional Warbond, players needed to spend nearly 2,000 Super Credits for a smaller selection of individually priced content. Making matters worse was the announcement that everything would only be available for a limited amount of time before being rotated out of the Superstore.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Arrowhead eventually went on to <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/helldivers-2-dev-insists-its-to-blame-for-killzone-pricing-debacle-amid-concern-over-sony-influence"><u>apologize</u></a> for its handling of Killzone Healldivers 2 content, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/helldivers-2-dev-gives-all-players-next-weeks-killzone-items-for-free-following-pricing-backlash-and-theyre-available-now"><u>gifting all players some of the crossover-themed goodies</u></a> for free while promising to do better in the future. Judging by the reaction to the Halo content, it sounds like the team is on the right track.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Arrowhead said they'll learn from feedback of the Killzone collab, and they did,” another <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Helldivers/comments/1mui024/comment/n9ivl1n/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>popular comment added</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Helldivers 2 will bring Halo: ODST content to players across PC, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series X | S next week. In the meantime, you can read up on <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/helldivers-2-patch-01003200-makes-a-big-balance-change-among-others-lets-you-plant-your-flag-in-the-face-of-your-enemy-and-lots-of-fixes"><u>everything included in one of Arrowhead’s most recent patches</u></a>. You can also check out the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/helldivers-2-finally-gifts-free-review-bomb-cape-to-players-in-nod-to-infamous-psn-account-linking-backlash"><u>infamous “review bomb” cape</u></a> now that it’s finally made its way into the game.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Michael Cripe is a freelance writer with IGN. He's best known for his work at sites like The Pitch, The Escapist, and OnlySP. Be sure to give him a follow on Bluesky (@mikecripe.bsky.social) and Twitter (@MikeCripe).</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/helldivers-2-is-officially-getting-halo-odst-content-but-its-first-legendary-warbond-is-going-to-cost-you]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BioShock Studio Cloud Chamber Undergoes Layoffs, Appoints Rod Fergusson New BioShock Head]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/bioshock-studio-cloud-chamber-undergoes-layoffs-appoints-rod-fergusson-new-bioshock-head</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/bioshock-studio-cloud-chamber-undergoes-layoffs-appoints-rod-fergusson-new-bioshock-head.1274076/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">New BioShock game to be "reworked" as team is reduced.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">2K Games is laying off an unknown number of individuals at BioShock studio Cloud Chamber, as it undergoes efforts to "rework" its upcoming new BioShock game.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It's also installing former Gears of War head and Diablo franchise lead Rod Fergusson as head of BioShock and Cloud Chamber at 2K. Fergusson <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/rod-fergusson-departs-blizzard-diablo-franchise">departed Blizzard earlier this month</a> with no word on why he left, or who would replace him.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">This was gleaned from an email sent by 2K president David Ismailer to staff and subsequently shared with IGN. It reads, in part:</p><blockquote>Work on the next BioShock game has been underway for several years. While we’re excited about the foundational gameplay elements of the project, we’ve made the decision with studio leadership to rework certain aspects that are core to a BioShock game, and in doing so are reducing the size of the development team to focus on this work and give the game more time in development. </blockquote><p data-cy="paragraph">Employees impacted are being informed today. 2K did not share how many were impacted.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"I recognize that today is a day of mixed emotions," the email concludes. "We’re excited to have Rod joining us, and are equally grateful to everyone at Cloud Chamber who has helped us get this far. These changes are rooted in 2K’s firm confidence in BioShock as one of the most beloved franchises, and our commitment to deliver the best game in franchise history."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">BioShock 4 was <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2018/04/13/2k-studio-reportedly-developing-new-bioshock">first reported on in 2018</a>, and news has been few and far between since. We know it's been in development at Cloud Chamber at least since then, and that former BioShock lead Ken Levine is not working on it. We've yet to see any gameplay or learn much about the game beyond that it <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/bioshock-4-setting-rapture-columbia-job-listings">takes place in a brand new setting</a>, and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/next-bioshock-game-hiring-writer-for-open-world-setting">is open world</a>. Earlier this month, <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-08-01/next-bioshock-game-changes-leaders-after-development-turmoil" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">a Bloomberg report stated</a> that the game would be undergoing a development overhaul after it was <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/bioshock-4-reportedly-getting-a-narrative-overhaul-amid-development-struggles">criticized by executives for narrative issues</a>. When we <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/bioshock-4-is-going-to-come-out-take-two-ceo-strauss-zelnick-promises-that-i-can-say-hand-on-heart-without-question">asked Take-Two CEO Strauss Zelnick about this a week later</a>, he reassured that BioShock 4 was "going to come out" for certain, but did not share information as to when, or what needed to be done to get it there.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Rebekah Valentine is a senior reporter for IGN. You can find her posting on BlueSky @duckvalentine.bsky.social. Got a story tip? Send it to rvalentine@ign.com.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/bioshock-studio-cloud-chamber-undergoes-layoffs-appoints-rod-fergusson-new-bioshock-head]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[One of My Favorite PC Games of All Time Is Super Cheap During the Humble Bundle Summer Sale]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/one-of-my-favorite-pc-games-of-all-time-is-super-cheap-during-the-humble-bundle-summer-sale</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/one-of-my-favorite-pc-games-of-all-time-is-super-cheap-during-the-humble-bundle-summer-sale.1274073/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Inscryption drops to just $7.99.</h2></p><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">I've played my fair share of video games in my life, but only a handful have ever truly changed the way I think about gaming. Inscryption is one of those experiences. This game beautifully blends genres in such a unique way that it's hard to really describe. I first went into gameplay thinking it was just a cool roguelike deck-building card game, which would have been interesting enough. But no, it's so much more than that.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Without spoiling anything important, I'll just say that Inscryption has a lot more depth than you'd expect and a <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/inscryption/Ending_Explained">pretty wild ending</a>. If you like the thrill of psychological horror <em>and</em> strategy, I can't recommend this game enough – especially when it's only $7.99. Just try not to read too much about it before you start playing so you can get the full experience.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Inscryption Is on Sale for $7.99 on PC</h2><div catalogid="374d8a96-90ae-40eb-aed9-9d99fe47b2e6" id="227072"><div id="227072" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Inscryption</h3></p><div data-cy="solo-product-description"><p>Available for PC and Mac.</p></div></div><p data-cy="paragraph">At $7.99, this matches the lowest price we've ever <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/1092790/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">seen the game go on Steam</a>. The latest discount is thanks to Humble Bundle's Summer Sale going on right now. According to the Humble Bundle website, this discount will last through <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/events/labor-day-sales">Labor Day</a>, so you have plenty of time to decide if you want it or not. Alongside Inscryption, this sale includes a ton of other PC games at some of the lowest prices of the year. You can check out the full sale below and even sign up for a Humble Choice subscription for an additional 20% off these discounts.</p></div><div catalogid="374d8a96-90ae-40eb-aed9-9d99fe47b2e6" id="227073"><div id="227073" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Humble Bundle Summer Sale</h3></p><div data-cy="solo-product-description"><p>Get an additional 20% off with a Humble Choice subscription.</p></div></div><h2 data-cy="title2">What We Said in Our Review</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">IGN gave the game a rare 9 out of 10 back in 2021 when the game first came out. Here's a snippet of what we though in our <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/inscryption-review">review of Inscryption</a>:</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>"Inscryption is a surprising and delightful meta-twist on the digital card games that have exploded in recent years. Its unsettling story is the perfect vehicle for its ever-evolving mechanics, which constantly keep the simple but entertaining card game at its heart fresh. It’s a wonderfully strange game, but Inscryption is truly excellent because it’s also a genuinely fun one – and like Pony Island before it, you should probably go in knowing as little as possible."</em> - Tom Marks</p></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Aug 19, 2025 3:36 pm</p></div></div><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/one-of-my-favorite-pc-games-of-all-time-is-super-cheap-during-the-humble-bundle-summer-sale]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trick-based 3D train platformer Denshattack! announced for PS5, Xbox Series, and PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/08/trick-based-3d-train-platformer-denshattack-announced-for-ps5-xbox-series-and-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/trick-based-3d-train-platformer-denshattack-announced-for-ps5-xbox-series-and-pc.1274070/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Due out in spring 2026.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Fireshine Games [85 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/enad-global-7/fireshine-games">Fireshine Games</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Undercoders [6 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/undercoders">Undercoders</a> have announced <em><a title="Games > Denshattack! [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/denshattack">Denshattack!</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [10,133 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [7,703 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [23,941 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> (<a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2524850/Denshattack/" target="_blank">Steam</a>, <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-us/games/store/denshattack/9n18l56xhk8z" target="_blank">Microsoft Store</a>). It will launch in spring 2026. <span id="more-985562"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Fireshine Games:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Flip, trick and grind your train in a fast-paced, off-the-rails ride through a colorful Japanese dystopia. Outmatch rival gangs, wreck a shady megacorp, and take back the tracks with nothing but skill, speed, and style.</p><p>Hop aboard your custom gravity-defying train and embark on a hectic quest to defeat the sinister Miraido corporation, alongside a vibrant pack of outcasts.</p></blockquote><div id="carousel_985571"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div><!-- AD: content -->
        <blockquote><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Pull Off Stylish Tricks</strong> – Ollie, kickflip, and grind your way through Japan’s biggest cities, as well as a world of meadows, volcanoes and oceans. Rack up points and chase that sweet high score as you flip, trick and stick the landing in your customizable ride.</li><li><strong>Build Your Reputation</strong> – Face off against a lineup of reimagined Japanese trains, gain the respect of an underground network of gangs and rebels, and turn rivals to allies as you master your skills. Journey from naive beginner to seasoned pro as you strive to race the fastest train in existence and become a legendary Denshattacker!</li><li><strong>Battle Bizarre Bosses</strong> – From mecha magical girls to moving castles, and mechanical worms to a Denshattacker army—face a flurry of madcap bosses that get wilder and wilder the further you get. Use what you’ve learned to stop them in their tracks.</li><li><strong>Discover a Transformed Japan</strong> – Travel from the countryside of Kyushu through the metropolises of Osaka, Tokyo and more, now sealed under domes by Miraido. Venture across Japan to the snowfields of Hokkaido… and beyond! Each new region holds fresh challenges to beat and rules to break.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch the announcement trailer below. View the first screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/denshattack/august-19-2025/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Denshattack!  - Announce Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/E1hNqwhSQqU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/08/trick-based-3d-train-platformer-denshattack-announced-for-ps5-xbox-series-and-pc]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Call Of Duty: Black Ops 7 Beta: Start Date, How To Get In, And Everything Else To Know]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-beta-start-time-how-to-get-in-and-everything-else-to-know/1100-6534073/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-beta-start-date-how-to-get-in-and-everything-else-to-know.1274067/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6534073">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>A multiplayer beta for <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-2025-everything-we-know-about-rumored-black-ops-2-sequel/1100-6529073/" data-ref-id="1100-6529073">Call of Duty: Black Ops 7</a> has been leaked on the Xbox website, revealing the first chance to try out the newest entry in the blockbuster FPS series is coming up this October.</p><p>Here's everything you need to know about the upcoming Black Ops 7 multiplayer beta, but be aware we don't know all that much yet since the existence of the product page just emerged minutes ago.</p><h2><strong>When does the Black Ops 7 beta start?</strong></h2><p>The Black Ops 7 multiplayer beta starts on October 2, according to an <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-us/games/store/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-cross-gen-bundle/9plbm5790l94" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Xbox.com product page for Black Ops 7.</a> But October 2 is only when the "early access" period begins. Everyone else can start playing on October 5, according to the product page.</p><h2><strong>How to get in to the Black Ops 7 beta</strong></h2><p>According to the product page that has seemingly gone live too early, it's an open beta, which suggests anyone can play it. The "early access" qualifier suggests only certain people can get in early. For Black Ops 6, Activision invited Game Pass subscribers and people who preordered the ability to get in first, but it remains to be seen what the deal is for Black Ops 7's beta.</p><h2><strong>What's in the Black Ops 7 beta?</strong></h2><p>Activision has not announced what maps and modes will be in the Black Ops 7 multiplayer beta. But all should become clear in the relatively near future. Given that the Xbox.com product page went live ahead of the Gamescom unveiling today, August 19, it's possible we'll learn more today.</p><p>Keep checking back with GameSpot for the latest.</p><p>Black Ops 7 is reportedly set to launch on November 14, which is about a month after Battlefield 6 arrives on October 10. Treyarch and Raven Software, the same developers that led the production of 2024's Black Ops 6, are returning to co-lead the development on Black Ops 7. </p><p>Black Ops 7 is coming to PS5, PS4, Xbox One, Xbox Series X|S, and PC, but <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/even-call-of-duty-black-ops-7-wont-get-xbox-to-price-a-game-at-80-report/1100-6534069/" data-ref-id="1100-6534069">reportedly not Switch 2</a>. It'll also be available on Xbox Game Pass and it <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/even-call-of-duty-black-ops-7-wont-get-xbox-to-price-a-game-at-80-report/1100-6534069/" data-ref-id="1100-6534069">likely won't cost $80.</a></p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-beta-start-time-how-to-get-in-and-everything-else-to-know/1100-6534073/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Obituary: Black Forest Games producer Dennis Schiefer has passed away]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/obituary-black-forest-games-producer-dennis-schiefer-has-passed-away</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/obituary-black-forest-games-producer-dennis-schiefer-has-passed-away.1274064/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-testid="article-base-contributors"><div data-component="contributors"><p><a data-testid="contributor-name" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/author/diego-arguello" data-discover="true">Diego Argüello</a><span data-testid="contributor-title">, <!-- -->Contributing Editor, News</span><span data-testid="contributor-title">, <!-- -->GameDeveloper.com</span></p><p data-testid="contributors-date">August 19, 2025</p></div><p><span data-component="icon" data-name="Clock"></span><span>2 Min<!-- --> <!-- -->Read</span></p></div><div data-component="captioned-content" data-testid="featured-image"><p><span>Picture via Black Forest Games</span></p></div><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Dennis Schiefer, a veteran producer with a seven-year tenure at Black Forest Games, has passed away.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Adrian Goersch, CEO and founder of Black Forest Games, a THQ Nordic Studio, shared the news two days ago </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/activity-7362787123709497345-u3QR?utm_source=social_share_send&amp;utm_medium=member_desktop_web&amp;rcm=ACoAAByD5EUBfxY4kCf3wHtdwCavc5euTv0rxzo">via LinkedIn</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. "It is with great sadness that I must share the news that Dennis Schiefer, a long-standing producer at #BlackForestGames, passed away last week," he wrote. "We are all shocked and heartbroken."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Goersch explained that Schiefer joined the studio back in 2016 and had a seven-year tenure until he took a break in 2023. "Dennis was kind, friendly, and always there for others," he added. "We never expected that he wouldn't come back."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The CEO considers Schiefer an exceptional producer, with credits on 2020's </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Destroy All Humans!</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> remake, as well as </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Destroy All Humans! 2: Reprobed</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">. According to his </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.mobygames.com/person/887500/dennis-schiefer/">Moby Games profile</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, Schiefer is also credited as producer for </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Fade to Silence</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Bubsy: The Woolies Strike Back</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Rogue Stormers</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Many fellow devs replied to Goersch's write-up expressing condolences, as well as sharing fond memories about Schiefer's impact on the industry and the people in it.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Sincerely sad to read this," current DICE game designer and former Black Forest mission designer Andrea Villa </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:7362787123709497345?commentUrn=urn%3Ali%3Acomment%3A%28activity%3A7362787123709497345%2C7362819910789476352%29&amp;dashCommentUrn=urn%3Ali%3Afsd_comment%3A%287362819910789476352%2Curn%3Ali%3Aactivity%3A7362787123709497345%29">wrote</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. "He was indeed a good human. My condolences especially to his loved ones, but I think everyone that got to know him even a little bit (like myself) will feel the loss."</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/starbreeze-says-pubg-collab-was-its-single-largest-revenue-contributor-in-q2" target="_self" data-discover="true">Starbreeze says PUBG collab was its 'single largest revenue contributor' in Q2</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Daniel Görlich, professor and head of the "Virtual Worlds and Game Technologies" Bachelor of Science Study Program at the Offenburg University of Applied Sciences, said that he had the privilege of working with Schiefer during the current summer semester until last month. "He taught project design and project management with such passion and expertise," Görlich </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:7362787123709497345?commentUrn=urn%3Ali%3Acomment%3A%28activity%3A7362787123709497345%2C7362793396517707776%29&amp;dashCommentUrn=urn%3Ali%3Afsd_comment%3A%287362793396517707776%2Curn%3Ali%3Aactivity%3A7362787123709497345%29">wrote</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Isabel Stiefvatter, a student and former intern at Black Forest, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:7362787123709497345?commentUrn=urn%3Ali%3Acomment%3A%28activity%3A7362787123709497345%2C7362810406370742273%29&amp;dashCommentUrn=urn%3Ali%3Afsd_comment%3A%287362810406370742273%2Curn%3Ali%3Aactivity%3A7362787123709497345%29">echoed the sentiment</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">: "He had a lot of experience that he was always eager to share with us students at Hs Offenburg, he was cheerful and motivating, even very understanding when someone had questions or didn’t understand something right away (speaking from personal experience). He was a happy man. This is shocking to me. I wish all the best to everyone that knew him. May the memories with him be cherished."</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Contributing Editor, News, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Diego Nicolás Argüello is a freelance journalist and critic from Argentina. Video games helped him to learn English, so now he covers them for places like The New York Times, NPR, Rolling Stone, and more. He also runs Into the Spine, a site dedicated to fostering and supporting new writers, and co-hosted Turnabout Breakdown, a podcast about the Ace Attorney series. He’s most likely playing a rhythm game as you read this.</span></p></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/obituary-black-forest-games-producer-dennis-schiefer-has-passed-away]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 open beta starts 2nd October]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-open-beta-starts-2nd-october</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-open-beta-starts-2nd-october.1274061/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Activision</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
    <div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/call-of-duty-black-ops-7">Call of Duty: Black Ops 7</a> will have an open beta starting on 2nd October for those who pre-order the game or subscribe to Game Pass Ultimate, Game Pass PC, or Game Pass Console. For those who don't pre-order, the open beta begins on 5th October.
</p>
<p>Pre-orders also include the Reznov Challenge Pack, which provides access to the SOG Reznov Operator Skin in <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/call-of-duty-2024">Black Ops 6</a> and Warzone (this must be redeemed before 14th November 2026). You'll also get the Stalingrad Reznov and Memory Reznov Operator Skins.</p>
<p>It's worth noting the game is available as a cross-gen bundle, meaning if you buy it you'll gain access to Black Ops 7 on the Xbox Series X/S, Xbox One, and Xbox PC. You might want to make sure you have an active Game Pass subscription going though, especially if you claim the game through Game Pass Ultimate.</p>

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 - Official 'The Guild - Don't Fear Tomorrow' Trailer" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/T4bWoiH5b1U?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 - Official 'The Guild - Don't Fear Tomorrow' Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/T4bWoiH5b1U?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/T4bWoiH5b1U?autoplay=1" title="Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 - Official 'The Guild - Don't Fear Tomorrow' Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Check out the latest Black Ops 7 trailer here.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=T4bWoiH5b1U" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>


<p><em>This is a news-in-brief story. This is part of <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/eurogamer-is-changing-to-give-you-more-of-what-you-want">our vision</a> to bring you all the big news as part of a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/today-in-video-games-19th-august-gamescoms-big-night-and-sword-of-the-sea-is-released">daily live report</a>.</em></p>

        </div>


      </article>



  
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-open-beta-starts-2nd-october]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kirby Air Riders will launch on November 20th]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/08/19/kirby-air-riders-will-launch-on-november-20th/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/kirby-air-riders-will-launch-on-november-20th.1274040/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>During Nintendo’s Kirby Air Riders Direct, Nintendo confirmed that the game will available from November 20th on Switch 2. Kirby Air Riders is a racing game sequel to Kirby Air Ride which launched in 2003 for the Gamecube, with Masahiro Sakurai taking on the director duties of the game. If you want an in depth look at the game, you can watch the full Kirby Air Riders direct below.</p>
<p><iframe title="Kirby Air Riders Direct 8.19.2025" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/QtkHiB7WKf4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>Kirby Air Riders will feature a roster of 16 playable characters, including Kirby, Meta Knight, King Dedede, Bandana Waddle Dee, Cappy, Chef Kawasaki, and Starman. After choosing your character you can also choose different Air Machines, with each having various stats that affect speed and durability, meaning some will be better to use when facing off against opponents. Each character also has a unique special ability that can give an advantage during races, apart from Kirby who has four abilities depending on which colour Kirby you play as. While the abilities are unique, all characters have the Copy Ability which allows characters to steal and use each other’s abilities.</p>
<p>Skyah is the main area players will be able to travel across freely starting off with a rather weak Air Machine. In Skyah, players will be able to attack opponents and take part in different events all over the map including races and battles. If you don’t fancy spending all your time in Skyah you can head to the Stadiums and take part in different challenges, with some challenges being recommended based on your machine stats. Air Ride Mode is a race mode that has six racers compete against each other to cross the finish line first. There is also a Lessons mode which is essentially a tutorial mode where players can try out different machines and characters.</p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QtkHiB7WKf4">YouTube</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/08/19/kirby-air-riders-will-launch-on-november-20th/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tales Of Xillia Remastered Coming This October, Confirmed 30fps For Switch]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/tales-of-xillia-remastered-coming-this-october-confirmed-30fps-for-switch</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/tales-of-xillia-remastered-coming-this-october-confirmed-30fps-for-switch.1274037/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>No Song 4 u, though</p>
</section></header><section>

<p>Bandai Namco has finally confirmed the next Tales series remaster, and — shocker! — it's <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/tales_of_xillia_remastered">Tales of Xillia Remastered</a>, and it's coming to Switch 1.</p>
<p>So, we all saw this coming after last week's leak, but here's the surprising bits of news — it's coming out on 31st October 2025, <em>and</em> only Xillia 1 is included, not Xillia 2. Well, the latter was sort of expected, but we hoped the sequel would be bundled too.</p>
<p>Like with <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/tales_of_graces_f_remastered">Graces f Remastered</a> earlier in the year, the Switch version of the remaster will also run at 30fps (confirmed on <a href="https://coexist.tales-ch.jp/">the Japanese website</a>) and will be 1080p docked, 720p handheld, making it a bit of a downgrade compared to other releases.</p>
<p>But there are a ton of other features that may make picking this remaster a sweeter deal. Detailed on <a href="https://en.bandainamcoent.eu/tales-of/tales-of-xillia-remastered">the official website</a> (under the What's New section), Tales of Xillia Remastered will include the following:</p>
<ul>
<li>Upgraded visuals</li>
<li>Access to the Grade Shop immediately, plus a new item in the shop — "50% off items"</li>
<li>Over 40 original DLC available from the start</li>
<li>Autosave</li>
<li>A new Enemy Encounter toggle, meaning you can entirely avoid combat (except for certain Events)</li>
<li>A Retry feature for regular fights</li>
<li>Subtitles in combat, which you can customise to your liking</li>
<li>A toggle for dashing</li>
<li>Map icons for story destinations, sub-events, and unacquired items and treasure chests</li>
<li>Toggle to automatically skip events</li>
<li>New Artes and items will now be marked</li>
<li>Item descriptions added to the Jet Black Feather Trading Post</li>
<li>Pressing the appropriate button in Option or in the Store will take you to the top of that screen/option from any level</li>
<li>Batch selection available for store development</li>
<li>Can open chests and items even if not facing them - as long as you're next to them, you can open them</li>
<li>You can switch between camera distances on the map to near, normal, or far</li>
<li>Key binding is available on the map and in battle</li>
<li>Additional volume settings, allowing you to adjust the volume of any individual sound aspect</li>
<li>The ability to swap between English and Japanese voices</li>
<li>Typos and errors corrected (in the Japanese version)</li>
<li>Some expressions have been tweaked.</li>
</ul>

<p>So... quite a lot has been tweaked, then! Plus, the biggie is that the game is no longer stuck on PS3. So that's good!</p>
<p>A Digital Deluxe Edition will include the digital soundtrack, artbook, a Battle BGM Pack and Super Growth Support Herb Set. Pre-ordering early will also get you a handful of in-game items to aid you in your journey, which includes Life Bottles and healing Gels.</p>
<p>Along with the announcement trailer up top, there's also a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=b1nfS6iEx2E&amp;ab_channel=BandaiNamcoEntertainmentAmerica">short video from the Tales series producer, Yusuke Tomizawa</a>.</p>
<p><em>Are you excited for Tales of Xillia Remastered? Let us know in the comments</em>.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-articles:176866,186504 @ 1755622806 --></section></article><div><p>Alana has been with Nintendo Life since 2022, and while RPGs are her first love, Nintendo is a close second. She enjoys nothing more than overthinking battle strategies, characters, and stories. She also wishes she was a Sega air pirate.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/AlanaHagues"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/alanahagues.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('AlanaHagues');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/tales-of-xillia-remastered-coming-this-october-confirmed-30fps-for-switch]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 Open Beta Announced for October]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-open-beta-october/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-open-beta-announced-for-october.1274034/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p><a href="https://wccftech.com/ea-battlefield-2042-update-battlefield-6-beta-end/">Battlefield 6</a> has had its open beta, and now it's Call of Duty's turn, as the <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-us/games/store/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-cross-gen-bundle/9plbm5790l94">official store page on Xbox website</a> confirms that Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 will have an open beta that will be live for Xbox Game Pass Ultimate subscribers on October 2, 2025, and for everyone else on October 5. The description doesn't say how long the beta will last, or if there will be a second weekend, but further down in the description it does say that "<em>Open Beta duration is 2 days</em>" at a minimum.</p>



<p>That said, we'll likely have much more information on the beta and on Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 in general after Gamescom ONL 2025 today, which is kicking off in just a little more than an hour at the time of this writing. The game's full reveal is <a href="https://wccftech.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-reveal-gamescom/">set to kick off the showcase</a> today, and it's a good bet that we'll hear more specifics about the open beta, and get a confirmation of the game's release date that seems to have <a href="https://wccftech.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-launch-november-14-no-switch-2/">already leaked just last week</a>. </p>



<p>Though the store page does potentially confirm the release date, since it says that the Reznov Challenge Pack that can be unlocked in Black Ops 6 "<em>Must be redeemed by November 14, 2025</em>."</p>







<p>What's interesting about these open beta dates, and the leaked release date, is that it means Black Ops 7 will be having its beta right around the time Battlefield 6 is launching, and if the leaked release date is correct, Battlefield 6 will have had a full month to build an audience and potential lead on Call of Duty before its even out on store shelves.</p>



<p>There's been a lot of talk about what the bout between both shooters will look like this year, with some thinking that <a href="https://wccftech.com/blizzard-president-battlefield-6-boot-stomp-call-of-duty-black-ops-7/">EA has the chance to take a win over Activision</a>, though others are less convinced, even while admitting that <a href="https://wccftech.com/battlefield-6-potential-to-do-best-battlefield-has-ever-done-600k-steam-pre-orders/">Battlefield 6 is looking like it'll be a tentpole entry for the series</a>.</p>



<p>Call of Duty has the strength of its annual releases and years of community built behind it, so it's definitely unlikely that Battlefield 6 will be able to go toe-to-toe with it Black Ops 7 on the sales charts. But it can certainly try, and for shooter fans, it's exciting to see both series back in fighting shape after years of Call of Duty dominance. </p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-open-beta-october/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[All the news from Gamescom Opening Night Live 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/760975/gamescom-opening-night-live-2025-news-trailers</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/all-the-news-from-gamescom-opening-night-live-2025.1274031/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><section><p>With Gamescom’s Opening Night Live, the summer of games comes to a close. Join Mr. Video Games himself, Geoff Keighley, on August 19th at 2PM ET as he emcees the last big video game livestream event before the kids go back to school and the adults break out the Halloween decorations.</p><div><p>We already <a href="https://x.com/geoffkeighley/status/1956355195287323133">know that we can expect</a> news of <em>Call of Duty: Black Ops 7</em>, <em>Ghost of Yōtei</em>, <em>Outer Worlds 2</em>, and more. Outside of video games, we might also get a new trailer for <a href="https://www.theverge.com/games/760687/fallout-season-two-first-look-prime-video"><em>Fallout</em> season two</a> and maybe an update on the <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/25/22350484/sony-ghost-of-tsushima-movie-film-director-john-wick-sucker-punch"><em>Ghost of Tsushima</em> movie</a>. And out of all the video game events of the last few years, this one might actually, truly, be the one where we get actual news of a release date for <em>Hollow Knight: Silksong</em>. <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/756538/silksong-will-also-at-nintendos-gamescom-booth">There will be a playable demo on the Gamescom floor</a>, which <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/760922/real-silksong-news-is-imminent">has to mean something</a>, right?</p></div><p>Follow along below for all of our coverage of the news and announcements from Opening Night Live 2025.</p></section><section id="updates-section"><ul><li role="article"><div><p>Skate on a train.</p><p>Or as a train, rather. That’s the premise of the slick-looking <em>Denshattack!</em> which combines the beauty of the Japanese rail system with, uh, skateboarding? I’m not really sure what’s going on but it looks fun, and launches next year.</p></div></li><li role="article"><div><p>Dotemu is making a Battlestar Galactica game.</p><p>In partnership with indie studio Alt Shift, Dotemu is working on <em>Battlestar Galactica: Scattered Hopes</em>, a “story-rich tactical roguelite” set in the universe of the cult classic sci-fi series. It’s launching on Steam in early 2026.</p></div></li><li role="article"><div><p>Gamescom’s Opening Night Live pre-show is about to start.</p><p>It kicks off at 1:30PM ET ahead of the main show at 2PM. You can watch everything on <a href="https://www.youtube.com/live/74oh7zD_jxI?feature=shared">YouTube</a> and <a href="https://www.twitch.tv/thegameawards">Twitch</a>. And you can follow all of our coverage <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/760975/gamescom-opening-night-live-2025-news-trailers">right here</a>.</p></div></li><li id="dmcyOnBvc3Q6NzYxNDUx" role="article"><h2><a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/761451/hollow-knight-silksong-special-announcement-youtube">Get ready for Silksong’s ‘special announcement’ on Thursday</a></h2></li><li id="dmcyOnBvc3Q6NzYxMDI3" role="article"><h2><a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/761027/gamescom-opening-night-live-2025-geoff-keighley-how-to-watch">How to watch Gamescom Opening Night Live 2025</a></h2></li></ul></section></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/news/760975/gamescom-opening-night-live-2025-news-trailers]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gears Of War Creator Says It ‘Doesn’t Feel Strange’ To See It Ported To PS5]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/gears-of-war-creator-cliffyb-ps5-port-thrilled-strange-xbox-return-to-gears-2000618463</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gears-of-war-creator-says-it-%E2%80%98doesn%E2%80%99t-feel-strange%E2%80%99-to-see-it-ported-to-ps5.1274022/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              
              <p><a href="https://kotaku.com/gears-of-war-1-reloaded-remaster-ps5-xbox-pc-summer-1851779167"><em>Gears of War</em> is making the leap to PlayStation 5 later this month</a> in what is one of the biggest signs that the <a href="https://kotaku.com/console-wars-are-over-ps5-xbox-forza-switch-2-sony-1851752956">console wars are over</a>. And while I find the idea of playing <em>Gears</em> on a PlayStation controller strange, franchise creator Cliff “CliffyB” Bleszinski is “thrilled” that something he worked so hard on will soon be available to more players.</p> <p><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/gears-of-war-creator-cliff-bleszinski-thrilled-about-seeing-his-once-xbox-exclusive-on-playstation">In a new interview with <em>Eurogamer</em></a>, Bleszinski was asked about the upcoming <a href="https://kotaku.com/gears-of-war-reloaded-crossplay-cross-save-progression-ps5-xbox-2000618072"><em>Gears of War: Reloaded</em></a>, which is a remaster of the original game’s <em>last</em> remaster. This new version with enhanced visuals and improved performance is launching on both Xbox and, for the first time in franchise history, PlayStation via a PS5 port. <a href="https://kotaku.com/xbox-gears-of-war-ps5-remake-remaster-halo-forza-port-1851779186">But while some fans find it all a bit bizarre</a> to chainsaw monsters with the DualSense’s circle button instead of the Xbox gamepad’s B, the original <em>Gears</em> trilogy’s director doesn’t feel the same.</p> <p>“It doesn’t feel strange,” Bleszinski explained to <em>Eurogamer</em> when asked if he finds the PS5 port weird. “I’m thrilled that more people are going to get to experience a big part of my legacy that I worked so hard on.”</p>

 <p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Gears of War: Reloaded - Official Trailer | PS5 Games" width="500" height="281" src="about:blank" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen="" data-rocket-lazyload="fitvidscompatible" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/vx8cUpL40Kc?feature=oembed"></iframe></p> <p>Bleszinski hasn’t worked on the <em>Gears</em> franchise since the launch of 2011’s<em> Gears of War 3</em> on Xbox 360. And since then, even after Microsoft bought the franchise in 2014 and started making its own third-person cover shooters, fans have continued to ask Bleszinski if he’d ever return to help make another<em> Gears of War</em> game. According to him, he’s asked “nearly every day on social media” about returning.</p> <p>“And I’m like ‘uh, I’ve said it a thousand times, I’m open to consult on any of it’,” said Bleszinski. But it seems Xbox isn’t interested in bringing him back to consult on a future game in the series, with the <em>Gears</em> creator adding, “Crickets. On to the next!” There is some irony in Xbox ignoring Cliff Bleszinski in 2025, despite <a href="https://youtu.be/AXO1mpgc-is">making “CliffyB” the rockstar face of the Xbox 360 </a>at the height of the console war between Microsoft’s device and the PS3 back in 2005, and positioning Epic’s then-upcoming game, <em>Gears of War,</em> as the 360’s killer app. Now they won’t even call him to get his input on the franchise.</p> <p><em>Gears of War: Reloaded</em> launches on Xbox Series X/S, PS5, and PC on August 26. <a href="https://kotaku.com/dragon-age-veilguard-gears-of-war-reloaded-game-pass-2000618432">It will be available on day one with Game Pass</a> and will be free to anyone who already owns <em>Gears of War: Ultimate Edition</em>, aka Xbox’s previous remaster of the game.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/gears-of-war-creator-cliffyb-ps5-port-thrilled-strange-xbox-return-to-gears-2000618463]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Confirmation On Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 Multiplayer Maps]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/confirmation-on-call-of-duty-black-ops-7-multiplayer-maps/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/confirmation-on-call-of-duty-black-ops-7-multiplayer-maps.1274019/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>The rumors have been confirmed as Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 will have 16 6v6 multiplayer maps available at launch. The news comes via the official Xbox store posting for the game. </p>



<p>In addition to the 6v6 maps, it was confirmed that there will be two 20v20 maps for players at launch as well. </p>



<p><strong>“Multiplayer explodes out of the gate with 16 electrifying 6v6 maps and two 20v20 maps at launch,” </strong>the game’s <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-us/games/store/call-of-duty-black-ops-7/9plbm5790l94" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">store page reads</a>. <strong>“From futuristic Tokyo vistas to the frozen, unforgiving wilds of Alaska, every environment is brimming with danger and opportunity. Master a cutting-edge arsenal and outmaneuver your enemies with an evolved Omnimovement system.”</strong></p>



<p>Going back to the maps, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-7-will-feature-16-6v6-maps-at-launch-its-claimed" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a recent leak suggests</a> that 13 of the 16 will be brand new. The other three will be remastered from past titles. </p>



<p>In addition to standard multiplayer, Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 will feature a co-op campaign that <strong>“redefines the Black Ops experience.”</strong></p>



<p><strong>“Take on high-stakes challenges across a wide spectrum of environments, from the neon-lit rooftops of Japan to the Mediterranean coast, and even into the deepest corners of the human psyche</strong>,” the game’s description reads.</p>



<p>Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 is scheduled to launch on November 14. If you can’t wait that long, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-beta-date-revealed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a multiplayer beta will take plac</a>e starting October 2.</p>



<p>What do you think of 16 multiplayer maps for Black Ops 7 at launch? Let us know down below, and talk about everything Call of Duty in the official <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums.</a></p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read about who’s joining 2K Games to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/rod-fergusson-joins-2k-to-lead-bioshock-franchise" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">lead the development of the next BioShock game</a>. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/confirmation-on-call-of-duty-black-ops-7-multiplayer-maps/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BioShock 4 Studio Laying Off Devs As Diablo Boss Takes Over]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/bioshock-4-studio-laying-off-devs-as-diablo-boss-takes-over/1100-6534080/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/bioshock-4-studio-laying-off-devs-as-diablo-boss-takes-over.1274016/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6534080">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Earlier this summer, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/bioshock-remake-cancelled-as-bioshock-4-reportedly-fails-a-review/1100-6533650/" data-ref-id="1100-6533650">BioShock 4 reportedly failed an internal review</a>, which led to Cloud Chamber head Kelley Gilmore exiting the studio. Now, Cloud Chamber has been hit with layoffs as a former Diablo boss steps in to take over the studio.</p><p>Bloomberg's <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/jasonschreier.bsky.social/post/3lwr7jxitg22z" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Jason Schreier</a> was the first to report about Cloud Chamber's layoffs. He also added that former Diablo boss Rod Fergusson will be the new studio head for Cloud Chamber. Fergusson previously took over production of BioShock Infinite and helped guide that game to completion. Fergusson recently <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/diablo-boss-departs-blizzard-after-five-years/1100-6533809/" data-ref-id="1100-6533809">announced his departure from Blizzard</a> after spending five years with the company.</p><p>2K Games subsequently shared an internal memo with GameSpot from president David Ismailer, which stressed that the BioShock franchise is important to the company. "While we're excited about the foundational gameplay elements of the project, we've made the decision with studio leadership to rework certain aspects that are core to a BioShock game," said Ismailer.</p><p>Ismailer characterized the Cloud Chamber layoffs as an opportunity for the remaining developers "to focus on this work and give the game more time in development." He also confirmed Fergusson's new role in the company and touted his track record in the industry.</p><p>"As Head of the BioShock Franchise, Rod will lead Cloud Chamber and oversee the development of the next BioShock game, as well as franchise extensions including our film partnership with Netflix. We will share more about Rod’s onboarding and how these changes will take shape in the coming days and weeks. Rod and I worked together 10+ years ago and I am grateful he has chosen to return to lead our BioShock efforts."</p><p>Fergusson also shared a statement on social media about his return to 2K Games.</p><div data-embed-type="tweet" data-src="https://twitter.com/RodFergusson/status/1957824815018213692" data-has-image="false"><blockquote data-conversation="none" data-mce-disable-toolbar="true"><p dir="ltr">Would you kindly allow me to share some news?<br>Some of you guessed it, I’m returning to 2K to lead a series that means a lot to me as the new Head of the BioShock Franchise. I’ll be heading up Cloud Chamber and overseeing development of the next BioShock game, along with…</p>  — Rod Fergusson (@RodFergusson) <a href="https://twitter.com/RodFergusson/status/1957824815018213692?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 19, 2025</a></blockquote>              </div><p>As for the BioShock movie at Netflix, Francis Lawrence is still attached to direct it. Lawrence's most recent update for the film indicated that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-tricky-bioshock-movie-is-not-dead-brings-on-a-new-writer/1100-6531560/" data-ref-id="1100-6531560">a new draft of the film has been written</a> by Terminator: Dark Fate scribe Justin Rhodes. So far, no cast members have been announced.</p><p>BioShock creator Ken Levine is still working on his next game, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/judas/" data-ref-id="5000-577619">Judas</a>, which be published by Take-Two at some point in the future.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/bioshock-4-studio-laying-off-devs-as-diablo-boss-takes-over/1100-6534080/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Monster Hunter Wilds PC Problems Will Be Addressed In An Update This Winter]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/monster-hunter-wilds-pc-problems-will-be-addressed-in-an-update-this-winter/1100-6534077/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/monster-hunter-wilds-pc-problems-will-be-addressed-in-an-update-this-winter.1274013/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-main">

      
                    
  
              <header id="masthead"><nav></nav></header>      
                            <div id="site-wrapper" role="main">
          <div id="default-content">
        
          <p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p>
  
    <article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6534077">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>As it currently stands, playing <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/monster-hunter-wilds/">Monster Hunter Wilds</a> on PC can be a subpar experience. It's had plenty of issues since launch, and while it's better now for some, it still suffers from numerous performance problems. However, Capcom is continuously working on solving the game's issues on PC, and in a <a href="https://x.com/monsterhunter/status/1957473035885121806" rel="nofollow ">post shared to the official Monster Hunter X account</a>, it explained the steps it intends to take, but it sounds like significant fixes may not arrive until this winter.</p><p dir="ltr">"To our hunters playing [Monster Hunter Wilds] on PC, we're committed to listening to your feedback and improving both performance and stability of the game," reads the post. "Although we will continue to implement gradual improvements in the weeks ahead, we are targeting Free Title Update Four this winter to implement a multifaceted plan, including CPU and GPU related optimizations, followed by a second stage of mitigation measures afterwards." The post ended by saying that specific details will be coming in the future.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="1444688507" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6465687,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Monster%20Hunter%20Wilds%20-%20Official%20Launch%20Trailer&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:251,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/monster-hunter-wilds-official-launch-trailer\/2300-6465687\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465687\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465687\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465687\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6465687&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6465687,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6534077&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;monster-hunter-wilds&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;action,role-playing&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;pc,xbox-series-x,playstation-5&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;capcom&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;franchise&quot;:&quot;monster-hunter&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;franchiseRoot&quot;:&quot;monster-hunter&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6465687},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6465687\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;Publisher Asset&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4443242-11.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/hhz8BMly.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1739398740,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="hhz8BMly" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> Monster Hunter Wilds - Official Launch Trailer</p>
      </div>
<p dir="ltr">Last week, a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/monster-hunter-wilds-patch-notes-new-update-adds-tougher-endgame-content-weapon-changes-more/1100-6533861/">new patch arrived in Monster Hunter Wilds</a>, bringing with it tougher endgame monsters and balance tweaks, but also a bug that would cause the game to <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/capcom-knows-about-that-monster-hunter-wilds-crashing-bug-is-working-on-a-fix/1100-6533906/">crash in certain circumstances</a>. That bug has <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/monster-hunter-wilds-gets-new-patch-fixing-crashing-bug-from-recent-update-and-more/1100-6533969/">since been fixed</a>, helping to pave the way for the game's third title update which is due out in September. A release date for title update four hasn't been announced just yet, so PC players will have to wait a while longer for more details.</p><p dir="ltr">You can check out GameSpot's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/monster-hunter-wilds-review-new-frontier/1900-6418338/">Monster Hunter Wilds review</a> to help you figure out if the game is worth it even with all of its troubles.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article>

    
  

</div>
                      <meta itemprop="seamless-content-list-items" data-list-items="[{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6533969&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/monster-hunter-wilds-gets-new-patch-fixing-crashing-bug-from-recent-update-and-more\/1100-6533969\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6533906&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/capcom-knows-about-that-monster-hunter-wilds-crashing-bug-is-working-on-a-fix\/1100-6533906\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534024&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/kirby-air-riders-nintendo-direct-coming-tuesday-will-run-a-whopping-45-minutes\/1100-6534024\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534004&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/what-pants-are-best-for-drag-x-drive-an-investigation\/1100-6534004\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534067&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/capcom-gears-up-for-resident-evil-30th-anniversary-celebration-with-new-website\/1100-6534067\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6533890&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/battlefield-6-devs-are-looking-into-unexpectedly-fast-time-to-kill-reports-from-open-beta\/1100-6533890\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6533922&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/metal-gear-solid-deltas-new-online-multiplayer-mode-wont-support-cross-play\/1100-6533922\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534065&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/pokemon-legends-z-as-latest-teaser-might-make-you-think-its-switched-genres\/1100-6534065\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6533902&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/crimson-desert-gets-delay-to-2026-developer-explains-why\/1100-6533902\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6530006&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/professor-layton-and-the-eternal-diva-animated-movie-blu-ray-amazon-deal\/1100-6530006\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6533927&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/avatar-the-last-airbender-magic-the-gathering-preorder-restock-buying-guide\/1100-6533927\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534034&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/razer-just-released-two-new-blackwidow-v4-low-profile-wireless-keyboards\/1100-6534034\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6533929&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/roblox-is-not-doing-enough-to-protect-kids-lawmaker-says\/1100-6533929\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6533987&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/mafia-the-old-country-will-expand-with-free-ride-mode-in-future-update\/1100-6533987\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6533899&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/grounded-2-reaches-major-player-milestone\/1100-6533899\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6533888&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/battlefield-6-devs-are-adjusting-helicopter-controls-after-first-beta\/1100-6533888\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6533995&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/new-crimson-desert-video-features-cannons-lightning-attacks-and-two-boss-battles\/1100-6533995\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534035&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/the-pokemon-tcg-is-getting-a-new-type-of-rare-mega-evolution-cards\/1100-6534035\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6533928&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/dragon-age-origins-wasnt-meant-to-be-the-origin-of-a-series\/1100-6533928\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6533962&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-will-blend-the-campaign-and-multiplayer-like-never-before-report\/1100-6533962\/&quot;}]">
            </div>
              
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/monster-hunter-wilds-pc-problems-will-be-addressed-in-an-update-this-winter/1100-6534077/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gamescom Opening Night Live 2025 livestream and blog]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/gamescom-opening-night-live-2025-livestream-and-blog</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gamescom-opening-night-live-2025-livestream-and-blog.1274010/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>Pre-show at 6.30pm UK, full show at 7pm.</p>

<p><span>
  Live
</span>    </p></div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Gamescom / Opening Night Live</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
    <div data-component="article-content">

        <div>



            <p>It's <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/everything-announced-at-gamescom-opening-night-live-2024">Gamescom</a> Opening Night Live time, which means <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/personas/geoff-keighley">Geoff Keighley</a>'s back with a probably slightly too long broadcast, containing, we hope, some exciting game announcements. I'll be joined in the commentary box by Tom Orry and we'll be watching the broadcast and bringing you a blow-by-blow account of it, right here. We also have a number of our team there at the show, so maybe they'll cause some mischief in the auditorium as we watch.</p>
<p>The important stuff: the Opening Night Live pre-show begins at 6.30pm UK time, and the main show at 7pm (8pm CEST / 2pm EDT / 11 am PDT). You don't need to do anything but keep this page open and watch and comment, and the coverage will roll in.</p>
<p>So what do we hope to see? We can expect a better look at the next Resi game, Resident Evil: Requiem, as well as some <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/silent-hill-f">Silent Hill f</a>, the new World of Warcraft expansion Midnight, and <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/ghost-of-yotei">Ghost of Yotei</a>, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/call-of-duty-black-ops">Call of Duty: Black Ops</a> 7, and The Outer Worlds 2. Oh and some Hollow Knight: Silksong, if you can believe it, although <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/no-hollow-knight-silksong-release-date-announcement-today-as-special-announcement-is-scheduled-for-thursday">a bigger announcement was announced - that's confusing - for this Thursday</a>. Still: Silksong! What's next - a Bloodborne remake? Half-Life 3?</p>
<p>Not long to go now so let's buckle up and get prepared. Snacks ahoy, let's do this.</p>

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="🔴 gamescom ONL 2025 Official Livestream: Call of Duty, Resident Evil, Fallout  (LIVE NOW!)" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/74oh7zD_jxI?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>🔴 gamescom ONL 2025 Official Livestream: Call of Duty, Resident Evil, Fallout  (LIVE NOW!)</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/74oh7zD_jxI?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/74oh7zD_jxI?autoplay=1" title="🔴 gamescom ONL 2025 Official Livestream: Call of Duty, Resident Evil, Fallout  (LIVE NOW!)">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Watch it right here.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=74oh7zD_jxI" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>



        </div>



  <div data-live="true">
      


  <div data-position="vertical">
          

    <ul data-items="1">
        <li data-hashid="74mj1g">
          <p><time datetime="2025-08-19T17:37:32+00:00" data-auto-relative-date="true">
      <span>17:37 pm</span>
      <span>August 19 2025</span>
  </time>
            <a href="#coverage-74mj1g">The pre-show begins!</a>
          </p>
        </li>
    </ul>
  </div>

      <template id="liveblog-mpu">
  <div class="advert_container mpu_container">
    <div class="mpu lazyload" data-dfp-id="eurogamer_net/mobile_web_display/article" data-dfp-sizes="300x250" data-dfp-targeting="site=eurogamer.net,pos=1,gto=false,position=mpu,gnpos=liveblog" id="lazy_mpu_liveblog" data-dfp-collapse="true" data-dfp-refresh-direct="true" data-prebid-config="MPU_1"></div>
  </div>
      </template>

      <nav>
        
      </nav>


    

      

    
  </div>


  </div>


      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/gamescom-opening-night-live-2025-livestream-and-blog]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tales of Xillia Remastered announced and it launches October 31st]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/08/19/tales-of-xillia-remastered-announced-and-it-launches-october-31st/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/tales-of-xillia-remastered-announced-and-it-launches-october-31st.1273989/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Bandai Namco has officially announced Tales of Xillia Remastered, which is not too much of a surprise as a remaster was leaked a little while ago. This release is only Tales of Xillia Remastered, and there is no mention of a remaster for the follow up Tales of Xillia 2. Tales of Xillia Remastered will be released on October 31st for PC, PS5, Xbox Series XS, and Switch. You can check out the announcement trailer below.</p>
<p><iframe title="Tales of Xillia Remastered - Announcement Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/feXG0jHLpU8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>Tales of Xillia Remastered will have enhanced visuals and quality of life improvements including the option to turn off encounters, auto save, destination markers, early access to the Grade Shop, and all the original DLC including character costumes and bonus items. Tales of Xillia was the first Tales of game that allowed players to pick one of two protagonists to play as and experience the story from different viewpoints. That also meant that to really get the full picture playing through as both Jude and Milla was pretty much necessary.</p>
<h2><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2013/08/06/tales-of-xillia-review-ps3/">Tales Of Xillia Review</a></h2>
<p>In the original Tales of Xillia review from 12 years ago, I wrote, <em>“Tales Of Xillia is a brilliant title, and could just be the breakout game that really establishes the series in Western markets. There’s a great story here, with likable characters and voice acting that makes the characters feel real. The streamlined leveling, equipment choices and skill tree make Xillia one of the best RPGs I’ve played. In fact Tales Of Xillia may just be what the JRPG genre needed.”</em></p>
<p><em>Source: Press Release</em></p>




<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/08/19/tales-of-xillia-remastered-announced-and-it-launches-october-31st/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BioShock 4 Developer Cloud Chamber Will Reportedly Suffer Layoffs, Diablo’s Rod Fergusson Taking Over as Studio Head]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/bioshock-4-cloud-chamber-developer-suffers-layoffs-diablo-rod-fergusson-studio-head/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/bioshock-4-developer-cloud-chamber-will-reportedly-suffer-layoffs-diablo%E2%80%99s-rod-fergusson-taking-over-as-studio-head.1273983/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>According to a report from Bloomberg's Jason Schreier, Cloud Chamber, the studio that's working on the next game in the BioShock series that we currently know as BioShock 4, is laying off some of its staff, and former general manager of the Diablo franchise, <a href="https://wccftech.com/blizzard-has-10-year-plan-for-diablo-iv/">Rod Fergusson</a>, will be taking over as Cloud Chamber's studio head.</p>



<p>Schreier shared the news in a <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/jasonschreier.bsky.social/post/3lwr7jxitg22z">quick post on Bluesky</a>, and also pointed out that Fergusson is seemingly finding himself in a similar position compared to the last time he worked on the BioShock series, since he was brought in at the eleventh hour to help cobble together BioShock Infinite when it was facing development struggles.</p>



<p>This report also follows Schreier's reporting from the <a href="https://wccftech.com/bioshock-4-reportedly-development-hell-failed-review-narrative-overhaul/">beginning of August</a>, when he shared that the game was in development turmoil and had undergone major leadership changes after it failed a milestone check-in with Take-Two.</p>







<p>Fergusson is taking over for Kelley Gilmore, who was removed from her role as studio head and pushed into a position on the publishing side of things earlier this month. It's unclear how much of the team Cloud Chamber is losing, but all these changes, save for Fergusson coming in, don't exactly spell good things to come for BioShock 4's development.</p>



<p>At least Fergusson has the chance to be a bright light for Cloud Chamber. He has a reputation for being able to save projects stuck in development hell, after famously doing it for BioShock Infinite, Gears of War, and Diablo IV. </p>



<p>On <a href="https://x.com/RodFergusson/status/1957824815018213692">X (formerly Twitter)</a>, Fergusson shared the news that he'd be returning to the series as the new head of BioShock at 2K, saying that it's a meaningful moment for him because BioShock is a series that "<em>means a lot</em>" to him, but understands that he's coming in at a difficult time.</p>



<p>"<em>While I’m excited to get started in the coming weeks, I recognize the studio restructuring is a difficult time for the team. I’m deeply grateful for the work done so far, and I’m committed to building a BioShock game we’ll be proud of and that our players will love,</em>" Fergusson wrote.</p>



<figure><div>
<blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>Would you kindly allow me to share some news?</p><p>Some of you guessed it, I’m returning to 2K to lead a series that means a lot to me as the new Head of the BioShock Franchise. I’ll be heading up Cloud Chamber and overseeing development of the next BioShock game, along with…</p></div>— Rod Fergusson (@RodFergusson) <a href="https://twitter.com/RodFergusson/status/1957824815018213692?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 19, 2025</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>



<p>BioShock 4 has been in the works in one way or another <a href="https://wccftech.com/bioshock-4-in-development-since-2015/">since approximately 2015</a>, and with no near end in sight for what's clearly been a marred development period, there's now a bit of hope for the game's future. Right now, it seems like if anyone can fix the issues it is having, Rod Fergusson is the one to do it.</p>



<p>Let's hope he can keep earning his reputation as a 'closer' to troubled projects, with the help of the rest of the remaining team at Cloud Chamber.</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/bioshock-4-cloud-chamber-developer-suffers-layoffs-diablo-rod-fergusson-studio-head/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sony just launched five new PC gaming peripherals, so I tried them all at once]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/hands-on/757680/sony-inzone-pc-gaming-headset-keyboard-mouse-hands-on</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sony-just-launched-five-new-pc-gaming-peripherals-so-i-tried-them-all-at-once.1273980/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Sony is finally ready to take on the likes of SteelSeries, Razer, and Logitech with its InZone brand of PC gaming accessories. While InZone started with monitors and headsets in 2022, with a few new products since then (including its <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/10/10/23911238/sony-inzone-buds-gaming-earbuds-h5-price">great InZone Buds</a> and the sleek but pricey <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/9/24/24253167/sony-inzone-gaming-monitor-m10s-480hz-oled">M10S OLED</a>), Sony is making a concerted effort to take over your desk. It just launched two new headsets, a gaming keyboard, a wireless mouse, and even a couple of mousepads, all developed alongside esports organization <a href="https://fnatic.com/">Fnatic</a>, and all available for preorder today.</p><p>As you might expect, Sony’s not aiming for the bargain bin here. Each of these peripherals is made for competitive play, and they come with high prices that don’t always feel justified.</p><p>To test them all out at once, I swapped out each of my regular PC peripherals for the new InZone gadgets, which made me feel like I was on a Sony Pictures movie set with <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2015/9/14/9321561/new-sony-ad-is-james-bond-product-placement-in-reverse">intense product placement</a>.</p><div><p id="sony-inzone-h9-ii"><h2>Sony InZone H9 II</h2></p></div><p>The InZone H9 II gaming headset is the successor to the <a href="https://youtu.be/VjTh03_ssHo?si=52u4_JuNStjdySvS&amp;t=260">bulkier H9</a> from 2022, with a refined finish, a handful of improvements, and a gen-to-gen price hike from $299.99 to $349.99. The headset is slimmer and lighter (273g versus 330g), and it features a clever “pinch-to-adjust” button on each side of its headband to let you easily find the right fit. The suspended headband design feels lightweight on my head, rivaling the most comfortable models I’ve used, like the <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23132836/steelseries-nova-pro-wireless-review-gaming-bluetooth-anc">SteelSeries Arctis Nova Pro Wireless</a>.</p><p>The new model has the same 30mm speaker drivers as Sony’s latest WH-1000XM6 flagship headphones. Even though they’re 10mm smaller than those in the previous-gen model, they sound just as phenomenal for music as they do for games. You’re also getting fantastic active noise cancellation, with the option to turn on a transparency mode that, notably, doesn’t affect the audio quality. You can customize the H9 II’s more granular settings within the company’s InZone Hub on PC or via Bluetooth in Sony’s Sound Connect mobile app — the same one used for several of its consumer headphone models.</p><p>This headset has several features every wireless model should have. The ear cups are on swiveling hinges, giving you the option to let them rest on your chest between matches, or if you need to remove them to talk in person. You can now listen to audio via a 3.5mm cable, even when the headset is out of battery. Wired mode will override any wireless connections. If you’d prefer to go wireless, it can maintain simultaneous connections over Bluetooth and its compact 2.4GHz USB-C transmitter, which has a toggle for PC and “other” platforms.</p><p>The headset works just fine with the PS5 and Switch 2, letting me listen to podcasts from my phone as I play. This model adds Bluetooth LE Audio support, allowing them to last longer per charge with better sound — love that, especially since I’m likely to keep them paired to two devices. Another new feature for this generation is a feature that several other headsets have: a removable boom microphone, in case you’d rather use a desktop mic or if you’re heading outdoors.</p><div><p id="sony-inzone-e9"><h2>Sony InZone E9</h2></p></div><p>The $149.99 InZone E9 wired in-ear monitors are small and lightweight, with good noise isolation. They’re simple to use, either connecting via 3.5mm jack or its included 3.5mm-to-USB-C dongle, which is required to personalize the audio in the InZone Hub app. Unlike normal earbuds, these and all other in-ear monitors have hooks that route the cables on top of your ear cartilage and down the back of your ears, so as to stay out of your face. It all ships in a nice case that springs open when unzipped, exposing several ear tip size options.</p><p>The E9 in-ear monitors are tuned for FPS games out of the box. The default equalizer setting gives a flat, reference-style sound that pursues accuracy over bombast — the better to locate footsteps and gunshots in game. It’s effective, but outside of gaming, I found the E9s boring to listen to compared to the full-bodied, warm sound of the <a rel="sponsored" href="https://www.amazon.com/Linsoul-Earphones-Faceplate-Detachable-Audiophile/dp/B07WTTJSCF?th=1&amp;tag=theverge02-20">Linsoul KZ ZSX</a> in-ear monitors that I bought on Amazon for about $60. That Linsoul model is the best-sounding set of headphones that I own — with detachable cables, no less — and I never expected to pay so little for something so good. Perhaps you’ll be as inspired as I was by our <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/7/20943377/chinese-hi-fi-audio-chifi-fiio-hifiman-tin-audio">2019 piece</a> on great Chinese hi-fi to find other options that are significantly cheaper, yet better-sounding than Sony’s new IEMs, at least for non-gaming needs.</p><p>Sony is one of the only major companies making gaming in-ear monitors, along with Razer, which makes the <a href="https://razer.a9yw.net/c/482924/642901/10229?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.razer.com%2Fstreaming-earphones%2Frazer-moray%2FRZ12-04450100-R3U1" rel="sponsored">Moray</a> (those have detachable cables and are $20 cheaper) but I hope it aims higher, and future models sound better than the cheaper competition.</p><div><p id="sony-inzone-keyboard"><h2>Sony InZone keyboard</h2></p></div><p>To type all of this, I’ve been using Sony’s InZone KBD-H75, a name so clunky that I’m just going to refer to it as the InZone keyboard. This wired milled-aluminum board took the place of my <a href="https://www.amazon.com/KINESIS-Gaming-Freestyle-Mechanical-Keyboard/dp/B07SXX7P6D?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored">split ergo gaming keyboard made by Kinesis Gaming</a>, which I use to manage wrist strain during and after work. So, this wasn’t a swap that I was exactly looking forward to for ergonomic reasons. However — forgetting my wrists for a moment — it feels nice to type on, once I got used to the 75 percent layout that omits several navigation keys I commonly use.</p><p>The KBD-H75 uses Hall effect magnetic switches that actuate faster and more accurately than mechanical switches. I’m accustomed to clicky Cherry MX Blue switches, and I found the InZone keyboard doesn’t have quite enough resistance for my taste. In fact, they’re so easy to press that I kept accidentally actuating keys in chat apps, making it look like I fell asleep at my desk. This can be rectified by customizing the actuation point of each key, between 0.1mm and 3.4mm. It’s a feature that’s common among its competitors. And thankfully, you won’t need to install the InZone Hub app to make adjustments; Sony took a page from other keyboard makers by building a web version of its app that can be accessed from any PC this keyboard is plugged into — perfect for tournaments or LAN tournaments.</p><p>Thanks to the milled-aluminum case and gasket-mounted switchplate, I couldn’t sense vibrations as I pounded out articles and messages. Tapping each key results in a quiet yet satisfying sound, and I know my partner wishes my split ergo was this quiet. But, again, I prefer switches that have a little bit more resistance. I’m sure if I were a professional gamer, I’d be happier with these.</p><p>Ask most people who are into keyboards and they’ll probably tell you a handful of alternatives with similar features to the InZone keyboard that cost less than the $299.99 Sony’s asking for. At this price, most gamers expect wireless support and hot-swappable switches. The <a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=1025X1701640&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.keychron.com%2Fproducts%2Flemokey-p1-he-wireless-magnetic-switch-custom-gaming-keyboard" rel="sponsored">$169.99 LemoKey P1 HE</a> has hot-swappable Hall effect switches, plus 1000Hz polling over 2.4GHz wireless. Unless Sony’s design and its promise of 8,000Hz polling rate are really doing it for you, there are many good options out there that cost less.</p><p>I’m dubious of this keyboard’s 8,000Hz polling rate, which is one of its selling points (as well as one of the mouse below). Instead of being limited to 1,000Hz, which means it can register your input once per millisecond, 8,000Hz increases the rate to register movement and clicks once every 0.125ms. Sony’s definitely not the first company to advertise 8,000Hz polling in a gaming peripheral, but its utility is just as questionable here as it is in other products. As it turns out, human reaction time is pretty slow, so, maybe you shouldn’t pay more for this feature.</p><p>I’ve been radicalized by <a href="https://youtu.be/MfgrnFzsuCs?si=GJRuWT6T7w0Y08zA&amp;t=145">Rocket Jump Ninja’s video</a> on YouTube, which demonstrates that 1,000Hz is more than enough speed for most people; in the video, it shows that even fast human reaction times are still over 150ms, or approximately 6.67Hz. So, unless you have superhuman reflexes, this feature just isn’t necessary. Plus, trawling through <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/MouseReview/comments/1fsyhws/how_much_impact_does_8k_polling_rate_really_have/">Reddit</a> shows that some gamers have had issues with an 8,000Hz polling rate affecting game performance.</p><div><p id="sony-inzone-mouse-a"><h2>Sony InZone Mouse-A</h2></p></div><p>Lastly, there’s the InZone Mouse-A — Sony’s first wireless gaming mouse. It costs $149.99, and at 48 grams, it’s the lightest mouse that I’ve ever used. This right-handed mouse is light on flourishes and excess buttons, with just a left and right click, two thumb buttons, the scroll wheel, and a profile-switching button on the bottom. As someone who typically uses the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Glorious-Model-Ergonomic-Matte-Gaming/dp/B0B63Z6PYV?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored">Glorious Model I</a>, I quickly warmed up to its soft, matte-textured arch, though I wish it had a thumb rest. It feels pretty similar to the <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/9/5/23043644/logitech-g-pro-x-superlight-2-gaming-mouse-price-release-date-specs">Logitech G Pro X Superlight</a> in terms of ergonomics. I have an average-sized hand, though small-handed gamers will also likely find this to be a comfortable pick. The click is swift and relatively quiet, and it has optical switches (as many gaming mice do at this point), letting inputs register faster than they would with mechanical switches.</p><p>To complement its new mouse, Sony has launched two cloth mousepads, both of which are 18.89 x 15.7 inches in size. The Mat-F is thicker at 6mm (versus 4mm), with a surface that’s meant to create some drag to prevent the mouse from moving any more than you want it to. It’s designed for tactical first-person shooters that don’t emphasize twitchy movement. It costs $59.99. The $34.99 Mat-D, is for those who want speed, and the ability to make quick flicks of the mouse to pull off headshots and other commands. I don’t typically use any kind of mousepad, just a mat that my keyboard, mouse, and drink sit on. Sony only sent the Mat-D for me to test, and while it’s step up from my desk mat, I think it’d prefer the Mat-F for its higher friction.</p><p>Of all of Sony’s InZone gear, the product that I’ll miss the most is the H9 II headset. Despite its $349.99 price, you’re getting great audio quality for the money. And, thanks to its removable mic, using it as a set of headphones away from your desk won’t make you look as ridiculous as the first-gen model does. Each of the new products has redeeming qualities, but a lack of novelty and high prices across the board make them tough to broadly recommend.</p><p>Sony is a household name, but not so much in esports. It’s going up against companies that have been making similar products — often with lower prices — and have years of goodwill attached to their names. But I suppose every company has to start somewhere. High prices aside, this isn’t a bad place to begin.</p><div><p><span><strong>Follow topics and authors</strong> from this story to see more like this in your personalized homepage feed and to receive email updates.</span></p><ul><li id="follow-author-article_footer-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTU2Ng=="><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span><span>Cameron Faulkner</span></span></span></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li></ul></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/hands-on/757680/sony-inzone-pc-gaming-headset-keyboard-mouse-hands-on]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Game Of Thrones Fan Tells George R.R. Martin He’ll Be Dead Soon During Recent Q&A]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/game-of-thrones-the-winds-of-winter-rude-fan-2000618451</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/game-of-thrones-fan-tells-george-r-r-martin-he%E2%80%99ll-be-dead-soon-during-recent-q-a.1273974/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
                              <figure id="attachment_featured" aria-describedby="featured-caption">
                                                                          <figcaption id="featured-caption">
                    <span>Samwell Tarly looks asconce at Jon Snow.</span> © HBO / Kotaku
                  </figcaption>
                </figure>
                                                      </p><div>
              
              
              <p><em>Game of Thrones</em> author George R.R. Martin recently appeared on a panel at Seattle WorldCon 2025 entitled The Shifting Landscape of Epic Fantasy, alongside Brandon Sanderson, Robin Hobb, Rebecca Roanhorse and Ryan Cahill. However, during the question-and-answer portion at the end of the session, one member of the audience got up in front of the all-star panel to complain that George R.R. Martin was taking far too long to write the penultimate book in the <em>A Song of Ice and Fire</em> series, <em>The Winds of Winter</em>, and given that he likely doesn’t have that long left to live, shouldn’t he let someone else write it?</p> <p>The outstandingly rude question was met with an astonished murmur in the hall, while the guests on stage looked incredibly uncomfortable and attempted to move the topic on. However, the audience member seemed not to be able to pick up on the mood they’d created, and just continued digging their hole with a series of staccato additional words. You can see the squirm-inducing moment here (thanks&nbsp;<em>ScreenRant</em>):</p> <p><iframe loading="lazy" title="GEORGE RR MARTIN WORLDCON PANEL 2025 FULL " width="500" height="281" src="about:blank" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen="" data-rocket-lazyload="fitvidscompatible" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rCiQWbjPtYI?start=7762&amp;feature=oembed"></iframe></p> <p>Which somehow means someone choosing to film a two-hour panel in portrait wasn’t close to the most offensive thing that happened.</p>

 <p>The bizarre, rambling question, which begins with the audience member talking somewhat incoherently about Martin Scorsese directing her in a movie, then takes a dramatic left-turn as she declares, “George, you’re not going to be around for much longer.”</p> <p>Martin, who is 76 and clearly still reasonably healthy, didn’t appear to react to the premonition of his death (although the person filming infuriatingly avoided filming him at any point). “This is a tough question,” the person at the mic continues while the audience begins audibly booing and vocally disagreeing, attempting to rescue herself by adding, “this is more directed at Brandon…” The reason being that Brandon Sanderson, a spritely 49, took over writing Robert Jordan’s unfinished <em>The Wheel of Time</em> epic fantasy series after the author died, aged only 58. The questioner wondered if the same could be arranged for <em>A Song of Ice and Fire</em>. “How would you feel about someone else taking over and finishing the books?” she said, seemingly now addressing Martin again, despite various members of the panel loudly saying, “No, no,” and getting up from their seats.</p> <p>“Not me,” you can hear Sanderson say, while Martin gets up from his seat. Even then, the person at the mic keeps going, responding to inaudible comments from the panel, in a room that surely could no longer contain any air at all.</p>

 <p>Obviously a lot of&nbsp;<em>GoT</em> fans are frustrated by <em>The Winds of Winter</em>‘s prolonged absence, given the book was due out 14 years ago. Given the series is <em>two</em> books away from being finished, and given Martin’s current output, it’s reasonable to wonder if any human would live long enough to get it finished at the current rate. Assuming another 14 years, Martin would be 90. However, there are obviously more human and decent ways to approach the subject.</p> <p><a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/movies/movie-features/george-r-r-martin-howard-waldrop-ugly-chickens-game-of-thrones-1236078329/">Martin said of the delay last year</a>, “How could I be 13 years late? I don’t know, it happens a day at a time.” He then added, “A lot of people are already writing obituaries for me. ‘Oh, he’ll never be finished.’ Maybe they’re right. I don’t know. I’m alive right now! I seem pretty vital!”</p> <p>And who knows! Maybe he’ll surprise everyone and release his version of the story’s conclusion all of a sudden (the <em>Game of Thrones </em>TV series had to write its own ending, given it unexpectedly ran out of source material). In the meantime, maybe don’t yell at the old dude on stage that you reckon he’ll die soon.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/game-of-thrones-the-winds-of-winter-rude-fan-2000618451]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 Beta Date Revealed]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-beta-date-revealed/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-beta-date-revealed.1273971/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-140295">

    <header>
        

        

    </header>

    


    <div>
        
<p>Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 is getting a pre-launch beta. Made public early by the <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-us/games/store/call-of-duty-black-ops-7/9plbm5790l94" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Xbox Store listing</a>, it’s been revealed that the Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 beta will begin on October 2 for those with early access.</p>



<p>The beta will open for everyone else on October 5.</p>



<p>In order to get early access to the beta, players must pre-order any digital edition of the game or be subscribed to Game Pass Ultimate, Game Pass PC, or Game Pass Console. The beta will let players get their first hands-on experience with the game on a wide scale, and will let people get a taste of some of the new multiplayer maps and features coming to the game. </p>



<p>Speaking of maps, it’s also been confirmed that there will be 16 6v6 maps and two 20v20 maps for Black Ops 6 at launch.</p>



<p>In addition to access to the beta, those who do pre-order the game will get the Reznov Challenge Pack that includes: Immediate acess to the SOG Reznov Operator Skin in Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 and Call of Duty: Warzone™ as well as access to the Stalingrad Reznov and Memory Reznov Operator Skins.</p>



<p>As of publishing, there’s been no confirmation regarding how long the beta will last. Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 is <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-releases-november-14/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">scheduled to launch</a> on November 14.</p>



<p>Are you excited about the Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 beta? Let us know down below, and take the discussion further in the official&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums.</a></p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, check out the official&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/kirby-air-riders-release-date-announced" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">release date for Kirby Air Riders</a>. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/sony-announces-new-inzone-product-lineup/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/sony-announces-new-inzone-product-lineup/">
                                Sony Announces New Inzone Product Lineup                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Sony has announced its latest lineup of Inzone gaming products, including a new keyboard, mouse, headset, and more!</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/rod-fergusson-joins-2k-to-lead-bioshock-franchise/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/rod-fergusson-joins-2k-to-lead-bioshock-franchise/">
                                Rod Fergusson Joins 2K To Lead BioShock Franchise                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Rod Fergusson has announced that he is joining 2K and Cloud Chamber as the new head of the BioShock franchise at the studio.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/gamescom-opening-night-live-2025-everything-announced/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/gamescom-opening-night-live-2025-everything-announced/">
                                Gamescom Opening Night Live 2025: Everything Announced                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Gamescom Opening Night Live took place in Cologne, and we’ve got all the details on everything announced during the showcase.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nhl-26-be-a-pro-features-announced/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nhl-26-be-a-pro-features-announced/">
                                NHL 26 Be A Pro Features Announced                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>EA Sports has released its deep dive on the NHL 26 Be A Pro mode coming along with all of the new features players can expect.</p>
                    </div>

                                                    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-beta-date-revealed/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Starbreeze says PUBG collab was its 'single largest revenue contributor' in Q2]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/starbreeze-says-pubg-collab-was-its-single-largest-revenue-contributor-in-q2</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/starbreeze-says-pubg-collab-was-its-single-largest-revenue-contributor-in-q2.1273965/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-testid="article-base-contributors"><div data-component="contributors"><p><a data-testid="contributor-name" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/author/diego-arguello" data-discover="true">Diego Argüello</a><span data-testid="contributor-title">, <!-- -->Contributing Editor, News</span><span data-testid="contributor-title">, <!-- -->GameDeveloper.com</span></p><p data-testid="contributors-date">August 19, 2025</p></div><p><span data-component="icon" data-name="Clock"></span><span>3 Min<!-- --> <!-- -->Read</span></p></div><div data-component="captioned-content" data-testid="featured-image"><p><span>Image via Starbreeze Studios</span></p></div><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Payday 3</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> developer Starbreeze Studios said that its </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>PUBG</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> collaboration project has been the "single largest revenue contributor" this last quarter.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">In the company's </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://corporate.starbreeze.com/en/press/press-releases/starbreeze-interim-report-january-june-2025/">interim report</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> for the period of January to June 2025, Starbreeze emphasized that leveraging the "full potential of the Payday IP" continues to be a "key strategic priority" for the studio.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Our </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>PUBG</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> project continues to perform ahead of expectations and stands as a testament to the strength of our internal development capabilities," Starbreeze CEO Adolf Kristjansson said in the financial report. "During the quarter, it was our single largest revenue contributor, demonstrating both commercial viability and production excellence."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">This is in reference to </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.starbreeze.com/news/starbreeze-partners-with-krafton-to-expand-payday-into-pubg-battlegrounds/">the partnership</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> between Starbreeze and Krafton announced back in December 2024. In short, while Starbreeze retains full ownership of the Payday intellectual property, Krafton acquired the rights to incorporate and adapt it within </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>PUBG</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"The partnership reflects Starbreeze’s strategy to maximize the potential of the Payday IP and having a broader portfolio of projects under development," read the announcement at the time.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">As detailed by Starbreeze, it seems this collaboration is paying off. In the second quarter of 2025, work-for-hire, which is how the studio referred to the collaboration back in December, accounted for SEK 19.6 million (around $2 million) of net sales. The total of SEK 53.8 million (around $5.6 million) also comprised SEK 8 million (around $834,435) from </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Payday 2</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, SEK 17.7 million (around $1.8 million) from </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Payday 3</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, and SEK 6.7 million (around $698,864) from third-party publishing.</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/gamescom-exec-surprised-latam-event-was-criticized-by-local-developers" target="_self" data-discover="true">Gamescom exec 'surprised' Latam event was criticized by local developers</a></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Starbreeze says recent strategic focus and organizational changes have 'started bearing fruit'">Starbreeze says recent strategic focus and organizational changes have 'started bearing fruit'</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Starbreeze has been steadily shaking things up internally this year. Last week, the company appointed </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/starbreeze-appoints-ea-veteran-jonas-skantz-as-general-manager-of-payday">EA veteran Jonas Skantz</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> as general manager of the Payday Franchise. This was the second managerial change of 2025, with </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/starbreeze-appoints-ea-veteran-jonas-skantz-as-general-manager-of-payday">fellow EA veteran Adolf Kristjansson</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> being appointed as the new CEO with the goal of turning the company into a "true multi-title studio."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">These changes came after Starbreeze explained </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Payday 3</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> was performing at "</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/starbreeze-admits-payday-3-is-massively-underperforming">significantly lower levels</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">" than it would have liked by February 2024. As noted in Starbreeze's </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/starbreeze-projects-positivity-as-payday-3-sales-tumble-into-the-abyss">fiscal report for the full-year ended December 2024</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, the company delivered annual net sales of SEK 185.9 million (around $17.3 million), compared to SEK 633.5 million ($58.1 million) recorded in FY2023.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Now, Kristjansson is optimistic about the future of the franchise. "Our strategic focus on the Payday franchise, proactive organizational changes, and emphasis on sustainable growth have started bearing fruit, guiding us on our path towards becoming an agile, profitable, and a proven leader in building and sustaining world-class IP," he said in the report.</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/roblox-corp-responds-to-louisiana-lawsuit-that-claims-it-built-the-perfect-place-for-pedophiles-" target="_self" data-discover="true">Roblox Corp responds to Louisiana lawsuit that claims it built 'the perfect place for pedophiles'</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">According to Starbreeze, the focused approach on "enhancing player experience in </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Payday 3</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">" continues to show "incremental improvements" in player numbers and community sentiment, which the CEO considers "vital indicators for long-term franchise growth."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Regarding the recent organizational changes, Kristjansson said Q2 marked significant steps towards simplifying Starbreeze's organizational structure, enhancing transparency, and empowering faster decision-making. Core studio functions now report directly to the CEO, and the studio has established three dedicated teams running Payday, its work-for-hire projects, and Baxter, the latter being Starbreeze's next internal project set in the world of </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Dungeons and Dragons</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">. "These are now fully accountable for their respective financial performance, fostering a culture of ownership, agility, and creativity throughout the organization," Kristjansson said.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Our refined organizational structure, clear strategic priorities, and commitment to delivering engaging gaming experiences position us strongly for sustainable success," the CEO added. "I remain confident in our direction and deeply appreciative of the team's relentless passion, creativity, and determination."</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/-it-is-not-our-aim-to-grow-grow-grow-gamescom-2025-touts-record-exhibitors-but-organizers-says-quality-is-better-than-quantity" target="_self" data-discover="true">'It is not our aim to grow, grow, grow:' Gamescom touts record exhibitors but organizers says quality is better than quantity</a></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Contributing Editor, News, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Diego Nicolás Argüello is a freelance journalist and critic from Argentina. Video games helped him to learn English, so now he covers them for places like The New York Times, NPR, Rolling Stone, and more. He also runs Into the Spine, a site dedicated to fostering and supporting new writers, and co-hosted Turnabout Breakdown, a podcast about the Ace Attorney series. He’s most likely playing a rhythm game as you read this.</span></p></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/starbreeze-says-pubg-collab-was-its-single-largest-revenue-contributor-in-q2]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BioShock 4 studio reportedly facing layoffs as former Diablo boss takes over amid "development turmoil"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/bioshock-4-studio-reportedly-facing-layoffs-as-former-diablo-boss-takes-over-amid-development-turmoil</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/bioshock-4-studio-reportedly-facing-layoffs-as-former-diablo-boss-takes-over-amid-development-turmoil.1273962/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>Project recently 'failed internal review'.</p>

    </div>


  

    

</header>
    <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
<a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/bioshock">BioShock</a> 4 developer Cloud Chamber is reportedly laying off an "unspecified" number of employees. The news comes as former Diablo boss Rod Fergusson joins as new studio head following claims of development "turmoil".
</p>
<p>
Word that BioShock 4's development had running into difficulties first emerged earlier this month when Bloomberg's Jason Schreier reported the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/bioshock-4-fails-to-impress-at-internal-2k-review-resulting-in-leadership-shake-up-and-revamped-narrartive">project had failed an internal review at publisher 2K Games</a>, with particular criticism being levied at its narrative. Soon after, studio head Kelley Gilmore was ousted and staff were warned the team needed to "become more agile and efficient", leading to concerns layoffs were imminent. And now Schreier <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/jasonschreier.bsky.social/post/3lwr7jxitg22z">reports</a> job cuts affecting an "unspecified number of staff" at Cloud Chamber have begun. Eurogamer has contacted 2K Games for comment.
</p>
<p>
Amid all this, former Diablo boss Rod Fergusson has now been revealed as Cloud Chamber's new studio head. Fergusson most recently served as general manager of the Diablo franchise at Blizzard, having joined the company in February 2020, but was <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/diablo-boss-rod-fergusson-leaves-blizzard">confirmed to be "stepping away" from his position</a> earlier this month. Notably, Fergusson <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/rod-fergusson-the-closer-who-helped-get-bioshock-infinite-out-the-door-is-leaving-irrational">played a key role in the release of the third BioShock title</a>, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/bioshock-infinite">BioShock Infinite</a>, joining Irrational Games to help the project over the finish line after its own difficult development.
</p>
<p>
Confirming his new role at Cloud Chamber <a href="https://x.com/RodFergusson/status/1957824815018213692">on social media</a>, Fergusson wrote, "Some of you guessed it, I'm returning to 2K to lead a series that means a lot to me as the new Head of the BioShock Franchise. I'll be heading up Cloud Chamber and overseeing development of the next BioShock game, along with franchise extensions like the in-development Netflix movie.
</p><p>
"While I'm excited to get started in the coming weeks, I recognise the studio restructuring is a difficult time for the team. I'm deeply grateful for the work done so far, and I'm committed to building a BioShock game we'll be proud of and that our players will love."
</p>
<p>
BioShock 4 was confirmed to be in development in 2019, with its release <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/bioshock-in-development-at-new-2k-studio-cloud-chamber">said to be "several" years away</a> at the time. 2K Games has, however, been attempting to get a sequel off the ground for over a decade - back in 2014, the publisher <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/zelnick-2k-marin-now-responsible-for-bioshock-franchise">announced its now-defunct 2K Marin studio would be responsible for the future of BioShock</a> after <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/ken-levine-steps-away-from-bioshock-to-create-something-new">series creator Ken Levine departed Irrational Games</a> to <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/bioshock-creator-ken-levine-reveals-new-studio-ghost-story">found Ghost Story Games</a>. Little has been heard of the project since its shift to Cloud Chamber, but in 2021 it was reported BioShock 4 would <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/next-bioshocks-setting-and-time-period-detailed-in-new-report">take place in a fictional Antarctic city set sometime during the 1960s</a>, roughly concurrent with the events of BioShock 1 and 2.
</p>
<p>
As for Levine and Ghost Story Games, the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/ken-levines-new-game-looks-like-bioshock-in-space">studio's next project, Judas</a>, is still without a release date - but it seems likely the BioShock-style shooter will emerge well before 2K's next official BioShock game.
</p>

        </div>


      </article>



  
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/bioshock-4-studio-reportedly-facing-layoffs-as-former-diablo-boss-takes-over-amid-development-turmoil]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘It’s Just Not Impressive If A Robot Is Doing It:’ Soundalike Voice Actors On AI]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/ai-voice-acting-soundalike-video-games</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/%E2%80%98it%E2%80%99s-just-not-impressive-if-a-robot-is-doing-it-%E2%80%99-soundalike-voice-actors-on-ai.1273959/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>In June, SAG-AFTRA video game voice actors ended a nearly <a href="https://aftermath.site/sag-aftra-video-game-voice-actor-strike" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">year-long strike</a> when they <a href="https://aftermath.site/sag-aftra-video-game-deal" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">reached an agreement</a> with a handful of major companies. While the new agreement offers considerable AI <a href="https://variety.com/2025/gaming/news/video-game-actors-strike-contract-ratified-sag-aftra-1236451291/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">protections</a>, soundalike voice actors have been and continue to be particularly impacted by AI and its growing influence on the industry.</p><h2>Voice match acting before the dawn of AI</h2><p>Soundalike, or voice match, actors are performers whose job is to imitate the speech pattern of a famous actor or celebrity. These actors can be used for many reasons. One well-known example is when Square Enix and Disney couldn’t secure Tom Hanks to reprise his role as Woody in <em>Kingdom Hearts 3</em>, and so cast his brother, Jim, to step in to voice Woody in his stead.</p><div><figure><p><iframe title="hollup…Let him cook (Woody - Kingdom Hearts 3)" width="710" height="399" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZG1W2xwp2s4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></figure></div><p>BAFTA-winning voice actor <a href="https://www.imdb.com/name/nm4047315/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Cissy Jones</a> has done her fair share of voice match acting, as well as being a renowned voice talent in her own right. She describes honing the craft as something similar to a musician tuning an instrument to match the cadence and tones of celebrity actors.&nbsp;</p><p>“It’s a lot like hearing musicality. I used to do a ton of voice matching. I did Charlize Theron, Rebel Wilson, Penelope Cruz, and Emma Thompson… [E]ssentially, it is hearing the musicality in a speaker’s voice,” Jones told Aftermath. “What I like to do when I get a script is, usually there’s an MP3 file that comes along with it [that] they want you to match and see if the timbre and the cadence are correct. I will often shut my eyes and listen to the file multiple times, play and repeat the music of it. That gets me right in the spot.”</p><p>When an actor excels at impersonating celebrities—like <a href="https://www.imdb.com/name/nm1082823/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Eric Bauza</a>’s uncanny voice match of Antonio Banderas in <em>Puss in Boots</em>—they often become a go-to substitute, much like a reliable understudy in a theater troupe. These voice match actors are called upon whenever the original star isn’t available, whether due to scheduling conflicts or budgetary constraints.&nbsp;</p><p>"If you look at <em>Kung Fu Panda</em>, they can’t afford to have Jack Black come in and do Po for the entire series, so <a href="https://www.imdb.com/name/nm1964186/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Mick Wingert</a> does it, and he’s amazing. He sounds exactly like [Black], and he makes scale,” Jones said. “[Companies] used to do it where they would swap out curse words for non-curse words, but they would have a [voice match] actor come in to do it. For games and animation, doing soundalike is definitely more cost-effective.”</p><p>Voice match actors’ work is especially valuable during the production of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scratch_vocal" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">scratch lines</a>—temporary audio placeholders used in trailers or early film edits. Producers may also rely on them in post-production to record additional dialogue or <a href="https://www.backstage.com/magazine/article/adr-film-explained-examples-75425/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">ADR</a> (automated dialogue replacement) that the original actor can’t return for. In some cases, voice match actors are tasked with resurrecting the vocal essence of a bygone performer, preserving their signature twang or cadence for nostalgia and continuity. Audiobooks often require narrators who can channel a specific vocal style. For example, Jones narrated the audiobook of<em> The Nightmare Before Christmas</em> in the breathy, high-registered, Mid-Atlantic accent of Catherine O’Hara.</p><p>“[Producers] would have voice actors come in and do a voice match for Charlize Theron to say, ‘We gotta get out of here,’ or whatever. They would have us come in and do things for the trailer so that it could go to air without having to pay her rates to come in. They paid me scale, but it was a good living,” Jones said.&nbsp;</p><p>Scale is the minimum wage for an actor. Once they join a union like SAG-AFTRA, a union job will guarantee a performer's base pay—which is the scale—for that contract, plus pension, health, and an agent commission scale. Jones says celebrities often receive multiple times the scale, where only a rare few prominent voice actors can demand double without it being a big deal; otherwise, most voice actors work at the standard scale. Depending on the contract, Jones says video games typically pay $950 for a four-hour session, plus pension, health benefits, and an agent's commission. Animation, which is also offered on a four-hour session basis, can pay an actor $1,100 per session. Other work, like commercials, which offer the highest payouts, is a completely different ballgame in terms of rates and residuals for rebroadcast.&nbsp;</p><figure><blockquote><p>It is crickets out there.</p><cite>Cissy Jones</cite></blockquote></figure><blockquote><span><blockquote></blockquote></span></blockquote><p>Voice matching isn’t just a subgenre of voice acting for up-and-comers. It includes prominent voice actors, such as Jennifer Hale of <em>Mass Effect</em> fame. When I reached out to Hale to discuss the work, she was actually on her way to a voice recording for soundalike work. While she couldn’t disclose for who or what her soundalike role pertained to, she reaffirmed that her soundalike sessions are about the human connection between the producer, the performer, and the role.&nbsp;</p><p>“They’re pulling me in. They’re not using AI, and it's because they truly value that beautiful human spark, which is what uplifts anything,” Hale said.&nbsp;</p><h2>How AI has impacted voice acting</h2><p>Before AI entered the scene, voice match actors I spoke to said they were already starting to see fewer opportunities. The general feeling was that unless they were doing the voice match for a celebrity in a video game, they weren’t getting much work. The main source of income for voice match actors has traditionally been commercial work, such as movie trailers, but even that is decreasing.</p><p>“For trailers, I used to get 10 to 15 voice match movie trailer auditions a week. Now, I might get three in a year. It’s died considerably—at least from my point of view,” Jones said. “Granted, I also used to work with a manager who had a lot more access to movie trailer companies and would get very specialized auditions. But even before I let that manager go, I really wasn’t seeing those kinds of auditions coming through anymore. It is crickets out there.”</p><p><a href="https://www.imdb.com/name/nm3084185/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Carin Gilfry</a>, who has done voice matching for celebrities like Kate McKinnon, Scarlett Johansson, and Brie Larson, feels that much of the reason voice acting as a profession has declined is due to reckless, unregulated use of AI. One way this is manifesting that several voice actors I spoke with brought up is how many synthetic voice websites claim to have been approved with consent, but<a href="https://kotaku.com/ai-voice-actors-steve-blum-elevenlabs-contracts-sell-1850108292" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> often aren’t</a>. For a quick buck—money actors will never see—fans can pay for soundbites of actors in character saying funny, off-color things for internet memes. Hale warns that <a href="https://gizmodo.com/ai-fears-and-short-sighted-execs-voice-acting-legend-jennifer-hale-lays-out-the-stakes-of-the-video-game-voice-actor-strike-2000501935" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sharing reposts of AI-generated content </a>helps spread unauthorized AI voice videos of their favorite actors.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><figure><blockquote><p>When that opportunity is given to a robot instead of a human, that human doesn't have the chance to make those connections.</p><cite>Carin Gilfry</cite></blockquote></figure><p>What’s more troubling about the rise of AI is how it can restrict new voice actors from breaking into the industry. Gilfry and voice actor <a href="https://www.imdb.com/name/nm12048923/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Michael Scott</a> told me beginning voice actors can no longer depend on voice matching as a way to get into the industry or land union jobs. Furthermore, situations like when Epic Games used a generative AI model to digitally recreate James Earl Jones’ voice (<a href="https://gizmodo.com/fortnite-darth-vader-ai-epic-games-star-wars-james-earl-jones-2000603304" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">who signed away his likeness to Lucasfilm before he died</a>) for their<em> </em><a href="https://aftermath.site/fortnite-ai-darth-vader-star-wars-epic-games-sag-aftra" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Star Wars</em> Darth Vader event</a> feel like a chilling effect legitimizing AI voice models over voice match actors. In the past, Jones said a company might have hired a voice match actor to mimic James Earl Jones. To Gilfry and Scott, AI voice technology has cut off a route for actors who, through their hard work and growing reputation as reliable voice matchers, would have moved forward—all because a c-suite executive saw using an AI prompt to replicate a celebrity’s voice as cheaper than finding someone with the talent to match a performer.&nbsp;</p><p>Most people today get into voice acting not through SAG-AFTRA union jobs, but through online casting sites such as <a href="https://voice123.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Voice123</a>, <a href="http://voices.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Voices.com</a>, or <a href="https://www.fiverr.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Fiverr.</a> Unfortunately, AI has taken over many of these seemingly entry-level roles, such as creating training videos, local commercials, or phone system recordings. When companies use more robotic AI to record full commercials, it takes away what could have been an entry-level job for a budding actor, especially since some companies claim that humanistic acting isn’t necessary.</p><p>“What I've seen every single one of my sessions for the past two months, [producers] say, Hey, so here's a scratch track. Here is the audio that we have that we want you to match, or we put it into the video so we can see what it sounds like with voice over—every single one of the sessions that I've been in so far has used an AI scratch track. Every single one,” Gilfry said. “That did not used to be the case before two months ago. I've kept track of the past two months. Every single one's an AI scratch track.”&nbsp;</p><p>Scratch voice-over is a gateway for many voice actors to break into the industry, serving as an entry-level opportunity for actors to gain work. It's how actors like Scott, who's done voice match for actors like Kid Cudi, broke into the industry.&nbsp;</p><p>“Kid Cudi is in the show <em>Young Love</em> [and] I voice-matched him, literally reading the whole script as scratch, and the producers fell in love with me and gave me a role,” Scott told Aftermath. “Before I knew it, I was 10 characters in the show, like a series regular, because that scratch was the pathway to get into that ongoing work. I wouldn't have had that opportunity with AI as a barrier.”</p><p>One of the most well-known examples of a scratch track leading to an actor securing a major role is when Disney was so impressed with<em> </em><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dSnrEve212M" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Coco</em> actor Anthony Gonzalez’s scratch performance as Miguel</a> that he was cast in the film.&nbsp;</p><div><figure><p><iframe title="Making of: Disney's COCO | The Voice of Miguel Rivera (Anthony Gonzalez)" width="710" height="399" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/dSnrEve212M?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></figure></div><p>“You form a relationship with the production team, with the directors, with everyone who's working on the project, and they start to know you,” Gilfry said. “When that opportunity is given to a robot instead of a human, that human doesn't have the chance to make those connections.”</p><p>Now, Gilfry says human scratch tracks are no longer used as much as AI because AI is cheaper and quicker, and producers no longer need to go through traditional casting. Instead, they are asking people to imitate an AI’s scratch performance.</p><p>“The production team starts to fall in love with the sound of the scratch. Then you, an actor, are being asked to mimic the timing and delivery of the AI voice—to bring your humanness to it, because they don't want the AI on the final product. But they want you to match what's there,” Gilfry said. “It's really a weird time.”</p><h2>How voice actors are trying to deal with AI as ethically as they can</h2><p>Unlike NFTs' fleeting life cycle that quickly shifted from a buzzword-worthy trend to an ethered tech bro venture, AI's influence on the creative industry is complex. It cannot be simply put back in the proverbial toothpaste tube. For actors, solutions aren’t as all-or-nothing as some online have made them out to be. One such solution is for actors to find ethical ways to utilize AI in a manner that ensures they have consent, control, and compensation for their voices being replicated.&nbsp;</p><p>Before the strike began, Jones said she often encountered platforms where producers praised the ease of using AI programs and the fact that they didn't have to call actors in for pickups — a sentiment she finds “incredibly violating.” To avoid that uncomfortable feeling, she co-founded <a href="https://ethovox.ai/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ethovox</a>, an AI voice startup where she also serves as CEO. According to Gilfry, Ethovox works by having a company working on a film request the use of a digital replica of a performer’s voice for that film only. Performers schedule a recording session with Ethovox, where they collect data, making a digital copy of their voice. From there, clients pay a generation fee, which is passed on to the human actor, to use their digital double for voice over on commercial or entertainment projects. With those parameters in place, a performer can expect to hear their voice used only for approved projects.&nbsp;</p><figure><blockquote><p>Our joke is AI doesn’t have trauma.</p><cite>Cissy Jones</cite></blockquote></figure><blockquote><blockquote><span><blockquote></blockquote></span></blockquote><span><blockquote></blockquote></span></blockquote><p>SAG-AFTRA’s <a href="https://www.sagaftra.org/sites/default/files/2025-06/2025%20Interactive%20Media%20%28Video%20Game%29%20Agreement%20Summary.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">contract</a> sets out rules for consent and pay around voice replicas, but some voice actors I spoke with still had suspicions around the idea, fearing that it is a concession to AI. Additionally, desperate performers just starting their careers might be willing to sell their voices for less than they’re worth for the promise of passive income, potentially harming themselves and their colleagues by having their synthetic voices eliminate them from commercial and entertainment opportunities down the line. Scott also mentioned a potential nightmare scenario hanging over actors: a client might cut corners by violating the terms of the agreement for voice replicas on projects beyond the scope of their approved usage.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><p>“If I am doing a radio commercial and they say it's supposed to run for six months, we have to put trust in the system, meaning our managers, our agents, the client, that they are ethically using our voice for the time and the term period that they licensed it for with AI. Who's to say they don't take every acting job we do and put it into perpetuity?” Scott said. “Part of the way we make money—either through residuals or through the contract terms—would go away, decimating our industry, because there is no increase in the renewal that you would typically get if the client decides, ‘Hey, I love this Christmas commercial. We're going to use it again this year, and we're going to pay you a little bit more because we love it so much.’ The amount increases slightly every year, or according to the terms. That's one of the biggest dangers with AI, is that the robot can just do the work whenever, however, forever, into perpetuity.”</p><p>Another problem with the still-in-its-infancy threat that AI poses is that there is no legislation in place to make unethical and unconsented uses of it punishable by law.</p><p>“The <a href="https://navavoices.org/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">National Association of Voice Actors</a> is trying to get legislation in place to make it so that every person has the intellectual property rights over their voice, image, name, and likeness. We're doing that in support of the <a href="https://www.coons.senate.gov/download/no-fakes-act-one-pager" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">No Fakes Act</a>, but also talking with the copyright office, working even overseas, to make sure that that happens with the EU, and ideally, we would all own ourselves so that you can license that out,” Gilfry said. “When someone wants to create an AI version of you, there are currently no federal laws or many state laws in the United States that protect our rights to ourselves. So, it's the wild west with AI, and I am worried that this new administration in the <a href="https://gizmodo.com/trump-releases-his-all-american-action-plan-for-ai-2000633155" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">US is so focused on AI progress</a> that they will not regulate it in a way that provides us with guardrails to do it ethically.”</p><p>While much of voice matching’s use case in all of this is allocated to substituting for celebrities in shows, film, and commercials, it is also affected by AI’s growing influence on how the industry operates, which is limiting who can join the space as a sonic doppelganger for celebrities. Some of that relates to how AI has already become part of SAG-AFTRA’s new contract, with AI usage in ADR included in contracts.&nbsp;</p><p>“With the new <a href="https://www.sagaftra.org/production-center/contract/813/getting-started" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">TV theatrical agreement with SAG-AFTRA</a>, AI ADR is built into that contract. So if [an actor is] signing on to the new TV theatrical contract, you are already automatically agreeing to let them do ADR using a synthetic voice, because it's all considered post-production. As long as it doesn't change too much of your performance, it's allowed,” Gilfry said.&nbsp;</p><p>No one I spoke with thought we’re so far gone that AI will cause irreparable damage to the industry, such as replacing actors, voice match, or similar roles, entirely.</p><p>“We’re designed to look for tigers,” Hale says. “Couple that with the notion that what you focus on grows, and if we’re all focusing on where the losses are and where the problems are, we’re going to miss the incredible burgeoning of creativity.”</p><div><figure><p><iframe title="Harrison Ford Crashes The Game Awards" width="710" height="399" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/TLxL3U91YaY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></figure></div><p>Put more bluntly, the performers I spoke with feel there is a desire for human actors to reclaim the space, as the trend of AI being the flavor of the month among tech bros on Wall Street and Silicon Valley is bound to cycle out again because AI doesn’t, and can never, hit the same way as a human performance.&nbsp;</p><p>“Our joke is AI doesn’t have trauma,” Jones said. “AI can’t bring the trauma to a performance like a human can, and I think there will be a middling out where a lot of main characters are going to be human actors and a lot of the background characters are probably going to be AI-generated.”</p><p>“If you think about the Olympics, we're looking at the peak of human performance. It is exciting to watch someone run 100 meters as fast as they possibly can. The same is true when I watch <em>Fences</em>, and I see Denzel Washington and Viola Davis, where tears are flowing down their face, I'm connected to the emotion of it, but I'm also impressed by their amazing ability to go there as people,” Gilfry said. “It's just not impressive if a robot is doing it. I feel no connection to it. I might be impressed by the technology for a second, but it's not something that is going to touch me, because I can't empathize. I can't relate to it. I know that someone prompted it to do that. It's just not impressive.”</p><p>“I suspect we'll go through a phase where we're infatuated with the shiny new object of, ‘Oh my goodness, [AI] can copy anything.’ You've seen some of the crazy videos that Google's put out where they've got ‘AI humans’ doing performances that seem quite intense, emotional and human,” Hale said. “But when you tune into your gut, there's a piece missing. I honestly suspect that creators will get through this infatuation period and begin to long for that human element—the actual, undefinable, beautiful spark of the human soul.”</p><p>While Hale admits that the indistinguishable spark is undervalued in areas where content is simply created, she believes the pendulum will eventually swing back as people crave the human element of a performance over AI-generated voices. Plus, the excitement of watching actors try their hand at either voice-matching performances for characters like <a href="https://gizmodo.com/mark-hamill-kevin-conroy-joker-batman-one-last-reunion-1851298354" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Mark Hamill’s Joker and Kevin Conroy’s Batman</a>, or putting their own stamp on characters like <a href="https://youtu.be/HwkeTEEbfc8?t=27" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Roger Craig Smith</a> with the caped crusader or <a href="https://youtu.be/9uIEng_Q9_0" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Josh Keaton as Spider-Man</a> is a sensation that fans will gravitate towards once folks grow bored of how tacky AI voices are in comparison.&nbsp;</p><p>“If you look at our culture from a sort of a very wide, you know, 30,000 foot view,&nbsp;</p><p>everybody's been all about chasing money for so long. I'm seeing everybody look around and realize how soulless, lonely, and disconnected that has left us. And we're beginning to seek each other, community, meaning, and connection because that shiny object—sometimes literally—is leaving us empty,” Hale said. “I believe we're gonna have the same experience even in soundalikes. With this technology, it's fun to play with, but we're going to miss home, and home is that divine spark of the human soul.”</p><p><strong>Correction, 8/19/25, 12pm--</strong>The original version of this article misstated which Hanks voiced Woody in <em>Kingdom Hearts 3</em>.</p></div><div><h2>Stay in touch</h2><p>Sign up for our free newsletter</p></div><div><h2><span>More from Aftermath</span></h2><div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/mafia-old-country-review-impressions"><h3>Curling Up With A Sandwich, A Warm Drink And Mafia: The Old Country</h3></a><p>'I'm genuinely wistful for a good 'ol 7/10, last-days-of -summer video game'</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/esports-world-cup-new-global-sport-conference-2025-hideo-kojima"><h3>Come On, Guys</h3></a><p>Nobody is forcing Hideo Kojima and a host of industry luminaries to attend a Saudi sportswashing conference. And yet!</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/alien-earth-noah-hawley-fx-hulu-ridley-scott"><h3>Alien: Earth Has The Juice</h3></a><p>I was skeptical, but Noah Hawley has not let me down yet.</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/cyberpunk-urban-design"><h3>What Cyberpunk 2077 Can Teach Real-World Cities</h3></a><p>Night City's urban design highlights the problems, and solutions, real cities deal with around walkability, housing, and mixed-use areas</p></div></div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/all">See all posts<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="#000" stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round"><path d="M5 12h13m-6-7 7 7-7 7"></path></svg></a></div></div><br/><br/>https://aftermath.site/ai-voice-acting-soundalike-video-games]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apidya Special is an authentic remake from the original developers]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/08/19/apidya-special-is-an-authentic-remake-from-the-original-developers/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/apidya-special-is-an-authentic-remake-from-the-original-developers.1273950/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Commodore Amiga owners were <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BWBSnBsCW5Y">spoilt for superb shoot ’em ups</a> with original games such as&nbsp; Xenon II, Project X, Swiv,&nbsp; and Bloody Money, and superb arcade ports such as R-Type.&nbsp;One title that stood out from the crowd was Apidiya, a game that ditched spaceships and battle stations and replaced them with insects and ponds.&nbsp; It was totally unique and it’s coming back in almost exactly the same form.</p>
<p>Apidya Special is a full remake rather than an emulated version of the original Amiga title and it’s been developed by the original team, together with a devoted Apidya super-fan-turned-developer. The new version is based on an unreleased console port from the 90s, presumably the Sega Megadrive version, and uses the original assets along with brand new pixel art.&nbsp; There’s also a new version of the soundtrack by legendary 16-bit composer Chris Hülsbeck.</p>
<p><iframe title="Apidya' Special Announcement Teaser Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/OHiFhz-yJkE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>“We never thought we’d return to Apidya after all these years,” said Peter Thierolf, original creator of the game. “but with new technology, the right team, and the passion of the community, we can finally deliver the version we always dreamed about.”</p>
<p>While remaining true to the original game there some new features that have been added, check them out:</p>

<p><strong>Key Features</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>
<ul>
<li><strong>Authentic Remake</strong>&nbsp;– Completely rebuilt from scratch; no emulation.</li>
<li><strong>Two Visual Modes</strong>&nbsp;– Seamlessly switch between HD widescreen or original Amiga 4:3 presentation.</li>
<li><strong>Exclusive Chris Hülsbeck OST</strong>&nbsp;– Newly arranged soundtrack alongside remixed and classic tracks.</li>
<li><strong>Retro Visual Effects</strong>&nbsp;– Optional CRT shaders, bloom, and authentic scanline simulation.</li>
<li><strong>Expanded Worlds</strong>&nbsp;– 5 diverse themed worlds (Meadow, Pond, Sewers, Cyber, Lair), up to 5 levels each, 20 unique bosses, and hidden special stages.</li>
<li><strong>Fresh Surprises</strong>&nbsp;– Randomized in-game events like “Night Mode” with new enemy sprites.</li>
<li><strong>Co-op Mode</strong>&nbsp;– Second player controls one of the helper drones.</li>
<li><strong>Accessibility Options</strong>&nbsp;– Modernized difficulty settings to make the game enjoyable for all generations (including the original devs).</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Apidya Special will launch next year on PC (Steam), PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X|S, and Nintendo Switch.</p>
<p>Can someone please remake SWIV now? Pretty please?</p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://www.gamespress.com/Apidya-Special-33-Years-in-the-Making" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Press release</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/08/19/apidya-special-is-an-authentic-remake-from-the-original-developers/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokémon Teases A Spooky Legends: Z-A Reveal Later This Week]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/pokemon-teases-a-spooky-legends-z-a-reveal-later-this-week</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pok%C3%A9mon-teases-a-spooky-legends-z-a-reveal-later-this-week.1273947/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>"Viewer discretion advised"</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure><a title="Pokemon Legends: Z-A" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/1c8ce1555d660/pokemon-legends-z-a.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Nintendo</em></figcaption></figure><p>We've got some more fresh <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/pokemon_legends_z-a">Pokémon Legends: Z-A</a> news coming our way this week, as The Pokémon Company is teasing a little YouTube Premiere for <strong>Thursday, 21st August</strong>.</p>
<p>All we have to go on is a post on social media site X confirming that a video will be dropping at <strong>6am PDT / 9am EDT / 2pm BST on Thursday</strong>, a photo of someone holding a gate at night, and a note saying: "Viewer discretion advised".</p>
<p>Yep, that really is it. You can see it below and try and deduce the situation yourselves, but it looks a little spooky. Maybe something Ghost-related?</p><div><figure data-videoid="vf32irwF2Do" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/vf32irwF2Do?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><iframe title="YouTube Video" src="javascript:''" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/vf32irwF2Do?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/vf32irwF2Do?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" type="text/html" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed5f76a2thozmk&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><figcaption><p><a title="Watch This Video on YouTube" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vf32irwF2Do" rel="noopener">Watch on <strong><span></span> YouTube</strong> <span></span></a></p>
<p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>830k</span></a></p>
</figcaption></figure></div>

<p>It's been a busy week for the upcoming Switch and Switch 2 Legends game, with <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/previews/first-impressions-pokemon-legends-z-a-is-an-attempt-to-catch-the-hardcore-again">our own hands-on impressions</a> going live last week, and the weekend's confirmation that Z-A will have <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/pokemon-legends-z-a-unveils-new-multiplayer-battle-mode-for-up-to-four-trainers">a four-player multiplayer mode</a>.</p>
<p><em>What do you think we'll see later this week? Let us know down below.</em></p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-articles:186643,186617 @ 1755624597 --></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://x.com/Pokemon/status/1957790171216158990" rel="noopener" href="https://x.com/Pokemon/status/1957790171216158990">x.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-info/ae6d0d5e1d60693eadd1198083b6976b @ 1755625325 --></div></article><div><p>Alana has been with Nintendo Life since 2022, and while RPGs are her first love, Nintendo is a close second. She enjoys nothing more than overthinking battle strategies, characters, and stories. She also wishes she was a Sega air pirate.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/AlanaHagues"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/alanahagues.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('AlanaHagues');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/pokemon-teases-a-spooky-legends-z-a-reveal-later-this-week]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>