<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2025 20:06:13 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Those Guys Are Frauds’: Drazah Fires Shots at LAT After Securing Madrid Major GF]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/drazah-shots-fired-lat-madrid-major/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/%E2%80%98those-guys-are-frauds%E2%80%99-drazah-fires-shots-at-lat-after-securing-madrid-major-gf.1098228/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/drazah-shots-fired-lat-madrid-major/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Atlanta FaZe just pulled off a remarkable reverse sweep at the Call of Duty League Major in Madrid. After a fairly dominant opener that saw LAT blitz FaZe, Atlanta switched things up during the mid-series Control and never slowed down. It boiled down to a round eleven showdown during map five that was quickly mopped up by FaZe.</p>



<p>The LA Thieves will now fall into the final fixture of the elimination bracket, going head-to-head (again) with the Miami Heretics. Earlier in the tournament, the LA Thieves booted Miami into the lower bracket after a 3-0 sweep.</p>



<p>Talking on stage after the match, Drazah had some choice words for the LA Thieves.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-rivalry-renewed">Rivalry Renewed</h2>



<p>The LA Thieves and Atlanta FaZe represent two of the biggest dogs in the CDL fight. They’re fronted by some of the sharpest talent in the Call of Duty League, and they have the most valuable rosters to boot.</p>



<p>This face-off series was never going to go any other way than to the wire – which is exactly what happened. With it coming down to single-digit kill counts, Atlanta FaZe prevailed, earning the first ticket to the grand final series of the Madrid Major.</p>



<p>On stage in the post-match interview, Drazah fired shots at LA Thieves:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>I’m feeling great – those guys are <strong>frauds</strong>. It’s Sunday, we’re on LAN, reverse-sweep, this shit is easy.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>In the last few weeks, the LA Thieves roster has been wrestling with the title of ‘Super Team’, which was branded upon the squad when it was assembled last year. For many, LAT hasn’t yet lived up to those lofty expectations, which is a sticking point for sure.</p>



<p>LA Thieves will now contend with the Miami Heretics for the sole remaining spot in the grand final. There’s a $150,000 prize awaiting the winner of Major I – who will secure it? Find out in just a couple of hours.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming esports, stay tuned to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/category/esports/">catch the latest news</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Roll7's critically acclaimed skating games OlliOlliWorld and Rollerdrome mysteriously yanked from Steam]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/roll7s-critically-acclaimed-skating-games-olliolliworld-and-rollerdrome-mysteriously-yanked-from-steam</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/roll7s-critically-acclaimed-skating-games-olliolliworld-and-rollerdrome-mysteriously-yanked-from-steam.1098207/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/roll7s-critically-acclaimed-skating-games-olliolliworld-and-rollerdrome-mysteriously-yanked-from-steam<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/ss_2eedf2ce30e307adc6252e60c092a53fcb3fca76.1920x1080.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Roll7 / Private Division</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/companies/roll7">Roll7</a>'s award-winning <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/rollerdrome">Rollerdrome</a> and <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/olliolli-world">OlliOlli World</a> have been mysteriously delisted on Steam.</p>
<p>Whilst there's been no formal word on why the critically acclaimed skating games have been pulled from sale on Steam, both games had been published on <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/companies/take-two-interactive">Take-Two Interactive</a>'s indie publishing label, Private Division, before it was sold to an unknown buyer, thought to be Haveli Investments, towards the end of last year.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Let's Play Rollerdrome PS5 Gameplay- HATERS GONNA SKATE!" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6I3zU5pIjtg?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Let's Play Rollerdrome PS5 Gameplay- HATERS GONNA SKATE!</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6I3zU5pIjtg?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/6I3zU5pIjtg?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Let's Play Rollerdrome PS5 Gameplay- HATERS GONNA SKATE!<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6I3zU5pIjtg" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>Neither game shows up if you search on Steam, whilst using the direct URL informs you that the games are <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1294420/Rollerdrome/">"no longer available on the Steam store"</a>, despite Roll7's previous games, <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/olliolli">OlliOlli</a> and OlliOlli 2: Welcome to OlliWood are still listed.</p><p>Curiously, both Rollerdrome and OlliOlli World are, for now at least, still available on the PlayStation Store. Whilst they still list Private Division as the publisher on those pages, the defunct Steam pages - which were quietly amended last week - have been <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/1294420/history/">updated</a> to replace the publisher Private Division with 2K.</p>
<p>At the time of writing, it's unclear if this is just an oversight, a licensing issue, or a signal that Roll7's portfolio did not transfer to the anonymous buyer and remains with 2K.</p>
<p>Grand Theft Auto and Borderlands publisher Take-Two Interactive <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/take-two-sells-private-division-label-confirms-closure-of-olliolli-world-and-kerbal-space-program-2-studios">announced the sale of its indie-focused publishing label Private Division in November 2024</a>. Additionally, the company also confirmed the closure of OlliOlli World developer Roll7 and Kerbal Space Program 2's Intercept Games, six months after CEO Strauss Zelnick insisted, "We didn't shutter those studios".</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battlefield’s Community Test Program Will be Revealed Tomorrow]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/bnattlefield-community-test-program/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/battlefield%E2%80%99s-community-test-program-will-be-revealed-tomorrow.1098189/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/bnattlefield-community-test-program/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-87584">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>DICE and EA have announced that the first details on the next Battlefield’s community test program will be revealed tomorrow.</p>



<p>The announcement was posted on the official X (formerly Twitter) account, where it was said, “Tune in tomorrow at 5PM CET / 8AM PDT for more on the upcoming <a href="https://x.com/hashtag/Battlefield?src=hashtag_click">#Battlefield</a> community testing program.”</p>



<p>Last week, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-6-playtests/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming exclusively reported that Battlefield playtests</a> were once again ramping up to test the multiplayer and Battle Royale experiences of the game. </p>



<p>While details on what will be announced tomorrow are incredibly slim, several sources have suggested that we’ll get our first look at pre-alpha gameplay of the game (abliet, only a few seconds).</p>



<p>Insider Gaming also understands that playtests for the next Battlefield title have been a weekly occurrence for months, with DICE and the other Battlefield studios relentlessly gaining player feedback; something they didn’t do for Battlefield 2042.</p>



<p>From small feedback sessions to large-scale player tests, Battlefield is now taking the much-needed “player first” approach to ensure that the next Battlefield game is a success, with the teams leaning from its mistakes of the series’ past couple of installments. </p>



<p>Are you looking forward to hearing more about the Battlefield Community Test Program? Let us know on the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/far-cry-new-dawn-60-fps-upgrade/">Far Cry New Dawn is getting a 60 FPS upgra</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/sleeping-dogs-movie-confirmed-story-kitchen/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/sleeping-dogs-movie-confirmed-story-kitchen/">Sleeping Dogs Movie Is Confirmed and Story Kitchen Is Bringing It To Life</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>It has been confirmed that the Sleeping Dogs movie exists and it’s being produced by Story Kitchen. Get the full story here.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/john-gonzalez-returns-to-obsidian/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/john-gonzalez-returns-to-obsidian/">Fallout: New Vegas Lead Writer Returns to Obsidian, But Says Its Not For New Vegas 2</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Fallout New Vegas and Horizon Zero Dawn lead writer John Gonzalez has announced he will be retuning to Obsidian after 14 years.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/far-cry-new-dawn-60-fps-upgrade/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/far-cry-new-dawn-60-fps-upgrade/">Far Cry: New Dawn Getting 60 FPS Update on Xbox Series and PS5</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Far Cry: New Dawn is getting a 60 FPS upgrade on both Xbox Series X|S and PlayStation 5 platforms. Check out the latest news here.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/overwatch-dead-ninja-marvel-rivals/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/overwatch-dead-ninja-marvel-rivals/">‘Overwatch is Dead and Gone’: Ninja Thinks Marvel Rivals Has Killed the Competition</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Ninja thinks that Marvel Rivals has effectively killed Overwatch, which in his words, is ‘dead and gone’. Get the full story here.</p>
                    </div>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokémon TCG Pocket admits restrictive trading system stops players "enjoying the feature as intended"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/pokemon-tcg-pocket-admits-restrictive-trading-system-stops-players-enjoying-the-feature-as-intended</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pok%C3%A9mon-tcg-pocket-admits-restrictive-trading-system-stops-players-enjoying-the-feature-as-intended.1098180/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/pokemon-tcg-pocket-admits-restrictive-trading-system-stops-players-enjoying-the-feature-as-intended<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div>
        

        <p>It's hardly pocket science.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Screenshot-2025-02-02-at-16.26.47.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Pokémon</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/pokemon-tcg-pocket-players-brand-trading-system-a-joke-and-downright-greedy">Within days of launching a controversial new update that added the ability to trade cards</a>, <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/pokemon-trading-card-game-pocket">Pokémon TCG Pocket</a> has acknowledged the community's backlash, saying it was "actively investigating" ways to improve.</p>
<p>A statement posted to social media stopped short of apologising to unhappy players, but admitted some of the new feature's restrictions were actively "preventing players from being able to casually enjoy" the card game.</p>
<figure><div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div><figcaption>Xbox Developer Direct - four promising games also coming to PlayStation.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=afaO_AuPw0o" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>"Since releasing the first iteration of the trading feature a few days ago, we have received a large number of comments. Thank you all for sharing your feedback," the statement from Creatures Inc began.</p>
<p>"The item requirements and restrictions implemented for the trading feature were designed to prevent abuse from bots and other prohibited actions using multiple accounts."</p> <div>

<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>As trading requires players use up valuable resources and adhere to a lengthy list of restrictions in order to acquire cards they don't already have, some players felt as though trading was actively discouraged, especially as its limited to players on your friends list, and only one trade can be conducted at a time. Currently, only cards of One, Two, Three or Four Diamond rarity can be offered for trade, alongside One Star rarity.</p>
<p>Now, however, the team says that the goal had only been to "balance" the game whilst "maintaining a fair environment for all players", adding "preserving the fun of collecting cards[...] is core to the Pokémon TCG Pocket experience".</p>
<p>"However, thanks to your feedback, we understand that some of the restrictions put in place are preventing players from being able to casually enjoy the feature as intended," the team concluded.</p>
<p>"We are actively investigating ways to improve the feature to address these concerns. Going forward, we also plan to offer multiple ways to obtain trade tokens including through event distributions.</p>
<p>"As always, thank you for being part of the Pokémon TCG Pocket community."</p>
<p>If you're trying to navigate the new update, Eurogamer can help out with a guide to <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/pokemon-tcg-pocket-trading-how-to-trade-cards">Pokémon TCG Pocket trading and how to trade cards</a>, as well as a deeper dive into <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/Pok%C3%A9mon%20TCG%20Pocket%20Trade%20Tokens%20and%20how%20to%20get%20Trade%20Tokens">Pokémon TCG Pocket Trade Tokens and how to get them</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PDP’s Riffmaster guitar controller is receiving a rare $20 discount]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/604360/pdp-riffmaster-fortnite-guitar-controller-amazon-fire-tv-stick-4k-deal-sale</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pdp%E2%80%99s-riffmaster-guitar-controller-is-receiving-a-rare-20-discount.1098171/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/604360/pdp-riffmaster-fortnite-guitar-controller-amazon-fire-tv-stick-4k-deal-sale<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/brandon-widder">Brandon Widder</a> <span>is a senior editor overseeing deals, gift guides, and commerce. He spent six years spearheading buying guides and consumer tech coverage at Digital Trends.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Last month, <em>Fortnite Festival</em>, the game’s <em>Rock Band</em>-like music mode, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/10/24340770/fortnite-festival-local-multiplayer">rolled out local multiplayer</a> on PlayStation and Xbox. It’s a great addition if you and up to three buddies want to relive the halcyon days of ‘07 on a single TV, particularly if you’re using a nostalgia-inducing peripheral like the <strong>PDP Riffmaster</strong> — which is now available from <a href="https://www.amazon.com/RIFFMASTER-Controller-PlayStation-Rechargeable-Officially-5/dp/B0CWN15TRF/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored">Amazon</a>, <a href="https://howl.me/cmAMlEcH9iA" rel="sponsored">Best Buy</a>, and <a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=1025X1701640&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.turtlebeach.com%2Fproducts%2Friffmaster-wireless-guitar-controller" rel="sponsored">PDP</a> for an all-time low of $109.99 ($20 off).</p><p>Much like the old guitars developed for <em>Rock Band</em>, PDP’s wireless gamepad allows you to strum along with real songs in both <em>Rock Band 4</em> (<a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/1/17/24041933/rock-band-4-dlc-songs-ending-fortnite-festival-harmonix">RIP</a>) and the free-to-play <em>Fortnite Festival</em>. It offers a lot of the same functionality as previous controllers, though, seeing as it’s been nearly a decade since Mad Catz’s last Stratocaster-style gamepad, the Riffmaster introduces a few modern tricks. That includes USB-C charging and a 3.5mm audio jack, along with a dedicated analog stick on the back of the neck for more straightforward navigation.</p><p>In true <em>RB4</em> fashion, the Riffmaster is also outfitted with five color-coded buttons higher up the neck and a second set lower down, each of which you can use to hammer out the various notes as they appear in their respective lanes. A strummer and a whammy bar make good on the classic <em>Rock Band</em> experience, letting you unleash vibrato on the Xbox, PlayStation, or PC with the included USB dongle.</p><div data-product-filter=""><p><span>$<!-- -->130</span></p><div><p>The wireless PDP Riffmaster is an alternative to Harmonix’s official <em>Rock Band 4</em> guitar. The PlayStation-licensed rhythm controller works for PS4 and PS5 and is usable with other games — including <em>Fortnite Festival</em>. It offers a 36-hour rechargeable battery, built-in volume control, an analog stick, and a collapsible neck design.</p></div></div><div><p id="more-ways-to-save-this-weekend"><h2>More ways to save this weekend</h2></p></div><div><ul><li><span>If you’re looking for a cheap way to <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/15/24344628/super-bowl-lix-tubi-stream-free-fox">stream Super Bowl LIX</a> next weekend, <strong><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/9/20/23882154/amazon-fire-tv-stick-4k-max-soundbar-announced">Amazon’s latest Fire TV Stick 4K</a></strong> is on sale at <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Amazon-Fire-TV-Stick-4K-streaming-device/dp/B0CJM1GNFQ/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored">Amazon</a>, <a rel="sponsored" href="https://howl.link/3pjhhydqhnqut">Best Buy</a>, and <a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/81938/2092?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Famazon-fire-tv-stick-4k-2024%2F-%2FA-91651394" rel="sponsored">Target</a> for $29.99 ($20 off), nearly matching its second-best price to date. It’s not quite as capable as the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0BP9SNVH9?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored">step-up Max model</a> — blame its lack of Wi-Fi 6E support and 8GB of storage — but the 4K streamer still offers Wi-Fi 6 and broad HDR support for Dolby Vision, HDR10, and HDR10 Plus.</span></li><li><span>The PlayStation version of <strong><em>Final Fantasy I-VI Collection Anniversary Edition</em></strong> is down to an all-time low of $39.99 ($35 off) at <a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8836598/type/dlg/https://electronics.woot.com/offers/square-enix-final-fantasy/" rel="sponsored">Woot</a> through 12:59AM ET on February 29th. The excellent remaster pulls together the first six <em>Final Fantasy </em>titles with revamped pixel graphics and rearranged orchestral scores, as well as an array of gameplay tweaks and quality-of-life improvements. I, for one, welcome the ability to turn off random encounters, which remain the bane of ‘90s-era JRPGs (sorry, not sorry).</span></li><li><span><strong>Lenovo’s Yoga Slim 7i Aura Edition</strong>, a thin-and-light Windows laptop with an Intel Core Ultra 7 256V processor and 16GB of RAM, is going for $899.99 ($500 off) at <a rel="sponsored" href="https://howl.link/5bnwoqulwsbbc">Best Buy</a> through the end of today, February 2nd. That’s a new low on the 15-inch machine, which, despite its bummer trackpad and other shortcomings, remains a solid rec thanks to good all-around performance, fantastic port selection, and bright 120Hz LCD display. <a href="https://www.theverge.com/24283884/lenovo-yoga-slim-7i-aura-edition-laptop-intel-lunar-lake-review">Read our review</a>.</span></li></ul></div><div><form><div><h2>Verge Deals</h2><p><span>Sign up for Verge Deals to get deals on products we’ve tested sent to your inbox weekly.</span></p></div></form></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Starting Strong In Sniper Elite: Resistance, Snagging The Best Deals In Nintendo's Latest Sale, And More Of The Week's Tips]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/stalker-2-marvel-snap-giveaway-gaming-tips-1851752786</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/starting-strong-in-sniper-elite-resistance-snagging-the-best-deals-in-nintendos-latest-sale-and-more-of-the-weeks-tips.1098120/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/stalker-2-marvel-snap-giveaway-gaming-tips-1851752786<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><figure id="" data-id="a8796ef001a05c8e967b2691d3a867b8" data-recommend-id="image://a8796ef001a05c8e967b2691d3a867b8" data-format="jpg" data-width="1280" data-height="720" data-lightbox="false" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="false" data-imagerights="in-house-art" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Sony / Valve / Kotaku<!-- -->, <!-- -->Nintendo<!-- -->, <!-- -->Second Dinner / Nuverse<!-- -->, <!-- -->Rebellion<!-- -->, <!-- -->Rebellion<!-- -->, <!-- -->Rebellion<!-- -->, <!-- -->Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Marvel / Kotaku<!-- -->, <!-- -->The Pokémon Company / Kotaku<!-- -->, <!-- -->Larian Studios / Kotaku<!-- -->, <!-- -->GSC Game World</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="a8796ef001a05c8e967b2691d3a867b8" data-recommend-id="image://a8796ef001a05c8e967b2691d3a867b8" data-format="jpg" data-width="1280" data-height="720" data-lightbox="false" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p> This week, we’ll help you hook up your PS VR2 to your PC, start strong in <em>Sniper Elite: Resistance</em>, and snag the best deals in Nintendo’s current Switch sale. Read on for these tips and more.</p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="4c8a5d3aa631bf49f44c76107369ef51" data-recommend-id="image://4c8a5d3aa631bf49f44c76107369ef51" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A promotional image of the PlayStation VR2 PC Adapter. The PlayStation VR2 headset is connected to the adapter, which is connected to a white desktop on the left side of the screen. A monitor is shown playing Half-Life Alyx." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A promotional image of the PlayStation VR2 PC Adapter. The PlayStation VR2 headset is connected to the adapter, which is connected to a white desktop on the left side of the screen. A monitor is shown playing Half-Life Alyx." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Sony / Valve / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="4c8a5d3aa631bf49f44c76107369ef51" data-recommend-id="image://4c8a5d3aa631bf49f44c76107369ef51" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A promotional image of the PlayStation VR2 PC Adapter. The PlayStation VR2 headset is connected to the adapter, which is connected to a white desktop on the left side of the screen. A monitor is shown playing Half-Life Alyx." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>The PlayStation VR2 Headset <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/playstation-vr2-headsets-production-sales-halt-sony-1851344240&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/playstation-vr2-headsets-production-sales-halt-sony-1851344240">didn’t light the world on fire</a></span> when it originally released in 2023, but its user base has grown despite a lackluster launch. Plus, the headset itself features some pretty impressive VR hardware. Following <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/psvr2-ps5-sale-discount-cheap-deal-1851608173?_gl=1*4cmjdb*_ga*MTM0Mjk0ODIxMC4xNjkxNzY3NjQ2*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczODE4MzQ4MC4xMTAuMS4xNzM4MTg2MzYyLjU3LjAuMA..&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/psvr2-ps5-sale-discount-cheap-deal-1851608173?_gl=1*4cmjdb*_ga*MTM0Mjk0ODIxMC4xNjkxNzY3NjQ2*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczODE4MzQ4MC4xMTAuMS4xNzM4MTg2MzYyLjU3LjAuMA..">a substantial $200 discount in 2024</a></span>, many PlayStation 5 owners got to enjoy <em>Beatsaber </em>and <em>Resident Evil 4</em> in first-person for the relatively more affordable price of $349.99. What’s more, Sony has since released a PC Adapter for the VR2, which provides access to the thousands of VR games available on Steam and a new option for VR gamers on PC. What’s not to love? - Timothy Monbleau <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/psvr2-pc-adapter-bluetooth-connection-displayport-1851750509&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/psvr2-pc-adapter-bluetooth-connection-displayport-1851750509">Read More</a></span></p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="1735407a45f9584dfc6004d6632983d0" data-recommend-id="image://1735407a45f9584dfc6004d6632983d0" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Nintendo</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="1735407a45f9584dfc6004d6632983d0" data-recommend-id="image://1735407a45f9584dfc6004d6632983d0" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>A new <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/nintendo-eshop-switch-slop-clones-unpacking-scam-ai-art-1851722248&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/nintendo-eshop-switch-slop-clones-unpacking-scam-ai-art-1851722248">Nintendo Switch eShop</a></span> sale is happening right now. Nearly 40 games are currently marked down, including some first-party hits from Nintendo and a selection of third-party titles, too.  - Zack Zwiezen <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/eshop-switch-sale-game-nintendo-supercharge-mario-deals-1851749300&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/eshop-switch-sale-game-nintendo-supercharge-mario-deals-1851749300">Read More</a></span></p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="358e7bcc8423eb490026fbd607f36ee3" data-recommend-id="image://358e7bcc8423eb490026fbd607f36ee3" data-format="png" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Moon Knight glides down with his cape extended outward." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Moon Knight glides down with his cape extended outward." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Marvel / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="358e7bcc8423eb490026fbd607f36ee3" data-recommend-id="image://358e7bcc8423eb490026fbd607f36ee3" data-format="png" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Moon Knight glides down with his cape extended outward." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>After <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/marvel-rivals-leak-rumored-heroes-characters-datamine-1851747643&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/marvel-rivals-leak-rumored-heroes-characters-datamine-1851747643"><em>Marvel Rivals</em></a></span>’<em> </em><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/marvel-rivals-first-balance-patch-gives-hela-a-slap-on-1851735498&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/marvel-rivals-first-balance-patch-gives-hela-a-slap-on-1851735498">latest patch</a></span> buffed Moon Knight’s ultimate ability, Hand of Khonshu, I noticed it was melting my teammates. I had already considered the AoE attack—which has a super-quick cast time and a decent radius of almost immediate damage—one of the most effective damage dealers in the game, then when it became even more powerful in the current season I didn’t question it. But it turns out its devastating efficiency might actually be a bug. - Kenneth Shepard <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/marvel-rivals-moon-knight-ultimate-ability-bug-glitch-1851748295&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/marvel-rivals-moon-knight-ultimate-ability-bug-glitch-1851748295">Read More</a></span></p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="1bc64c59788745ec6c962d0ee19159b6" data-recommend-id="image://1bc64c59788745ec6c962d0ee19159b6" data-format="png" data-width="1855" data-height="1044" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Manaphy smiles at something off-screen." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Manaphy smiles at something off-screen." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->The Pokémon Company / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="1bc64c59788745ec6c962d0ee19159b6" data-recommend-id="image://1bc64c59788745ec6c962d0ee19159b6" data-format="png" data-width="1855" data-height="1044" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Manaphy smiles at something off-screen." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>If you’re the type of <em>Pokémon </em>fan who cares about collecting every variation of its 1,000+ monsters, that means constantly seeking out special events to receive a rare critter or searching for hours to find one with a low spawn rate hiding in the tall grass. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/pokemon-shiny-odds-scarlet-violet-ivs-red-gyarados-1850248457&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-shiny-odds-scarlet-violet-ivs-red-gyarados-1850248457">Shiny Pokémon</a></span> are the rarest of the rare, with a color scheme different from the regular versions of any given pocket monster. Some rare legendaries are even “shiny-locked,” meaning they will never appear in games with the alternate coloring. But good news: two of them are finally being made available, although you’ll have to complete the entire Pokédex in <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/pokemon-legends-arceus-gameplay-model-scarlet-violet-1849105177&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-legends-arceus-gameplay-model-scarlet-violet-1849105177"><em>Pokémon Legends: Arceus</em></a></span> or <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/the-new-pokemon-diamond-and-pearl-remakes-are-barebones-1848113404&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/the-new-pokemon-diamond-and-pearl-remakes-are-barebones-1848113404"><em>Brilliant Diamond </em>and <em>Shining Pearl</em></a></span><em> </em>to claim them. - Kenneth Shepard <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/pokemon-home-shiny-enamorous-manaphy-bdsp-legends-1851749346&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-home-shiny-enamorous-manaphy-bdsp-legends-1851749346">Read More</a></span></p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="9e3a9c13fabc4bf3cf27dfd7b2a244d9" data-recommend-id="image://9e3a9c13fabc4bf3cf27dfd7b2a244d9" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Ketheric Thorm looks angrily at something off-screen." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Ketheric Thorm looks angrily at something off-screen." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Larian Studios / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="9e3a9c13fabc4bf3cf27dfd7b2a244d9" data-recommend-id="image://9e3a9c13fabc4bf3cf27dfd7b2a244d9" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Ketheric Thorm looks angrily at something off-screen." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/baldurs-gate-3-bg3-review-dungeons-dragons-rpg-larian-1850726491&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/baldurs-gate-3-bg3-review-dungeons-dragons-rpg-larian-1850726491"><em>Baldur’s Gate 3</em>’s</a></span> <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/baldurs-gate-3-patch-8-cross-play-photo-mode-date-1851709476&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/baldurs-gate-3-patch-8-cross-play-photo-mode-date-1851709476">eighth big patch</a></span> is in the works over at Larian Studios right now, and the team is going to let players stress test the update at some point before it’s pushed live. However, it looks like the patch has mysteriously appeared on PlayStation 5, and Larian’s not sure why. If you want to get an un-tested preview of the patch, go ahead and download it on your PS5. But be warned, it will affect your saves while Larian sorts through the issue. - Kenneth Shepard <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/baldurs-gate-3-patch-8-playstation-5-ps5-early-update-1851748476&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/baldurs-gate-3-patch-8-playstation-5-ps5-early-update-1851748476">Read More</a></span></p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="8ecbd3f95d56cc9adba4c38be53dd89a" data-recommend-id="image://8ecbd3f95d56cc9adba4c38be53dd89a" data-format="jpg" data-width="832" data-height="468" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Wolverine, Deadpool, and Venom grab their make goods. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Wolverine, Deadpool, and Venom grab their make goods. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Second Dinner / Nuverse</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="8ecbd3f95d56cc9adba4c38be53dd89a" data-recommend-id="image://8ecbd3f95d56cc9adba4c38be53dd89a" data-format="jpg" data-width="832" data-height="468" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Wolverine, Deadpool, and Venom grab their make goods. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p><em>Marvel Snap</em> is trying to make it up to fans after it <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/tiktok-ban-marvel-snap-down-trump-bytedance-1851743130&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/tiktok-ban-marvel-snap-down-trump-bytedance-1851743130">briefly disappeared</a></span> as part of the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/tiktok-us-ban-supreme-court-date-bytedance-china-1851715772&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/tiktok-us-ban-supreme-court-date-bytedance-china-1851715772">TikTok ban earlier this month</a></span>. While the hit mobile card game’s makers are searching for a new publisher to prevent another huge outage in the future, it’s also welcoming players back with tons of free stuff including gold, credits, and bonus season pass XP.  - Ethan Gach <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/marvel-snap-free-gold-credits-booster-tiktok-ban-reward-1851748419&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/marvel-snap-free-gold-credits-booster-tiktok-ban-reward-1851748419">Read More</a></span></p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="c6a07ca922dbe68b6e2687191c1af415" data-recommend-id="image://c6a07ca922dbe68b6e2687191c1af415" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1079" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A sniper uses a zipline to descend into a construction site." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A sniper uses a zipline to descend into a construction site." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="false" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Rebellion</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="c6a07ca922dbe68b6e2687191c1af415" data-recommend-id="image://c6a07ca922dbe68b6e2687191c1af415" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1079" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A sniper uses a zipline to descend into a construction site." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p><em>Sniper Elite: Resistance</em> is all about making the most of your equipment and stealthy instincts as you work to complete the objectives scattered around each map. As such, you’ll need to invest some points into skills as you level up, granting you some boons to help you survive. Here are the skills most folks should buy first. - Billy Givens <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/sniper-elite-resistance-first-skills-early-game-1851750442&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/sniper-elite-resistance-first-skills-early-game-1851750442">Read More</a></span></p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="06a7785eb68f48dea18a7b0a4ec852f7" data-recommend-id="image://06a7785eb68f48dea18a7b0a4ec852f7" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="The protagonist of Sniper Elite: Resistance carries a body while fireing a gun." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="The protagonist of Sniper Elite: Resistance carries a body while fireing a gun." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="false" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Rebellion</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="06a7785eb68f48dea18a7b0a4ec852f7" data-recommend-id="image://06a7785eb68f48dea18a7b0a4ec852f7" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="The protagonist of Sniper Elite: Resistance carries a body while fireing a gun." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p><em>Sniper Elite: Resistance</em> is the newest entry in the long-running franchise. Launching on January 30 for PS5, Xbox Series X/S, and PC (in addition to last gen PlayStation and Xbox consoles), the new game brings a brand-new operative to the forefront of the story while maintaining the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/sniper-elite-resistance-games-pc-ps5-best-1851747402?rev=1737768811350&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/sniper-elite-resistance-games-pc-ps5-best-1851747402?rev=1737768811350">tense, stealth-focused gameplay</a></span> fans have come to know and love. As with all the games in the series, you can expect a fairly lengthy campaign with plenty of different ways to approach your objectives.  - Billy Givens <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/sniper-elite-resistance-how-long-campaign-difficulty-1851749581&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/sniper-elite-resistance-how-long-campaign-difficulty-1851749581">Read More</a></span></p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="73b283c41fec275866ee1dfff29117af" data-recommend-id="image://73b283c41fec275866ee1dfff29117af" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A sniper fires a gun while hiding admist the wreckage of war." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A sniper fires a gun while hiding admist the wreckage of war." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="false" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Rebellion</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="73b283c41fec275866ee1dfff29117af" data-recommend-id="image://73b283c41fec275866ee1dfff29117af" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A sniper fires a gun while hiding admist the wreckage of war." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p><em>Sniper Elite: Resistance</em> is a challenging sequel that doesn’t shy away from testing your marksmanship. As such, you’ll want to bring your best self to each mission. Below, we’ve got a handful of tips we think might help you do exactly that, so take a look and put ‘em to good use. - Billy Givens <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/sniper-elite-resistance-tips-ping-health-noise-1851749709&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/sniper-elite-resistance-tips-ping-health-noise-1851749709">Read More</a></span></p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="3494f694ddc962ad966b90b33cffb9ca" data-recommend-id="image://3494f694ddc962ad966b90b33cffb9ca" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A press screenshot for Stalker 2: Heart of Chornobyl featuring a military commander." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A press screenshot for Stalker 2: Heart of Chornobyl featuring a military commander." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="false" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->GSC Game World</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="3494f694ddc962ad966b90b33cffb9ca" data-recommend-id="image://3494f694ddc962ad966b90b33cffb9ca" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A press screenshot for Stalker 2: Heart of Chornobyl featuring a military commander." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>The Zone is home to countless mutations and enemies, like bandits wielding shotguns and Snorks ambushing a lone Stalker foolish enough to wander into an abandoned factory at night. Sure, the right weapon, like a <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/stalker-2-riemann-smg-deluxe-edition-dlc-worth-it-find-1851713004&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/stalker-2-riemann-smg-deluxe-edition-dlc-worth-it-find-1851713004">powerful submachine gun</a></span> or <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/stalker-2-best-sidearm-rhino-location-upgrade-1851751837?rev=1738264838469&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/stalker-2-best-sidearm-rhino-location-upgrade-1851751837?rev=1738264838469">fast-firing revolver</a></span>, will make quick work of most enemies in the game, giving you the edge in pushing forward with your assault. But what about defense? Your typical suit won’t stop a bullet, nor will it make you stronger and faster. But an exoskeleton will!  - Brandon Morgan <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/stalker-2-exoskeleton-locations-best-upgrades-1851751957&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/stalker-2-exoskeleton-locations-best-upgrades-1851751957">Read More</a></span></p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PlatinumGames quietly removes all mentions of Project G.G. from website]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/platinumgames-quietly-removes-all-mentions-of-project-gg-from-website</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/platinumgames-quietly-removes-all-mentions-of-project-g-g-from-website.1098117/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/platinumgames-quietly-removes-all-mentions-of-project-gg-from-website<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div>
        

        <p>"I feel deeply insulted by this," says former Platinum producer.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Screenshot-2025-02-02-at-14.02.51.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>PlatinumGames</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>PlatinumGames has removed all mentions of its superhero game, Project G.G., from its website.</p>
<p>Whereas previously, <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20241224141257/https:/www.platinumgames.com/games/">22 released and upcoming games had been listed</a> there, all but nine have been <a href="https://www.platinumgames.com/works/world-of-demons">removed</a>, with even <a href="https://www.platinumgames.com/games/projectgg">the codenamed project's dedicated URL</a> now redirecting to the main page.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Project G.G. Teaser Trailer - Platinum Games" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wTpr66fIbv0?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Project G.G. Teaser Trailer - Platinum Games</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wTpr66fIbv0?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/wTpr66fIbv0?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Project G.G. Teaser Trailer - Platinum Games.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wTpr66fIbv0" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>Games like <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/star-fox-zero">Star Fox Zero</a>, <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/babylons-fall">Babylon's Fall</a>, <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/teenage-mutant-ninja-turtles-mutants-in-manhattan">Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles: Mutants in Manhattan</a>, <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/transformers-devastation">Transformers: Devastation</a>, and The Legend of Korra have also been scrubbed from Platinum's <a href="https://www.platinumgames.com/works/">"all works"</a> page.</p>
<p>Former Platinum Games mastermind Hideki Kamiya announced the project - codenamed Project G.G. - back in June 2020. It had been described as Kamiya described as the third and final entry in his now-trilogy of hero works following the <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/viewtiful-joe">Viewtiful Joe</a> series and The Wonderful 101.</p>
<p>However, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/bayonetta-creator-hideki-kamiya-leaving-platinumgames">Kamiya left the studio in 2023</a> and <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/okami-sequel-in-the-works-with-capcom-and-hideki-kamiyas-new-studio-clovers">joined Clovers at the end of last year</a>. There has been no update on the fate of Project G.G. since his departure.</p>
<p>"Saw this on ResetEra, and I have no idea why they did it, but PlatinumGames erasing its history on its website is extremely regrettable," opined former PlatinumGames producer, JP Kellams (thanks, <a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/project-ggs-status-remains-uncertain-after-platinum-removes-the-game-from-its-website/">VGC</a>).</p>
<p>"I wonder if the pulled the carpet tiles out of the lobby, too. As someone proud of working on those games, I feel deeply insulted by this."</p> <div>
<div data-domain="twitter.com"><blockquote><p dir="ltr" lang="en">Saw this on ResetEra, and I have no idea why they did it, but <a href="https://twitter.com/platinumgames?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@platinumgames</a> erasing its history on its website is extremely regrettable. I wonder if the pulled the carpet tiles out of the lobby, too. As someone proud of working on those games, I feel deeply insulted by this. <a href="https://t.co/a1rmAMO0Tc">pic.twitter.com/a1rmAMO0Tc</a></p>— JP Kellams (@synaesthesiajp) <a href="https://twitter.com/synaesthesiajp/status/1885786875119517994?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 1, 2025</a></blockquote></div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>Last week's <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/ninja-gaiden-4-announced-from-team-ninja-and-platinumgames">Xbox Developer Direct kicked off with the reveal of Ninja Gaiden 4</a>, a fresh mainline entry in the legendary action game series in development by Team Ninja and PlatinumGames.</p>
<p>It's the first new entry in the series for 13 years, and is set to launch this autumn on PC, PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X/S, including on Xbox Game Pass.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sleeping Dogs Movie Is Confirmed and Story Kitchen Is Bringing It To Life]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/sleeping-dogs-movie-confirmed-story-kitchen/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sleeping-dogs-movie-is-confirmed-and-story-kitchen-is-bringing-it-to-life.1098078/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/sleeping-dogs-movie-confirmed-story-kitchen/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Recently, Simu Liu took to social media to suggest he was working on a live-action representation of Sleeping Dogs, the 2012 open-world game. When Sleeping Dogs was released over a decade ago, it was to critical acclaim, boasting an intense story, masterful combat mechanics, and a star-studded cast. For the longest time, fans of the one-and-done game have been holding out hope for a sequel, but it has never surfaced.</p>



<p>Now, we have confirmation that the Sleeping Dogs movie <strong>is in production</strong>. It’s being pieced together by Story Kitchen, in collaboration with Square Enix, and Simu Liu, of MCU fame, is poised to star as the game’s protagonist, Wei Shen.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-it-took-you-long-enough">It Took You Long Enough</h2>



<p>Sleeping Dogs was one heck of a game when it was released in 2012. This gritty, crime-fuelled title put players in control of Wei Shen, an undercover police officer infiltrating the seedy, gang-driven underbelly of Hong Kong. It was seen as a solid GTA competitor, even if it was ultimately overshadowed by the release of Grand Theft Auto 5 just a year later.</p>



<p>Following a string of successful expansions, Sleeping Dogs was effectively laid to rest, and any hope of a sequel was extinguished as the years wore on. For almost a decade, fans have been toying with rumours and suggestions of a Sleeping Dogs movie surfacing, and <strong>now</strong>, we can say for certain that it is happening.</p>



<p>In a report <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-sleeping-dogs-movie-is-in-development-and-were-hearing-shang-chi-star-simu-liu-is-set-to-play-wei-shen" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">published by IGN</a>, it was revealed that Story Kitchen (Sonic the Hedgehog, Tomb Raider, Streets of Rage) is collaborating with Square Enix to produce a Sleeping Dogs movie. The production is set to star Simu Liu as the lead character, Wei Shen. That revelation hasn’t been met with much jubilation from fans worldwide, though.</p>



<p>On social media, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/sleeping-dogs-adaptation-and-sequel-mentioned-by-simu-liu/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Simu Liu mentioned</a> a ‘sequel game’ for Sleeping Dogs. In 2013, a proposed follow-up game was cancelled, with the original title’s developer going bust a couple of years later.</p>



<p>Do you plan on checking out the Sleeping Dogs movie when it’s released, or is Simu Liu’s involvement presenting an issue for you? Let us know on the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/far-cry-new-dawn-60-fps-upgrade/">Far Cry New Dawn is getting a 60 FPS upgrade</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Sleeping Dogs Movie IS in Development and We’re Hearing Shang-Chi Star Simu Liu Is Set to Play Wei Shen]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/the-sleeping-dogs-movie-is-in-development-and-were-hearing-shang-chi-star-simu-liu-is-set-to-play-wei-shen</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-sleeping-dogs-movie-is-in-development-and-we%E2%80%99re-hearing-shang-chi-star-simu-liu-is-set-to-play-wei-shen.1098000/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/the-sleeping-dogs-movie-is-in-development-and-were-hearing-shang-chi-star-simu-liu-is-set-to-play-wei-shen<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">This week, Marvel Cinematic Universe star Simu Liu got Sleeping Dogs fans excited when he tweeted to say <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/marvel-star-simu-liu-says-hes-working-to-get-sleeping-dogs-a-film-adaptation">he was working with the rights holders to bring the much-loved video game to the big screen</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It turns out things are a little further ahead than that. A source close to the project has told IGN that the Sleeping Dogs movie <em>is </em>in development, and we’re hearing Simu Liu, who plays Shang-Chi in <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/movies/shang-chi-and-the-legend-of-the-ten-rings">Shang-Chi and the Legend of the Ten Rings</a>, is producing and set to play the lead role of Wei Shen.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">IGN has asked Square Enix for comment.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/sleeping-dogs">Sleeping Dogs</a> was first released in 2012 on PlayStation 3, Xbox 360, and PC and tells the story of detective Wei Shen as he infiltrates one of Hong Kong's notorious Triad crime syndicates. While it failed to meet publisher Square Enix's lofty sales expectations, it is much-loved by fans and sequel hopes have followed it ever since.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/02/01/sleeping-dogs-1738448345955.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Sleeping Dogs is set for a wake-up call with a movie adaptation. Image credit: Square Enix.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2017/03/03/donnie-yen-to-star-in-sleeping-dogs-video-game-adaptation"><u>The original adaptation was announced in 2017</u></a> with Donnie Yen set to star, but <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2018/02/05/sleeping-dogs-movie-donnie-yen-confirms-its-still-in-production"><u>the film disappeared a year later</u></a> and, just a few weeks ago, Yen himself confirmed it had been scrapped.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“I spent a lot of time and did a lot of work with these producers, and I even invested some of my own money into obtaining the drafts and some of the rights," Yen told <a href="https://www.polygon.com/action/506279/sleeping-dogs-movie-donnie-yen-release-update" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Polygon</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"I waited for years. Years. And I really want to do it. I have all these visions in my head, and unfortunately… I don’t know, you know how Hollywood goes, right? I spent many, many years on it. It was an unfortunate thing. Well, on to better things."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">So when Liu tweeted to say he was working to make the Sleeping Dogs movie a reality, there was a degree of confusion among fans. Liu himself followed up with <a href="https://x.com/SimuLiu/status/1885252869483340236" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">another statement</a> that added fuel to the fire, and even revealed his intention to help bring a Sleeping Dogs video game sequel to life.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“So few film projects make it from pitch phase to greenlight,” he said. “Pitching execs who don’t understand the game has been tiring. Everyone’s overwhelming love of Sleeping Dogs here has really given us life!</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“First a movie, then a sequel game for everyone… that’s always been the dream.”</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Shang-Chi and the Legend of the Ten Rings: Who's Who in the Cast</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">IGN can reveal that Story Kitchen is leading the Sleeping Dogs live action feature film project, with Square Enix the rights holder in question. Story Kitchen has form when it comes to video game adaptations, having worked on everything from the Sonic the Hedgehog films to Netflix’s animated Tomb Raider series. It’s currently working on the upcoming Streets of Rage adaptation and an adaptation of It Takes Two for Amazon.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Last year, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/just-cause-movie-announced-with-blue-beetle-director-at-the-helm">Story Kitchen announced a film adaptation of Square Enix's Just Cause</a>, with Blue Beetle director Ángel Manuel Soto signed on. IGN understands the Sleeping Dogs project has a writer and major filmmaker attached to the project, but there’s no release date or word on when production will begin just yet.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The movie marks a significant revival for Sleeping Dogs, which saw its video game sequel canceled in late 2013 before it entered production, and its original developer, United Front Games, shut down three years later. Now, over a decade later, Sleeping Dogs could finally be set for a wake-up call.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokemon Go February 2025 Events: Raids, Spotlight Hours, Community Day, And More]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/pokemon-go-february-2025-events-raids-spotlight-hours-community-day-and-more/1100-6529181/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pokemon-go-february-2025-events-raids-spotlight-hours-community-day-and-more.1097943/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/pokemon-go-february-2025-events-raids-spotlight-hours-community-day-and-more/1100-6529181/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529181">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>A new month has begun, and that means a variety of new events are on the horizon for <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/pokemon-go/" data-ref-id="5000-449545">Pokemon Go</a>. The mobile game is closing out its Dual Destiny season with several big activities in February, including a Hoopa Unbound Raid Day and a Road to Unova event leading up to the Pokemon Go Tour: Unova celebration early next month.</p><p>On top of that, the game will feature new Spotlight Hours and raid bosses this month, as well as a special Community Day starring two Pokemon. You can see all of the biggest Pokemon Go events happening in February below.</p><div data-embed-type="toc"><p><span><strong>Table of Contents</strong> [<a data-toggle="collapse" href="#toc_list">hide</a>]</span></p><ul id="toc_list"><li><a href="#February_Raid_Schedule">February Raid Schedule</a><ul><li><a href="#Max_Battles">Max Battles</a></li><li><a href="#Five_star_Raids">Five-star Raids</a></li><li><a href="#Mega_Raids">Mega Raids</a></li><li><a href="#Shadow_Raids">Shadow Raids</a></li></ul></li><li><a href="#February_Spotlight_Hours">February Spotlight Hours</a></li><li><a href="#Small_Yet_Strong">Small Yet Strong</a><ul><li><a href="#Wild_Pokemon">Wild Pokemon</a></li><li><a href="#Eggs">Eggs</a></li></ul></li><li><a href="#February_Community_Day">February Community Day</a></li><li><a href="#Beloved_Buddies">Beloved Buddies</a></li><li><a href="#Hoopa_Unbound_Raid_Day">Hoopa Unbound Raid Day</a></li><li><a href="#Scattered_To_The_Winds">Scattered To The Winds</a></li><li><a href="#Road_To_Unova">Road To Unova</a><ul><li><a href="#Wild_Pokemon">Wild Pokemon</a></li><li><a href="#Eggs">Eggs</a></li><li><a href="#Raids">Raids</a></li></ul></li><li><a href="#Pokemon_Go_Tour__Unova_Global">Pokemon Go Tour: Unova Global</a></li></ul></div><h2 id="February_Raid_Schedule">February Raid Schedule</h2><p>Pokemon Go is refreshing its raid rotation once again in February.</p><p>A handful of legendary Pokemon are returning to five-star raids this month, including the Hisuian legendary Enamorus and the cover monsters from Pokemon X and Y, Xerneas and Yveltal. Mega Raids, meanwhile, will feature Mega Tyranitar and Mega Garchomp, while Shadow Regirock will appear in special Shadow Raids every weekend this month.</p><p>You can see February's full raid schedule below:</p><h3 id="Max_Battles">Max Battles</h3><p><strong>February 3-10</strong></p><ul><li>Squirtle</li><li>Machop</li><li>Krabby</li><li>Moltres</li><li>Sobble</li></ul><p><strong>February 10-17</strong></p><ul><li>Machop</li><li>Cryogonal</li><li>Scorbunny</li><li>Skwovet</li><li>Falinks</li></ul><p><strong>February 17-24</strong></p><ul><li>Machop</li><li>Pidove</li><li>Grookey</li><li>Falinks</li></ul><p><strong>February 24-March 3</strong></p><ul><li>Pidove</li><li>Darumaka</li><li>Sobble</li></ul><p><strong>March 3-4</strong></p><ul><li>Gastly</li><li>Beldum</li><li>Pidove</li><li>Darumaka</li><li>Sobble</li></ul><h3 id="Five_star_Raids">Five-star Raids</h3><p><strong>January 24-February 6</strong></p><ul><li>Dialga</li></ul><p><strong>February 6-17</strong></p><ul><li>Enamorus (Incarnate Forme)</li></ul><p><strong>February 17-24</strong></p><ul><li>Yveltal</li><li>Xerneas</li></ul><h3 id="Mega_Raids">Mega Raids</h3><p><strong>January 24-February 6</strong></p><ul><li>Mega Medicham</li></ul><p><strong>February 6-17</strong></p><ul><li>Mega Tyranitar</li></ul><p><strong>February 17-March 4</strong></p><ul><li>Mega Garchomp</li></ul><h3 id="Shadow_Raids">Shadow Raids</h3><p><strong>Weekends in February</strong></p><ul><li>Shadow Regirock</li></ul><h2 id="February_Spotlight_Hours">February Spotlight Hours</h2><p>Pokemon Go's weekly Spotlight Hour events roll on in February with a new selection of featured Pokemon and bonuses.</p><p>Every Tuesday evening from 6-7 PM local time, a particular species of Pokemon will be appearing more frequently in the wild, making this a good opportunity to fill out your Pokedex and stock up on candy. Not only that, but you'll also earn an extra bonus during that hour, such as double XP for evolving Pokemon.</p><p>You can see February's Spotlight Hour schedule below:</p><p><strong>February 4</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Featured Pokemon:</strong> Carvanha</li><li><strong>Bonus:</strong> 2x evolution XP</li></ul><p><strong>February 11</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Featured Pokemon:</strong> Luvdisc</li><li><strong>Bonus:</strong> 2x catch Stardust</li></ul><p><strong>February 18</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Featured Pokemon:</strong> Inkay</li><li><strong>Bonus:</strong> 2x catch XP</li></ul><p><strong>February 25</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Featured Pokemon:</strong> Snivy, Tepig, and Oshawott</li><li><strong>Bonus:</strong> 2x catch candy</li></ul><h2 id="Small_Yet_Strong">Small Yet Strong</h2><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/scale_super/1578/15787979/4436867-6030256254-0rw05blVIduo5qMwnbVXpa-dvyuZwOC5Mn9cIlCq_xSM8qlxtk0rWN6_AWGO455_MeC6uX2NSuqQJsN2b_wNRHdQQ8_XFod12Fn4ynkfjlXEXcs%3Dw1440-e365.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4436867" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1440" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/scale_super/1578/15787979/4436867-6030256254-0rw05blVIduo5qMwnbVXpa-dvyuZwOC5Mn9cIlCq_xSM8qlxtk0rWN6_AWGO455_MeC6uX2NSuqQJsN2b_wNRHdQQ8_XFod12Fn4ynkfjlXEXcs%3Dw1440-e365.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4436867"></a><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/scale_super/1578/15787979/4436867-6030256254-0rw05blVIduo5qMwnbVXpa-dvyuZwOC5Mn9cIlCq_xSM8qlxtk0rWN6_AWGO455_MeC6uX2NSuqQJsN2b_wNRHdQQ8_XFod12Fn4ynkfjlXEXcs%3Dw1440-e365.jpg"></figure><p>Pokemon Go is kicking February off with a <a href="https://pokemongolive.com/post/small-yet-strong-2025?hl=en" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Small Yet Strong</a> event from <strong>February 5-8</strong>.</p><p>Throughout the event, tiny Pokemon like Natu, Burmy, Joltik, and Nymble will be appearing more frequently in the wild, and you'll have your first opportunity to catch a shiny Nymble in the game. On top of that, you'll have an increased chance of encountering XXS and XXL Pokemon.</p><p>Along with the featured Pokemon, the game will offer new, event-themed Timed and Field Research tasks to complete, as well as a new Collection Challenge. A few other bonuses will also be active throughout the event, including double XP for catching Pokemon.</p><h3 id="Wild_Pokemon">Wild Pokemon</h3><ul><li>Red Flower Flabebe (Europe, Middle East, and Africa)</li><li>Blue Flower Flabebe (Asia-Pacific region)</li><li>Yellow Flower Flabebe (Americas)</li><li>Paras</li><li>Natu</li><li>Plant Cloak Burmy</li><li>Sandy Cloak Burmy</li><li>Trash Cloak Burmy</li><li>Joltik</li><li>Tynamo</li><li>Nymble</li></ul><h3 id="Eggs">Eggs</h3><p><strong>2 km</strong></p><ul><li>Togepi</li><li>Azurill</li><li>Budew</li><li>Chingling</li><li>Espurr</li><li>Dedenne</li></ul><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1578/15787979/4436872-2496672624-mRutHT9NomAzXn64ywfhafOoOXRpNDKsrEVnSKMYPEUlfdqpQ2DSwwah3oJ9hL_9AJ3MOulfY1A02KvFImAHI-KqjPTJlN_icgjL6bx4ShfaXw%3Dw1440-e365.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4436872" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1440" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1578/15787979/4436872-2496672624-mRutHT9NomAzXn64ywfhafOoOXRpNDKsrEVnSKMYPEUlfdqpQ2DSwwah3oJ9hL_9AJ3MOulfY1A02KvFImAHI-KqjPTJlN_icgjL6bx4ShfaXw%3Dw1440-e365.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4436872"></a><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1578/15787979/4436872-2496672624-mRutHT9NomAzXn64ywfhafOoOXRpNDKsrEVnSKMYPEUlfdqpQ2DSwwah3oJ9hL_9AJ3MOulfY1A02KvFImAHI-KqjPTJlN_icgjL6bx4ShfaXw%3Dw1440-e365.jpg"></figure><p>Pokemon Go's <a href="https://pokemongolive.com/post/communityday-february-2025-karrablast-shelmet?hl=en" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">February Community Day</a> is set for <strong>February 9</strong>, and this time, there are two featured Pokemon: Shelmet and Karrablast.</p><p>From 2-5 PM local time, both featured Pokemon will be appearing in the wild much more frequently, and you'll have an increased chance of encountering shiny versions of them.</p><p>On top of that, various bonuses will be available throughout the event. Any Lure Modules or Incense that you use will last for three hours rather than their usual duration, and you'll earn triple XP and double candy for catching Pokemon. In addition, trades will cost 50 percent less Stardust than usual, and you can make up to two Special Trades for the day.</p><p>Finally, both featured Pokemon will be able to learn an exclusive move as long as you evolve them before February 16, 10 PM local time. Any Shelmet that you evolve into Accelgor during that time will learn the Charged Attack Energy Ball, while any Karrablast that you evolve into Escavalier will learn the Charged Attack Razor Shell.</p><h2 id="Beloved_Buddies">Beloved Buddies</h2><p>Pokemon Go is keeping the festivities rolling with a new event called Beloved Buddies, which is set to run from <strong>February 11-15</strong>. Additional details will be announced closer to the event.</p><h2 id="Hoopa_Unbound_Raid_Day">Hoopa Unbound Raid Day</h2><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1578/15787979/4436875-2440172656-Bsi9IQU-IpS8dq1joxP5Zak_dp0NHn5z7X-C7Ubi6Itc0gLxEybbNxSuBKu_NSJzI9HAJ-twsqRjF1ox4tUD3a5ouH-THGXyJV8hjjGm7Bx_ww%3Dw1440-e365.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4436875" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1440" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1578/15787979/4436875-2440172656-Bsi9IQU-IpS8dq1joxP5Zak_dp0NHn5z7X-C7Ubi6Itc0gLxEybbNxSuBKu_NSJzI9HAJ-twsqRjF1ox4tUD3a5ouH-THGXyJV8hjjGm7Bx_ww%3Dw1440-e365.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4436875"></a><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1578/15787979/4436875-2440172656-Bsi9IQU-IpS8dq1joxP5Zak_dp0NHn5z7X-C7Ubi6Itc0gLxEybbNxSuBKu_NSJzI9HAJ-twsqRjF1ox4tUD3a5ouH-THGXyJV8hjjGm7Bx_ww%3Dw1440-e365.jpg"></figure><p>Pokemon Go is giving players another chance to catch the legendary Pokemon Hoopa with a special <a href="https://pokemongolive.com/post/hoopa-raid-day-2025?hl=en" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Hoopa Unbound Raid Day</a> on <strong>February 15</strong>.</p><p>From 2-5 PM local time, Hoopa Unbound will be appearing more frequently in five-star raids, giving you another opportunity to add one to your collection. Additionally, the game will give out up to five extra free Raid Passes when you spin the Photo Disc at Gyms, and the Remote Raid Pass limit is temporarily being increased to 20 for the event.</p><p>Finally, a new, paid event ticket will be on sale in the item shop for $5. Players who purchase the ticket will earn additional bonuses during the event, including 50 percent more XP and double Stardust from Raid Battles.</p><h2 id="Scattered_To_The_Winds">Scattered To The Winds</h2><p>Another new event called Scattered to the Winds is slated to take place from <strong>February 18-20</strong>. More details will be announced later this month.</p><h2 id="Road_To_Unova">Road To Unova</h2><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1578/15787979/4437171-9092417504-PxULmNIIhYqZjtXbesoZ08g6JYMCC6VHxK7RJjGArL6c64hdkx0ufyYXhV5zA2Mzf0-4uaMZ5BZY0IOPjAOK-luPovPpp2OwPjOFShrcjrbV_w%3Dw1440-e365.png" data-ref-id="1300-4437171" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1440" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1578/15787979/4437171-9092417504-PxULmNIIhYqZjtXbesoZ08g6JYMCC6VHxK7RJjGArL6c64hdkx0ufyYXhV5zA2Mzf0-4uaMZ5BZY0IOPjAOK-luPovPpp2OwPjOFShrcjrbV_w%3Dw1440-e365.png" data-ref-id="1300-4437171"></a><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1578/15787979/4437171-9092417504-PxULmNIIhYqZjtXbesoZ08g6JYMCC6VHxK7RJjGArL6c64hdkx0ufyYXhV5zA2Mzf0-4uaMZ5BZY0IOPjAOK-luPovPpp2OwPjOFShrcjrbV_w%3Dw1440-e365.png"></figure><p>Pokemon Go is gearing up for its global Unova Tour next month with a <a href="https://pokemongolive.com/post/road-to-unova-event?hl=en" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Road to Unova</a> event from <strong>February 24-March 1</strong>.</p><p>Throughout the event, a variety of Pokemon originally from the Unova region will be appearing more frequently in the wild. Different Unova legendary Pokemon like Genesect, Reshiram, and Zekrom will also appear in raids each day of the event.</p><p>Additionally, there will be free Timed Research tasks to complete, as well as various paid tickets that offer extra perks. A few bonuses will also be active throughout the event. Eggs that are placed in incubators will hatch at half the distance they typically require, and the Remote Raid Pass limit will be temporarily increased to 20.</p><h3 id="Wild_Pokemon">Wild Pokemon</h3><ul><li>Snivy</li><li>Servine</li><li>Tepig</li><li>Pignite</li><li>Oshawott</li><li>Dewott</li></ul><h3 id="Eggs">Eggs</h3><p><strong>2 km</strong></p><ul><li>Roggenrola</li><li>Timburr</li><li>Karrablast</li><li>Shelmet</li><li>Larvesta</li></ul><h3 id="Raids">Raids</h3><p><strong>One-star</strong></p><ul><li>Snivy</li><li>Tepig</li><li>Oshawott</li></ul><p><strong>Three-star</strong></p><ul><li>Druddigon</li></ul><p><strong>Five-star</strong></p><p>February 24</p><ul><li>Genesect</li><li>Genesect (Shock Drive)</li><li>Genesect (Burn Drive)</li><li>Genesect (Chill Drive)</li><li>Genesect (Douse Drive)</li></ul><p>February 25</p><ul><li>Cobalion</li><li>Terrakion</li><li>Virizion</li></ul><p>February 26</p><ul><li>Therian Forme Tornadus</li><li>Therian Forme Thundurus</li><li>Therian Forme Landorus</li></ul><p>February 27</p><ul><li>Reshiram</li></ul><p>February 28</p><ul><li>Zekrom</li></ul><h2 id="Pokemon_Go_Tour__Unova_Global">Pokemon Go Tour: Unova Global</h2><p>The global Pokemon Go Tour: Unova event takes place <strong>March 1-2</strong>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[INTERVIEW: FaZe aBeZy and Cellium Talk Dominance – ‘No One Can Beat Us’]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/interview-faze-abezy-cellium-madrid-major/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/interview-faze-abezy-and-cellium-talk-dominance-%E2%80%93-%E2%80%98no-one-can-beat-us%E2%80%99.1097925/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/interview-faze-abezy-cellium-madrid-major/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Atlanta FaZe just secured a 3 – 0 victory over Toronto Ultra to push one step forward at the CDL Madrid Major. The massive victory forced Ultra into the elimination bracket to square off against the Royal Ravens – their last chance at staying in the running.</p>



<p>Following the sweep of a match, I sat down with Atlanta FaZe’s Tyler ‘aBeZy’ Pharris and McArthur ‘Cellium’ Jovel to talk about their nine-game win streak, playing more aggressively this season, and how they bounced back from a rough start.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-i-was-underperforming">‘I Was Underperforming’</h2>



<p>Atlanta FaZe didn’t have the cleanest start to the 2025 CDL season. The squad suffered a 0 – 3 loss in a qualifying stage for the first time since May 2023. That decisive defeat was handed down by the Carolina Royal Ravens, a team that has been on fire so far in 2025.</p>



<p>From there, FaZe lost three matches back-to-back-to-back before taking a break and turning things around. Presently, the team is on a near-historic nine-match win streak, almost refusing to drop a map in any series.</p>



<p>I caught up with Cellium and aBeZy to chat about the change-up:</p>



<p><em><strong>Cellium: </strong>For me personally, I was underperforming really badly. There were a lot of internal team talks about how we play the game and how we think about everything, and I think it definitely helped us improve over the break. Everyone is on the same page now and we trust each other.</em></p>



<p><em><strong>aBeZy: </strong>We had a team talk after the break, leading after the Falcons match that we won. We put everything on the table and after that, we’ve just been firing on all cylinders. Like he said, we just trust each other in every situation that we’re in and we’re just frying.</em></p>



<p>The talk turned to a recent comment made by Drazah, who wasn’t present for the chat. He’d previously said that ATL would take on ‘anyone, anytime’, suggesting the strategy had now turned to aggression. I asked aBeZy and Cellium if that was the case:</p>



<p><em><strong>aBeZy: </strong>Yeah, 100%. I don’t think it matters who we play. I feel like if we’re playing at our best, I feel like no one can beat us.</em></p>



<p>Cellium mirrored that sentiment, echoing with the claim: <em>‘I just think we’re the best team right now, by a mile.’</em></p>



<p>For the third time in two days, I asked the Call of Duty League pros what they thought about the crowds supporting the tournament here in Madrid. Thus far, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/optic-shotzzy-wants-more-eu-majors-thanks-to-madrid-crowd/">OpTic Texas</a> and LA Thieves have agreed that the EU crowds are on another level compared to NA, and that was supported by the Atlanta FaZe guys:</p>



<p><em><strong>aBeZy</strong>: I think EU crowds are insane … Even this crowd is <strong>crazy</strong>.</em></p>



<p><em><strong>Cellium: </strong>Both times I’ve went to Europe so far, it has been amazing. I would use the EU crowd is insane.</em></p>



<p>Atlanta FaZe now pushes into the winner’s final against the LA Thieves, which is set to take place tomorrow evening. The loser of that match will be pushed down into the elimination bracket for a final chance to go forward, and they’ll be taking on either Toronto, Carolina, Miami, or Minnesota.</p>



<p>For more coverage of the Madrid Major, check out my interview <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/lat-scrap-and-ghosty-interview-cdl-super-team/">with LA Thieves’ Scrap and Ghosty</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>Stay tuned to Insider Gaming for more of the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/category/esports/">latest esports news</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[INTERVIEW: LAT Scrap and Ghosty on Being The CDL’s ‘Godlike’ Super Team]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/lat-scrap-and-ghosty-interview-cdl-super-team/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/interview-lat-scrap-and-ghosty-on-being-the-cdl%E2%80%99s-%E2%80%98godlike%E2%80%99-super-team.1097907/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/lat-scrap-and-ghosty-interview-cdl-super-team/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>The LA Thieves just destroyed the Miami Heretics on (sort of) home turf, pushing them down into the elimination bracket following a complete sweep. The 3 – 0 scoreline was probably easy enough to predict, but it came a little closer than some would have expected, with the Heretics putting up a considerable fight.</p>



<p>In the aftermath of the win, which pushed LA Thieves further towards the grand final, I caught up with Dan ‘Ghosty’ Rothe and Thomas ‘Scrap’ Ernst to learn how they were handling the expectations of being the CDL’s ‘Super Team’ this season.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-shouldering-it">Shouldering It</h2>



<p>For the opener, I asked Scrap and Ghosty whether they felt extra pressure trying to live up to these lofty expectations and whether they believed they <strong>had</strong>. In the run-up to the CDL kicking off, the LA Thieves’ squad was billed as being a Super Team, with Nadeshot making it very public (even if in jest) just how much securing the talented roster had cost the organisation.</p>



<p>Here’s what they had to say:</p>



<p><em><strong>Ghosty: </strong>I feel like there’s always a sense of pressure as a competitor to be the best version you can be. There’s definitely more external pressure from other teams, fans, whatever – but it still doesn’t amount to the personal pressure you put on yourself as a competitor.</em></p>



<p><em><strong>Scrap: </strong>For myself, from how much shit I talk, there’s just pressure from the whole community on me, no matter what team I play for. People can call us a Super Team, yeah, I’ll call myself a Super Team because <strong>my team is godlike</strong>. You know, we have pressure on us, but we go into every match taking no-one lightly.</em></p>



<p>Following that, Scrap walked me through his growth in the CDL since entering the League as a rookie during the MWII season. He was painted as (and loved being) the villain, going on a notorious arc that set his profile ablaze.</p>



<p><em><strong>Scrap: </strong>I don’t think I’ll ever change. Honestly, I’m just being myself up on that stage, to be honest. If it comes out, it comes out. I feel like over the past couple of years in the League I’ve grown into more of a leadership role of a sort, not like the kid that just flies around. Now that I’m on a younger team that has a lot of young players and I’m just trying to work as best around them.</em></p>



<p>Like <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/optic-shotzzy-wants-more-eu-majors-thanks-to-madrid-crowd/">OpTic Texas’ Shotzzy</a>, the pair agreed that the crowd in Madrid is one of the most energetic they’ve ever seen, and they are ‘down for some more’ EU tournaments.</p>



<p>For more news from the Call of Duty League’s Major in Madrid, check out my coverage of <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/royal-ravens-dominate-cdl-major-i/">the Royal Ravens eliminating OpTic Texas</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/category/esports/">esports news</a>, stay tuned to Insider Gaming</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[There's A Great New RPG On Game Pass And A Fantastic New Dungeon Crawler On Steam]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/eternal-strands-great-dungeon-crawlers-pokemon-pocket-1851752787</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/theres-a-great-new-rpg-on-game-pass-and-a-fantastic-new-dungeon-crawler-on-steam.1097889/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/eternal-strands-great-dungeon-crawlers-pokemon-pocket-1851752787<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><figure id="" data-id="dcccb6cbd6947a14d6ba481b5b43fd92" data-recommend-id="image://dcccb6cbd6947a14d6ba481b5b43fd92" data-format="jpg" data-width="1280" data-height="720" data-lightbox="false" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="false" data-imagerights="in-house-art" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Papertip Studio / Buried Treasure<!-- -->, <!-- -->Yellow Brick Games<!-- -->, <!-- -->Warner Bros. / Kotaku<!-- -->, <!-- -->Creatures, Inc. / DeNA<!-- -->, <!-- -->Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Blizzard Entertainment<!-- -->, <!-- -->Blizzard Entertainment<!-- -->, <!-- -->Marvel</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="dcccb6cbd6947a14d6ba481b5b43fd92" data-recommend-id="image://dcccb6cbd6947a14d6ba481b5b43fd92" data-format="jpg" data-width="1280" data-height="720" data-lightbox="false" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>This week, our roundup of takes includes a recommendation for a very cool new RPG on Game Pass and an even stronger rec for a new dungeon crawler on Steam. Also, we look at what certain reactions to a new <em>Superman </em>TV spot reveal about how some fans relate to movies nowadays, and see why the trading system in <em>Pokémon TCG Pocket </em>has fans so upset. Read on for all this and more.</p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="0403cc58d807815299f575cb7553a4ae" data-recommend-id="image://0403cc58d807815299f575cb7553a4ae" data-format="jpg" data-width="2560" data-height="1440" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A swarm of beetles and bugs issue from an enemy toward our character, in a tiresomely brown room." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A swarm of beetles and bugs issue from an enemy toward our character, in a tiresomely brown room." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Papertip Studio / Buried Treasure</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="0403cc58d807815299f575cb7553a4ae" data-recommend-id="image://0403cc58d807815299f575cb7553a4ae" data-format="jpg" data-width="2560" data-height="1440" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A swarm of beetles and bugs issue from an enemy toward our character, in a tiresomely brown room." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>This feels too good to be true! How can it possibly be that I’m about to be the person to tell you there’s a new contender for the <em>Legend of Grimrock</em> throne? How is this not already the talk of the gaming town? Seriously, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://store.steampowered.com/app/2918410/Tower_of_Mask/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2918410/Tower_of_Mask/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Tower of Mask</em></a></span> is a fantastic <em>Dungeon Master</em>-like with incredible combat, and one that deserves to become very big. - John Walker <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/tower-of-mask-legend-of-grimrock-dungeon-crawler-review-1851748174&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/tower-of-mask-legend-of-grimrock-dungeon-crawler-review-1851748174">Read More</a></span></p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="1a2956f143580f898f65e2febc8492ed" data-recommend-id="image://1a2956f143580f898f65e2febc8492ed" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A screenshot shows a woman in armor running from a dragon in the sky. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A screenshot shows a woman in armor running from a dragon in the sky. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Yellow Brick Games</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="1a2956f143580f898f65e2febc8492ed" data-recommend-id="image://1a2956f143580f898f65e2febc8492ed" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A screenshot shows a woman in armor running from a dragon in the sky. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>As a massive dragon-like drake hurled fireballs at me, I fired arrows back while dodging the projectiles. And I did a good job. None of them got me! But they did hit the wooden scaffolding I was standing on. Seconds later, it was burning and collapsing. And I was very high up. So I hopped down to a part that wasn’t on fire, turned around, and used my magical powers to grab a piece of the burning scaffolding and launched it back at the monster, doing enough damage to kill it. I felt extremely cool in that moment. Then I ran across a piece of debris that had landed on the platform and my character’s physics got weird and I fell off the tower to the ground below, where I stood alive, but damaged. Just another day in<em> </em><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/games/eternal-strands&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/games/eternal-strands"><em>Eternal Strands</em></a></span>, a sometimes wonky, but ambitious and fun action adventure RPG.  - Zack Zwiezen <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/eternal-strands-game-pass-laidlaw-open-world-zelda-ps5-1851748657&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/eternal-strands-game-pass-laidlaw-open-world-zelda-ps5-1851748657">Read More</a></span></p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="90014250b71920b27347ad65e7eecb84" data-recommend-id="image://90014250b71920b27347ad65e7eecb84" data-format="jpg" data-width="1764" data-height="992" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Superman flies toward the camera, surrounded by ice, his eyes looking slightly in two directions." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Superman flies toward the camera, surrounded by ice, his eyes looking slightly in two directions." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Warner Bros. / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="90014250b71920b27347ad65e7eecb84" data-recommend-id="image://90014250b71920b27347ad65e7eecb84" data-format="jpg" data-width="1764" data-height="992" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Superman flies toward the camera, surrounded by ice, his eyes looking slightly in two directions." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>There’s little that can spoil a game, film, book, or show more than its loudest fans. I’m reminded of this by the utterly bizarre reaction to the most recent <em>Superman</em> TV spot, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/JamesGunn/status/1883606788249206932&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/JamesGunn/status/1883606788249206932" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">shared by James Gunn</a></span> and responded to by those who purport to be the movie’s future audience as if he’s committed a war crime. Stop it! Everyone just stop it! You’re liking things all wrong, and it’s ruining it for everyone. - John Walker <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/superman-teaser-flying-james-gunn-cg-eyes-1851749084&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/superman-teaser-flying-james-gunn-cg-eyes-1851749084">Read More</a></span></p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="6c127592cce96173133e317724734c23" data-recommend-id="image://6c127592cce96173133e317724734c23" data-format="png" data-width="1080" data-height="607" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Pokemon TCG players trade a Raichu for a Taurus. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Pokemon TCG players trade a Raichu for a Taurus. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Creatures, Inc. / DeNA</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="6c127592cce96173133e317724734c23" data-recommend-id="image://6c127592cce96173133e317724734c23" data-format="png" data-width="1080" data-height="607" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Pokemon TCG players trade a Raichu for a Taurus. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Good news! You can finally trade cards with friends in <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/pokemon-tcg-pocket-impressions-gacha-mobile-card-game-1851686829&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-tcg-pocket-impressions-gacha-mobile-card-game-1851686829"><em>Pokémon TCG Pocket</em></a></span>. Bad news! It sucks. It feels even more limited and backwards than when it was originally teased, and fans are in full revolt over the long-anticipated feature’s completely bungled rollout.  - Ethan Gach <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/pokemon-tcg-pocket-how-trades-work-tokens-crown-rare-1851750299&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-tcg-pocket-how-trades-work-tokens-crown-rare-1851750299">Read More</a></span></p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="b079e5ce415fe88fb30538bfbc204550" data-recommend-id="image://b079e5ce415fe88fb30538bfbc204550" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Lucio wears the Cyber DJ skin." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Lucio wears the Cyber DJ skin." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Blizzard Entertainment</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="b079e5ce415fe88fb30538bfbc204550" data-recommend-id="image://b079e5ce415fe88fb30538bfbc204550" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Lucio wears the Cyber DJ skin." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>On January 29, Blizzard announced it would be holding an <em>Overwatch 2 </em>Spotlight event next month <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-spotlight-date-time-where-watch-marvel-1851751740&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-spotlight-date-time-where-watch-marvel-1851751740">to reveal “groundbreaking changes”</a></span> to the hero shooter after about two months of <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/marvel-rivals-review-hero-shooter-overwatch-netease-1851717975&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/marvel-rivals-review-hero-shooter-overwatch-netease-1851717975"><em>Marvel Rivals</em></a></span><em> </em>eating its lunch. The announcement included confirmation that the support hero Lucio’s Cyber DJ legendary skin would be made available as a free Twitch drop next month as part of the event. That sounds all well and good, right? Well, the problem is the Cyber DJ skin was made available for purchase in the store a day <em>before</em> the announcement, and those who already paid up are less thrilled. - Kenneth Shepard <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/livid-overwatch-2-fans-are-asking-for-refunds-after-pai-1851752055&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/livid-overwatch-2-fans-are-asking-for-refunds-after-pai-1851752055">Read More</a></span></p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="fb0dc7e15f3f97b7b7b2f7960c45faaa" data-recommend-id="image://fb0dc7e15f3f97b7b7b2f7960c45faaa" data-format="jpg" data-width="3840" data-height="2160" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Kiriko holds her charm and kunai while standing on a rooftop." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Kiriko holds her charm and kunai while standing on a rooftop." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Blizzard Entertainment</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="fb0dc7e15f3f97b7b7b2f7960c45faaa" data-recommend-id="image://fb0dc7e15f3f97b7b7b2f7960c45faaa" data-format="jpg" data-width="3840" data-height="2160" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Kiriko holds her charm and kunai while standing on a rooftop." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Blizzard has announced it’s holding a big blowout event for <em>Overwatch 2 </em>next month. The <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://overwatch.blizzard.com/en-us/news/24173039/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://overwatch.blizzard.com/en-us/news/24173039/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Overwatch 2 </em>Spotlight</a></span> showcase will take place on February 12 at 10 a.m. Pacific/1 p.m. Eastern and will unveil “groundbreaking changes to the PvP experience that will be unlike anything you’ve seen before,” as well as new maps, playable heroes, and more. We won’t know what that means for a couple of weeks. Still, given that Blizzard <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/blizzcon-2024-diablo-warcraft-overwatch-war-within-1851436455&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/blizzcon-2024-diablo-warcraft-overwatch-war-within-1851436455">didn’t hold its annual Blizzcon event in 2024</a></span>, I imagine this is the <em>Overwatch 2</em> team’s chance to regain the lost promo time they didn’t get last year. But something else has happened in the months since Blizzcon would have taken place that has shaken Blizzard’s mostly uncontested spot as the hero shooter king: It now has real competition in <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/marvel-rivals-review-hero-shooter-overwatch-netease-1851717975&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/marvel-rivals-review-hero-shooter-overwatch-netease-1851717975"><em>Marvel Rivals</em></a></span>. - Kenneth Shepard <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-spotlight-date-time-where-watch-marvel-1851751740&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-spotlight-date-time-where-watch-marvel-1851751740">Read More</a></span></p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="48f012732174e727ee9de78696ac0168" data-recommend-id="image://48f012732174e727ee9de78696ac0168" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="The Fantastic Four rides through New York City." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="The Fantastic Four rides through New York City." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Marvel</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="48f012732174e727ee9de78696ac0168" data-recommend-id="image://48f012732174e727ee9de78696ac0168" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="The Fantastic Four rides through New York City." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/marvel-rivals-review-hero-shooter-overwatch-netease-1851717975?_gl=1*1p4rase*_ga*MTMxODc3NjkwMi4xNzI1Njc2NzM3*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczODA5MzUxMS4xMjMuMS4xNzM4MDkzNTM4LjMzLjAuMA..&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/marvel-rivals-review-hero-shooter-overwatch-netease-1851717975?_gl=1*1p4rase*_ga*MTMxODc3NjkwMi4xNzI1Njc2NzM3*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczODA5MzUxMS4xMjMuMS4xNzM4MDkzNTM4LjMzLjAuMA.."><em>Marvel Rivals</em></a></span><em> </em>has been given a lot of shit for its unapologetic poaching of <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-skins-characters-reddit-steam-2023-1851119014&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-skins-characters-reddit-steam-2023-1851119014"><em>Overwatch</em>’s ideas</a></span>. From the overall format down to individual hero’s kits, NetEase copiedBlizzard’s homework and didn’t try to change it much. That being said, it’s nice that <em>Overwatch 2</em> has a direct competitor to put its feet to the fire, and if both of these games must co-exist, they both can learn a lot from each other. Here are six things <em>Marvel Rivals </em>and <em>Overwatch 2 </em>should steal from each other. - Kenneth Shepard <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/marvel-rivals-overwatch-2-role-queue-cross-progression-1851749687&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/marvel-rivals-overwatch-2-role-queue-cross-progression-1851749687">Read More</a></span></p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BioWare staff "loaned" to other EA studios may not be returning, new report suggests]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/bioware-staff-loaned-to-other-ea-studios-may-not-be-returning-new-report-suggests</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/bioware-staff-loaned-to-other-ea-studios-may-not-be-returning-new-report-suggests.1097886/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/bioware-staff-loaned-to-other-ea-studios-may-not-be-returning-new-report-suggests<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div>
        

        <p>"If they want to work at BioWare again, they would have to look for job openings and re-apply."</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/The-Next-Mass-Effect---Official-Teaser-Trailer-1-20-screenshot.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>BioWare</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>A new report now suggests that some BioWare staff "loaned" to other EA studios will not be returning.</p>
<p>Earlier this week, amid reports of potential layoffs at BioWare, studio general manager <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/bioware-confirms-many-staff-moved-elsewhere-in-ea-as-core-team-focuses-on-mass-effect-5-in-downsized-studio">Gary McKay has confirmed "many" employees have now been moved elsewhere in EA</a> following the completion of <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/dragon-age-the-veilguard-walkthrough-tips-and-tricks-guide">Dragon Age: The Veilguard</a> - and that a remaining core team is fully focused on <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/mass-effect-5">Mass Effect 5</a>.</p>
<p>Now, however, <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/newsletters/2025-01-31/electronic-arts-slashes-bioware-after-dragon-age-sales-miss">Bloomberg</a> is reporting that the "loans" made by BioWare to support EA teams elsewhere have now "morphed into permanent relocations".</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="The Next Mass Effect - Official Teaser Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Lg-Ctg6k_Ao?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>The Next Mass Effect - Official Teaser Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Lg-Ctg6k_Ao?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/Lg-Ctg6k_Ao?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>A teaser trailer for the new Mass Effect shared in 2020.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Lg-Ctg6k_Ao" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>According to Bloomberg sources and "people familiar with what happened", staff are no longer BioWare employees "temporarily on assignment elsewhere" but, in fact, now work for whichever EA subsidiary had borrowed them.</p>
<p>"If they want to work at BioWare again in the future, they would have to look for job openings and re-apply," Bloomberg stated.</p>
<p>"This was an unwelcome development for some of the employees, who now find themselves on brand-new teams at studios they’d never planned to join. Some had come to BioWare to work on storied role-playing game franchises and found the idea of working on action or sports games less appealing."</p>
<p>This means BioWare has seemingly halved its 200 headcount to around 100 in just two years.</p>
<p>Dragon Age and <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/mass-effect">Mass Effect</a> veteran Trick Weekes is among a group of <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/bioware-veteran-writer-among-those-looking-for-work-after-post-dragon-age-the-veilguard-downsizing">BioWare veterans who recently announced they are now looking for work</a> <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/bioware-confirms-many-staff-moved-elsewhere-in-ea-as-core-team-focuses-on-mass-effect-5-in-downsized-studio">following the news that BioWare is downsizing</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[It took more than a decade for a surreal RPG to get its final translation]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/games/603938/off-rpg-translation-interview</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/it-took-more-than-a-decade-for-a-surreal-rpg-to-get-its-final-translation.1097880/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/games/603938/off-rpg-translation-interview<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>In 2008, Mortis Ghost made a game with his friend, composer Alias Conrad Coldwood. It was <a href="https://offtherpg.com/">a surreal roleplaying game about a baseball player fighting ghosts called <em>Off</em></a>. He shared it for free on a French-speaking forum, where it garnered a small audience. One player was a French artist who was inspired to make a piece of fan art, which she shared with her then-girlfriend. “I was very intrigued,” says Quinn K, now a writer and game developer. At the time, she was a 15-year-old living in Austria who had no idea how influential <em>Off</em> would be for her, nor she for <em>Off</em>.</p><p>After beating the game, K lay awake at night thinking about the ending. “Something had gotten its hooks in me,” she says. Wanting to show it to more friends, she resolved to translate the game from French to English — neither of which were her first language. “I wasn’t the right person for the job,” she says. “I was just the person that did it.”</p><p>Fan translation for games is often a tricky process, not just because of linguistics but also technical limitations and potential copyright claims by the original developers. But K knew it was possible to make her version work because there was already a partial translation, and when she contacted Ghost, he gave his approval. With the help of some friends in proofreading and asset creation, she put together a translation of the 10-ish-hour RPG by 2011. She posted it on the forums for a website called Starmen.net, which was popular among fans of the <em>Mother</em> / <em>EarthBound</em> series. K was partially inspired by a <em>Mother 3</em> translation, and other <em>Mother</em> fans quickly connected with the similar vibes in <em>Off</em>. </p><p>After the initial release, K put out an improved version in 2012. By 2013, <em>Off</em> was an “astonishing success,” says Ghost, with users who discovered it on the Starmen forums spreading it via fan creations like art and cosplay to DeviantArt and Tumblr. On the latter, it was the sixth-most-talked-about game of the year, behind major franchises like <em>Pok</em>é<em>mon</em>, <em>Animal Crossing</em>, <em>Kingdom Hearts</em>, <em>The Legend of Zelda</em>, and <em>Mass Effect</em>. Unlike those established hits, <em>Off</em> was free, spread only through word of mouth, and was still clearly finding a devoted audience.</p><p>Despite its popularity, K was aware that the translation wasn’t perfect. “A lot of people rip [it], and I get why,” she says. “It was full of very severe flaws, just born from the fact that I’m neither an English native speaker nor a French native speaker. So it was possible to make mistakes in both languages.” There were also other fans making their own translations or patches that added to K’s work. One of these, released in 2017 by artist <a href="https://ladysaytenn.art/">Lady Saytenn</a>, added an option for the player themselves to be referred to with they / them pronouns.</p><div><p>“It was full of very severe flaws”</p></div><p>“That inspired me so much,” says K. Having had a few years of space from <em>Off</em>, and having improved in both English and French as well as “grown a bit wiser as a person,” she embarked on making a third version of her translation. This time, she collaborated directly with Lady Saytenn, as well as another artist who created image assets, Rosie Brewster.</p><p>K categorizes the second translation as the one that “most millennials” have played, while the third reached a younger wave of fans. K says that she was actually surprised to find that many people who encountered <em>Off</em> through the third translation hold it in high regard because “back when it first came out, that translation was not particularly popular.”</p><p>Some changes were straightforward, like correcting pop culture references that K had been unaware of, as well as an error where she had interpreted the French word femme as “wife,” rather than “woman.” It can mean either, but K’s choice changed the implication of a key line, and Ghost let her know it wasn’t what he originally intended.</p><p>However, some fans felt that the newest translation was overly sanitized; K says she deliberately made some characters “a little less crass” since “a big sign of an inexperienced translator is swearing a lot.” She also removed an instance of the R-slur, which upset “some edgy people.” </p><p>More nuanced was the shift to clearer language and a tendency to stick more closely to the original lines. The 2.0 translation had been vague and sometimes confusing in a way that players appreciated; it seemed to reflect the atmosphere of the game. “The little weirdnesses [in the 2.0 translation] really twist the knife on how strange and off putting the world of the game is,” says K.</p><div><p>“I’m excited to rediscover the game.”</p></div><p>But some of that was down to K’s imperfect French and English, so in the third version, she chose to clarify some lines, leading some players to feel that she had removed an aspect of whimsy and poetry that they had actually enjoyed. </p><p>These are tensions inherent to the act of translation, which is always adaptive. Now that <em>Off</em> is getting an official remaster, there will be a fourth version later this year, and it’s not clear how they’ll balance clarity and atmosphere, as well as its own adaptation, with K’s. The announcement was careful to acknowledge K’s work and says that the remaster will be “based on” K’s translation. She’s also been paid for what was once years of fan labor. But it does seem that the script is in the process of being readapted by professional localizers. (Publisher Fangamer did not respond to requests for confirmation.)</p><p>For K, the readaptation is a good thing. “The one thing I can say from everything I’ve seen of their updated version of the translation is they’ve improved it in every conceivable way,” she says. “I’m excited to rediscover the game.”</p><p>On the other hand, “it’s a strange feeling to be most well known for the work that you did on somebody else’s work,” says K, who has made several of her own games and is now working on <a href="https://blanksword.carrd.co/"><em>Blanksword</em></a>, a roguelike RPG “very strongly inspired by <em>Off</em>.” Ghost, too, says he’s changed a lot in the 17 years since <em>Off</em>’s original release. “I am of course very proud to have produced a game that has touched so many people, but I think that the game now belongs much more to the community,” he says. He is currently working on a new game called <em>Help</em>.</p><p>The remake won’t just feature an improved script but will also have updated combat mechanics, new animations, and some additional content written by Ghost. The goal was to “completely preserve the original atmosphere, while polishing everything that could be [polished],” he says. As with all remakes, this will be a difficult balancing act; adding in the complex adaptive work of translation, there will always be divided opinions over which of the now four major versions is the best.</p><p>But K’s efforts undeniably made <em>Off</em> what it is today, and the remake acknowledging and building on that history is a rare step in an industry where fan translations are usually unacknowledged at best and taken down at worst.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MultiVersus players who bought $100 Founder's Pack feel "scammed" by game's closure]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/multiversus-players-who-bought-100-founders-pack-feel-scammed-by-games-closure</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/multiversus-players-who-bought-100-founders-pack-feel-scammed-by-games-closure.1097877/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/multiversus-players-who-bought-100-founders-pack-feel-scammed-by-games-closure<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div>
        

        <p>"Anyone saying consumers deserve to be defrauded because it says tokens, not characters, is insane."</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/MultiVersus---Official-Launch-Trailer-_Stars-Collide.-Pies-Fly._-2-58-screenshot.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Warner Bros.</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/multiversus">MultiVersus</a> players who bought the premium Founder's Pack have hit out at <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/companies/warner-bros-games">Warner Bros. Games</a> for cancelling its free-to-play live-service fighting game before they had a chance to redeem all of their rewards.</p>
<p>After learning yesterday that <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/thats-all-folks-another-warner-bros-live-service-bites-the-dust">MultiVersus' fifth season will be its last</a>, some players who stumped up $100 for MultiVersus' Founder's Pack have taken to social media saying they've been "scammed" given they'd paid for 30 character tokens and 2500 Gleamium that they've yet to use.</p>
<figure><div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div><figcaption>Xbox Developer Direct - four promising games also coming to PlayStation.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=afaO_AuPw0o" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>Whilst some point out that, with the arrival of Aquaman and Lola, there will be 35 characters in the roster, some founder players <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/MultiVersus/comments/1iegmz7/comment/ma7ih74/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button">said</a> that "Gold was a lot more generous back [during the beta]" so they'd been able to redeem characters via the in-game currency, which is why they have character tokens left over.</p><p>Others <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/MultiVersus/comments/1iegmz7/comment/ma8atkc/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button">say</a> they were keeping their tokens for "future updates"  and that as six of those 35 fighters were given away freely - Banana Guard, Jason, Shaggy, Wonder Woman, Lola, and Aquaman - many Founder Pack owners may have unused credits (thanks, <a href="https://www.thegamer.com/multiversus-players-unhappy-season-5-shutdown-100-dollar-founders-pack-feel-scammed/">TheGamer</a>).</p>
<p>"23 characters were already unlocked before purchasing Premium Founders," the OP <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/MultiVersus/comments/1iegmz7/comment/ma7l9d0/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button">explained</a>. "They still charged despite that. Means they promised the purchaser that they would be able to use all 30 of those tokens knowing that they bought it even after unlocking everything that was released at that moment."</p>
<blockquote data-embed-height="740"><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/MultiVersus/comments/1iegmz7/did_i_just_get_scammed_got_founders_around_when/">Did I Just Get Scammed? Got Founders Around when Marvin Came Out. Only 12 characters came after.</a><br> by<a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/RockmanBN/">u/RockmanBN</a> in<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/MultiVersus/">MultiVersus</a></blockquote><p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span></p><p>"That's not how it works. they promised 30 tokens and you were given 30 tokens," <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/MultiVersus/comments/1iegmz7/comment/ma8pjfq/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button">countered</a> another.</p>
<p>"Anyone here saying consumers deserve to be defrauded because it says tokens, not characters, is insane," <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/MultiVersus/comments/1iegmz7/comment/ma9p2hu/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button">opined</a> one unhappy player.</p>
<p>"The concept of the item has to then be useable, if a product is unusable or is described improperly at time of purchase, the consumer is due a refund."</p>
<p>At the time of writing, there has been no formal word from Warner Bros. Games or developer Player First Games if they will refund some or all of the cost of Founder's Packs.</p>
<p>In a post to players yesterday, the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/thats-all-folks-another-warner-bros-live-service-bites-the-dust">MultiVersus team confirmed Season 5 will end on 30th May</a>, although the game will still be available offline "for the foreseeable future".</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>