<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 13:30:44 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ubisoft has disbanded the Prince of Persia: The Lost Crown team]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/10/23/ubisoft-has-disbanded-the-prince-of-persia-the-lost-crown-team/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ubisoft-has-disbanded-the-prince-of-persia-the-lost-crown-team.1017174/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/10/23/ubisoft-has-disbanded-the-prince-of-persia-the-lost-crown-team/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Following reports yesterday, Ubisoft has confirmed that the team behind <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/prince-of-persia-the-lost-crown">Prince of Persia: The Lost Crown</a> has been disbanded, with its employees at Ubisoft Montpellier being moved along to other projects. This will be hugely disappointing news to fans of the Metroidvania twist on Prince of Persia.</p>
<p>The news came yesterday from French reporter Gautoz in their show on the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8HgkIyq0emY">Origami YouTube channel</a>, with Ubisoft reportedly making the decision to allow for the <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/09/30/prince-of-persia-the-lost-crown-mask-of-darkness-is-a-near-essential-dlc/">DLC</a> and cosmetics roadmap to be released for the game, but end support there and not greenlight a sequel or any further expansions. The decision went so far as to say this was so as not to “cannibalize” long term sales of the game.</p>


<p>While the specifics of the reporting haven’t been confirmed by Ubisoft, the general gist has been. Abdelhak Elguess, Prince of Persia: The Lost Crown senior producer said in <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/ubisoft-responds-to-report-prince-of-persia-the-lost-crown-development-team-disbanded">a statement to Eurogamer</a>:</p>
<p>“I’m extremely proud of our team’s work and passion at Ubisoft Montpellier to create a game that resonated with players and critics alike, and I am confident in its long-term success.</p>
<p>“Prince of Persia: The Lost Crown is now at the end of its Post-Launch roadmap with three free content updates and one DLC that released in September. We are now focusing on making the game available to more players: it was recently launched on Steam, and will be available on Mac by this winter.</p>

<p>“Most of the team members who worked on Prince of Persia: The Lost Crown have shifted to other projects that will benefit from their expertise.</p>
<p>“We know players have a love for this brand and Ubisoft is excited to bring more Prince of Persia experiences in the future.”</p>
<p>Sadly, it seems that it simply didn’t sell well enough for Ubisoft’s liking – roughly 1 million copies, per Insider Gaming – when Ubisoft is looking to really maximise sales amid a string of disappointment bigger budget titles. Perhaps part of the problem was having a higher price point when compared to indie metroidvania standouts – The Lost Crown was $50 – and not releasing on Steam would have hurt PC sales as well.</p>
<p>Ubisoft Montpellier is the lead studio on Beyond Good &amp; Evil 2, which has been in development for what feels like forever. <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/prince-of-persia-three-new-projects/">Insider Gaming reports</a> that the team has been spread across BG&amp;E2, Project Ovr, which is the next Ghost Recon game, and Project Steambot, a&nbsp;Rayman remake in development with Ubisoft Milan.</p>
<p>Prince of Persia: The Lost Crown launched in January and was an early highlight of the year. “Prince of Persia: The Lost Crown is one of the finest metroidvanias I’ve ever played,”<a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/01/11/prince-of-persia-the-lost-crown-review/"> Ade wrote in our review</a>, “and a fantastic way to start 2024. Thrilling and kinetic platforming, thumping combat, and a vast game world that demands exploration, and makes it a joy to do. It’s time to kick nostalgia firmly in the unmentionables; this is the best Prince of Persia ever.”</p>
<p>Sources: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8HgkIyq0emY">Origami</a>, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/ubisoft-responds-to-report-prince-of-persia-the-lost-crown-development-team-disbanded">Eurogamer</a>, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/prince-of-persia-three-new-projects/">Insider Gaming</a></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No Man’s Sky Gets Creepy ‘The Cursed’ Halloween Update]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/no-mans-sky-gets-creepy-the-cursed-halloween-update/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/no-man%E2%80%99s-sky-gets-creepy-%E2%80%98the-cursed%E2%80%99-halloween-update.1017171/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/no-mans-sky-gets-creepy-the-cursed-halloween-update/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Today, Hello Games has announced and released a new update for its ever-evolving open galaxy game No Man's Sky. This update is titled The Cursed and is obviously meant to be a creepy one, much like many of the Halloween events that are being launched across live games this week.</p>
<p>According to Hello Games, The Cursed is a new Expedition in which players struggle to keep a grip on reality while being haunted by visions and voices from another dimension. It is set in a twilight universe straddling the line between realities. Here, time can shift unexpectedly as day turns to night at an unnatural pace.</p>
<p>Players will employ the new Boundary StarShip while traveling this haunted universe. This StarShip is a flying saucer, the first available in No Man's Sky, and the team described it as a 'Giger-esque coil of tubes, pipes, and engines.'</p>
<p>In The Cursed, players must protect themselves from the eroding boundaries of reality. The player exosuit's regular hazard protection has been replaced for the occasion with a special Anomaly Suppressor, the key to survival as the universe collapses around you.</p>
<p>As players explore these haunted worlds, they may encounter ghostly beings that drift across the boundaries. Sometimes, these spectral anomalies will be merely observant; on other occasions, they can become much more hostile. These encounters will introduce players to new, challenging enemies and boss battles on an unprecedented scale in No Man's Sky.</p>
<figure>
<div>

<div>
		
		
		<p><span>2 of 9</span>
	</p></div></div>
</figure>


<p>While playing The Cursed Expedition, travelers won't have access to hyperdrive technology, meaning no warping between star systems. Instead, interstellar travel requires careful planning and the use of an ancient portal network. Moreover, from another dimension, players will hear haunting voices offering guidance, information, strange blueprints, and secrets. Players must reflect on who these voices belong to, where they come from, and whether they can be trusted. Completing The Cursed will provide players exclusive spooky rewards, including exosuit customization inspired by Cthulhu-esque, bioluminescent pets, and the UFO-like Boundary Herald starship. This No Man's Sky Expedition begins today and lasts approximately three weeks.</p>
<p>Hello Games also said in the press release that the previous update, <a href="https://wccftech.com/no-mans-sky-aquarius-update-finally-adds-fishing/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Aquarius</a>, which introduced fishing to the game, was yet another success. Overall, 2024 is shaping up to be one of the biggest years for No Man's Sky in terms of popularity, and the British studio has promised 'several more surprises' in the remaining weeks before the end of the year, including the PS5 Pro enhancement patch available at launch on November 7.</p>

				

			
	<div>
		<h2>Products mentioned in this post</h2>
		
		<!--<p class="story-notice text-center">The links above are affiliate links. As an Amazon Associate, Wccftech.com may earn from qualifying purchases.</p>-->
	</div>

			
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Romancing SaGa 2: Revenge of the Seven (PS5) Review – Avalon Wasn’t Built in a Day]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/review/romancing-saga-2-revenge-of-the-seven-ps5-review/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/romancing-saga-2-revenge-of-the-seven-ps5-review-%E2%80%93-avalon-wasn%E2%80%99t-built-in-a-day.1017168/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/review/romancing-saga-2-revenge-of-the-seven-ps5-review/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
				<main>

					

					<!--<div class="ads-container banner-ad floated p-0">
						<div data-pg-ad-spot='div-gpt-ad-wccftechcom38564' style="min-height: 280px;"></div>
					</div>-->
					
										<div><header>Game Info</header><div><div>
						<h5>Romancing SaGa 2: Revenge of the Seven</h5><p><span>October 24th, 2024</span>
					</p></div><div>
							<h5>Platform</h5><p><span>PlayStation 4, PlayStation 5, Nintendo Switch, and PC (Steam)</span>
						</p></div><div>
							<h5>Developer</h5><p><span>Square Enix, Xeen Inc.</span>
						</p></div></div></div>
					<p><span>In most RPG mythology, the legendary heroes are folks to be revered and their stories tell of hope and a positive future. However, in Romancing SaGa 2: Revenge of the Seven, those same Seven Heroes hare instead left behind a legacy of revenge and vile fiends roaming the land. It’s a narrative that brings some contemporary charm to an otherwise all-too-familiar mythology and this full 3D remake presents this groundbreaking JRPG in a whole new light.</span></p>

<figure></figure>

<p><span>Following the passing of a family member at the hands of one of these legendary Seven Heroes, the Emperor (or Empress) of Avalon vows revenge against these heroes and to cleanse the world of their influence. From humble beginnings of a small empire nestled away in the northwest corner of the world, the player will see Varennes grow into a global superpower by ridding the world of these Seven Heroes one by one and bringing countries rid of their troubles under one united flag.</span></p>
<p><span>Romancing SaGa 2: Revenge of the Seven promises an open-ended adventure and has some interesting ways to make good on that promise, while the limitations of the original Super Famicom release are still present in how the narrative is shaped. Guided by little more than a rumor or piece of advice from your chancellor at the start of each generation, players can venture out into the world however they see fit once news of some sort of goings-on is brought to the player’s attention. Players only need to journey through dungeons and open fields once to reach a new city before it’s added to the list of fast travel options. All of these paths tend to converge at the same end, so regardless of which order the world is liberated and which of the Seven Heroes are dispatched, there’s a very similar design to how all of these paths intersect.&nbsp;</span></p>

<figure></figure>

<p><span>While not completely possible to see everything in a single playthrough, players can still complete a good 90-95% of the available quests in Revenge of the Seven during a single run if they so choose. I had somehow neglected to check up on an active volcano in an earlier generation and went back a generation or two later to see how things were going only to discover another natural disaster awaiting a nearby village. Had I gone sooner, I would have been granted the opportunity to learn about Dark Magic if I followed a very specific story path. Alas, the island itself was saved and this critical quest was locked away for the remainder of the playthrough.</span></p>
<p><span>Note for note, bar for bar, Revenge of the Seven is largely a familiar retelling of this experimental JRPG throughout in spite of the overhaul that’s been done to the game’s mechanics. Familiar story beats follow the same narrative journey as players solve the issues plaguing the world left in the wake of the Seven Heroes taking their own form of revenge and unleashing hordes of demons unto the world. Pick up any strategy guide penned for the PlayStation 4/Vita pixel remake from 2016 and you’ll be able to at least follow the story along even if all of the treasure chests and maps have been overhauled for this full 3D remake.</span></p>

<figure></figure>

<p><span>Despite the non-linear nature promised in Romancing SaGa 2: Revenge of the Seven, there’s a sort of guarantee to the flow of progression. Finding new places to explore or quests to undertake often takes little more than chatting up the bartender at a local tavern or speaking with the common people around each town. There isn’t much mystery as to where to get a new quest as eligible NPCs all have the same telltale question mark icon to indicate they have something to offer. Most every other NPC can be readily ignored unless the player wishes to get a little more flavor text to the world and the troubles ailing them.</span></p>
<p><span>Behind the scenes of Romancing SaGa 2: Revenge of the Seven is an invisible timer that counts down the end of one generation and the beginning of the next. It’s not number of hours or minor quests completed that leads to the passage of time but rather world-shaping events and defeating any one of the Seven Heroes. Typically three major quests is the sweet spot to undertake as the current Emperor before the throne must be abdicated, 150-or-so years pass by, and a new Emperor is selected to ascend to the throne of Avalon. This same formal transfer of power also proceeds if the entire party is wiped out, rather than forcing the player into a Game Over scenario.</span></p>

<figure></figure>

<p><span>In this transfer of responsibilities, players are given a pool of six or so heroes that can assume the title of Emperor and lead the expansion of Varennes. These options are pulled from any available quest that’s been unlocked with a few notable selections. For example, the marionette puppet Coppelia can only be selected for a single generation before she is passively discarded (if you do happen to come across her, a hidden rendition of Wipe Your Tears plays and you’re rewarded with her signature ability, Poker Face, which renders whoever is equipped with the ability complete immunity to status effects). Because of the random nature, there’s no guarantee that you’ll receive an option that comes with the weapon skills you’ve previously been leveling or even the right class to complete a particular quest. No matter how much I tried, I couldn’t get the Corsair as an available option, thus leaving one specific quest incomplete as I was unable to have the maritime experience necessary for traversing the open seas.</span></p>
<p><span>Combat in Romancing SaGa 2: Revenge of the Seven is perhaps its most notable and welcomed change from the original releases. Kawazu and his team have updated the battle system to be more in line with recent SaGa titles such as Minstrel Song and SaGa: Emerald Beyond. Fights take place on a shared timeline where individual Speed stats determine the turn order rather than moving as one complete unit and the timeline can provide insight as to when an enemy’s turn may be coming up or if they’re preparing a brutal attack. Save for a few key weapon skills or formations, there’s little that can be done with manipulating the timeline outside of buffing/reducing a character’s Speed stat. Magicks require no casting times, so they can be issued the same as regular attacks and Techs. Striking an enemy’s weakness fills a separate Overdrive gauge that serves as this SaGa entry’s form of a combo system. Once filled, heroes can tag the next party member in line to do a combined pair of Tech/Spell attacks pulled from a random list.</span></p>
<p><span>There’s some rhyme and reason to how these combinations are pulled out, typically with like weapon types or elements being used in tandem. It wasn’t uncommon for my Martial Artist-specialized Emperor to tag in the next party member to do a matching attack. For most of the adventure, players will be limited to just two players being linked together but by way of finding the hidden Mr. S collectibles and adding more regions under the Empire’s banner, players can link together more party members and even gain a second Overdrive Gauge (which carries over between battles, so it can be beneficial to grind just a little bit before tackling a dungeon boss). Precious BP used to cast Tech and Spells alike is typically only recharged through one-time use checkpoints before boss encounters or by resting at an inn, although there are rare BP-restoring items that can be purchased or found in treasure chests. Romancing SaGa 2 isn’t like Persona or Metaphor where there’s a strict calendar dictating your movements, so returning to town to restock is often a viable option.</span></p>
<p><span>True to previous SaGa titles, Revenge of the Seven is not a JRPG where grinding is intended. While it is more lenient than its successors, there is still a persistent Battle Rank that ticks up as players progress the narrative and undergo a certain number of battles. This Battle Rank will affect the enemies that players come across, so while grinding in one spot might sound like a good idea initially to learn a few new Tech or raise a weapon’s skill, grinding too much can have the adverse effect of introducing enemies that are too challenging to defeat given the player’s current equipment and skills.&nbsp;</span></p>
<figure>
<div>

<div>
		
		
		<p><span>2 of 9</span>
	</p></div></div>
</figure>


<p><span>There’s no true leveling system in Romancing SaGa 2: Revenge of the Seven and this holds true for either SaGa titles as well. In lieu of a stated character level, winning a battle will typically raise one of three stats for a character: their HP, their BP, and whatever Weapon/Spells they used (or if they didn’t have a chance to act, whatever they used in the last fight). Any other stat, such as Defense or one of the five core attributes, is instead increased through equipped gear. Using a particular Weapon or Spell Skill will not only raise the amount of damage done but also unlock the opportunity to have a sudden spark of inspiration, or ‘Glimmer”, and discover a brand new attack on the battlefield. Each Weapon type comes with its own unique list of Tech attacks to learn, most branching from one skill or another once the right conditions are met (typically the character’s Weapon Skill in combination with the enemy’s strength).</span></p>
<p><span>Glimmering one of these Techs not only adds it to that character’s list of skills but also can be passed along to future generations through the Empire’s Training Hall. All of that passive knowledge in the form of Weapon Skills and Techs is recorded in the imperial records, so that as time passes and a new generation begins, the cumulative knowledge is carried forth and the next generation might have the power needed to defeat one of the Seven Heroes. By the time I inherited the tidal of Final Emperor and was ready to finish the adventure, I had just under 1,000 HP, a Martial Arts skill around level 60, and could easily hit for 15-20,000 from a single GuanYin and much more if it was a critical hit or used in an Overdrive combo.</span></p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Romancing SaGa 2: Revenge of the Seven | Overview Launch Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wCloP3y0LnY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p><span>While <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2455640/Romancing_SaGa_2_Revenge_of_the_Seven/">Romancing SaGa 2: Revenge of the Seven</a> features the same narrative and core gameplay under the hood, this 3D remake turns the influential JRPG into a brand new experience. For players that rightfully enjoyed Kawazu’s non-linear storytelling in prior SaGa titles, Revenge of the Seven is a must-play. Just make sure to dust off one of those old Super Famicom strategy guides if you plan to see all of the tourism and fiends that Avalon has to offer.</span></p>
<p>[Editor's Note: a PlayStation 5 copy was provided by the publisher.]</p>

					
					<div>
	<div>
			
			<p>Romancing SaGa 2: Revenge of the Seven</p>
		</div>
	<header>Romancing SaGa 2: Revenge of the Seven</header>
</div>

<p>One of Akitoshi Kawazu's most experimental titles from the Super Famicom, Romancing SaGa 2: Revenge of the Seven shows that a classic JRPG can be given a complete overhaul to turn into something brand new while still retaining its unique quirks and charm.</p>

<div>
		<div>
		<h6>
			<span>Pros</span>
		</h6>
		<ul>
			<li>Overhauled modern SaGa battle system
</li><li>A new Tech chart shows not only what skills can Glimmer new attacks but also if a character even has the forte to learn something new
</li><li>Character growth passed forward into new generations or New Game Plus
</li><li>Original and Remastered soundtracks
</li><li>Defeat only leads to a new generation, not a Game Over
</li><li>Playable Demo available to try before you buy</li>		</ul>
	</div>
			<div>
		<h6>
			<span>Cons</span>
		</h6>
		<ul>
			<li>Not specializing in just a few Weapon Skills or Magic Elements can drastically reduce damage potential
</li><li>Random nature to Emperor selection and character growth
</li><li>Several techs locked behind using weapon skills with a select number of heroes
</li><li>Many missable quests without a guide
</li><li>Magic is underwhelming for most of the adventure
</li><li>Enemy strength can overwhelm players if carelessly grinding</li>		</ul>
	</div>
	</div>


<p>The links above are affiliate links. As an Amazon Associate, Wccftech.com may earn from qualifying purchases.</p>
					
				</main>
			</article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Massive The Sims 4 Update Paves the Way for Life and Death Expansion]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/massive-sims-4-update-life-and-death</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/massive-the-sims-4-update-paves-the-way-for-life-and-death-expansion.1017165/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/massive-sims-4-update-life-and-death<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>EA has released a massive new&nbsp;<em>The Sims 4&nbsp;</em>update ahead of a new expansion that's due to arrive next week, and the update brings lots of new spooky goodies including new death reactions, ghost creation, and more.</p>
<p><em>The Sims 4</em>'s latest expansion&nbsp;<em>Life and Death&nbsp;</em>is <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/the-sims-4-expansion-pack-life-and-death-revealed">set to launch on Halloween</a> (because of course it is), and a free update has been released ahead of that launch to prepare&nbsp;<em>The Sims 4&nbsp;</em>for a spooky time.</p>
<p>First up, Sims can now react to other Sims' deaths "based on traits and relationships", so you might see your Sim weeping for the death of a loved one, for instance, or even "retching at a stranger's death". Charming.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/the-sims-4-update-life-and-death-reaper.jpg?itok=y3rS8kZ6 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/the-sims-4-update-life-and-death-reaper.jpg?itok=ZMGhrxPD 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>A new&nbsp;<em>The Sims 4&nbsp;</em>update is here, and it's all about death, ghosts, and other spooky things.</figcaption></figure><p>You can now create Ghost Sims during the Create a Sim process, and once a Sim has passed on, they'll become a Ghost Sim with a new set of needs including the likes of "Goo Waste", "Spooky Diversions", and "Apparition Cleansing".</p>
<p>If a Sim that's married to another Sim dies, they'll be widowed, but the Sims can ask to stay married in order to reinstate their marriage status if you wish them to.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Perhaps most importantly, per the patch notes, "Sims can WooHoo with the Grim Reaper again", so all you freaky&nbsp;<em>The Sims 4&nbsp;</em>players who've been wanting to show Death how you really feel, this one's for you.</p>
<p>Tons of other changes have been made as part of this update, so you can read <a href="https://www.ea.com/games/the-sims/the-sims-4/news/update-10-22-2024" rel="noopener" target="_blank">the full patch notes here</a> if you want to know everything that's changed.</p>

<p>This update comes not long after <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/ea-no-plans-the-sims-5">an announcement</a> regarding the&nbsp;<em>Sims&nbsp;</em>franchise's future back in September, wherein EA revealed that it had no plans for&nbsp;<em>The Sims 5&nbsp;</em>anytime soon.</p>
<p>Instead,&nbsp;<em>The Sims 4&nbsp;</em>will continue to be supported and updated with regular patches like this one, as well as expansions like&nbsp;<em>Life and Death&nbsp;</em>and new Creator Kits made by community figures.</p>
<p>You can check out&nbsp;<em>The Sims 4&nbsp;</em>right now for free on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1222670/The_Sims_4/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="noopener" target="_blank">PC</a>, <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-gb/games/the-sims-4/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">PS4</a>, and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/the-sims-4/c08jxnk0vg5l" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Xbox One</a>. Naturally, it's also playable on PS5 and Xbox Series X|S thanks to the wonders of backwards compatibility.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Day Before Dev Cancels Failing Kickstarter and Announces Another Game in the Same Breath]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/the-day-before-dev-cancels-failing-kickstarter-and-announces-another-game-in-the-same-breath</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-day-before-dev-cancels-failing-kickstarter-and-announces-another-game-in-the-same-breath.1017156/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/the-day-before-dev-cancels-failing-kickstarter-and-announces-another-game-in-the-same-breath<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">"After careful analysis and discussion."</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">The Day Before developer Fntastic has cancelled its failing Kickstarter for one game and announced another in the same breath.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Fntastic, who released the utterly disastrous The Day Before in December 2023 before pretending to shut down, resurfaced in September asking for money for a new game: the physics based multiplayer game Escape Factory.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It has now cancelled this project, however, after it reached just 15.73% of its <a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/fntasticgames/escape-factory/description" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Kickstarter</a> goal with $3,146 raised of a $20,000 goal. "Our campaign on Kickstarter is unlikely to reach our goal," Fntastic said in a statement published to <a href="https://x.com/FntasticHQ/status/1848982250316304734?ref_src=twsrc%5Egoogle%7Ctwcamp%5Eserp%7Ctwgr%5Etweet" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">X/Twitter</a> announcing another game.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"After careful analysis and discussion with the team, we have decided that our Escape Factory project has not generated enough interest," it said. The Kickstarter reached the 15.73% mark after four weeks. "With this in mind, we have decided to temporarily suspend work on Escape Factory and postpone it until a more appropriate time."</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>After careful analysis and discussion with the team, we have decided that our Escape Factory project has not generated enough interest.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Fntastic is now allegedly working on Items, an action horror prop hunt game. "Your wishes are very important to us," it said. "This is exactly what many of you have been waiting for."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">No Kickstarter was announced but Fntastic said it may return to the crowdfunding route "or explore other options" once a demo for the game is made. Development will "require significant resources" so Fntastic has "decided to release mobile games" to support the process.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"All funds generated from these apps will go directly into development," it said. "We believe this will help us create the game of your dreams."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The term "dream" was often used in Fntastic's marketing for The Day Before. "We hope that after the game's success, we’ll give people faith that in this life, if you persevere toward a dream, it will come true, despite all the obstacles and doubts," Fntastic told IGN in January 2023.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The Day Before launched to <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-day-before-review">an almost impossibly rare 1/10 in IGN's review</a> and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-day-before-studio-fntastic-announces-closure-just-days-after-early-access-launch">its shutdown was announced</a> just four days after <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-day-before-player-count-drops-almost-90-in-4-days-enters-steams-10-worst-reviewed-games-list">it launched in Early Access</a>. It was one of the most controversial and catastrophic game launches in recent memory (now joined by PlayStation 5's Concord) as <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-day-before-accused-of-copying-other-games-again">what was touted as the "next generation of post-apocalyptic MMO open-world survival games"</a> was released as a barebones and broken extraction shooter.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">The Strange Saga of The Day Before</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Once Steam's most wishlisted game, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-strange-saga-of-the-day-before">suspicion mounted around The Day Before and Fntastic</a> as time went on. It announced delay after delay amid revelations <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-day-before-developer-steam-most-wishlisted-game-defends-unpaid-volunteers">the studio used unpaid workers to develop its games</a>, then <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-strange-saga-of-the-day-before">a trademark dispute caused more issues</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Allegations the entire game was a scam then emerged from the disgruntled fanbase, made worse by the myriad copycat accusations against Fntastic. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-day-before-accused-of-copying-other-games-again">Shots in its trailers and screenshots lined up almost perfectly with other games</a> such as Call of Duty: Black Ops Cold War, Cyberpunk 2077, and Grand Theft Auto 5.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">For example, a trailer for The Day Before used the phrase: "Welcome to the next generation of post-apocalyptic MMO open-world survival games like never before. Immerse yourself in The Day Before." Alongside not making grammatical English sense, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/videos/cyberpunk-2077-world-explainer-gameplay-trailer">Cyberpunk 2077's Official Gameplay Trailer</a>, published years earlier in 2020, used the very similar phrasing: "Welcome to the next-generation of open-world adventure. Immerse yourself in Cyberpunk 2077."</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/videos/red-dead-redemption-2-official-gameplay-trailer">Red Dead Redemption 2's Official Gameplay Video</a>, published even further back, used the phrases "...to make combat deep and engaging at all times. Each weapon has unique characteristics, with realistic reload and recoil." A trailer for The Day Before used: "...to ensure that combat remains deep and engaging at all times. Each weapon boasts unique characteristics, as well as realistic reload and recoil mechanics."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">These are just two examples of myriad accusations with similar weight, but Fntastic denied any wrongdoing, leaned on the "fake news" defence, and implied the accusations were just an attempt at attention seeking. "We all live in a time of disinformation and lack of fact-checking," it said following the second wave of accusations. "Anyone can say anything for views, and everyone will believe it," it said. "Disinformation needs to be dealt with."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Fntastic has put out plenty of disinformation and blatant lies of its own, however, like <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-day-before-devs-say-delay-was-planned-before-trademark-dispute">saying the aforementioned trademark dispute caused a delay</a> when one was planned all along, and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-day-before-studio-fntastic-announces-closure-just-days-after-early-access-launch">saying the studio was shutting down</a> before announcing another game just months later. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-day-before-dev-promises-refunds-tells-customers-st-happens">"S**t happens," it told fans</a> who were frustrated with the misleading information and failure of The Day Before.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Ryan Dinsdale is an IGN freelance reporter. He'll talk about The Witcher all day.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PS5 System Software Update Improves Activities Display]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/ps5-system-software-update-improves-activities-display</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ps5-system-software-update-improves-activities-display.1017144/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/ps5-system-software-update-improves-activities-display<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Sony has released a new update for the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/playstation-5">PlayStation 5</a> that improves how the Activities cards display information.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Version 24.07-10.20.00, which weighs in at 1.3GB, changes how activities display to show 'In Progress,' 'Not Started,' or 'Completed,' depending on whether you have ever started or completed the activity. The patch notes, per the <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-my/support/hardware/ps5/system-software-info/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">PlayStation website</a>, are below.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Activities, which Sony touted as one of the PS5’s key new features ahead of its November 2020 launch, let players jump straight into specific missions, modes, and quests from the console’s Control Centre, although they don’t always get players back into the action as quickly as they’d like.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/10/23/ps5-1729677725323.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption>PS5 Activities. Image credit: Sony Interactive Entertainment.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Elsewhere, the PS5 update improves “performance and stability,” as these updates always do, and improves the messages and usability on some screens.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The PS5 update comes ahead of the launch of the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/tech/playstation-5-pro">PS5 Pro</a> on November 7. The $700 mid-gen upgrade is set to run video games with improved framerates and visual quality, with over 70 set to receive the PS5 Pro Enhanced label. Updates for PS5 games are coming in <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-last-of-us-part-1-and-the-last-of-us-part-2-remastered-both-get-ps5-pro-support-patches">thick</a> and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/alan-wake-2-on-ps5-pro-quality-mode-30-fps-remedy-games">fast</a> to prepare for the console’s launch, each making use of the beefier hardware in different ways.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The PS5 is now up to 61.7 million units sold, although sales are declining as the console enters the second half of its lifecycle.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">PS5 system software update version 24.07-10.20.00 patch notes:</h2><ul data-cy="list"><li>Activities now display as <strong>In Progress</strong>, <strong>Not Started</strong>, or <strong>Completed</strong>, depending on whether you have ever started or completed the activity.<ul data-cy="list"><li>Potential spoilers will still be hidden.</li></ul></li><li>We've improved system software performance and stability.</li><li>We've improved the messages and usability on some screens.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Diablo IV Vases of Hatred Promotion Lets You Send Evil Flowers To Your Frenemies]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/diablo-iv-vases-of-hatred-promotion-lets-you-send-evil-flowers-to-your-frenemies/1100-6527332/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/diablo-iv-vases-of-hatred-promotion-lets-you-send-evil-flowers-to-your-frenemies.1017138/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/diablo-iv-vases-of-hatred-promotion-lets-you-send-evil-flowers-to-your-frenemies/1100-6527332/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6527332">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>The first expansion for <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/diablo-4-review-mother-knows-best/1900-6418072/" data-ref-id="1900-6418072">Diablo IV</a>, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/diablo-4-vessel-of-hatred-review-piercing-the-veil/1900-6418298/" data-ref-id="1900-6418298">Vessel of Hatred</a>, was released earlier this month to critically acclaim from players. Now, Blizzard has found a way to bring a little touch of darkness from the game into the real world by allowing people in Los Angeles and New York to have evil flowers delivered to the special frenemies in your life.</p><p>This sinister Vases of Hatred floral arrangement was designed by celebrity florist Dead Flowers and inspired by the events of the expansion. Within the game, the villain Mephisto has the ability to infect and corrupt plant life and almost anything he touches. The flowers come in a vase that was designed to invoke Nahantu, the newly introduced location in the game that is under Mephisto's control.</p><div data-embed-type="tweet" data-src="https://twitter.com/Diablo/status/1848393878887415992" data-has-image="true"><blockquote data-conversation="none" data-mce-disable-toolbar="true"><p dir="ltr">Mephisto’s corruption is seeping beyond Sanctuary 😈<br>Spread Evil and show your nemesis you’ve been thinking about them with a poisonous bouquet of flowers.<br>Vases of Hatred. October 22, 9am PT. <a href="https://t.co/zNBvcuBBIc" rel="nofollow ">pic.twitter.com/zNBvcuBBIc</a></p>  — Diablo (@Diablo) <a href="https://twitter.com/Diablo/status/1848393878887415992?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 21, 2024</a></blockquote>              </div><p>According to the announcement, the floral arrangement includes "a collection of carnivorous flowers and trypophobia-inducing buds, with stems and leaves singed by the fires of hell." There may have been some creative liberties taken with that description. But even if there's no one in your life that you'd want to send these flowers to, there is an in-game reward--the Little Lady mount bundle--for doing so.</p><p>The official site for <a href="http://vasesofhatred.diablo.com/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Vases of Hatred</a> has all of the details for ordering the flowers for people in Los Angeles and New York. However, the promotion will only run as long as the supply of flowers is still on hand. Everyone outside of New York or LA can also get the in-game reward after sending someone the evil flowers digital card.</p><p>Diablo IV: Vessel of Hatred is out now for PlayStation 5, PlayStation 4, Xbox One, Xbox Series X|S, and PC.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fallout PC And Console Games Are On Sale For Fallout Day]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fallout-pc-and-console-games-are-on-sale-for-fallout-day/1100-6527326/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fallout-pc-and-console-games-are-on-sale-for-fallout-day.1017135/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fallout-pc-and-console-games-are-on-sale-for-fallout-day/1100-6527326/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6527326">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>October 23 is Bethesda's Fallout Day--a yearly celebration of the game series marked by the day the bombs fell in the Fallout universe. In celebration, the Fallout games and DLC are on sale at multiple online retailers, making today the perfect time to fill out your collection with these beloved post-apocalyptic RPGs. <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.anrdoezrs.net%2Fclick-100770772-13797872%3Fsid%3Dsubid_value%26url%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.fanatical.com%2Fen%2Ffranchises%2Ffallout&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Ffallout-pc-and-console-games-are-on-sale-for-fallout-day%2F1100-6527326%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Fanatical</a> and <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.jdoqocy.com%2Fclick-100770772-15232592%3Fsid%3Dsubid_value%26url%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.gog.com%2Fen%2Fpromo%2F2024_fallout_day&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Ffallout-pc-and-console-games-are-on-sale-for-fallout-day%2F1100-6527326%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">GOG</a> have some of the best deals for PC players, though you'll also find select Fallout titles on sale at <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fhumblebundleinc.sjv.io%2Fc%2F1804712%2F2059850%2F25796%3FsubId1%3Dsubid_value%26u%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.humblebundle.com%2Fstore%2Fsearch%3Fsort%3Dbestselling%26search%3DFallout%26page%3D1&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Ffallout-pc-and-console-games-are-on-sale-for-fallout-day%2F1100-6527326%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Humble</a> and <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/sale/falloutdaysale2024" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Steam</a> for as much as 75% off. If you'd rather go with the console versions, you can get digital copies of many Fallout titles in both the <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/search/fallout" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">PlayStation</a> and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/browse/fallout-day-sale" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Xbox stores</a>. Check out the list of sales below.</p><p><strong>See Fallout Day Sales at:</strong></p><ul><li><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.anrdoezrs.net%2Fclick-100770772-13797872%3Fsid%3Dsubid_value%26url%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.fanatical.com%2Fen%2Ffranchises%2Ffallout&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Ffallout-pc-and-console-games-are-on-sale-for-fallout-day%2F1100-6527326%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Fanatical</a></li><li><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.jdoqocy.com%2Fclick-100770772-15232592%3Fsid%3Dsubid_value%26url%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.gog.com%2Fen%2Fpromo%2F2024_fallout_day&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Ffallout-pc-and-console-games-are-on-sale-for-fallout-day%2F1100-6527326%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">GOG</a></li><li><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fhumblebundleinc.sjv.io%2Fc%2F1804712%2F2059850%2F25796%3FsubId1%3Dsubid_value%26u%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.humblebundle.com%2Fstore%2Fsearch%3Fsort%3Dbestselling%26search%3DFallout%26page%3D1&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Ffallout-pc-and-console-games-are-on-sale-for-fallout-day%2F1100-6527326%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Humble</a></li><li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/sale/falloutdaysale2024" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Steam</a></li><li><a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/search/fallout" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">PlayStation Store</a></li><li><a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/browse/fallout-day-sale" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Xbox</a></li></ul><p>PC players will want to check out Fanatical's big Fallout Day sale, which includes deals on the <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.jdoqocy.com%2Fclick-100770772-13797872%3Fsid%3Dsubid_value%26url%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.fanatical.com%2Fen%2Fgame%2Ffallout-a-post-nuclear-role-playing-game&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Ffallout-pc-and-console-games-are-on-sale-for-fallout-day%2F1100-6527326%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">original Fallout</a> and <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.kqzyfj.com%2Fclick-100770772-13797872%3Fsid%3Dsubid_value%26url%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.fanatical.com%2Fen%2Fgame%2Ffallout-2-a-post-nuclear-role-playing-game&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Ffallout-pc-and-console-games-are-on-sale-for-fallout-day%2F1100-6527326%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Fallout 2</a>. You can also grab both in the <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.dpbolvw.net%2Fclick-100770772-13797872%3Fsid%3Dsubid_value%26url%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.fanatical.com%2Fen%2Fgame%2Ffallout-classic-collection&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Ffallout-pc-and-console-games-are-on-sale-for-fallout-day%2F1100-6527326%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Fallout Classic Collection</a> for just $4.59 (was $20), which also includes the often-overlooked spin-off, <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.kqzyfj.com%2Fclick-100770772-13797872%3Fsid%3Dsubid_value%26url%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.fanatical.com%2Fen%2Fdlc%2Ffallout-tactics-brotherhood-of-steel&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Ffallout-pc-and-console-games-are-on-sale-for-fallout-day%2F1100-6527326%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Fallout Tactics: Brotherhood of Steel</a>.</p><p>For those who want to play the modern Bethesda-made outings, you can grab <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.anrdoezrs.net%2Fclick-100770772-13797872%3Fsid%3Dsubid_value%26url%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.fanatical.com%2Fen%2Fgame%2Ffallout-3&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Ffallout-pc-and-console-games-are-on-sale-for-fallout-day%2F1100-6527326%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Fallout 3</a>, <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.anrdoezrs.net%2Fclick-100770772-13797872%3Fsid%3Dsubid_value%26url%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.fanatical.com%2Fen%2Fgame%2Ffallout-4&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Ffallout-pc-and-console-games-are-on-sale-for-fallout-day%2F1100-6527326%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Fallout 4</a>, <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.dpbolvw.net%2Fclick-100770772-13797872%3Fsid%3Dsubid_value%26url%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.fanatical.com%2Fen%2Fgame%2Ffallout-new-vegas-ultimate-edition&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Ffallout-pc-and-console-games-are-on-sale-for-fallout-day%2F1100-6527326%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Fallout: New Vegas</a>, and <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.anrdoezrs.net%2Fclick-100770772-13797872%3Fsid%3Dsubid_value%26url%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.fanatical.com%2Fen%2Fgame%2Ffallout-76&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Ffallout-pc-and-console-games-are-on-sale-for-fallout-day%2F1100-6527326%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Fallout 76</a> all at discounts, plus numerous DLC expansions for each. You can also get Fallout 3 and Fallout: New Vegas for as little as $7 total if you grab them as part of <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.tkqlhce.com%2Fclick-100770772-13797872%3Fsid%3Dsubid_value%26url%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.fanatical.com%2Fen%2Fpick-and-mix%2Fbuild-your-own-special-editions-bundle&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Ffallout-pc-and-console-games-are-on-sale-for-fallout-day%2F1100-6527326%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Fanatical's Build Your Own Special Editions Bundle</a>. Alongside the Fallout games, the bundle offers several other standouts, including more Bethesda-published titles like Wolfenstein: The New Order, The Evil Within, and Dishonored. If you throw five or more games into the bundle, you'll only pay $3 for each.</p><h2>Fanatical Fallout Day Deals</h2><ul><li><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.dpbolvw.net%2Fclick-100770772-13797872%3Fsid%3Dsubid_value%26url%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.fanatical.com%2Fen%2Fgame%2Ffallout-classic-collection&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Ffallout-pc-and-console-games-are-on-sale-for-fallout-day%2F1100-6527326%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Fallout Classic Collection</a> -- $4.59 (<del>$20</del>)</li><li><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.jdoqocy.com%2Fclick-100770772-13797872%3Fsid%3Dsubid_value%26url%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.fanatical.com%2Fen%2Fgame%2Ffallout-a-post-nuclear-role-playing-game&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Ffallout-pc-and-console-games-are-on-sale-for-fallout-day%2F1100-6527326%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Fallout</a> -- $2.29 (<del>$10</del>)</li><li><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.kqzyfj.com%2Fclick-100770772-13797872%3Fsid%3Dsubid_value%26url%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.fanatical.com%2Fen%2Fgame%2Ffallout-2-a-post-nuclear-role-playing-game&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Ffallout-pc-and-console-games-are-on-sale-for-fallout-day%2F1100-6527326%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Fallout 2</a> -- $2.29 (<del>$10</del>)</li><li><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.kqzyfj.com%2Fclick-100770772-13797872%3Fsid%3Dsubid_value%26url%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.fanatical.com%2Fen%2Fdlc%2Ffallout-tactics-brotherhood-of-steel&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Ffallout-pc-and-console-games-are-on-sale-for-fallout-day%2F1100-6527326%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Fallout Tactics: Brotherhood of Steel</a> -- $10</li><li><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.anrdoezrs.net%2Fclick-100770772-13797872%3Fsid%3Dsubid_value%26url%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.fanatical.com%2Fen%2Fgame%2Ffallout-3&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Ffallout-pc-and-console-games-are-on-sale-for-fallout-day%2F1100-6527326%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Fallout 3</a> -- $2.29 (<del>$10</del>)</li><li><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.anrdoezrs.net%2Fclick-100770772-13797872%3Fsid%3Dsubid_value%26url%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.fanatical.com%2Fen%2Fgame%2Ffallout-3&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Ffallout-pc-and-console-games-are-on-sale-for-fallout-day%2F1100-6527326%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Fallout 3: Game of the Year Edition</a> -- $4.59 (<del>$20</del>)</li><li><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.dpbolvw.net%2Fclick-100770772-13797872%3Fsid%3Dsubid_value%26url%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.fanatical.com%2Fen%2Fgame%2Ffallout-new-vegas-ultimate-edition&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Ffallout-pc-and-console-games-are-on-sale-for-fallout-day%2F1100-6527326%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Fallout: New Vegas Ultimate Edition</a> -- $20</li><li><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.anrdoezrs.net%2Fclick-100770772-13797872%3Fsid%3Dsubid_value%26url%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.fanatical.com%2Fen%2Fgame%2Ffallout-4&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Ffallout-pc-and-console-games-are-on-sale-for-fallout-day%2F1100-6527326%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Fallout 4</a> -- $5.79 (<del>$20</del>)</li><li><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.kqzyfj.com%2Fclick-100770772-13797872%3Fsid%3Dsubid_value%26url%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.fanatical.com%2Fen%2Fgame%2Ffallout-4-vr&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Ffallout-pc-and-console-games-are-on-sale-for-fallout-day%2F1100-6527326%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Fallout 4 VR</a> -- $60</li><li><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.anrdoezrs.net%2Fclick-100770772-13797872%3Fsid%3Dsubid_value%26url%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.fanatical.com%2Fen%2Fdlc%2Ffallout-4-season-pass&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Ffallout-pc-and-console-games-are-on-sale-for-fallout-day%2F1100-6527326%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Fallout 4 Season Pass</a> -- $19 (<del>$35</del>)</li><li><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.jdoqocy.com%2Fclick-100770772-13797872%3Fsid%3Dsubid_value%26url%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.fanatical.com%2Fen%2Fdlc%2Ffallout-4-far-harbor-dlc&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Ffallout-pc-and-console-games-are-on-sale-for-fallout-day%2F1100-6527326%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Fallout 4: Far Harbor DLC</a> -- $8 (<del>$15</del>)</li><li><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.tkqlhce.com%2Fclick-100770772-13797872%3Fsid%3Dsubid_value%26url%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.fanatical.com%2Fen%2Fdlc%2Ffallout-4-automatron&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Ffallout-pc-and-console-games-are-on-sale-for-fallout-day%2F1100-6527326%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Fallout 4: Automatron DLC</a> -- $4.49 (<del>$10</del>)</li><li><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.dpbolvw.net%2Fclick-100770772-13797872%3Fsid%3Dsubid_value%26url%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.fanatical.com%2Fen%2Fdlc%2Ffallout-4-vault-tec-workshop&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Ffallout-pc-and-console-games-are-on-sale-for-fallout-day%2F1100-6527326%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Fallout 4: Vault-Tec Work Shop DLC</a> -- $2.69 (<del>$5</del>)</li><li><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.anrdoezrs.net%2Fclick-100770772-13797872%3Fsid%3Dsubid_value%26url%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.fanatical.com%2Fen%2Fdlc%2Ffallout-4-contraptions-workshop&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Ffallout-pc-and-console-games-are-on-sale-for-fallout-day%2F1100-6527326%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Fallout 4: Contraptions Work Shop DLC</a> -- $2.69 (<del>$5</del>)</li><li><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.dpbolvw.net%2Fclick-100770772-13797872%3Fsid%3Dsubid_value%26url%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.fanatical.com%2Fen%2Fdlc%2Ffallout-4-wasteland-workshop&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Ffallout-pc-and-console-games-are-on-sale-for-fallout-day%2F1100-6527326%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Fallout 4: Wasteland Workshop DLC</a> -- $2.69 (<del>$5</del>)</li><li><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.jdoqocy.com%2Fclick-100770772-13797872%3Fsid%3Dsubid_value%26url%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.fanatical.com%2Fen%2Fdlc%2Ffallout-4-nuka-world&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Ffallout-pc-and-console-games-are-on-sale-for-fallout-day%2F1100-6527326%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Fallout 4: Nuka-World DLC</a> -- $5.39 (<del>$10</del>)</li><li><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.anrdoezrs.net%2Fclick-100770772-13797872%3Fsid%3Dsubid_value%26url%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.fanatical.com%2Fen%2Fgame%2Ffallout-76&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Ffallout-pc-and-console-games-are-on-sale-for-fallout-day%2F1100-6527326%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Fallout 76</a> -- $9.19 (<del>$40</del>)</li><li><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.tkqlhce.com%2Fclick-100770772-13797872%3Fsid%3Dsubid_value%26url%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.fanatical.com%2Fen%2Fdlc%2Ffallout-76-atlantic-city-high-stakes-bundle&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Ffallout-pc-and-console-games-are-on-sale-for-fallout-day%2F1100-6527326%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Fallout 76: Atlantic City - High Stakes Bundle DLC</a> -- $30</li><li><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.kqzyfj.com%2Fclick-100770772-13797872%3Fsid%3Dsubid_value%26url%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.fanatical.com%2Fen%2Fgame%2Ffallout-76-skyline-valley-deluxe-edition&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Ffallout-pc-and-console-games-are-on-sale-for-fallout-day%2F1100-6527326%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Fallout 76: Skyline Valley - Deluxe Edition</a> -- $21.59 (<del>$60</del>)</li></ul><hr><p>GOG is also running a Fallout sale, which is great news for those who prefer DRM-free PC games. The sale is less robust than what's on offer at other Fanatical and other retailers, but the upshot is you own your games and can play without the need for launchers like Steam. GOG also offers the "Game of the Year" or "Ultimate" editions of newer Fallout games, which are not discounted at other outlets. These versions include all their expansion content at some pretty great prices.</p><h2>GOG.com Fallout Day Deals</h2><ul><li><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.jdoqocy.com%2Fclick-100770772-15232592%3Fsid%3Dsubid_value%26url%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.gog.com%2Fen%2Fgame%2Ffallout&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Ffallout-pc-and-console-games-are-on-sale-for-fallout-day%2F1100-6527326%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Fallout</a> -- $2.49 (<del>$10</del>)</li><li><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.tkqlhce.com%2Fclick-100770772-15232592%3Fsid%3Dsubid_value%26url%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.gog.com%2Fen%2Fgame%2Ffallout_2&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Ffallout-pc-and-console-games-are-on-sale-for-fallout-day%2F1100-6527326%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Fallout 2</a> -- $2.49 (<del>$10</del>)</li><li><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.tkqlhce.com%2Fclick-100770772-15232592%3Fsid%3Dsubid_value%26url%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.gog.com%2Fen%2Fgame%2Ffallout_tactics&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Ffallout-pc-and-console-games-are-on-sale-for-fallout-day%2F1100-6527326%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Fallout: Tactics</a> -- $2.49 (<del>$10</del>)</li><li><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.tkqlhce.com%2Fclick-100770772-15232592%3Fsid%3Dsubid_value%26url%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.gog.com%2Fen%2Fgame%2Ffallout_3_game_of_the_year_edition&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Ffallout-pc-and-console-games-are-on-sale-for-fallout-day%2F1100-6527326%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Fallout 3: Game of the Year Edition</a> -- $5 (<del>$20</del>)</li><li><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.dpbolvw.net%2Fclick-100770772-15232592%3Fsid%3Dsubid_value%26url%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.gog.com%2Fen%2Fgame%2Ffallout_new_vegas_ultimate_edition&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Ffallout-pc-and-console-games-are-on-sale-for-fallout-day%2F1100-6527326%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Fallout: New Vegas Ultimate Edition</a> -- $8 (<del>$20</del>)</li><li><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.kqzyfj.com%2Fclick-100770772-15232592%3Fsid%3Dsubid_value%26url%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.gog.com%2Fen%2Fgame%2Ffallout_4_game_of_the_year_edition&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Ffallout-pc-and-console-games-are-on-sale-for-fallout-day%2F1100-6527326%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Fallout 4: Game of the Year Edition</a> -- $10 (<del>$40</del>)</li></ul><p><em>Disclosure: GameSpot and Fanatical are both owned by Fandom.</em></p><div data-embed-type="pinbox" data-ref-id="4304">  <ul>                              <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/both-arcane-league-of-legends-steelbook-editions-get-big-limited-time-amazon-discounts/1100-6525146/">Both Arcane: League Of Legends Steelbook Editions Get Big, Limited-Time Amazon Discounts</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/retrorealms-arcade-halloween-ash-vs-evil-dead-special-edition-preorder-amazon/1100-6525752/">RetroRealms Special Edition Preorder Summons Michael Myers To Your House This Halloween</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-strategy-guide-book-preorder-books-of-knowledge/1100-6524739/">Elden Ring Books Of Knowledge Volume 3 Releases On Halloween, Preorders Discounted At Amazon</a></li>                          <li>         <span>+ Show More More Gaming, Tech, and Entertainment Deals &amp; Preorders Links (5)</span>       </li>          <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/amazon-kindle-colorsoft-e-ink-color-ereader-comic-books-new-kindle-models-2024/1100-6527202/">Amazon's New Full-Color Kindle Could Be A Game Changer For Comic Books</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-preorder-guide/1100-6524005/">Call Of Duty: Black Ops 6 Preorders - Bonuses, Game Pass Deals, Branded Gear, And More</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-this-75-bundle-has-all-you-need-to-play-no-console-or-pc-required/1100-6527064/">Call Of Duty: Black Ops 6 - This $75 Bundle Has All You Need To Play, No Console Or PC Required</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/black-ops-6-gets-official-corsair-gear-call-of-duty-themed-gaming-pc-keyboard-mouse-and-more/1100-6526620/">Black Ops 6 Gets Official Corsair Gear - Call Of Duty-Themed Gaming PC, Keyboard, Mouse, And More</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/lego-nes-is-on-sale-for-20-off-this-week-save-54-while-supplies-last/1100-6526872/">Lego NES Is On Sale For 20% Off This Week - Save $54 While Supplies Last</a></li>   </ul> </div>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No Man's Sky's The Cursed is a spooky expedition for Halloween set in a collapsing reality]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/no-mans-skys-the-cursed-is-a-spooky-expedition-for-halloween-set-in-a-collapsing-reality</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/no-mans-skys-the-cursed-is-a-spooky-expedition-for-halloween-set-in-a-collapsing-reality.1017132/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/no-mans-skys-the-cursed-is-a-spooky-expedition-for-halloween-set-in-a-collapsing-reality<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>Out today, with a new flying saucer ship.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/nms-cursed2.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Hello Games</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
We've only just said farewell to <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/no-mans-sky">No Man's Sky</a>'s <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/no-mans-sky-gets-reel-in-new-aquarius-fishing-update">fishing-themed Aquarius expedition</a>, but already there's another here to take its place - and this time it's a special, spooky themed event straddling the boundary between one reality and the next.
</p>
<p>
No Man's Sky's The Cursed expedition starts today and runs for a comparatively brisk three weeks, taking space explorers on an adventure that'll see them navigating a collapsing reality where time can shift unexpectedly, "day spinning to night at a vertigo inducing rate".
</p>
<p>
And that's not the worst of it; as players journey across this twilight universe and the boundaries of reality weaken, they'll be haunted by visions, voices, and spectral entities - some benign, others considerably less so - from another dimension. Developer Hello Games teases "enemies and boss battles at a scale not seen before in No Man's Sky."
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="No Man's Sky The Cursed Expedition Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/QyPJUtsQiEY?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>No Man's Sky The Cursed Expedition Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/QyPJUtsQiEY?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/QyPJUtsQiEY?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>No Man's Sky - The Cursed trailer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QyPJUtsQiEY" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
To survive this spectral onslaught, players must maintain their Anomaly Suppressor - which replaces their Exosuit's usual hazard protection - and stay safe in their Boundary Starship, a new Giger-inspired flying saucer. And with no hyperdrive technology to rely on, they'll also need to traverse the cosmos using No Man's Sky's ancient portal network.
</p>
<p>
"Haunting voices leak through from another dimension, providing guidance, information, strange blueprints... and mystery," Hello Games teases. "Players will have to decide who these voices belong to, where they are coming from, and if they are to be trusted..."
</p>
<p>
By completing The Cursed expedition's various milestone objectives, players can unlock a range of exclusive rewards, including a Cthulhu-esque Horror Exosuit customisation, bioluminescent pets, and their very own UFO-like Boundary Herald Starship. Full patch notes for today's update can be <a href="https://www.nomanssky.com/2024/10/expedition-sixteen-the-cursed/">found on Hello Games' website</a>.
</p><p>
Additionally, the studio confirms there's still more in store for No Man's Sky, including "several more surprises" due "in the coming weeks". One of those is an update specifically designed to take advantage of PlayStation 5 Pro at launch in November, but we've also yet to hear more about the Worlds Part 2 release teased alongside the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/no-mans-skys-borrows-some-of-light-no-fires-fancy-tech-for-a-planetary-overhaul-in-latest-update">massive Worlds Part 1 update</a> back in July, so perhaps that'll also rear its head before the year is through.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Romance of the Three Kingdoms 8 Remake Review]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/10/23/romance-of-the-three-kingdoms-8-remake-review/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/romance-of-the-three-kingdoms-8-remake-review.1017126/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/10/23/romance-of-the-three-kingdoms-8-remake-review/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
			
			<p><a href="http://thesixthaxis.com/tag/romance-of-the-three-kingdoms-8-remake">Romance of the Three Kingdoms 8 Remake</a> presents one of the series’ strongest instalments for both a new generation of strategy gamer and long-time fans, supercharging the PS2 original with new content and features. For those completely new to ROTK, it’s a grand strategy series that’s been around since the 1980s and takes place during the Three Kingdoms era in Ancient China – around the third century CE – in a time of nationwide turmoil that gives rise to stoic heroes and treacherous villains all vying for power.</p>
<p><iframe title="Romance of the Three Kingdoms 8 Remake - Second Trailer | PS5 &amp; PS4 Games" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Febv7UPopIw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Publisher <a href="http://thesixthaxis.com/tag/koei-tecmo">Koei Tecmo</a> has a well-established affinity for this historic setting. <a href="http://thesixthaxis.com/tag/dynasty-warriors">Dynasty Warriors</a> – arguably the company’s flagship franchise – is also based on the somewhat fictionalised Romance of the Kingdoms, though it couldn’t be any more different than <a href="http://thesixthaxis.com/tag/koei">Koei’</a>s strategy games. Where Dynasty Warriors focuses purely on high octane, button-bashing action, ROTK immerses players in a dense web of menus and dialogue exchanges that steer you on the path to conquest and unification.</p>


<p>In Romance of the Three Kingdoms 8 Remake, you can tackle a number of historic campaigns, selecting from a host of different factions, ranks, and characters to play as. At one end of the scale you can act as a ruler, with full military and political control. At the other end, you can become a free officer who, as the name implies, is free to wander Ancient China, aligning with whoever they wish, or potentially gathering their own army and territories. There are plenty of officer roles that fall in between the two, offering different privileges based on your rank and influence within a faction.</p>


<p>Romance of the Three Kingdoms 8 Remake is menu-heavy from the word go. That’s pretty much a staple for any game that falls under the grand strategy banner, though thankfully there are plenty of helpful tutorials on hand and Koei does a great job of easing players in without completely bombarding them, gently gesturing in the right direction without any obnoxious guard rails. There are a myriad of moving parts though it won’t take long for lapsed strategy fans and newcomers to get a grip on how everything works.</p>
<p>From slandering a rival officer and hosting banquets to increasing public order, you’ll have a limited number of points to spend on actions per turn. Then, by resting, time will progress to the next month, with each three-month season punctuated by a meeting of parliament (if you are aligned with a ruler). This is where more impactful decisions are made such as forging alliances, conducting espionage, or even marching to battle. These choices are made by high-ranking officers, of course, though even as a small retainer you can still have your say and put your name forward. Saying that, playing ROTK at the bottom of the ladder seems like a strange choice and one that leaves you fairly powerless until you gradually work your way through the ranks.</p>
<p>Compared to more recent entries in the series, ROTK 8 focuses on characters building relationships between one another. Although there’s plenty of planning, and politicising, you’ll spend most of your time simply getting to know your fellow officers, forging bonds that have a multitude of positive effects. Upon meeting certain conditions, you’ll also unlock Tales – character interactions that feed into a bigger, overarching narrative, usually reflecting what happened during specific points in history.</p>

<p>With the game having originally launched in 2001, there has been a significant visual overhaul from top to bottom. For a start, the city and campaign maps are far more dynamic and easier to navigate without shedding their charming ROTK aesthetic. Each officer is brought to life through gorgeous character artwork that transitions into 3D whenever you engage in the Duel and Debate mini-games, adding a welcome layer of immersion.</p>
<p>As for the battle system, there’s nothing overly complex. After deployment, armies will take it in turns to move their units, engage opponents, and activate stratagems. The outcome of most battles can usually be determined by who has the bigger army, though there is scope to tactically outmanoeuvre your foe, making use of the different unit types and arranging them in formations that confer morale bonuses. Table-turning stratagems can also come into play as well as emergent events such as having an enemy general challenge you to a one-on-one duel.</p>
<p>Through achieving dominance, both on and off the battlefield, you’ll eventually expand your territory and solidify an inner circle of confidents including a spouse and sworn siblings. Needless to say, the road to either total conquest or reaching any of the historical campaign victory requirements will take a very, very long time with many meandering paths depending on how you want your story to play out.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Towers of Aghasba launches in Early Access on November 19]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/10/towers-of-aghasba-launches-in-early-access-on-november-19</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/towers-of-aghasba-launches-in-early-access-on-november-19.1017123/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/10/towers-of-aghasba-launches-in-early-access-on-november-19<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Open-world fantasy builder priced at $29.99.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Open-world fantasy builder <em><a title="Games > Towers of Aghasba [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/towers-of-aghasba">Towers of Aghasba</a></em> will launch in Early Access for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,229 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a> and <a title="Platforms > PC [21,532 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2178070/Towers_of_Aghasba/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> on November 19 for $29.99, developer <a title="Companies > Dreamlit Games [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/dreamlit-games">Dreamlit Games</a> announced. <span id="more-923137"></span></p><p>The Early Access release will include the following content:</p><ul><li>Three types of unique ecosystems to restore and grow.</li><li>Three types of towns to construct.</li><li>Over 40 creatures to unlock.</li><li>Over 120 plants to grow and harvest.</li><li>Over 150 decoration recipes.</li><li>Exploration across vast <a title="Genres > Open-World [502 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/open-world">open-world</a> lands.</li><li>Ruins and relics to discover, unlocking ancient knowledge.</li><li>Variety activities (such as fishing).</li><li>Much more.</li></ul><p>Users who pre-order the PlayStation 5 version will receive the following exclusive additional content:</p><ul><li>Custom Harelope Mount Design – Ride across the lands of Aghasba in style with a unique design for your majestic harelope mount.</li><li>Five unique decorations.</li><li>Three exclusive masks.</li></ul><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Dreamlit Games:</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>Towers of Aghasba</em> tells the story of the Shimu people, forced to flee their homeland when a mysterious force, known as the Withered, ravaged the land. As junior architect, it’s your job to rebuild the villages of your once-mighty civilization and nurture Aghasba’s ecosystems back to life. Core gameplay lets you traverse the wide world of Aghasba— scaling colossal mountains, gliding across jaw-dropping vistas, and befriending majestic creatures. Craft weapons, armors, and elixirs to aid in battle against monsters afflicting the land with rot, cultivate outlandish flora and fauna as you restore ecosystems, and uncover ancient knowledge hidden among ruins. Back at homebase, flex your creativity by designing a bustling civilization and customizing your island home with decorations. Once your villages and ecosystems are in place, invite up to three friends to explore your island, trade items, hunt creatures, and battle the Withered as a team.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Explore the Island of Aghasba</strong> – Traverse varied terrain, scale colossal mountains and gaze out upon jaw-dropping vistas, all brought to life in a vibrant, high-fidelity art style. Befriend strange and memorable creatures, learn the storied history of the Shimu people and uncover the dark origins of the Withered.</li><li><strong>Rebuild the Shimu Civilization</strong> – Build sprawling settlements and watch them come alive as they’re inhabited by members of the Shimu tribe. Lose yourself in a rich creative sandbox as you decorate and construct your villages in a way that’s uniquely you.</li><li><strong>Restore Aghasba’s Ecosystems</strong> – Restore life to a devastated land by nurturing the growth of beautifully bizarre ecosystems. Grow plant life, attract &amp; feed animals, and work with the gods of Aghasba to revitalize the island.</li><li><strong>Brave the Withered Lands</strong> – Much of Aghasba is still infested with the Withered, a dark force that absorbs the life from all it touches. Craft weapons, armor and elixirs before venturing into the Withered Lands and battle bloodthirsty Withered monsters, gradually ridding the island of the Withered plague.</li><li><strong>Invite Friends to Your Island</strong> – Once you build your villages and grow your ecosystems how you want, it’s time to show them off! Invite up to 3 friends to explore your island, trade items, hunt creatures and battle the Withered as a team.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below. View a new set of screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/towers-of-aghasba/october-23-2024/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>Gameplay Showcase + Early Access Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Towers of Aghasba: Gameplay Showcase + Release Date Announcement!" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/-Cm-02rxXdY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><span>Screenshots</span></h2><div id="carousel_923138"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Asus ROG Phone 9 Revealed, Launches November 19]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/asus-rog-phone-9-revealed-launches-november-19/1100-6527330/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/asus-rog-phone-9-revealed-launches-november-19.1017120/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/asus-rog-phone-9-revealed-launches-november-19/1100-6527330/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6527330">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Asus has revealed its new smartphone, the ROG Phone 9. Like the previous models, this is a gaming-centric Android smartphone that packs an impressive amount of technology inside its frame, and Asus says it'll be released on November 19.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4389212-asus-rog-phone-9.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4389212" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4389212-asus-rog-phone-9.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4389212"></a><figcaption>Asus ROG Phone 9</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4389212-asus-rog-phone-9.jpg"></figure><p>The new model will be powered by the SnapDragon 8 Elite chipset, and it's one of the first smartphones to utilize this new hardware. This mobile platform also includes a second-generation Qualcomm Oryon CPU and the enhanced Adreno GPU, which theoretically, will make for smooth gaming experiences on the ROG Phone 9. Asus has also confirmed that the phone will continue to have a gamer-centric design, as it showed off a device with sharp angles that match the general aesthetic of other Republic of Gamers devices.</p><p>There's also a dot-matrix display on the rear with this model, which isn't unusual to see on Asus hardware. Several of its ROG laptops sport a customizable panel and Asus also makes a controller that includes a tiny OLED panel that can be used to convey useful information when you're playing games.</p><p>Meanwhile, Apple has just released its new line of<a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/iphone-16-has-hardware-accelerated-ray-tracing-and-native-support-for-aaa-games/1100-6526379/" data-ref-id="1100-6526379"> iPhone 16 smartphones</a>. It has a five-core GPU and a new A18 GPU, and both the iPhone 16 and 16 Plus support hardware-accelerated ray tracing.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ajU2oDdeCgw" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/ajU2oDdeCgw" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>While there are only a handful of games that can really push the iPhone hardware to its limits--like iOS versions of Resident Evil 7: Biohazard, Death Stranding, and Assassin's Creed Mirage--it's still a fascinating time to see how Apple is putting a <a href="https://youtu.be/ajU2oDdeCgw" rel="nofollow ">greater emphasis on using its smartphones and tablets for gaming</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/108490194306897153177?rel=author">Darryn Bonthuys</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Black Ops 6 Has An Option To Pay For Better Audio]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/black-ops-6-has-an-option-to-pay-for-better-audio/1100-6527328/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/black-ops-6-has-an-option-to-pay-for-better-audio.1017117/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/black-ops-6-has-an-option-to-pay-for-better-audio/1100-6527328/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6527328">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>In the week of its release, it's been revealed that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-2024-release-date-trailer-news/1100-6523361/" data-ref-id="1100-6523361">Call of Duty: Black Ops 6</a> has an option to pay $20 for personalized spatial audio. The third-party audio tool is built into Black Ops 6's settings menu, and will also be coming to Warzone with Season 1.</p><p>A screenshot of the audio menu was shared by COD content-creator <a href="https://x.com/Omeqa_/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Omeqa</a> on X (formerly Twitter), showing a pop-up offering a free trial for Embody's Immerse spatial audio. The service creates a personalized spatial audio profile based on players' head and ear shape, and costs $20 for five years.</p><p>The paid service is part of the Enhanced Headphone Mode setting, for which a <a href="https://x.com/Omeqa_/status/1848487292010434833" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">follow-up screenshot</a> is displayed prominently in the game's audio options. The setting uses a universal profile by default, with the option to pay for a personalized one.</p><p>Black Ops 6 isn't the only game to offer personalized spatial audio through Embody, but it's one of only a few to currently partner with the company. Final Fantasy XIV has offered personalized audio through Embody for a few years, while Cyberpunk 2077 added the option earlier this year.</p><div tabindex="0" data-id="318781621" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6465298,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Call%20of%20Duty%3A%20Black%20Ops%206%20-%20Black%20Ops%20Story%20So%20Far%20Trailer&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:104,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:false,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-black-ops-story-so-far-trailer\/2300-6465298\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465298\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465298\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465298\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6465298&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6465298,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6527328&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;call-of-duty-black-ops-6&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;xbox-series-x,playstation-5,pc,playstation-4,xbox-one&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;activision,microsoft-game-studios&quot;,&quot;franchise&quot;:&quot;call-of-duty&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;franchiseRoot&quot;:&quot;call-of-duty&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6465298},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6465298\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;Publisher Asset&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4380589-11.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/4ritACm0.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1728396900,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="4ritACm0" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle" data-embed-type="video" data-ref-id="2300-6465298" data-src="/videos/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-black-ops-story-so-far-trailer/2300-6465298/" data-width="100%" data-height="100%" data-video-start="0"><div><p>Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 - Black Ops Story So Far Trailer</p><div><p>         Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?       </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!       </p></div></div><p>       Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.     </p><p>       This video has an invalid file format.     </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div><p>While Embody isn't the only third-party company out there offering personalized spatial audio for games, it's rare to see the option built into the game's menus. Unlike other third-party services, Embody's spatial audio is developed in tandem with each game's developers--however this means you have to pay for a separate "Immerse Gamepack" for every game you want to use it with.</p><p>While Embody's Gamepacks aren't overly expensive for a five-year period, the jury is out on whether they're worth paying for at all. Many Final Fantasy XIV players aren't impressed with the audio offering, according to <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/ffxiv/comments/13pvico/immerse_gamepack/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Reddit posts</a> on the subject, and some have pointed out that what Embody provides is not too different from Dolby Atmos.</p><p>Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-2024-release-date-trailer-news/1100-6523361/" data-ref-id="1100-6523361">arrives on October 25</a>, with preloading available now. If you do want to check out Embody's personalized audio options, it's compatible with the PC, Xbox Series X|S, and PlayStation 5 editions of the game.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A Rayman Remake Is in Development by Ubisoft; Prince of Persia Developers, Series’ Creator Are Part of the Development Team]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/rayman-remake-prince-of-persia-team/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/a-rayman-remake-is-in-development-by-ubisoft-prince-of-persia-developers-series%E2%80%99-creator-are-part-of-the-development-team.1017105/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/rayman-remake-prince-of-persia-team/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>A Rayman remake is currently in the works, and members of the recently disbanded Prince of Persia: The Lost Crown development team are said to be working on the game alongside the series' creator, Michel Ancel.</p>
<p>As reported today by&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/rayman-remake-team-prince-of-persia/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Insider Gaming</a>, this remake, known internally as Project Steambot, is getting put together by a team located primarily at Ubisoft Milan, the studio behind many successful projects, including the Mario + Rabbids series.&nbsp;<span>Members of the recently&nbsp;<a href="https://wccftech.com/prince-of-persia-the-lost-crown-sequel-isnt-happening-due-to-low-sales-ubisoft-disbanded-the-team/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">disbanded Ubisoft Montpellier studio</a>, the team behind the latest entry in the Rayman series, Rayman Origins, and Legends, are part of the development team, and the series creator, Michel Ancel, is also on board as a consultant.</span>&nbsp;His presence, however, is causing concern among the development team members due to his toxic leadership, which came to light in 2020 following the abandoning of the Beyond Good &amp; Evil 2 development.</p>
<p>As Ubisoft has yet to confirm a Rayman remake is indeed in the works, we have to take everything revealed by Insider Gaming today with a grain of salt. The outlet proved to be extremely reliable in the past, however, so there's a very good chance that the classic platform game series is indeed coming back in the future.</p>
<p>The disbanding of the Ubisoft Montpellier team is definitely disappointing, given how Prince of Persia: The Lost Crown is among the best Metroidvania games released in the past few years, but it is good to know that some of its team members are possibly working on this Rayman remake. You can learn more about the team's excellent final game by checking out my <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/prince-of-persia-the-lost-crown-who-needs-sands-time/">review.</a></p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PlayStation 5 System Software 24.07-10.20.00 Brings Activities, Performance and Stability Improvements]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/playstation-5-system-software-24-07-10-20-00-performance-improvements/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/playstation-5-system-software-24-07-10-20-00-brings-activities-performance-and-stability-improvements.1017099/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/playstation-5-system-software-24-07-10-20-00-performance-improvements/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>A new PlayStation 5 system software update is now live, introducing Activities improvements, among other things.</p>
<p>The 24.07-10.20.00 system software improves the console's Activities feature. From now on, each activity will display In Progress, Not Started, or Completed, depending on its current status, with spoilers continuing to be hidden even after these changes. The new system software also brings the usual unspecified performance and stability improvements and enhanced messages and usability on some screens.</p>
<p>The previous major PlayStation 5 system software update, <a href="https://wccftech.com/playstation-5-system-software-24-06-3d-audio/">update 24.06</a>, was released last month. It introduced some new features to the system, such as the Welcome hub, personalized 3D audio profiles, Remote Play improvements, and more. The Welcome hub is a personalized space on the console's home screen that can be customized with different widgets that display the console's storage, battery levels for accessories, online friends, trophies, and more. The Remote Play improvements include the option to enable Remote Play for select users on the system.</p>
<p>The latest major PlayStation 5 system software update also introduced some changes that impacted several games, such as Final Fantasy XVI, requiring Sony to release another<a href="https://wccftech.com/playstation-5-system-software-24-06-10-01-00/"> firmware update to address the issue.</a></p>
<p>More information on the latest PlayStation 5 system software updates can be found on the console's <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-my/support/hardware/ps5/system-software-info/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">official website</a>.</p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Towers of Aghasba Has You Revitalize an Island with New Mechanics]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/towers-of-aghasba-hands-off-preview-revitalize-island-with-new-mechanics</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/towers-of-aghasba-has-you-revitalize-an-island-with-new-mechanics.1017096/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/towers-of-aghasba-hands-off-preview-revitalize-island-with-new-mechanics<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em><a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="b2ff7c2f-3a27-4fa4-89cd-ea40cb660f04" href="https://techraptor.net/games/towers-of-aghasba">Towers of Aghasba</a>&nbsp;</em>is an adventure <a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="taxonomy_term" data-entity-uuid="79049f40-72c8-4ae4-beb2-b4522e0ae471" href="https://techraptor.net/genre/city-builder">city builder</a> being developed by Dreamlit Games and set to release in Early Access on November 19, 2024. It features a variety of mechanics from multiple genres, including base building, exploration, combat, animal taming, multiplayer mode, and more. When offered the chance to get a more in-depth look at the gameplay and learn about the inspiration behind&nbsp;<em>Towers of Aghasba</em>, I jumped at the chance. Though the preview was hands-off, my excitement is piqued and I cannot wait until it launches.</p>
<h2><em>Towers of Aghasba&nbsp;</em>Preview Introduces Exciting Features</h2>
<p>To kick off the preview, Dreamlit Games CEO Khang Le dove into the inspiration behind&nbsp;<em>Towers of Aghasba.</em>&nbsp;Inspired&nbsp;by Studio Ghibli movies, <a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="2f103da7-e1c4-4b2e-b0ff-a20e181b64c1" href="https://techraptor.net/games/animal-crossing-new-horizons"><em>A</em><em>nimal Crossing: New Horizons</em></a>, and various African tribes, the game blends multiplayer cooperation with expansive city building, exploration-driven adventure, and environmental restoration. What you get is a responsive world that differs from other players depending on two key locations.&nbsp;</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/towers-of-aghasba-colossal-seed-tree.jpg?itok=Yb5M93Gv 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/towers-of-aghasba-colossal-seed-tree.jpg?itok=kx4Z4e-m 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>You play as a member of the Shimu people as they return to their ancestral home. Having been promised a paradise, the land is laid barren due to the Withered, a disease that sent your people fleeing from the island years ago. There are pockets of desert where you can build your base, but the most important thing to do is plant a colossal seed.</p>
<p>Unlike most open world crafting games,&nbsp;<em>Towers of Aghasba</em>&nbsp;doesn't give you a plethora of resources to harvest at the beginning or your adventure. You have to start restoring the environment if you want materials to craft with.&nbsp;</p>
<p>This is where your island will start to become different from your friends. Depending on the location you plant the seed, the animals that return to the area, as well as the plants that grow, will be different. Plant it near the ocean and you'll get more sea creatures. Plant it at the top of a cliff, you could end up with more birds.</p>
<p>This also gets impacted by the different biomes you grow your seed in. The desert will produce different flora and fauna than a swamp. At the start of Early Access, there will be three biomes to choose your starting location from and restore.&nbsp;</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/towers-of-aghasba-base-building.jpg?itok=QF-l3r8D 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/towers-of-aghasba-base-building.jpg?itok=xhZe4XLZ 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>Thanks to this mechanic, sharing resources with your friends and other players can be extremely important. Trading for materials you don't have available on your island is just one way to utilize multiplayer.</p>
<p>You can also party up and explore Withered areas, which are populated with Withered enemies. These corrupted creatures are aggressive and you can be killed. Adventuring through these zones is the only way to learn the cause of the disease. If you're looking for a relaxing experience, you can visit your friend's islands and go for a tour of their city.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Another ecological focus of&nbsp;<em>Towers of Aghasba</em>&nbsp;is caring for animals and sustainable hunting and gathering. Instead of stockpiling meat, leather, or feathers, there are significant consequences to overhunting a species of animal.</p>
<p>Pushed to the extreme you can cause a creature to go extinct, which impacts the whole ecosystem in that area. Instead, caring for wounded animals, harvesting what you need, and attempting to farm resources in a non-lethal manner are rewarded. There are over 40 creatures that can spawn in your environment and 120 plants that can grow.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Once you do have enough materials you can start to build your base. The location you choose can impact what type of city you create, even though there are over 150 decorative elements to choose from. There are different focuses, such as a farming or mining city, that will differentiate your creation from others. While you can put as many crafting items in one place, picking from one of the three types of cities can allow more efficient production.&nbsp;</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/towers-of-aghasba-withered-combat.jpg?itok=KSNR5wdb 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/towers-of-aghasba-withered-combat.jpg?itok=xDPPRuSq 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>It may seem like taming animals, growing plants, and building a city are all there is to do in&nbsp;<em>Towers of Aghasba</em>, but you'd be wrong. There are other activities, like collecting ancient relics, fishing, swimming, and gliding around the world. These are all available at the start of early access, with a roadmap of what's to come in the future becoming available when the game launches.&nbsp;</p>
<p>As a die hard <a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="9e2fac55-7c08-4df9-8cd3-a855c0dff7df" href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/guides/survival-games-why-we-keep-on-coming-back-for-more">survival crafting</a> game fan, I am super excited to get my hands on&nbsp;<em>Towers of Aghasba</em>. Not only is the world gorgeously produced with hand-painted backgrounds, but the unique spin on many of the "expected" survival and base building mechanics has me seriously interested.</p>
<p>I can't wait to see how restoring the world of the Shimu people looks in real time and how these changes can impact other games being developed in the genre.&nbsp;</p>
<hr><p><em>TechRaptor was invited to see Towers of Aghasba by the game's developer.</em></p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
<div><p> | Staff Writer / Contributor</p></div>
<p>Ashley Erickson is an experienced writer focusing on the video games industry since 2013. Starting off with cosplay features, she moved to game guides and… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/ashley-erikson">More about Ashley</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sunderfolk GM Anjali Bhimani Explains How She Voices Multiple Characters]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/interviews/sunderfolk-gm-anjali-bhimani-explains-how-she-voices-multiple-characters</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sunderfolk-gm-anjali-bhimani-explains-how-she-voices-multiple-characters.1017093/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/interviews/sunderfolk-gm-anjali-bhimani-explains-how-she-voices-multiple-characters<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/features/anjali-bhimani-talks-with-us-about-lady-amangeaux-and-dimension-20-ravening-war">Anjali Bhimani</a> is an actor, writer, TTRPG player, and recently announced GM for <em>Sunderfolk</em>, a unique title that makes board-game night more accessible for family and friends, Bhimani takes on the role of narrator as well as voicing all the NPCs. Reaching out for her thoughts on the experience, I was able to chat with her about <em>Sunderfolk</em>.</p>
<h2>Reinventing Game Night with <em>Sunderfolk</em></h2>
<p><em>Sunderfolk</em>&nbsp;is a <a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="b94efb2d-271e-4538-9184-818a6bdea666" href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/features/in-ttrpg-rolling-dice-or-not-doesnt-matter">TTRPG</a> video game with a fully voiced cast of characters, different classes to pick from, and a focus on storytelling. Developed by Dreamhaven, the studio created by Blizzard co-founder Mike Morhaime, it's the first internally created title to be announced. The team includes numerous former Blizzard devs, including&nbsp;Chris Sigaty who was the <a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="ef33aa60-a7ad-4324-adbf-4ca288d1e741" href="https://techraptor.net/games/starcraft-ii-wings-of-liberty"><em>StarCraft II</em></a>&nbsp;executive producer and&nbsp;is heading up the&nbsp;<em>Sunderfolk</em>&nbsp;project.</p>

<p>The dev team isn't the only all star working on&nbsp;the project.&nbsp;Bhimani is a veteran actor with both on screen and voice-over credits. She's deeply committed to the tabletop community. She's played&nbsp;<a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="3579fb91-ffa9-4c99-a750-de9f92ba642f" href="https://techraptor.net/games/dungeons-dragons"><em>Dungeons &amp; Dragons</em></a>&nbsp;since she was a child with her brother, as well as board games with her family.&nbsp; A regular guest on&nbsp;<a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="a49b5305-f71e-4b04-a989-6db6823aa8cc" href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/interviews/critical-role-and-legend-of-vox-machina-s3-cast-discuss-changing-story">Critical Role</a>, she's also a member of DesiQuest, has appeared on <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/features/zac-oyama-talks-fantasy-high-junior-year-gorgugs-development-and-how-elmville-is">Dimension20</a>, and runs her own charity campaign, Puppy Roll.&nbsp;</p>
<p>"There's a connection you can have with people through game playing that doesn't necessarily come in other places."</p>
<p><i>Sunderfolk </i>is&nbsp;not a traditional tabletop game, however. Before diving into the specifics of her role as GM, Bhimani gave me more details on the game itself and how it differs from what's currently on the market.</p>
<p>"The barrier to entry to a lot of TTRPGs is the amount of stuff you have to learn. Trying to bring more friends into that world is sometimes challenging," Bhimani lamented.</p>
<p>Depending on the system, prospective players can spend hours reading lore, learning what different dice rolls mean, creating a character, and actually setting up the space to play. The barrier to entry for many TTRPGs is so high that people don't even bother to learn about another game system, try to find faster ways to play, or continue to show any interest at all in the community.&nbsp;</p>
<p>"My feeling, much like what they've done with&nbsp;<em>Sunderfolk</em>,&nbsp;is that as long as you know how to have fun and tell a good story, that should be it. That's all it is, as long as you're there to have a good time and share in this experience with your fellow players."</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/sunderfolk-town-screenshot.jpg?itok=nsXLkJN7 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/sunderfolk-town-screenshot.jpg?itok=HqLf-Yjs 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>When it comes to bringing more people to the world of tabletop,&nbsp;<em>Sunderfolk</em>&nbsp;is on the right track.</p>
<p>"I was really, really taken by both the quality of the work they had already put together, even before we started, the deck, and the art. And the deep love that they clearly had, not just for the tabletop community, but for the essence of how gaming brings people together."&nbsp;</p>
<p>This focus on bringing people together for game night to tell a good story is what prompted Bhimani to join&nbsp;<em>Sunderfolk&nbsp;</em>as the GM, voicing the narrator for the game as well as all the various NPCs.</p>
<p>"The work I do as an actor has played into that. Also knowing that, much like you'd want to do in a <a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="taxonomy_term" data-entity-uuid="ea988cf8-aaa8-4b3e-839c-a01fc3d3270b" href="https://techraptor.net/topic/voice-acting">voice over</a> situation, if I was in an animated series and I was doing all the different voices and it was only audio like a podcast, you would need to hear the difference to know who was talking," Bhimani stated.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Diving in more on&nbsp;<em>Sunderfolk </em>itself<em>,</em>&nbsp;there are a number of NPCs that are ready to steal the show. From a button mushroom to Sinclair the mole and Amaia the penguin, there are plenty of characters to interact with in the narrative-heavy game.</p>
<p>The great part is there's no prep, and if your party can't get through a quest or need more time, you can pick the game up right where you left off. It's also child friendly, making it an easy addition to a family game night.&nbsp;</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/sunderfolk-amaia-dialogue.jpg?itok=wO8eE1OA 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/sunderfolk-amaia-dialogue.jpg?itok=XytsgDek 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p><em>Sunderfolk</em>&nbsp;takes a story and puts it on a shared screen. All the tools needed are at your fingertips on your phone or mobile device. "There's nothing like it, so I don't specifically know what to compare it to," she explained. Once you get your friends and family together, just turn on the game to start adventuring.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Bhimani then expanded on the feel of <em>Sunderfolk</em>. "There are sections that will feel a little bit like a storybook that are similar to cutscenes that we see in certain video games. Then there are also sections that are just full-on gameplay grid situations where you will be in battle or encounter of some kind."</p>
<p>The Dreamhaven team have created an access point for many new to TTRPGs that want to learn more about that genre,&nbsp;experience a different kind of game night, or are too busy to put together a campaign.&nbsp;<em>Sunderfolk&nbsp;</em>is looking to become a bridge between video game enthusiasts and TTRPG players. With an experienced GM helming the storytelling, it could shake up the industry.</p>
<p>Before wrapping up the interview, I briefly touched on Bhimani's other work, especially her charity efforts with live-play campaigns like Puppy Roll.&nbsp;Puppy Roll is a finalist in the Sustainability, Environment, and Climate category of the Anthem Awards for 2024 due to it raising money for animals.&nbsp;Noting that playing TTRPGs is fun, she also wants to have an additional benefit aside from entertainment.</p>
<p>"When we get a chance to create something that is super fun to watch and to play and to create and we get to make a difference in the world, it's really lovely that that effort has been noticed," Bhimani said.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
<div><p> | Staff Writer / Contributor</p></div>
<p>Ashley Erickson is an experienced writer focusing on the video games industry since 2013. Starting off with cosplay features, she moved to game guides and… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/ashley-erikson">More about Ashley</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nature-rekindling sandbox Towers of Aghasba gets early access release date]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/nature-rekindling-sandbox-towers-of-aghasba-gets-early-access-release-date</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nature-rekindling-sandbox-towers-of-aghasba-gets-early-access-release-date.1017087/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/nature-rekindling-sandbox-towers-of-aghasba-gets-early-access-release-date<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Towers-of-Aghasba_-Gameplay-Showcase-%2B-Release-Date-Announcement!-7-18-screenshot.png?width=1200&amp;height=1200&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Dreamlit Games</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
Cast your mind back a month, and you may remember a promising-looking open-world sandbox popping up in <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/everything-announced-sonys-playstation-state-of-play">Sony's September PlayStation State of Play</a>. That game was Towers of Aghasba, and it now has an early access release date for PC and PS5: 19th November. 
</p>
<p>A mix of sandbox survival in a land of big beasts, and an overarching quest of refertilising and rebuilding its ruined open world, Towers of Aghasba stood out as offering a larger gameplay arc than simply rubbing a few sticks together and sticking up a couple of wooden shacks. 
</p>
<p>Here, the emphasis is on renewing Aghasba's world (presumably, named Aghasba), returning its dusty ruins to grassy fields and then growing crops or encouraging animal life. You can hunt said animal life for quick rewards, or take the slower, kinder approach and... well, the trailer below shows you getting some kind of colourful hearts in return.</p>
<p>The whole thing looks a treat too, which always helps, even if you can spot its various gameplay influences a mile off. Here's an extended look at what Towers of Aghasba's early access has to offer:</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Towers of Aghasba: Gameplay Showcase + Release Date Announcement!" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/-Cm-02rxXdY?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Towers of Aghasba: Gameplay Showcase + Release Date Announcement!</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/-Cm-02rxXdY?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/-Cm-02rxXdY?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Towers of Aghasba early access gameplay footage.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-Cm-02rxXdY" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
Towers of Aghasba is the first project from Dreamlit Games, a small Californian startup founded in 2020. Intrigued? You can find it over on <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/concept/10010067">PlayStation Store</a>.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elden Ring Shadow of the Erdtree Drives Up Bandai Namco’s Earnings Forecast]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-earnings-bandai-namco/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-drives-up-bandai-namco%E2%80%99s-earnings-forecast.1017075/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-earnings-bandai-namco/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The Elden Ring Shadow of the Erdtree expansion has significantly increased publisher Bandai Namco's earnings forecast.</p>
<p>As <a href="https://www.bandainamco.co.jp/files/E_20241023E38080E6A5ADE7B8BEE4BA88E683B3E4BFAEE6AD.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">confirmed</a> today by the Japanese publisher today, the success of the expansion of the latest game by FromSoftware and repeat sales of the base game have increased the earnings forecast<br>
for the current fiscal year, with significant increases in sales, operating, recurring, and net profit. The expansion, in particular, is considered to have become a hit in markets worldwide, according to the publisher, while the base game is continuing to perform well.</p>
<p>It's no surprise that Elden Ring Shadow of the Erdtree has been successful enough to significantly boost its publisher's earnings forecasts. While the expansion is basically just more of the base game, the high quality of the new content makes it a must-have for all those who previously journeyed to The Lands Between, as I highlighted in my <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-worthy-of-the-greater-wills-blessing/">review.</a></p>
<p><em>Elden Ring: Shadow of the Erdtree expands the base game by offering more of what made it one of the best open-world games ever. It features a well-sized map dense with secrets to discover, new masterfully designed dungeons, and introduces new, fun tools to help the Tarnished tackle some of the most challenging enemies in the game's dark and brutal world. While the lack of new gameplay mechanics may disappoint some, don't let this deter you. Shadow of the Erdtree is every bit as good as the base game, and it is an essential purchase for all those who loved FromSoftware's amazing action role-playing game.</em></p>
<p>Elden Ring Shadow of the Erdtree is now available on PC, PlayStation 5, PlayStation 4, Xbox Series X, Xbox Series S, and Xbox One worldwide.</p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rayman Remake Development Bolstered by Former Prince of Persia Team]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/rayman-remake-team-prince-of-persia/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/rayman-remake-development-bolstered-by-former-prince-of-persia-team.1017072/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/rayman-remake-team-prince-of-persia/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>It was just yesterday that the news broke regarding the (now former) team working on Prince of Persia: The Lost Crown. It was claimed that the team had been disbanded and that a sequel pitch for the game had been shot down by Ubisoft, who had reportedly ‘made it clear’ just weeks after the game was released that these very steps would be on the cards.</p>



<p>Now, Insider Gaming is exclusively reporting that former Prince of Persia team members have migrated into another squad – one working on a Rayman Remake. But not all is going well.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-from-one-to-another">From One to Another</h2>



<p>Per our sources close to the situation, the unannounced Rayman Remake is under development with the codename ‘Project Steambot’, and it’s being pieced together by a team located primarily at Ubisoft Milan. This studio has directly contributed to the creation of more than two dozen Ubisoft games over a twenty-year window.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Our sources have also confirmed that Michel Ancel, the creator of Rayman (and other franchises like Beyond Good &amp; Evil), is in place as a consultant. This has raised some concerns among team members, least of all because Ancel found himself embroiled in a ‘toxic leadership’ debacle pioneered <a href="https://www.liberation.fr/images/2020/09/25/jeu-video-les-coulisses-effarantes-d-un-blockbuster-geant_1800522/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">by a French news outlet in 2020</a>.</p>



<p>That is enough to have cast a less-than-popular light on the Rayman Remake project internally at Ubisoft, even if Ancel is only on board from a consultancy perspective.</p>



<p>It has been estimated that around a dozen developers from the disbanded Prince of Persia team have migrated to work on the Rayman Remake. Elsewhere, other developers have pivoted to work on Beyond Good &amp; Evil 2 and the next Ghost Recon title.</p>



<p>Are you looking forward to a Rayman Remake? Let us know on the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out our <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-6-pay-to-hear-scandal/">explanation of the Black Ops 6 ‘pay-to-hear’ scandal</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EXCLUSIVE – Prince of Persia Devs Move to Three New Projects at Ubisoft]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/prince-of-persia-three-new-projects/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/exclusive-%E2%80%93-prince-of-persia-devs-move-to-three-new-projects-at-ubisoft.1017069/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/prince-of-persia-three-new-projects/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Yesterday, a new rumor revealed that Ubisoft had disbanded its Prince of Persia: The Lost Crown team after the game failed to meet internal expectations. It was somewhat of a murky picture as to what actually happened, but Ubisoft has since clarified in a statement confirming some of the details.</p>



<p><span>In a statement to&nbsp;<a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/ubisoft-responds-to-report-prince-of-persia-the-lost-crown-development-team-disbanded" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Eurogamer</a>, the publisher sa</span>id that the Prince of Persia: The Lost Crown team has moved on to “other projects that will benefit from their expertise” and that Ubisoft is focused on “making the game available to more players.”</p>



<p>Insider Gaming understands that the decision to move on from Prince of Persia: The Lost Crown and a any potential sequel was made around May of this year and was due to the game missing internal expectations. Sources say that Ubisoft was expecting The Lost Crown to sell similarly to the biggest Metroidvania’s in the market, with millions of units sold in a relatively short space of time. Prince of Persia: The Lost Crown has sold approximately one million units at the time of writing.</p>



<p>As for which projects Prince of Persia: The Lost Crown developers have joined, it’s understood that the majority have since moved onto three different projects. Most of the team has joined the development of Beyond Good and Evil 2, which was revived internally in 2017. Around a dozen employees have moved to Project Ovr, the next mainline Ghost Recon game. Around a dozen have also moved on to Project Steambot, a Rayman Remake in development at Ubisoft Milan.</p>



<p>Beyond Good and Evil 2 is a project still a few years away, with developers across the entire publisher confused as to why Ubisoft continues to invest tens of millions a year in development, which it’s never likely to get back. Project Steambot has also proved somewhat unpopular internally, as original creator Michal Ancel looms over the project as a consultant.</p>



<p>Developers tell me that Prince of Persia: The Lost Crown was a “perfect project. ” It was first pitched in June 2020 and saw a relatively straightforward development pipeline, a luxury that most development teams at Ubisoft don’t have. Yet still, Ubisoft’s ridiculously high internal expectations for such a project have once again prevented developers from exploring creative ideas. </p>



<p>What do you think of Ubisoft moving away from Prince of Persia: The Lost Crown and a sequel? Let us know on the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read about the team behind The Prince of Persia: The Lost Crown&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/prince-of-persia-the-lost-crown-team-disbanded-at-ubisoft-its-claimed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">reportedly being disbanded</a>. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NCSoft suffers layoffs and cancels projects, including ultra-realistic thriller Project M]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/ncsoft-suffers-layoffs-and-cancels-projects-including-ultra-realistic-thriller-project-m</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ncsoft-suffers-layoffs-and-cancels-projects-including-ultra-realistic-thriller-project-m.1017063/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/ncsoft-suffers-layoffs-and-cancels-projects-including-ultra-realistic-thriller-project-m<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>As company announces formation of four new "wholly-owned" subsidiaries.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Screenshot-from-Project-M-trailer-showing-a-young-female-woman-with-dark-hair.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>NCSoft</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>NCSoft has announced a reorganisation of its projects and staff, resulting in layoffs and the end of several games - including the promising and ultra-realistic-looking thriller Project M.</p>
<p>Earlier this week, the Korean developer and publisher <a href="https://kr.ncsoft.com/en/pr/newsDetail/5835.do">announced</a> the shift to focusing on four "wholly-owned" subsidiaries. Three of these will act as independent game studios, known as Studios X, Y, and Z. These will be "established to enhance global competitiveness", with a focus on Throne and Liberty, LLL and Tactan.</p>
<p>The fourth subsidiary, known as NC AI, will set its focus on "AI technology development and business expansion", it added.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="NCing | Project M Trailer I eNCounter I 엔씨소프트(NCSOFT)" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/1SApk_2ktfg?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>NCing | Project M Trailer I eNCounter I 엔씨소프트(NCSOFT)</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/1SApk_2ktfg?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/1SApk_2ktfg?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Here's Project M's announcement trailer from 2022. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1SApk_2ktfg" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>NCSoft said this "strategic realignment" within the company will result in some "internal reorganisation". This would include ceasing development on certain projects, as well as the "reassignment of internal members and the implementation of a voluntary retirement program".</p>
<p>South Korean news agency <a href="https://www.yna.co.kr/view/AKR20241021134500017">Yonhap</a>  (thanks, <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/throne-and-liberty-and-guild-wars-company-ncsoft-suffers-layoffs-amid-significant-restructure">IGN</a>) said NCSoft co-CEOs Taek-Jin Kim and Byung-Moo Park blamed layoffs at the company on its financial troubles, with the execs apologising to affected staff.</p>
<p>"As a result of operating in a way that most of the manpower and functions are concentrated at the headquarters, financial performance has continued to deteriorate and we are at risk of becoming a chronically loss-making company," the CEOs said, adding the situation "is seriously damaging the creativity and challenging spirit that NCSoft originally possessed".</p>
<p>As for NCSoft's cancelled projects, <a href="https://www.gamemeca.com/view.php?gid=1754249">Game Meca</a> quotes an NCSoft spokesperson as confirming Project M's cancellation, as well as Minibus and Toguri Adventure. Work on its currently-in-service multiplayer game Battle Crush will also come to a close.</p>
<p>NCSoft's four new subsidiaries will be officially established on 1st February next year.</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Screenshot-from-Project-M-trailer-showing-a-male-character-in-an-apartment.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>NCSoft</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>We <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/stunning-korean-heavy-rain-like-thriller-is-next-game-from-ncsoft">first got a look at Project M in 2022</a>, with NCSoft revealing a trailer filled with quicktime events reminiscent of <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/heavy-rain">Heavy Rain</a> and <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/detroit-become-human">Detroit: Become Human</a>. Its ultra-realistic graphics immediately caught the attention of many. </p>
<p>However, since then, word on the project has been limited save for an <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/ncsoft-shows-new-trailers-for-project-m-and-lll">additional trailer released last November</a>. At this time, NCSoft also shared a trailer for LLL, which remains in development. </p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Most Prince Of Persia: The Lost Crown devs have moved to other projects, Ubisoft confirm, following report about rejected sequel pitch]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/most-prince-of-persia-the-lost-crown-devs-have-moved-to-other-projects-ubisoft-confirm-following-report-about-rejected-sequel-pitch</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/most-prince-of-persia-the-lost-crown-devs-have-moved-to-other-projects-ubisoft-confirm-following-report-about-rejected-sequel-pitch.1017048/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/most-prince-of-persia-the-lost-crown-devs-have-moved-to-other-projects-ubisoft-confirm-following-report-about-rejected-sequel-pitch<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Prince-of-Persia%E2%84%A2-The-Lost-Crown2024-1-4-21-48-23.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Rock Paper Shotgun/Ubisoft</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>"Move over Hollow Knight," declared Katharine (RPS in peace) in our <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/prince-of-persia-the-lost-crown-review">Prince Of Persia: The Lost Crown review</a>, summarising this freshly-honed hunk of POP art as "a deep and challenging Metroid-like with some of the best platforming this side of Moon's Ori games." Sadly, for all the plaudits, the game doesn't seem to have earned sufficient megabucks to justify keeping its development team together. Earlier this week, French journalist Gautoz reported that Ubisoft had disbanded The Lost Crown's core dev team after turning down proposals for a sequel and further expansions. Speaking to RPS this morning, Ubisoft have confirmed that "most" of the Lost Crown's dev team have moved onto other projects, while noting that there have been no layoffs as a result.</p><!--more-->
<p>Find the Gautoz report on <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8HgkIyq0emY">Youtube</a>, which is based on conversations with anonymous developers. Beware that it's in French. And here's Ubisoft's statement in full from the game's senior producer, Abdelhak Elguess.</p>
<blockquote><p>I'm extremely proud of our team's work and passion at Ubisoft Montpellier to create a game that resonated with players and critics alike, and I am confident in its long-term success. Prince of Persia: The Lost Crown is now at the end of its Post-Launch roadmap with three free content updates and one DLC that released in September. We are now focusing on making the game available to more players: it was recently launched on Steam, and will be available on Mac by this winter. Most of the team members who worked on Prince of Persia: The Lost Crown have shifted to other projects that will benefit from their expertise.</p>
<p>We know players have a love for this brand and Ubisoft is excited to bring more Prince of Persia experiences in the future.</p></blockquote>
<p>Ubisoft are in a prickly place at the moment. Back in September, one investor <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/an-ubisoft-investor-wants-to-dethrone-ubisofts-founders-so-ubisoft-can-lay-more-developers-off">threatened to organise a rebellion</a> and depose the founding Guillemot brothers in response to disappointing returns on blockbuster games, not least Star Wars Outlaws. Ubisoft subsequently <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/assassins-creed-shadows-delayed-to-2025-as-ubisoft-try-to-recover-from-softer-than-expected-star-wars-outlaws-launch">kicked back the release of Assassin's Creed Shadows to 2025</a> to avoid another Outlaws-style spongy landing. It's also reported that the Guillemots and Tencent, who are currently minority shareholders, are considering <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/tencent-and-guillemot-family-considering-buyout-of-ubisoft-report-says">buying the company out</a>. All this occurs against the backdrop of labour action, with <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/700-ubisoft-staff-in-france-hold-strikes-in-response-to-worldwide-return-to-office-mandate-from-assassins-creed-publisher">700 staff in France striking in response to a return to the office mandate</a>.</p><p>Taking a longer view, Ubisoft are one among many larger publishers who are struggling to justify smaller, more eccentric projects such as The Lost Crown, which don't aim for the whopping revenues currently expected of the triple-As. As Graham has just lamented to me in our Slack, Ubisoft once had more of a track record for oddball B-listers and smaller artisanal curios - games like Driver, the musically minded Rayman reboots, Mario + Rabbids, and Child Of Light. Nowadays, projects of that scope with relatively modest commercial ambitions don't seem to cut the mustard. </p>
<p>As our guides writer Jeremy added in the same Slack chat, Ubisoft have also really muddled the waters with Prince Of Persia in particular. The Lost Crown has had to compete for attention with another POP side-scroller created by a third-party, Evil Empire's <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-rogue-prince-of-persia-is-a-new-roguelite-that-combines-wall-running-with-arkham-style-agile-combat">The Rogue Prince Of Persia</a>. Like Star Wars Outlaws, it was also exclusive to Ubisoft's own storefront for the first few months of release, reducing the impact of its eventual release on Steam, the largest PC marketplace. Finally, The Lost Crown has had to weather lingering uncertainty about the long-promised, much-delayed Prince Of Persia: Sands Of Time remake, which is <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/prince-of-persia-the-sands-of-time-remake-resurfaces-after-years-of-silence-to-tease-a-release-in-2026">now slated to launch in 2026</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Four years after PS5's launch, Minecraft finally gets a native version]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/four-years-after-ps5s-launch-minecraft-finally-gets-a-native-version</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/four-years-after-ps5s-launch-minecraft-finally-gets-a-native-version.1017042/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/four-years-after-ps5s-launch-minecraft-finally-gets-a-native-version<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>



            <p>
PlayStation 5 will celebrate its fourth birthday in just a few days, and finally there's a native version of Minecraft available for it.
</p>
<p>
The PS5 native version of Minecraft is available now, and comes as a free upgrade from the <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-gb/concept/212779">PlayStation Store</a> if you own the game's PS4 version already. As with all other Bedrock versions of the game, this is the cross-platform edition, which lets you play alongside those on PC, mobile, Switch and Xbox.
</p>
<p>
What's new? Well, specifically in the PS5 version, not much. Minecraft fans will be able to take advantage of graphical improvements already found on Xbox Series X, such as 4K visuals and 60fps gameplay.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Bundles of Bravery" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Fyf9gibpX1c?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Bundles of Bravery</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Fyf9gibpX1c?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/Fyf9gibpX1c?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Minecraft's Bundles of Bravery update adds item bundles.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Fyf9gibpX1c" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
Across the Minecraft Bedrock edition generally, today does bring two new features, however. Firstly, a Hardcore mode which limits you to just one life (after which you can only visit your world as a ghost). Second, the ability to bundle different items together in your inventory to save space (in effect, Minecraft has added folders).
</p>
<p>
Minecraft is, of course, owned by Microsoft - which is slowly publishing more of its games on PlayStation consoles. Next up is <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-everything-we-know-9408">Indiana Jones and the Great Circle</a>, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-confirmed-for-playstation-5">which arrives for PS5 next year</a>.
</p>
<p>Earlier this year, <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/sea-of-thieves">Sea of Thieves</a>, Grounded, <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/hi-fi-rush">Hi-Fi Rush</a> and Pentiment all also made the move across to additional platforms. On its PlayStation debut, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/former-xbox-console-exclusive-just-topped-europes-ps5-download-charts">Sea of Thieves went onto top the PS5's download charts</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Wolf Among Us 2 Isn’t Canceled, Confirms Telltale Games]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/the-wolf-among-us-2-isnt-canceled-confirms-telltale-games/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-wolf-among-us-2-isn%E2%80%99t-canceled-confirms-telltale-games.1017036/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/the-wolf-among-us-2-isnt-canceled-confirms-telltale-games/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>A few hours ago, a rumor that The Wolf Among Us 2 had been canceled started spreading on the Web. However, a spokesperson for Telltale Games has since <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-wolf-among-us-2-not-cancelled-telltale-confirms" target="_blank" rel="noopener">confirmed</a> to Eurogamer that it's not actually true.</p>
<p><em>As a rule, we don't comment on rumors and unsubstantiated Reddit threads. But development on The Wolf Among Us 2 continues and we're excited to share more about the game with Telltale fans and our community when the time is right.</em></p>
<p>Fans had every right to be worried, though. A follow-up to that beloved first season of episodes was first announced at San Diego Comic-Con 2017. However, in September 2018, Telltale<a href="https://wccftech.com/telltale-games-closing-walking-dead/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> shut down</a> and its projects, including this one, were canceled.</p>
<p>It wasn't long until fans' hopes were rekindled, with the announcement of <a href="https://wccftech.com/telltale-games-revived/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Telltale's resurrection</a> coming in August 2019 and the subsequent confirmation that development on The Wolf Among Us 2 would <a href="https://wccftech.com/the-wolf-among-us-2-development-reboot-unreal/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">restart from scratch</a>. The game originally <a href="https://wccftech.com/the-wolf-among-us-2-delayed-beyond-2023-unreal-engine-5/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">targeted</a> a 2023 launch, but Telltale delayed it around a year and a half ago to avoid putting too much pressure on its employees with crunch practices. Contextually, we learned that the studio had decided to switch the game to Epic's Unreal Engine 5. The last we heard about The Wolf Among Us 2 was in April when the developer <a href="https://wccftech.com/the-wolf-among-us-2-gets-first-ue5-screenshots/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">shared</a> the first Unreal Engine 5 screenshots.</p>
<p>We don't know a whole lot about the story except for some tidbits that were <a href="https://wccftech.com/the-wolf-among-us-2-is-set-six-months-after-the-original-season/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">released</a> nearly two years ago. The Wolf Among Us 2 takes place six months after the original season, just after Snow White takes over as deputy mayor of Fabletown. Bigby is still struggling to transition from a typical fairytale villain to sheriff and protector. This new season explores more nuances and difficulties of hiding in plain sight, dealing with mostly new moles, and taking place all over New York, with the city said to play a bigger role.</p>
<p>Telltale also said that it's going to be even more about the human experience of a fable that strips away the fantasy and leaves players with many uncomfortable and messy choices to make.</p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Don't mind me, I'm simply microwaving an instant frog in Creature Packets]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dont-mind-me-im-simply-microwaving-an-instant-frog-in-creature-packets</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dont-mind-me-im-simply-microwaving-an-instant-frog-in-creature-packets.1017033/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dont-mind-me-im-simply-microwaving-an-instant-frog-in-creature-packets<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
  

        <p>Just like in the Lion King</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/creature-packets.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>kenforest</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>I feel this one largely speaks for itself, honestly. I could theorise on the fictional conceit of bringing packaged creatures to life using a microwave and also, sometimes, a blender, but to do so would be to stare into a gift horse’s abyssal oat hole so intently that…</p>
<p>…I was going to finish that with something about its molars staring back, but I had to quickly Google “do horses have molars?” only to misspell it. “Yes, horses can have a strong sense of right and wrong, and what is fair,” went the AI overview. “Some say that horses can teach people to live in the present and to be authentic.”</p>
<p>Thanks for that.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>Anyway, Creature Packets is a short, name-your-own-price game by kenforest. You can find it on <a href="https://kenforest.itch.io/creature-packets">Itch here</a>. It is not exactly a <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-best-horror-games">horror</a> game, but the room in which you select creatures from a vending machine then cook them <em>does </em>feel like the sort of place in which a small slice of horror game could occur. It’s almost like a very elaborate Resident Evil puzzle spun out into its own thing.</p><p>There’s also a bit of an Overcooked vibe, without the time pressure. You’re given orders through a monitor, and you’ll need to read yellowing, crumpled recipes on notepad pages, haphazardly pinned about the room. These three bugs make a snail, these creatures make a frog - horrible chimeric procedures of that nature. I think my favourite thing about it is the vending machine. You can stick me in the most unnatural situation imaginable, and as long as the vending machine is in working order, I’ve at least got some sense of normality. I’ll ignore the fact that the vending machine appears to stock itself.</p>
<p>This one’s a <a href="https://ldjam.com/events/ludum-dare/56">Ludum Dare 56</a> entry. We previously covered<a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/heres-a-free-god-sim-from-the-shotgun-king-devs-in-which-you-build-the-sun"> this tiny game</a> in which you Build The Sun, and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/combo-critters-is-a-free-crunchy-creature-collecting-deck-builder-from-the-shotgun-king-devs">this crunchy creature collecting deckbuilder</a>, both by PUNKCAKE Délicieux.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ubisoft responds to report Prince of Persia: The Lost Crown development team disbanded]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/ubisoft-responds-to-report-prince-of-persia-the-lost-crown-development-team-disbanded</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ubisoft-responds-to-report-prince-of-persia-the-lost-crown-development-team-disbanded.1017027/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/ubisoft-responds-to-report-prince-of-persia-the-lost-crown-development-team-disbanded<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>"We know players have a love for this brand."</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/PrinceOfPersia_HERO.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Ubisoft</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
Ubisoft has responded to a report published yesterday that claimed <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/prince-of-persia-the-lost-crown">Prince of Persia: The Lost Crown</a>'s team had been disbanded.
</p>
<p>
In a statement to Eurogamer, the Assassin's Creed publisher largely confirmed what had been reported - though made clear that the game's team were still present and busy at development studio Ubisoft Montpellier, albeit now on "other projects that will benefit from their expertise".
</p>
<p>
Yesterday's report by <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8HgkIyq0emY">Origami</a> was not fully clear on the status of the team behind The Lost Crown - which received a positive critical response upon its launch this year, though failed to set tills ringing.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Prince of Persia  The Lost Crown   Story Trailer #TGA" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/aoNjAB4V7o0?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Prince of Persia  The Lost Crown   Story Trailer #TGA</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/aoNjAB4V7o0?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/aoNjAB4V7o0?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Here's a Prince of Persia: The Lost Crown story trailer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aoNjAB4V7o0" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
The report also suggested The Lost Crown would not receieve a sequel as a result of its commercial performance - something Ubisoft does not contradict today - with ideas for a follow-up reportedly merged into plans for the game's DLC.
</p><p>
"I'm extremely proud of our team's work and passion at Ubisoft Montpellier to create a game that resonated with players and critics alike, and I am confident in its long-term success," Abdelhak Elguess, Prince of Persia: The Lost Crown senior producer said in a statement to Eurogamer. 
</p>
<p>
"Prince of Persia: The Lost Crown is now at the end of its Post-Launch roadmap with three free content updates and one DLC that released in September. We are now focusing on making the game available to more players: it was recently launched on Steam, and will be available on Mac by this winter. 
</p>
<p>
"Most of the team members who worked on Prince of Persia: The Lost Crown have shifted to other projects that will benefit from their expertise.
</p>
<p>
"We know players have a love for this brand and Ubisoft is excited to bring more Prince of Persia experiences in the future."
</p>
<p>One of these is, of course, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/prince-of-persia-sands-of-time-remake-now-targeting-2026-gets-briefest-of-trailers">Ubisoft's long-awaited Prince of Persia: Sands of Time remake</a>, which currently sits with a 2026 release window - some six years after it was initially revealed. </p>
<p>It's unclear which projects at Ubisoft Montpellier the team behind The Lost Crown have joined, though the studio is <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/beyond-good-evil-2-remains-vapourware-it-seems">still toiling on Ubisoft's even-longer awaited Beyond Good &amp; Evil 2</a>.</p>
<p>"Ubisoft ditches its normal formula and finds the ideal way to bring gaming's original Prince back to life," Christian Donlan wrote in <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/prince-of-persia-the-lost-crown-review-fabulous-exploration-and-combat">Eurogamer's Prince of Persia: The Lost Crown review</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Killzone Certainly Sounds Far from Guerrilla’s Thoughts – ‘The Themes of Horizon Are Relatable for Everyone’]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/killzone-certainly-sounds-far-from-guerrillas-thoughts-the-themes-of-horizon-are-relatable-for-everyone/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/killzone-certainly-sounds-far-from-guerrilla%E2%80%99s-thoughts-%E2%80%93-%E2%80%98the-themes-of-horizon-are-relatable-for-everyone%E2%80%99.1017012/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/killzone-certainly-sounds-far-from-guerrillas-thoughts-the-themes-of-horizon-are-relatable-for-everyone/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>It's been almost eleven years since the last Killzone game was released, and it doesn't look like that will change any time soon. Art Director Roy Postma, a Guerrilla veteran who has worked at the Dutch studio since its foundation, <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/entertainment/video-games/2024/10/21/lego-horizon-adventures-is-all-ages-crossover-sonys-dreams/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">told The Washington Post</a> in no uncertain terms that the developer believes Horizon's themes are much more interesting for a bigger audience.</p>
<p><em>We were done with it as a team. As a studio, we needed to refresh the palette. It was, by choice, the opposite of ‘Killzone.’ I think the themes that this story and the characters represent are relatable for all ages and people, like having a found family of friends and finding your place in the world.</em></p>
<p>While there is truth to the assessment, and Horizon has certainly brought much greater success to Guerrilla, Killzone earned its own share of fans, too, over the four mainline installments and two spin-offs developed for the PlayStation Portable and PlayStation Vita. Its unique 'sci-fi Nazi' setting could have warranted a much greater narrative development than what we've actually seen in the games.</p>
<p>Sony has been very active in remastering its previous games, and it would be interesting to see how many players would get a Killzone: Shadow Fall remaster for PlayStation 5 and PC. The game certainly still looks good to this day and would shine even brighter on the new hardware.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, though, Guerrilla is wholly focused on Horizon. They are about to launch LEGO Horizon Adventures, a spin-off action/adventure game targeted at a younger audience. This title, co-developed with Studio Gobo, will be launched right away on PC and Nintendo Switch in addition to PlayStation 5, and there's also cooperative multiplayer for the first time in the franchise (while Guerrilla's bulk is working on the <a href="https://wccftech.com/horizon-online-is-guerrillas-next-big-game-with-horizon-3-a-ways-off/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">full-fledged Horizon multiplayer game</a>).</p>
<p>Next week, Nixxes will also release the controversial <a href="https://wccftech.com/horizon-zero-dawn-remastered-launching-this-october-on-pc-and-ps5/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Horizon Zero Dawn Remastered</a>.</p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>