<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 20:34:41 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Latest Acolyte Episode Is Star Wars At Its Most Sexy, Deadly]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/star-wars-acolyte-episode-5-qimir-master-review-1851562506</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-latest-acolyte-episode-is-star-wars-at-its-most-sexy-deadly.912501/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/star-wars-acolyte-episode-5-qimir-master-review-1851562506<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Star Wars</em> is a lot of things, but it is rarely sexy. A few things spring to mind: Anakin Skywalker’s bare chest after a nightmare, Padme’s midriff in the fighting pit, or a sidelong glance from Han Solo, but in recent history the franchise has been somewhat devoid of sex and death. Kylo Ren and Rey Skywalker had some chemistry, sure, but it was akin to two teenagers first discovering horniness: clumsy, awkward, and at times, downright weird. And too many modern characters have been protected by plot armor, be it Boba Fett in his shitty Disney Plus series or side characters in <em>The Mandalorian</em>. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="194617" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Fortnite Introduces Force Abilities In Latest Star Wars Collab" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="122" data-playlist="194617,193897,194499" data-current="194617"><div><p>Fortnite Introduces Force Abilities In Latest Star Wars Collab</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/194617/194617_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/194617/194617_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/194617/194617_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/194617/194617_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/20078.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>The latest episode of <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/acolyte-episode-one-review-star-wars-1851544768&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/acolyte-episode-one-review-star-wars-1851544768"><em>The Acolyte</em></a></span>, titled The Master, is tailor-made for <em>Star Wars</em>’ adult audiences, giving us a sexy villain and a body count usually reserved for <em>House of the Dragon</em>—and it just so happened to be one of the strongest episodes of the franchise yet. <br></p><figure id="" data-id="afpvuwnfoibrncd6upmy" data-recommend-id="image://afpvuwnfoibrncd6upmy" data-format="png" data-width="800" data-height="88" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A SPOILER WARNING!" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><span data-id="afpvuwnfoibrncd6upmy" data-recommend-id="image://afpvuwnfoibrncd6upmy" data-format="png" data-width="800" data-height="88" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A SPOILER WARNING!" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>The first thing I notice about the strange, helmeted baddie that shows up to fight the Jedi in this episode are his arms. They’re bare, something we almost never see for <em>Star Wars</em> bad guys, and they are rippling with sweat-glistened muscles. As he takes on the small army of Jedi trying to protect Wookiee master Kelnocca, his biceps and triceps and forearms are on full display, moving with incredible, dangerous speed, like a cobra repeatedly coiling and striking.</p><p>The lightsaber battle he takes part in is one of the coolest I’ve ever seen in <em>Star Wars</em>. It’s masterfully choreographed, with Dafne Keen’s Jecki and Lee-Jung Jae’s Sol showing off some impressive skills as they face off against someone who doesn’t follow the typical rules of engagement. We watch as they struggle to adapt to the stranger’s tactics, which include him using his helm to block and temporarily disable lightsabers. We see their faces change as they realize this is something the Jedi have never encountered, could not even fathom.<br></p><figure id="" data-id="c8a7ebb2e8a8b38daa2ca7ba70f02017" data-recommend-id="image://c8a7ebb2e8a8b38daa2ca7ba70f02017" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Jecki looks at her disabled lightsaber. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Jecki looks at her disabled lightsaber. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Disney / Lucasfilm</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="c8a7ebb2e8a8b38daa2ca7ba70f02017" data-recommend-id="image://c8a7ebb2e8a8b38daa2ca7ba70f02017" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Jecki looks at her disabled lightsaber. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p><em>The Acolyte</em> showrunners said they wanted to give us a lightsaber battle that would rival <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://collider.com/the-acolyte-lightsaber-fight-duel-of-the-fates/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://collider.com/the-acolyte-lightsaber-fight-duel-of-the-fates/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>The Phantom Menace</em>’s Duel of the Fates</a></span>, and boy, did they. Jecki is light on her feet and fast, leapfrogging off of objects to execute a stronger strike, while Sol’s anger at the loss of so many of his kind slowly overtakes him, manifesting in the way he fights. By the time the opening half of the episode is over, there are cauterized holes gently emitting steam in almost all of the Jedi, including Keen’s Jecki, who dies quite terribly after knocking the helmet off the mystery man.<br></p><p>We watch him punch three holes through her with his newly split dual sabers, and as her body falls to the ground we get our big reveal: It’s Manny Jacinto’s Qimir, his hair dripping with sweat and falling in pointed slices across his face, arms on full display, eyes full of rage. Evil has never looked this good.<br></p><p>And in case you weren’t sure that Qimir, who has been secretly pretending to be a bumbling idiot and not the master controlling Mae (one of two roles for Amandla Stenberg), is evil, he soon after kills Yord (Charlie Barnett) in quite possibly the most gruesome manner ever seen in <em>Star Wars</em>. With Yord kneeling down in front of him, Qimir brutally snaps his neck. Yeah, he bad <em>bad</em>.<br></p><p>I watched nearly the entire episode with my mouth hanging open in shock—shock that <em>The Acolyte</em> would kill off two characters we were just getting to know, shock at how good the fights were, shock at the holes through bodies, the snapped neck, and the unparalleled, unapologetic sexiness of Jacinto. The Dark Side should tempt you, and there’s no easier way to do that than by being hot as shit.<br></p><p>That the episode ends with what appears to be a few notes of Kylo Ren’s theme as Qimir tenderly covers Osha’s unconscious body with a shawl tells me two things: <em>The Acolyte </em>showrunners<em> </em>know that we yearn for sexy, murderous bad boys, and this series may tie into the movies more so than we expected. Is Qimir the first ever Knight of Ren, the acolytes of the Dark Side who rose to power when the Sith were considered extinct, whose name Kylo took as his own? It sure seems like it. </p><hr><p>The next episode of <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://disneyplus.bn5x.net/c/379647/564546/9358?subId1=KT-&amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.disneyplus.com%2Fseries%2Fthe-acolyte%2F39RAA0bOYXQ0&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://disneyplus.bn5x.net/c/379647/564546/9358?subId1=KT-&amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.disneyplus.com%2Fseries%2Fthe-acolyte%2F39RAA0bOYXQ0" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>The Acolyte</em></a></span> airs on Tuesday July 2 on Disney Plus. I hope your air conditioning is working, because I’m sure it’s gonna be another hot one. </p><p>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Patent document showcases the cloud-only streaming Xbox console that never was]]></title>
            <link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=2033759</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/patent-document-showcases-the-cloud-only-streaming-xbox-console-that-never-was.912498/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://arstechnica.com/?p=2033759<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="main">



<article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/NewsArticle" id="">
      <div>
        <header>
            <h4>
      keystone revealed    —
</h4>
            
            <h2 itemprop="description">Microsoft couldn't get the price of its streaming Xbox low enough to release it.</h2>
                    </header>
        <div itemprop="articleBody">
                                    
  




<!-- cache miss 44:single/related:f6497c57db2f4015220e76963dbe55bc --><!-- empty -->
  <div>
    <ul>
              <li data-thumb="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/xbox-keystone-2-150x150.png" data-src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/xbox-keystone-2.png" data-responsive="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/xbox-keystone-2-980x634.png 1080, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/xbox-keystone-2-1440x932.png 2560" data-sub-html="#caption-2033780">
          <figure>
            
                          <figcaption id="caption-2033780">
                <span></span>
                                  <p>
                    The streaming-only Xbox would have looked like a smaller, squarer relative of the Series S.                   </p>
                                                  <p><span></span>
                                          Microsoft                                      </p>
                              </figcaption>
                      </figure>
        </li>
              <li data-thumb="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/xbox-keystone-7-150x150.png" data-src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/xbox-keystone-7.png" data-responsive="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/xbox-keystone-7-980x551.png 1080, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/xbox-keystone-7-1440x810.png 2560" data-sub-html="#caption-2033785">
          <figure>
            
                          <figcaption id="caption-2033785">
                <span></span>
                                  <p>
                    The console had cutouts on the bottom and back, presumably for air cooling.                   </p>
                                                  <p><span></span>
                                          Microsoft                                      </p>
                              </figcaption>
                      </figure>
        </li>
              <li data-thumb="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/xbox-keystone-3-150x150.png" data-src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/xbox-keystone-3.png" data-responsive="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/xbox-keystone-3-980x554.png 1080, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/xbox-keystone-3-1440x814.png 2560" data-sub-html="#caption-2033781">
          <figure>
            
                          <figcaption id="caption-2033781">
                <span></span>
                                  <p>
                    Front-mounted Xbox button and USB port, much like the Series S.                   </p>
                                                  <p><span></span>
                                          Microsoft                                      </p>
                              </figcaption>
                      </figure>
        </li>
              <li data-thumb="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/xbox-keystone-4-150x150.png" data-src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/xbox-keystone-4.png" data-responsive="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/xbox-keystone-4-980x567.png 1080, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/xbox-keystone-4-1440x833.png 2560" data-sub-html="#caption-2033782">
          <figure>
            
                          <figcaption id="caption-2033782">
                <span></span>
                                  <p>
                    Rear-mounted Ethernet, HDMI, and power. The console would likely have worked over Wi-Fi, too, but wired Ethernet does help with latency and consistency when streaming games.                   </p>
                                                  <p><span></span>
                                          Microsoft                                      </p>
                              </figcaption>
                      </figure>
        </li>
              <li data-thumb="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/xbox-keystone-5-150x150.png" data-src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/xbox-keystone-5.png" data-responsive="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/xbox-keystone-5-980x652.png 1080, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/xbox-keystone-5-1440x958.png 2560" data-sub-html="#caption-2033783">
          <figure>
            
                          <figcaption id="caption-2033783">
                <span></span>
                                  <p>
                    Controller sync button on the side.                  </p>
                                                  <p><span></span>
                                          Microsoft                                      </p>
                              </figcaption>
                      </figure>
        </li>
              <li data-thumb="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/xbox-keystone-6-150x150.png" data-src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/xbox-keystone-6.png" data-responsive="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/xbox-keystone-6-980x781.png 1080, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/xbox-keystone-6-1440x1148.png 2560" data-sub-html="#caption-2033784">
          <figure>
            
                          <figcaption id="caption-2033784">
                <span></span>
                                  <p>
                    There was a logo and a Series S-ish circle on the top of the Keystone Xbox, but there are no cutouts depicted, so this may have been a stylistic choice rather than a place for the console to vent hot air.                   </p>
                                                  <p><span></span>
                                          Microsoft                                      </p>
                              </figcaption>
                      </figure>
        </li>
          </ul>
  </div>


<p>Microsoft's mid-generation plans for the Xbox Series S and X consoles looked a whole lot different a couple of years ago than it does now. <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2023/09/ftc-v-microsoft-document-leak-outs-detailed-plans-for-mid-gen-xbox-refresh/">A leaked slide deck from the <em>FTC v. Microsoft</em> case last year</a> outlined detailed plans for a spruced up Series S, an overhauled Series X, and even a redesigned controller. Another part of that roadmap included a streaming-only version of the Xbox, codenamed Keystone, that was designed to connect to Microsoft's Xbox Cloud Gaming servers rather than rendering games locally.</p>

<p>Microsoft has talked openly about this version of the Xbox before. Microsoft Gaming CEO Phil Spencer <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/11/15/23460485/microsoft-xbox-streaming-console-keystone-delay-price">told The Verge</a> that the Keystone console was designed and fully functional, but that it wasn't launched because Microsoft had a hard time getting the price down low enough that it made sense next to the $299 Series S (which already occasionally goes on sale in the $200 to $250 range).</p>
<p>We've already seen glimpses of the Keystone design—once <a href="https://www.windowscentral.com/gaming/xbox/microsoft-gaming-chief-phil-spencer-teases-an-unreleased-mini-xbox-console">on Spencer's shelf</a>, and again in the <em>FTC v. Microsoft</em> documents. Both of those depictions were partial, or seen from a distance. But a new design patent document (<a href="https://ppubs.uspto.gov/dirsearch-public/print/downloadPdf/D1009161">PDF</a>) unearthed by <a href="https://www.windowscentral.com/gaming/xbox/the-xbox-that-never-was-our-first-detailed-look-at-the-keystone-cloud-streaming-console-design">Windows Central</a> shows even more detailed renderings of what the cloud Xbox would have looked like.</p>
<h2>Series S meets Apple TV</h2>
<p>Keystone's styling was strongly reminiscent of the disc-drive-less Series S, with the same boxy white design and front-mounted Xbox button and USB port. There's also a similar circular cutout on top, though it may not be an air vent as it is in the Series S—all of the holes depicted in the patent are on the back and bottom, and a streaming box certainly wouldn't have needed the same cooling capacity as the AMD-designed CPU and GPU in the Series S.</p>                                            
                                                        
<p>The console also would have been square-shaped and considerably smaller than a Series S—not quite as small as a dedicated video-streaming box like an Apple TV or Roku Ultra, but not too far off either (the patent document doesn't list dimensions, but we've done a rough size comparison using the HDMI and Ethernet ports on the Keystone box and an Apple TV 4K). The console's controller sync button would have been mounted on its side, rather than in front, as it is on the Series S.</p>
<figure><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/cloud-xbox-apple-tv.png" data-height="1500" data-width="2000" alt="The cloud Xbox compared to a current-generation Apple TV 4K, with sizes roughly normalized based on the sizes of the HDMI and Ethernet ports. The Xbox console would have been a bit larger, but not dramatically so. "></a><figcaption><p><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/cloud-xbox-apple-tv.png" data-height="1500" data-width="2000">Enlarge</a> <span>/</span> The cloud Xbox compared to a current-generation Apple TV 4K, with sizes roughly normalized based on the sizes of the HDMI and Ethernet ports. The Xbox console would have been a bit larger, but not dramatically so. </p><p>Apple/Microsoft/Andrew Cunningham</p></figcaption></figure>
<p>In the alternate reality of the&nbsp;<em>FTC v. Microsoft</em> slide deck, all of these new consoles and the new controller would have been announced or launched by now. But as Spencer <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2023/09/xbox-exec-says-leaked-old-emails-and-documents-have-outdated-info/">said</a> shortly after those documents leaked, the company's plans have changed substantially in the interim. A <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2024/06/microsoft-reveals-first-disc-less-xbox-series-x/">disc-less version of the Series X</a> is coming, but it looks exactly like the current version of the console without a disc drive; Microsoft is also pursuing a strategy where it <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2024/02/microsoft-confirms-which-xbox-games-are-going-to-switch-playstation/">takes more of its internally developed games multi-platform</a> rather than restricting them to the Xbox and to Windows PCs. These moves are at least partially in response to <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2024/04/putting-microsofts-cratering-xbox-console-sales-in-context/">sliding revenue from Microsoft's console business</a>, which has seen its revenue decline by double digits year over year for the last couple of years.</p>
<p>Neither Spencer nor Microsoft has ever said never about the Keystone console, leaving the door open to an eventual release if and when the price of manufacturing the console comes down. In the meantime, the streaming-only Xbox lives on <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/apps/xbox-app-for-tv">as an app for newer Samsung smart TVs</a>.</p>

        <p><em>Listing image by Microsoft</em></p>
                                                      </div>
    </div>

<section>
          
    
    <p>
      <section>
        <a href="https://arstechnica.com/author/andrew_cunningham">Andrew Cunningham</a>
        Andrew is a Senior Technology Reporter at Ars Technica, with a focus on consumer tech including computer hardware and in-depth reviews of operating systems like Windows and macOS. Andrew lives in Philadelphia and co-hosts a weekly book podcast called <a href="https://overduepodcast.com/">Overdue</a>.      </section>
    </p>

  </section>

  </article>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How To Save On Disney Epic Mickey: Rebrushed For PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/how-to-save-on-disney-epic-mickey-rebrushed-for-pc/1100-6524512/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/how-to-save-on-disney-epic-mickey-rebrushed-for-pc.912495/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/how-to-save-on-disney-epic-mickey-rebrushed-for-pc/1100-6524512/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6524512">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>15 years after it first launched on the Nintendo Wii, Epic Mickey: Rebrushed is making a comeback on PC and consoles on September 24. Like most new games, the remake is priced at $60, but PC users can get a substantial discount through Fanatical. Right now, you can <strong><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.dpbolvw.net%2Fclick-100770772-13797872%3Fsid%3Dsubid_value%26url%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.fanatical.com%2Fen%2Fgame%2Fdisney-epic-mickey-rebrushed&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fhow-to-save-on-disney-epic-mickey-rebrushed-for-pc%2F1100-6524512%2F%3Fftag%3DCAD-01-10abi2f&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">save 17% on your preorder with promo code FANATICAL17</a></strong>. This drops the price of your Steam key to $49.79. Thanks to the ongoing <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/over-8000-pc-games-discounted-in-new-fanatical-sale-that-also-includes-freebies/1100-6524318/" data-ref-id="1100-6524318">Red Hot Sale</a>, if you preorder before July 11, you'll also get a free mystery gam or coupon for your next purchase</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4325041-epic-mickey.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4325041" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4325041-epic-mickey.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4325041"></a><figcaption>Disney Epic Mickey: Rebrushed</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4325041-epic-mickey.jpg"></figure><p>It's worth noting that Digital preorders come with 24-hour early access and a costume pack featuring Steam Boat Willie, Football, and Brave Little Tailor costumes.</p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/disney-epic-mickey-rebrushed-is-a-full-circle-moment-for-the-games-original-narrative/1100-6522520/" data-ref-id="1100-6522520">The return of Epic Mickey is kind of a big deal</a>, as video game legend Warren Spector's vision for a Disney game was a Wii exclusive. An imaginative romp through Disney's forgotten history, the game teamed Mickey up with Oswald Rabbit as they explored an alternate version of Disneyland that had been lost to the sands of time. Naturally, this new version will offer a massive visual leap forward when compared to the 480p graphics of the original Wii game.</p><p>Developer <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/disney-epic-mickey-rebrushed-is-a-full-circle-moment-for-the-games-original-narrative/1100-6522520/" data-ref-id="1100-6522520">Purple Lamp is aiming to create a remake that will appeal to modern players</a>, and while it looks like the core gameplay has been retained, there are updated controls as well. If you're looking to get the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/disney-epic-mickey-rebrushed-preorder-guide/1100-6521491/" data-ref-id="1100-6521491">Epic Mickey: Rebrushed collector's edition</a>, you'll sadly have a hard tim. Only 5,000 of these are being made, and they sold out quickly when listings went live.</p><p>You can check out our <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/disney-epic-mickey-rebrushed-preorder-guide/1100-6521491/" data-ref-id="1100-6521491">Epic Mickey: Rebrushed preorder guide</a> for details on the standard versions available on console ahead of its release later this year.</p><p>While you're preordering your copy of Epic Mickey, you should also check out <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.kqzyfj.com%2Fclick-100770772-15540845%3Fsid%3Dsubid_value%26url%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.fanatical.com%2Fen%2Fbundle%2Fgames&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fhow-to-save-on-disney-epic-mickey-rebrushed-for-pc%2F1100-6524512%2F%3Fftag%3DCAD-01-10abi2f&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Fanatical's latest game bundles</a>. Highlights include the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/add-a-bunch-of-steam-deck-games-to-your-backlog-for-cheap-with-the-handheld-heroes-bundle/1100-6524494/" data-ref-id="1100-6524494">Handheld Heroes bundle for Steam Deck</a> and a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/grab-up-to-16-bethesda-games-for-only-3-each/1100-6524465/" data-ref-id="1100-6524465">Bethesda bundle</a> that includes many of the publisher's best games for as low as $3 each. If you're feeling lucky, check out the <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.anrdoezrs.net%2Fclick-100770772-13797872%3Fsid%3Dsubid_value%26url%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.fanatical.com%2Fen%2Fbundle%2Fsummer-mystery-bundle&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fhow-to-save-on-disney-epic-mickey-rebrushed-for-pc%2F1100-6524512%2F%3Fftag%3DCAD-01-10abi2f&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Summer Mystery Bundle</a>, which lets you get 20 random Steam games for $14.</p><p><em>Disclosure: GameSpot and Fanatical are both owned by Fandom.</em></p><div data-embed-type="pinbox" data-ref-id="4304">  <ul>                              <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/lord-of-the-rings-4k-blu-ray-box-set-amazon-preorder/1100-6524366/">Lord Of The Rings 4K Blu-Ray Steelbook Collection Is Back In Print, Preorders Live At Amazon</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/official-xbox-controllers-get-significant-discounts-at-amazon-and-walmart/1100-6524341/">Official Xbox Controllers Get Significant Discounts At Amazon And Walmart</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/zelda-links-awakening-is-back-in-stock-for-40-at-amazon/1100-6511630/">Get Ready For Zelda: Echoes Of Wisdom With This Great Link's Awakening Deal</a></li>                          <li>         <span>+ Show More Best Gaming &amp; Tech Deals This Week Links (2)</span>       </li>          <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/save-big-on-nintendo-switch-joy-con-controllers-at-amazon-and-walmart/1100-6523566/">Save Big On Nintendo Switch Joy-Con Controllers At Amazon And Walmart</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/inside-out-2-fans-should-check-out-the-new-lego-mood-cube-set/1100-6524400/">Inside Out 2 Fans Should Check Out The New Lego Mood Cube Set</a></li>   </ul> </div>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/108490194306897153177?rel=author">Darryn Bonthuys</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Future of Black Desert Online: Everything from Heidel Ball 2024]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/the-future-of-black-desert-online/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-future-of-black-desert-online-everything-from-heidel-ball-2024.912465/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/the-future-of-black-desert-online/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>It's been a while since I last wrote about Black Desert Online, and it's<a href="https://wccftech.com/review/black-desert-online-review-updates/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> been even longer since I reviewed it</a> in 2016. I have played it since then, but something always gets in the way, such as eating, sleeping, and bathing. However, I recently attended Heidel Ball 2024 as a guest of Pearl Abyss in Beynac-et-Cazenac, the inspiration of Heidel itself, and learned about what's coming. They're not slowing down.</p>
<p>With good reason, when you look at the facts. Way back in 2020, the announcement of Crimson Desert saw a 400% increase in share price. One could argue causation vs correlation, but investors haven't been as bullish since then. However, with the proposed release of <a href="https://wccftech.com/crimson-desert-rumored-to-launch-early-next-year-following-gamescom-demo/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Crimson Desert</a> next year, <a href="https://irsvc.teletogether.com/pearlabyss/pdf/pearlabyss2024Q1_eng.pdf?2" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a recent uptick in revenue for Black Desert Online</a>, and the hopes that these will work together to drive renewed interest, you can understand why they're pushing hard.</p>
<p>The entire Heidel Ball stream can be viewed below, but I'll summarize it for those who want the high notes. Let's start with the technical first.</p>
<p><iframe title="Heidel Ball 2024 | Black Desert" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/tpNn9qAFXxs?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<h2>A PlayStation 5 Version of Black Desert Online is Coming</h2>
<p>Let's not beat around the bush about Black Desert Online's inability to take advantage of the PS5 fully. Following the Calpheon Ball last winter, a version coming wasn't a secret, but Pearl Abyss revealed some more concrete information.</p>
<p>No concrete date has been given as to its launch, but what was said is that it will feature improved graphics, ranging from enhanced effects and textures to an increased draw distance, a better frame rate, improved loading times, and more. There will be a test before the end of this year.</p>
<h2>Hardcore Servers - for the PVP Lovers</h2>
<p>One would honestly think PVP should appeal to me. I like skill-based games, and I hate all of you humans. Every single one of you. Especially you. Still, I'm not a fan of player-vs-player combat, not in an MMORPG anyway. I'm very much a play-a-story and explore-a-world, in my own way and pace, kind of guy. Some arsehole chasing me across a field before catching me and then shoving their dagger up my sphincter does not a good experience make.</p>
<p>I'm saying this partly because Black Desert Online brings something genuinely interesting with Hardcore Servers. Please make no mistake: these are for those who want a PVP experience. Starting on the hardcore server, you'll be given a level 60 character with equipment starting at 230ap and 260dp, which can be enhanced. PVP is always on. You can't chat, you can't form parties, and when you die, you're sent to jail.</p>
<p>You get out of jail by gaining rest points or by fighting others in jail. I'm essentially looking at the jail as a mini-version of The Hunger Games, in a larger version of The Hunger Games, all done in the style of Black Desert Online. May the odds ever be in your favor.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/Black-Desert-Online-Heidel-Ball-Updates-03-Dosa-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>

<p>Of course, the PS5 version and Hardcore server are more than just technical, which brings us to the bulk of updates.</p>
<h2>Introducing the Dosa - the 28th Class</h2>
<p>Twenty-eight classes. That isn't a small number; many MMOs never have such a wide range. Part of this is the enormous amount of balancing any new class requires. Wielding a sword and a pipe, the Dosa is arguably one of the most ostentatious of the game's characters, which is saying something.</p>
<p>Playing Black Desert Online as the Dosa will have you attacking enemies with a flurry of slashes from your Hwando sword. So far, so simple. Only here, you have a pipe. The Gombangdae (Asian) smoking pipe here is unique, allowing you to summon spectral allies and other abilities from its smoke. From Archers and Spearmen, which will attack your enemies, to what appears like AoE abilities to negatively affect those around you.</p>
<p>If there's anything to say, it looks impressive from the trailer. The Dosa's story links closely to the upcoming expansion, which I'll cover shortly. Long story short, he comes from a noble family accused of treason, though he managed to escape. From stealing food on the streets, he encountered the master of the "Sangdo School" and became her disciple. All of this takes place in the location of the main update.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/Black-Desert-Online-Heidel-Ball-Updates-04-Seoul-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>

<h2>Black Desert Online: Land of the Morning Light - Seoul</h2>
<p>Pearl Abyss is fond of recreating locations, as they have created Heidel out of Beynac-et-Cazenac. For the next update, they're going to Seoul. Having worked with the South Korean Cultural Heritage Administration, they have recreated Gyeongbokgung Palace using drones, LIDAR, and other sources.</p>
<p>Following the previous expansion, <a href="https://wccftech.com/land-of-the-morning-light-black-desert-qa-pearl-abyss-ditches-monster-grinding-for-boss-blitz/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Land of the Morning Light</a>, based on South Korea, it made sense that Black Desert Online would take you to the capital. Of course, it's Pearl Abyss' version of the capital, featuring eight new bosses as part of the eight Korean tales it will tell us. With new five-player bosses and benefits to guilds, the team hopes the new content will help bring guilds closer together.</p>
<p>New primordial-grade Sovereign weapons will be introduced to reward your progress in Seoul. These will have their enhancement levels, later enhancements giving visual effects and being customizable, with up to five different effects to make that weapon your own. You will require at least one PEN Blackstar Weapon to gain your Sovereign weapon.</p>

<figure></figure>

<p>Rounding out this is Palace Management. Once you've completed the story, you can utilize a management system the developers say is not too dissimilar to a simulation game. Naturally, that piques my interest. With the Palace Management mode, you can utilize several production nodes that can increase in level. These work into a system that allows automated processing and trade, eventually leaving you only needing to sell the finished goods. It may not be a get-rich-quick scheme, but Pearl Abyss says it will offer a valuable income stream.</p>
<h2>Black Desert Online: Chapter 2 - Into the Past</h2>
<p>Probably the biggest news will be what's coming later. Ten years in, Black Desert Online is now at the end of its first chapter, so Pearl Abyss has started dropping some information on Chapter 2.</p>
<p>The first things to come will be a trip to Everfrost and then to the Demon Land. Following on from the Mountain of Eternal Winter expansion and quest line, you'll venture to the Everfrost mountains and find a massive dungeon with one hundred floors to fight through, each with increasing difficulty. Pearl Abyss promises that this, in particular, will promise a lot for those interested in the lore.</p>
<p>Then there is the Demon Land, which we have been told is designed to be one huge fortress. This will mark the end of Chapter One, and it's said that it will push you and your characters to the limit. Following this trip to the Demon Land will bring Black Desert Online's biggest update as it moves to Chapter Two. It's a trip into the past.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/Black-Desert-Online-Heidel-Ball-Updates-06-Demon-Realm-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>

<p>With the same world, but different, you will take a trip thousands of years into the past. What is desert now used to be lush. The world you know is different, and part of this exploration into the past will be to see where the Black Spirit originated from, and you may even get to change the future. Little more has been revealed regarding Chapter Two, but for those interested in the world and lore, it's likely an exciting trip.</p>

				

			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Acolyte can and should indulge in the Star Wars sequel trilogy’s Knights of Ren lore]]></title>
            <link>https://www.polygon.com/star-wars/24186170/acolyte-master-sith-knights-of-ren</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-acolyte-can-and-should-indulge-in-the-star-wars-sequel-trilogy%E2%80%99s-knights-of-ren-lore.912462/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.polygon.com/star-wars/24186170/acolyte-master-sith-knights-of-ren<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  <p id="AUZWDS">Ever since George Lucas claimed the “echoes” between his original and prequel Star Wars trilogies were <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=egdOaJMSj7A">“poetry,”</a> the mega-franchise has faced criticism of trapping characters in an everything-is-connected universe. When Kid Anakin is building C-3PO and Boba Fett’s dad is the base DNA for the Stormtroopers, Star Wars’ poetry suddenly looked more like Mad Libs than William Blake.</p>
<p id="5YNp1M">True to form, Lucasfilm’s newest series, <a href="https://www.polygon.com/star-wars/24181235/star-wars-acolyte-mae-master-jedi-force-choke-origin"><em>The Acolyte</em></a>, is forming similar<em> </em>echoes (hey, a show about twins!) and Easter eggs (turns out folks have <a href="https://comicbook.com/starwars/news/star-wars-acolyte-wookieepedia-changes-death-threats-fan-reactions-ki-adi-mundi/">a lot of strong feelings about Ki-Adi-Mundi</a>). But its 100-year distance from known Skywalker Saga storytelling feels like expansion, the way history should. George R.R. Martin gets the approach — <a href="https://www.polygon.com/23367111/house-dragon-time-jumps-years-timeline">look at <em>House of the Dragon</em></a> — and <em>The Acolyte </em>creator Leslye Headland, mining <a href="https://www.polygon.com/star-wars/23673259/star-wars-high-republic-explained">the High Republic era</a>, comes closer than most of her Star Wars contemporaries. </p>
<p id="q0mUfu">In episode 5, “Night,” Headland and <em>The Acolyte</em>’s writing team make a direct connection to a Big Star Wars thing, with the potential for an even loftier end goal: an embrace of sequel-trilogy lore. At least, I hope it is, because I am here for the Knights of Ren.</p>
<p id="X5uyxd">[<strong>Ed. note:</strong> This post contains major spoilers for <em>The Acolyte </em>episode 5.]</p>
  <figure>
  <span>
    
    <span data-original="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25504509/star_wars_mae_master_.png">
      
        <picture data-cid="site/picture_element-1719431277_7050_6314" data-cdata="{&quot;asset_id&quot;:25504509,&quot;ratio&quot;:&quot;*&quot;}">
  


  <source srcset="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/72zCBEAVp0L8TORx-yuuSRnhPEU=/0x0:2417x954/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:2417x954):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25504509/star_wars_mae_master_.png 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/02beY_EBcDRObv7zYiVpDGT1qdM=/0x0:2417x954/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:2417x954):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25504509/star_wars_mae_master_.png 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/CAsePuoUqx1GgFZQX91I4qOAOKo=/0x0:2417x954/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:2417x954):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25504509/star_wars_mae_master_.png 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/aMh84hsiFIaPc1-6Rc0T2TfqTu8=/0x0:2417x954/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:2417x954):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25504509/star_wars_mae_master_.png 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/oRtr2VES7eVwUBYC7BmANpP0OK0=/0x0:2417x954/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:2417x954):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25504509/star_wars_mae_master_.png 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/LTW4urlMeCHH-LZxoZnsDPRAJ8U=/0x0:2417x954/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:2417x954):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25504509/star_wars_mae_master_.png 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/djyCu9BZF_jLSj-uPd1VOS3iUMo=/0x0:2417x954/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:2417x954):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25504509/star_wars_mae_master_.png 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VKZe2B0wIEIswKi1_j5Lyv1TaXU=/0x0:2417x954/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:2417x954):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25504509/star_wars_mae_master_.png 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/GquZgwQ4hloiFt1YEFtjxmz93a8=/0x0:2417x954/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:2417x954):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25504509/star_wars_mae_master_.png 1920w" sizes="(min-width: 1221px) 846px, (min-width: 880px) calc(100vw - 334px), 100vw" type="image/webp">




</picture>

      
    </span>
    
  </span>
  
    <span>
      
      
        <cite>Image: Lucasfilm</cite>
      
    </span>
  
</figure>


<p id="xackDG">Picking up where episode 4, “Day,” left off, “Night” is wall-to-wall lightsaber action as the Master slices his way through Jedi adversaries, and Mae and Osha deal with their shit. A face off with Jecki Lon (Dafne Keen) finally takes the Master’s metal face... off... for the show’s big reveal: It’s been Qimir, a so-called smuggler who turns out to be a wannabe Sith Master who hoped Mae was his ticket to the big time.</p>
<p id="qZSenF">When Sol asks him what he wants his answer is simple, if nebulous: “Freedom. The freedom to wield my power the way I like without having to answer to Jedi like you. I want a pupil, an acolyte. But this one went back on our deal.”</p>
<p id="Ljo0nc">Star Wars fandom went into a meltdown after “Day,” when the aforementioned Ki-Adi-Mundi popped up at the Jedi morning meeting to discuss what to do about the Master and Mae. A faction of vocal fans jumped to the conclusion <a href="https://www.cbr.com/star-wars-acolyte-ki-adi-mundi-plot-hole/">that the Master must be Sith</a>, and that <em>The Acolyte</em> invalidated Ki-Adi-Mundi’s assertion in <em>The Phantom Menace</em> that “the Sith have been extinct for a millennium.” In theory, if Ki-Adi-Mundi and the High Republic Jedi (including Yoda) encountered a Sith back in the day, then Ki-Adi-Mundi is either a big fat liar in <em>The Phantom Menace</em> or <em>The Acolyte </em>broke canon. Or maybe the Master isn’t Sith?</p>
<p id="eXbTEa">“Night” does little to quell the fears of Ki-Adi-Mundi stans. When Sol has a chance to question the Master (emitting indie sleaze energy via actor Manny Jacinto), he comes up short. “I have no name,” the Master tells Sol, “but a Jedi like you might call me Sith.”</p>
<p id="8Gs823">That’s an open-and-shut case for people who think the remaining three episodes of <em>The Acolyte</em> will offer zero dramatic turns or greater reveals. But the Master’s use of “might” is doing a lot of work for me, as well as his desperate attempt to find an acolyte. I’m surprised more of the upset Star Wars fans aren’t picking up what Jacinto is putting down in the scene: coming off like an extremely disgruntled fanboy.</p>
  <figure>
  <span>
    
    <span data-original="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507116/mannyjacinto_acoylte.jpg">
      
        <picture data-cid="site/picture_element-1719431277_6276_6315" data-cdata="{&quot;asset_id&quot;:25507116,&quot;ratio&quot;:&quot;*&quot;}">
  


  <source srcset="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9G8_jGuFVRRaWc0Yp9FN1eKwbBk=/0x0:1798x739/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:1798x739):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507116/mannyjacinto_acoylte.jpg 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/unH103EF03z6FURZPTZ4BePYGFo=/0x0:1798x739/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:1798x739):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507116/mannyjacinto_acoylte.jpg 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/LQ2Va_y-G4taw1moYV4NM1XesfA=/0x0:1798x739/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:1798x739):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507116/mannyjacinto_acoylte.jpg 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qJBCBmFaOnCvzwbTEmHk09Cy61k=/0x0:1798x739/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:1798x739):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507116/mannyjacinto_acoylte.jpg 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/yFMtU1Wa4Jgex5ddpi1ZoFarBYs=/0x0:1798x739/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:1798x739):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507116/mannyjacinto_acoylte.jpg 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Mc-UusUeON2qa8me6zYKwaB--oE=/0x0:1798x739/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:1798x739):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507116/mannyjacinto_acoylte.jpg 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Kba2KbJuAI19ePGA4Hye1YH-jUA=/0x0:1798x739/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:1798x739):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507116/mannyjacinto_acoylte.jpg 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/w9Ydp-ko61kCZosUd_sJjzY7TsQ=/0x0:1798x739/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:1798x739):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507116/mannyjacinto_acoylte.jpg 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Dz3bh1KQcVHC_-hFYTICCuu1yNo=/0x0:1798x739/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:1798x739):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507116/mannyjacinto_acoylte.jpg 1920w" sizes="(min-width: 1221px) 846px, (min-width: 880px) calc(100vw - 334px), 100vw" type="image/webp">




</picture>

      
    </span>
    
  </span>
  
    <span>
      
      
        <cite>Image: Lucasfilm</cite>
      
    </span>
  
</figure>


<p id="QNtvGj">In the final scene of “Night,” the Master utters some poetic parting words for the smacked-down Osha. Behind him, composer Michael Abels creates another connection to Star Wars history by quoting John Williams’ Kylo Ren theme from <em>The Force Awakens</em>. This feels extremely telling — as a student of the genetically engineered Force-user Snoke (the sequels were a wild time!) who eventually led the Knights of Ren, Kylo was never a true Sith, just an enthusiast with Darth Vader memorabilia in his bedroom. Abels, nodding to Kylo through music, shades the Master with a similar gray; he might want Sol to refer to him as a Sith, but would a man of integrity like Ki-Adi-Mundi <em>dignify</em> him as such? Or is it more an eager Force-user manifesting his dream role?</p>
<p id="ux8C7u">The blurriness has brought me to my most fan-theorizing moment of <em>The Acolyte</em>, and a bit of my own wishful thinking: The Master might be a founder of the Knights of Ren, previously seen in the sequel trilogy.</p>
<p id="f2Jw5D">On top of the overt nod to Kylo, the design of the Master in <em>The Acolyte</em> is leaning way further into the Knights of Ren than anything in the Sith wardrobe. While the movies offered little in the way of explanation for the Knights of Ren, save for a passing mention by Snoke in <em>The Force Awakens</em> and their bits of action in <em>The Rise of Skywalker</em>, auxiliary Star Wars materials have carved out plenty of foundational canon in true Star Wars fashion. As depicted in the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Star-Wars-Rise-Kylo-Marvel/dp/1302924184?tag=polygon05-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank" has-subtag="true" data-cdata="{&quot;rewritten_url&quot;:&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Star-Wars-Rise-Kylo-Marvel/dp/1302924184?ascsubtag=___pl__p_23950211__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder\u0026tag=polygon05-20&quot;,&quot;subtag_max_length&quot;:99,&quot;subtag_delim_length&quot;:3,&quot;subtag_key&quot;:&quot;ascsubtag&quot;,&quot;subtag_data&quot;:{&quot;ascsubtag&quot;:&quot;___pl__p_23950211__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder&quot;,&quot;tag&quot;:&quot;polygon05-20&quot;},&quot;encode_subtag&quot;:false}"><em>Rise of Kylo Ren</em></a> comics (written by Charles Soule, who also happens to be an engineer of the High Republic era), the Knights were roided-out marauders who wielded the Force with abandon as they pillaged sites across the galaxy. Their vibe screams “would own a Cybertruck.”</p>
  <figure>
  <span>
    
    <span data-original="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19538002/Screen_Shot_2019_12_17_at_9.40.53_PM.png">
      
        <picture data-cid="site/picture_element-1719431277_2767_6316" data-cdata="{&quot;asset_id&quot;:19538002,&quot;ratio&quot;:&quot;*&quot;}">
  


  <source srcset="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/53vu6iooMi04Zb4rV-DBT6apmMY=/0x0:858x671/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:858x671):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19538002/Screen_Shot_2019_12_17_at_9.40.53_PM.png 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/HK_P5uc4GIxAGyQ7oa0NuqIuKOo=/0x0:858x671/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:858x671):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19538002/Screen_Shot_2019_12_17_at_9.40.53_PM.png 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NGwyzewGcldtyrvqmFS0Mvq2x-s=/0x0:858x671/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:858x671):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19538002/Screen_Shot_2019_12_17_at_9.40.53_PM.png 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/CBF5zOnp7GtP8ebMXdn31reKtkI=/0x0:858x671/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:858x671):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19538002/Screen_Shot_2019_12_17_at_9.40.53_PM.png 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/vMsJNc-Qg78qUAx7fUJpdCX2h3o=/0x0:858x671/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:858x671):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19538002/Screen_Shot_2019_12_17_at_9.40.53_PM.png 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cBzyrhrL72rkEBZje_hn7SWtOe8=/0x0:858x671/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:858x671):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19538002/Screen_Shot_2019_12_17_at_9.40.53_PM.png 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/jLPn-xbESLLLfC86GqNlyj63_Oo=/0x0:858x671/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:858x671):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19538002/Screen_Shot_2019_12_17_at_9.40.53_PM.png 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/sBghppJGBlGX03kbagJDwACiXz8=/0x0:858x671/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:858x671):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19538002/Screen_Shot_2019_12_17_at_9.40.53_PM.png 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Z8vj8UutKcgaX2We_N-AyBeobXk=/0x0:858x671/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:858x671):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19538002/Screen_Shot_2019_12_17_at_9.40.53_PM.png 1920w" sizes="(min-width: 1221px) 846px, (min-width: 880px) calc(100vw - 334px), 100vw" type="image/webp">




</picture>

      
    </span>
    
  </span>
  
    <span>
      
      
        <cite>Image:  Charles Soule, Will Sliney/Marvel Comics</cite>
      
    </span>
  
</figure>


<p id="nXG2zz"><em>The Acolyte </em>costume designer Jennifer Bryan told Polygon that <a href="https://www.polygon.com/star-wars/24185141/star-wars-acolyte-master-mask-donnie-darko-design"><em>Donnie Darko</em> was a major inspiration</a> for the creepy, toothed-smile look of the Master’s helmet, but when I saw him bust out his lightsaber moves in “Night,” muscled arms jabbing from under a flowing robe, I immediately pictured the leader of the Knights of Ren from the New Republic era. I could definitely see the Master running with [<em>checks notes</em>] “Vicrul, the Reaper of the Fallen” and other Knights of Ren with totally chill nicknames. </p>
<p id="zecbmo">In 2022’s <a href="https://www.amazon.com/STAR-WARS-CRIMSON-Steven-Cummings/dp/0785194681?tag=polygon05-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank" has-subtag="true" data-cdata="{&quot;rewritten_url&quot;:&quot;https://www.amazon.com/STAR-WARS-CRIMSON-Steven-Cummings/dp/0785194681?ascsubtag=___pl__p_23950211__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder\u0026tag=polygon05-20&quot;,&quot;subtag_max_length&quot;:99,&quot;subtag_delim_length&quot;:3,&quot;subtag_key&quot;:&quot;ascsubtag&quot;,&quot;subtag_data&quot;:{&quot;ascsubtag&quot;:&quot;___pl__p_23950211__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder&quot;,&quot;tag&quot;:&quot;polygon05-20&quot;},&quot;encode_subtag&quot;:false}"><em>Star Wars: Crimson Reign</em></a>, Charles Soule again expands the mythology of the Knights of Ren. The comic book series focuses on Qi’ra, from <em>Solo</em> (who has become <a href="https://www.polygon.com/comics/22464295/war-of-the-bounty-hunters-1-review-star-wars-comic">unexpectedly vital to Star Wars lore</a>?), and the attempt destabilize the growing Empire. Part of Qi’ra’s plan? Hiring the Knights of Ren to pull off a heist at Vader’s castle on Mustafar. The relevant but almost throwaway line in the action-forward book is that the Knights of Ren have existed for centuries — and at some point fell from grace.</p>
  <figure>
  <span>
    
    <span data-original="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507031/crimsondawn4.jpg">
      
        <picture data-cid="site/picture_element-1719431277_7867_6317" data-cdata="{&quot;asset_id&quot;:25507031,&quot;ratio&quot;:&quot;*&quot;}">
  


  <source srcset="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rpWdW25lk5BoTcjxL_Ik1dfpyo4=/0x0:800x515/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:800x515):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507031/crimsondawn4.jpg 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/YCLDaw32EuR87Xdj9zqsFOBDJfA=/0x0:800x515/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:800x515):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507031/crimsondawn4.jpg 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/oGysToP-XYGWsJWSuiZmNK7o9ZA=/0x0:800x515/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:800x515):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507031/crimsondawn4.jpg 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/SxPBIopKzqTLEYmqTrU3UIlGiqk=/0x0:800x515/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:800x515):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507031/crimsondawn4.jpg 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/DuItKLytwDDibx2Tr4OlW6OXt28=/0x0:800x515/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:800x515):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507031/crimsondawn4.jpg 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/h9TLzDI14H5kTu-Yk3YPX96nJBc=/0x0:800x515/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:800x515):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507031/crimsondawn4.jpg 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/uiCd_wNicptKi_gaNMRfBWJv_i0=/0x0:800x515/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:800x515):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507031/crimsondawn4.jpg 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BKjQEAELl_NvwuoLjMJxOlgHGgk=/0x0:800x515/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:800x515):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507031/crimsondawn4.jpg 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xO1Wtz6oF8yi01cE7tC7oOjAqo4=/0x0:800x515/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:800x515):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507031/crimsondawn4.jpg 1920w" sizes="(min-width: 1221px) 846px, (min-width: 880px) calc(100vw - 334px), 100vw" type="image/webp">




</picture>

      
    </span>
    
  </span>
  
    <span>
      
      
        <cite>Image: Charles Soule, Steven Cummings/Marvel Comics</cite>
      
    </span>
  
</figure>


<p id="KGDks0">The Master may very well be the first step forward for a new age of Sith, and the Star Wars timeline continues to make less and less sense. But even as someone bristled over <em>The Rise of Skywalker</em>’s all-too-neat Palpatine connections and the Exquisite Corpse exercise of the sequel trilogy, I would be eager to see Headland thread the Knights of Ren into broader Star Wars context. </p>
<p id="FeiYvx">The intrigue of the original Star Wars movies was that everything we see, even in a flash, has history behind it. There’s danger in carving out the backstory of characters like the Knights of Ren, basically window dressing with legs, but as Soule proved out in the comics, they do play an essential role in Kylo’s (underbaked) journey to the Dark Side and the spectrum of Force use in the galaxy. The High Republic readers know there are already established marauders in this era — see: <a href="https://www.polygon.com/star-wars/2021/1/12/22221112/light-of-the-jedi-spoilers-author-charles-soule-interview">Marchion Ro and the vicious Nihil</a> — but if Headland wants to make the Star Wars universe more cohesive, more lived-in, sidestepping the obvious reveal of a new Sith for something more complicated would be a delightful twist for <em>The Acolyte. </em>The “acolyte” of the title could be Mae or Osha, but as it stands after episode 5, the Master himself might fit the description, a devotee of the Dark Side who... just hasn’t invented the Knights of Ren yet.</p>

  
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Steam Just Made It Super Easy To Record All Your Biggest Gaming Moments]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/steam-valve-game-recording-editing-update-beta-deck-1851562386</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/steam-just-made-it-super-easy-to-record-all-your-biggest-gaming-moments.912459/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/steam-valve-game-recording-editing-update-beta-deck-1851562386<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>A new beta update for Steam adds a robust and useful gameplay recording tool to the popular PC launcher, letting you record, edit, and share amazing moments or horrible mistakes with ease on both desktop and <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/valve-steam-deck-pc-console-switch-horizon-zero-dawn-re-1848628507&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/valve-steam-deck-pc-console-switch-horizon-zero-dawn-re-1848628507">Steam Deck</a></span>. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="193627" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="The Top Ten Most Played Games On Steam Deck: January 2023 Edition" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="140" data-playlist="193627,195189,196131" data-current="193627"><div><p>The Top Ten Most Played Games On Steam Deck: January 2023 Edition</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/193627/193627_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/193627/193627_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/193627/193627_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/193627/193627_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/19077.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>When Steam first launched in 2003 it was just a way to <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Steam_(service)#:~:text=In%20November%202004,rollout.%5B14%5D&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Steam_(service)#:~:text=In%20November%202004,rollout.%5B14%5D" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">update some Valve games like <em>Half-Life 2</em></a></span> and buy digital titles. But now, 20 years later, Steam has evolved into a large platform that includes forums, mods, DLC, streaming, and the ability to share guides and screenshots with other players. And you can now add gameplay capture to the long list of things Steam can do. </p><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://store.steampowered.com/sale/gamerecording&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://store.steampowered.com/sale/gamerecording" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Announced on June 26, Steam Game Recording</a></span> is a new suite of tools and features that will let players easily record gameplay in any game, even non-Steam games. As long as Steam is open and the overlay works, you can record gameplay footage of any game. </p><p>Before you start messing around with all the cool new recording and editing tools, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://store.steampowered.com/sale/gamerecording#:~:text=Settings%20%3E%20Interface%20%3E%20Beta,On%20Demand%20recording&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://store.steampowered.com/sale/gamerecording#:~:text=Settings%20%3E%20Interface%20%3E%20Beta,On%20Demand%20recording" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">you’ll need to opt into the Steam beta branch</a></span>. Just head to the Steam menu, go to settings, and then interface, and from there select either of the beta options. Steam will then restart and, bam, you’ll be able to record yourself dying 200 times to an <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-steam-reviews-1851557175&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-steam-reviews-1851557175"><em>Elden Ring</em> boss</a></span>. </p><h2 id="h132582"><a id=""></a>All you can do with Steam’s new video recording tool</h2><p>Valve has launched the new Game Recording tool (which it says is still in beta) with a bunch of useful options. You can have Steam always recording in the background when playing a game and you can also limit how much space these recordings can take up before Valve starts to overwrite the recorded footage. Valve suggests this could let you go back and clip—using basic editing tools included in Steam—a cool moment or even let you go back to see what an NPC said about a sidequest. You can also set up Game Recording to record clips manually, too. </p><figure id="" data-id="d7ebd14217e691d8249b1546f24ea866" data-recommend-id="image://d7ebd14217e691d8249b1546f24ea866" data-format="gif" data-width="800" data-height="450" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A gif showing the new gameplay recording options in Steam. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A gif showing the new gameplay recording options in Steam. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Gif<!-- -->: <!-- -->Valve / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="d7ebd14217e691d8249b1546f24ea866" data-recommend-id="image://d7ebd14217e691d8249b1546f24ea866" data-format="gif" data-width="800" data-height="450" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A gif showing the new gameplay recording options in Steam. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Some games—currently only <em>DOTA </em>2 and <em>Counter-Strike 2</em>—will also be able to add custom markers to your gameplay’s timeline, making it easy to edit together montages of headshots or wins.<br></p><p>Even better, you and your recordings aren’t trapped within Steam. Valve will let you easily export any clip or recording as a raw .mp4 that you can edit and alter using third-party software. You can even share clips with other Steam users via chat or a QR code. You can also send clips recorded on your Steam Deck to your PC for easy editing later. And yes, all of this works on Steam Deck, making the handheld PC even more useful. </p><p>This is just another example of how Valve has continued to make Steam the best PC store launcher out there by a huge margin. Even though I want games to launch on more platforms and PC stores, I understand <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/desktop-launcher-pc-review-ea-battle-net-ubisoft-app-1850489703&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/desktop-launcher-pc-review-ea-battle-net-ubisoft-app-1850489703">why so many people prefer Valve’s software</a></span>. It’s free, easy to use, and always getting better. </p><p> .<br></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This Real Life Monkey Ball Is My New Favorite Video Game Controller]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/super-monkey-ball-banana-rumble-controller-switch-1851562449</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/this-real-life-monkey-ball-is-my-new-favorite-video-game-controller.912456/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/super-monkey-ball-banana-rumble-controller-switch-1851562449<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="b146837e2da960578e7c68f0f113d105" data-recommend-id="image://b146837e2da960578e7c68f0f113d105" data-format="gif" data-width="800" data-height="450" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A monkey ball is rolled to play the game. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A monkey ball is rolled to play the game. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Gif<!-- -->: <!-- -->Thomas Tilley / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="b146837e2da960578e7c68f0f113d105" data-recommend-id="image://b146837e2da960578e7c68f0f113d105" data-format="gif" data-width="800" data-height="450" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A monkey ball is rolled to play the game. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>Anything can become a gaming controller <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-super-louis-64-banana-controller-emulator-bo-1848657617&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-super-louis-64-banana-controller-emulator-bo-1848657617">if you try hard enough</a></span>, even a monkey in a ball. Thomas Tilley proved that after his recent creation went viral, making every match of <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/super-monkey-ball-banana-rumble-review-nintendo-switch-1851556393&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/super-monkey-ball-banana-rumble-review-nintendo-switch-1851556393"><em>Super Monkey Ball Banana Rumble</em></a></span> played on a normal Switch Joy-Con controller feel like a huge missed opportunity by comparison. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196165" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="What’s Coming Out Beyond Pokémon: The Indigo Disk | The Week In Games" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="95" data-playlist="196165,196698,196572" data-current="196165"><div><p>What’s Coming Out Beyond Pokémon: The Indigo Disk | The Week In Games</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196165/196165_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196165/196165_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196165/196165_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196165/196165_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21711.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p> Tilley, who you may know as the creator of the world’s biggest playable Game &amp; Watch handheld, used a tripod with a mouse tracking ball at the bottom and a plastic ball to make the dream reality. “Everybody’s adding AI to things these days so I thought I’d add AiAi to my DIY soccer/football controller,” he <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/DrTomTilley/status/1805790393927450683&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/DrTomTilley/status/1805790393927450683" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">tweeted</a></span> more recently. He had already made a similar setup for playing <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=grBtq9hROtg&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=grBtq9hROtg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Armadillo Racing</em></a></span>. All he had to do was 3D print a sculpture of AiAi, <em>Super Monkey Ball</em>’s main hero, paint him, and get him glued down inside the ball.</p><p><strong>Buy <em>Super Monkey Ball: Banana Rumble:</em></strong><em>&nbsp;</em><span><a data-ga="[]" href="https://www.amazon.com/Super-Monkey-Ball-Banana-Rumble-Nintendo/dp/B0CW3W97PS/ref=sr_1_1?asc_campaign=kinjakotakulink-20&amp;asc_refurl=https://kotaku.com/super-monkey-ball-banana-rumble-controller-switch-1851562449&amp;asc_source=&amp;tag=kinjakotakulink-20" target="_blank" rel="sponsored noopener noreferrer nofollow noskim" data-vtas-click="self:InlineUrl:inline-url-postbody" data-amazonasin="B0CW3W97PS" data-amazontag="kinjakotakulink-20">Amazon</a></span> | <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://howl.me/cmw2S3qYJTh&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://howl.me/cmw2S3qYJTh" target="_blank" rel="sponsored noopener noreferrer nofollow noskim" data-vtas-click="self:InlineUrl:inline-url-postbody">Best Buy</a></span> | <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.anrdoezrs.net/click-8335294-14555742?sid=KT-&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.humblebundle.com%2Fstore%2Fsuper-monkey-ball-banana-rumble-switch%3Fhmb_source%3Dsearch_bar&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/click-8335294-14555742?sid=KT-&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.humblebundle.com%2Fstore%2Fsuper-monkey-ball-banana-rumble-switch%3Fhmb_source%3Dsearch_bar" target="_blank" rel="sponsored noopener noreferrer nofollow noskim" data-vtas-click="self:InlineUrl:inline-url-postbody">Humble Bundle</a></span></p><p>The platform is made out of cardboard while deodorant roller-balls attached at three points help stabilize the ball without inhibiting its movement. As Tilley explained in a previous thread when he was adapting the mechanism for<em> Katamari Damacy</em>. “A FreePIE script maps the mouse movement to two virtual vJoy thumbsticks for the in-game control,” he <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/DrTomTilley/status/1613846136074432512&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/DrTomTilley/status/1613846136074432512" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">wrote</a></span> when describing the peripheral last year. </p><p>For some it was reminiscent of the<em> </em><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/SodaCanTablet/status/1805845639936590169&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/SodaCanTablet/status/1805845639936590169" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Super Monkey Ball Ticket Blitz</em> arcade cabinet</a></span>, though even that one didn’t have a bespoke AiAi running around on it. If <em>Super Monkey Ball Banana Rumble</em> ever gets a collector’s edition and it doesn’t come with one of these I’ll be disappointed now. For those without the ingenuity or tools, you’ll just have to ponder AiAi’s orb in your free time. Fortunately, <em>Super Monkey Ball Banana Rumble </em>sounds like its <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/super-monkey-ball-banana-rumble-review-nintendo-switch-1851556393&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/super-monkey-ball-banana-rumble-review-nintendo-switch-1851556393">excellent enough</a></span> even without a special controller. </p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Brazen Blaze launches July 18]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/06/brazen-blaze-launches-july-18</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/brazen-blaze-launches-july-18.912453/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/06/brazen-blaze-launches-july-18<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/meta/quest">Quest</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Virtual reality three-versus-three "smack-and-shoot action" game dated.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Genres > Virtual Reality [144 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/virtual-reality">Virtual reality</a> three-versus-three “smack-and-shoot action” game <em><a title="Games > Brazen Blaze [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/brazen-blaze">Brazen Blaze</a></em> will launch for <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2511050/Brazen_Blaze/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">SteamVR</a> and <a title="Platforms > Quest [105 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/meta/quest">Quest</a> on July 18 for $14.99, developer <a title="Companies > MyDearest [37 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/mydearest">MyDearest</a> announced. <a href="https://www.meta.com/experiences/7109109785811976/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Meta Store</a> pre-orders are available today at a 13 percent-off discount price, and include exclusive skins. <span id="more-894947"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2511050/Brazen_Blaze/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam page</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>Brazen Blaze</em> is a three-versus-three smack-and-shoot virtual reality <a title="Genres > Action [1,965 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action game</a> with emphasis on close quarter melee combat! Choose from a range of unique Runners each equipped with individual skills meant to destroy whatever blocks your path to sure victory!</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li>Buckle up, Runners! Each clash is a lightning round—five to ten minutes of pure adrenaline! Fists fly, lasers flash, skills ignite—think fast, fight smart, and dominate the arena!</li><li>Forget generic pew-pew, we’re talking simplified yet exciting battles. Spit lead with the Submachine Gun, dance with Death with the Sword, or laugh off bullets with Shield. Choose your Runner, choose your style, and become the next President of the World!</li><li>Strike down the last player in the enemy team and unlock a satisfying finishing move! Punch and blast foes into outer space, slice the enemy in bits, fill ’em with holes with multiple guns—it’s fun to kill and get killed too.</li><li>Wreak havoc on the battlefield of the Presidential War. You can smash buildings, taxis, statues of political importance, and anything you fancy breaking.</li></ul><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>The President of the World is chosen by strength. Raise your gauntlets, and get ready for the Presidential War!</p><p><strong>Non-Stop Updates</strong></p><p>Expect non-stop, continuous updates throughout the entire Open Beta based on the community’s feedback to improve not only the actual gameplay but also the new future content!</p></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><p><iframe title="Brazen Blaze - Release Date Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/y4O1fzy1Fak?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe title="【ブレイゼンブレイズ】 発売日告知トレーラー" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Kt4ajMBcF9U?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[THRASHER launches July 25 for Quest and Apple Vision Pro, in December for SteamVR]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/06/thrasher-launches-july-25-for-quest-and-apple-vision-pro-in-december-for-steamvr</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/thrasher-launches-july-25-for-quest-and-apple-vision-pro-in-december-for-steamvr.912447/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/06/thrasher-launches-july-25-for-quest-and-apple-vision-pro-in-december-for-steamvr<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div role="main">
  
  <article>

    
<header>

  <div>

    <ul>
        </ul>

    
    <p><span>Flatscreen versions to follow.</span>
      </p></div>

  

</header>  

<!-- Moved from templates/posts/default.php -->

    <div><p>“Cosmic racer and essential audiovisual experience” game <em><a title="Games > THRASHER [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/thrasher">THRASHER</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > Quest [105 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/meta/quest">Quest</a> and Apple Vision Pro on July 25 for $19.99, followed by <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2702300/Thrasher/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">SteamVR</a> in December, publisher <a title="Companies > Creature [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/creature">Creature</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Puddle [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/puddle">Puddle</a> announced. A flatscreen version and console versions will follow. <span id="more-895271"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Creature:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>From the artist and composer behind the cult hit <em><a title="Games > Thumper [7 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/thumper">THUMPER</a></em> comes <em>THRASHER</em>, a mind-melting cosmic racer and essential audiovisual experience. Use fast paced gestural controls to evolve your space eel from worm to megabeast in a breakneck race for <a title="Genres > Survival [293 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/survival">survival</a> that begins at the dawn of time.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Transcend Spacetime</strong> – Immerse yourself in a dazzling <a title="Genres > Adventure [1,590 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a> across space, where music, visuals and gameplay mesh into one transcendent experience.</li><li><strong>You vs. the Universe</strong> – Use elegant gestural controls to swoop, dash and thrash across the void at breakneck speed, busting through obstacles and stacking up combos as you battle towards the next boss.</li><li><strong>Sound and Fury</strong> – Lose yourself in the thumping soundtrack created by designer Brian Gibson, bassist for the band Lightning Bolt. Thrasher is a 3D audio showcase, combining spatial audio and haptics to create a stunning sensory experience.</li><li><strong>Chill or Challenge</strong> – Vibe out and enjoy the crazy journey, or push yourself to the limit by chaining together huge combos to worm your way up the rankings.</li></ul><!-- AD: content -->
        </blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="THRASHER Release Date Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/08g2lnQpKYc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div>

        
    
  </article>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Get Asus' Wireless Xbox And PC Controller For Only $60 For A Limited Time]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/get-asus-wireless-xbox-and-pc-controller-for-only-60-for-a-limited-time/1100-6524510/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/get-asus-wireless-xbox-and-pc-controller-for-only-60-for-a-limited-time.912444/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/get-asus-wireless-xbox-and-pc-controller-for-only-60-for-a-limited-time/1100-6524510/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6524510">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Contrary to what your folks told you, looks do matter, especially in the competitive space of video game controllers. Ahead of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/amazon-prime-day-deals/">Amazon Prime Day 2024</a>, the <em>very </em>good-looking <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fgoto.walmart.com%2Fc%2F1804712%2F565706%2F9383%3Fveh%3Daff%26sourceid%3Dimp_000011112222333344%26u%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FASUS-ROG-Raikiri-officially-licensed-Xbox-controller-remappable-buttons-triggers-2-rear-buttons-step-linear-adjustable-joystick-sensitivity-3-5mm-jac%2F5455816964%26subId1%3Dsubid_value&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fget-asus-wireless-xbox-and-pc-controller-for-only-60-for-a-limited-time%2F1100-6524510%2F%3Fftag%3DCAD-01-10abi2f&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Asus ROG Raikiri wireless controller</a> has gotten a nice discount, as the price of this officially licensed Xbox peripheral has dropped from $100 to $60 at Walmart. This puts it around the same price point as a standard Xbox controller--which is <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fgoto.walmart.com%2Fc%2F1804712%2F565706%2F9383%3Fveh%3Daff%26sourceid%3Dimp_000011112222333344%26u%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FMicrosoft-Xbox-Wireless-Controller-Arctic-Camo%2F2186264517%3Fathbdg%3DL1102%26subId1%3Dsubid_value&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fget-asus-wireless-xbox-and-pc-controller-for-only-60-for-a-limited-time%2F1100-6524510%2F%3Fftag%3DCAD-01-10abi2f&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">also on sale at Walmart</a>--although it does have a few neat tricks up its proverbial sleeve, including remappable back buttons, adjustable stick sensitivity, trigger locks, and a built-in audio DAC.</p><h3>Asus ROG Raikiri Controller -- $60 (was $100)</h3><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4325025-raikiri-1.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4325025" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4325025-raikiri-1.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4325025"></a><figcaption>Asus Raikiri Controller</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4325025-raikiri-1.jpg"></figure><p>Like other third-party devices, there's a focus on customization with two programmable back buttons. You can also toggle the triggers to have less push and quicker actuation, while the Asus Armory Crate app allows for more fine-tuning. Otherwise, you're getting everything else you'd expect on a PC and Xbox controller: Solid face buttons, a dedicated capture button for grabbing snapshots and videos, a 3.5mm jack, and a USB-C connection for when you want to play in a wired mode. If Walmart sells out, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/ASUS-ROG-connectivity-remappable-Sensitivity/dp/B0C6WQX5ZW?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Amazon is selling the controller for $75</a>.</p><hr><h2>Asus ROG Raikiri Pro Controller -- $130 (was $150)</h2><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4325026-raikiri-2.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4325026" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4325026-raikiri-2.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4325026"></a><figcaption>Asus ROG Raikiri Pro</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4325026-raikiri-2.jpg"></figure><hr><p>If you feel like moving a step up, the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/ASUS-ROG-connectivity-remappable-Sensitivity/dp/B0CJN1LXT8?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Asus Raikiri Pro</a> adds two more back buttons and an OLED display. This is more of a cosmetic extra, but a fun one as you can create custom animations, see which custom gaming profile you have selected, and monitor your controller power status.</p><p>There are a few other great controllers on sale right now as well. <strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Revolution-Officially-Licensed-PlayStation-Controller-5/dp/B0CLBLFDBL?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Nacon's new Revolution 5 Pro controller</a></strong>, which is compatible with PS5 and PC, offers some interesting hardware and a possible edge in fighting games with its unique swap-out D-Pad. It also has remappable microswitch back paddles, interchangeable weights, trigger locks, and Hall Effect (anti-drift) sticks.</p><p><strong>Nacon Revolution 5 Pro deal (PS5/PC)</strong></p><ul><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Revolution-Officially-Licensed-PlayStation-Controller-5/dp/B0CLBLFDBL?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Amazon</a> -- $175 ($<strike>200</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fshop-links.co%2F1846189413506010154%3Fu1%3Dsubid_value&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fget-asus-wireless-xbox-and-pc-controller-for-only-60-for-a-limited-time%2F1100-6524510%2F%3Fftag%3DCAD-01-10abi2f&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Best Buy (Black model only)</a> -- $175 ($<strike>200</strike>)</li></ul><p>Back on the Xbox and PC side of things, you can't go wrong with Microsoft's excellent <strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Xbox-Elite-Wireless-Controller-Gaming-Console/dp/B07SFKTLZ?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Elite Series 2 controllers</a></strong>. The <strong><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fgoto.target.com%2Fc%2F1804712%2F81938%2F2092%3FsubId1%3Dsubid_value%26u%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Fxbox-elite-core-wireless-controller-red%2F-%2FA-88533778&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fget-asus-wireless-xbox-and-pc-controller-for-only-60-for-a-limited-time%2F1100-6524510%2F%3Fftag%3DCAD-01-10abi2f&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Core model got a big discount at Target--$96 instead of $140</a></strong>--and is a good option if you don't mind not having a collection of extra parts for more in-depth customization.</p><p>Otherwise, you can pick up an <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Xbox-Elite-Wireless-Controller-Gaming-Console/dp/B07SFKTLZ?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Elite Series 2 controller</a> with all of the additional accessories for $175 at Amazon, down from its usual $200 price. Best Buy has the same deal, but only for the black model.</p><p><strong>Xbox Elite Series 2 deal (Xbox/PC)</strong></p><ul><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Xbox-Elite-Wireless-Controller-Gaming-Console/dp/B07SFKTLZ?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Xbox Elite Series 2 controller</a> -- $151 ($<strike>180</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fgoto.target.com%2Fc%2F1804712%2F81938%2F2092%3FsubId1%3Dsubid_value%26u%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Fxbox-elite-core-wireless-controller-red%2F-%2FA-88533778&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fget-asus-wireless-xbox-and-pc-controller-for-only-60-for-a-limited-time%2F1100-6524510%2F%3Fftag%3DCAD-01-10abi2f&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Xbox Elite Series 2 Core controller</a> -- $96 ($<strike>140</strike>)</li></ul><div data-embed-type="pinbox" data-ref-id="4304">  <ul>                              <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/lord-of-the-rings-4k-blu-ray-box-set-amazon-preorder/1100-6524366/">Lord Of The Rings 4K Blu-Ray Steelbook Collection Is Back In Print, Preorders Live At Amazon</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/official-xbox-controllers-get-significant-discounts-at-amazon-and-walmart/1100-6524341/">Official Xbox Controllers Get Significant Discounts At Amazon And Walmart</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/zelda-links-awakening-is-back-in-stock-for-40-at-amazon/1100-6511630/">Get Ready For Zelda: Echoes Of Wisdom With This Great Link's Awakening Deal</a></li>                          <li>         <span>+ Show More Best Gaming &amp; Tech Deals This Week Links (2)</span>       </li>          <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/save-big-on-nintendo-switch-joy-con-controllers-at-amazon-and-walmart/1100-6523566/">Save Big On Nintendo Switch Joy-Con Controllers At Amazon And Walmart</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/inside-out-2-fans-should-check-out-the-new-lego-mood-cube-set/1100-6524400/">Inside Out 2 Fans Should Check Out The New Lego Mood Cube Set</a></li>   </ul> </div>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/108490194306897153177?rel=author">Darryn Bonthuys</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fortnite's Popular New Mode Is Adding An Important Feature Soon]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fortnites-popular-new-mode-is-adding-an-important-feature-soon/1100-6524541/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fortnites-popular-new-mode-is-adding-an-important-feature-soon.912438/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fortnites-popular-new-mode-is-adding-an-important-feature-soon/1100-6524541/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6524541">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">Get ready to find the peanut butter to your jelly because duos is on the way for Fortnite Reload. Developer Epic revealed today that squads won't be the only option in the popular new mode starting tomorrow.</p><p dir="ltr">The <a href="https://x.com/FortniteGame/status/1806018400197443729" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">official Fortnite account</a> on X (formerly known as Twitter) announced Reload Duos will launch at 6 AM PT / 9 AM ET on June 27. Currently, Fortnite Reload only features squads consisting of four players.</p><p dir="ltr">For those unfamiliar, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fortnite-reload-mode-is-live-exclusive-loot-available-for-those-who-like-a-challenge/1100-6524461/" data-ref-id="1100-6524461">Fortnite Reload takes place on a smaller island</a> featuring the beloved location Tilted Towers. There is a maximum of 40 people and players can respawn instead of revived by teammates. But that only happens if one of your squadmates is still alive. It's all similar to Call of Duty: Warzone's Resurgence. It would seem that duos will lead to even shorter matches, since eliminating full teams should be a lot easier.</p><p dir="ltr">So far, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fortnite-reload-is-an-apology-to-sweaty-streamers-and-its-amazing/1100-6524502/" data-ref-id="1100-6524502">Fortnite Reload feels like an apology to sweaty streamers</a>. Not only that, but GameSpot writer Phil Owen believes the new mode appeals to a wider audience, too. He wrote: "So, yeah, I love Fortnite Reload, and I wasn't even one of those folks who hated Chapter 5 Season 3--I've been a big fan of this season's whole car thing, in fact."</p><p dir="ltr">Fortnite Reload isn't the only new, big-time event to take place in the game recently. Over this past weekend, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/a-metallica-concert-is-coming-to-fortnite-this-month/1100-6524177/" data-ref-id="1100-6524177">there was a Metallica concert in the game</a>, as well.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox Streaming Console Patent Unearthed, Showing What Cloud Gaming Could Have Been]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/xbox-streaming-console-patent-unearthed-showing-what-cloud-gaming-could-have-been/1100-6524542/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/xbox-streaming-console-patent-unearthed-showing-what-cloud-gaming-could-have-been.912435/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/xbox-streaming-console-patent-unearthed-showing-what-cloud-gaming-could-have-been/1100-6524542/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6524542">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Microsoft was previously working on a console that would stream Xbox games through the cloud. It was codenamed Keystone but it will likely never see the light of day. However, a patent of Keystone was uncovered and it shows what it could have looked like.</p><p>Found by <a href="https://www.windowscentral.com/gaming/xbox/the-xbox-that-never-was-our-first-detailed-look-at-the-keystone-cloud-streaming-console-design" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Windows Central</a>, the patent was filed in 2022. It shows the Keystone's potential shape and internal functions. It looks to be about half the size of an Xbox Series S, being a square with a large circular vent, just like the Series S has. It's reminiscent of the first PlayStation console, which had its disk drive on the top.</p><p>The front has both the console's power button as well as a USB-A port, while the back has ports for HDMI, ethernet, power. There's also what looks like a pairing button for the Xbox controller.</p><p>Back in 2022, Xbox chief Phil Spencer revealed why it had not released Keystone, saying <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/phil-spencer-on-why-the-xbox-streaming-console-isnt-ready-yet/1100-6509207/" data-ref-id="1100-6509207">that it was more expensive than Microsoft expected</a> it to be when the device was actually built out. Spencer said that the device should have costed between $99-$129, but Microsoft couldn't achieve that price point, partially because it would have also come bundled with a controller, which typically costs <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/accessories/controllers/xbox-wireless-controller" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">between $50-$60 by itself</a>. The Series S already was $300, so the potential price delta between it and Keystone was not large enough.</p><p>Instead, however, Microsoft refocused those efforts toward creating <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/you-can-now-stream-xbox-games-from-a-new-samsung-tv-no-console-required/1100-6505013/" data-ref-id="1100-6505013">Xbox streaming apps for Smart TVs</a>, such as the ones in the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-samsung-xbox-tv-app-works-great-but-who-is-it-for/1100-6504321/" data-ref-id="1100-6504321">2022 Samsung models</a>. That's not to say that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/xbox-streaming-box-still-years-away-despite-prototype-tease/1100-6508679/" data-ref-id="1100-6508679">Xbox won't try again in the future</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/115776530127739146123?rel=author">George Yang</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Eldritch Automata, The Cosmic Horror Mecha TTRPG, Blows Up On Backerkit]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/eldritch-automata-cosmic-horror-mecha-ttrpg-blows-up-on-backerkit</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/eldritch-automata-the-cosmic-horror-mecha-ttrpg-blows-up-on-backerkit.912408/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/eldritch-automata-cosmic-horror-mecha-ttrpg-blows-up-on-backerkit<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="page-content">
<article role="article" about="/tabletop/news/eldritch-automata-cosmic-horror-mecha-ttrpg-blows-up-on-backerkit">
<div>



<div>
<div><p>Back in January, Gehenna Games launched a <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/eldritch-automata-combines-mecha-with-cosmic-horror" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Kickstarter campaign</a> for the cosmic horror mecha TTRPG <em>Eldritch Automata</em>. Ultimately, the campaign fell short of its funding goal. Now, the studio has relaunched the campaign on Backerkit, where it reaches its funding goal in 36 minutes.</p>

<p>According to the <a href="https://www.backerkit.com/c/projects/gehenna-gaming/eldritch-automata-action-horror-ttrpg">Backerkit campaign page</a>, <em>Eldritch Automata</em> is a high-octane TTRPG set in a dark and dangerous setting. It is set in a recent-apocalyptic world packed with body horror, man-eating eldritch Horrors, and angelic Seraphs with mind-control powers. Your only weapon against them is your Automata, a monstrous mecha that slowly kills you.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/eldritch-automata-strand-screenshot.jpg?itok=VulxeNUT 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/eldritch-automata-strand-screenshot.jpg?itok=f1Te1QgQ 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Pilots have Strands, connections to people central to their lives.</figcaption></figure><p>For fans of mecha and cosmic horror, <em>Eldritch Automata</em> wears its inspirations on its sleeve. The campaign cites Guillermo del Toro's <em>Pacific Rim</em>, Sunrise Studios' <em>The Vision of Escaflowne</em>, and Hideaki Anno's iconic <em>Neon Genesis Evangelion</em>.</p>
<p>The inspiration for the latter is explicit in <em>Eldritch Automata's</em> character archetypes. Based on the <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/free-league-announces-year-zero-engine-ogl" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Year Zero Engine</a>, the game features twelve archetypes such as The Bound, The Control Freak, The Hedgehog's Dilemma, The Manufactured, and The Thanatos.</p>
<p>Players can customize their pilot and one of twelve different Automata. In addition to different attributes and skills, players manage their Ego. This represents the pilots consciousness and identity. It fuels your Automata's special abilities. If your Ego is fully depleted, it will cause you and your Automata to go berserk.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/eldritch-automata-backerkit-horror-artwork.jpg?itok=SiEIU4HN 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/eldritch-automata-backerkit-horror-artwork.jpg?itok=2RV1dXyB 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Even in a giant robot, I'd be terrified of fighting this thing.</figcaption></figure><p>The <em>Eldritch Automata</em> Backerkit campaign contains several stretch goals. They include additional customization options, a physical deluxe edition core rulebook, as well as official enhanced support for <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/interviews/alchemy-rpg-vtts-and-focus-on-roleplaying" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Alchemy RPG</a>, Its various pledge levels are as follows:</p>
<ul><li><strong>Civilian for $35:</strong> A PDF copy of the core rulebook and Alchemy RPG access</li>
<li><strong>Automata for $55:</strong> A physical hardcover copy of the game and everything in Civilian level</li>
<li><strong>Horror for $100:</strong> Everything in Automata level, a quick launch guide, official dice, GM Screen, and Horror Dossier Pack</li>
<li><strong>Seraph for $200:</strong> Everything in Horror level, a Deluxe Edition physical copy, official metal dice, and Seraph Dossier Pack</li>
<li><strong>Architect (All-In) for $300</strong>: Everything from the Seraph level, Equipment and Armor cards, Seraph and Automata Metal Dice, and Legends Never Die Dossier Pack</li>
</ul><p>At the time of writing, the <em>Eldritch Automata</em> campaign has raised $55,609, more than five times its initial funding goal. The campaign concludes on July 25.</p>
</div>


<div><p><span><div>

<p>Ever since he was small, Tyler Chancey has had a deep, abiding love for video games and a tendency to think and overanalyze everything he enjoyed. This… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/tyler-chancey">More about Tyler</a></p>
</div></span></p></div>
</div>



<div>
<ul>
<p>Additional topics:</p>
<p>
<li><a href="https://techraptor.net/topic/crowdfunding" hreflang="en">Crowdfunding</a></li>
</p>
<p>
<li><a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/rpg-0" hreflang="en">RPG</a></li>
</p>
</ul>
</div>

</div>
</article>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Here's what Xbox's ill-fated cloud gaming console might have looked like, according to newly surfaced patent]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/heres-what-xboxs-ill-fated-cloud-gaming-console-might-have-looked-like-according-to-newly-surfaced-patent</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/heres-what-xboxs-ill-fated-cloud-gaming-console-might-have-looked-like-according-to-newly-surfaced-patent.912405/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/heres-what-xboxs-ill-fated-cloud-gaming-console-might-have-looked-like-according-to-newly-surfaced-patent<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/xbox-keystone-patent-1.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Microsoft/USPTO</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
Remember Microsoft's Xbox cloud gaming device, codenamed Keystone? The one that got announced in 2021, was cancelled in its original form a year later, then showed up on Phil Spencer's shelf after that, bamboozling everyone? Well if you've ever wondered what it could have looked like in more detail, a newly surfaced patent might have some answers.
</p>
<p>
The <a href="https://ppubs.uspto.gov/dirsearch-public/print/downloadPdf/D1009161">patent in question</a> was originally filed with the US Patent and Trademark Office in June 2022 - several months after Microsoft announced it would no longer be proceeding with Keystone in its existing form - and features designs for a proposed machine only referred to as an "electronic console device". There's nothing explicitly linking to the document to Keystone, but <a href="https://www.windowscentral.com/gaming/xbox/the-xbox-that-never-was-our-first-detailed-look-at-the-keystone-cloud-streaming-console-design">Windows Central</a> claims that's precisely what it is.
</p>
<p>
A side-by-side comparison with the "old prototype" version of Keystone that <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/fans-think-phil-spencers-shelf-is-teasing-the-xbox-game-pass-streaming-box">appeared on Phil Spencer's desk in October 2022</a> also supports that claim, with both the patent and prototype version featuring the same front panel.
</p>
<figure><div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div><figcaption>Newscast: For Xbox, could this be the year it all pays off?<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mPVhT_7O0iE" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
The patent, however, reveals a lot more of the design Microsoft was at one point apparently considering for its cloud streaming games console. It bears much in common with the current Xbox Series S, albeit with that machine's horizontal footprint compacted into square. It's also pictured with an Xbox Series X-style "Hello from Seattle" plate on its bottom.
</p>
<p>
As for the ports on this proposed form - attributed to principal Microsoft designer Chris Kujawski - there's an Xbox button and USB port on the front, a controller pairing button one one side, plus HDMI, ethernet, and power connectors to the rear. And aside from a whole bunch of heat-dissipating holes, that's your lot - no details of the machine's innards are revealed in the patent.
</p>
<p>
When Microsoft <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/microsoft-decides-to-pivot-away-from-xbox-game-pass-streaming-box-for-now">addressed the progress of Keystone</a> back in May 2022, it said it had "made the decision to pivot away from the current iteration" of the device, and would refocus its efforts on a "new approach". Xbox boss Phil Spencer <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/11/15/23460485/microsoft-xbox-streaming-console-keystone-delay-price">later confirmed</a> the project had been canned because it was "more expensive than we wanted it to be when we actually built it out with the hardware that we had inside" - and that Microsoft's "new approach" was its Xbox TV app, enabling users to stream Xbox Cloud Gaming titles at 1080p and up to 60fps.
</p>
<p>
So while Xbox's square-shaped dreams of a dedicated cloud gaming console are perhaps long dead, its ambitions in the game streaming space are far from over.
</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Steam’s new native gameplay recording tool also works on the Steam Deck]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2024/6/26/24186716/valve-steam-native-game-recording-tool-deck</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/steam%E2%80%99s-new-native-gameplay-recording-tool-also-works-on-the-steam-deck.912402/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/2024/6/26/24186716/valve-steam-native-game-recording-tool-deck<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><article id="content"><div><div><h2>Steam’s new native gameplay recording tool also works on the Steam Deck</h2><p><span><span> / </span><h2>You can try the new feature in beta now.</h2></span></p></div><div><p><span>By</span> <span><span></span> <span><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/jay-peters">Jay Peters</a></span><span>, <span>a news editor who writes about technology, video games, and virtual worlds. He’s submitted several accepted emoji proposals to the Unicode Consortium.</span></span></span></p><p><time datetime="2024-06-26T19:16:34.921Z"> <!-- -->Jun 26, 2024, 7:16 PM UTC</time></p><div><h2>Share this story</h2></div><p>If you buy something from a Verge link, Vox Media may earn a commission.<!-- --> <a href="https://www.theverge.com/ethics-statement">See our ethics statement.</a></p></div></div><div><div><p>Valve is adding a native gameplay recording tool to Steam so that you can more easily capture and share clips. The game recording feature is available now in beta — including on Steam Deck.</p><p>You’ll be able to both continuously record clips with background recording or manually turn on recording with a hotkey, according <a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=1025X1701640&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fstore.steampowered.com%2Fsale%2Fgamerecording">to Valve’s website about the updates</a>. When you’re recording, you’ll see the “Steam Timeline,” and you can add markers to note interesting moments you might want to come back to later. Developers can also have their games mark notable moments on the timeline, which Valve has already implemented with <em>Dota 2</em> and <em>Counter-Strike 2</em>.</p><p>The tool won’t record your desktop, and you can pick which audio channels are included in the recording. To share your clips, Valve will offer a number of options: exporting a clip to MP4; sending the clip to the Steam mobile app; or even creating a temporary link. </p><p>As for how the tool might affect your computer’s performance, here’s what Valve has to say:</p><div><blockquote><p>Steam Game Recording has been designed with the goal of taking as little computer resources away from the game you are playing as possible. It takes advantage of NVIDIA and AMD graphics cards to remove most of the performance cost of creating video recordings. When run on systems without those graphics cards, the system’s CPU is used to create video recordings which may cause a noticeable performance impact on those systems.</p></blockquote></div><p>Valve promises that more features are in the works for game recording, too, such as individualized game settings.</p><div><p>Earlier this year, Valve launched another big upgrade to Steam: <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/3/18/24105220/steam-families-shared-library-parental-controls">an overhauled family sharing system</a>. </p></div></div><div><p>Most Popular</p><p>Most Popular</p><ol><li><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/6/23/24183875/dr-disrespect-twitch-ban-explanation"><h2>Twitch banned Dr Disrespect after viewing messages sent to a minor, say former employees</h2></a><hr></li><li><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/6/25/24185767/google-pixel-hardware-ai-event-august-date"><h2>Google announces surprise Pixel 9 hardware event in August</h2></a><hr></li><li><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/6/25/24185821/dr-disrespect-twitch-ban-explanation-inappropriate-messages"><h2>Dr Disrespect finally shares why he was banned from Twitch</h2></a><hr></li><li><a href="https://www.theverge.com/24184777/boox-palma-e-ink-smartphone-reader"><h2>The Boox Palma is an amazing gadget I didn’t even know I wanted</h2></a><hr></li><li><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/6/24/24185107/aeb-nhtsa-reconsider-auto-industry"><h2>Auto industry pleads with Biden administration to ‘reconsider’ automatic braking rule</h2></a><hr></li></ol></div></div></article></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Wyrmspan Review - Takes Wingspan To New Heights]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/wyrmspan-review-takes-wingspan-to-new-heights</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/wyrmspan-review-takes-wingspan-to-new-heights.912399/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/wyrmspan-review-takes-wingspan-to-new-heights<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>You hear the bellowing roar of a creature in the distance, above you the looming shadow of a huge pair of wings blots out the sun as a sudden gust of wind announces the presence of, you guessed it, a dragon! Do you have the resources to entice these majestic creatures to live in the habitats you’ve created for them? Find out in our review of <a href="https://stonemaiergames.com/games/wyrmspan/"><em>Wyrmspan</em></a>, based on the <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/wingspan-review-pleasant-from-beak-to-tailfeather">monumentally popular <em>Wingspan</em></a> - both by <a href="https://stonemaiergames.com/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Stonemaeir games</a>!</p>
<h2><em>Wyrmspan -&nbsp;</em>The Basics</h2>
<p><em>Wyrmspan&nbsp;</em>is a tabletop board game for 1 - 5 players, where you take on the role of an amateur dracologist in a realm where dragons of all different shapes, sizes, and personalities rule the skies. In this strategy board game, you'll manage resources and plan your actions carefully to lure dragons to your personal board, scoring points in a variety of ways. In the end, the player with the most victory points wins!</p>
<p>The game contains 183 dragon cards, each vastly different from one-another (and none of these cards are direct copies of&nbsp;<em>Wingspan</em>&nbsp;cards, which I'll speak more about momentarily). In the game, your goal is to lure these dragons to roost on your land by excavating cave spaces on your board (of which there are 75 cave cards), using resources to pay for dragons, and moving your little meeple dracologist around the board to trigger special actions.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/wyrmspan-review-full-table_0.jpg?itok=9hBHL4vO 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/wyrmspan-review-full-table_0.jpg?itok=kZihf_EM 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Though there are many elements to the game, two players can cram everything onto a mid-sized coffee table!</figcaption></figure><p>Our first game took us a little under two hours to play (with two players), and we're&nbsp;<em>very</em> familiar with&nbsp;<em>Wingspan.&nbsp;</em>But subsequent plays got us right down to the 90 minute game time as advertised on the box.</p>
<h2>How is&nbsp;<em>Wyrmspan&nbsp;</em>Different From&nbsp;<em>Wingspan</em>?</h2>
<p>In many ways,&nbsp;<em>Wyrmspan&nbsp;</em>follows a similar game flow and much of the same core rules with&nbsp;<em>Wingspan</em>, but these are two completely different, stand-alone games. The base game of&nbsp;<em>Wyrmspan</em>&nbsp;is slightly more complicated and strategic compared to the core base game of&nbsp;<em>Wingspan</em>&nbsp;(though it feels close in levels of complexity when you add in expansions like&nbsp;<em>Oceania</em>). Here are some of the ways that <i>Wyrmspan&nbsp;</i>is different from&nbsp;<em>Wingspan</em>:</p>
<h3><em>Wyrmspan </em>introduces the concept of the Dragon Guild&nbsp;</h3>
<p>In&nbsp;<em>Wyrmspan,&nbsp;</em>there's a new board set to the side of the game called the Dragon Guild board. There are four different guild cards you can place on this board, and it essentially creates a circular track that players can move around to gain additional resources, benefits, and points.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/wyrmspan-review-dragon-guild-board.jpg?itok=vC1CT7Hs 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/wyrmspan-review-dragon-guild-board.jpg?itok=awFAbFHl 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>It's a mad dash around the Dragon Guild Board!</figcaption></figure><h3>You have to excavate your spaces in&nbsp;<em>Wyrmspan</em>&nbsp;</h3>
<p>In&nbsp;<em>Wingspan</em>, when you want to play a bird in a space you simply have to pay the cost (and additional egg costs) and place them. With&nbsp;<em>Wyrmspan</em>, you first have to excavate that space on your board (you start with three pre-excavated spaces).</p>
<p>You do this by drawing and playing a Cave card. And while this is an added step in the process, these Cave cards are some of the most fun aspects of the game, as they bestow immediate "When Played" benefits, some of which are incredibly powerful.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/wyrmspan-review-dragon-and-cave-card-board.jpg?itok=lbJLXC-7 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/wyrmspan-review-dragon-and-cave-card-board.jpg?itok=XPPa-r2a 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Dragon and Cave cards now coexist on their own board, each with their own unique powers!</figcaption></figure><h3>Actions can carry over in&nbsp;<em>Wyrmspan</em></h3>
<p>In&nbsp;<em>Wingspan</em>, actions you played were tracked with action cubes, and your turn ended when you used up all your cubes. In&nbsp;<em>Wyrmspan</em>, actions are tracked by spending coins (you start with six), and some special effects give you extra actions&nbsp;<em>plus</em>&nbsp;you can always end your turns in a round before using all your coins -- meaning you can carry them over for a very impactful next round!</p>
<p>These are the three largest differences between&nbsp;<em>Wingspan&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>Wyrmspan</em>, but the <a href="https://stonemaiergames.com/games/wyrmspan/rules-faq/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Stonemaier&nbsp;<em>Wyrmspan</em> FAQ</a> has a really nice rundown of all the differences - big and little - if you're curious.</p>
<h2>But do all of these rules changes over-complicate <em>Wyrmspan</em>?</h2>
<p>In my opinion, absolutely not! What you get from these added elements isn't an over-wrought game design, but instead a lot more player agency and choice. There are also more moments for surprise in this game, as you never know what powerful Cave cards you'll flip into the display.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/wyrmspan-review-card-closeup.jpg?itok=wcpAJMqm 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/wyrmspan-review-card-closeup.jpg?itok=LzE3WefP 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Hatchlings need milk (??) to grow, but will eventually give you a powerful reward!</figcaption></figure><p>Being able to gain more actions and hold actions from one round to the next left me feeling very empowered in our games. I was able to play the game at a cadence that worked for me, and suited my play style well, as I like to hold my actions in the early game and go for a big mega-round in the second half.</p>
<p>The race around the Dragon Guild board also provided way more of a sense of tension than I was expecting in my play-throughs.</p>
<p>What I thought would just be an add-on that we didn't pay much attention to turned out to be one of the main focuses of our gameplay, and a source of friendly competition.</p>
<h2>Wyrmspan Review - Final Thoughts</h2>
<p>When it was first announced that Stonemaeir Games would be releasing <em>Wyrmspan</em>, a new interpolation of their blockbuster birding hit <em>Wingspan</em>, I have to admit - I was left scratching my head.</p>
<p>What made <em>Wingspan</em> such a masterpiece, in my opinion, was the wonderfully “normal” theme of the game: birding. Along with Audubon Society-style illustrations, the game eschewed wizards, aliens, and, well… dragons for a topic much more down to earth.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/wyrmspan-review-final-game-board.jpg?itok=Ua7OrZoA 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/wyrmspan-review-final-game-board.jpg?itok=o_SAmy7j 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>A finished board at the end of the game, look at all these gorgeous dragons!</figcaption></figure><p>But the core engine of the&nbsp;<em>Wingspan&nbsp;</em>is so strong, and so damned fun, that I knew I immediately wanted to see how&nbsp;<em>Wyrmspan</em>&nbsp;ideated on the original. And besides, it's not like I&nbsp;<em>don't love</em>&nbsp;dragons! As soon as I started reading the rulebook for&nbsp;<em>Wyrmspan</em>, and began to get a sense of the changes it brought to the game engine, I knew I'd be hooked.</p>
<p><em>Wyrmspan</em>&nbsp;is a game that takes something incredible and perfects upon it further, pushing the design right up to the limits to create a bold, inviting, and strategically rewarding experience. I think&nbsp;<em>Wyrmspan&nbsp;</em>may be one of the most engrossing gaming experiences I've had this year, and fans of the original&nbsp;<em>Wingspan</em> absolutely need to check this game out as soon as possible.</p>
<p>Even if the birding aspect is what initially drew you into&nbsp;<em>Wingspan</em>, rest assured that this game - full of its own swath of gorgeous illustrations - will completely sink its talons into you and your gaming group!</p>
<hr><p><em>The copy of&nbsp;</em>Wyrmspan&nbsp;<em>used in the creation of this review was provided to us by Stonemaier Games. All photos courtesy of the author.</em></p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
<div>
<h2>Review Summary</h2>

<p>
Wyrmspan is a triumph of game design, taking a near-perfect blueprint from Wingspan and enhancing it. (<a href="https://techraptor.net/review-score-policy">Review Policy</a>)
</p>
</div>
<div>
<div>
<h3>Pros</h3>
<div><ul><li>New game elements bring more player agency</li><li>Saving actions and playing cave cards add excitement to the game</li><li>High production quality continues in the classic Stonemaier Games tradition</li></ul></div>
</div>
<div>
<h3>Cons</h3>
<div><ul><li>Gamers coming in without at least some previous Wingspan experience may find the game a bit complicated</li><li>As with Wingspan, limited player vs. player interaction may bristle some competitive gamers.</li></ul></div>
</div>
</div>
</div></span></p></div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Giaco Furino joined the TechRaptor team as a Staff Writer in 2019 after searching for a dedicated place to write and talk about Tabletop Games. In 2020, he… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/giaco-furino">More about Giaco</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I accidentally killed my favorite NPC in Elden Ring and I’ve lost my will to live]]></title>
            <link>https://www.polygon.com/24186714/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-moore-npc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/i-accidentally-killed-my-favorite-npc-in-elden-ring-and-i%E2%80%99ve-lost-my-will-to-live.912396/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.polygon.com/24186714/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-moore-npc<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  <p id="mvUlqZ">I accidentally killed my favorite NPC in <em>Elden Ring</em>, and my life as I know it is over. Here’s how you can avoid making the same mistake.</p>
<p id="6NOTG8">[<strong>Ed. note:</strong> This article contains spoilers for Moore’s storyline in <em>Elden Ring: Shadow of the Erdtree</em>.]</p>
<p id="C1Ms3C">Early in <em>Shadow of the Erdtree</em>, if you ride toward the legacy dungeon of Belurat, you encounter two NPCs at the Main Gate Cross. One is Ansbach, a retired old warrior. And the other is Moore, a rotund and soft-spoken merchant knight, who will sell you useful consumables, as well as a note about unlocking sealed spiritsprings.</p>
<h3 id="qyolYH"><strong>Who is Moore in Shadow of the Erdtree?</strong></h3>
<p id="d14eKm">Moore is adorable, crouching over his little pot, and he tells you in a halting way that he likes finding things for the rest of Miquella’s followers. I immediately fell in utter love with him. We have so much in common: I also love things, and finding things. And he’s so cute and round. Wow, a beacon of light and hope in the darkness of the shadow realm!</p>
<p id="FXcGH9">You can ask Ansbach what Moore’s deal is, and he’ll warn you that Moore has been working with the forager brood, and not to harm the brood if you come across them.</p>
<p id="W6r7jB">What this dialogue doesn’t spell out for you, which I will, is that the forager brood are the Kindred of Rot, centipede-like creatures that you might recognize from the base <em>Elden Ring</em> game as <em>really obnoxious enemies that shoot strings at you.</em></p>
<p id="9PghqE">You see where this is going.</p>
<h3 id="z4PDf6"><strong>Why does Moore fight you?</strong></h3>
<p id="U4iRUr">It was late at night. I was tired, on autopilot, and I saw a Kindred of Rot just lying on the ground outside the Church of the Crusade, and I thought, <em>What the hey!</em> and gave him a whack with my sword. The poor guy died, and immediately I was invaded by Moore. He told me to stop hurting forager brood. Before I knew it, we were dueling to the death.</p>
<p id="mjV3xu">Moore is a beefy but honestly pretty tame enemy. He throws big pots that inflict scarlet rot, but they’re easy to dodge. He also crouches behind his shield and rushes you. He’s got a lot of health but, well, I do a lot of damage. I traveled back to the Main Gate Cross after killing him, hoping that it was all just a bad dream, and found his bell bearing in the place he used to sit.</p>
<p id="YVe5mA">I’m devastated!</p>
  <figure>
  <span>
    
    <span data-original="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507551/Moore_2.png">
      
        <picture data-cid="site/picture_element-1719429851_5292_114885" data-cdata="{&quot;asset_id&quot;:25507551,&quot;ratio&quot;:&quot;*&quot;}">
  


  <source srcset="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Ji-y0LfP5Xd8I-BZEaMtiI5IiyM=/0x0:1920x1080/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:1920x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507551/Moore_2.png 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Hlgpd8O3kAuHwSLpjpwcUWcD5r0=/0x0:1920x1080/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:1920x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507551/Moore_2.png 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/w8LeisU13lf_k6rAMym8_GrGjIw=/0x0:1920x1080/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:1920x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507551/Moore_2.png 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/XGY5Qpo11xIcCI4UN-oiUvG8dZM=/0x0:1920x1080/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:1920x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507551/Moore_2.png 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/lnMiMfrofDU9oCyQlFauT3TIq_M=/0x0:1920x1080/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:1920x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507551/Moore_2.png 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zBHFyssrcx7M8f0NvKNZvf7Kous=/0x0:1920x1080/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:1920x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507551/Moore_2.png 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/KXhFS09882xJtB9BYDC4RVNw4qw=/0x0:1920x1080/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:1920x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507551/Moore_2.png 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8gMFLMvfIiEUphqeJdTpCDWCTYY=/0x0:1920x1080/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:1920x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507551/Moore_2.png 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-wA91wgIdzg5raP4MtZxUxdGaxI=/0x0:1920x1080/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:1920x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507551/Moore_2.png 1920w" sizes="(min-width: 1221px) 846px, (min-width: 880px) calc(100vw - 334px), 100vw" type="image/webp">




</picture>

      
    </span>
    
  </span>
  
    <span>
      
        <figcaption>Moore’s shield didn’t prevent me from murdering him.</figcaption>
      
      
        <cite>Image: FromSoftware/Bandai Namco via Polygon</cite>
      
    </span>
  
</figure>


<p id="aW7lor">Based on a quick poll of my colleagues who are also playing the DLC, we’re not sure if killing this specific Kindred is the only trigger for turning Moore hostile. I heard from some colleagues that they had killed the Kindred and not been invaded — so it’s possible that triggering Moore’s invasion is more complex than smashing one bug. Only time will tell.</p>
<h3 id="F9GRvY"><strong>Why you shouldn’t kill the Kindred of Rot</strong></h3>
<p id="19UXVH">But there’s no point in killing the Kindred of Rot anyway! If you see one in the <em>Shadow of the Erdtree</em> DLC, know that they’re apparently friendly and you can talk to them and they’ll give you foraged items. In fact, healing the Kindred at the Church of the Crusade will give you a Forager Brood cookbook that isn’t available anywhere else in the game.</p>
<p id="GMDaGv">More importantly, you won’t have to kill sweet, round baby boy Moore, and get his really good verdigris armor. (But at what cost?!?!?!)</p>
<h3 id="siWY5l"><strong>What if I’m a sicko and want to kill Moore?</strong></h3>
<p id="AHUGCC">If you are indeed a sick bastard and want Moore dead for whatever reason, make sure you do it after meeting Thiollier at the Pillar Path Cross Grace. Speaking to Moore after meeting Thiollier will give you the option to get Black Syrup from Moore. Giving this to Thiollier will unlock Thiollier’s Concoction, a critical and powerful poison that you can use later in the game.</p>
<p id="8MfiqS">After this, I guess you’re free to kill Moore if you want. But please, let my baby boy live!</p>
  
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cinematic horror virtual reality rescue mission game Deep Cuts announced for PS VR2, SteamVR, and Quest]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/06/cinematic-horror-virtual-reality-rescue-mission-game-deep-cuts-announced-for-ps-vr2-steamvr-and-quest</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cinematic-horror-virtual-reality-rescue-mission-game-deep-cuts-announced-for-ps-vr2-steamvr-and-quest.912393/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/06/cinematic-horror-virtual-reality-rescue-mission-game-deep-cuts-announced-for-ps-vr2-steamvr-and-quest<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps-vr2">PS VR2</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/meta/quest">Quest</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Quest version due out this fall.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > tinyBuild [120 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/tinybuild">tinyBuild</a> and <em><a title="Games > Happy's Humble Burger Farm [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/happys-humble-burger-farm">Happy’s Humble Burger Farm</a></em> developer <a title="Companies > Scythe Dev Team [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/scythe-dev-team">Scythe Dev Team</a> has announced <em><a title="Games > Deep Cuts" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/deep-cuts">Deep Cuts</a></em>, a cinematic <a title="Genres > Horror [433 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/horror">horror</a> <a title="Genres > Virtual Reality [144 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/virtual-reality">virtual reality</a> rescue mission coming to <a title="Platforms > Quest [105 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/meta/quest">Quest</a> this fall, followed by <a title="Platforms > PS VR2 [187 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps-vr2">PlayStation VR2</a> and SteamVR in 2025. <span id="more-894927"></span></p><p>“With <em>Deep Cuts</em>, we’ve harnessed every inch of the <a title="Platforms > Meta [105 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/meta">Meta</a> Quest hardware to create an unmatched experience, pushing the boundaries of what’s possible in the physical virtual reality medium,” said Scythe Dev Team director, founder, and principal technical engineer Kaleb Alfadda in a press release. “Our team meticulously optimized every aspect to ensure fluid performance and rich, detailed environments that truly bring the game to life. We’re excited to offer players an experience that fully exploits the potential of the hardware, setting a new bar for standalone virtual reality.”</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via tinyBuild:</p><blockquote><p><em>Deep Cuts</em> is a cinematic horror virtual reality rescue mission.</p><p>Following the success of <em>Happy’s Humble’s Burger Farm</em>, Scythe and tinyBuild return with yet another exhilarating horror experience, this time blending it with classic cinema in an all-new way only achievable in virtual reality. Plunge into a messy physics-based action gameplay with highly interactive worlds, a hair-raising atmosphere, and a rich narrative.</p><p>Lights, camera, action! Filmmaker Elise Weber and best friend/creative partner Malcolm Micheaux enjoyed an illustrious career until their villainous cartoon creations went mad. As Elise, explore the Lights Camera Faction studio premises in hopes of saving Malcolm. Enter a series of blockbuster worlds based on the duo’s extensive film catalog alongside Bowie, the only sane cartoon character left.</p></blockquote><!-- AD: content -->
        <div id="carousel_894935"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div><blockquote><p>Take Elise right into the heart of a movie set. Survive the ’80s horror-inspired “Forsaken Festival,” fend off creatures in the ’70s space thriller “Origin Drill,” or take a stroll through the Wild West in “Bastard Town.”</p><p>Each blockbuster world contains numerous interactable objects—grab a boom mic for an improvised weapon, fire off a prop machine gun, and discover hidden lore secrets. Solve intricate puzzles with the help of time manipulation abilities, and embrace the power of an ultimate Film Director!</p></blockquote><p>Watch the announcement trailer below. View the first screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/deep-cuts/june-26-2024/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Deep Cuts - Reveal Trailer 🎬" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/iYpJ1ryq26A?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Steam Introduces New Game Recording Feature, And It Works With Steam Deck]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/steam-introduces-new-game-recording-feature-and-it-works-with-steam-deck/1100-6524538/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/steam-introduces-new-game-recording-feature-and-it-works-with-steam-deck.912390/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/steam-introduces-new-game-recording-feature-and-it-works-with-steam-deck/1100-6524538/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6524538">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">Steam has just introduced a new feature for players called Game Recording. Though still in the beta-testing phase, Game Recording is exactly what it sounds like: a built-in feature that allows users to record and share gameplay footage.</p><p dir="ltr">Players can use Game Recording to record a quick clip of a particularly impressive 360° no-scope kill in a live-service game, record an entire RPG campaign playthrough, and everything in between. Clips can then be edited as needed (for instance, cutting out all the shots you missed prior to an impressive headshot) and then uploaded for the world to see.</p><p dir="ltr">Game Recording has two modes: Background Recording and On Demand Recording. In Background Recording mode, gameplay is continuously saved to the player's preferred drive (never exceeding the player's specified recording duration or storage limits). On Demand Recording mode can be used at-will, stopping and starting via manual input from the player. Steam's new Game Recording tool also allows players to use the Steam Timeline and Event Markers included in the mode to locate and mark high-intensity moments in the recording.</p><p dir="ltr">There's also a Replay option, which can be used to get a better idea of how your character inexplicably died during a fight, or replay NPC dialogue you may have missed the first time around.</p><p dir="ltr">"In addition to being able to record any game you’re playing, timeline-enhanced games are games that can proactively notify Steam when relevant events happen," reads <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/sale/gamerecording" rel="nofollow">Steam's official Game Recording</a> webpage. "These events are represented along the timeline with details specified by developers."</p><p dir="ltr">Game Recording works with any and all games on Steam, and is also compatible with Steam Deck, allowing players to record and share clips from their Steam Deck to their PC or phone. Additionally, Game Recordings can be exported in .MP4 format for editing outside of Steam.</p><p dir="ltr">The new tool also has privacy settings, which allow players to select options that will prevent Game Recording from capturing footage of their desktop and other parts of the screen that aren't part of a game. According to steam, more features are coming to Game Recording, including "individualized game settings" which are reportedly "coming soon."</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Steam's average controller use triples to 15 percent, with majority usage from Xbox controllers]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/steam-s-average-controller-use-triples-to-15-percent-with-majority-usage-from-xbox-controllers</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/steams-average-controller-use-triples-to-15-percent-with-majority-usage-from-xbox-controllers.912387/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/steam-s-average-controller-use-triples-to-15-percent-with-majority-usage-from-xbox-controllers<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Valve introduced controller support to Steam in 2018, and the developer says controller usage has shot up to </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://steamcommunity.com/games/593110/announcements/detail/4142827237888316812">15 percent,</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> three times the amount six years ago.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Back in </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/game-platforms/controller-use-on-steam-has-more-than-doubled-since-2018">2020</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, Valve released a similar factoid, saying at the time usage had doubled. Of this new metric, it's said that 59 percent stems from Xbox gamepads, with PlayStation trailing behind at 26 percent. 10 percent of players use their Steam Deck.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"More players than ever are choosing to play Steam games with a controller," Valve noted. It added that its Steam Input service (which functions as an emulator for game controllers) was used for 42 percent of controller sessions.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Last year, Valve let developers post which </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/steam-will-let-devs-put-playstation-controller-support-on-store-pages">PlayStation controllers</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> their games support (between DualShock and DualSense). The feature reflected PlayStation's growing PC presence, which had grown to 27 percent from 2018's 11 percent.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Both PlayStation and Xbox have been adding their exclusives to Steam, often with a recommendation that a controller be used in place of mouse and keyboard. Some types of games (like </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Helldivers 2 </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">or </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Starfield</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">) may necessitate a controller.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">In the years since controller support was implemented, Valve's added new features and expanded the range of support for controllers from the two consoles. It cites that as the reason for increased support, and said it'll keep working on that and Steam Input for the future.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author(s)</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Contributing Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">A Kansas City, MO native, Justin Carter has written for numerous sites including IGN, Polygon, and SyFy Wire. In addition to Game Developer, his writing can be found at io9 over on Gizmodo. Don't ask him about how much gum he's had, because the answer will be more than he's willing to admit.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Steam is getting an official controller, but Valve isn’t making it]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2024/6/26/24186645/valve-steam-controller-officially-licensed-wireless-horipad-announcement-specs</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/steam-is-getting-an-official-controller-but-valve-isn%E2%80%99t-making-it.912351/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/2024/6/26/24186645/valve-steam-controller-officially-licensed-wireless-horipad-announcement-specs<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Nearly five years after Valve discontinued its experimental <a href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2019/11/26/20984123/valve-steam-controller-discontinued-sale-price">Steam Controller</a>, a new officially licensed gamepad for Steam is on the way. The new controller is made by Hori, and it’s only coming to Japan (at least for now).</p><p>Dubbed the <a href="https://horistore.com/shop/g/gHPC-055/">Wireless Horipad for Steam</a>, the PC-centric controller matches the Steam Deck’s menu buttons and has similar touch sensors atop its sticks to activate gyro controls. It also supports Bluetooth wireless and USB-C wired connections as well as a whole bunch of custom programmability using Hori’s software. But while it shares a lot with the Steam Deck, it’s not a <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23499215/valve-steam-deck-interview-late-2022#:~:text=Valve%20wants%20a%20Steam%20Controller%202">Steam Controller 2</a> — it lacks rumble, a matching set of four back buttons, and the handheld’s signature trackpads.</p><p>The new controller is set to launch in Japan on October 31st in four colors (black, white, neon yellow, and violet), selling for 7,890 yen (about $50).</p><p>There’s no word yet if this new Steam controller is coming to the US or elsewhere, but the Wireless Horipad bears a striking resemblance to the <a href="https://stores.horiusa.com/horipad-pro-designed-for-xbox-series-x-s-xbox-one/">wired Horipad Pro</a> that’s currently available for Xbox consoles. I tested the Horipad Pro for our <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23025443/best-xbox-controllers-one-series-x-s">Xbox controller buying guide</a> and found it to be <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23025443/best-xbox-controllers-one-series-x-s#:~:text=mentioned%20above%2C%20the-,Horipad%20Pro,-has%20one%20of">serviceable with fine ergonomics and a great D-pad</a> — though it was somewhat outclassed by other options that run cheaper. </p><p>However, the Wireless Horipad seems to have a whole lot more going on. For starters, it’s actually wireless, albeit limited to Bluetooth, which is usually less reliable than a USB wireless dongle. The Steam version also has four programmable buttons, although, unlike the Steam Deck, there are only two on the rear — the other two are on the front directly below the D-pad and on the right thumbstick.</p><div><p>It certainly looks familiar if you squint</p></div><p>While it seems long overdue for Valve to once again have a branded go-to gamepad for Steam and docked Steam Deck use, we’ll have to wait to see if or when it becomes more widely available. Hori’s decision to start sales in its home country makes sense, but it may also speak to the rise of PC gaming in Japan, with handhelds being such a popular choice there that Valve spun up a partnership with an entirely different company for <a href="https://steamdeck.komodo.jp/">Steam Deck distribution</a> (including <a href="https://boilingsteam.com/steam-deck-launches-in-stores-in-japan-full-coverage/index.html">in-store availability</a>). </p><p>In general, gamepad usage in Steam is on the rise — as Valve’s <a href="https://steamcommunity.com/games/593110/announcements/detail/4142827237888316812">just-released statistics</a> show. Those numbers also come with a summary of <a href="https://steamcommunity.com/games/593110/announcements/detail/4142827237888316812#:~:text=Here%20are%20some%20of%20the%20new%20features%20we%E2%80%99ve%20shipped%20for%20Steam%20Input%20and%20controller%20users%20recently%3A">new controller optimizations</a> Valve has recently implemented in Steam. Perhaps this is setting the table for a wide swath of licensed Steam controllers from a variety of manufacturers like we see on Xbox consoles — with more wireless options, I hope. One thing I know is I’m now dying to try this Wireless Horipad.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Congrats to Overwatch’s Zenyatta for getting name-dropped in an Oscar-nominated screenplay]]></title>
            <link>https://www.polygon.com/24186512/past-lives-overwatch-zenyatta-screenplay</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/congrats-to-overwatch%E2%80%99s-zenyatta-for-getting-name-dropped-in-an-oscar-nominated-screenplay.912348/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.polygon.com/24186512/past-lives-overwatch-zenyatta-screenplay<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  <p id="lz4i87"><a href="https://www.polygon.com/23767663/the-sims-4-past-lives-celine-song-the-seagull-interview"><em>Past Lives</em></a> was one of my <a href="https://www.polygon.com/what-to-watch/23597815/best-movies-2023">favorite movies of 2023</a>. It’s a heartfelt, funny romantic drama; a nuanced depiction of grown-up love; and a remarkable first feature from writer-director Celine Song, a playwright and dedicated gamer. Before <em>Past Lives, </em>Song previously staged a production of <a href="https://www.polygon.com/2020/10/29/21540644/sims-4-chekhov-the-seagull-new-york-theatre-workshop">Anton Chekhov’s classic play <em>The Seagull</em> within a Sims game</a> and <a href="https://www.lecinemaclub.com/journal/qa-with-celine-song/">regularly plays <em>Valorant, Overwatch</em>,<em> </em>and <em>Fortnite</em></a>.</p>
<p id="qyiSQR">Turns out <em>The Sims</em> isn’t the only video game franchise present in Song’s work: <em>Overwatch </em>makes a brief appearance in <em>Past Lives. </em>The level of detail in the script caught me by surprise. After meeting up with her childhood sweetheart Hae Sung (Teo Yoo) for the first time in years, Nora (Greta Lee) returns home to find her husband Arthur (John Magaro) playing <em>Overwatch</em>. <em>Overwatch </em>isn’t terribly relevant to the scene – it’s just the activity he’s doing when she comes home, but <a href="https://deadline.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Past-Lives-Read-The-Screenplay.pdf">the Oscar-nominated script</a> is quite specific about who he’s playing and what happens in his game.</p>
  <figure>
  <span>
    
    <span data-original="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507087/Screenshot_2024_06_26_093458.png">
      
        <picture data-cid="site/picture_element-1719429481_4011_134017" data-cdata="{&quot;asset_id&quot;:25507087,&quot;ratio&quot;:&quot;*&quot;}">
  


  <source srcset="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/CyGN_Ote_eBn7RhDCQ5znHrg-hg=/0x0:691x575/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:691x575):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507087/Screenshot_2024_06_26_093458.png 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/70aw3ZCBkH2546bVknv7ja3Nr7Y=/0x0:691x575/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:691x575):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507087/Screenshot_2024_06_26_093458.png 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/iKOO-hA4iOUcZ77ZYHmh0vVxL0s=/0x0:691x575/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:691x575):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507087/Screenshot_2024_06_26_093458.png 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Ih39MKbsbY7_G0rHaUzPl_t95Vo=/0x0:691x575/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:691x575):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507087/Screenshot_2024_06_26_093458.png 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/IqF_UAR0duJ6bEU0HuG2Zr9N-D4=/0x0:691x575/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:691x575):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507087/Screenshot_2024_06_26_093458.png 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cXpQsbVC-tqP0XaunNmU712744g=/0x0:691x575/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:691x575):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507087/Screenshot_2024_06_26_093458.png 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2WXbi8bTrC-I1-XkWrmJ3-lA7ow=/0x0:691x575/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:691x575):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507087/Screenshot_2024_06_26_093458.png 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/luev310muIoNsaB-97YANarG69c=/0x0:691x575/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:691x575):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507087/Screenshot_2024_06_26_093458.png 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/b0oj2lUyBubm03gsFIQymwchOhI=/0x0:691x575/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:691x575):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507087/Screenshot_2024_06_26_093458.png 1920w" sizes="(min-width: 1221px) 846px, (min-width: 880px) calc(100vw - 334px), 100vw" type="image/webp">




</picture>

      
    </span>
    
  </span>
  
    <span>
      
      
        <cite>Image: A24</cite>
      
    </span>
  
</figure>


<p id="ENYhn5">The <em>Past Lives </em>script specifies Arthur plays <a href="https://www.polygon.com/2015/5/13/8601353/overwatch-gameplay-video-zenyatta">Zenyatta</a>, and even adds some information about who Zenyatta is and what he’s all about. It’s also a great character detail for Arthur, a sweet man who absolutely would play a support character in a team game, and is relatively understanding about the love of his life’s childhood sweetheart suddenly entering the picture. </p>
<p id="PAfuEN">A character’s choice of who they play in a game like <em>Overwatch </em>is an under-tapped mine of personality-building in fiction. There’s also a bit of comedy in here: “DEFEAT” showing up in all-caps immediately after Nora reveals Hae Sung did indeed come to New York to see her is great stuff. (And as a coworker joked: “This is why no one wants to play support. There’s always the concern that your wife is gonna leave you.”)</p>
<p id="4ccCKw">Song’s next project is the rom-com <em>Materialists</em>, starring Dakota Johnson, Chris Evans, and Pedro Pascal. Like <em>Past Lives </em>(and <a href="https://www.polygon.com/reviews/24127886/challengers-review-zendaya-luca-guadagnino"><em>Challengers</em></a>, written by her husband, Justin Kuritzkes), it reportedly focuses on a love triangle. But I know what I’m most focused on: which video game will get an unexpected mention. </p>
  
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Assassin’s Creed joins the Magic: The Gathering roster on July 5, here’s where to pre-order]]></title>
            <link>https://www.polygon.com/deals/24182707/assassins-creed-magic-the-gathering-pre-order-universes-beyond-expansion</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/assassin%E2%80%99s-creed-joins-the-magic-the-gathering-roster-on-july-5-here%E2%80%99s-where-to-pre-order.912345/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.polygon.com/deals/24182707/assassins-creed-magic-the-gathering-pre-order-universes-beyond-expansion<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  <p id="NGFY2l">Assassin’s Creed is the latest <a href="https://www.polygon.com/23925728/magic-the-gathering-marvel-crossover">Universes Beyond</a> expansion for <em>Magic: The Gathering</em>, and will be popping out of an unsuspecting haystack near you starting on July 5. The new set features a total of 100 mechanically unique cards inspired by the stealthy, stabby franchise. </p>
<p id="ZmArMx">While these new cards won’t include characters or settings from the recently announced <a href="https://www.polygon.com/24156633/ubisoft-assassins-creed-shadows-trailer-release-date-codename-red"><em>Assassin’s Creed Shadows</em></a>, you can expect appearances from virtually every other corner of the Assassin’s Creed universe, including Altair, Ezio, Eivor, and more. If you’d like to add any of these new cards to your existing collection, the new expansion is available to pre-order in a variety of formats from Amazon and GameStop, which we’ve linked out to below, along with a list of their contents.</p>

<hr id="glXOrp">

  <figure>
  <span>
    
    <span data-original="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507311/rqucvohq.jpg">
      
        <picture data-cid="site/picture_element-1719427275_4181_137688" data-cdata="{&quot;asset_id&quot;:25507311,&quot;ratio&quot;:&quot;*&quot;}">
  


  <source srcset="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/SYo7Pav5D4zhqmm4-ODqUYME8S4=/0x0:3466x1950/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:3466x1950):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507311/rqucvohq.jpg 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZcZf3s3UZNMluzwivtGfJDD5vrQ=/0x0:3466x1950/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:3466x1950):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507311/rqucvohq.jpg 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8RP3mXeMtiaf5V5ScKELcUDYtuk=/0x0:3466x1950/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:3466x1950):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507311/rqucvohq.jpg 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/vbXJuA1OrkXEkHfGo3V5ck-XHfE=/0x0:3466x1950/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:3466x1950):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507311/rqucvohq.jpg 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/I633p4bhDlXpwSXHxv4w7Vp37GY=/0x0:3466x1950/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:3466x1950):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507311/rqucvohq.jpg 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/GeKAz7QOMFM3eFFzVeJ7KXlMPwY=/0x0:3466x1950/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:3466x1950):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507311/rqucvohq.jpg 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/adcG_gL1ndHIFVhv4nmozNI9jog=/0x0:3466x1950/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:3466x1950):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507311/rqucvohq.jpg 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xSrcSEJnTHSThYWWTrheI0NeKr4=/0x0:3466x1950/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:3466x1950):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507311/rqucvohq.jpg 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/OTxTT5DrLBHml9KJkBk-2BKAXxk=/0x0:3466x1950/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:3466x1950):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507311/rqucvohq.jpg 1920w" sizes="(min-width: 1221px) 846px, (min-width: 880px) calc(100vw - 334px), 100vw" type="image/webp">




</picture>

      
    </span>
    
  </span>
  
    <span>
      
      
        <cite>Image: Wizards of the Coast</cite>
      
    </span>
  
</figure>


<p id="CqA7Gu">The Assassin’s Creed Universes Beyond Starter Kit is the fastest way to start playing with the new cards introduced in this set. Each box comes packaged with a pair of pre-constructed 60-card decks, which both feature a pair of Mythic Rare cards in addition to eight rares and a storage box for each deck, and a Learn-to-Play guide. Both decks are constructed exclusively with the new cards introduced with the new expansion. The Starter Kit is currently available to pre-order from <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CTKWRHNW?tag=polygon05-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank" has-subtag="true" data-cdata="{&quot;rewritten_url&quot;:&quot;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CTKWRHNW?ascsubtag=___pl__p_23946748__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder\u0026tag=polygon05-20&quot;,&quot;subtag_max_length&quot;:99,&quot;subtag_delim_length&quot;:3,&quot;subtag_key&quot;:&quot;ascsubtag&quot;,&quot;subtag_data&quot;:{&quot;ascsubtag&quot;:&quot;___pl__p_23946748__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder&quot;,&quot;tag&quot;:&quot;polygon05-20&quot;},&quot;encode_subtag&quot;:false}">Amazon</a> or <a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;mid=24348&amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Ftoys-games%2Ftrading-cards%2Fproducts%2Fmagic-the-gathering-assassins-creed-beyond-starter-kit%2F409267.html&amp;u1=PolygonAC062624" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank" has-subtag="true" data-cdata="{&quot;rewritten_url&quot;:&quot;https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?u1=[]pl[p]23946748[m]m-placeholder[s]s-placeholder[t]w[c]c-placeholder[r]r-placeholder[d]d-placeholder\u0026id=nOD/rLJHOac\u0026mid=24348\u0026murl=https://www.gamestop.com/toys-games/trading-cards/products/magic-the-gathering-assassins-creed-beyond-starter-kit/409267.html&quot;,&quot;subtag_max_length&quot;:72,&quot;subtag_delim_length&quot;:2,&quot;subtag_key&quot;:&quot;u1&quot;,&quot;subtag_data&quot;:{&quot;u1&quot;:&quot;[]pl[p]23946748[m]m-placeholder[s]s-placeholder[t]w[c]c-placeholder[r]r-placeholder[d]d-placeholder&quot;,&quot;id&quot;:&quot;nOD/rLJHOac&quot;,&quot;mid&quot;:&quot;24348&quot;,&quot;murl&quot;:&quot;https://www.gamestop.com/toys-games/trading-cards/products/magic-the-gathering-assassins-creed-beyond-starter-kit/409267.html&quot;},&quot;encode_subtag&quot;:false}">GameStop</a> for $19.</p>
<div id="hYLw7i">
    <ul>
    
      
        <li>
          <a data-analytics-link="product-card" data-analytics-viewport="product-card" data-vars-analytics-action="product-card" data-vars-analytics-link-title="Amazon         $19" has-subtag="true" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CTKWRHNW?tag=polygon05-20" data-cdata="{&quot;rewritten_url&quot;:&quot;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CTKWRHNW?ascsubtag=___pl__p_23946748__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder\u0026tag=polygon05-20&quot;,&quot;subtag_max_length&quot;:99,&quot;subtag_delim_length&quot;:3,&quot;subtag_key&quot;:&quot;ascsubtag&quot;,&quot;subtag_data&quot;:{&quot;ascsubtag&quot;:&quot;___pl__p_23946748__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder&quot;,&quot;tag&quot;:&quot;polygon05-20&quot;},&quot;encode_subtag&quot;:false}">
             
             <span>
               $19
             </span>
             
           <span>
              at Amazon
           </span>
          </a>
        </li>
      
    
      
        <li>
          <a data-analytics-link="product-card" data-analytics-viewport="product-card" data-vars-analytics-action="product-card" data-vars-analytics-link-title="GameStop         $20" has-subtag="true" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank" href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;mid=24348&amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Ftoys-games%2Ftrading-cards%2Fproducts%2Fmagic-the-gathering-assassins-creed-beyond-starter-kit%2F409267.html&amp;u1=PolygonAC062624" data-cdata="{&quot;rewritten_url&quot;:&quot;https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?u1=[]pl[p]23946748[m]m-placeholder[s]s-placeholder[t]w[c]c-placeholder[r]r-placeholder[d]d-placeholder\u0026id=nOD/rLJHOac\u0026mid=24348\u0026murl=https://www.gamestop.com/toys-games/trading-cards/products/magic-the-gathering-assassins-creed-beyond-starter-kit/409267.html&quot;,&quot;subtag_max_length&quot;:72,&quot;subtag_delim_length&quot;:2,&quot;subtag_key&quot;:&quot;u1&quot;,&quot;subtag_data&quot;:{&quot;u1&quot;:&quot;[]pl[p]23946748[m]m-placeholder[s]s-placeholder[t]w[c]c-placeholder[r]r-placeholder[d]d-placeholder&quot;,&quot;id&quot;:&quot;nOD/rLJHOac&quot;,&quot;mid&quot;:&quot;24348&quot;,&quot;murl&quot;:&quot;https://www.gamestop.com/toys-games/trading-cards/products/magic-the-gathering-assassins-creed-beyond-starter-kit/409267.html&quot;},&quot;encode_subtag&quot;:false}">
             
             <span>
               $20
             </span>
             
           <span>
              at GameStop
           </span>
          </a>
        </li>
      
    
    </ul>
  </div>
<h2 id="j5mqjk"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CTKWCNGZ?tag=polygon05-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank" has-subtag="true" data-cdata="{&quot;rewritten_url&quot;:&quot;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CTKWCNGZ?ascsubtag=___pl__p_23946748__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder\u0026tag=polygon05-20&quot;,&quot;subtag_max_length&quot;:99,&quot;subtag_delim_length&quot;:3,&quot;subtag_key&quot;:&quot;ascsubtag&quot;,&quot;subtag_data&quot;:{&quot;ascsubtag&quot;:&quot;___pl__p_23946748__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder&quot;,&quot;tag&quot;:&quot;polygon05-20&quot;},&quot;encode_subtag&quot;:false}"><strong>Assassin’s Creed Universes Beyond Booster Box</strong></a></h2>
  <figure>
  <span>
    
    <span data-original="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507308/91cig3zu.jpg">
      
        <picture data-cid="site/picture_element-1719427275_1986_137689" data-cdata="{&quot;asset_id&quot;:25507308,&quot;ratio&quot;:&quot;*&quot;}">
  


  <source srcset="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/LtvC1D-tTrFTvLTVZ_gbF4I91HA=/0x0:3362x1892/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:3362x1892):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507308/91cig3zu.jpg 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rTq1RSFr346pA-En-tfd8nsM0Sw=/0x0:3362x1892/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:3362x1892):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507308/91cig3zu.jpg 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/z6sQdB2ePwVEdDlr7iUmBfE9SCI=/0x0:3362x1892/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:3362x1892):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507308/91cig3zu.jpg 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/XOl-l9uCHy6ROg3qq1ekrwnvj6o=/0x0:3362x1892/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:3362x1892):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507308/91cig3zu.jpg 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/y0p_-Q1fwsxgLHlj0jvGYaIB2N4=/0x0:3362x1892/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:3362x1892):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507308/91cig3zu.jpg 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/D1Qs6Qjg_wiK51mkjD1laaQOz2c=/0x0:3362x1892/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:3362x1892):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507308/91cig3zu.jpg 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5OIgclBSvHwpzvooXEDEyDIeJ6U=/0x0:3362x1892/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:3362x1892):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507308/91cig3zu.jpg 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/joDrzpR1VeG-e7wlPZn8JLDSpac=/0x0:3362x1892/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:3362x1892):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507308/91cig3zu.jpg 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/V6-VgE5BEhclu-2onRevXy442-Q=/0x0:3362x1892/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:3362x1892):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507308/91cig3zu.jpg 1920w" sizes="(min-width: 1221px) 846px, (min-width: 880px) calc(100vw - 334px), 100vw" type="image/webp">




</picture>

      
    </span>
    
  </span>
  
    <span>
      
      
        <cite>Image: Wizards of the Coast</cite>
      
    </span>
  
</figure>


<p id="rdZ8xh">The Assassin’s Creed Universes Beyond set is introducing a slightly different take on the classic Booster Pack format with Beyond Boosters. These seven-card packs can include up to four rare cards, in addition to at least one foil art card and borderless art card. Each box comes with a total of 27 Beyond Boosters, and can be pre-ordered for around $131 from <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CTKWCNGZ?tag=polygon05-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank" has-subtag="true" data-cdata="{&quot;rewritten_url&quot;:&quot;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CTKWCNGZ?ascsubtag=___pl__p_23946748__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder\u0026tag=polygon05-20&quot;,&quot;subtag_max_length&quot;:99,&quot;subtag_delim_length&quot;:3,&quot;subtag_key&quot;:&quot;ascsubtag&quot;,&quot;subtag_data&quot;:{&quot;ascsubtag&quot;:&quot;___pl__p_23946748__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder&quot;,&quot;tag&quot;:&quot;polygon05-20&quot;},&quot;encode_subtag&quot;:false}">Amazon</a> or from <a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;mid=24348&amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Ftoys-games%2Ftrading-cards%2Fproducts%2Fmagic-the-gathering-assassins-creed-beyond-booster-24-pack%2F411642.html&amp;u1=PolygonAC062624" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank" has-subtag="true" data-cdata="{&quot;rewritten_url&quot;:&quot;https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?u1=[]pl[p]23946748[m]m-placeholder[s]s-placeholder[t]w[c]c-placeholder[r]r-placeholder[d]d-placeholder\u0026id=nOD/rLJHOac\u0026mid=24348\u0026murl=https://www.gamestop.com/toys-games/trading-cards/products/magic-the-gathering-assassins-creed-beyond-booster-24-pack/411642.html&quot;,&quot;subtag_max_length&quot;:72,&quot;subtag_delim_length&quot;:2,&quot;subtag_key&quot;:&quot;u1&quot;,&quot;subtag_data&quot;:{&quot;u1&quot;:&quot;[]pl[p]23946748[m]m-placeholder[s]s-placeholder[t]w[c]c-placeholder[r]r-placeholder[d]d-placeholder&quot;,&quot;id&quot;:&quot;nOD/rLJHOac&quot;,&quot;mid&quot;:&quot;24348&quot;,&quot;murl&quot;:&quot;https://www.gamestop.com/toys-games/trading-cards/products/magic-the-gathering-assassins-creed-beyond-booster-24-pack/411642.html&quot;},&quot;encode_subtag&quot;:false}">GameStop</a> for $179.99. Individual Beyond Boosters are also available from <a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD%2FrLJHOac&amp;mid=24348&amp;u1=polygon&amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Ftoys-games%2Ftrading-cards%2Fproducts%2Fmagic-the-gathering--assassins-creed-beyond-booster-sleeved%2F409264.html" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank" has-subtag="true" data-cdata="{&quot;rewritten_url&quot;:&quot;https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?u1=[]pl[p]23946748[m]m-placeholder[s]s-placeholder[t]w[c]c-placeholder[r]r-placeholder[d]d-placeholder\u0026id=nOD/rLJHOac\u0026mid=24348\u0026murl=https://www.gamestop.com/toys-games/trading-cards/products/magic-the-gathering--assassins-creed-beyond-booster-sleeved/409264.html&quot;,&quot;subtag_max_length&quot;:72,&quot;subtag_delim_length&quot;:2,&quot;subtag_key&quot;:&quot;u1&quot;,&quot;subtag_data&quot;:{&quot;u1&quot;:&quot;[]pl[p]23946748[m]m-placeholder[s]s-placeholder[t]w[c]c-placeholder[r]r-placeholder[d]d-placeholder&quot;,&quot;id&quot;:&quot;nOD/rLJHOac&quot;,&quot;mid&quot;:&quot;24348&quot;,&quot;murl&quot;:&quot;https://www.gamestop.com/toys-games/trading-cards/products/magic-the-gathering--assassins-creed-beyond-booster-sleeved/409264.html&quot;},&quot;encode_subtag&quot;:false}">GameStop</a> for $7.99 each.</p>
<div id="LGYc70">
    <ul>
    
      
        <li>
          <a data-analytics-link="product-card" data-analytics-viewport="product-card" data-vars-analytics-action="product-card" data-vars-analytics-link-title="Amazon         $131" has-subtag="true" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CTKWCNGZ?tag=polygon05-20" data-cdata="{&quot;rewritten_url&quot;:&quot;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CTKWCNGZ?ascsubtag=___pl__p_23946748__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder\u0026tag=polygon05-20&quot;,&quot;subtag_max_length&quot;:99,&quot;subtag_delim_length&quot;:3,&quot;subtag_key&quot;:&quot;ascsubtag&quot;,&quot;subtag_data&quot;:{&quot;ascsubtag&quot;:&quot;___pl__p_23946748__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder&quot;,&quot;tag&quot;:&quot;polygon05-20&quot;},&quot;encode_subtag&quot;:false}">
             
             <span>
               $131
             </span>
             
           <span>
              at Amazon
           </span>
          </a>
        </li>
      
    
      
        <li>
          <a data-analytics-link="product-card" data-analytics-viewport="product-card" data-vars-analytics-action="product-card" data-vars-analytics-link-title="GameStop         $180" has-subtag="true" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank" href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;mid=24348&amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Ftoys-games%2Ftrading-cards%2Fproducts%2Fmagic-the-gathering-assassins-creed-beyond-booster-24-pack%2F411642.html&amp;u1=PolygonAC062624" data-cdata="{&quot;rewritten_url&quot;:&quot;https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?u1=[]pl[p]23946748[m]m-placeholder[s]s-placeholder[t]w[c]c-placeholder[r]r-placeholder[d]d-placeholder\u0026id=nOD/rLJHOac\u0026mid=24348\u0026murl=https://www.gamestop.com/toys-games/trading-cards/products/magic-the-gathering-assassins-creed-beyond-booster-24-pack/411642.html&quot;,&quot;subtag_max_length&quot;:72,&quot;subtag_delim_length&quot;:2,&quot;subtag_key&quot;:&quot;u1&quot;,&quot;subtag_data&quot;:{&quot;u1&quot;:&quot;[]pl[p]23946748[m]m-placeholder[s]s-placeholder[t]w[c]c-placeholder[r]r-placeholder[d]d-placeholder&quot;,&quot;id&quot;:&quot;nOD/rLJHOac&quot;,&quot;mid&quot;:&quot;24348&quot;,&quot;murl&quot;:&quot;https://www.gamestop.com/toys-games/trading-cards/products/magic-the-gathering-assassins-creed-beyond-booster-24-pack/411642.html&quot;},&quot;encode_subtag&quot;:false}">
             
             <span>
               $180
             </span>
             
           <span>
              at GameStop
           </span>
          </a>
        </li>
      
    
    </ul>
  </div>
<h2 id="lmurJb"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CTKXN28J?tag=polygon05-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank" has-subtag="true" data-cdata="{&quot;rewritten_url&quot;:&quot;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CTKXN28J?ascsubtag=___pl__p_23946748__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder\u0026tag=polygon05-20&quot;,&quot;subtag_max_length&quot;:99,&quot;subtag_delim_length&quot;:3,&quot;subtag_key&quot;:&quot;ascsubtag&quot;,&quot;subtag_data&quot;:{&quot;ascsubtag&quot;:&quot;___pl__p_23946748__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder&quot;,&quot;tag&quot;:&quot;polygon05-20&quot;},&quot;encode_subtag&quot;:false}"><strong>Assassin’s Creed Universes Beyond Bundle</strong></a></h2>
  <figure>
  <span>
    
    <span data-original="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507306/xzo34ag9.jpg">
      
        <picture data-cid="site/picture_element-1719427275_7495_137690" data-cdata="{&quot;asset_id&quot;:25507306,&quot;ratio&quot;:&quot;*&quot;}">
  


  <source srcset="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/DitOB8rVpo9FZvVQ-oBdg674doc=/0x0:3179x1788/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:3179x1788):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507306/xzo34ag9.jpg 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_f-xZ2e20Vi-hNDsGQrk79qc7qg=/0x0:3179x1788/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:3179x1788):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507306/xzo34ag9.jpg 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rRv2OeJ05Kaaplhu2JPR_p-SP-Y=/0x0:3179x1788/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:3179x1788):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507306/xzo34ag9.jpg 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2bxqe2wgvEm9EX-wLoGSFKlJ8S8=/0x0:3179x1788/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:3179x1788):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507306/xzo34ag9.jpg 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Qtn351o0QprvyGIBCkLnpKFGjm8=/0x0:3179x1788/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:3179x1788):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507306/xzo34ag9.jpg 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/x2inprn4aSPvcIYxC8MC0FerNNE=/0x0:3179x1788/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:3179x1788):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507306/xzo34ag9.jpg 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/swmZrYT3hI3U7iKlGcS0CgUyIng=/0x0:3179x1788/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:3179x1788):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507306/xzo34ag9.jpg 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_M7CcfePkedsCJ62amrzrcvL8A4=/0x0:3179x1788/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:3179x1788):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507306/xzo34ag9.jpg 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NXmTSLSaBCnDEfNYjVP0GZBBjdU=/0x0:3179x1788/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:3179x1788):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507306/xzo34ag9.jpg 1920w" sizes="(min-width: 1221px) 846px, (min-width: 880px) calc(100vw - 334px), 100vw" type="image/webp">




</picture>

      
    </span>
    
  </span>
  
    <span>
      
      
        <cite>Image: Wizards of the Coast</cite>
      
    </span>
  
</figure>


<p id="3YnwoE">If you’re looking to supplement your existing <em>MTG</em> collection with cards from this new set, the Assassin’s Creed Universes Beyond Bundle is the quickest way to do it. Each bundle is packaged with nine Beyond Boosters from the new set in addition to 40 lands (20 of which are foil cards). Each box also features a single exclusive alternate-art foil card and an Assassin’s Creed-themed spindown life counter. The $65 Assassin’s Creed Universes Beyond Bundle is available to pre-order from <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CTKXN28J?tag=polygon05-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank" has-subtag="true" data-cdata="{&quot;rewritten_url&quot;:&quot;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CTKXN28J?ascsubtag=___pl__p_23946748__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder\u0026tag=polygon05-20&quot;,&quot;subtag_max_length&quot;:99,&quot;subtag_delim_length&quot;:3,&quot;subtag_key&quot;:&quot;ascsubtag&quot;,&quot;subtag_data&quot;:{&quot;ascsubtag&quot;:&quot;___pl__p_23946748__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder&quot;,&quot;tag&quot;:&quot;polygon05-20&quot;},&quot;encode_subtag&quot;:false}">Amazon</a> and <a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;mid=24348&amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Ftoys-games%2Ftrading-cards%2Fproducts%2Fmagic-the-gathering--assassins-creed-beyond-bundle%2F409266.html&amp;u1=PolygonAC062624" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank" has-subtag="true" data-cdata="{&quot;rewritten_url&quot;:&quot;https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?u1=[]pl[p]23946748[m]m-placeholder[s]s-placeholder[t]w[c]c-placeholder[r]r-placeholder[d]d-placeholder\u0026id=nOD/rLJHOac\u0026mid=24348\u0026murl=https://www.gamestop.com/toys-games/trading-cards/products/magic-the-gathering--assassins-creed-beyond-bundle/409266.html&quot;,&quot;subtag_max_length&quot;:72,&quot;subtag_delim_length&quot;:2,&quot;subtag_key&quot;:&quot;u1&quot;,&quot;subtag_data&quot;:{&quot;u1&quot;:&quot;[]pl[p]23946748[m]m-placeholder[s]s-placeholder[t]w[c]c-placeholder[r]r-placeholder[d]d-placeholder&quot;,&quot;id&quot;:&quot;nOD/rLJHOac&quot;,&quot;mid&quot;:&quot;24348&quot;,&quot;murl&quot;:&quot;https://www.gamestop.com/toys-games/trading-cards/products/magic-the-gathering--assassins-creed-beyond-bundle/409266.html&quot;},&quot;encode_subtag&quot;:false}">GameStop</a>.</p>
<div id="hdwQiO">
    <ul>
    
      
        <li>
          <a data-analytics-link="product-card" data-analytics-viewport="product-card" data-vars-analytics-action="product-card" data-vars-analytics-link-title="Amazon         $65" has-subtag="true" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CTKXN28J?tag=polygon05-20" data-cdata="{&quot;rewritten_url&quot;:&quot;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CTKXN28J?ascsubtag=___pl__p_23946748__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder\u0026tag=polygon05-20&quot;,&quot;subtag_max_length&quot;:99,&quot;subtag_delim_length&quot;:3,&quot;subtag_key&quot;:&quot;ascsubtag&quot;,&quot;subtag_data&quot;:{&quot;ascsubtag&quot;:&quot;___pl__p_23946748__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder&quot;,&quot;tag&quot;:&quot;polygon05-20&quot;},&quot;encode_subtag&quot;:false}">
             
             <span>
               $65
             </span>
             
           <span>
              at Amazon
           </span>
          </a>
        </li>
      
    
      
        <li>
          <a data-analytics-link="product-card" data-analytics-viewport="product-card" data-vars-analytics-action="product-card" data-vars-analytics-link-title="GameStop         $65" has-subtag="true" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank" href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;mid=24348&amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Ftoys-games%2Ftrading-cards%2Fproducts%2Fmagic-the-gathering--assassins-creed-beyond-bundle%2F409266.html&amp;u1=PolygonAC062624" data-cdata="{&quot;rewritten_url&quot;:&quot;https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?u1=[]pl[p]23946748[m]m-placeholder[s]s-placeholder[t]w[c]c-placeholder[r]r-placeholder[d]d-placeholder\u0026id=nOD/rLJHOac\u0026mid=24348\u0026murl=https://www.gamestop.com/toys-games/trading-cards/products/magic-the-gathering--assassins-creed-beyond-bundle/409266.html&quot;,&quot;subtag_max_length&quot;:72,&quot;subtag_delim_length&quot;:2,&quot;subtag_key&quot;:&quot;u1&quot;,&quot;subtag_data&quot;:{&quot;u1&quot;:&quot;[]pl[p]23946748[m]m-placeholder[s]s-placeholder[t]w[c]c-placeholder[r]r-placeholder[d]d-placeholder&quot;,&quot;id&quot;:&quot;nOD/rLJHOac&quot;,&quot;mid&quot;:&quot;24348&quot;,&quot;murl&quot;:&quot;https://www.gamestop.com/toys-games/trading-cards/products/magic-the-gathering--assassins-creed-beyond-bundle/409266.html&quot;},&quot;encode_subtag&quot;:false}">
             
             <span>
               $65
             </span>
             
           <span>
              at GameStop
           </span>
          </a>
        </li>
      
    
    </ul>
  </div>
<h2 id="jxGVdQ"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CTKW15QS?tag=polygon05-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank" has-subtag="true" data-cdata="{&quot;rewritten_url&quot;:&quot;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CTKW15QS?ascsubtag=___pl__p_23946748__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder\u0026tag=polygon05-20&quot;,&quot;subtag_max_length&quot;:99,&quot;subtag_delim_length&quot;:3,&quot;subtag_key&quot;:&quot;ascsubtag&quot;,&quot;subtag_data&quot;:{&quot;ascsubtag&quot;:&quot;___pl__p_23946748__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder&quot;,&quot;tag&quot;:&quot;polygon05-20&quot;},&quot;encode_subtag&quot;:false}"><strong>Assassin’s Creed Universes Beyond Collector Boosters</strong></a></h2>
  <figure>
  <span>
    
    <span data-original="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507313/h6lu82tz.jpg">
      
        <picture data-cid="site/picture_element-1719427275_5397_137691" data-cdata="{&quot;asset_id&quot;:25507313,&quot;ratio&quot;:&quot;*&quot;}">
  


  <source srcset="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Vzhz2Sq_ZiEZRRFqtOVw5A5FTcw=/0x0:3348x1884/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:3348x1884):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507313/h6lu82tz.jpg 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4_YAPdQ23gn4K8bHUZVR4QPFN1o=/0x0:3348x1884/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:3348x1884):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507313/h6lu82tz.jpg 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/RtNjoRplL7VX1pExUc_I0RdUw7o=/0x0:3348x1884/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:3348x1884):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507313/h6lu82tz.jpg 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3J00-BtQW1B38hvt1EXHTnQOCQE=/0x0:3348x1884/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:3348x1884):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507313/h6lu82tz.jpg 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nzeo0bHPz2DH8kXMvVh2TLcQLY0=/0x0:3348x1884/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:3348x1884):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507313/h6lu82tz.jpg 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gbs1bxpkeHatijPT-X8vatjO_Ws=/0x0:3348x1884/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:3348x1884):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507313/h6lu82tz.jpg 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0pWuZSDi1MC31hzwRsGRAYnuPfs=/0x0:3348x1884/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:3348x1884):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507313/h6lu82tz.jpg 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Jn-jy3L3h6sb3cJsx4mqLuUrXak=/0x0:3348x1884/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:3348x1884):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507313/h6lu82tz.jpg 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nWu4Tt1L8SdxIE_cVBMOPrnS7qk=/0x0:3348x1884/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:3348x1884):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25507313/h6lu82tz.jpg 1920w" sizes="(min-width: 1221px) 846px, (min-width: 880px) calc(100vw - 334px), 100vw" type="image/webp">




</picture>

      
    </span>
    
  </span>
  
    <span>
      
      
        <cite>Image: Wizards of the Coast</cite>
      
    </span>
  
</figure>


<p id="GIwPvs">The Assassin’s Creed Universes Beyond set will also launch with Collector Booster Packs, perfect for scooping up all the tastiest foil and alternate-art cards introduced with this expansion. Each Collector Booster contains ten rare cards with at least one extended art and borderless art card in addition to at least two foil-etched cards. A box of 12 Collector Boosters can be pre-ordered from <a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;mid=24348&amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Ftoys-games%2Ftrading-cards%2Fproducts%2Fmagic-the-gathering---assassin%25E2%2580%2599s-creed-collector-boosters-12-packs%2F411643.html&amp;u1=PolygonAC062624" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank" has-subtag="true" data-cdata="{&quot;rewritten_url&quot;:&quot;https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?u1=[]pl[p]23946748[m]m-placeholder[s]s-placeholder[t]w[c]c-placeholder[r]r-placeholder[d]d-placeholder\u0026id=nOD/rLJHOac\u0026mid=24348\u0026murl=https://www.gamestop.com/toys-games/trading-cards/products/magic-the-gathering---assassin%E2%80%99s-creed-collector-boosters-12-packs/411643.html&quot;,&quot;subtag_max_length&quot;:72,&quot;subtag_delim_length&quot;:2,&quot;subtag_key&quot;:&quot;u1&quot;,&quot;subtag_data&quot;:{&quot;u1&quot;:&quot;[]pl[p]23946748[m]m-placeholder[s]s-placeholder[t]w[c]c-placeholder[r]r-placeholder[d]d-placeholder&quot;,&quot;id&quot;:&quot;nOD/rLJHOac&quot;,&quot;mid&quot;:&quot;24348&quot;,&quot;murl&quot;:&quot;https://www.gamestop.com/toys-games/trading-cards/products/magic-the-gathering---assassin%E2%80%99s-creed-collector-boosters-12-packs/411643.html&quot;},&quot;encode_subtag&quot;:false}">GameStop</a> for $279.99 or from <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CTKW15QS?tag=polygon05-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank" has-subtag="true" data-cdata="{&quot;rewritten_url&quot;:&quot;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CTKW15QS?ascsubtag=___pl__p_23946748__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder\u0026tag=polygon05-20&quot;,&quot;subtag_max_length&quot;:99,&quot;subtag_delim_length&quot;:3,&quot;subtag_key&quot;:&quot;ascsubtag&quot;,&quot;subtag_data&quot;:{&quot;ascsubtag&quot;:&quot;___pl__p_23946748__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder&quot;,&quot;tag&quot;:&quot;polygon05-20&quot;},&quot;encode_subtag&quot;:false}">Amazon</a> for around $308. Collector Boosters can also be pre-ordered piecemeal from <a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD%2FrLJHOac&amp;mid=24348&amp;u1=polygon&amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Ftoys-games%2Ftrading-cards%2Fproducts%2Fmagic-the-gathering-assassins-creed-collector-booster%2F409265.html" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank" has-subtag="true" data-cdata="{&quot;rewritten_url&quot;:&quot;https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?u1=[]pl[p]23946748[m]m-placeholder[s]s-placeholder[t]w[c]c-placeholder[r]r-placeholder[d]d-placeholder\u0026id=nOD/rLJHOac\u0026mid=24348\u0026murl=https://www.gamestop.com/toys-games/trading-cards/products/magic-the-gathering-assassins-creed-collector-booster/409265.html&quot;,&quot;subtag_max_length&quot;:72,&quot;subtag_delim_length&quot;:2,&quot;subtag_key&quot;:&quot;u1&quot;,&quot;subtag_data&quot;:{&quot;u1&quot;:&quot;[]pl[p]23946748[m]m-placeholder[s]s-placeholder[t]w[c]c-placeholder[r]r-placeholder[d]d-placeholder&quot;,&quot;id&quot;:&quot;nOD/rLJHOac&quot;,&quot;mid&quot;:&quot;24348&quot;,&quot;murl&quot;:&quot;https://www.gamestop.com/toys-games/trading-cards/products/magic-the-gathering-assassins-creed-collector-booster/409265.html&quot;},&quot;encode_subtag&quot;:false}">GameStop</a> for $27.99.</p>
<div id="BsKFoj">
    <ul>
    
      
        <li>
          <a data-analytics-link="product-card" data-analytics-viewport="product-card" data-vars-analytics-action="product-card" data-vars-analytics-link-title="Amazon         $308         (6% off)" has-subtag="true" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CTKW15QS?tag=polygon05-20" data-cdata="{&quot;rewritten_url&quot;:&quot;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CTKW15QS?ascsubtag=___pl__p_23946748__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder\u0026tag=polygon05-20&quot;,&quot;subtag_max_length&quot;:99,&quot;subtag_delim_length&quot;:3,&quot;subtag_key&quot;:&quot;ascsubtag&quot;,&quot;subtag_data&quot;:{&quot;ascsubtag&quot;:&quot;___pl__p_23946748__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder&quot;,&quot;tag&quot;:&quot;polygon05-20&quot;},&quot;encode_subtag&quot;:false}">
             
             <span>
               $308
             </span>
             
           <span>
              at Amazon
           </span>
          </a>
        </li>
      
    
      
        <li>
          <a data-analytics-link="product-card" data-analytics-viewport="product-card" data-vars-analytics-action="product-card" data-vars-analytics-link-title="GameStop         $280" has-subtag="true" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank" href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;mid=24348&amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Ftoys-games%2Ftrading-cards%2Fproducts%2Fmagic-the-gathering---assassin%25E2%2580%2599s-creed-collector-boosters-12-packs%2F411643.html&amp;u1=PolygonAC062624" data-cdata="{&quot;rewritten_url&quot;:&quot;https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?u1=[]pl[p]23946748[m]m-placeholder[s]s-placeholder[t]w[c]c-placeholder[r]r-placeholder[d]d-placeholder\u0026id=nOD/rLJHOac\u0026mid=24348\u0026murl=https://www.gamestop.com/toys-games/trading-cards/products/magic-the-gathering---assassin%E2%80%99s-creed-collector-boosters-12-packs/411643.html&quot;,&quot;subtag_max_length&quot;:72,&quot;subtag_delim_length&quot;:2,&quot;subtag_key&quot;:&quot;u1&quot;,&quot;subtag_data&quot;:{&quot;u1&quot;:&quot;[]pl[p]23946748[m]m-placeholder[s]s-placeholder[t]w[c]c-placeholder[r]r-placeholder[d]d-placeholder&quot;,&quot;id&quot;:&quot;nOD/rLJHOac&quot;,&quot;mid&quot;:&quot;24348&quot;,&quot;murl&quot;:&quot;https://www.gamestop.com/toys-games/trading-cards/products/magic-the-gathering---assassin%E2%80%99s-creed-collector-boosters-12-packs/411643.html&quot;},&quot;encode_subtag&quot;:false}">
             
             <span>
               $280
             </span>
             
           <span>
              at GameStop
           </span>
          </a>
        </li>
      
    
    </ul>
  </div>

  
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Players Are Obsessed With Shadow Of The Erdtree's Number One Hater]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-dlc-erdtree-igon-bayle-the-dread-hater-1851562224</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/players-are-obsessed-with-shadow-of-the-erdtrees-number-one-hater.912342/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-dlc-erdtree-igon-bayle-the-dread-hater-1851562224<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>If you’ve been roaming the Land of Shadow in <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/tag/elden-ring&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/tag/elden-ring"><em>Elden Ring</em>’</a></span>s recently released expansion, there’s a good chance that you’ve met the greatest hater to ever live. No, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/kendrick-drake-beef-rap-battle-memes-internet-reactions-1851458972&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/kendrick-drake-beef-rap-battle-memes-internet-reactions-1851458972">Kendrick Lamar</a></span> is not suddenly in <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-dlc-expansion-review-1851545505&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-dlc-expansion-review-1851545505"><em>Shadow of the Erdtree</em></a></span>, he’s <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.latimes.com/entertainment-arts/music/story/2024-06-24/kendrick-lamar-not-like-us-music-video-compton#:~:text=Days%20after%20rocking%20the%20Kia,in%20his%20latest%20music%20video.&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.latimes.com/entertainment-arts/music/story/2024-06-24/kendrick-lamar-not-like-us-music-video-compton#:~:text=Days%20after%20rocking%20the%20Kia,in%20his%20latest%20music%20video." target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">too busy in Compton</a></span> making <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.vibe.com/news/events/kendrick-performs-not-like-us-6-times-the-pop-out-los-angeles-concert-setlist-1234887520/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.vibe.com/news/events/kendrick-performs-not-like-us-6-times-the-pop-out-los-angeles-concert-setlist-1234887520/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Drake’s life a living hell</a></span>. Instead, you would have met Igon, who’s both one of the most emphatically voiced characters ever in a From Software game, and the pettiest dude alive. We have no choice but to stan this Ahab insert in this storyline ripped straight from the pages of <em>Moby Dick</em>.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="195502" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="The Most Sought After Elden Ring Sword Has A Storied History" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="307" data-playlist="195502,195624,196394" data-current="195502"><div><p>The Most Sought After Elden Ring Sword Has A Storied History</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195502/195502_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195502/195502_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195502/195502_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195502/195502_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/20979.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p><strong>Spoilers for Igon’s questline in <em>Shadow of the Erdtree </em>follow.</strong></p><p>Igon can be first encountered west of the site of grace at the Pillar Path Waypoint, but you won’t know him by his appearance as much as his voice. Here’s the content creator <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.twitch.tv/dansgaming&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.twitch.tv/dansgaming" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">DansGaming</a></span> bumping into an “NPC making some very weird sounds” that turns out to be none other than Igon, a drake warrior on his final mission.</p><p><strong>Order <em>Elden Ring: Shadow of the Erdtree:</em></strong>&nbsp;<span><a data-ga="[]" href="https://www.amazon.com/ELDEN-RING-Erdtree-PRE-PURCHASE-Digital/dp/B0D4TZ1RYK/ref=sr_1_6?asc_campaign=kinjakotakulink-20&amp;asc_refurl=https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-dlc-erdtree-igon-bayle-the-dread-hater-1851562224&amp;asc_source=&amp;tag=kinjakotakulink-20" target="_blank" rel="sponsored noopener noreferrer nofollow noskim" data-vtas-click="self:InlineUrl:inline-url-postbody" data-amazonasin="B0D4TZ1RYK" data-amazontag="kinjakotakulink-20">Amazon</a></span> | <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://howl.me/cmn8lfikrvq&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://howl.me/cmn8lfikrvq" target="_blank" rel="sponsored noopener noreferrer nofollow noskim" data-vtas-click="self:InlineUrl:inline-url-postbody">Best Buy</a></span> | <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.dpbolvw.net/click-8335294-14555742?sid=KT-&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.humblebundle.com%2Fstore%2Felden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree%3Fhmb_source%3Dsearch_bar&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.dpbolvw.net/click-8335294-14555742?sid=KT-&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.humblebundle.com%2Fstore%2Felden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree%3Fhmb_source%3Dsearch_bar" target="_blank" rel="sponsored noopener noreferrer nofollow noskim" data-vtas-click="self:InlineUrl:inline-url-postbody">Humble Bundle</a></span></p><p>When you chance upon Igon, he’s been beaten down and scarred. He can’t really use his arms, and it seems like his legs have failed him too. For all intents and purposes, Igon is dragging himself across the Land of Shadow to kill Bayle the Dread, a traitorous dragon who wounded Placidusax—a name you might remember as the crazy dragon boss you fought in Farum Azula in <em>Elden Ring</em>—and struck Igon with a crippling fear that’s kept him from partaking in Dragon Communion, which gave his life worth.<br></p><p>Talking to him in this state provides a lot of anguished cries and repeated calls for “vile Bayle,” and kicks off a quest line following Igon’s journey. When he’s not growling every other line he utters, he’s deeply wounded and scared of Bayle, who’s inflicted a horror on Igon that literally still haunts him, and the way that voice actor Richard Lintern zips between these extremes is nothing short of impressive. He comes across like two distinct characters rather than dimensions of the same man, and people are already hailing Lintern’s full-throated performance as Igon.</p><p>Following up with Igon provides ample opportunity to continue hearing his rantings and ravings, but before long, he realizes that his body’s failing him, and he won’t physically make it to Bayle. At this point, he does the craziest thing yet and <em>gives </em>you his finger in order to summon his spirit to fuck Bayle up when you eventually get to the boss fight. And then the boss fight happens and Igon reaches hater levels previously thought unattainable.<br></p><p>The moment you summon him, Igon immediately shouts “Curse you, Bayle,” and launches into the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/Bri4nF/status/1805475033998852302&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/Bri4nF/status/1805475033998852302" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">mother of all tirades</a></span>. He even gasses you up, saying “Behold, a true drake warrior! And I, Igon!” <em>You’re the</em> true drake warrior he’s talking up! My favorite line, though, is when he screams at Bayle that he will “riddle with holes your rotten hide,” and immediately follows it up by giddily delivering the line, “With a hail of harpoons!” Dude wants Bayle dead <em>so </em>badly, he doesn’t seem like he’ll ever shut up, but he eventually does.<em> </em>And so Igon takes up his bow made of dragon bone, and the harpoons he specifically fashioned to sink into Bayle’s “rotten hide,” and does exactly what he was put on this Earth to do, and kills that dragon.<br></p><p>Igon’s storyline is so batshit, and Lintern’s readings of every line are so unhinged, that the character has immediately become a standout of the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-shadow-of-erdtree-steam-reviews-difficulty-1851561745&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-shadow-of-erdtree-steam-reviews-difficulty-1851561745">expansion</a></span>, as well as FromSoft’s evolving gallery of weird little guys. Many players have made <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/Eldenring/comments/1dnq5gs/igons_voice_actor_didnt_get_payed_enough/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Eldenring/comments/1dnq5gs/igons_voice_actor_didnt_get_payed_enough/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">memes</a></span> about the dude and his clearly obsessive anger. Others are simply <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/Eldenring/comments/1dlsra5/i_fking_love_igon/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Eldenring/comments/1dlsra5/i_fking_love_igon/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">paying their respects</a></span> to a performance that absolutely enraptured them. One person has <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/Eldenring/comments/1dncm9i/screw_miquella_i_am_a_devoted_follower_of_igon/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Eldenring/comments/1dncm9i/screw_miquella_i_am_a_devoted_follower_of_igon/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">sworn fealty to the guy</a></span> for the insane rally he pulls at the end despite everything afflicting him, ultimately dubbing Igon a “gigachad.”<br></p><p>Interestingly enough, a <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/YourBudTevin/status/1805310032600346980&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/YourBudTevin/status/1805310032600346980" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">few savvy folks</a></span> have managed to piece together that both Bayle and Igon are tied to another work of literature besides <em>Moby Dick</em>. Considering that <em>A Song of Ice and Fire</em>’s author George R.R Martin worked on the lore of <em>Elden Ring</em>, it probably shouldn’t come as a surprise that both names take inspiration from his main body of work. Bayle is a reference to a literal dread dragon named Balerion in <em>ASOIAF</em>, who’s ridden by the phonetically similar Aegon Targaryen. And so it all comes full circle. </p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Best Secret Identity Games (2024)]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/best-secret-identity-games</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/best-secret-identity-games-2024.912339/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/best-secret-identity-games<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>Secret identity board games, or social deduction games, are incredibly popular among casual and hardcore audiences, and it isn’t hard to see why. Perhaps it is the thrill of lying to your friends' faces and knowing that everything will still be okay between you when the game ends, or maybe it’s the excitement of learning that the quiet one in your group secretly harbors an excellent poker face. Either way, these titles often make for some of the <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-board-games-for-parties-and-large-groups"><u>best party games</u></a>, thanks to the memories they frequently create.</p><p>Most already know about genre staples like Mafia and Werewolf, but the category is incredibly deep, with diverse games for various audiences. The secret identity genre features longer epic experiences as well as quick playthroughs – games for large groups and titles for just two players. Regardless of skill level and general interest in the hobby, no matter what you’re in the mood for, social deduction games are a surefire hit to break out at your next get-together.</p><h3>TL;DR The Best Secret Identity Board Games</h3><ul data-cy="list"><li><a href="#blood">Blood on the Clocktower</a></li><li><a href="#deception">Deception: Murder in Hong Kong</a></li><li><a href="#res">The Resistance: Avalon</a></li><li><a href="#night">One Night Ultimate Werewolf</a></li><li><a href="#fake">A Fake Artist Goes to New York</a></li><li><a href="#spy">Spyfall 2</a></li><li><a href="#inhuman">Inhuman Conditions</a></li><li><a href="#feed">Feed the Kraken</a></li></ul><h2 id="blood">Blood on the Clocktower</h2><div id="202425" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p><h3>Blood on the Clocktower</h3></p></div><ul data-cy="list"><li>Age: 15+</li><li>Player: 6-21</li><li>Play Time: 30-120 mins</li></ul><p>While Blood on the Clocktower isn’t quite as accessible as some other titles on this list, its additional rules aren’t simply bloat, either. Instead, Blood on the Clocktower adds new wrinkles that often solve problems some players have with other games in the genre. It requires a larger group and a bit more time than some other recommendations in the space, but if you can find the time and the players, Blood on the Clocktower is easily one of the <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-family-board-games"><u>best board games</u></a> money can buy.</p><p>The core mechanics of Blood on the Clocktower play out in a manner that those familiar with the genre will immediately grasp: players each receive a secret role with accompanying abilities, the demon kills another player during the nighttime phase when players’ eyes are closed, and during the daytime phase the townsfolk get together to try and deduce who the villains are and ultimately sentence someone to death. The goal of the good team is to execute the demon, and the goal of the evil team is to survive until the end. However, things get truly interesting when Blood on the Clocktower deviates from classic secret identity games like Mafia and Werewolf.</p><p>One notable difference is that executed players remain in the game. They lose their various abilities, but they can still contribute to the deduction and even retain one final vote on who to put to death. Additionally, players can share their secret identities, but this is a double-edged sword as it will also give the demon valuable information. It’s also challenging to know who to trust because the demon gets to see three different unused identities at the beginning of the game, meaning they can pretend to be one of these characters. Blood on the Clocktower is one of those games that your group will have just as much fun discussing afterward as they did actually playing it.</p><h2 id="deception">Deception: Murder in Hong Kong</h2><div id="202426" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p><h3>Deception: Murder in Hong Kong</h3></p></div><ul data-cy="list"><li>Age: 14+</li><li>Player: 4-12</li><li>Play Time: 20 mins</li></ul><p>Players take on the roles of investigators hoping to solve the titular murder in Hong Kong. However, one of the investigators is secretly the murderer. As a twist, one player knows the killer's identity but cannot say it. Instead, they are only allowed to give clues concerning aspects of the crime, such as the cause of death or location. In front of each player are cards with potential murder weapons and clues, leaving the investigators to solve the rest. There is still enough ambiguity within the cards that players are left to discuss who they believe the culprit is, resulting in some classic moments of deduction and a mountain of lies. In a sense, Deception: Murder in Hong Kong plays out as a hidden identity version of Clue, making the stakes feel much more personal as a result.</p><h2 id="res">The Resistance: Avalon</h2><div id="162037" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p><h3>The Resistance: Avalon</h3></p></div><ul data-cy="list"><li>Age: 13+</li><li>Player: 5-10</li><li>Play Time: 30 mins</li></ul><p>The Resistance: Avalon is a team-based social deduction game set against the backdrop of Arthurian legend. It’s a classic good versus evil showdown but with hidden identities. Players work to get elected to positions of power to advance their team’s goals, but they attempt to do so without revealing their alliances. Only the player taking on the role of Merlin knows who is who, but disclosing this information risks losing their team the game, meaning there are layers upon layers of deception going on simultaneously. Fans of the Secret Hitler board game will recognize many of the rules and mechanics in The Resistance: Avalon, but the latter title is far less likely to offend anyone at your next get-together.</p><h2 id="night">One Night Ultimate Werewolf</h2><div id="162031" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p><h3>One Night Ultimate Werewolf</h3></p></div><ul data-cy="list"><li>Age: 8+</li><li>Player: 3-10</li><li>Play Time: 10 mins</li></ul><p>One Night Ultimate Werewolf has cemented itself as one of the most accessible party games, thanks mainly to an excellent audio app that walks players through each phase. It’s so easy to pick up and play that One Night Ultimate Werewolf has become a favorite among nongamers as well as more serious hobbyists. This bluffing game offers players a single card, each with a different role. Some are villagers, some have special abilities, and some are the titular werewolves. For the most part, the villagers want to identify the werewolves, and the werewolves want to remain anonymous.</p><p>One Night Ultimate Werewolf has two phases: night and day. During the nighttime phase, players put their heads down as the app narrates them through various card-swapping, identification, and general trickery. In the day phase, players open their eyes and attempt to deduce what happened the night before. Following the thread of who had what card at what time can get quite confusing, helping to cloak the deceit in uncertainty.</p><h2 id="fake">A Fake Artist Goes to New York</h2><div id="202427" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p><h3>A Fake Artist Goes to New York</h3></p></div><ul data-cy="list"><li>Age: 8+</li><li>Player: 5-10</li><li>Play Time: 20 mins</li></ul><p>A Fake Artist Goes to New York is a fun twist on deductive games and drawing-based titles like Pictionary. Players take turns collectively drawing a single picture one line at a time. The twist is that every player except for one knows what the final drawing is supposed to look like. The fake artist must guess what the image is supposed to be and add a line to the drawing when it is their turn, using only a vague category and the picture forming in front of them. After each player draws two lines, the group can guess who they believe the fake artist is. Identifying the phony artist may seem simple, but as many people are simply bad at drawing, it is more challenging to decipher who the trickster is than you might think.</p><h2 id="spy">Spyfall 2</h2><div id="202428" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p><h3>Spyfall 2</h3></p></div><ul data-cy="list"><li>Age: 13+</li><li>Player: 3-12</li><li>Play Time: 15 mins</li></ul><p>Spyfall 2 is an ingeniously simple game where players try to deduce who the spy is with only a card and a location. Each player receives a single card, all of which, except for one (or two if you’re playing with multiple spies), has a location on it. The outlier card simply says the word “spy.” Players must discover who the spy is among them by asking questions about the listed location. The key is to pose questions and give answers that won’t reveal the setting so the spy doesn’t catch on. Unless you're the spy, then the goal is to bluff your way to victory. After just a few minutes, the group concludes the interrogation process and votes on who they think the spy is. Not only is the game fun and addictive, but it's also simply a joy to locate the cartoon spy lurking in the background in each card’s artwork.</p><h2 id="inhuman">Inhuman Conditions</h2><div id="202429" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p><h3>Inhuman Conditions</h3></p></div><ul data-cy="list"><li>Age: 12+</li><li>Player: 2</li><li>Play Time: 5 mins</li></ul><p>A true rarity in the secret identity space, Inhuman Conditions is a social deduction game for only two players. It’s not just the player count that makes Inhuman Conditions unique; it’s also that this Blade Runner-inspired bluffing game is centered around a five-minute conversation. In each game, there is one investigator and one suspect. The investigator's goal is to identify whether the suspect is a human or a robot, and the suspect's goal is to pass as a human. However, this is easier said than done, as robots are given specific prompts to follow. The trick is to naturally work these prompts into the conversation, which can quickly become tricky when every word you say is being analyzed by the other player. As Inhuman Conditions’ writing can be a bit wacky, it is best suited for two players who can embrace its sillier role-playing elements.</p><h2 id="feed">Feed the Kraken: Deluxe Edition</h2><div id="202430" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p><h3>Feed the Kraken</h3></p></div><ul data-cy="list"><li>Age: 12+</li><li>Player: 5-11</li><li>Play Time: 45-90 mins</li></ul><p>While most social deduction games omit the board altogether, Feed the Kraken: Deluxe Edition brings players to the figurative and literal table surrounding a beautifully constructed board and stunning minis. Players in Feed the Kraken are split between three secret roles: sailors, pirates, and cultists. The players’ goal is to simply move the ship from one side of the board to the other, but each team is secretly working to navigate toward a different game-ending location. Each game starts with one player selected as the captain, and that player chooses their lieutenant and navigator. This trio ultimately decides the direction the ship will head for that turn, but opportunities for mutiny ensure fate isn’t always left in their hands.</p><p>Along the way, the ship might move to spaces with icons that enable the captain to perform various tasks, such as seeing another player’s role or even keeping someone from talking for the rest of the game. If the ship reaches a Kraken tile, the captain will fulfill the title by feeding the sea beast a crew member. However, feeding the cult leader to the Kraken will result in victory for the cultist team, so players should tread carefully.</p><p>If you’re looking for more great titles to play with larger groups, check out our picks for the <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-6-player-board-games"><u>best six-player board games</u></a> and the <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-board-games-for-4-players"><u>best four-player board games</u></a>.</p><p><em>Bobby Anhalt is a contributing freelancer for IGN covering board games and LEGOs. He has more than 8 years of experience writing about the gaming industry with bylines at Game Rant, Screen Rant, TheXboxHub, and Ranker. You can follow him on </em><a href="https://twitter.com/BobbyAnhalt" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Twitter</em></a><em>.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PlayStation Plus Games for July 2024 Announced]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/playstation-plus-games-for-july-2024-announced</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/playstation-plus-games-for-july-2024-announced.912333/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/playstation-plus-games-for-july-2024-announced<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Borderlands 3, NHL 24, and more.</h2></div><section><p>Sony has announced the PlayStation Plus Essential Tier games for July 2024 are Borderlands 3 (PS4 and PS5), NHL 24 (PS4 and PS5), and Among Us  (PS4 and PS5).</p><p>Revealed on the <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2024/06/26/playstation-plus-monthly-games-for-july-borderlands-3-nhl-24-among-us/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">PlayStation Blog</a>, all three games will be made available at no extra cost to PlayStation Plus subscribers on July 2. Genshin Impact players will also gain access to the PlayStation Plus Pack on July 16 which includes 160 Primogems, four Fragile Resin, 20 Hero's Wit, 30 Mystic Enhancement Ore, and 150,000 Mora.</p><p>Borderlands 3 is perhaps the biggest game in July's line-up as the latest game in Gearbox's beloved looter shooter franchise. Players explore the world of Pandora either solo or with friends, taking on all manner of over the top baddies and teaming up with just as many wacky allies.</p><p><a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2019/09/09/borderlands-3-review">In our 9/10 review</a>, IGN said: "Borderlands 3 sticks to its guns and outdoes itself with an amazing arsenal of weapons, humor, and missions."</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>Perfectly timed with the NFL season wrapping up, fans can keep the excitement going with NHL 24, the latest in EA Sports' hockey franchise.</p><p>"NHL 24’s new gameplay features reinvigorate the on-ice action, but its collection of unimproved game modes has grown increasingly boring with each passing year," <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nhl-24-review">IGN said in our 7/10 review</a>.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3>NHL 24 Gameplay Screenshots</h3></div></output><p>Finally, the PlayStation version of viral deception game Among Us will be available at no extra cost to PlayStation Plus subscribers. Players must work together with a team of crewmates to prepare a spaceship for departure, but not everyone will play nice.</p><p>"Among Us successfully transfers the devious gameplay of in-person cloak-and-dagger games to video game form," <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/among-us-review">IGN said in another 9/10 review</a>. "Murder and deception on a whimsical cartoony spaceship is so much fun that the only real question is what took it so long to catch on?"</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>Borderlands 3, NHL 24, and Among Us will be available be available at no extra cost until August 6, 2024. Those who've yet to add June 2024's PlayStation Plus games to their library — <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/spongebob-squarepants-the-cosmic-shake">SpongeBob Squarepants: The Cosmic Shake</a>, <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/aew-fight-forever">AEW Fight Forever</a>, and<a href="https://www.ign.com/games/aew-fight-forever"> </a><a href="https://www.ign.com/games/streets-of-rage-4">Streets of Rage 4</a> — have until July 1 to do so.</p><div data-cy="playlist-view-trigger"><h3>PlayStation Plus Extra &amp; Premium Game Catalog</h3><p>Browse, sort, and search the full list of PS Plus PS4 and PS5 catalog games, available to Extra and Premium members. Track your backlog, mark games complete, and better organize your play. Sort by "Recently Added" to see the newest additions to the catalog.</p></div><p><em>Ryan Dinsdale is an IGN freelance reporter. He'll talk about The Witcher all day.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>