<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2024 06:23:12 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Deadlock Soars Past 120,000 Peak Players as Valve Introduces ‘Wall Jumping’]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/deadlock-player-count-changes/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/deadlock-soars-past-120-000-peak-players-as-valve-introduces-%E2%80%98wall-jumping%E2%80%99.969003/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/deadlock-player-count-changes/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>It was a few days ago that Valve acknowledged the existence of Deadlock, an all-new third-person hero shooter that’s turning heads worldwide. Before the announcement, Deadlock had pulled in tens of thousands of players on Steam during a closed testing period, and despite the rules not having changed, that number has continued to swell.</p>



<p>People can gain access to the Deadlock test by being invited by someone already in it. Last night, the peak player count skyrocketed to 127,000 players, which is huge considering it’s still being kept behind closed doors for the most part.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-making-moves">Making Moves</h2>



<p>Valve has already deployed a major update to Deadlock, introducing a wall-jumping mechanic and more than 100 balancing changes. Players diving into the game yesterday would have noticed a patch being installed, and it seems that Valve is already leaning on community feedback to shape the future of Deadlock.</p>



<p>Everyone from top-tier streamers to competitive gamers is enjoying Deadlock and feeding back a positive sentiment about the shooter. Given that it comes from Valve, the creator of Counter-Strike, it seems that there’s a strong esports future in store for the game.</p>



<p>In the most recent patch, Valve addressed issues with pause abuse, menu interactions, reporting functions, and matchmaking mechanics. As the issues and suggestions surface, the team seems to be implementing them at a breakneck pace, which is refreshing for players worldwide.</p>



<p>It hasn’t been confirmed how many people at Valve are working on Deadlock, but the recent patch had so many changes wrapped up in it that it’d make your head spin to see the full list. If the team is starting as it means to go on, we could have a seriously disruptive shooter on our hands.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out our <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-6-beta-impressions/">impressions of the Black Ops 6 beta</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>
    
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[James Gunn Says ‘The Batman’ Game Isn’t Happening]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/james-gunn-the-batman-game-not-happening/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/james-gunn-says-%E2%80%98the-batman%E2%80%99-game-isn%E2%80%99t-happening.968997/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/james-gunn-the-batman-game-not-happening/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Recently, a rumour surfaced claiming that a game set in ‘The Batman’ universe and focusing on Penguin was in development at WBD. It was said that the Matt Reeves-directed movie starring Robert Pattinson as the titular character would evolve into a game, but the rumours weren’t properly corroborated.</p>



<p>Now, James Gunn has emerged on social media to stress that there ‘is no truth whatsoever’ behind these rumours.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-unreal-claims">Unreal Claims</h2>



<p>There are plans to expand on the success of The Batman but in the form of a television series at HBO. In the recent claims that surfaced regarding the potential Penguin game, it was said that ‘nothing is concrete’, but James Gunn quickly came out on social media and confirmed that it absolutely isn’t happening.</p>



<p>On <a href="https://www.threads.net/@jamesgunn/replies?xmt=AQGzbNHC-YWsmn8C7mpOqIayJI-xwOG7tPs9vt9c0_w2kg" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Threads</a>, the superstar director, writer, and co-chief of DC Studios wrote:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>Sadly there is no truth to this whatsoever.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>The line indicates that he’d <strong>like </strong>for it to be real, but it simply isn’t. With James Gunn being perfectly placed to know what’s going on regarding the franchise, it’s definitive enough for this rumour to be completely discredited.</p>



<p>If you’re heartbroken about this revelation, you can make sure you pick up Batman: Arkham Shadow, coming to Meta Quest 3 later this year. It’ll patch the gap a little until the next Batman game is inevitably released, but <strong>this one </strong>won’t ever materialise.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/milepost-zero-update-download/">Fallout 76’s next update needs a mega-sized download</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>
    
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MSI Has the Only 2TB PS5 SSD for Under $100]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/msi-has-the-only-2tb-ps5-ssd-for-under-100</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/msi-has-the-only-2tb-ps5-ssd-for-under-100.968982/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/msi-has-the-only-2tb-ps5-ssd-for-under-100<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><section><p>SSD prices are trending upward for 2024, but there are still some excellent deals to be found if you're vigilant. Today, MSI is offering its PS5-compatible <a href="https://msi.pxf.io/jrPym0" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">MSI Spatium M482</a> 2TB PCIe Gen4 x4 M.2 Solid State Drive (SSD) for only $99.99 wtih free shipping. This is the best price currently for a 2TB SSD that fulfills all of the mandatory and recommended requirements for the PS5 console. You'll need to supply a heatsink, but you can easily get a <a href="https://zdcs.link/OGrjj?object_uuid=26cba1be-b601-4434-805b-c228114bdc33&amp;t=article" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">PS5 heatsink for under $10</a>. </p><h2>MSI Spatium 2TB M.2 SSD (PS5-Compatible) for $99.99</h2><div id="206826" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p><h3>MSI Spatium M482 2TB M.2 SSD</h3></p></div><p>The PS5 is an outstanding gaming console, but the 1TB SSD is a real bottleneck. Call of Duty: Modern Warfare 3, for example, can <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/activision-explains-huge-call-of-duty-modern-warfare-3-file-sizes">exceed 200GB alone</a>. NBA 2K23 weighs in at 150GB and even older games like God of War: Ragnarok and Horizon Forbidden West require 90GB of space. Future games like Grand Theft Auto VI will undoubtedly demand even more space. The advantage of a PS5 console over the Xbox Series X is that the SSD slot is not proprietary; you can install most third-party PCIe Gen4 x4 SSDs as long as they are fast enough. Slower drives will still work, but they may bottleneck the original SSD so they aren't recommended if you want a seamless experience.</p><p>The MSI Spatium M482 meets all the requirements for your PS5 upgrade. This is a PCIe Gen4 x4 SSD with an M.2 2280 form factor and transfer speeds of up to 7,300MB/s read and 6,400MB/s write which is well above the 5,500MB/s minimum threshold. It also makes an excellent boot drive for your gaming PC, especially with its 2TB storage capacity. For 2024, we've rarely come across a PS5-compatible 2TB SSD priced under $100, so you should jump on this deal. We may see deals of this caliber during Black Friday, but that's still a few months away, and there's no guarantee that SSD prices won't rise again.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p><em>Willing to pay more for another brand? Check out all of the </em><a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-best-ps5-ssd-deals-for-2024"><em>best PS5 SSD deals today</em></a><em>.</em></p></section><div><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Aug 31, 2024 2:25 am</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cardfight!! Vanguard Dear Days 2 announced for Switch, PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/cardfight-vanguard-dear-days-2-announced-for-switch-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cardfight-vanguard-dear-days-2-announced-for-switch-pc.968979/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/cardfight-vanguard-dear-days-2-announced-for-switch-pc<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Competitive card game sequel due out on January 30, 2025.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Bushiroad Games [56 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/bushiroad/bushiroad-games">Bushiroad Games</a> and developer <a title="Companies > FuRyu [361 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/furyu">FuRyu</a> have <a href="https://prtimes.jp/main/html/rd/p/000008018.000014827.html" rel="noopener" target="_blank">announced</a> competitive card game sequel <em><a title="Games > Cardfight!! Vanguard Dear Days 2 [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/cardfight-vanguard-dear-days-2">Cardfight!! Vanguard Dear Days 2</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > Switch [15,932 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a> and <a title="Platforms > PC [21,126 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> (Steam). It will launch on January 30, 2025 worldwide for $69.99 / 7,678 yen. A physical edition will also be available for Switch in Japan. It will support English and Japanese language options. <span id="more-911497"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its <a href="https://vgdd2.cf-vanguard.com/en/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">official website</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>To all card game fans Behold the pinnacle of this century’s <em>Cardfight!! Vanguard</em> digital card game!</p><p>Triumph over your rivals in fierce battles and etch your victory as the ultimate Vanguard cardfighter!</p><p><strong>System</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <ul><li><strong><a title="Companies > Experience [210 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/experience">Experience</a> the Ultimate Evolution in Vanguard Cardfights!</strong> – The highly acclaimed <em>Cardfight!!&nbsp; Vanguard Dear Days</em> returns with a massive upgrade! Enjoy cardfights with the same rules as the actual card game! Dive into exciting battles in the new <em>Cardfight!!&nbsp; Vanguard Dear Days</em>!</li><li><strong>Experience Thrilling Cardfights Anytime, Anywhere, With Anyone!</strong> – Enjoy the game on your own in story mode, or dive into the online battle mode to engage in cardfights with friends from afar and the strongest cardfighters you’ve yet to meet!</li><li><strong>Over 3,000 Playable Cards!</strong> – Cards from the first Standard format booster pack “Genesis of the Five Greats” to DZ-LBT01 “Lyrical Monasterio Sparkling Stars!” will be available to play! With the addition of around 500 cards from the latest “Divinez” series, there are over 3,000 playable cards! (Downloading with a network connection is required. Additional card updates via downloadable content are also being planned.)</li></ul><p><strong>Story</strong></p><p>The paths of Yuki Ichidoji and Otowa Dosaki intertwine!</p><p>Featuring character designs by Akira Ito, a fully original story supervised by <a title="Companies > Bushiroad [122 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/bushiroad">Bushiroad</a> starring Otowa Dosaki and the protagonist of the previous game Yuki Ichidoji unfolds!</p><p>From <em>Cardfight!! Vanguard Divinez</em>, owners of the <a title="Series > Fate [64 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/series/fate">Fate</a>d One cards also make an appearance! Akina and others appear with newly drawn illustrations! Not only will they play an active role in the story, but they can also be selected as player characters!</p><p><strong>Characters</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Yuki Ichidoji</strong> (voiced by Yuka Nishio) – A second-year high school student at Omi Academy, and the student council president. Through Vanguard, she discovered the will to fight not for others’ wishes but for her own. She revived the legendary team Setsugetsuka and united the members’ desires.</li><li><strong>Otowa Dosaki</strong> (voiced by MoeMi) –&nbsp;A transfer student at the high school division of Omi Academy. She has a bright personality and a love for sweets, Highly skilled, she became a professional cardfighter at a young age but has distanced herself from Vanguard since a certain event.</li><li><strong>Kisato Kuga</strong> (voiced by Seiji Maeda) – The student council vice president at Omi Academy. A diligent and hardworking silver medalist. Despite her constant efforts, she is always easily outdone by Yuki, leading her to develop a bit of a complex.</li><li><strong>Gaku Nijo</strong> (voiced by Hiro Shimono) – A scion of a prestigious family attending the middle school division of Omi Academy. Due to his upbringing in a strict family environment, he has a quiet personality. Playing Vanguard during his spare time between lessons serves as a source of comfort and relaxation for him.</li><li><strong>Roh Nijo</strong> (voiced by Hiro Shimono) – A mysterious person brimming with confidence and possessing overwhelming strength in cardfights.</li></ul><p><strong><em>Cardfight!! Vanguard Divinez</em> Characters</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Yu-yu Kondo</strong> (voiced by Shouta Aoi) – The leader of Team Blackout. Danji Momoyama’s sudden appearance drew him into the world of Vanguard cardfights and its captivating charm. He has a kind and considerate personality.</li><li><strong>Raika Koshiba</strong> (voiced by Jin Ogasawara) – A member of Team Tirnanog Youth. The student council president at Yu-yu’s high school. He is on good terms with Yu-yu as a rival. He greatly respects Michiru and holds him in high regard.</li><li><strong>Urara Haneyama</strong> (voiced by Karin Kagami) – A member of Team Blackout and Team Tirnanog Youth. A first-year middle school girl. She is usually shy, but a switch flips when she focuses on something she loves, and she displays amazing pressure and talent.</li><li><strong>Danji Momoyama</strong> (voiced by Yuki Ono) – A legendary Vanguard cardfighter who once led Team Blackout. With a bold and forthright personality, he interacts with everyone impartially.</li><li><strong>Tohya Ebata</strong> (voiced by Yuma Uchida) – An elite cardfighter with astonishing records in unofficial matches. Though confident and naturally gifted, he is also a hard worker. Always buys cards by the carton.</li><li><strong>Megumi Okura</strong> (voiced by Amane Shindo) – A member of Team Blackout. She is fiercely competitive. As a high school girl who is normally flawless to a fault in sports, academics and even demeanor, she is known as “Gloria Vanguard Meg” in school. She calls Danji “Big Bro” and greatly admires him.</li><li><strong>Zakusa Ishigame</strong> (voiced by Masahiro Ito) – A member of Team Blackout. A gentle young man with a soft demeanor. He has an artistic outlook and expresses it in creative ways, so his words and <a title="Genres > Action [2,134 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a>s are often difficult for ordinary people to understand.</li><li><strong>Tomari Seto</strong> (voiced by Hikaru Tono) – A member of Team Blackout. By day, she works diligently as a policewoman, but once a cardfight begins, she transform into an intense MC and fiercely stirs up the crowd.</li><li><strong>Mirei Minae</strong> (voiced by Yuki Nakashima) – As the leader of Team Daybreak, her popularity rivals that of idols. Danji’s younger sister. She has a competitive spirit, but she is also caring, lively and cheerful.</li></ul><p><strong><em><a title="Games > Cardfight!! Vanguard Dear Days [6 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/cardfight-vanguard-dear-days">Cardfight!! Vanguard Dear Days</a></em> Characters</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Rasen Ichidoji</strong> (voiced by Marina Inoue) – A third-year middle school student at Omi Academy. Through cardfights with formidable opponents, he has grown from a timid younger brother that was always in need of help, into a dependable figure who runs errands to support Yuki.</li><li><strong>Gosetsu Katsushika</strong> (voiced by Taiten Kusunoki) – Owner of the card shop Osen. As someone who has a deep understanding of the cardfighters, he often acts as an advisor and confidant. He fondly watches over as new life is breathed into the team he once led and brought together once more by Yuki. He keeps in touch with Kanji occasionally.</li><li><strong>Kanji Meguro</strong> (voiced by Show Hayami Owner of the card shop chain Berserk. He can sometimes be found at the store counter, guiding troubled cardfighters on their path. He hosts the major tournament “V-Nation” and strives to further popularize Vanguard.</li><li><strong>Masaru Kita</strong> (voiced by Katsuhiro Tokuishi) – Unruly and short-tempered, he is quick to snap at anyone. A member of Setsugetsuka, and the one who was most thrilled about the team’s revival. Putting his skill level aside, his passion for Vanguard is second to none.</li><li><strong>Doshi Nakano</strong> (voiced by Jun Kasama) – A reticent cardfighter. He used to believe that the strength of cards reflected the strength of the cardfighter, but after playing against Rasen and the others, he had a change of heart and now believes in battling to overcome oneself. A member of the newly revived Setsugetsuka.</li><li><strong>Mika Shibuya</strong> (voiced by Kanna Nakamura) – Her cool demeanor remains unchanged, but she now spends her days with her teammates at Osen. Her passion for Vanguard is ever-present, and she helps motivates her troubled allies through intense cardfights. A member of the newly revived Setsugetsuka.</li><li><strong>Kuro Minato</strong> (voiced by Rin Sato) – A prideful narcissist with a tendency for delusions of grandeur. Though haughty, he shows his own form of respect towards the strong. He often accompanies his former teammate Haru.</li><li><strong>Haru Shinagawa</strong> (voiced by Mai Kanno) – A mysterious girl who likes to converse in idioms. She is in tune with her former teammate Kuro and often accompanies him.</li><li><strong>Tatsuki Bunkyo</strong> (voiced by Ryota Suzuki) – Always calm and composed even as his heart burns with passion, he believes in having fun. He struggles between the paths of inheriting the family shrine and advocating Vanguard. A member of the newly revived Setsugetsuka.</li><li><strong>Kana Aoyama</strong> (voiced by Hina Aoki) – A second-year high school student at Omi Academy and Yuki’s classmate. She’s bright and energetic high school girl who is a regular on the basketball team and enjoys pursuing her interests beyond Vanguard.</li><li><strong>Yui Itabashi</strong> (voiced by Sayumi Suzushiro) – A second-year high school student at Omi Academy and Yuki’s classmate. She is the type to get hooked once she has fun doing something. She is close to Kana and enjoys playing Vanguard with her.</li><li><strong>Taiji Arakawa</strong> (voiced by Rio Takahashi) – A twisted individual who thinks nothing of deceiving others. Once loyal to Kanji, he now harbor resentment after being betrayed. He frequently spends time with Noi, who attends the same high school.</li><li><strong>Noi <a title="Companies > TAITO [128 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/taito">Taito</a></strong> (voiced by Sousuke Shimokawa) – A cunning and sly person who doesn’t hesitate to deceive others. He feels betrayed and discarded by Kanji, whom he once deeply admired. He is often found with Taiji, who attends the same high school.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch the announcement trailer below.</p><h2><span>Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><p><iframe title="【PV】Cardfight!! Vanguard Dear Days 2" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/vXBV5OxQ7rU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe title="カードファイト!! ヴァンガード ディアデイズ2 発売決定！" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/dm0B9Nmm4Q4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Metaphor: ReFantazio ‘United Kingdom of Euchronia’ trailer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/metaphor-refantazio-united-kingdom-of-euchronia-trailer</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/metaphor-refantazio-%E2%80%98united-kingdom-of-euchronia%E2%80%99-trailer.968973/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/metaphor-refantazio-united-kingdom-of-euchronia-trailer<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Encounter compelling characters and scenic locales as you travel the world.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > ATLUS [2,025 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/atlus">ATLUS</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Studio Zero [81 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/atlus/studio-zero">Studio Zero</a> have released a new trailer for <em><a title="Games > Metaphor: ReFantazio [30 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/metaphor-refantazio">Metaphor: ReFantazio</a></em> introducing the game’s setting of the United Kingdom of Euchronia. <span id="more-911499"></span></p><p><em>Metaphor: ReFantazio</em> is due out for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [7,845 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [6,015 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,143 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [21,126 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2679460/Metaphor_ReFantazio/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-us/games/store/metaphor-refantazio/9n5dv8310xp7" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Microsoft Store</a> on October 11.</p><p>Watch the trailer below. If you missed the latest <em>Metaphor: ReFantazio</em> showcase, watch it <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/metaphor-refantazio-atlus-exclusive-introduces-locations-traveling-on-the-gauntlet-runner-quest-dungeons-and-eupha">here</a>.</p><h2><span>United Kingdom of Euchronia Trailer</span></h2><p>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=I2T2fk6yGQ</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Concord Is Estimated to Have Sold Only 25,000 Units. Here’s Why Analysts Think It’s Failing]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/concord-is-estimated-to-have-sold-only-25000-units-heres-why-analysts-think-its-failing</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/concord-is-estimated-to-have-sold-only-25-000-units-here%E2%80%99s-why-analysts-think-it%E2%80%99s-failing.968925/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/concord-is-estimated-to-have-sold-only-25000-units-heres-why-analysts-think-its-failing<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>For the last week, there’s been a lot of online discussion on Sony’s newly-launched multiplayer shooter, Concord. But it’s not because everyone’s playing it – it’s because seemingly no one is.</p><p>Plenty of games don’t sell well at launch, but observers have latched onto Concord’s dramatic failure due to its high-profile nature as a Sony first-party game, and its <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/sony-live-service-shooter-concord-debuts-to-a-tragic-697-concurrent-players-on-steam"><u>shockingly low Steam concurrent player numbers</u></a> at launch. Upon its August 23 debut, Concord only had 697 Steam concurrent players, and it hasn’t risen any higher since. At the time I’m writing this, 130 entire people are playing Sony’s brand new, first-party game on Steam. That’s real, real low, even for a game with <a href="https://www.metacritic.com/game/concord/critic-reviews/?platform=playstation-5" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>middling critical reviews</u></a> (<a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/concord-review"><u>we gave it a 7/10</u></a>, which at IGN means it’s “good”).</p><p>So, what happened? Why did a big Sony first-party game get sent out to die immediately? Is it <em>actually</em> selling badly, or are we just reading the numbers wrong? As usual when questions of this nature crop up, I asked a bunch of professional industry analysts to explain it to me.</p><h2>Is Concord actually selling that badly?</h2><p>Unfortunately for Sony…yeah.</p><p>While historically low numbers like the ones being experienced by Concord have a tendency to be used to drive narratives that don’t always paint a full picture, that’s not what’s happening here. Liam Deane, principal analyst at Omdia, said, “The Steam numbers are so bad that even without the exact data on the PS5 side we can be pretty certain that the game is doing very badly.”</p><p>Other analysts were able to share a bit of insight on the PlayStation side with me. Per Circana analyst Mat Piscatella citing Circana’s Player Engagement Tracker, on Monday August 26, “Concord ranked 147th in US PS5 daily active players across all titles, with fewer than 0.2% of Monday's active PS5 players playing the game.” And analyst Simon Carless, who authors the <a href="https://gamediscover.co/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>GameDiscover.co newsletter</u></a>, estimated that Concord’s total sales are sitting around 10,000 units on Steam, and around 15,000 on PlayStation (he responded to my email Wednesday, August 28, 2024).</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>Sadly, making a fun, high-quality shooter is not enough in the oversaturated live-service space these days.</p></div><p>Many of the analysts I spoke to lamented the reality. As they pointed out, Concord <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/sonys-live-service-hero-shooter-concord-has-been-in-development-for-around-8-years"><u>has been in development for years now</u></a>, a substantial financial and time investment for Sony. And incredibly talented people worked on it: it’s well-produced, and as Midia Research analyst Rhys Elliott specifically notes, it’s fun to play. But, Elliott continued, “sadly, making a fun, high-quality shooter is not enough in the oversaturated live-service space these days.”</p><h2>Why Isn’t Concord Selling?</h2><p>Usually, when I reach out to analysts for comment on a piece like this, they largely have similar assessments of the big picture but can offer differing perspectives on certain details. In the case of Concord, everyone I spoke to agreed on the reasons it had failed. Concord suffered from poor marketing, a high price point, and most critically, a lack of differentiation in an oversaturated genre.</p><p>Start with the marketing. According to Piscatella, Sony dropped the ball on this front, badly damaging its ability to build momentum ahead of release. He said it suffered from “low awareness and purchase intent among video game players” and indicated that Circana’s PlayerPulse was showing that as of July, only a very small percentage of players were even aware Concord existed to begin with. Retail promotion was limited, “with just a handful of web placements across GameStop, Best Buy, Target, Walmart and the PlayStation Store.” Joost van Dreunen, NYU Stern professor and <a href="https://superjoost.net/about" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>author of the SuperJoost newsletter</u></a>, agreed, saying that “while there has been trailers and some gameplay reveals for Concord, pre-launch promotion for the game appears to have been relatively limited.” </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>At $40, Concord also suffered from what was considered to be an overly high price point given that its main competitors are free-to-play. As Carless pointed out, high-skill multiplayer shooters can struggle to gain traction, because players will only “shift” their preferred game if all their friends also agree to do so. Even then, players may be reluctant due to sunk cost fallacy around the various cosmetics and other perks they’ve picked up on their preferred game over time. This is also a problem, he says, for content creators, who won’t know in advance if their audiences will be interested in a new game they’re considering switching to.</p><p>For free-to-play games, players can at least jump in, try something out, and see if it sticks without a high commitment cost. But with Concord, the $40 price makes players unlikely to give it a shot in the first place, and van Dreunen adds that this is even less likely near the end of a console cycle when players are more reluctant than usual to take a chance on new games.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>Overall the hero shooter market is already well served.</p></div><p>“A tight-knit group of players might be willing to take a chance on a new game for free, but paying $40 is a big ask in today’s macroeconomic climate,” Elliott observed. “Launching Concord as a premium game limited its audience numbers and user acquisition. The more people who play a game, the more appealing it is. Network effects are crucial for building a healthy, engaged ecosystem. </p><p>“Concord should have launched free-to-play – or at least as part of the PlayStation Plus subscription – to have a fighting chance in its overcrowded genre. It is not too late for this to happen, of course, but the damage might have already been done. First impressions matter.”</p><p>Every analyst I spoke to also hammered home what may be Concord’s biggest problem: lack of differentiation. Piers Harding-Rolls of Ampere Analysis noted that when Concord started development, Sony was banking on the then-hot trend of multiplayer shooters such as Overwatch. But in the years since, other studios made the same bet, many to great success.</p><p>“Since then, we’ve had a few more big budget hero shooters come to market – Apex Legends, Valorant and Overwatch 2 – each with their unique gameplay attributes,” said Harding-Rolls. “All three of these games are played by millions of gamers every month and dominate this category. Concord’s gunplay compares most closely to Overwatch 2 and overall the hero shooter market is already well served with a collection of very strong free-to-play titles.”</p><p>It also doesn’t help that Concord released on August 23, 2024, just three days after Black Myth: Wukong. Though the two games are significantly different, it’s hard to deny that the launch of the former overshadowed the latter in terms of marketing, hype, and sales. For what it’s worth, <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/concord-gets-new-cinematic-and-gameplay-trailer-and-a-release-date-state-of-play-2024"><u>Concord’s release date</u></a> was announced five months after <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/black-myth-wukong-has-a-release-date-but-still-no-reply-to-reports-of-sexism-the-game-awards-2023"><u>Black Myth: Wukong’s</u></a>. For one reason or another, Sony did not opt to nudge the game out of its wake.</p><h2>What does this mean for Sony and live service games?</h2><p>I asked all the analysts I spoke to if this means live service is over, especially for Sony. Hardly, they all say – but this should serve as a reality check.</p><p>“Live service games have a high failure rate,” Deane said. “There are many reasons for that but the main one is because they rely on network effects. Sometimes a single-player game can have a slow launch but eventually find its way to success. But the clock is now ticking on Concord in a big way because unless the player counts pick up soon there’ll be nobody to play against. So even if you personally would like to give it a try, there’ll be nothing to play. But while the risks are big, so are the rewards. It’s no secret that many of the highest-earning games in the market today are live service games. According to our data, only about 16% of the total revenue of the games market now comes from traditional full-game sales. Publishers are going to keep chasing that 84%.”</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3>Concord Gameplay Screenshots</h3></div></output><p>As for Sony itself, Deane expects it will continue chasing live service. Helldivers 2, after all, was a huge hit earlier this year. “Though clearly they won’t want any more Concord-level disasters, if half of their forthcoming slate of live service games over the next few years succeed, that won’t be a bad result.”</p><p>Elliott agreed. “It only takes one big live-service win to generate billions upon billions in revenue and unlock new audiences – two things PlayStation very much wants right now, as the console business is facing growth challenges and reaching saturation. That said, I also expect some resources to be redirected to strategies that are working better for the company: PC launches and cross-media/transmedia, for example.”</p><p>Nevertheless, analysts suggested that Concord is a perfect example of the dangers of AAA companies chasing trends, especially with how long game development cycles have become. Elliott pointed out a growing list of failures in the space, even from major companies: BioWare’s Anthem, Crystal Dynamics’ Marvel’s Avengers, PlatinumGames’ Babylon’s fall. Some developers, he notes, have even canceled projects in advance, such as Sega with Hyenas or PlayStation’s The Last of Us Online.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>Sometimes everything that can go wrong does go wrong.</p></div><p>“Pivoting to live services is high-risk, high-reward venture, and the risk is heightening to levels that might not be worth it for many AAA console/PC publishers that aren’t already active in the space,” he said.</p><p>Concord’s failure has attracted attention due to the contrast between its status as a Sony first-party title in a popular genre with high production value, and the overwhelming cricket sounds that accompanied its launch. But the story of its failure is mundane. Sony, for whatever reason, chose not to market the game heavily enough to ensure players were aware of it. It chose to sell it at a premium price point despite all its serious competition going free-to-play. Had these factors been different, Concord might have stood a chance despite its relative lack of standout characteristics in an oversaturated genre. But even then, Concord was always fighting a difficult battle – a battle that will only get more fierce the more multiplayer shooters go to market in future years.</p><p>As Mat Piscatella summed up, “Sometimes everything that can go wrong does go wrong. Although it's quite rare to see everything go this wrong.”</p><p><em>Rebekah Valentine is a senior reporter for IGN. Got a story tip? Send it to rvalentine@ign.com.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Borderlands 4 Concept Art Revealed At PAX West 202]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/borderlands-4-concept-art-revealed-at-pax-west-202/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/borderlands-4-concept-art-revealed-at-pax-west-202.968898/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/borderlands-4-concept-art-revealed-at-pax-west-202/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>PAX West is currently underway, and the convention will end on September 3, 2024. Many developers and publishers gather at PAX West, including Gearbox Software, the developers responsible for the Borderlands franchise. At PAX West, Borderlands 4 details were revealed, albeit very vague. Those excited about the new Borderlands game got a glimpse at the concept art for <a href="https://wccftech.com/borderlands-4-officially-announced-for-2025/">Borderlands 4</a>, showcasing some of the new worlds players can expect to explore.</p>
<p>Four images were showcased at PAX West, all of which contrast with each other in some way. While most shared the same futuristic vibe in previous Borderlands games, one screenshot stood out in particular as quite different from the rest. In the screenshot below, while the area still looks relatively futuristic in places, it has a somewhat dated and industrial feel.</p>

<figure></figure>

<p>Borderlands fans have commented on the artwork <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/first-borderlands-4-concept-art-revealed-at-pax-west-showing-off-a-glimpse-of-its-new-worlds" target="_blank" rel="noopener">first posted on IGN</a>, saying that the art style reminds them of Borderlands: The Pre-Sequel. From what is seen in the art work, the mood overall seems a lot darker just by the color palette alone, suggesting that players are in for a dark and twisted tale.</p>
<p>At PAX West, Gearbox Studios spoke out a little bit more about Borderlands 4, saying that the small teaser trailer that fans saw at Gamescom was set to happen just seconds before the conclusion of Borderlands 3. It now seems possible that we might see some returning characters from Borderlands 3 with this new revelation.</p>
<p>Adam May, the Art Director behind Borderlands 4 described the concept art to the audience, "The Borderlands universe is super interesting and there is so much to get to play with. It is a post-apocalyptic world but in the distant future, so it's like high tech but lo-fi. It creates all kinds of interesting opportunities with what we can do with our tech, our weapons, our characters, and world in general."</p>
<p>With that statement being put out to the audience, it now begs whether it's some sort of alternate timeline to Borderlands 3, since the trailer was said to be seconds before the conclusion of the third game. It's a bit confusing to wrap your head around, and a lot of it is just down to pinpoint where this game could be in the timeline.</p>
<p>"I can't say much, but this has a lot to do with it here. A lot of the things we haven't had much chance to play with in the past is some of that high technology stuff," which is evidently seen through the concept art screenshots.</p>
<p>Borderlands 4 doesn't have an official release date at the moment, but it is slated for release sometime in 2025.</p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[First Borderlands 4 Concept Art Revealed at PAX West Showing Off a Glimpse of Its New Worlds]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/first-borderlands-4-concept-art-revealed-at-pax-west-showing-off-a-glimpse-of-its-new-worlds</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/first-borderlands-4-concept-art-revealed-at-pax-west-showing-off-a-glimpse-of-its-new-worlds.968883/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/first-borderlands-4-concept-art-revealed-at-pax-west-showing-off-a-glimpse-of-its-new-worlds<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">A better look at what Gearbox says is its "most diverse and beautiful game" ever.</h2></div><section><p>Gearbox Software <a href="https://www.twitch.tv/videos/2238145538" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>attended PAX West 2024</u></a> to reveal a collection of concept art and new details for its recently announced looter-shooter sequel, Borderlands 4.</p><p>Each shot highlights new foreign locations for players to explore while also not revealing too much about how the fourth Borderlands game will shake up the formula. If there’s one thing to take away from the concept art drop it’s that Gearbox wants to give players a variety of areas to loot and shoot through. One image shows a smokey, candle-lit room decorated with glowing blue lighting, while another shows a small neon town surrounded by snowy mountains. You can see some of what Borderlands 4 has in store in the gallery below.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3>Borderlands 4 Concept Art - PAX West 2024</h3></div></output><p>“The Borderlands universe is super interesting and there is so much to get to play with,” art director Adam May said when describing the concept images at PAX West. “It is a post-apocalyptic world but in the distant future, so it’s like high-tech but lo-fi. It creates all kinds of interesting opportunities with what we can do with tech, our weapons, our characters, and world in general.”</p><p>The Gearbox team teased even more at PAX West. For starters, the <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/borderlands-4-announced-with-teaser-trailer-at-opening-night-live-gamescom-2024"><u>Borderlands 4 teaser that was revealed at gamescom Opening Night Live</u></a> earlier this month is now confirmed to take place seconds following the conclusion of Borderlands 3’s story. With new parts of its universe to explore, the team has taken the opportunity to incorporate technology in ways that haven’t been touched on in the past.</p><p>“I can’t say much, but this has a lot to do with it here,” May said. “A lot of the things we haven’t had much of a chance to play with too much in the past is some of that high technology stuff.”</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>He continued, teasing that the Gearbox team got to play with more tech and color than ever before, calling Borderlands 4 “the most diverse and beautiful game we’ve ever made.” A Borderlands 4 release date has not been revealed, but it is expected to launch for PC, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series X | S sometime in 2025. Gearbox still has more work to do before revealing more, so in the meantime, be sure to catch up on <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/borderlands-4-teaser-trailer-contains-several-secrets-randy-pitchford-says-and-fans-are-on-the-hunt"><u>some of the more popular fan theories</u></a> that have spawned from that first teaser trailer.</p><p><em>Michael Cripe is a freelance contributor with IGN. He started writing in the industry in 2017 and is best known for his work at outlets such as The Pitch, The Escapist, OnlySP, and Gameranx.</em></p><p><em>Be sure to give him a follow on Twitter @MikeCripe.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[September’s Unmissable Game Releases]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/septembers-biggest-game-releases/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/september%E2%80%99s-unmissable-game-releases.968841/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/septembers-biggest-game-releases/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>We hope your wallet is ready because September’s biggest game releases are on the horizon, and there are a lot of them to sift through. Let’s look at the most exciting upcoming games of September, along with a handful of honorable mentions we think are also worth your time!</p>



<h2 id="h-upcoming-games-in-september-2024">Upcoming Games in September 2024</h2>



<p>At first glance, September looks like a fantastic month for the gaming community. We have countless indie projects finally launching after months or years of hype, alongside numerous high-profile releases. From space-based simulation games to previously console-exclusive titles, there’s a lot to play this month!</p>



<h3 id="h-star-trucker">Star Trucker</h3>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Star Trucker  - Date Reveal Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ue68N_CpVlM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<ul>
<li><strong>Release Date</strong>: September 3</li>



<li><strong>Platforms</strong>: PC, Xbox Series X|S</li>
</ul>



<p>In what felt like one of the most unique and surprising titles during Steam Next Fest, Star Trucker won us over with its science-fiction take on the truck simulator genre. Instead of hauling cargo from a small town in California to a hub in Texas, we’re roaming the stars in style, using a jet-powered truck cab that occasionally requires repairs. Oh, and it’s customizable. Star Trucker looks like it’ll shake up the transportation and hauling simulation community!</p>



<h3 id="h-the-casting-of-frank-stone">The Casting of Frank Stone</h3>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="The Casting of Frank Stone | Gameplay Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/O1xixINNd6I?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<ul>
<li><strong>Release Date</strong>: September 3</li>



<li><strong>Platforms</strong>: PC, PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X|S</li>
</ul>



<p>I genuinely didn’t expect the Dead by Daylight franchise to spawn multiple spin-offs, yet here we are, eagerly awaiting the first one from developer Supermassive Games. The studio, known for its choice-driven horror stories, such as The Quarry, is creating a vibrant and enthralling story-driven experience in The Casting of Frank Stone. It’s a horror game in which friends uncover the mystery surrounding an infamous serial killer.</p>



<h3 id="h-astro-bot">Astro Bot</h3>



<figure><p>
<iframe loading="lazy" title="Astro Bot - Launch Trailer | PS5 Games" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/unYFdcEjV9k?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<ul>
<li><strong>Release Date</strong>: September 6</li>



<li><strong>Platforms</strong>: PlayStation 5</li>
</ul>



<p>Utilizing the full power of the PlayStation 5 and its branding, Astro Bot launches us on an adventure spanning multiple levels and biomes, from jungles to volcanoes, as we unlock unique abilities and rescue lost crewmates. The PS5 exclusive features new powers and all-new enemies but retains its platforming mechanics that so many fell in love with. </p>



<h3 id="h-warhammer-40-000-space-marine-2">Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine 2</h3>



<figure><p>
<iframe loading="lazy" title="Warhammer 40k: Space Marine 2 - The Angels Of Death Cinematic Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/-vnbKeOFPrI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<ul>
<li><strong>Release Date</strong>: September 9</li>



<li><strong>Platforms</strong>: PC, PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X|S</li>
</ul>



<p>How much fan service can you fit into one game? All of it is the answer. Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine 2 lets us finally step into the up-armored boots of an Ultramarine, wielding various melee and ranged weapons, including the iconic Chainsword, Thunder Hammer, and Heavy Bolters, as we stomp, slash, and slay Tyranids across multiple planets. With a full single-player campaign, cooperative missions, and a PvP mode, there’s a lot to love about Space Marine 2!</p>



<h3 id="h-dead-rising-deluxe-remaster">Dead Rising Deluxe Remaster</h3>



<figure><p>
<iframe loading="lazy" title="Dead Rising Deluxe Remaster - Announcement Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/FIAiUWhxmrs?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<ul>
<li><strong>Release Date</strong>: September 18</li>



<li><strong>Platforms</strong>: PC, PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X|S</li>
</ul>



<p>Frank returns, albeit with a new voice actor, in the upcoming Dead Rising Deluxe Remaster. This remaster is more like a remake, with enhanced graphics, modern controls, quality-of-life features, and full voice acting across the board. But despite its monumental changes on the technical side of the spectrum, DRDR retains its core gameplay loop of infiltrating the Willamette Mall, rescuing civilians, and fighting psychopaths amid a zombie apocalypse!</p>



<h3 id="h-god-of-war-ragnarok">God of War: Ragnarok</h3>



<figure><p>
<iframe loading="lazy" title="God of War: Ragnarok - PC Announcement Trailer | State of Play 2024" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wSHZIckO8kw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<ul>
<li><strong>Release Date</strong>: September 19</li>



<li><strong>Platforms</strong>: PC</li>
</ul>



<p>God of War launching on PC was a most welcome surprise, but it left us eager for more. Thankfully, Sony enjoys money, so it wishes to capitalize on the PC gaming community by releasing more of its console-exclusive titles. In September, we’ll see God of War: Ragnarok, the continuation of Kratos and Atreus’ story. The PC port features unlocked frame rates, high-fidelity graphics, enhanced lightning, upscaling, and ultrawide support on day one!</p>



<h3 id="h-frostpunk-2">Frostpunk 2</h3>



<figure><p>
<iframe loading="lazy" title="Frostpunk 2 | Official Gameplay Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/PWlLOpqIYjA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<ul>
<li><strong>Release Date</strong>: September 20</li>



<li><strong>Platforms</strong>: PC</li>
</ul>



<p>To many, the survival city-building genre set itself apart with Frostpunk. The tough-as-nails strategy game tasked players with building a society following a worldwide calamity that froze the planet to its core. Now, the sequel aims to expand and enhance the formula that won over so many—us included—by introducing new mechanics and new settings and pushing the story forward by 30 years. It all goes down in September!</p>



<h2 id="h-honorable-mentions-for-september">Honorable Mentions for September</h2>



<p>Of course, the few we’ve listed here are just a snippet of what’s launching in September. There’s also:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Ale &amp; Tale Tavern</strong></li>



<li><strong>Selfloss</strong></li>



<li><strong>Mirthwood</strong></li>



<li><strong>Lollipop Chainsaw RePop</strong></li>



<li><strong>REKA</strong></li>



<li><strong>Chef RPG</strong></li>



<li><strong>Test Drive Unlimited Solar Crown</strong></li>



<li><strong>Wild Bastards</strong></li>



<li><strong>Final Fantasy 16</strong></li>



<li><strong>Tiny Glade</strong></li>



<li><strong>Disney Epic Mickey: Rebrushed</strong></li>



<li><strong>Greedfall 2: The Dying World</strong></li>
</ul>



<hr>



<p>September is jam-packed with hot new titles, but there’s one I’ve personally got my eye on. <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-forever-winter-early-access-september/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The Forever Winter launches into Early Access this month</a>!</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>
    
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pick Up This Outstanding, Delightfully Weird Shooter On Sale]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/control-playstation-sale-remedy-connected-universe-1851637320</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pick-up-this-outstanding-delightfully-weird-shooter-on-sale.968811/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/control-playstation-sale-remedy-connected-universe-1851637320<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Last year, Remedy released the survival horror title <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/alan-wake-2-review-control-max-payne-1850994952&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/alan-wake-2-review-control-max-payne-1850994952"><em>Alan Wake 2</em></a></span>, a sequel effectively 13 years in the making and the next step in the studio’s universe of connected games. Among them is <em>Control</em>, a brilliant and utterly weird third-person shooter focusing on the character <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/the-sexiness-of-control-1840876335&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/the-sexiness-of-control-1840876335">Jesse Faden </a></span>and her exploits with the Federal Bureau of Control, a government agency that tries to contain supernatural threats and phenomena. In <em>Control</em>, you face off against these forces inside of The Oldest House, a brutalist office building in the heart of New York whose unwieldy innards are constantly shifting.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196470" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="The Week In Games: Reignited Rivalries And More New Releases" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="123" data-playlist="196470,195922,196345" data-current="196470"><div><p>The Week In Games: Reignited Rivalries And More New Releases</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196470/196470_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196470/196470_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196470/196470_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196470/196470_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/22020.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>That is just the tippy top of the bizarre iceberg that is <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/control-the-kotaku-review-1837569523&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/control-the-kotaku-review-1837569523"><em>Control</em></a></span><em>, </em>which is not only celebrating a fifth anniversary this week but is also coincidentally on sale on PlayStation.<strong> If you care (and I do believe you should), you can nab yourself the ultimate edition of </strong><em><strong>Control </strong></em><strong>(including its very necessary DLCs) for $10.</strong><br></p><p>I say that these are necessary because <em>Control </em>isn’t just tangentially connected to <em>Alan Wake </em>and the universe that Remedy is building. It and its supplementary material (as well as <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/surprise-two-more-control-games-are-in-the-works-1847196296&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/surprise-two-more-control-games-are-in-the-works-1847196296">the sequel and multiplayer spinoff</a></span> that are on the way) are quintessential to understanding the connectedness of it all. You get a much fuller picture of the scope of things by first playing <em>Control</em>, which outlines a lot of the concepts, like Altered World Events and Objects of Power, that factor into <em>Alan Wake 2</em> quite heavily. It’s like a kind of side-sequel to the first <em>Alan Wake</em>, providing a wider window into the larger world that it only teased and connecting countless dots in the interim.</p><p>Beyond its role as connective tissue, <em>Control </em>is also its own loving ode to all things weird. The FBC is basically just <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SCP_Foundation&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SCP_Foundation" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">the SCP Foundation</a></span>, which has its own basis in the history of internet creepypasta and urban myths. It is a world where the weirdo monsters we created as children are real and where cursed objects do exist. Some, like the floppy disk, grant blessings like the ability of telekinesis. Others, like a rubber duck, might dart around and prove to be a simple nuisance. And then there are fridges that might contain powerful beings beyond comprehension unless someone maintains eye contact with it at all times.</p><p>Much like the things it attempts to contain, the FBC’s headquarters is impossible to pin down. Unless you know to look for it, or are a particularly powerful parautilitarian, you can’t actually find and enter the Oldest House. Once you’re there, there’s no guarantee you won’t get lost within its walls either. That, or die in one of its “shifts” that drastically changes the layout of whole floors and departments. </p><p>All the while, the Oldest House is simultaneously the most aggressively mundane office building. Everywhere you look, concrete walls are blanketed by the glow of sterile white office lights. Typical desks and office chairs dot cubicles and offices that you explore. Little boxes all the same as far as the eye can see. But despite that, the environment is still suffused with an uneasy, sometimes menacing, feeling. One office will have <em>way</em> <em>too many</em> post-it notes adorning its surfaces, while a hallway in another wing of the building will seemingly spiral into nothingness. Bodies of office employees hang suspended in the air. And for all of the bland office space, there are jaw-dropping and impossible vistas to be seen in places like the Black Rock Quarry, or the very bottom of the Oldest House.<br></p><p>The environment does a lot of talking in <em>Control</em>. Whole stories can be gleaned from the layout of things, but <em>Control </em>also<em> </em><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/fiddlecub/status/1828741627365429748&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/fiddlecub/status/1828741627365429748" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">features <em>a lot </em>of notes</a></span>, often shared between workers in departments that expertly build out and add further mystique to the game’s fiction. And then <em>Control </em>does one of my favorite things that only a game can do, and allows you to occasionally explore and <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/mysteries-are-the-heart-of-control-1844900378&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/mysteries-are-the-heart-of-control-1844900378">uncover the mysteries</a></span> it builds up in the background of the central thrust of the story. Reader, it rarely, if ever disappoints on this front.<br></p><p><em>Control</em>, down to its central weapon, is just endlessly intriguing and teeming with possibility. The Service Weapon, itself an Object of Power, can morph into all manner of firearms, including a pistol, a shotgun, and eventually even a kind of grenade launcher. In tandem with Jesse’s increasing range of abilities, such as levitation and a shield, it’s very easy to become this all-encompassing powerhouse. Maybe that’s what I really love about <em>Control. </em>Not the power fantasy of it all, but how impossible it feels to fence in or nail down, how consistently and expertly it adapts different modes and forms that feel they can all breathe within <em>Control</em>’s seemingly limitless possibilities.</p><p><em>Control</em> is, simply put, one of the most special games of the last generation. Despite struggling a bit out the door, it eventually found its audience and has already grown into a title worthy of reverence. If you don’t already know what’s up, do yourself a favor and block off some time to pick up <em>Control </em>and just sink beneath its surface. You will not regret the time you’ll spend uncovering what the Oldest House has to hide.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Squirrel with a Gun Review]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/squirrel-with-a-gun-review</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/squirrel-with-a-gun-review.968808/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/squirrel-with-a-gun-review<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">This amusing sandbox game has a lot of heart, but is every bit as shallow and short-lived as its goofy premise seems.</h2></div><div><section><p>Few premises are more immediately appealing than Squirrel with a Gun’s. A sandbox game where you control a gun-toting rodent and wreak havoc on the local population? Yes, please! And that premise certainly delivers to some extent, with quite a few laugh-out-loud funny moments right out the gate and a lot of enjoyment to be found in the goofy adventure’s opening hours. But this wacky Sciuridae simulator isn’t sitting on a stockpile of comedic acorns, instead stuffing its cheeks with silly gags all in one go, before finding its stores empty as the winter season fast approaches. Compounding that short-lived mirth are fairly serious performance issues, including regular crashes that made me repeat long stretches, which really took the wind out of my furry wings. Squirrel with a Gun still offers a couple hours of amusing sandbox goofiness, and I eagerly await a more fleshed out sequel in the same vein as <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/goat-simulator-3-review">Goat Simulator 3</a>, but this first shot misses the target once the joke has run its course.</p><p>Like <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2019/09/20/untitled-goose-game-review">Untitled Goose Game</a> and <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2014/04/24/octodad-dadliest-catch-ps4-review">Octodad: Dadliest Catch</a> before it, Squirrel with a Gun is a zany sandbox game where you play a troublemaking animal who becomes a real problem for the humans around them. After obtaining a pistol from a clumsy government spook, you’re let loose on a suburban community to rob people at gunpoint, wantonly destroy personal property, and exercise your Second Amendment right to blast fools in the face like the bloodthirsty little varmint you are. It’s a good time! But that dopey bit is exactly as shallow as it sounds, and though it only took me four hours to roll credits, it took even less time for the laughs to peter out.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3>Squirrel with a Gun Gallery</h3></div></output><p>Fighting as a squirrel packing heat proves pretty hollow. You’ll use pistols, rifles, and even grenade launchers to send <a href="https://www.ign.com/movies/franchise/the-matrix"><u>Agent Smith</u></a>-looking sons of a gun to their doom – and they mostly stand around and let you do so while putting up very little resistance. They’re the only enemies to be found here, and they all go down in a couple of shots. One highlight is when you stun enemies and are then able to kill them off with a special finishing move, like peppering an enemy with lead from an uzi or swatting their grasping hands away while you perform gunjitsu like a furry <a href="https://www.ign.com/movies/franchise/john-wick"><u>John Wick</u></a>. Unfortunately, there’s only one of these animations for each weapon, so the novelty runs out fairly quickly. There isn’t much to combat beyond these basics, and each weapon feels like just another indistinctive piece in the arsenal in a matter of seconds.</p><p>There are two boss fights to shake things up, however, where you take on giant military vehicles, like a tank. These encounters are quick sequences where you shoot at glowing spots and whittle down a health bar, which doesn’t provide much of a challenge, but they are at least a nice change of pace and have a few gags that made me smile. If more stuff like this made it into the story, it might have gone a long way to extend my enjoyment, but like everything else in this brief adventure, these antics are fleeting.</p><p>The puzzle-platforming, on the other hand, is much more satisfying. Firing your weapons as a means of double-jumping or otherwise propelling yourself into the air to overcome platforming challenges is far more interesting than any of the combat in Squirrel with a Gun. The submachine gun is a great way to keep yourself airborne for extended periods of time while crossing gaps, but nothing beats the rocket launcher in terms of pure height – it sends you sailing into the air to land (mostly) safely on faraway platforms. None of the platforming is particularly tricky, but making your fluffy avatar sail from place to place doesn’t get old nearly as quickly as the rest of the gameplay.</p><p>Unfortunately, Squirrel with a Gun’s good times are prone to interruption by technical issues that proved quite problematic, even during its brief runtime. I found myself staring at a frozen screen more than five times in as many hours, losing a good chunk of progress in the process, and was forced to repeat entire sections. By the end, I got into the fear-driven habit of rushing over to the static save points that can be found in each area – and a good thing too, because crashes seemed to happen more frequently in the back half of the adventure. And that’s not the only issue I ran into, either: One cutscene triggered and forgot to add the squirrel where he’s supposed to go, which broke everything and forced me to reset, and there were several times where my tiny buddy passed through geometry when moving at high speeds and sent me tumbling to the ground, which forced me to repeat certain platforming sections. Thankfully, Squirrel with a Gun already embraces a certain kind of chaotic energy, so the occasional goofy glitch isn’t the end of the world. But it did make some of the otherwise entertaining sections lose some of their luster once I had to replay them a third time in the wake of a crash.</p></section><div data-cy="verdict"><h3>Verdict</h3><p>Squirrel with a Gun is an awesome, immediately charming idea with legs as short as its fluffy protagonist. While platforming around by firing off weapons and causing mayhem in the small sandbox areas yields plenty of enjoyable moments, shallow combat, numerous technical issues, and short runtime left me wanting more. Even the over-the-top boss fights, which are definitely a high point in the zany adventure, come to an end all too quickly and are in short supply. I still adore this violent rodent and have high hopes for a sequel that’s bigger, more fleshed out, and less prone to crashing, but this first shot leaves a fair bit to be desired.</p></div></div><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3><div><h3 data-cy="object-review-title">Squirrel with a Gun Review</h3><div><p>okay</p><p>Squirrel with a Gun is a uniquely amusing sandbox game, but it’s as shallow and short-lived as its goofy premise seems.</p><a href="https://www.ign.com/person/Tieguytravis" title="Travis Northup"><span></span><figcaption><p>Travis Northup</p></figcaption></a></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[IGN Is Your Ultimate Destination for Star Wars Outlaws]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/ign-is-your-ultimate-destination-for-star-wars-outlaws</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ign-is-your-ultimate-destination-for-star-wars-outlaws.968805/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/ign-is-your-ultimate-destination-for-star-wars-outlaws<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Explore the galaxy like never before.</h2></div><div><section><p>Star Wars Outlaws is one of the biggest gaming releases of 2024, and IGN is your ultimate destination for the game. Whether you're looking for guides to assist your journey through each of the massive planets or for a review to determine if you're going to pick up the game, we've got you covered.</p><h3>Detailed Map Genie Maps for Each Planet</h3><div id="206556" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p><h3>Map Genie</h3></p><div><p>Explore Toshara, Tatooine, Kijimi, and Akiva with Map Genie to never miss a quest, collectible, or POI.</p></div></div><p>The IGN team has Map Genie maps live for each planet in the game, ensuring you won't miss a collectible or side quest in your playthrough! These maps will continue to be updated throughout the next week, but dozens of collectibles are already live across four planets!</p><h3>Leading Game Help</h3><p>IGN is your go-to for all the latest guides on Star Wars Outlaws, from a <a href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/star-wars-outlaws/Walkthrough">complete walkthrough</a> to tips on <a href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/star-wars-outlaws/Kessel_Sabacc_-_How_to_Play_and_Rewards">Kessel Sabacc</a>. Check out some of our available tips to help you get started below:</p><ul data-cy="list"><li><a href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/star-wars-outlaws/How_to_Earn_Credits_(Money)_Fast">How to Earn Credits (Money) Fast</a></li><li><a href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/star-wars-outlaws/Secrets_and_Easter_Eggs">Star Wars Outlaws Secrets and Easter Eggs</a></li><li><a href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/star-wars-outlaws/All_Outfit_Sets">All Outfit Sets</a></li></ul><p>Be sure to stay tuned for more, as we'll be updating and adding new guides well past launch day!</p><h3>Star Wars Outlaws - The IGN Review</h3><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>IGN Video Producer <a href="https://www.ign.com/person/tristan_ign_au">Tristan Ogilvie</a> reviewed Star Wars Outlaws, giving the game <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/star-wars-outlaws-review">a 7/10</a>. In our review, he stated, "It’s ironic that Kay’s ship is called the Trailblazer, since there’s actually not a whole lot of ideas in Star Wars Outlaws that haven’t been done before in other action and open-world adventures. Instead, it’s quite like the Millenium Falcon: a bucket of bolts held together with repurposed parts and prone to breaking down, but at its best it’s more than capable of jolting your pleasure centres into Star Wars fan hyperspace."</p><h3>More Star Wars: Outlaws Content on IGN</h3><p>Beyond game help, Map Genie, and our review, IGN has even more Star Wars Outlaws coverage available now and on the way! Our <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/how-star-wars-outlaws-fulfills-the-starship-fantasy-ign-first">IGNFirst coverage</a> dives deep into the game with exclusive commentary from the developers at Ubisoft Massive. Moving forward, we'll also have plenty of breakdowns surrounding the game's biggest features, analysis on the story, and all kinds of news surrounding the upcoming DLC. </p><h3>Star Wars Collection at IGN Store</h3><p>Last but not least, be sure to check out our Star Wars Collection at IGN Store. Whether you're in the market for a new shirt, figure, or even hot sauce, there's dozens of Star Wars-themed items available now. </p><div><div id="206517" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p><h3>STAR WARS Dark Side Hot Sauce by TRUFF</h3></p></div><div id="206518" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p><h3>Star Wars - Comic Caper - T-Shirt</h3></p></div><div id="206519" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p><h3>Star Wars: The Mandalorian - This Is The Bouquet Grogu - Button Down</h3></p></div></div></section><div><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Aug 30, 2024 7:10 pm</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Disney Epic Mickey: Rebrushed Feels Just as Vibrant As Ever in 2024]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/disney-epic-mickey-rebrushed-feels-just-as-vibrant-as-ever-in-2024</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/disney-epic-mickey-rebrushed-feels-just-as-vibrant-as-ever-in-2024.968802/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/disney-epic-mickey-rebrushed-feels-just-as-vibrant-as-ever-in-2024<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Warren Spector’s love letter to Disney was already great, but this faithful remake looks to fix its biggest flaws.</h2></div><section><p>There’s something… well… magical about 2010’s Wii-exclusive Epic Mickey getting a remake in 2024. As those who played the original know, the game itself is a quest through a realm of forgotten Disney characters and attractions called the Wasteland and, after playing a demo of Disney Epic Mickey: Rebrushed at D23, I’m more confident than ever that this adventure with an impressive new coat of paint will thankfully not be lost to the unforgiving hands of time, like some that sadly came before it.</p><p>What impressed me the most about Disney Epic Mickey: Rebrushed is how much it looks and, perhaps most importantly, feels like a 2024 game. In our original Epic Mickey review, we gave it an 8/10 and said that this ‘Great’ game was held back by a camera and control system that were “flawed to a point where the larger experience becomes damaged.” None of those issues were present in what I played of the remake and it felt like an absolute joy to play. Oh, and it running at a smooth 60FPS didn’t hurt its case either.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>Mickey himself has also improved in the 14 years since he first entered the Wasteland, as he can now sprint, dash, and ground pound around the gorgeous-yet-dark world that is very much like a twisted version of Disneyland. These new traversal additions are the Minnie to Mickey’s paint brush abilities, and they dance in a way that is just as beautiful as Disney Parks’ best nighttime spectaculars. </p><p>I just had the biggest smile on my face as I jumped around the opening level of Disney Epic Mickey: Rebrushed and didn’t have to deal with the frustrating motion and camera controls of the Wii version, leaving me to paint and thin with ease while feeling so much more agile. The best remakes implement changes that seem almost preposterous to think they were never there, and these fit that bill. </p><h3>A Remake in Every Sense of the Word</h3><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>As for the visuals of Disney Epic Mickey: Rebrushed, they are another highlight in large part to remake developer Purple Lamp’s decision to not only rebuild the whole game with the original assets so it was playable from start to finish, but to then remake every asset from scratch and do it all over again. This dedication appears to have been worth it, as the Wasteland is now a place I wish I could explore forever.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>Fans will be able to look forward to three times as many collectibles to find, from pins to film reels to artwork and so much more. </p></div><p>From the inky black paint-like blot floating off Mickey as he runs and jumps to the colors and sharpness of the alternate flying elephant  and tea cup attractions, Disney Epic Mickey: Rebrushed takes place in a world that I can just watch and listen to a subtle and haunting version of ‘Once Upon a Dream’ and still feel like I had a worthy play session. </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>The side-scrolling, 2D projector stages that take Mickey from one level to another also look so much better and, in one of the new additions to Disney Epic Mickey: Rebrushed, you can go back and play through them again as you wish in the game’s Main Street Cinema. This means you can replay levels based on such classic Mickey cartoons as Steamboat Willie, Mickey and the Beanstalk, and more as you please. </p><p>Now, there isn’t a ton new in Disney Epic Mickey: Rebrushed as it is a very faithful remake, but fans will be able to look forward to three times as many collectibles to find, from pins to film reels to artwork and so much more. The team also told me there will be some new puzzles to solve, but that’s really about it.</p><p>So, if you didn’t love the story or painting gameplay or the first interaction between Mickey Mouse and Oswald the Lucky Rabbit, these modern upgrades may not be enough to sway you. However, like me, if you saw in the original something that was held back from greatness on the Wii - or you never had a Wii and just love Disney and Mickey - this is one adventure you should keep an eye on.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>I’ll be very curious to see how the rest of the game holds up, as I was only able to play that opening level, but what I experienced left such an impression on me that it’s making September 24 a whole lot harder to wait for. </p><p>To end, I just wanted to share a few words from my chat with game design legend Warren Spector, the creative director on the original who also consulted on Rebrushed, as he sums up why Epic Mickey is one the games he is “most proud of.” High praise from the creator of Deus Ex and System Shock.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>“I wanted to make a game for families that parents and children could play together, that kids could teach their parents how to play because that's the way it would work, not the other way around.”</p></div><p>“The thing that I love the most about this game is that it touched people emotionally,” Spector said. “I wanted to make a game for families that parents and children could play together, that kids could teach their parents how to play because that's the way it would work, not the other way around.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>“Additionally, one of the things that characterizes Disney is that things last. They have lasting value. How many 1937 films are people still watching today that weren't made by Walt Disney? So, the idea that a game had that kind of impact and longevity is really special. But the biggest thing, really the biggest thing, is when people come up to me as they have at D23 and say, ‘I played this game as a child and now I get to play it with my child.’ That brings tears to my eyes. It just shows the real power and potential of games to do more than I think most of us realize.”</p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[An Astro Bot Sequel May Already Be In The Works]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/atro-bot-platinum-trophy-sequel-or-dlc-1851637283</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/an-astro-bot-sequel-may-already-be-in-the-works.968784/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/atro-bot-platinum-trophy-sequel-or-dlc-1851637283<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="373cd92b09aa772543830445688270ef" data-recommend-id="image://373cd92b09aa772543830445688270ef" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="false" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Sony Interactive Entertainment</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="373cd92b09aa772543830445688270ef" data-recommend-id="image://373cd92b09aa772543830445688270ef" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>As far as games, September looks to be just as fruitful as August, with the month that was owned by <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/black-myth-wukong-steam-reviews-1851634466&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/black-myth-wukong-steam-reviews-1851634466"><em>Black Myth: Wukong</em></a></span> and <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/star-wars-outlaws-review-size-how-big-hours-xbox-ps5-pc-1851631123&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/star-wars-outlaws-review-size-how-big-hours-xbox-ps5-pc-1851631123"><em>Star Wars Outlaws</em></a></span> being followed by yet another hyped release in <em>Astro Bot</em>. And for those who can’t resist looking even further ahead, you may be in for a treat. It seems Team Asobi, the developer behind <em>Astro Bot</em>, is considering a sequel even before the first game launches worldwide. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196805" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="I Hate This FF7 Rebirth Character’s Whole Vibe" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="93" data-playlist="196805,195905,196646" data-current="196805"><div><p>I Hate This FF7 Rebirth Character’s Whole Vibe</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196805/196805_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196805/196805_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196805/196805_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196805/196805_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/22362.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>Over on X/Twitter, user <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/Genki_JPN/status/1829165000910602705?ref_src=twsrc%5Egoogle%7Ctwcamp%5Eserp%7Ctwgr%5Etweet&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/Genki_JPN/status/1829165000910602705?ref_src=twsrc%5Egoogle%7Ctwcamp%5Eserp%7Ctwgr%5Etweet" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@Genki_JPN</a></span> uncovered the game’s Platinum Trophy, which reads, “<strong>Earned all trophies. Well done, and see you in Astro’s next adventure</strong>.”</p><p>It’s important to note that a trophy description isn’t an official announcement or confirmation from the team regarding a sequel. This description could easily point toward DLC, a full-blown expansion pack, or even a crossover with another game such as <em>Fortnite</em>. (Let’s be honest. Everyone is doing a crossover with <em>Fortnite </em>these days.)<br></p><p>On the topic of <em>Astro Bot</em>, the team recently discussed the potential for a PC version but shut down the PlayStation VR2 hype. A PC release remains on the table so long as there is fan interest, so the studio asked everyone who wants one to voice their excitement online.<br></p><p>No matter what you think of the prospect of an <em>Astro Bot </em>sequel (even if you’re soulless enough to not want as many installments as we can get), we’ll likely see more of the lovable character in some capacity following the game’s launch in September. It’s just a matter of how much and how soon. </p><p>Stay tuned more PlayStation news, which includes the three free titles (<em>Harry Potter: Quidditch Champions</em>, <em>MLB The Show 24</em>, and <em>Little Nightmares II)</em>&nbsp;<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/harry-potter-quidditch-champions-free-ps-plus-september-1851634283&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/harry-potter-quidditch-champions-free-ps-plus-september-1851634283">coming to PS Plus next month</a></span>.</p><p>.</p><p>.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Darkest Dungeon II free Kingdoms update part one coming this year]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/08/30/darkest-dungeon-ii-free-kingdoms-update-part-one-coming-this-year/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/darkest-dungeon-ii-free-kingdoms-update-part-one-coming-this-year.968766/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/08/30/darkest-dungeon-ii-free-kingdoms-update-part-one-coming-this-year/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Darkest Dungeon II is getting a major campaign expansion for free called Kingdoms, alongside a paid DLC called Inhuman Bondage, and Red Hook Studios has released details about both. First off the paid DLC, Inhuman Bondage, will be coming in Q4 2024. This will add a new Hero who will have unique trinkets, weapons, palettes, and mechanics. It will also add a new region the size of the Sluice which will also add a new enemy faction and items.</p>



<p>The Kingdoms campaign will be released in three parts and the first of that is Hunger of the Beast Clan. This release will need players to protect the realm from a new enemy factions, which in this case are the beast men. Players will have to travel across the land to complete quests and upgrade the inns around the realm. Kingdoms will run parallel to the main Confessions campaign.</p>
<h2><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2023/07/31/darkest-dungeon-ii-review-highway-to-hell/">Darkest Dungeon II Review – Highway to Hell</a></h2>
<p>In our Darkest Dungeon II review, Steve said, <em>“Darkest Dungeon II is to be applauded for not resting on its laurels, instead opting to make significant changes from its predecessor. The style, challenge, and strategic brilliance remain and that is enough to make it stand out still. However, the focus on roguelike randomness and excessive grind does make this a very different experience and one that didn’t gel for me. If you have the patience to explore the rich detail of the mechanics and the stoicism to deal with the inevitable deaths and disappointments then this is a journey worth taking. Just don’t expect it to be a comfortable ride.”</em></p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://www.threads.net/@redhookstudios/post/C_Q-FQZSJWm/?xmt=AQGzp-IQ7gWdQW_lz0PKueU3IbRE5PBaujFwjoXBzKEZNg">Threads</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Castlevania Dominus Collection Is Already On Sale For 25% Off]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/castlevania-dominus-collection-is-already-on-sale-for-25-off/1100-6526214/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/castlevania-dominus-collection-is-already-on-sale-for-25-off.968763/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/castlevania-dominus-collection-is-already-on-sale-for-25-off/1100-6526214/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6526214">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>The newly released Castlevania Dominus Collection is the latest remaster of classic Castlevania games, and if you're looking for a monster-hunting fix on PC, Green Man Gaming has you covered. The retailer is offering <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fgreenmangaming.sjv.io%2Fc%2F1804712%2F1219987%2F15105%3FsubId1%3Dsubid_value%26u%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.greenmangaming.com%2Fgames%2Fcastlevania-dominus-collection-pc&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fcastlevania-dominus-collection-is-already-on-sale-for-25-off%2F1100-6526214%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Castlevania Dominus Collection for 25% off</a> its list price, knocking the cost down to $18.74 for four 2D Castlevania titles. If you grab this deal, you'll get a key to redeem on Steam, which is pretty cool considering Steam itself has the collection for the full $25 price.</p><p>Castlevania Dominus Collection includes three side-scrolling games that were originally released on the Nintendo DS: Castlevania: Dawn of Sorrow, Castlevania: Portrait of Ruin, and Castlevania: Order of Ecclesia. The ports bring all those games to a single screen, as opposed to the DS's dual screens for which they were designed, which means all three have been slightly redesigned to compensate. Map and inventory screens now appear on the right side, as opposed to the bottom screen on DS. Another notable change is Dawn of Sorrow's stylus drawing mechanic has been been adapted into quick-time events.</p><p>In addition to the three Nintendo DS Castlevanias, the Dominus Collection also includes a remaster of the first Castlevania arcade game, Haunted Castle. The port features a reworked version of the arcade game, as well as the option to play it in its original format.</p><p>Dominus Collection also adds a few quality-of-life improvements to all the games, like rewind features and save states.</p><p>This is actually the third Castlevania game collection as Konami has released old entries in the series that were only available on dated hardware. You can also snag the PC version of 2019's <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.tkqlhce.com%2Fclick-100770772-13797872%3Fsid%3Dsubid_value%26url%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.fanatical.com%2Fen%2Fgame%2Fcastlevania-anniversary-collection&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fcastlevania-dominus-collection-is-already-on-sale-for-25-off%2F1100-6526214%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Castlevania Anniversary Collection on Fanatical</a>, which knocks 20% off the list price, bringing the cost down to $15.74 from the usual tag of $20. The Anniversary Collection includes eight games: Castlevania, Castlevania II Simon's Quest, Castlevania III: Dracula's Curse, Super Castlevania IV, Castlevania The Adventure, Castlevania II Belmont's Revent, Castlevania Bloodlines, and Kid Dracula. It also packs in the ebook History of Castlevania - Book of the Crescent Moon, which documents the franchise's development history.</p><p>The Dominus Collection is slated to get a physical release with multiple cover options from Limited Run Games, and preorders will be available in September. You can also get physical additions of the Castlevania Anniversary Collection and Konami's other re-release of Castlevania games, Castlevania Advance Collection, on Amazon, some of which offer alternative cover art. Check out the list below. Fair warning: Many of these physical editions are quite expensive, as they are out of print and sold by third parties.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Castlevania-Anniversary-Collection-Limited-Nintendo-Switch/dp/B09ML8N2K6?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Castlevania Anniversary Collection (Switch)</a></li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Castlevania-Collection-Advanced-Limited-Run/dp/B0D14WQVX2?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Castlevania Advance Collection - Advanced Edition (Switch)</a></li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Castlevania-Advance-Collection-Advanced-Limited/dp/B0D14WKWL1?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Castlevania Advance Collection - Advanced Edition (PS4)</a></li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Castlevania-Advance-Collection-Advanced-Limited-Xbox/dp/B0D3JGG6MB?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Castlevania Advance Collection - Advanced Edition (Xbox One)</a></li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Castlevania-Advance-Collection-Sorrow-Limited/dp/B0CWP6Z6NY?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Castlevania Advance Collection - Classic Edition - Aria of Sorrow Cover (PS4)</a></li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Castlevania-Advance-Collection-Sorrow-Cover-Limited/dp/B0CZ2TRQ5S?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Castlevania Advance Collection - Classic Edition - Aria of Sorrow Cover (Xbox One)</a></li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Castlevania-Advance-Collection-Classic-Circle/dp/B0CWP883FS?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Castlevania Advance Collection - Classic Edition - Circle of the Moon Cover (Switch)</a></li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Castlevania-Advance-Collection-Circle-Cover-Limited/dp/B0CZ2QD42B?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Castlevania Advance Collection - Classic Edition - Circle of the Moon Cover (Xbox One)</a></li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Castlevania-Advance-Collection-Classic-Dracula/dp/B0CQBF61X2?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Castlevania Advance Collection - Classic Edition - Dracula X Cover (Switch)</a></li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Castlevania-Advance-Collection-Playstation-Dracula/dp/B0CQB5H595?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Castlevania Advance Collection - Classic Edition - Dracula X Cover (PS4)</a></li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Castlevania-Advance-Collection-Classic-Dissonance/dp/B0CQ7MFKDW?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Castlevania Advance Collection - Classic Edition - Harmony of Dissonance Cover (Switch)</a></li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Castlevania-Advance-Collection-Playstation-Dissonance-4/dp/B0CQC32JKF?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Castlevania Advance Collection - Classic Edition - Harmony of Dissonance Cover (PS4)</a></li></ul><p><em>Disclosure: GameSpot and Fanatical are both owned by Fandom.</em></p><div data-embed-type="pinbox" data-ref-id="4304">  <ul>                              <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/berserk-the-complete-1997-tv-series-is-only-37-at-amazon-best-price-yet/1100-6524954/">Berserk: The Complete 1997 TV Series Is Only $37 At Amazon, Best Price Yet</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/astro-bot-ps5-dualsense-controller-preorder/1100-6525376/">Astro Bot PS5 Controller Preorders Restocked At Walmart</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/star-wars-the-skywalker-saga-complete-digital-collection-is-only-20-at-amazon/1100-6526122/">Star Wars: The Skywalker Saga Complete Digital Collection Is Only $20 At Amazon</a></li>                          <li>         <span>+ Show More More Gaming, Tech, and Entertainment Deals &amp; Preorders Links (5)</span>       </li>          <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/lego-atari-2600-gets-huge-price-cut-at-best-buy/1100-6520830/">Lego Atari 2600 Gets Huge Price Cut At Best Buy</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/star-wars-outlaws-preorder-guide/1100-6522523/">Star Wars Outlaws Preorders - Where To Find The Best Bonuses</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/buy-two-get-one-free-nintendo-switch-games-and-preorders-my-best-buy-members/1100-6525928/">B2G1 Free All Nintendo Switch Games - Zelda: Echoes Of Wisdom, Mario &amp; Luigi, And More Preorders</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/dragon-age-the-veilguard-preorder-guide/1100-6525830/">Dragon Age: The Veilguard Collector's Edition Preorders Live Now</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/doom-anthology-preorders-quakecon-2024/1100-6525656/">Doom Anthology Preorders Are Live - Comes With 6 Games, Steelbook Case, And Replica BFG</a></li>   </ul> </div>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Warhammer 40K Space Marine 2 Q&A with Tim Willits – ‘We Have a Game That Will Exceed Expectations’]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/warhammer-40k-space-marine-2-qa-with-tim-willits-we-have-a-game-that-will-exceed-expectations/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/warhammer-40k-space-marine-2-q-a-with-tim-willits-%E2%80%93-%E2%80%98we-have-a-game-that-will-exceed-expectations%E2%80%99.968745/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/warhammer-40k-space-marine-2-qa-with-tim-willits-we-have-a-game-that-will-exceed-expectations/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>At Gamescom 2024, I had the amazing opportunity to speak with veteran developer Tim Willits about Warhammer 40K Space Marine 2, Saber Interactive, and the industry as a whole. Willits worked at id Software for 24 years, eventually becoming Studio Director. He left the Texan developer in July 2019 and <a href="https://wccftech.com/ex-id-software-studio-director-tim-willits-joins-saber-interactive-as-chief-creative-officer/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">became</a> Chief Creative Officer at Saber Interactive only about a month later.</p>
<p>Of course, the main focus of our chat was the impending launch of Warhammer 40K Space Marine 2 (due on September 9, with a full year of post-launch roadmap already <a href="https://wccftech.com/warhammer-40k-space-marine-2-reveals-first-year-of-post-launch-support/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">revealed</a>), but we also discussed ongoing issues within the industry and how Saber is tackling those challenges. Keep scrolling to read a very interesting conversation.</p>
<p><iframe title="Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine 2 - The Angels Of Death" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/buT5yuGwg8s?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p><strong>With Space Marine 2, you are taking a beloved game and finally making a sequel around a decade later. Are you feeling the pressure of the fans?</strong></p>
<p>Yes. The Warhammer 40K franchise has been around for 45 years now, and millions of people love the franchise in itself. The first game was very popular. But I also want to say that if you, as a fan or as an action gamer, have never played the first game, don't worry about that. You can start with Space Marine 2 and it's a complete game. It's actually difficult to play the first game now because it's only on Steam.</p>
<p>There is an expectation from Warhammer 40K fans that we treat the universe with respect and that we get things correct. Then there's an expectation from fans of the first game, as well as just fans of Saber and action games. So yes, the expectations are very high, but I believe that we have a game that will exceed those expectations. We have a very dense game with a campaign mode that you can play by yourself or with two friends. We have our PvE missions where the story kind of runs parallel to the campaign, and then we have a full 6v6 PvP mode with three game modes, so it's a lot to offer. It's all wrapped together in our Saber proprietary technology with the Swarm tech and AI director, so we believe we are delivering the true ultimate Space Marine experience.</p>
<p><strong>How long did it take to make this game?</strong></p>
<p>Games always take a long time nowadays. About four years or so in this case, but we're very proud of where it is now. We're very happy with our work, and the people who played the preview were happy. Preorders are great. Right now, what we're focused on is September 9, you know, making sure that the servers are up and running for everyone, making sure that any issues are ironed up, but everything's looking good; it's all green lights. The game is fun and solid, so yeah, I'm excited about the launch.</p>
<p><strong>I believe the game was originally meant to come out in late 2023. Can you share what were the reasons behind this nine-month delay and what did you improve during this additional time?</strong></p>
<p>We just needed more time to polish it. You know that old saying a game is only late until it ships, but a bad game is bad forever. We wanted to focus on making sure that every component, the single player campaign and the PvE co-op mode, all those were solid.</p>
<p>There's a lot to this game and I feel that players will feel good regarding value and content. When you have all those systems, you have progression, and you have multiplayer, sometimes things take longer to get right, but I'm glad that we took the time we needed to make sure that we got it correct because Warhammer 40K fans want it correct. If we screwed something up, they would be mad, you know, and so we really wanted to honor the franchise, we wanted to respect the universe, and we wanted to make the game that people want to play.</p>
<p><strong>You worked closely with Games Workshop, right?</strong></p>
<p>Yes, they were a great partner. Everything had to be approved, from a small insignia to iconography, dialogue, etc. But they were great to work with and helped us every step of the way, so it was a real partnership.</p>
<p><strong>I guess that includes the storyline.</strong></p>
<p>Definitely. Our storyline with Titus - did you play the original?</p>
<p><strong>Not much.</strong></p>
<p>Okay, which is fine because, again, like I said, you don't have to play the first one.</p>
<p><strong>I know Titus, the protagonist, was demoted at the end of the first game.</strong></p>
<p>Yes, and then he spent 200 years in Deathwatch. This is kind of a fresh start for him, but we tried to add more personality and emotions into his story and his relationship with his squadmates and how they feel about him. He needs to win their trust while also saving the universe, so it is more than just a run-and-gun game. Titus's story is an important part of the experience.</p>
<p><strong>Especially because nowadays gamers want more. They're not just fine with shooting, like in the days of the original DOOM.</strong></p>
<p>Yes. It's important to note that the Warhammer 40K universe has been an inspiration for so many video games throughout the last decades. Just look at the original DOOM space marine; what does he look like? Look at the chain sword in Gears - where did that come from? Look at things like the Power Armor in Fallout. That looks a lot like a Space Marine. This IP has influenced many games, so I hope gamers who may be younger or may not understand the 40K universe can look at this and understand how effective it is.</p>
<p><strong>Speaking of the storyline, something I noticed while playing the preview is that one of Titus's squadmates is very confrontational with him.</strong></p>
<p>Yes, Gadriel and Chairon. Yes, he gets a little whiny, and I want to punch him, but yes, he's like, "What is up with you?" There's an event in the game between Titus and him, but it is interesting to see how that plays out.</p>
<p><strong>Based on your estimates, how long is the campaign going to be?</strong></p>
<p>It took me 12 hours to complete it, but it all depends on how you play it, on the difficulty, whether you are with your human buddies or by yourself, etc.</p>
<figure><figcaption>'We have plans to add more classes to the multiplayer modes after launch.'</figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>The PvE co-op Operations mode basically continues the story of the campaign, right?</strong></p>
<p>Yes. When you play through the campaign, there are times when other Space Marine squads go off and do other important missions in the big storyline, so it's like there's one mission where you have to send a signal, and the defenses have to be knocked out, and you hear that there's a squad doing that. Well, when you play PvE Operations, you're that squad. The battle is so big and there's so much going on that we've engineered these co-op missions to fit into the story and make you feel part of the bigger conflict.</p>
<p><strong>I know you have a class system for the multiplayer modes. Can you talk about that?</strong></p>
<p>Indeed. Are you familiar with World War Z? It's a little similar. Our game director, Dmitry Grigorenko, was the Game Director on World War Z, and he's very good at progression, class identities, and attributes. As you play, even in PvE, as you progress, you unlock different classes and you can earn experience. You can use some of that experience to upgrade your characters even in PvP, so it's like World War Z, where you have things like the Assault class, the Heavy class, and the Support class. We have Warhammer 40K names for them, but you can pick one that you like that fits your style and then you can you can apply your experience to those classes.</p>
<p><strong>Okay. How deep is the progression for each class?</strong></p>
<p>It's deep. World War Z was deep. I don't have the numbers off the top of my head, but I feel that players will be happy. Like World War Z, we will have updates where we will expand classes, weapons, and game modes, all for free.</p>
<p><strong>Do you have plans to add new classes to Space Marine 2 post-launch?</strong></p>
<p>Yes, we have plans for it. There will be new stuff for everything.</p>
<p><strong>Is there some sort of randomness attached to the co-op mode to keep things interesting?</strong></p>
<p>Yes. The game knows that you've played those missions before, and if you play them again, you can have different enemies, so you may play a mission, and then all of a sudden, Chaos Marines show up. We do add variety to that. It comes back to our AI Director, which is a key component in our <a href="https://www.pcgamingwiki.com/wiki/Engine:Swarm_Engine" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Swarm Engine</a>. We have the Swarm Deck, which controls the actions of the Swarms of Tyranids. When the Swarm breaks and each Tyranid starts to come at you, then the AI Director kicks in and it understands the state of the battles.</p>
<p>It can bring in heavies, and it can bring in ranged attack Tyranids. As a Space Marine, you are the ultimate killing machine. You are plowing through these Tyranids, but at some point, you start to feel overwhelmed, and you're fighting and fighting, and then you just finally make it through with barely enough armor left to survive.&nbsp;But you've done it, and that is all due to this very advanced AI director that helps kind of orchestrate those battles.</p>
<p><strong>Are the class skills in multiplayer the same across PvE and PvP, or did you balance them differently?</strong></p>
<p>There are similarities, but there are also differences because, obviously, fighting Chaos Marines is way more difficult than fighting Tyranids. There are behind-the-scenes changes and adjustments that allow for challenging yet approachable gameplay in PvP, as well as having fun with your buddies in PvE.</p>
<p><strong>When you're in PvE, it's okay to feel overpowered. In PvP, not so much.</strong></p>
<p>Yes. What's great about PvP is something I call the Dance of Death, where you can't just button mash; you gotta move. You have your blocks, you have your grabs, you have your counters, you have your fast melees, you have your long melees, and then you can have weapons. You need to keep moving and then attack, block, attack, so there is this Dance of Death that we've created in PvP.</p>
<figure><figcaption>'Nothing has really changed since we returned independent. The great thing about Saber is there's me, Matthew, Andrey, and Anton. There's like four of us that make all the decisions. That was always the case. We've announced some other games we're working on, like Jurassic Park Survival, A Quiet Place: The Road Ahead, coming out in October, and&nbsp;Toxic Commando.&nbsp;We'll be talking about that soon after we launch Space Marine 2. Things are going well for us.'</figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>You're independent again, with Saber CEO Matthew Karch owning parent company Beacon Interactive after the <a href="https://wccftech.com/saber-interactive-splits-embracer/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">split</a> with Embracer. How does it feel, and what changed?</strong></p>
<p>Nothing really. The great thing about Saber is there's me, Matthew, Andrey, and Anton. There's like four of us that make all the decisions. That was always the case before we were purchased by Embracer, even while we worked with Embracer, and now that we're independent again, it really hasn't changed much.</p>
<p>I'm focusing on the games. That's my job, making sure that each of the teams has what they need to make the best game they can. I jump in when I'm free. I'm not in the trenches like Dmitry, but I do have exposure to all the titles and work with the teams, which makes my job awesome, I love my job. But nothing's really changed. We work with Focus for Space Marine 2 and RoadCraft. <span>We've announced some other games we're working on, like Jurassic Park Survival, <a href="https://wccftech.com/a-quiet-place-the-road-ahead-launches-17-october/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">A Quiet Place: The Road Ahead</a>, coming out in October, and&nbsp;<a href="https://wccftech.com/john-carpenters-toxic-commando-is-a-co-op-fps-powered-by-sabers-swarm-engine-and-due-in-2024/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Toxic Commando</a>.</span>&nbsp;We'll be talking about that soon after we launch Space Marine 2. Things are going well for us.</p>
<p><strong>Are you maybe going to self-publish some titles, too?</strong></p>
<p>Yeah. We're self-publishing Jurassic Park Survival and A Quiet Place: The Road Ahead, and we're also publishing third-party games like <a href="https://wccftech.com/saber-interactive-announces-the-knightling-a-fantasy-action-adventure/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The Knightling</a>. We own 3D Realms, so there are a number of titles that we publish.</p>
<p><strong>Recently, the industry was shaken by various events, like studio closures and mass layoffs. Some developers are quite pessimistic about the future. What do you think?</strong></p>
<p>I have seen all the cycles. I started in 1995, and I remember the death of consoles; I remember the death of the PC. I remember that, yes, there's always cycles, but good games and good teams will always be successful. One of the things that Saber has done well is that we have studios around the world and we focus on the right scopes for our games. We focus on the right deal for our games. Each of our studios has multiple projects, so we don't have 200 people sitting around waiting for pre-production to finish. We're very smart with our money, and we focus on the core aspects of the game. We focus on what's truly fun, whether it's a $5 million game, $10 million game, or $50 million; it doesn't matter.</p>
<p>But if that core game loop is not there, it's not going to be a success, and we've done well by managing our teams, having teams and around the world at different cost structures, and finding the most talented people. If you're a world-class artist, you don't need to be in California.</p>
<p><strong>I guess, like you said, perhaps the secret is really managing your budget really well. Because some game franchises have had their budgets balloon with certain sequels.</strong></p>
<p>Well, that's because some teams have, especially in North America, 150-200 people. They pay everyone well. If your burn rate is a couple of million dollars a month and you wanna change an idea three months later, that's like $6 million wasted. We can make a game for $6 million.</p>
<p>That's one of the problems, you got these huge teams working on one game. If they want to iterate, that's expensive. Each studio at Saber has a main team working on something, and it's a natural ramp, and we have people experimenting with ideas that are starting some really small projects. Maybe five people want to work on an idea, and they can change it, they iterate, they're not spending millions of dollars. As soon as that idea is solid and we're happy with it, after going through our evaluations and our gates, then we ship people over to that project.</p>
<p>We also have a culture at Saber where everyone can work on every project. I've seen studios in North America where people are like, I'm on the red team; I'm not going to work on the blue team. But here, we're all Team Saber. For instance, we are ramping people off Space Marine 2 because it's coming out soon. Now, those people will work on Jurassic Park Survival or Toxic Commando. That's how we remain lean and make money. We don't have ridiculously expensive budgets, so we don't have to sell four million copies to be a success, you know what I'm saying? There are games in North America that, if they don't sell 4 to 6 million copies, they are a failure. That is dangerous.</p>
<p><strong>Just one last question. Electronic Arts actually came out a few months ago during an investor's call after canceling a Star Wars game in development at Respawn to <a href="https://wccftech.com/ea-lays-off-5-of-its-employees-cancels-star-wars-respawn-fps-and-seeks-to-move-away-from-licensed-ips/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">say</a> that they would lean less on licensed franchises in the future. Do you think that's where the industry is headed, partially to offset those growing budgets?</strong></p>
<p>Oh no, no. We're working on a Jurassic Park game. That's one of the world's biggest IPs, and we have other things we are working on that we haven't announced yet. No, you have to manage how much money you are spending on your team. You have to manage how your teams are working.</p>
<p>If you have the right brand, the right IP, it can really benefit you. Even we have had great success working with other IPs. Look at World War Z. I believe the game has made more money than the movie did—I believe, but I'm not sure about that. But you have to manage your teams and your business, and you have to make the right game with the right budget in the right part of the world. That's what we do well.</p>
<p><strong>Okay, well, thank you a lot for your time.</strong></p>

				

			
	<div>
		<h2>Products mentioned in this post</h2>
		
		<!--<p class="story-notice text-center">The links above are affiliate links. As an Amazon Associate, Wccftech.com may earn from qualifying purchases.</p>-->
	</div>

			
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How Black Ops 6 Being Forced To Wipe The Slate Clean Led To Its Biggest New Feature]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/how-black-ops-6-being-forced-to-wipe-the-slate-clean-led-to-its-biggest-new-feature/1100-6526217/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/how-black-ops-6-being-forced-to-wipe-the-slate-clean-led-to-its-biggest-new-feature.968742/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/how-black-ops-6-being-forced-to-wipe-the-slate-clean-led-to-its-biggest-new-feature/1100-6526217/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6526217">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/call-of-duty-black-ops-6/" data-ref-id="5000-630093">Black Ops 6</a> arrives on October 25, and tons of new information was revealed for multiplayer and Warzone during Activision's Call of Duty: Next event on August 28, including live gameplay featuring Treyarch's new omnimovement system. GameSpot was able to attend the event and speak with Treyarch about the changes in development for the new shared engine and how it enabled the studio to create Call of Duty's new advanced movement.</p><p dir="ltr">The last Treyarch game was 2020's Black Ops Cold War, which was a Call of Duty that was created on a shorter development cycle and required a pivot to work-from-home conditions during the pandemic. Now, Treyarch is back in the action again with an extended four-year development cycle for Black Ops 6, and it is the studio's first game on Call of Duty's new shared engine, which was introduced with 2022's Modern Warfare 2 reboot.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="655939368" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6465027,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;39%20Minutes%20of%20COD%3A%20Black%20Ops%206%20Zombies%20Gameplay%20Full%20Round%20On%20Liberty%20Falls&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:2356,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/39-minutes-of-cod-black-ops-6-zombies-gameplay-full-round-on-liberty-falls\/2300-6465027\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465027\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465027\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465027\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6465027&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6465027,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6526217&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;call-of-duty-black-ops-6&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;action,first-person,shooter,tactical&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;xbox-series-x,playstation-5,pc,playstation-4,xbox-one&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;activision,microsoft-game-studios&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;franchise&quot;:&quot;call-of-duty&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;franchiseRoot&quot;:&quot;call-of-duty&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6465027},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6465027\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;GameSpot&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4359245-gameplay_cod_blops6_zombies_ray_gun_v1.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/bjrFrATG.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1724965200,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="bjrFrATG" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> 39 Minutes of COD: Black Ops 6 Zombies Gameplay Full Round On Liberty Falls</p>
      </div>
<p dir="ltr">This is also the most ambitious Call of Duty game since Infinite Warfare in the jetpack era, with Black Ops 6's new omnimovement system that allows players to sprint, slide, and dive in any direction. Players can also go prone and spin around 360 degrees, making fancy moves that let them play out their own action-hero fantasy in matches of Call of Duty across multiplayer, Zombies, and Warzone.</p><p dir="ltr">We spoke with associate design director Matt Scronce and senior director of production Yale Miller, and while the discussion held a focus on the development cycle and movement system, we were also able to touch a little on Black Ops 6's integration into Warzone.</p><p dir="ltr">When discussing Black Ops 6's longer development time, Miller provided more insight into the first year of that development, explaining, "Part of that time was just getting the core Black Ops experience, rebuilding that from the ground up, and getting multiplayer to feel like Black Ops."</p><p dir="ltr">Miller stated he's not sure if Black Ops 6's new movement system would've come to fruition without the transition to the new engine, saying, "I don't know if omnimovement would have happened the same way, [and] I don't know if it's specifically because of the time, but I think part of it was because of the fact that we had to wipe the slate clean and start fresh with rebuilding movement from the beginning."</p><p dir="ltr">"And it really forced the team, and this is my perspective," Miller clarified, "to think of all the pieces that were really important, and that kind of led us down the path of, well, fluidity is king."</p><p dir="ltr">Putting a focus on fluidity for Black Ops 6 led Miller and the team to consider plenty of questions about movement in the game that eventually led to omnimovement.</p><p dir="ltr">"And you maybe wouldn't have had that [thought process] if you were building from the prior code base," Miller said.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394540/4359787-bo6-cod-next-04-wz-0152.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4359787" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394540/4359787-bo6-cod-next-04-wz-0152.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4359787"></a><figcaption>Dive in any direction with omnimovement</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394540/4359787-bo6-cod-next-04-wz-0152.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">Treyarch games are also known for having a faster pace, a more arcade-style design, and a vibrant color palette. One of the community concerns prior to seeing Black Ops 6 footage, was wondering if Treyarch would lose its signature style on the new shared engine.</p><p dir="ltr">Scronce shared some insight to the studio's initial thoughts on keeping Treyarch's style when moving to the new engine. "It was definitely a huge focus," he said. "I wouldn't say it was a worry, really. That first year was like, let's get it feeling like a Black Ops game. Then, we started asking ourselves, what does a Black Ops game feel like? So, asking those hard questions and you come up with some really interesting answers, and it really lets you kind of galvanize what is a Black Ops game?"</p><p dir="ltr">"Every Black Ops has its own story," Scronce said. "And this one was like, oh, we're redefining what it means to be a Black Ops game."</p><p dir="ltr">Omnimovement is the biggest feature of Black Ops 6, and following the integration into Warzone, it will become one of the main focuses of battle royale for the new year. When discussing how Treyarch and Raven Software will keep Warzone fresh, Miller said, "I think the biggest change to Warzone, frankly, is going to be movement, and that's where a lot of our focus is. Working with that crew [Raven Software] on how we can make sure this stuff all feels right."</p><p dir="ltr">Unfortunately, for Warzone players hoping to prestige this year, there will be a bit of a disadvantage. Black Ops 6 brings back Call of Duty's traditional prestige system, which will rest progression and locks all of the guns and attachments from level 1-55.</p><p dir="ltr">This might not be a burden for old-school Call of Duty players, but Treyarch confirmed this would be a shared prestige system across multiplayer, Zombies, and Warzone. This will be Warzone's first year with a classic prestige system, so players who choose to prestige will need to grind to earn all of those weapons and attachments again for their meta loadouts. However, this classic-style prestige choice in Black Ops 6 and Warzone will be optional.</p><p dir="ltr">The choice to prestige in Black Ops 6 will offer some rewards, including unique Black Ops-themed cosmetics and permanent unlocks for things like weapons and perks. And the developer said players can choose to protect certain items from the reset with those permanent unlock token rewards, but otherwise all content unlocked from levels 1-55 will be reset with each prestige, regardless of which mode you play.</p><p dir="ltr">Black Ops 6 will integrate with Warzone by adding Treyarch's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/new-cod-warzone-map-area-99-is-where-nuketown-was-born/1100-6526171/">new Area 99 Resurgence map</a>. In past years, a new Call of Duty integrated into Warzone with a standard, large-scale battle royale map, but this year will focus on a new Resurgence experience with Urzikstan remaining the large map until Warzone's original <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-warzone-is-finally-returning-to-verdansk-in-2025/1100-6526178/">Verdansk map arrives in the spring</a>.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394540/4359788-bo6-cod-next-04-wz-0022.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4359788" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394540/4359788-bo6-cod-next-04-wz-0022.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4359788"></a><figcaption>Area 99 map layout</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394540/4359788-bo6-cod-next-04-wz-0022.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">Scronce explained this by saying they were really focused on the new Resurgence map, because it was themed around Black Ops lore with it being the birthplace of Nuketown.</p><p dir="ltr">"That has been the focus," Miller added. "Bringing in an awesome new Resurgence map that only Treyarch can do was some of the way that we thought about it. The spring news is pretty big. So, I think it's going to be nice with Area 99, and then we're going to have big news in the spring, which obviously we have not had that kind of an opportunity in this way."</p><p dir="ltr">"Before you got a big map in the start, but you didn't get one in the spring," Miller continued. "So, I think it's about pacing the experience."</p><p dir="ltr">Our full GameSpot interview with Treyarch can be found below. For more on Black Ops 6, here are all <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-2024-release-date-trailer-news/1100-6523361/">the announcements for launch-day content</a>. Players can get hands-on with multiplayer during the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-beta-dates-how-to-get-in/1100-6524124/">Black Ops 6 beta</a>, which is live now with week one.</p><p dir="ltr"><strong>GameSpot:</strong> <strong>Just looking at the development time, this is the longest development cycle you guys have had. Do you feel like that was more or less pressure, and is there a feature that probably wouldn't have made it into the game if you didn't have this extended time? </strong></p><p dir="ltr"><strong>Miller:</strong> We moved from the Treyarch engine to the shared Call of Duty engine. So, part of that time was just getting the core Black Ops experience, rebuilding that from the ground up, and getting multiplayer to feel like Black Ops. That was a huge part of it. And I think with that huge transition of even just the tech change, how we needed to rebuild stuff, but also just all the really talented people at all the studios working on the stuff who came from working on the Treyarch engine to the Call of Duty engine. We were learning all the new tools and all those things. So, that was a big part of it.</p><p dir="ltr">I think the other one there is just like, because of how we rebuilt the stuff. I don't know if omnimovement would have happened the same way, but I don't know if it's specifically because of the time, but I think part of it was because of the fact that we had to wipe the slate clean and start fresh with rebuilding movement from the beginning. And it really forced the team, and this is my perspective, to think of all the pieces that were really important, and that kind of led us down the path of like, well, fluidity is king. Because you're reimplementing only sprint forward. You're like, why does that work that way? Why don't we try this? And you maybe wouldn't have had that [thought process] if you were building from the prior code base.</p><p dir="ltr"><strong>Is omnimovement something you guys would be open to tweaking later on?</strong></p><p dir="ltr"><strong>Miller:</strong> Probably during the beta and probably beyond, that's probably the reality of it, because we'll try things.</p><p dir="ltr"><strong>I think a lot of people were worried that with this new shared engine, Treyarch would maybe lose their signature style, but it definitely still looks like a Black Ops game. Were you guys worried about making the move over?</strong></p><p dir="ltr"><strong>Miller:</strong> It was a focus.</p><p dir="ltr"><strong>Scronce:</strong> It was definitely a huge focus. I wouldn't say it was a worry, really. That first year was like, let's get it feeling like a Black Ops game. Then, we started asking ourselves, what does a Black Ops game feel like? So, asking those hard questions and you come up with some really interesting answers, and it really lets you kind of galvanize what is a Black Ops game?</p><p dir="ltr">It was fun. I've worked on every single Black Ops game. Every Black Ops has its own story. And this one was like, oh, we're redefining what it means to be a Black Ops game. So, I'm glad it's come through.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394540/4359791-bo6_multiplayer_action_branded2.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4359791" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394540/4359791-bo6_multiplayer_action_branded2.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4359791"></a><figcaption>Black Ops 6's Rewind multiplayer map</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394540/4359791-bo6_multiplayer_action_branded2.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr"><strong>For the Gunsmith, you talked about the global builds, but it seems like a more simplified version of the Gunsmith. Does this mean what we're seeing is what we're getting, or will there be additional features like aftermarket parts, or anything like that coming to the Gunsmith? </strong></p><p dir="ltr"><strong>Scronce:</strong> I think what you're seeing is what you'll be getting in the beta. We're still working on some things, but you're right that it is a more simplified approach.</p><p dir="ltr"><strong>Which I don't think it's a bad thing!</strong></p><p dir="ltr"><strong>Scronce:</strong> Absolutely not. It was a big goal.</p><p dir="ltr"><strong>Miller:</strong> Intentional.</p><p dir="ltr"><strong>Scronce:</strong> Every single thing we've done in Black Ops 6 is like, how do we streamline? How do we make it easier to get into? I mean, on the attachments, right? We talked about it. We have almost no cons on our attachments, right? We just want it to always feel great to put an attachment on your weapon. Now, some like a magazine, if you've got a big mag, you're gonna reload a little bit slower, but for the large majority of things, it's just gonna they're like, don't worry about it. What's your play style? Do you want ADS fast? You wanna move fast? Slap that on, put five attachments on, or throw a Wildcard on, go for eight attachments, and just have fun.</p><p dir="ltr"><strong>But that's not set in stone, right? That's just what we're seeing for the beta, but you guys might still have other things to change it up?</strong></p><p dir="ltr"><strong>Scronce:</strong> Yeah, for sure.</p><p dir="ltr"><strong>Are there any game modes that we haven't seen today that are more centered around the omnimovement? I feel like this would play well with a mode like Blitz or Gridiron. Are there any other modes you can talk about today? </strong></p><p dir="ltr"><strong>Scronce:</strong> Nothing to talk about right now. It's definitely a topic of conversation within the game modes team. And since omnimovement is a big part of Black Ops 6, we feel like it is a part of every game mode, just like you know, the weapons team make sure that it sits well within that world, but specifically movement based game modes and how can we lean into that? And some of the fun post launch stuff, we'll definitely talk about it.</p><p dir="ltr"><strong>Miller:</strong> New seasons will have new maps and modes.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394540/4359792-bo6-cod-next-02-mp-0202.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4359792" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394540/4359792-bo6-cod-next-02-mp-0202.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4359792"></a><figcaption>Take opponents hostage and use them as a meat shield in MP and Warzone</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394540/4359792-bo6-cod-next-02-mp-0202.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr"><strong>It's so important to have loadouts in battle royale, but if you prestige in Black Ops 6, do you lose your gun and attachment unlocks across all modes, including Warzone?</strong></p><p dir="ltr"><strong>Miller:</strong> You can choose, and you can also choose to protect items.</p><p dir="ltr"><strong>Scronce:</strong> Yeah, permanent unlock tokens. But yeah, it'll, it'll reset your level 1 to 55 content.</p><p dir="ltr"><strong>Being four years into Warzone and once Black Ops 6 integrates, what do you plan on doing to keep it fresh content wise?</strong></p><p dir="ltr"><strong>Miller:</strong> So, I think for Ted [Timmins, Warzone Senior Creative Director at Raven Software] and all the folks at Raven, I think some of the big things are quality of life and improving the experience. And they're doing a lot of work looking at loot and even little things like zip lines and ascenders. Just improvements, improvements, improvements. We're excited.</p><p dir="ltr">I think the biggest change to Warzone, frankly, is going to be movement, and that's where a lot of our focus is. Working with that crew [Raven Software] on how we can make sure this stuff all feels right.</p><p dir="ltr">And then taking an intentional pass across all the perks, gear, and all those things. Just because Black Ops 6 stuff is coming, doesn't mean if there's this awesome piece of gear from a previous title or something that it should go away. So, it's like the best of everything.</p><p dir="ltr">The foundational change, though, I think is a big one. Really talking about Season 1, it's movement. Movement is going to be a huge change. And then I think they have a ton of plans, which we can't talk about here, on how to take it forward.</p><p dir="ltr"><strong>With Warzone in past years, we've gotten a big map within the integration during Season 1 or Season 1 Reloaded. But it looks like we're getting Verdansk in the spring, and we're keeping Urzikstan. Are we keeping that for the entirety of the time? Is there a reason you can provide for why a new big map isn't coming early on? </strong></p><p dir="ltr"><strong>Scronce:</strong> I can, I mean, we were heavily focused on Area 99 as the birthplace of Nuketown for Resurgence.</p><p dir="ltr"><strong>Miller:</strong> So, yeah, I think, that has been the focus. Bringing in an awesome new Resurgence map that only Treyarch can do was some of the way that we thought about it. The spring news is pretty big. So, I think it's going to be nice with Area 99, and then we're going to have big news in the spring, which obviously we have not had that kind of an opportunity in this way.</p><p dir="ltr">Before you got a big map in the start, but you didn't get one in the spring. So, I think it's about pacing the experience.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fallout's three-game Classic Collection is free again on the Epic Store]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/fallouts-three-game-classic-collection-is-free-again-on-the-epic-store</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fallouts-three-game-classic-collection-is-free-again-on-the-epic-store.968739/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/fallouts-three-game-classic-collection-is-free-again-on-the-epic-store<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>As is Wild Card Football.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fallout-og.jpg?width=1200&amp;height=1200&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Black Isle Studios/Bethesda</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
As Dame Shirley Bassey once famously <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yzLT6_TQmq8">bellowed</a>, "It's all just a little bit of history repeating". And so it is with this week's Epic Games Store giveaway of the <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/fallout">Fallout</a> Classic Collection, which Tim Sweeney previously wafted at storeshop visitors in <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/fallout-fallout-2-and-fallout-tactics-all-free-from-the-epic-games-store">December 2022</a> and February this year.
</p>
<p>
For those who didn't grab it previously, the good news is there's some <em>neato</em> stuff in the Fallout Classic Collection. You get, for instance, the game that started it all - Black Isle Studios' original 1997 post-apocalyptic RPG, Fallout - plus its 1998 sequel. Both, of course, are bona fide classics, and Eurogamer sang their praises as part of a retrospective back in 2011.
</p>
<p>
"From the unrelentingly bleak, darkly ironic tone to the novelty of the open-world, post-apocalyptic setting," Keza MacDonald <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/fallout-retrospective-article">wrote</a>, "from the inspired, cerebral turn-based combat system to the immense degree of variety and personality in the character-customisation, the superbly-written quests and characters and the gallows humour that underpins the games without lessening their emotional impact, even the well-placed, gritty violence; there's very little about the games that doesn't command as much respect now as they did a decade ago."
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="18 things you didn't know about Fallout 1 &amp; 2" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/iRA37myO-zE?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>18 things you didn't know about Fallout 1 &amp; 2</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/iRA37myO-zE?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/iRA37myO-zE?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>18 things you didn't know about Fallout 1 &amp; 2.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iRA37myO-zE" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
As for the Fallout Classic Collection's third game, 2001's <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/fallout-tactics-brotherhood-of-steel">Fallout Tactics: Brotherhood of Steel</a>, it's less widely revered, but still solidly enjoyable, introducing squad-based combat action to the isometric wasteland of its illustrious RPG predecessors. That, though, isn't <em>quite</em> everything Epic is giving away this week, and its full list of freebies looks something like this:
</p>
<ul>
<li>Fallout 1</li>
<li>Fallout 2</li>
<li>Fallout Tactics: Brotherhood of Steel</li>
<li>Wild Card Football</li>
</ul>
<p>
That last one, if it's previously managed to pass you by (I, also, was unfamiliar), comes from Saber Interactive, and is described as a "fun pick-up-and-play arcade-style football game featuring 7v7 team-focused gameplay with the unique Wild Card system that lets you change the course of the action in an instant with special power-ups and rule-breaking abilities."
</p>
<p>
<a href="https://store.epicgames.com/en-US/p/wild-card-football">Wild Card Football</a> and the <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/en-US/bundles/fallout-classic-collection">Fallout Classic Collection</a> can be permanently added to your Epic Games Store library for zero pee right now until next Thursday, 5th September. At which point Football Manager 2024 and Sniper Ghost Warrior will stumble blinking into the freebie arena, waiting to be snapped up by curious hands.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>