<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 18:55:09 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[11Bit Studios Responds To The Alters Generative AI Controversy]]></title>
            <link>https://gameinformer.com/2025/06/30/11bit-studios-responds-to-the-alters-generative-ai-controversy</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/11bit-studios-responds-to-the-alters-generative-ai-controversy.1232076/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p>Last week, it was discovered that <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/preview/2024/05/24/aiming-to-replicate-success">The Alters</a>, 11 Bit Studios’ sci-fi narrative management game, included undisclosed use of generative AI in its background flavor text, translations, and image assets. The ensuing anger from players has sullied the reputation of the otherwise well-received title, and the developer has issued a response.</p><p>The Alters launched on June 13 to positive reviews, but the discourse began this past weekend when players began sharing their discoveries of AI prompts for background flavor text as well as translated subtitles. <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vysetron.pixeldie.com/post/3lsc3n4zhfc2k">One Bluesky post </a>showed a screenshot of a computer display with generic science text accompanied by a prompt reading, “Sure, here’s a revised version focusing purely on scientific and astronomical data.”</p><p>Other players found the localization of various languages has clear evidence of being generated using AI due to bizarre or outright incorrect translations, or simply displayed similar AI prompts. <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/windblow.org/post/3lsomoc4mac2g">One example shared on Bluesky </a>is from one of the in-game licensed movies, in which a subtitle, translated to Brazilian Portuguese, reads "Sure! The text translated to Brazilian Portuguese is: Every conversation two people can have, right? So we-"</p><p height="360" width="640" url="https://www.youtube.com/embed/965Km7t6KwM"><iframe width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/965Km7t6KwM" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay" allowfullscreen="true">&nbsp;</iframe></p><p>"Honestly, a beautiful game but I don’t get why the devs felt it was necessary to use genAI," reads on negative <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1601570/The_Alters/">Steam review</a>. "The icons for Earth Calls seem to use AI (or concept art refurbished through AI). Flavour text on one of the displays contains a piece of original prompt. Heavy AI use in its marketing. But worst of all the translation has major problem with AI. So far I noticed Russian, German and Portuguese all having lines straight up saying something like “Sorry, I don’t know how to translate Moollie. Can you give more context as to what it means?” or just prompt text instead of actual lines. It’s heartbreaking to see such unique artistic vision ruined by AI. I am very disappointed in an otherwise good game. i hope the devs will listen and fix it in the future."</p><p>The other big sticking point is 11Bit's lack of transparency regarding its use of AI. Since January 2024, Steam requires games to <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/group/4145017/view/3862463747997849618">disclose</a> if a game features AI-created content, both pre- and live-generated. At launch, The Alters’ <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1601570/The_Alters/">Steam page</a> did not include this disclaimer. "Generative AI use is not acceptable, reads another Steam user. "Undisclosed generative AI use is even less so. I would not have purchased with this information, and I will not be buying from 11 bit again."</p>










<article data-entity-type="file" data-entity-uuid="df0bdd19-9bc1-4371-8be7-5cc00ebfa521" data-embed-button="image_browser_uploader" data-entity-embed-display="view_mode:file.body_default_rendered" data-entity-embed-display-settings="{&quot;link_url&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;link_target&quot;:0,&quot;link_original&quot;:0,&quot;image_source&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;embed_source&quot;:0,&quot;image_caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;embed_caption&quot;:0,&quot;content_warning&quot;:0}" data-langcode="en">

	






</article>
<p>Today, 11Bit has shared a <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/11bitstudios.bsky.social/post/3lstiwaoxcc2i">lengthy response on social media</a>. The developer states it used certain AI-generated assets strictly as temporary placeholders in a “very limited manner." The studio claims one particular AI-generated graphic meant as a development placeholder for a piece of background texture snuck into the final release due to “an internal oversight”. 11Bit claims this asset is being updated, while also sharing a screenshot of the graphic in question, explaining, “While we do not want to downplay the situation, we also want to clearly show its limited impact on your gameplay experience.”</p><p>For the translation issues stemming from the localization of the licensed movies featured in the game, 11Bit says those were added during the late stages of development and were externally produced; thus, it was not involved in that creative process. Furthermore, these elements required last-minute translations, and the studio cites “extreme time constraints” for why it did not utilize its usual translation partners, instead turning to AI in order to localize the videos by launch. 11Bit says updated translations are in the process of being implemented.</p>










<article data-entity-type="file" data-entity-uuid="ab34eca1-3b36-47ca-92cd-85e2a25dc4df" data-embed-button="image_browser_uploader" data-entity-embed-display="view_mode:file.body_default_rendered" data-entity-embed-display-settings="{&quot;link_url&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;link_target&quot;:0,&quot;link_original&quot;:0,&quot;image_source&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;embed_source&quot;:0,&quot;image_caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;embed_caption&quot;:0,&quot;content_warning&quot;:0}" data-langcode="en">

	






</article>
<p>11Bit also points out that the offending translations for those external movies represent 0.3 percent of the overall text in the game (10K words out of 3.4 million across multiple languages). It says the alternative was to release those specific lines of dialogue only in English, which it believed would be a worse decision. “In hindsight, we acknowledge this was the wrong call,” says 11Bit.</p><p>The studio also apologizes for not disclosing its use of AI, saying, “Even more so, no matter what we decided, we should have simply let you know.”</p><p>You can read 11Bit’s full response below (click the image to enlarge):</p>










<article data-entity-type="file" data-entity-uuid="46320b05-65eb-4b4b-aeb5-eea9668496d2" data-embed-button="image_browser_uploader" data-entity-embed-display="view_mode:file.body_default_rendered" data-entity-embed-display-settings="{&quot;link_url&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;link_target&quot;:0,&quot;link_original&quot;:1,&quot;image_source&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;embed_source&quot;:0,&quot;image_caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;embed_caption&quot;:0,&quot;content_warning&quot;:0}" data-langcode="en">

	

<a data-featherlight="image" href="">
</a>







</article>
</div></div><br/><br/>https://gameinformer.com/2025/06/30/11bit-studios-responds-to-the-alters-generative-ai-controversy]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Halo Studios Will Reveal What’s Next For The Halo Series At HaloWC 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/halo-studios-whats-next-for-halo-halowc-2025/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/halo-studios-will-reveal-what%E2%80%99s-next-for-the-halo-series-at-halowc-2025.1232073/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Halo Studios, the new name for the studio formerly known as 343 Industries, will reveal what's next for the Halo series in October 2025 at the Halo World Championship 2025 event.</p>



<p>In a blog post on the <a href="https://www.halowaypoint.com/news/halowc25-june">Halo Waypoint website</a>, the team addressed that there have been rumors floating around about what's next for the series. The post doesn't single out any specific rumor, like the rumors about the <a href="https://wccftech.com/halo-the-master-chief-collection-playstation-5-switch-2/">Master Chief Collection</a> coming to PlayStation and Nintendo Switch 2, or that the next Halo game will <a href="https://wccftech.com/unrevealed-new-halo-game-could-launch-on-playstation-5-according-to-new-information/">release on PlayStation </a>alongside its Xbox and PC releases. </p>



<p>But it does confirm that it will be "<em>continuing the conversation</em>" it began at last year's HaloWC, where it announced Project Foundry, the team's switch to using Unreal Engine 5, and the studio name change from 343 Industries to Halo Studios. </p>



<figure></figure>



<div><p>"<em>Over the past few weeks, there's been a fair bit of speculation about when and where more details might emerge about any of the multiple projects Halo Studios is actively working on,</em>" the studio began. "<em>We don't usually comment on such matters, but this time we want to enter the chat and share a little more perspective for Halo fans who might be on the fence about whether to attend this year's event</em>."</p><p>"<em>Last year at HaloWC,</em> <em>we premiered 'A New Dawn' where we talked about the switch to Unreal Engine, gave you a behind the scenes look at Project Foundry, and debuted our evolution to Halo Studios as we enter a new chapter for Halo. For us, 'A New Dawn' was just the beginning - at this year's HaloWC, we look forward to continuing the conversation.</em>"</p><p>"<em>Speculation is always fun, but if you want the official scoop on what Halo Studios has been working on, you won't want to miss this year's Halo World Championship. We really hope you'll join us in Seattle this October!</em>"</p></div>



<div><p>The last major entry into the long-running shooter series was <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/halo-infinite-review/">Halo Infinite</a>, which was a mostly well-made game for all intents and purposes, but failed to take over the world in the same way new Halo games have done in the past. </p><p>Whatever Halo Studios has planned for the series, it is arguably the most important release for the Halo franchise yet. If it's not a success, it's worth asking whether Microsoft continues the series at all. That might feel like an insane thought, that Microsoft and Xbox would stop making Halo games. But a few short years ago, so did the idea that Microsoft would publish its first-party developed games on PlayStation and Nintendo devices. </p></div>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/halo-studios-whats-next-for-halo-halowc-2025/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Date Everything will make you see your favorite household objects in a sexy new light]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/games/695123/date-everything-review-sassy-chap-games</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/date-everything-will-make-you-see-your-favorite-household-objects-in-a-sexy-new-light.1232070/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="zephr-anchor"><p><a href="https://dateeverything.com/"><em>Date Everything!</em></a> isn’t the dating sim it appears to be. Though the game’s cutesy art style and lighthearted premise indicate an unserious game that’s making yet another joke at the expense of the genre, <em>Date Everything </em>actually contains novel explorations of human relationships and sharp-as-shit political critique. </p><p><em>Date Everything</em> (the title technically includes an exclamation point) is a game where you, with the help of special glasses called “dateviators,” can turn everyday household objects into potential romantic partners. Every in-game day you’re given five opportunities to find new and talk to already discovered characters called dateables. As you interact with them, the things you say and do influence their feelings for you. Winning a dateable’s love, hate, or friendship will also increase the level of one of your personality traits — smarts, poise, empathy, charm, and sass — which unlocks more advanced dialogue responses. Say the right thing, and Dorian (your door, voiced by Ben Starr) will be your best friend boosting your poise. Say the wrong thing and your toilet Jean-Loo Pissoir (Max Mittelman) will swear eternal enmity, boosting your sassiness.</p><p><em>Date Everything</em> is your favorite voice actor’s favorite video game. The game is a veritable murderers’ row of video game voice actors. Neil Newbon, Ben Starr, Ray Chase, Debra Wilson, Felicia Day, Ashley Johnson, Ashly Burch, and more lend their voices to this project. To borrow a line from <em>Super Smash Bros. Ultimate</em>, <a href="https://youtu.be/EXnbMp1yr1k?si=z5DPmI4qvz6YcNlC">everyone is here</a> and they’re delivering high-quality performances more associated with <a href="https://www.theverge.com/interview/653315/clair-obscur-expedition-33-rpg-interview-andy-serkis"><em>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</em></a> than <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2014/9/5/6110091/hatoful-boyfriend"><em>Hatoful Boyfriend</em></a>. </p><p>I love how you don’t have to dig through the credits to know who voices what, as each dateable is given a biography which includes their voice performer. This approach makes sense because <em>Date Everything</em> was created by them. Ray Chase (Noctis Lucis Caelum, <em>Final Fantasy XV</em>), Robbie Daymond (Tuxedo Mask!!), and Max Mittelman (Ryuji Sakamoto, <em>Persona 5</em>) founded Sassy Chap Games. <em>Date Everything</em> is the studio’s first title that’s found viral success mainly because it’s giving the dating sim community — one that’s been left to languish on jokey cast-offs and the odd Valentine’s Day-themed events — exactly what they want: their favorite performers having fun. Every performer in<em> Date Everything</em> is having the time of their lives and you can hear it in their performances. Upon meeting Curt (Davied Morales) and Rod (Jacquis Neal) — any guesses as to what they are — I was delighted by their shade-throwing shenanigans.</p><p>What those faves are saying is just as important as who’s saying it. The game’s dialogue is sharp and hilarious, stuffed with puns and clever wordplay — but make the right choices and it can veer into adult territory that doesn’t feel too corny or vulgar. I was giggling and kicking my feet flirting with my vacuum cleaner (Zeno Robinson) because of the suggestiveness of some of our conversations. </p><p>I’ve never been able to fully inhabit the self-insert characters I play in dating sims mainly because the dialogue options I choose and what I hear hardly ever reflect things I’d actually say or hear in real life. The biggest appeal of<em> Date Everything</em> is that it’s written in a way that closes some of the distance between me the person and me the character in the game. My vacuum cleaner had lines that would have legit worked on me.</p><p>Another trait that has me swiping right on <em>Date Everything</em> is how it’s constructed. Dateables run the gamut of ethnicities, sexualities, and body types. There’s a neat, built-in content warning feature that lets players know if talking to a particular dateable might bring up potentially triggering topics. Every line of dialogue is fully voiced and every new interaction with a dateable comes with a voiced description of the character, a boon for low-vision players. </p><p>The game also lets you know precisely the politics of its creators in incredibly rad and funny ways. Within seconds of starting the story, I was newly hired then promptly fired by the tech megacorporation that developed the dateviators because my job had been automated by AI. Throughout the game, I’ll get updates from the CEO, which are part hilarious interludes, part scathing criticisms of the video game industry. At one point, the CEO fired the company’s event planner in the same breath he praised her for running a successful event. During one message, the CEO was begging for the dateviators back — stolen in a moment of corporate sabotage — because they’ve promised the technology to the, and I friggin’ quote, “US government’s department of Overseas Violence.” A dig that could be aimed at any number of companies, including one <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/643670/microsoft-employee-protest-50th-annivesary-ai">very obvious one</a>.</p><p>There’s a tendency in the dating sim community to get reflexively defensive against cutesy-looking dating sims, especially those developed in the West. While the genre is a staple with a storied history, typically these games are treated as a joke. I am frequently annoyed when a big game publisher announces it’s making one <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/640147/palworld-pubg-dating-sims">only for it to be a prank</a>. Or if one is released, it’s often <a href="https://www.vox.com/the-goods/2019/10/1/20891585/kfc-dating-simulator-branding">a short, unserious side project made for laughs</a>. There’s nothing wrong with that (pigeon dating game <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2014/9/5/6110091/hatoful-boyfriend"><em>Hatoful Boyfriend</em> sends its regards</a>), but it gets grating when virtually every release is done for the lolz.</p><p><em>Date Everything </em>feels like it should be one of those pranks. But in the same way I didn’t realize how sexy a vacuum cleaner could be until I talked to him, you won’t know how serious and special <em>Date Everything</em> is until you try it.</p><p><sub>Date Everything <em>is out now on PC, Xbox, PlayStation, and Nintendo Switch.</em></sub></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/games/695123/date-everything-review-sassy-chap-games]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Is Changing The Switch Price For Millions Of People Soon]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-is-changing-the-switch-price-for-millions-of-people-soon/1100-6532846/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-is-changing-the-switch-price-for-millions-of-people-soon.1232037/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6532846">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Nintendo has strongly suggested that the original Switch is about to get more expensive for millions of people. In Canada, Nintendo said it will change prices on the Switch family of consoles, including the Switch, Switch Lite, and Switch OLED.</p><p>Physical and digital Switch games and accessories could be getting more expensive in Canada as well, along with Nintendo Switch Online subscriptions and Amiibo toys.</p><p><a href="https://www.newswire.ca/news-releases/nintendo-switch-pricing-update-892304996.html" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Nintendo's announcement</a> did not say if pricing is going up or down--only that a "pricing update" is coming--but many believe this will be a price increase due to the wording specifically mentioning that the changes are coming due to "market conditions." GameSpot has contacted Nintendo in an attempt to get more information.</p><p>Whatever the case, the pricing changes do not apply to the Switch 2 console, games, or accessories. Nintendo of Canada did not announce what the price changes will be, but the company said it will share this information on the Nintendo of Canada website on August 1.</p><p>Recently, US President Donald Trump announced that <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2025/06/27/trump-canada-trade-talks-tariffs.html" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">he was ending trade talks with Canada</a> over the country's digital services tax proposal. That's no longer going forward, however, with <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2025/06/30/canada-rescinds-digital-services-tax-after-trump-cuts-off-us-trade-talks.html" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Canada walking back plans.</a></p><p>The Switch currently sells for $400 CAD, with the Switch OLED going for $450 CAD, and the Switch Lite selling for $260 CAD. The Switch 2, meanwhile, sells for $630 CAD or $700 CAD for the Mario Kart World bundle.</p><p>Many expected the Switch 2 to get more expensive in the US following Nintendo's announcement of the device's price on April 2, which was the same day that Trump announced his "Liberation" tariff plan. While Nintendo did not raise prices on the console in the US, where it sells for $450 or $500 with Mario Kart World, it <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-preorder-guide-mario-kart-world-bundle/1100-6530531/" data-ref-id="1100-6530531">did jack up prices on some accessories.</a></p><p>The Switch 2 officially launched on June 5 and became the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/switch-2-has-become-the-fastest-selling-home-console-of-all-time-in-just-four-days/1100-6532341/" data-ref-id="1100-6532341">fastest-selling console from any company in history.</a></p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-is-changing-the-switch-price-for-millions-of-people-soon/1100-6532846/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elden Ring: Tarnished Edition Release Date Could Be Revealed Soon, As Switch 2 Rating Spotted]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/06/elden-ring-tarnished-edition-release-date-could-be-revealed-soon-as-switch-2-rating-spotted</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/elden-ring-tarnished-edition-release-date-could-be-revealed-soon-as-switch-2-rating-spotted.1232031/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>M for Maidenless</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure><a title="Elden Ring: Tarnished Edition" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/b0e093ec3bac6/elden-ring-tarnished-edition.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Bandai Namco</em></figcaption></figure><p>We all may still be waiting for an official release date, but <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/elden-ring-tarnished-edition">Elden Ring: Tarnished Edition</a> has finally secured a Switch 2 rating from the ESRB.</p>
<p>As brought to our attention on Twitter by <a href="https://x.com/necrolipe" tabindex="-1">@necrolipe</a>, the game's official <a href="https://www.esrb.org/ratings/40550/elden-ring-tarnished-edition/">ESRB listing</a> has been updated with an M ( Mature 17+) rating, noting that it contains "Blood and Gore, Language, Suggestive Themes, and Violence," <em>and</em> "in-game purchases".</p>
<p>Here's the official summary from the ESRB website, which goes into the specifics behind the rating:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>This is an action role-playing game in which players assume the role of a character trying to retrieve a magical ring and become the Elden Lord. From a third-person perspective, players explore environments, collect items, and battle various enemies (e.g., knights, fantastical creatures) in melee combat. Players use swords, spears, axes, arrows, and magic to enemies; combat is highlighted by cries of pain, splatters of blood, and impact sounds. The game includes depictions of gore: collectible items that include severed fingers and tongues; a boss character cutting off its arm; severed arms hanging from a ceiling. During the course of the game, a humanoid monster is depicted partially nude, with scales/scars covering its breast and pelvic regions. The word “sh*t” appears in the dialogue.</p></blockquote><blockquote>
</blockquote>
<p>This is hardly all that surprising when we consider that the original Elden Ring, its Shadow of the Erdtree DLC and Nightreign all received an identical 'M' from the ratings board, but hey, it might imply that things are progressing behind closed doors.</p>
<p>The upcoming Switch 2 release wasn't specifically mentioned in the recently revealed line-up for <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/06/bandai-namcos-summer-showcase-promises-plenty-of-switch-news-later-this-week">Bandai Namco's Summer Showcase</a>, but there's every chance that it <em>might</em> make an appearance, with a release date attached. For now, we can only dream.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:181979,184543 @ 1751309124 -->
<p><em>Are you excited to check out Elden Ring on Switch 2? Dodge roll into the comments and let us know.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://www.esrb.org/ratings/40550/elden-ring-tarnished-edition/" rel="noopener" href="https://www.esrb.org/ratings/40550/elden-ring-tarnished-edition/">esrb.org</a>, via <a title="External Link: https://x.com/necrolipe/status/1939679836664152469" rel="noopener" href="https://x.com/necrolipe/status/1939679836664152469">x.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-info/d1da8c8b98800a80cdae480bbdb74bc9 @ 1751307349 --></div></article><div><p>Jim came to Nintendo Life in 2022 and, despite his insistence that The Minish Cap is the best Zelda game and his unwavering love for the Star Wars prequels (yes, really), he has continued to write news and features on the site ever since.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/JimNorman"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/jimnormann.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('JimNorman');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/06/elden-ring-tarnished-edition-release-date-could-be-revealed-soon-as-switch-2-rating-spotted]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Recent Magic: The Gathering Ban List Update Removes Several Cards From Standard]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/recent-magic-gathering-ban-list-update-removes-several-cards-from-standard</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/recent-magic-the-gathering-ban-list-update-removes-several-cards-from-standard.1232028/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>The latest <a href="https://techraptor.net/games/magic-the-gathering" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"><em>Magic: The Gathering</em></a> ban list update is here. Wizards of the Coast's latest change to their widely popular card game includes an "early rotation" for the popular Standard format, banning seven cards from competitive play.</p>



<p>In an official blog post, several members of Magic's design team, Carmen Klomparens, Jadine Klomparens, Arya Karamchandani, Garvin Varhey, and Dave Finseth, broke down the Magic: The Gathering ban list update and explained their process.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/magic-the-gathering-ban-list-update-cori-steel-cutter-card-artwork.jpg?itok=VbhosPdS 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/magic-the-gathering-ban-list-update-cori-steel-cutter-card-artwork.jpg?itok=KOIt6fZM 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>As mentioned before, the format changing the most from this ban list is Standard format. Officially, seven cards are now banned from Standard, which is a lot according to Jadinee Klomparens. Those seven cards are as follows:</p>

<ul><li><em>Cori-Steel Cutter</em></li>
	<li><em>Abuelo's Awakening</em></li>
	<li><em>Monstrous Rage</em></li>
	<li><em>Heartfire Hero</em></li>
	<li><em>Up the Beanstalk</em></li>
	<li><em>Hopeless Nightmare</em></li>
	<li><em>This Town Ain't Big Enough</em></li>
</ul><p>There is a lot to unpack. The biggest offender on this list is Cori-Steel Cutter. It is a key card in the Izzet Prowess deck, represented in 40% of the Standard format meta at the recent <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/magic-gathering-final-fantasy-spotlight-event-is-coming-to-japan" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"><em>Magic: The Gathering Final Fantasy</em> Pro Tour</a>.</p>

<p>According to the post, Izzet Prowess is having an overall negative effect on the meta. This is why <em>Cori-Steel Cutter</em> is getting banned, it is too strong compared to everything else. Low cost, big impact, still affects the battlefield even if it's destroyed quickly. For the long-term health of the game, it is a sensible ban.</p>

<p>As for the other bans in the <em>Magic: The Gathering</em> ban list update, they are mostly for similar reasons. <em>Monstrous Rage</em> is too strong in mono-red decks so it's out. Same thing with <em>Heartfire Hero</em>. <em>Abuelo's Awakening</em> has synergized too well with <em>Omniscience</em>, so it's on the list. <em>Up The Beanstalk</em> has been on ban lists before in Modern format, and it is now banned in Standard for similar reasons.</p>

<p><em>Hopeless Nightmare</em> has proven to be too potent in self-bounce decks, making it a disruptive, aggressive deck. Finally, <em>This Town Ain't Big Enoug</em>h, when parred with <em>Stormchaser's Talent</em>, leads to a lot of momentum-killing endgame lock-outs. So to keep things fun, it is now banned.</p>

<p>Overall, this updated ban list is a measured change for the game. As for how this will change the competitive meta, that is something only time can tell.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Ever since he was small, Tyler Chancey has had a deep, abiding love for video games and a tendency to think and overanalyze everything he enjoyed. This… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/tyler-chancey">More about Tyler</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/recent-magic-gathering-ban-list-update-removes-several-cards-from-standard]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo And Amazon Deny Being In An Ongoing Switch 2 Feud]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/switch-2-amazon-pokemon-za-donkey-kong-preorder-1851785352</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-and-amazon-deny-being-in-an-ongoing-switch-2-feud.1232025/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="81c79847fc856c696737fd4565c0cb9b" data-recommend-id="image://81c79847fc856c696737fd4565c0cb9b" data-format="png" data-width="800" data-height="450" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Mario appears in a suit. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Mario appears in a suit. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Nintendo</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="81c79847fc856c696737fd4565c0cb9b" data-recommend-id="image://81c79847fc856c696737fd4565c0cb9b" data-format="png" data-width="800" data-height="450" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Mario appears in a suit. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>Anyone who’s recently tried to buy stuff from Nintendo through Amazon will have noticed that something weird is going on. Lots of new games you’d expect to find on the online retailer aren’t available there, and the ones that are often arrive with region codes indicating they were originally intended for Europe or elsewhere. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/switch-2-review-best-things-list-hate-love-nintendo-1851783873?_gl=1*rk5cn5*_ga*MTc0MjY2NTg1OS4xNzQwMzc1OTc4*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*czE3NTEzMDQ5NTEkbzE1OCRnMCR0MTc1MTMwNDk1NCRqNTckbDAkaDA.&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/switch-2-review-best-things-list-hate-love-nintendo-1851783873?_gl=1*rk5cn5*_ga*MTc0MjY2NTg1OS4xNzQwMzc1OTc4*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*czE3NTEzMDQ5NTEkbzE1OCRnMCR0MTc1MTMwNDk1NCRqNTckbDAkaDA.">Even the Switch 2 itself</a></span>, which just had the fastest console launch sales ever is still not for sale on Jeff Bezos’ marketplace almost a month later. Now both Nintendo and Amazon swear everything is normal. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="197565" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Nintendo Switch 2 Could Launch With Almost No Reviews" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="122" data-playlist="197565,197567,196230" data-current="197565"><div><p>Nintendo Switch 2 Could Launch With Almost No Reviews</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197565/197565_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197565/197565_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197565/197565_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/23089.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>These denials of any headbutting between the companies come in response to a <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-06-30/amazon-lost-right-to-sell-nintendo-switch-2-amid-sales-dispute?sref=HrWXCALa&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-06-30/amazon-lost-right-to-sell-nintendo-switch-2-amid-sales-dispute?sref=HrWXCALa" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">new report by Bloomberg</a></span> alleging that Nintendo pulled its products from Amazon because of store listings that undercut its products with cheaper prices from third-party sellers who had likely been importing things for cheap from Southeast Asia. Amazon reportedly tried to offer better labeling to make it clear which products were coming officially from Nintendo and which ones weren’t, but that apparently wasn’t enough to mend the relationship. </p><p> “There is no such fact. We do not disclose details of negotiations or contracts with retailers,” a spokesperson for Nintendo told Bloomberg. Amazon also played dumb, calling the reporting “inaccurate” and stating that it was “pleased to offer Nintendo products directly to our customers as part of our commitment to providing an exceptional shopping experience with the widest selection possible.” </p><p>Those products it does offer include the original Switch and first-party games for it, as well as third-party releases for the Switch 2 like<em> Cyberpunk 2077</em>. The Switch 2 and its Nintendo games, however, remain absent. Search for <em>Mario Kart World </em>and you will instead get listings for <em>Mario Kart 8 Deluxe</em>. Two notable exceptions: you can currently pre-order both <em>Donkey Kong Bananza</em> and <em>Pokémon Legends: Z-A</em>. </p><p>Has the beef been squashed, or are these pre-orders for upcoming games just a test run to see if Amazon can <em>allegedly</em> get back into Nintendo’s good graces? <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/metroid-prime-4-screenshots-release-date-trailer-planet-1851772753&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/metroid-prime-4-screenshots-release-date-trailer-planet-1851772753"><em>Metroid Prime 4</em></a></span>, also launching this year, does not have a pre-order listing. In fact, Amazon canceled previously placed pre-orders for the game <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/Games/comments/1hywkdq/amazon_is_canceling_metroid_prime_4_beyond/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Games/comments/1hywkdq/amazon_is_canceling_metroid_prime_4_beyond/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">earlier this year</a></span>. </p><p>Meanwhile, online deals retailer Woot, which is owned by Amazon, frequently sells physical copies of Nintendo’s Switch 1 games at steep discounts. <em>Super Mario Bros. Wonder</em>, <em>Paper Mario: The Thousand-Year Door</em>, and <em>The Legend of Zelda: Echoes of Wisdom</em> are all $15 off at the moment. Even<em> Tears of the Kingdom</em> is just $48. Buy it and pay $10 for the  upgrade and you’re effectively saving $22 off the sticker price of a Switch 2 launch game. I’m sure Nintendo’s not pissed about that at all.</p><p>.</p></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/switch-2-amazon-pokemon-za-donkey-kong-preorder-1851785352]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EA Reviving College Basketball Series After College Football Broke Records]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/ea-college-basketball-march-madness-return-2028-ps5-1851785339</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ea-reviving-college-basketball-series-after-college-football-broke-records.1232022/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="b094e995a262612b55e24e041bbeec16" data-recommend-id="image://b094e995a262612b55e24e041bbeec16" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot from 2009's <em>NCAA Basketball 10 </em>on PS3</figcaption><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->EA / NCAA / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="b094e995a262612b55e24e041bbeec16" data-recommend-id="image://b094e995a262612b55e24e041bbeec16" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>Fans of digital college basketball, get excited. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/ea-college-football-title-update-october-ai-patch-notes-1851681679&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/ea-college-football-title-update-october-ai-patch-notes-1851681679">Electronic Arts</a></span> has officially announced that it is bringing back its college basketball franchise, though it might be a while before you get to play it. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="197589" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Ring Psychology: Understanding The 6 Phases Of A Wrestling Match Through Heel Era John Cena" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="659" data-playlist="197589,197586,197585" data-current="197589"><div><p>Ring Psychology: Understanding The 6 Phases Of A Wrestling Match Through Heel Era John Cena</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197589/197589_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197589/197589_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197589/197589_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/23110.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/EASPORTS/status/1939703160479637660&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/EASPORTS/status/1939703160479637660" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">On June 30, EA Sports posted</a></span> on social media a simple, short message that promised a lot: “Bring the Madness. Let’s run it back. #CBB #ItsInTheGame” The CBB likely stands for “College Basketball.” Alongside this message, EA posted a photo of a basketball with the EA Sports logo slapped on it. The post is clearly a tease for a new college basketball game developed and published by EA. </p><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/MattBrownEP/status/1939712326888038696&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/MattBrownEP/status/1939712326888038696" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Matt Brown of<em> Extra Points</em> reported</a></span> that the new game won’t be called “NCAA Basketball” but might instead be called <em>EA Sports College Basketball</em>. The NCAA will still be involved in the game as a “licensing partner.” The upcoming college basketball game is reportedly still early in development and likely won’t be out until 2028. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://insider-gaming.com/ea-sports-announces-return-of-college-basketball/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://insider-gaming.com/ea-sports-announces-return-of-college-basketball/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Insider Gaming</em> further corroborated this possible release window</a></span>. </p><p><em>Kotaku </em>has<em>&nbsp;</em>reached out to EA Sports for more information on the game. </p><p>2009's<em> NCAA Basketball 10</em> was the last EA Sports-published college basketball game. Since then, fans had hoped EA (or <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/2k-college-hoops-ea-college-football-26-1851784967&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/2k-college-hoops-ea-college-football-26-1851784967">2K, which published a few college ball games around 2006</a></span>) would bring the franchise back. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/MikeStrawMedia/status/1869824116339159465&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/MikeStrawMedia/status/1869824116339159465" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">In 2024, reports surfaced that both EA and 2K were internally discussing potential college basketball games.</a></span> </p><p>The return of collegiate b-ball at EA is likely happening because<em> EA Sports College Football 25 </em>was a massive success for the publisher. That game became the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/ea-college-football-25-best-selling-sports-game-us-ps2-1851724385&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/ea-college-football-25-best-selling-sports-game-us-ps2-1851724385">best-selling sports game in history in less than a year</a></span>. It was also one of the top-selling games in 2024. Even more impressive, according to Mat Piscatella, executive director and video game industry advisor at Circana, last year’s college football game has already landed in the top 50 best-selling games of all time in the United States. So yeah, you can see why EA might be interested in doing a college basketball game again. </p><p>&nbsp;.<br></p></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/ea-college-basketball-march-madness-return-2028-ps5-1851785339]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Game Pass Adds This Underrated Call Of Duty Game Today]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/game-pass-adds-this-underrated-call-of-duty-game-today/1100-6532845/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/game-pass-adds-this-underrated-call-of-duty-game-today.1232010/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6532845">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>It's a big day for Game Pass, as the library grows with the addition of the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/game-pass-adds-11-more-games-soon-including-a-great-call-of-duty-game/2900-6674/#1" data-ref-id="2900-6674">underrated Call of Duty game</a>, Call of Duty: WWII. The game is available now on console and PC not just for Game Pass Ultimate and PC Game Pass, but also the less-expensive Game Pass Standard tier.</p><p>Originally released in 2017, Call of Duty: WWII was developed by Sledgehammer Games and was notable at the time in part for being the first WWII-set CoD game since 2008's Call of Duty: World at War. Some of its most memorable missions including the Saving Private Ryan-like D-Day opening sequence and a mission where you go undercover in a German building in Paris featuring some tense moments.</p><p>You play as Ronald "Red" Daniels, with supporting squadmates including soldiers voiced by people like Josh Duhamel, Jeffrey Pierce, Jonathan Tucker, and Brett Zimmerman. The campaign's intensity is ramped up by the fact that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-ww2-ditching-health-regen-has-some-fo/1100-6449627/" data-ref-id="1100-6449627">there is no automatic health regeneration.</a></p><p>CoD: WWII is also fondly remembered by players for its Headquarters social space, which is similar to The Tower from Bungie's Destiny in that it's a big open space <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-ww2s-headquarters-trailer-reveals-its/1100-6452757/" data-ref-id="1100-6452757">where players can mingle together and even challenge players to 1v1 matches.</a> People have been petitioning Activision to bring back Headquarters, or something like it, ever since--but it's never happened.</p><p>The multiplayer mode, meanwhile, was notable for using a simplified "Divisions" system, which replaced the create-a-class system from earlier games. CoD: WWII also has a Nazi Zombies mode. GameSpot's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/call-of-duty-wwii-review/1900-6416800/" data-ref-id="1900-6416800">CoD: WWII review</a> scored the game a 9/10.</p><p>In other CoD news, the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/cod-black-ops-6-and-warzone-season-4-reloaded-adds-beavis-and-butt-head-and-cel-shaded-maps/2900-6709/" data-ref-id="2900-6709">Season 4 Reloaded update for Black Ops 6 and Warzone releases on July 2, adding Beavis and Butt-Head to the game (and lots more).</a> Looking further out, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-2025-everything-we-know-about-rumored-black-ops-2-sequel/1100-6529073/" data-ref-id="1100-6529073">Call of Duty: Black Ops 7</a> is coming this year, featuring Gilmore Girls actor Milo Ventimiglia as David Mason.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/game-pass-adds-this-underrated-call-of-duty-game-today/1100-6532845/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ghost of Yōtei’s collector’s edition has been detailed]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/06/30/ghost-of-yoteis-collectors-edition-has-been-detailed/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ghost-of-y%C5%8Dtei%E2%80%99s-collector%E2%80%99s-edition-has-been-detailed.1232007/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Sony and Sucker Punch have released details for the Ghost of Yōtei collector’s edition, but it will not be cheap coming in $249.99/£219.99. If you do not fancy spending that much you will also have the options of the standard edition for £69.99 or the Digital Deluxe Edition for £79.99. You can see the details of Ghost of Yōtei following the trailer for the collector’s edition.</p>
<p><iframe title="Ghost of Yōtei - Collector's Edition Trailer | PS5 Games" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ndGaJhOm5Fc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://direct.playstation.com/en-gb/buy-games/ghost-of-yotei-ps5?srsltid=AfmBOoryAAQU5l6IvSS-o71MiU_VTTyKNcSbtQU625wpe0m3swAuSGDnSwo&amp;utm_content=YT3-OAxnTv2_ztzKaVU1og0O3k5tv6qzYSGm3SpySPGjM3XqBXTfMC46dLmhTfEZhbsGbkLj_02CLXdiKqeSZ4jMVQdE&amp;utm_term=UC-2Y8dQb0S6DtpxNgAKoJKA&amp;utm_medium=product_shelf&amp;utm_source=youtube">Ghost of Yōtei standard edition</a> (£69.99) – Base game + pre-order bonus of Atsu + Yōtei Six Avatar set and in game mask.</li>
<li><a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-gb/product/UP9000-PPSA26344_00-GHOST2DDEBUNDLE0/?utm_content=YT3-rGvDGU7M0UqsGGNOX_9zZZ2uC_8_2rWR8tWiKtsBG5eo7Q0zt1z5qB58NCvqGts5zpGMAOYvP-ea6k7H8KHGmBzX&amp;utm_term=UC-2Y8dQb0S6DtpxNgAKoJKA&amp;utm_medium=product_shelf&amp;utm_source=youtube">Ghost of Yōtei digital deluxe edition</a> (£79.99) – Base game + The Snake Armour, Digital Deluxe Armour Dye, Digital Deluxe Horse &amp; Saddle, Sword Kit, Traveller’s Maps (Early Unlock), and Charm</li>
<li>Ghost of Yotei Collector’s Edition (£219.99) – All of the items from standard and digital editions + Ghost Mask, Sash, Tsuba, Papercraft Ginkgo Tree. Art Cards, and Zeni Hajiki Coin Game &amp; Pouch.</li>
</ul>
<p>Ghost of Yōtei is set a couple of centuries after Ghost of Tsushima, and introduces Atsu as the new protagonist.&nbsp; A gang of outlaws known as the Yōtei Six killed Atsu’s family and left her for dead, pinned to a burning ginkgo tree. But she’s not dead, and instead spent the last sixteen years learning to fight, kill and hunt. Now she’s returning to her home to track down The Snake, The Oni, The Kitsune, The Spider, The Dragon, and Lord Saito one by one and seek vengeance.</p>


<h2><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2020/07/14/ghost-of-tsushima-review/">Ghost of Tsushima Review</a></h2>
<p>In our Ghost of Tsushima review, I said, ”&nbsp;“Ghost of Tsushima is an artistic triumph, capturing a real cinematic feel through its visuals, immersive world and soundtrack. However, Jin is a serviceable main character and he and his journey to save Tsushima is often overshadowed by secondary characters and smaller, more personal stories found in the side quests. Throw in some formulaic missions and an awkward user interface, and Ghost of Tsushima is at times more style than substance.”</p>

<p>Ghost of Yōtei is due to be released on October 2nd exclusively for PS5.</p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ndGaJhOm5Fc">YouTube</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/06/30/ghost-of-yoteis-collectors-edition-has-been-detailed/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Alters Dev Admits It Used GenAI With Some Assets “Mistakenly” Left In The Game, While Other Uses Were Intentional]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/the-alters-generative-ai-assets/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-alters-dev-admits-it-used-genai-with-some-assets-%E2%80%9Cmistakenly%E2%80%9D-left-in-the-game-while-other-uses-were-intentional.1232004/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p><a href="https://wccftech.com/the-alters-qa-creating-a-game-about-the-roads-not-taken/">The Alters</a> developer, 11 bit Studios, has addressed allegations that generative AI technology was used in the game's development, admitting that it did use GenAI tech when making the game, though in some cases it was never meant to be in the final version. While other instances were intentional choices the team made due to "<em>time constraints</em>."</p>



<p>The Alters released earlier this month to strong critical acclaim, with the game currently sitting at an <a href="https://www.metacritic.com/game/the-alters/critic-reviews/?platform=pc">84 on Metacritic</a>, with both critics and players praising its narrative woven between different versions of one person. However, over the weekend it faced its first dash of <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/fans-slam-the-alters-after-discovering-evidence-of-undisclosed-gen-ai-in-images-text-and-translation">controversy</a> after players discovered what they believed to be confirmation that 11 bit Studios used generative AI technology when making The Alters. </p>



<p>A major sticking point for players regarding the use of GenAI is how 11 bit studios used it for localization purposes, with players citing poor translations for Portuguese, Russian, and German, though the most significant aspect of 11 bit Studios using GenAI that has upset players is the fact that 11 bit Studios did not disclose they had used the technology. </p>



<p>Per <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/group/4145017/view/3862463747997849618">Valve's updated rules</a> for games published on Steam, the use of GenAI to produce the final product that's sold on the digital storefront must be disclosed to players. At the time of this writing, the disclosure is not on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1601570/The_Alters/">The Alters Steam page</a>. </p>



<p>Now, we have 11 bit Studios side of the story, with <a href="https://x.com/altersgame/status/1939707458152448118">a long statement published to the game's official X account</a>, where the team explains how one of the instances players have brought up was never meant to make it into the final version of the game. It also provides a screenshot of where the GenAI text can be found, showing how little of the game screen real estate it takes up, and claims it to be an isolated mistake, though says it isn't trying to "<em>downplay</em>" the situation.</p>



<p>"<em>AI-generated assets were used strictly as temporary WIPs during the development process and in a very limited manner. Our team has always prioritized meaningful, handcrafted storytelling as one of the foundations of our game</em>," the studio writes at the top of its statement. </p>



<p>"<em>During production, an AI-generated text for a graphic asset, which was meant as a piece of background texture, was used by one of our graphical designers as a placeholder. This was never intended to be part of the final release. Unfortunately, due to an internal oversight, this single placeholder text was mistakenly left in the game. We have since conducted a thorough review and confirmed that this was an isolated case, and the asset in question is being updated</em>."</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>Other choices, like using GenAI for localization work, it admits, were intentional choices made due to time constraints that it now says were "<em>the wrong call."</em> 11 bit Studios also claims that it always intended to go back and release a hotfix for the proper translations.</p>



<p>"<em>In addition to that, a few licensed movies that the alters can watch in the social area of the base were added at the final stage of development. While those were externally produced, our team was not involved in the creative process, and these required additional last-minute translations. Due to extreme time constraints, we chose not to involve our translation partners and had these videos localized using AI to have them ready on launch. It was always our intention to involve our trusted translation agencies after release as part of our localization hotfix, to ensure those texts would be handled with the same care and quality as the rest of the game. That process is now underway, and updated translations are being implemented</em>."</p>



<p>11 bit Studios goes on to describe just how little of the game's text is GenAI, and how it wanted to have translations for the aforementioned films to ensure that it didn't only feature the English dialogue while localization work for other languages continued. "<em>In hindsight, we acknowledge this was the wrong call. Even more so, no matter what we decided, we should have simply let you know</em>."</p>



<p>There are <a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ex-steam-labs-dev-claims-1-000-steam-games-use-generative-ai">plenty of games</a> that use generative AI technology in development, whether as part of the process without intending GenAI assets to be in the final game, or as part of the final product. Like it or not, generative AI technology is part of the modern game development landscape, and it isn't going away anytime soon. It's clear that 11 bit Studios' biggest fumble here wasn't just using GenAI for a poor band-aid solution to its problems, but trying to sneak its GenAI use past players, hoping to patch the game before anyone noticed.</p>



<p>It'll be interesting to see how Steam reacts to this, and if the storefront's rules around the disclosure of GenAI, and the failure disclose, will result in punitive action against developers who take the risk of trying to sneak GenAI assets past Steam.</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/the-alters-generative-ai-assets/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Capcom finally put a bullet in Resident Evil: RE:Verse but haven't entirely given up on Resident Evil online]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/capcom-finally-put-a-bullet-in-resident-evil-reverse-but-havent-entirely-given-up-on-resident-evil-online</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/capcom-finally-put-a-bullet-in-resident-evil-re-verse-but-havent-entirely-given-up-on-resident-evil-online.1232001/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>I had totally forgotten that <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/resident-evil-village">Resident Evil Village</a> was in development alongside a new Resident Evil multiplayer game, which (at the risk of yet again inflating my own importance) is perhaps why Capcom have just shut the latter down. As <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/resident-evils-multiplayer-spin-off-reverse-is-shutting-down-later-this-year">promised earlier this year</a>, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/resident-evil-reverse">Resident Evil RE:Verse</a> is no more. Capcom have burned down the game’s storefront listing, taken a shovel to its DLC pages, and now put a pitchfork through the servers. Run tell the peasantfolk that the beast is finally dead.</p><!--more-->
<p>When they confirmed the suspension of support, Capcom said that they released Re:Verse back in 2022 to celebrate the original game's 25th anniversary. The game peaked at 2080 concurrent players on Steam, which is not exactly Counter-Strike numbers, but Capcom feel nonetheless that "Resident Evil Re:Verse has served its original, celebratory purpose admirably". Ah, this reminds me of me telling my mother that I had an intimidating persona when nobody showed up for my 16th birthday party.</p>
<p>RE:Verse was a six player third-person shooter featuring a cross-section of nods to older Resident Evils, including the ability to chug a potion and transform into a celebrity baddy such as Resident Evil 7’s chainshear-wielding scruffer Jack Baker. It was the latest in Capcom’s quixotic efforts to make a multiplayer Resi, a quest that has given us such wibbly fare as <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/resident-evil-operation-raccoon-city">Resident Evil: Operation Raccoon City</a>, which Richard Cobbett <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/wot-i-think-resident-evil-operation-raccoon-city">summarised</a> as “not so much bad as grindingly unenthusiastic”. </p>
<p>I’m not aware of an all-timer multiplayer Resident Evil game but they were getting there with the co-op features for games like <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/resident-evil-5">Resident Evil 5</a>, and Resident Evil Outbreak – a multiplayer survival game set in Raccoon City – should have been a doozie. In Capcom’s defence, they released that back in primordial 2003, when online was a novelty, and online Japanese games especially had you communicating with the servers by means of a specially trained seagull. I’ve still got my seagull from the dial-up days. He’s running a major publisher now. I won’t tell you which one, but let’s just say that the guano rolls downhill at Ubisoft Inc.</p>
<p>While RE:Verse is most assuredly dead - the fate of <a hef="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/70-of-games-with-online-requirements-are-doomed-according-to-stop-killing-games-survey">70% of games that have online requirements</a>, according to one study - Capcom continue to chase the tipsy T-viral daydream of Resident Evil multiplayer. According to the most recent round of Resident Evil Requiem developer interviews, they <a href="https://www.msn.com/en-xl/news/other/capcom-ditches-online-plans-for-resident-evil-requiem/ar-AA1HyiP1">toyed with</a> another online-focussed Resident Evil before moving ahead with Requiem’s premise of being <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/resident-evil-requiem-has-its-own-version-of-lady-dimitrescu-but-i-doubt-youll-be-thirsting-for-this-hag">stuck in a hotel with a stampeding hag</a>.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/capcom-finally-put-a-bullet-in-resident-evil-reverse-but-havent-entirely-given-up-on-resident-evil-online]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[You Have Until Wednesday To Take Down The Latest Nightreign Everdark Sovereign, Fulghor]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/elden-rign-nightreign-everdark-es-sovereign-fulghor-1851785340</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/you-have-until-wednesday-to-take-down-the-latest-nightreign-everdark-sovereign-fulghor.1231992/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Nightreign</em> players arguably consider Fulghor, Champion of Nightglow to be one of the hardest Day-Three Bosses in the game. With the introduction of Everdark Sovereigns (ES), which are beefed up versions of current bosses, Fulghor is back once again to terrorize you.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="197589" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Ring Psychology: Understanding The 6 Phases Of A Wrestling Match Through Heel Era John Cena" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="659" data-playlist="197589,197586,197585" data-current="197589"><div><p>Ring Psychology: Understanding The 6 Phases Of A Wrestling Match Through Heel Era John Cena</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197589/197589_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197589/197589_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197589/197589_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/23110.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>Like <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-nightreign-everdark-sovereign-adel-baron-1851785048&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-nightreign-everdark-sovereign-adel-baron-1851785048">last week’s ES Adel, Baron of Night</a></span>, ES Fulghor has some dramatically different attack patterns and new moves to throw at players. Here are some tips on how to beat it and what to expect.</p><h2 id="h25783"><a id="1"></a>Preparation</h2><p>Like its normal form, <strong>ES Fulghor is still weak to lightning elemental attacks</strong>, so a corresponding weapon will be helpful in dealing damage. However,<strong> ES Fulghor seemingly starts in the original’s second phase and will use its most dangerous move: the one where it charges up an aura to summon blades of lightning from the ground</strong>. Lightning elemental attacks will break its guard and prevent it from executing that attack.</p><p>Any class composition will suffice as long as players are skilled enough, but <strong>having more melee based classes like </strong><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-nightreign-play-guardian-tank-defend-magic-1851783574&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-nightreign-play-guardian-tank-defend-magic-1851783574"><strong>Guardian</strong></a></span><strong>, </strong><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-nightreign-wylder-guide-onslaught-claw-shot-1851783361&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-nightreign-wylder-guide-onslaught-claw-shot-1851783361"><strong>Wylder</strong></a></span><strong>, </strong><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-nightreign-executor-beast-dexterity-arcane-1851784376&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-nightreign-executor-beast-dexterity-arcane-1851784376"><strong>Executor</strong></a></span><strong>, and </strong><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-nightreign-raiden-ultimate-art-strength-1851783752&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-nightreign-raiden-ultimate-art-strength-1851783752"><strong>Raider</strong></a></span><strong> will be useful</strong>. Fulghor hits hard and is very aggressive, so you’ll need players who can dish out damage just as well as they take.</p><h2 id="h25784"><a id="2"></a>Fighting Everdark Soveriegn Fulghor</h2><p>ES Fulghor retains most of its normal attacks, which involve swiping its giant weapon on the ground and creating shockwaves. The swipe itself is easy to dodge, but there’s a delay between the shockwave’s emergence, which can be a bit difficult to avoid. When Fulghor swipes at you, it’s best to dodge <em>towards</em> it, so you don’t get caught in the shockwave after.</p><p>Visually, one of the biggest changes to Fulghor is that it now has its other arm back! It’ll still grow out that grotesque purple arm, though, just like the normal version. When Fulghor reveals the giant purple arm, it’ll slam the ground, unleashing a purple shockwave AOE. This attack comes out incredibly fast, and you’re very unlikely to outrun the blast radius, so your best option is to time your dodge to avoid it.</p><figure id="" data-id="3b7747ed767133e3662ebedb80045580" data-recommend-id="image://3b7747ed767133e3662ebedb80045580" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1101" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="ES Fulghor falls to the ground to deliver an attack." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="ES Fulghor falls to the ground to deliver an attack." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->FromSoftware / George Yang / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="3b7747ed767133e3662ebedb80045580" data-recommend-id="image://3b7747ed767133e3662ebedb80045580" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1101" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="ES Fulghor falls to the ground to deliver an attack." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>ES Fulghor carries over its rush attack from its normal version. Here, Fulghor will charge at you a few times, leaving a trail of explosive light behind. It takes a few seconds for the light trail to blow up, so it’s to just move out of the way.</p><p>One of ES Fulghor’s new tricks sees it floating up in the sky, and then creating “clouds” that shoot arrows of light towards the ground. The clouds can track your position, so be aware, but they will dissipate shortly. </p><figure id="" data-id="d901e44fdd5d9c1632efe2720d49a4d0" data-recommend-id="image://d901e44fdd5d9c1632efe2720d49a4d0" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Arrows rain down from the sky." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Arrows rain down from the sky." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->FromSoftware / George Yang / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="d901e44fdd5d9c1632efe2720d49a4d0" data-recommend-id="image://d901e44fdd5d9c1632efe2720d49a4d0" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Arrows rain down from the sky." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Fulghor can now also turn its weapon into a giant twinblade of light. It’ll then perform a 360 degree sweep around itself twice before jumping up and slamming the blade down into the ground, creating a small shockwave. The best way to avoid these attacks is to just dodge-roll through them.</p><p>Last and certainly not least, ES Fulghor’s new most dangerous attack is when it gallops into the air and charges up a giant arrow of light. This attack has an absolutely huge AOE radius and is hard to run away from. Your best option here is to have the entire team disperse in different directions so that when Fulghor targets one of you, the other two are far away enough to avoid the explosion that comes after the arrow.</p><figure id="" data-id="3690a09cd30bc4ec0e61247a097efc24" data-recommend-id="image://3690a09cd30bc4ec0e61247a097efc24" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1083" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="The players run from a massive arrow attack." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="The players run from a massive arrow attack." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->FromSoftware / George Yang / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="3690a09cd30bc4ec0e61247a097efc24" data-recommend-id="image://3690a09cd30bc4ec0e61247a097efc24" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1083" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="The players run from a massive arrow attack." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>After defeating Fulghor, you’ll earn 25 Sovereign Sigils, which can be spent at the new Collector Signboard outside of the castle hub area. With the introduction of ES Fulghor, there’s a new Relic based on it called the Dark Night of the Champion. It costs 12 Sovereign Sigils to purchase and comes with the following effects:</p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li>Increased Maximum Stamina</li><li>Boosts Attack Power of Added Affinity Attacks</li><li>Defeating enemies fills more of the Art gauge</li></ul><p>Everdark Sovereigns cycle in and out every week. Fulghor is available to fight against until July 2 at 5:59 PM PDT to make way for the next one, which is seemingly Sentient Pest.</p><hr><p><br><em>Elden Ring Nightreign</em> is now available on PS5, Xbox Series X/S, and Windows PCs. </p></div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/elden-rign-nightreign-everdark-es-sovereign-fulghor-1851785340]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[16 Years After The Last NCAA Basketball Game, EA Sports Is 'Bringing Back the Madness']]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/16-years-after-the-last-ncaa-basketball-game-ea-sports-is-bringing-back-the-madness</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/16-years-after-the-last-ncaa-basketball-game-ea-sports-is-bringing-back-the-madness.1231977/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">After 16 years, college basketball (CBB) is coming back to EA Sports. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">If you're looking for more details than that, then bad news — EA really isn't talking as yet — but in a message posted to social media earlier today, the division responsible for EA's sports games said: "Bring the Madness. Let's run it back." </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The message was appended with two hashtags: "CBB" — an acronym for college basketball — and EA Sports' customary "It's in the Game." Oh, and there was an image of a basketball, too.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">If you're unfamiliar with basketball and EA Sports' relationship with it, it's worth noting that this is <em>big</em> news, as it marks the first time EA Sports has taken us into the heart of college basketball since 2009's <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/ncaa-basketball-10"><u>NCAA Basketball 10</u></a>. It follows the similar resurrection of EA Sports' College Football franchise, which came back to life last July with <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/college-football-25">College Football 25</a>.</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr">Bring the Madness. Let’s run it back. <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/CBB?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">#CBB</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/ItsInTheGame?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">#ItsInTheGame</a> <a href="https://t.co/iBNhGxn2yj" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/iBNhGxn2yj</a></p>— EA SPORTS (@EASPORTS) <a href="https://twitter.com/EASPORTS/status/1939703160479637660?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">June 30, 2025</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">As for the other basketball video game, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/nba-2k25"><u>NBA 2K25</u></a>? We thought the latest iteration was Good, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nba-2k25-review"><u>awarding 7/10</u></a>, writing: "A handful of improvements mean NBA 2K25 has a few tricks up its sleeve to be pleasantly surprised by this year, even as many long-term issues continue." It's currently one of the games up for grabs with this month's <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/playstation-plus-monthly-games-for-june-2025-confirmed-plus-bonus-game-catalog-and-classics-catalog-games-announced"><u>PlayStation Plus free games</u></a>, along with the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/alone-in-the-dark"><u>Alone in the Dark</u></a> remake, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/bomb-rush-cyberfunk"><u>Bomb Rush Cyberfunk</u></a>, and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/destiny-2-the-final-shape"><u>Destiny 2: The Final Shape</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Vikki Blake is a reporter for IGN, as well as a critic, columnist, and consultant with 15+ years experience working with some of the world's biggest gaming sites and publications. She's also a Guardian, Spartan, Silent Hillian, Legend, and perpetually High Chaos. Find her at </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vixx.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>BlueSky</em></a><em>.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/16-years-after-the-last-ncaa-basketball-game-ea-sports-is-bringing-back-the-madness]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Former Nintendo Devs Reminisce About 'Amazing' Colleagues Who Were So Good At Making Games, They Seemed Like 'Celestial Beings']]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/former-nintendo-devs-reminisce-about-amazing-colleagues-who-were-so-good-at-making-games-they-seemed-like-celestial-beings</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/former-nintendo-devs-reminisce-about-amazing-colleagues-who-were-so-good-at-making-games-they-seemed-like-celestial-beings.1231974/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline"> "I remember constantly wondering how I could demonstrate my own worth in such an environment."</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Takaya Imamura — a video game designer and manga artist perhaps best known for his work on F-Zero, Star Fox, and The Legend of Zelda — has said that despite his lofty credits, there were "so many amazing people" in Nintendo, he felt "inferior" enough that it was a relief to eventually leave the company.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"There were so many incredible people at Nintendo,” Imamura <a href="https://x.com/ima_1966/status/1938107363799798252" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>wrote on X</u></a>, as spotted and translated by <a href="https://v/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Automaton</u></a>, "and I remember constantly wondering how I could demonstrate my own worth in such an environment," adding there was always "a sense of inferiority lingering somewhere."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"When I left the company, it’s true that I felt a sense of freedom, as if I had been released from the inferiority complex I’d carried for years," Imamura <a href="https://x.com/ima_1966/status/1938107363799798252" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>added</u></a>. "But at the same time, there was also a loneliness in thinking, 'I won’t be able to work with these people anymore…' That said, with only a few years left until retirement anyway, and since game development often takes many years, I felt a stronger desire to move forward at my own pace, doing more freely creative things."</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">While reading that may come as a surprise, it seems that sentiment is shared by many former Nintendo employees. One former Nintendo designer, Shinji Watanabe, who now heads up Epsilon Software, followed up to <a href="https://x.com/es_s_watanabe/status/1938131920317256011" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>liken</u></a> his former colleagues to "celestial beings," whilst Ken Watanabe, who worked at Nintendo for 10 years before branching out an an indie creator, <a href="https://x.com/waken/status/1938109693035216959" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>concurred</u></a>, said: "There really is nothing but amazing people [at Nintendo]. Trying to find a way to stand out among them was both draining and fulfilling."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">On the subject of Nintendo… did you know <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/super-mario-strikers"><u>Super Mario Strikers</u></a> — or Mario Smash Football, as it's known in Europe — is joining <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/tech/nintendo-switch-2"><u>Nintendo Switch 2</u></a>'s Nintendo Switch Online GameCube library next week? It's the first game to have been added to the library since Switch 2 launched earlier this month. And don't forget, an extremely cool replica <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-says-switch-2-gamecube-controller-will-work-with-non-gamecube-games-but-there-may-be-issues"><u>GameCube controller is also available</u></a> for maximum nostalgia…</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Nintendo Switch 2 is off to a strong start, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/has-switch-2-been-a-failure-so-far-for-non-nintendo-games-the-numbers-paint-a-mixed-picture"><u>with 3.5 million consoles sold</u></a>, but an <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/has-switch-2-been-a-failure-so-far-for-non-nintendo-games-the-numbers-paint-a-mixed-picture"><u>analysis on the console's launch week sales paints a mixed picture of how well games not made by Nintendo are now selling</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Vikki Blake is a reporter for IGN, as well as a critic, columnist, and consultant with 15+ years experience working with some of the world's biggest gaming sites and publications. She's also a Guardian, Spartan, Silent Hillian, Legend, and perpetually High Chaos. Find her at </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vixx.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>BlueSky</em></a><em>.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/former-nintendo-devs-reminisce-about-amazing-colleagues-who-were-so-good-at-making-games-they-seemed-like-celestial-beings]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[FBC: Firebreak Launch Wasn't What Studio Hoped For, But Remedy Isn't Giving Up]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fbc-firebreak-launch-wasnt-what-studio-hoped-for-but-remedy-isnt-giving-up/1100-6532823/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fbc-firebreak-launch-wasnt-what-studio-hoped-for-but-remedy-isnt-giving-up.1231959/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6532823">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Alan Wake and Control developer Remedy Entertainment launched its newest game, the co-op FPS <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/fbc-firebreak/" data-ref-id="5000-647734">FBC: Firebreak</a>, in mid-June. The game didn't exactly take the world by storm, <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/2272540/charts/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">with Steam concurrents topping out under 300 over the last week</a>, and Remedy itself admitting it "had hoped for a better launch." But Steam concurrent numbers do not tell the whole story, of course, and Remedy isn't giving up on Firebreak. Far from it.</p><p>Speaking to GameSpot, Remedy communications director Thomas Puha responded to the game's launch and outlined some of what's to come as part of the game's ongoing content roadmap. Puha said the team at Remedy is "super motivated" to build upon FBC and make changes based on player feedback. More than <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/2272540/view/536605983645893033?l=english" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">1 million people</a> have played the game so far, and players haven't wasted time submitting feedback.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="998520479" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6466147,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;FBC%3A%20Firebreak%20GameSpot%20Review&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:636,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/fbc-firebreak-gamespot-review\/2300-6466147\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466147\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466147\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466147\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6466147&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6466147,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6532823&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;fbc-firebreak&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;3d,action,first-person,shooter&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;pc,playstation-5,xbox-series-x&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;remedy-entertainment&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;franchise&quot;:&quot;control&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;franchiseRoot&quot;:&quot;control&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6466147},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6466147\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;GameSpot&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4519981-fbc_site.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/7SfBSwKm.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1750773840,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="7SfBSwKm" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> FBC: Firebreak GameSpot Review</p>
      </div>
<p>"One of the great things about an online game like FBC: Firebreak is that we receive a wealth of player data and community feedback to inform our decision-making. We read all of it, and we are there talking with the players online," Puha explained.</p><p>We also asked Puha about the decision to bring Firebreak to Game Pass and PlayStation Plus at launch. He said Remedy is still crunching the numbers, but remarked that a "good number" of new players are joining FBC on console every day via the subscription services from Microsoft and Sony.</p><blockquote data-size="small" data-align="left"><p>"We feel strongly that what we have in the pipeline is going to be exciting for players. There is some game-changing content in development." -- Remedy's Thomas Puha</p></blockquote><p>Some in the video game industry have questioned whether or not it makes good business sense to launch new games directly into a subscription service, including those who have done just that. Recently <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/dev-who-launched-game-into-game-pass-warns-against-launching-games-into-game-pass/1100-6532306/" data-ref-id="1100-6532306">the developer of the day-one Game Pass release Revenge of the Savage Planet questioned whether it was indeed a good idea to launch the game into Game Pass</a>, citing concerns about the "devaluation" of content. We don't know about the financial specifics for any deals Remedy may have made for Firebreak, however. At the same time, others have argued that launching directly into a subscription service could be a recipe for success to help a game reach a wider audience out of the gate.</p><p>Beyond financial performance, Puha said it's "pretty clear" that although people who may join Firebreak from Game Pass or PS Plus might not stick with the game for as long as someone who may have bought the game outright, "it's also easier for them to return."</p><p>Puha also <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/control-spin-off-fbc-firebreak-is-a-defiant-punk-rock-take-on-co-op-shooters/1100-6531475/" data-ref-id="1100-6531475">reiterated</a> that Firebreak was never designed to require people to play every day to unlock daily login rewards or anything that could make it feel like playing Firebreak was "your other job." The game was purposefully designed to not take over your life, he said. "Instead, you play Firebreak for a while, take a break, and come back when we release new content in the form of major updates," he said. "We feel strongly that what we have in the pipeline is going to be exciting for players. There is some game-changing content in development."</p><p>While Puha said Remedy has already had to make key strategic decisions like prioritizing some areas and deprioritizing others due to the feedback at launch, he said fans can expect Remedy to stick with FBC. "Remedy is fully committed to FBC: Firebreak. We are all curious to see what it will be like later in the year," he said.</p><p>You can read our full interview with Puha below.</p><p>Next up for Firebreak is <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/2272540/view/536605983645893033?l=english" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">the 1.3 patch</a>, which is targeting release early this week. Remedy said the patch aims to "enhanced the overall game experience" with things like changes to the game's perk economy. This follows on from a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/remedy-is-bringing-major-changes-to-fbc-firebreak-after-launch-backlash/1100-6532591/" data-ref-id="1100-6532591">previous patch that responded to some initial frustrations</a> with the game about the onboarding and progression, among other things.</p><p>GameSpot's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/fbc-firebreak-review-controlled-chaos/1900-6418376/" data-ref-id="1900-6418376">FBC: Firebreak review</a> scored the game an 8/10. "FBC: Firebreak is an enjoyably chaotic power fantasy, and an interesting experiment for Remedy between its bigger, weirder projects," reviewer Mark Delaney wrote.</p><p>Remedy's ongoing support for Firebreak is just one of the development efforts that remains ongoing at the company. The Finnish studio is also working on <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/control-2-enters-full-production-as-alan-wake-2-has-finally-recouped-development-costs/1100-6529420/" data-ref-id="1100-6529420">Control 2</a> and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/max-payne-1-and-2-remakes/">remakes of Max Payne and May Payne 2.</a></p><p><b>Can you speak to the Steam numbers for FBC so far, and how do you view Steam in terms of importance relative to console in the overall mix?</b></p><p>Steam is a very important part of the business of FBC: Firebreak. The Steam CCU is a very easy statistic to dig up, but it isn't everything.</p><p>We aren't naïve; we had hoped for a better launch, but the team here is super-motivated to continue building the game and responding to player feedback. We already reacted during launch week with patch 1.2, making some big changes to the game. As Remedy does, we'll do things with smaller teams in our way and try to solve challenges creatively.</p><p><b>What can Remedy say about launching FBC directly into Game Pass and PS Plus? Did this have the desired results for Remedy thus far?</b></p><p>Subscription services are an easy way for a large number of players to try the game, and it's great for cross-platform matchmaking--you have more folks to play with.</p><p>Being on these services also makes it easy for players to return when we release new updates and exciting new content.</p><p><b>What trends has Remedy observed for the Game Pass/PS Plus audience relative to people who may have bought the game outright? Are you seeing people who have never played a Remedy game before try it out, thanks to the subscription offering?</b></p><p>It's very early days, and we have a lot of data, which is very helpful for a game like this. We can see there is a significant number of FBC: Firebreak players who, for example, don't own Control. The game's a bit bewildering for them, to say the least, but we are going to improve on that significantly. Then, it's pretty clear that players from subscription services tend to stick around for shorter periods than those who purchased the game, but it's also easier for them to return. There is a good number of new players coming in every day on consoles.</p><p><b>What are some efforts you might take to help grow the FBC player base and retain the players you have already?</b></p><p>The simple answer is to develop and release great content to the game now that it's live. Post-launch content, as we have always said, will be free. Listen to the player base to understand what they want; their opinion is what matters, while ensuring that Remedy's creativity remains in the mix.</p><p>We never designed the game to be something that requires daily login for some random stuff, making the game your other job. Instead, you play Firebreak for a while, take a break, and come back when we release new content in the form of Major Updates.</p><p>We feel strongly that what we have in the pipeline is going to be exciting for players. There is some game-changing content in development.</p><p>One of the great things about an online game like FBC: Firebreak is that we receive a wealth of player data and community feedback to inform our decision-making. We read all of it, and we are there talking with the players online.</p><p>The drive within the Remedy development team is incredible to see, but of course, the content ultimately will decide what players think, not words.</p><p>It's been interesting to examine the data and feedback, and see that players who spent many hours playing the experience rated the game significantly higher than those who ended it early. So we know we've got something great at the core of the game.</p><p>We didn’t do a great job at all with onboarding and what we call the “first hours” progression, so players' frustration at the beginning of the game is understandable when there are a lot of systems thrown at you with little explanation, and the tier 1 weapons weren’t hitting that hard amongst other things.</p><p><b>What level of ongoing support can FBC players expect going forward as it relates to new content and updates?</b></p><p>Let's keep in mind the game is barely a week and a half old. We have a lot to process.</p><p>We outlined our post-launch plans before releasing the game, so there are two new Jobs and features coming in 2025. That's still the case.</p><p>Ultimately, we always knew that the launch of these types of games would have an impact on our post-launch roadmap. As it has proven to be, we've rearranged some of our development plans, prioritized certain features, and deprioritized others already during the week of the game being live. The game is live, players' feedback comes in, things will change, that’s what we expected.</p><p>We relied more on building game systems that we can expand in the future, and we can do so, so much more. We are going to discuss what's coming to the game in the near future. It takes time to review the feedback, assess what's possible, and communicate it.</p><p>It's exciting that the game starts evolving now that its live, Remedy is fully committed to FBC: Firebreak. We are all curious to see what it will be like later in the year.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fbc-firebreak-launch-wasnt-what-studio-hoped-for-but-remedy-isnt-giving-up/1100-6532823/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ace Combat 30th Anniversary Movie Highlights Series' Evolution, Teases New Projects]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ace-combat-30th-anniversary-movie-highlights-series-evolution-teases-new-projects/1100-6532844/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ace-combat-30th-anniversary-movie-highlights-series-evolution-teases-new-projects.1231956/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6532844">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Believe it or not, the Bandai Namco fighter-jet series Ace Combat is now three decades old. To commemorate the anniversary of the first game's release in Japan on June 30, 1995, the company has put out a neat video showing off how the series has evolved over time.</p><p>The short movie highlights clips from various Ace Combat games, giving a glimpse of how the colorful PlayStation 1 art of Air Combat (the first entry in the series) transformed into the hyper-realistic near-future science-fiction of the later entries, such as Ace Combat 7.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OYWwUqkBXAI" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/OYWwUqkBXAI" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>In addition to the series sizzle reel, the video also teases some projects in the works to further celebrate the anniversary. For instance, Bandai Namco overhauled the Ace Combat website, and it announced <a href="https://acecombat.jp/en/news/30th-anniversary-event1/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">a special symphony</a> to be held on January 31, 2026 at Japan's Saitama Kaikan concert hall. Bandai Namco also shared that additional projects will be announced beginning in July.</p><p>It's cool to see how far Ace Combat has come since the early days. Being roughly the same age as the series and having grown up in the 2000s, I have a soft spot for Ace Combat 5 and Ace Combat 6. I remember playing the fifth game for hours at kiosks in local Targets, and the sixth was one of the first games I owned on my Xbox 360.</p><p>For those of you who, like me, are looking forward to seeing what the Ace Combat team can do with modern hardware, we'll likely still have to wait for a while. The company <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/new-ace-combat-game-confirmed-new-developer-involved/1100-6495310/" data-ref-id="1100-6495310">announced back in 2021</a> that a new game is in the works, but there's been little additional information since then. It does seem like work continues, though: In <a href="https://acecombat.jp/en/news/fan-message/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">a post to fans</a> today, series brand director Kazutoki Kono wrote, "We're ready. Everything is in place. It's time to take flight once again--toward even greater heights."</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ace-combat-30th-anniversary-movie-highlights-series-evolution-teases-new-projects/1100-6532844/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bandai Namco Summer Showcase Airs This Week]]></title>
            <link>https://gameinformer.com/2025/06/30/bandai-namco-summer-showcase-airs-this-week</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/bandai-namco-summer-showcase-airs-this-week.1231953/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text" typeof="schema:Article"><p>Bandai Namco is holding a Summer Showcase this week on Wednesday, July 2. The digital event will feature new information on upcoming games as well as a couple of exclusive reveals. The showcase begins at 12 p.m. PT/3 p.m. ET.&nbsp;</p><p>In terms of new announcements, a trailer teases the reveal of a new <em>My Hero Academia</em> game and an exclusive trailer for a mysterious new title. The showcase will also feature a gameplay deep dive for Digimon Story Time Stranger.</p><p url="https://youtu.be/zNFuG1BpViI?si=FXYkOQBHfOTkxYfN" width="640" height="360" responsive="1" show_suggested="1" privacy_mode="0" autoplay="0" show_player="1" start_at=""><iframe width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/zNFuG1BpViI" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay" allowfullscreen="true">&nbsp;</iframe></p><p>Furthermore, expect updates for the following titles:</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/sgf-2025/2025/06/06/code-vein-ii-is-coming-in-2026">Code Vein II</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/2025/06/23/check-out-20-minutes-of-the-blood-of-dawnwalker-in-new-gameplay-overview">The Blood of Dawnwalker</a></li><li>Death Note Killer Within</li><li><a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/nintendo-direct/2025/03/27/nintendos-final-switch-direct-shows-more-metroid-and-announces-new">Everybody’s Golf: Hot Shots</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/2025/06/24/little-nightmares-iii-arrives-in-october-and-has-10-minutes-of-new-gameplay-footage">Little Nightmares III</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/nintendo-direct/2025/03/27/nintendos-final-switch-direct-shows-more-metroid-and-announces-new">Patapon 1+2 Replay</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/preview/2025/06/23/eat-or-be-eaten">Shadow Labyrinth</a></li><li>Super Robot Wars Y</li><li><a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/review/tekken-8/aggressively-absurd">Tekken 8</a></li></ul><p>You can watch the Bandai Namco Summer Showcase live on <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@BandaiNamcoAmerica">YouTube</a> and <a href="https://www.twitch.tv/bandainamcous">Twitch</a>. Which game are you most excited to see during the presentation? Let us know in the comments.&nbsp;</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://gameinformer.com/2025/06/30/bandai-namco-summer-showcase-airs-this-week]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gallery: My Goodness, Superdeluxe's Castlevania Anniversary Collection Is Proper Lush]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/06/gallery-my-goodness-superdeluxes-castlevania-anniversary-collection-is-proper-lush</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gallery-my-goodness-superdeluxes-castlevania-anniversary-collection-is-proper-lush.1231950/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Deluxe indeed!</p>
</section></header><section>
<figure><a title="Gallery: Superdeluxe Castlevania Anniversary Collection 1" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/302bf8e793cbe/gallery-superdeluxe-castlevania-anniversary-collection-1.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Damien McFerran / Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure><p>When Japanese physical publisher <a href="https://superdeluxegames.jp/">Superdeluxe Games</a> <a href="https://www.timeextension.com/news/2025/02/superdeluxe-is-giving-us-serious-fomo-with-these-castlevania-deluxe-editions">announced</a> it was giving <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/castlevania_anniversary_collection">Castlevania Anniversary Collection</a> the physical release treatment earlier this year, I immediately sat up and took notice.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2024/11/gallery-unboxing-superdeluxes-lush-switch-editions-for-radiant-silvergun-clock-tower-and-wizardry">Having already seen how excellent the company's other physical editions can be</a>, I couldn't wait to see what <a href="https://www.timeextension.com/features/sometimes-the-only-way-to-preserve-a-game-is-to-own-it-japanese-publisher-superdeluxe-gets-physical">Superdeluxe</a> had in store for this one, as <a href="https://www.timeextension.com/guides/the-best-castlevania-games-of-all-time">Castlevania</a> is without a doubt my favourite game series.</p>
<p>Despite the firm's connection with fellow physical publisher <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/features/limited-run-talks-switch-2-game-key-cards-huge-carts-and-difficult-pitches">Limited Run Games</a>, this edition is different from the one that was released (and then quickly sold out) on LRG's site.</p><div><figure data-videoid="C1rrCdi_XjA" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><iframe title="YouTube Video" src="javascript:''" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" type="text/html" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed3be067jpmykh&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><figcaption><p><a title="Watch This Video on YouTube" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=C1rrCdi_XjA" rel="noopener">Watch on <strong><span></span> YouTube</strong> <span></span></a></p>
<p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>825k</span></a></p>
</figcaption></figure></div>

<figure><a title="Gallery: Superdeluxe Castlevania Anniversary Collection 10" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/7af36cfacbe0a/gallery-superdeluxe-castlevania-anniversary-collection-10.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Damien McFerran / Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>This amazing collection includes a physical copy of the game (complete with a full-colour instruction manual in both Japanese and English), a trading card, a selection of art cards, a four-disc soundtrack, and a bonus "Castlevania: The Secret History of the Crescent Moon" book.</p>
<p>It's worth noting that while the game is intended for the Japanese market, it plays in your system's selected language on Switch and Switch 2. <em>Phew!</em></p>

<figure><a title="Gallery: Superdeluxe Castlevania Anniversary Collection 11" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/366229eb8a2a7/gallery-superdeluxe-castlevania-anniversary-collection-11.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Damien McFerran / Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure>

<p>This particular edition costs ¥8,980 / $62 / £45, but you'll naturally have to cover the cost of shipping from Japan.</p>
<p>"Even with the questionable inclusion of <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nes/castlevania_ii_simons_quest">Simon's Quest</a> and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gameboy/castlevania_the_adventure">Castlevania: The Adventure</a>, the 'highs' on offer are among the highest points in the entire franchise, and a Western debut for <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nes/kid_dracula">Kid Dracula</a> is a lovely treat for retro gamers looking for something new," <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/switch-eshop/castlevania_anniversary_collection">is what we said in our 8/10 review of Castlevania Anniversary Collection</a>. "As long as you’re willing to ignore the lesser titles in this package and you're not too bummed out by the omission of other classic entries, then you’re going to have a very good time with what’s left."</p>
<p>Please note that some external links on this page are affiliate links, which means if you click them and make a purchase we may receive a small percentage of the sale. Please read our <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/advertising">FTC Disclosure</a> for more information.</p>

<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-articles:184386,177893,174607 @ 1751306490 --></section></article><div><p>Damien has been writing professionally about tech and video games since 2007 and oversees all of Hookshot Media's sites from an editorial perspective. He's also the editor of <a href="https://www.timeextension.com/">Time Extension</a>, the network's newest site, which – paradoxically – is all about gaming's past glories.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Damo"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/damienmcferran.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Damo');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/06/gallery-my-goodness-superdeluxes-castlevania-anniversary-collection-is-proper-lush]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Space Marine 2 Will Get A Second Year of Free and Paid Updates and DLC]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/space-marine-2-second-year-updates-dlc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/space-marine-2-will-get-a-second-year-of-free-and-paid-updates-and-dlc.1231947/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Developer Saber Interactive and publisher Focus Entertainment have announced that&nbsp;<em>Warhammer 40k: Space Marine 2&nbsp;</em>will get a second year of free updates and paid DLC.</p>

<p>In a <a href="https://community.focus-entmt.com/focus-entertainment/space-marine-2/blogs/229-june-community-update" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">community update</a>, the studios say that a second yearly season pass is in the works, made possible by the "unwavering support" of the&nbsp;<em>Space Marine 2&nbsp;</em>community. The new pass will offer "new PvE missions, enemies, weapons, and...more", according to Focus, but it's too early for the studio to pin down exactly what's coming.</p>

<p>As well as that second year of content,&nbsp;a major&nbsp;<em>Space Marine 2&nbsp;</em>update is coming in September. Update 10.0 will include a brand new PvP mode, with the intervening Update 9.0 bringing "only balancing changes".</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/space-marine-2-second-year-updates-dlc-shooting.jpg?itok=ajGZlZZF 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/space-marine-2-second-year-updates-dlc-shooting.jpg?itok=s4V_i5o3 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Warhammer 40k: Space Marine 2&nbsp;</em>is getting itself a second year of content.</figcaption></figure><p>According to Focus and Saber, the new PvP mode will take place on a brand new map, and it'll pit two warring Chaos factions against one another. You will also be able to pilot a Helbrute, which pretty much justifies the new mode in and of itself.</p>

<p>As part of this new mode, you can also expect new Chaos-themed armor sets to be added to&nbsp;<em>Space Marine 2</em>, and a new melee weapon will also be added in the form of the Power Axe, so you'll have another way to cleave heretics in twain (or followers of the False Emperor, whatever your poison may be).</p>

<p>Update 10.0 will additionally bring a new class in the form of the Techmarine, which Focus and Saber say they'll reveal more about in the coming weeks.</p>

<p>The latest community update also contains lots of information about how Saber and Focus learned from the new Siege Mode's public test period, so if you had strong opinions about that mode, you might want to check out their thoughts on that.</p>




<p>Elsewhere in&nbsp;<em>Space Marine&nbsp;</em>news, it was revealed recently that <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/warhammer-40k-space-marine-3-revealed" rel="nofollow">a third&nbsp;<em>Space Marine&nbsp;</em>game</a> is in development, and while not much has been revealed about it yet, we do know that it will likely see protagonist Captain Titus returning from the previous two installments.</p>

<p>Not only that, but the devs behind&nbsp;<em>Space Marine 2&nbsp;</em>are currently <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/space-marine-2-devs-hasbro-tentpole-ip" rel="nofollow">working on a brand new AAA-level game</a> using a "tentpole" Hasbro IP. If it doesn't turn out to be a&nbsp;<em>Monopoly&nbsp;</em>Soulslike, I'll be very sad indeed.</p>

<p>You can check out&nbsp;<em>Warhammer 40k: Space Marine 2&nbsp;</em>right now on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2183900/Warhammer_40000_Space_Marine_2/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC</a>, <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/product/UP4133-PPSA04452_00-SPACEMARINESII00" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PlayStation 5</a>, and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/warhammer-40000-space-marine-2/9n9pczwhvp2l/0010" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Xbox Series X|S</a>, and you can read my review of the game (from before its many updates) <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/warhammer-40000-space-marine-2-review" rel="nofollow">right here</a>.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/space-marine-2-second-year-updates-dlc]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Oblivion Remastered gets its inevitable lightsaber mod, made by someone who once accidentally decapitated the entire population of Cyrodiil]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/oblivion-remastered-gets-its-inevitable-lightsaber-mod-made-by-someone-who-once-accidentally-decapitated-the-entire-population-of-cyrodiil</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/oblivion-remastered-gets-its-inevitable-lightsaber-mod-made-by-someone-who-once-accidentally-decapitated-the-entire-population-of-cyrodiil.1231944/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Just in case you don't fancy saving Marty Septim while wielding a literal tree</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>CosmicBoogaloo</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>It's happened. <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/the-elder-scrolls-4-oblivion-remake">Oblivion Remastered</a> <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/oblivion-remastered-gets-fallout-4-style-building-from-modder-who-wants-to-collaborate-on-a-full-settlement-system">modding</a> is one step closer to 100% completion.</p>
<p>The 2025 game about a 2006 game that's undergone some serious plastic surgery has gotten its first <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/oblivion-remastered-best-mods">mod</a> that adds in Star Wars' iconic fighty sticks, so you can pretend to be Suke Lkywalker, Yo Da, or the other ones.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>The modder who's stepped up the plate and <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/oblivionremastered/mods/4702?tab=description">added lightsabers</a> to Oblivin' on a prayer Remastered is CosmicBoogaloo. They've delivered five different colours of light-up sword, all with authentic 'vzzzzhhhh' and 'vwwwummm' sound effects.</p>
<p>There's red, green, blue, purple, and yellow. All I'll say is, if you join the Dark Brotherhood and use a red one, even Lucien Lachance might think you're a bit too edgy. You'll have to console command them into your inventory once you've downloaded the mod, which requires <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/oblivionremastered/mods/32">UE4SS</a>, <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/oblivionremastered/mods/1272">TesSyncMapInjector</a>, <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/oblivionremastered/mods/1331">Runtime EditorIDs (Console)</a>, and <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/oblivionremastered/mods/473">NL-Tag Remover</a>. Think of it as just another force power that involves typing midichlorian-infused item IDs into your brain code.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Oblivion Remastered Mod - Lightsaber sound effects" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/GGbkqdjLY3s?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Oblivion Remastered Mod - Lightsaber sound effects</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/GGbkqdjLY3s?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/GGbkqdjLY3s?autoplay=1" title="Oblivion Remastered Mod - Lightsaber sound effects">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GGbkqdjLY3s" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>CosmicBoogaloo's a modder whose stuff I've seen pretty regularly in my regular trips to Oblivion Remastered's Nexus Mods page. They've also recently added <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/oblivionremastered/mods/4681">a gun</a> into the game, in case you'd prefer to roleplay as John McClane while you save Cyrodiil. I'll be honest, their mods which add <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/oblivionremastered/mods/4232">a literal tree</a> and <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/oblivionremastered/mods/4076">a brick</a> to OR as melee weapons are probably more up my alley.</p>
<p>I also feel like I have to mention that <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/oblivionremastered/mods/3453?tab=description">one of their mods</a> saw them attempt to make the heads of every Oblivion Remastered character type invisible, and they apparently accidentally ended up rendering "pretty much EVERY normal NPC" in Cyrodiil headless. Happens to the best of us.</p>
<p>Anyway, that's to take nothing away from their lightsaber achievement. <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/morrowind/mods/42462?tab=description">Every</a> <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/oblivion/mods/26200">Elder</a> <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrimspecialedition/mods/92440">Scrolls</a> game needs a bunch of lightsaber mods.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/oblivion-remastered-gets-its-inevitable-lightsaber-mod-made-by-someone-who-once-accidentally-decapitated-the-entire-population-of-cyrodiil]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Plucky Squire's Next Update Ups The Challenge With New Game Modes & Enemies]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/06/the-plucky-squires-next-update-ups-the-challenge-with-new-game-modes-and-enemies</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-plucky-squires-next-update-ups-the-challenge-with-new-game-modes-enemies.1231920/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Story time</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure><a title="The Plucky Squire - Challenge Update" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/e585a0ce5fce0/the-plucky-squire-challenge-update.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Devolver Digital</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>We're sure that many of you will have played <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/plucky_squire">The Plucky Squire</a> when it arrived on Switch last year, but did you find the whole thing a little... easy? Well, the next free update from developer All Possible Futures sounds particularly designed for you (thanks for the heads up, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-plucky-squire-too-easy-for-you-the-developer-heard-you-and-said-challenge-accepted">Eurogamer</a>).</p>
<p>The fittingly-named 'Challenge Update' arrived on Steam last week, and will be coming to consoles "soon". As you might expect, this one is all about upping the difficulty, and it throws in two new game modes to ensure it does so. 'Challenge Mode' introduces tougher enemies and a greater level of challenge, while 'Iron Squire' leaves poor Jot with just one life and no second chances — <em>eesh</em>.</p>
<p>On top of that, the new update will add new enemy types, and make some tweaks to the retro-inspired minigames for an extra slice of, you guessed it, <em>challenge</em>.</p>
<p>All Possible Futures announced on <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/thepluckysquire.bsky.social/post/3lsjn2npg4c2d">BlueSky</a> that these additions come alongside "several other features and tweaks" in the update, including select page layout changes and the chance to fast-forward through dialogue scenes.</p>
<p>We had a perfectly pleasant time with The Plucky Squire last year, but felt that its performance let it down. From our tests, things are running substantially better on Switch 2, though some hiccups remain. Hey, the Challenge Update could be the perfect opportunity to dive back in, whenever it comes our way.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/switch-eshop/related-articles:171973,183481 @ 1751308252 -->
<p><em>Will you be checking out this free update when it arrives on Switch? Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://bsky.app/profile/thepluckysquire.bsky.social/post/3lsjn2npg4c2d" rel="noopener" href="https://bsky.app/profile/thepluckysquire.bsky.social/post/3lsjn2npg4c2d">bsky.app</a>, via <a title="External Link: https://www.eurogamer.net/the-plucky-squire-too-easy-for-you-the-developer-heard-you-and-said-challenge-accepted" rel="noopener" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-plucky-squire-too-easy-for-you-the-developer-heard-you-and-said-challenge-accepted">eurogamer.net</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/switch-eshop/related-info/afcc12959eaa842646bec9f57bc6bef4 @ 1751307375 --></div></article><div><p>Jim came to Nintendo Life in 2022 and, despite his insistence that The Minish Cap is the best Zelda game and his unwavering love for the Star Wars prequels (yes, really), he has continued to write news and features on the site ever since.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/JimNorman"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/jimnormann.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('JimNorman');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/06/the-plucky-squires-next-update-ups-the-challenge-with-new-game-modes-and-enemies]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EA Sports College Basketball Is Coming Back, Set To Arrive Nearly Two Decades After The Last Game]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/ea-sports-college-basketball-return/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ea-sports-college-basketball-is-coming-back-set-to-arrive-nearly-two-decades-after-the-last-game.1231917/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The success of <a href="https://wccftech.com/newzoo-july-2024-report-reveals-ea-sports-college-football-25-is-an-instant-hit/">EA Sports College Football 2025</a> doesn't just mean more college football games down the line for American football fans. It also means the return of other collegiate-level sports games from EA, as the company has just pointed to an EA Sports College Basketball game on the horizon.</p>



<p>A post on the <a href="https://x.com/EASPORTS/status/1939703160479637660">official EA Sports X account</a> teases the return of the series, captioned with EA saying "<em>Bring the Madness. Let's run it back</em>,<em>" </em>adding hashtags for college basketball as 'CBB' and the popular EA Sports tagline 'It's in the game.'</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>The last time EA released a college basketball game was 2009, with the release of NCAA Basketball 10, and according to <a href="https://www.extrapointsmb.com/p/memo-ea-sports-looks-to-bring-back-college-basketball-video-games-starting-in-2028-2029-0ef3">Extra Points</a> (spotted by <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ea-announces-college-basketball-game-16-years-after-the-last-one/1100-6532831/">GameSpot</a>), a memo from the Collegiate Licensing Company (CLC) puts the first game in EA's return to college basketball arriving in 2028. </p>



<p>If it hits that release window, then that means the first game in what'll likely be called 'EA Sports College Basketball' will be out almost two decades since the last time EA had a college basketball game on shelves. </p>



<p>Earlier this year, <a href="https://ir.ea.com/press-releases/press-release-details/2025/Electronic-Arts-Reports-Q4-and-FY25-Results/default.aspx">EA confirmed</a> that sales for College Football 25 exceeded $1 billion, so it's not the biggest shock that the company would look to bring back its other collegiate-level sports series. It'll be interesting to see how <a href="https://wccftech.com/ea-sports-college-football-26-madden-nfl-26-release-dates-announced-no-ps4-and-xbox-one-versions/">EA Sports College Football 26</a> does in comparison, to see just how strong the desire is from college sports fans to have these games return as an annual series again.</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/ea-sports-college-basketball-return/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[11 Bit confirm that they used generative AI for The Alters "in a very limited manner"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/11-bit-confirm-that-they-used-generative-ai-for-the-alters-in-a-very-limited-manner</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/11-bit-confirm-that-they-used-generative-ai-for-the-alters-in-a-very-limited-manner.1231914/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>"We should have simply let you know"</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>11 bit Studios</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Well, that was quick. Following rumours last week and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/clone-generating-game-the-alters-may-have-used-ai-to-generate-some-writing-despite-the-lack-of-a-steam-disclosure">our own report just today</a>, 11 Bit Studios have confirmed that they made use of generative AI tools in sci-fi management sim <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/the-alters">The Alters</a> for the translation and localisation of what they say is a very small amount of text. They've also revealed that they used AI-generated assets as placeholders during development, but "in a very limited manner".</p>
<p>11 Bit argue that all of this represents "a limited impact on your gaming experience", but concede that they should have fessed up about it regardless. For context, the game launched on PC with no mention of any AI-generated material, including on Steam, where <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/call-of-dutys-generative-ai-disclosure-reveals-a-glaring-issue-with-steams-policies">Valve requires developers to disclose such things</a>.
</p>
<!--more-->
<p>
All this comes in the form of <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:a564tr4carmvmz72gc2xog5i/post/3lstiwaoxcc2i?ref_src=embed">a Bluesky post</a>. "AI-generated assets were used strictly as temporary WIPs during the development process and in a very limited manner," it reads. "Our team has always prioritized meaningful, handcrafted storytelling as one of the foundations of our game.
</p>
<p>
"During production, an AI-generated text for a graphic asset, which was meant as a piece of background texture, was used by one of our graphical designers as a placeholder," the post continues. "This was never intended to be part of the final release. Unfortunately, due to an internal oversight, this single placeholder text was mistakenly left in the game."
</p>
<p>
You can find a screenshot of the asset in question below. 11 Bit say they have carried out a review of the game and "confirmed that this was an isolated case". The asset is now being updated.
</p>
<figure>

<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>11 Bit</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>
The developers also confirm that The Alters has made use of AI translation or localisation. The game features parody licensed movies you can watch with your clones to boost their morale. These were externally produced, 11 Bit say, and required "last-minute" translations.</p>
<p>"Due to extreme time constraints, we chose not to involve our translation partners and had these videos localized using AI to have them ready on launch", the post goes on, while insisting that 11 Bit had always intended to have the relevant materials properly translated by agencies in the course of a localisation hotfix after release. The hotfix in question is now in development.
</p>
<p>
The developers conclude by noting that the external movies are "approx. 10k words out of 3.4 million across all languages in the game, or just 0.3% of the overall text". The alternative to using genAI to create them, 11 Bit argue, was to release the dialogue exclusively in English. They didn't want to do this, but now "acknowledge this was the wrong call" and that "no matter what we decided, we should have simply let you know". 
</p>
<p>I think the defence that the vast majority of The Alters was made the Old-Fashioned Way by tangible beings of flesh is fair enough. That said, I feel inclined to pass on <a href="https://zaratustra.itch.io/dordle">Dordle</a> developer <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/zaratustra.bsky.social/post/3lstkkc62ns26">Zaratustra</a>'s response to 11 Bit's statement: "If you feel 0.3% of the game's text is not a big deal to have generated with AI, which percentage would you draw the line at[?]"</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/11-bit-confirm-that-they-used-generative-ai-for-the-alters-in-a-very-limited-manner]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>