<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 11:41:42 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Metroid Prime 4: Beyond Playable At Fan Expo Canada This Month]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/metroid-prime-4-beyond-playable-at-fan-expo-canada-this-month</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/metroid-prime-4-beyond-playable-at-fan-expo-canada-this-month.1261353/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>And it's still releasing this year, according to Nintendo!</p>
</section></header><div><section>

<p>We are all pretty excited for <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/metroid-prime-4-beyond-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Metroid Prime 4</a>'s arrival at this stage, we think you'll agree. In fact, apart from the ever-elusive <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/hollow-knight-silksong">Silksong</a>, we can't think of another game that's got us biting on our furniture as we wait for further information about when we can actually play the bleddy thing again, as <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/previews/hands-on-metroid-prime-4-beyond-on-switch-2-is-staggering">we loved it so much first time around</a>. Deep breaths.</p>
<p>Now though, Nintendo has just gone and casually announced that lucky gamers who happen to be attending <a href="https://fanexpohq.com/fanexpocanada/buy-tickets/#multi-day-tier-2">Fan Expo Canada</a> at the end August, will be able to get a hands-on and play the game. They've also, just casually mind, reconfirmed that Samus' latest outing will see a release in the year of our lord 2025. Which is the same year that we are currently in. Hooray for that!</p>
<p>Yes, <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/en-ca/whatsnew/fan-expo-canada-attendees-will-have-access-to-play-the-latest-and-upcoming-titles-on-nintendo-switch-2/?srsltid=AfmBOooPAAaf2Y9seC-9Ow9iIqy8VogVNAAEYA4UWFML6gxabbcr3B07">over on their official website</a>, (cheers, <a href="https://mynintendonews.com/2025/08/04/nintendo-confirms-metroid-prime-4-to-be-playable-at-fan-expo-canada-and-still-due-2025/">MyNintendoNews</a>), Nintendo has had the following exciting statement to make regarding the event:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Nintendo of Canada is inviting you to visit the Fan Expo Canada in Toronto, Ontario, to check out the latest—and upcoming—games for the Nintendo Switch™ 2 system.</p>
<p>Bring your friends and family to experience games like <strong>Mario Kart™ World</strong>, and the newly released <strong>Donkey Kong™ Bananza</strong>. Fan Expo attendees will be able to play upcoming games like Metroid Prime™ 4: Beyond (available later in 2025). Guests will also be able to play Nintendo’s partner titles such as <strong>Street Fighter™ 6 Years 1-2 Fighters Edition</strong>, and upcoming games Hades II, <strong>Borderlands 4</strong>and ELDEN RING Tarnished Edition.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>That's a hell of a line-up, and between some <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/borderlands-4">Borderlands 4</a>, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/metroid-prime-4-beyond-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Metroid</a> and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/hades-ii">Hades 2</a> action, this writer is considering booking some tickets to Toronto for the 21st of August.</p>
<hr>
<p><em>Looking forward to finally getting a release date for Metroid Prime 4? Let us know how excited you are for this one!</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://mynintendonews.com/2025/08/04/nintendo-confirms-metroid-prime-4-to-be-playable-at-fan-expo-canada-and-still-due-2025/" rel="noopener" href="https://mynintendonews.com/2025/08/04/nintendo-confirms-metroid-prime-4-to-be-playable-at-fan-expo-canada-and-still-due-2025/">mynintendonews.com</a>, via <a title="External Link: https://www.nintendo.com/en-ca/whatsnew/fan-expo-canada-attendees-will-have-access-to-play-the-latest-and-upcoming-titles-on-nintendo-switch-2/?srsltid=AfmBOooPAAaf2Y9seC-9Ow9iIqy8VogVNAAEYA4UWFML6gxabbcr3B07" rel="noopener" href="https://www.nintendo.com/en-ca/whatsnew/fan-expo-canada-attendees-will-have-access-to-play-the-latest-and-upcoming-titles-on-nintendo-switch-2/?srsltid=AfmBOooPAAaf2Y9seC-9Ow9iIqy8VogVNAAEYA4UWFML6gxabbcr3B07">nintendo.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-info/4458e89a12ff38471f795c3ea0b57fe0 @ 1754304504 --></div></article><div><p>PJ is a staff writer across Hookshot Media. He's been playing video games pretty much nonstop since the early 1980s, which is ages ago. Favourite genres include RPGs, puzzle games and lovely big single player adventures of all kinds. The weirder the better.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/PJOReilly"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('PJOReilly');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/metroid-prime-4-beyond-playable-at-fan-expo-canada-this-month]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nioh 3 Alpha Demo Feedback Report Highlights Gameplay, Visual and Performance Improvements Coming in The Final Release]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/nioh-3-visual-performance-improvements/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nioh-3-alpha-demo-feedback-report-highlights-gameplay-visual-and-performance-improvements-coming-in-the-final-release.1261350/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Nioh 3 is getting a slew of gameplay, balance, and performance improvements based on the alpha demo that was made available on PlayStation 5 for a limited time only this past June.</p>



<p>Today, Team NINJA and Koei Tecmo published an Alpha Demo Feedback Report on the game's <a href="https://teamninja-studio.com/nioh3/uk/feedback.html">official website</a>, showing the results of the survey players were asked to complete after playing the demo, and confirming some of the improvements coming to the final game based on feedback. These include control improvements to make them more responsive and adding customization options, adjusting the balance of enemies considered too difficult, improving the quality of the environment, improving visibility and balance of stages, and the open field to make exploration elements easier to understand and more well-balanced. </p>



<p>Going into more detail on some of these planned improvements, Team NINJA also plans to improve Global Illumination behavior in stages, reduce the fog in some areas, adjust elements that look as if they have a matte texture, and better optimize the game for a more stable framerate. Considering how the Japanese developer's games <a href="https://wccftech.com/rise-of-the-ronin-is-yet-another-disappointing-pc-port-from-koei-tecmo/">often leave something to be desired in terms of performance even on PC,</a> gathering feedback from PC players as well would have been beneficial, but it's sadly unlikely an alpha demo will launch on the platform.</p>



<p>Nioh 3 was announced during the now traditional <a href="https://wccftech.com/nioh-3-announced-with-action-packed-trailer-launches-in-early-2026-on-playstation-5/">PlayStation State of Play June presentation</a>. While the game may not look too different from its predecessors at a glance, the third entry in the series will set itself apart by adding a new Ninja fighting style that can be switched on the flay, and a revamped level design. Even with its issues, the alpha demo showed that the series has taken a very interesting direction that is likely to improve the already engaging formula of the franchise, combining Soulslike stamina-based combat with an intricate loot system and mechanics more akin to pure action games.</p>



<p>Nioh 3 launches in early 2026 on PC and PlayStation 5.</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/nioh-3-visual-performance-improvements/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Skyblivion Team Now on Its Final Stretch, Release Still Planned for 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/skyblivion-team-now-on-its-final-stretch-release-still-planned-for-2025/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/skyblivion-team-now-on-its-final-stretch-release-still-planned-for-2025.1261347/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Yesterday, Skyblivion project lead Rebelzize <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3MH-BqXk2WA&amp;pp=ygUKc2t5Ymxpdmlvbg%3D%3D" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">posted</a> the sixth development diary for the full conversion mod project. The video is aptly titled 'The Final Stretch Toward Release', and Rebelzize assured fans that the goal is still to launch Skyblivion in 2025, as promised nearly two years ago.</p>



<p>That said, the team still needs volunteers to complete the project. Currently, they are seeking modders with expertise in scripting, quests, record editing, perks, NPC creation, level design, and 3D artists skilled in creating clothing and plant models.</p>



<p>Following this plea, the developer diary shows off the Gold Coast region, a vibrant zone located on the Western edge of Cyrodiil. The city of Anvil has been restructured around a central harbor basin, with expanded commercial, residential, and guild districts. The footage also shows Sutch, a town cut from the original Oblivion game before its release. Skyblivion restores this city to a state that balances decay and bandit occupation with expanded content, including adding a patron divine at a derelict chapel dedicated to Kynareth. Both the expansion of Anvil and the restoration of Sutch exemplify how this project differs greatly from the recently released <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-remastered-back-in-cyrodiil-19-years-later/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion Remastered</a>, which focused on a big visual overhaul and other tweaks, without, however, touching any original content.</p>



<p>On the other hand, the total conversion mod project reconstructs the entire game with new areas, gameplay enhancements, and environmental redesigns, making it feel like a fresh experience even for long-time players of the fourth mainline Elder Scrolls installment.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="The Final Stretch Towards RELEASE | SKYBLIVION Development Diary 6" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/3MH-BqXk2WA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>This philosophy extends to the whole game, including the titular Oblivion realms, which have been expanded and diversified. For example, the Deadlands now include two biomes: The Burn is the one seen in the original game, while The Sever is brand new and was inspired by the zone's rendition in The Elder Scrolls Online and introduces novel environmental hazards and enemy types to enhance gameplay challenge and variety. Lastly, there are now eleven randomly selectable worlds, up from seven, again in an effort to improve variety.</p>



<p>The next Skyblivion developer diary will focus on the Imperial City, the capital of Cyrodiil and the Empire as a whole.</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/skyblivion-team-now-on-its-final-stretch-release-still-planned-for-2025/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Wait, What? Titan Quest II Is A Thing, And Is Out In Early Access?]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/titan-quest-2-early-access-out-now-2000614459</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/wait-what-titan-quest-ii-is-a-thing-and-is-out-in-early-access.1261341/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
                              <figure id="attachment_featured" aria-describedby="featured-caption">
                                                                          <figcaption id="featured-caption">
                    <span>An explosion in the middle of a path, in a battle near and old broken wheel.</span> © THQ Nordic
                  </figcaption>
                </figure>
                                                      </p><div>
              
              
              <p>2006 action-RPG <em>Titan Quest</em> has never really gone away, through a combination of DLC, re-releases, a mobile version from DotEmu, belated console ports, and expansions released as recently as 2021. It remains incredibly playable today, a game I personally return to every few years, a friendly, approachable <em>Diablo</em>-like. It turns out, however, that there’s now a sequel?! <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bY6yb8OoFvw">Announced a year ago</a>, but barely ever talked about,&nbsp;<em>Titan Quest II</em> entered early access Friday 1 August.</p> <p>Released almost 20 years ago in 2006,&nbsp;<em>Titan Quest</em> was the first and last project made by Iron Lore Entertainment–a studio set up by <em>Age of Empires</em>‘ Brian Sullivan–an action-RPG set within Greek and Egyptian mythology. And crucially, it was an action-RPG released midway through the enormous, aching twelve-year gap between <em>Diablo II</em> and&nbsp;<em>Diablo III</em>. It delivered so perfectly, this lower-intensity, more easily accessible loot-hoovering click-fest, and I dearly loved it. <a href="https://kotaku.com/diablo-4-action-rpg-blizzard-torchlight-path-of-exile-1850506636/3#content">Love it, in fact</a>. So much so that just a few nights ago–entirely unaware that <em>Titan Quest II</em> even existed–I suggested that my 10-year-old give the original a go on his Android tablet, given the game and its many DLCs are all free on Play Pass. He’s been playing it obsessively ever since, fueled by his love of Greek mythology and his innate understanding of game systems…and his love for hitting stuff with sticks.</p> <p>It was only because of his boasting that I even learned&nbsp;<em>Titan Quest II</em> existed, let alone had released into early access. He got me to start the game over on my own tablet, and was then boasting that he was a higher level than me. Can’t have that. So I re-installed the game on my PC to see what saves I had. Sadly, everything from the original preceded even Steam, let alone cloud saves, but fortunately I had at least a low-level character still higher than his own on the&nbsp;<em>Tenth Anniversary Edition</em>. And in the process of putting him in his place, I noticed “<em>Titan Quest II</em>” coming up as a search result. I assumed it was some sort of wishful thinking, checked it out, and, er, it’s a thing!</p>

 <p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Titan Quest II | Early Access Release Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="about:blank" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen="" data-rocket-lazyload="fitvidscompatible" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ikmiyR8rutw?feature=oembed"></iframe></p> <p>It’s honestly just weird not to have heard this game was coming. Even though I have a few massive gaps in my perception, as a games critic I tend to have a decent idea what’s in development–but that I was unaware of a sequel to one of my all-time favorite games remains just weird. Then again, a similar sentiment was shared on Reddit’s r/ARPG earlier this year, <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/ARPG/comments/1ja4xm5/how_in_the_hell_is_no_one_in_here_talking_about/">with a post titled</a> “How in the hell is no one here talking about <em>Titan Quest 2</em> Playtest?” No one there continued to talk about it.</p> <p>It perhaps doesn’t help that it’s nothing to do with the original game. While 2006’s&nbsp;<em>Titan Quest</em> was published by THQ, that company ceased to properly exist in 2013 when it went spectacularly bankrupt, auctioning off all its licenses. Eventually the trademark was bought by Nordic Games, the company that would go on to be called Embracer Group, and THQ Nordic remains a publishing arm that handles a lot of former THQ properties. Also, developer Iron Lore is long gone, unable to secure funding for a second game in 2008, with a bunch of the developers going on to form Crate Entertainment, creators of the wildly successful <em>Grim Dawn</em>. Instead&nbsp;<em>Titan Quest II</em> is developed by Grimlore Games, a studio created by Nordic Games in 2013, but that has since only released a barely noticed remake of <em>Spellforce III</em>. It’s all so strange!</p> <p>I’ve just started playing, and honestly, after barely 15 minutes, I’m delighted! This looks and feels like&nbsp;<em>Titan Quest</em>, but updated in a bunch of useful ways. I will continue on and report back in much more detail soon.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/titan-quest-2-early-access-out-now-2000614459]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Metroid Prime 4 still launching this year says Nintendo as delay speculation intensifies]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/metroid-prime-4-still-launching-this-year-says-nintendo-as-delay-speculation-intensifies</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/metroid-prime-4-still-launching-this-year-says-nintendo-as-delay-speculation-intensifies.1261332/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Amid rumours of a potential delay for <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/metroid-prime-4">Metroid Prime 4: Beyond</a>, Nintendo has reiterated the extremely long-awaited new entry in its beloved sci-fi series is still due to launch this year.
</p>
<p>
Metroid Prime 4 was <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/metroids-true-return-is-a-glorious-thing-to-behold">originally revealed to be in development</a> all the way back in 2017, but Nintendo <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/metroid-prime-4-development-rebooted-from-scratch">announced it would be restarting the project</a> two years later, saying its initial attempt had "not reached the standard" it sought from the series. Since then, we've had a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/metroid-prime">Metroid Prime</a> 1 remaster and the enjoyable <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/metroid-dread">Metroid Dread</a>, but it wasn't until last year that <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/metroid-prime-4-gets-gorgeous-first-gameplay-trailer-and-its-out-next-year">Metroid Prime 4 finally resurfaced with a first gameplay trailer</a> and word of a 2025 release.
</p>
<p>
And officially, that release window has stayed firm, with Nintendo <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/metroid-prime-4-beyond-will-give-samus-psychic-powers">reiterating a 2025 launch during its big Switch 2 blowout</a> back in March. However, the lack of updates since then - alongside <a href="https://x.com/kiwitalkz/status/1951705042060497286">claims</a> by YouTuber Reece "Kiwi Talkz" Reilly that Metroid Prime 4 was originally planned to be a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/digitalfoundry-2025-nintendo-switch-2-the-digital-foundry-hardware-review">Switch 2</a> launch window title but was delayed (supposedly the cause of that <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/metroid-prime-4-beyond-no-longer-out-now-as-london-underground-advertisement-is-updated">London Underground mix-up</a>) and still "isn't finished" - has lead some fans to believe a push into 2026 might be possible.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Metroid Prime 4: Beyond – Nintendo Direct 3.27.2025" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/nmwAhBxakw4?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Metroid Prime 4: Beyond – Nintendo Direct 3.27.2025</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/nmwAhBxakw4?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/nmwAhBxakw4?autoplay=1" title="Metroid Prime 4: Beyond – Nintendo Direct 3.27.2025">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Our most recent look at Metroid Prime 4.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nmwAhBxakw4" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
But despite all this, Nintendo has now recommitted to its previously announced 2025 release window in a <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/en-ca/whatsnew/fan-expo-canada-attendees-will-have-access-to-play-the-latest-and-upcoming-titles-on-nintendo-switch-2/">press release confirming its presence at the upcoming Fan Expo Canada</a>. During the show, attendees will have the opportunity to play the likes of <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/hades-2">Hades 2</a>, Borderlands 4, Elden Ring: Tarnished Edition, and - of most relevance to us - Metroid Prime 4: Beyond, which the company adds, is "available later in 2025". So if there's any word of truth to recent delay speculation, Nintendo certainly isn't blinking yet.
</p>
<p>
Metroid Prime 4 was <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/metroid-prime-4-beyond-pops-up-on-the-korean-ratings-board-sparking-hope-well-get-a-firm-release-date-soon">recently submitted for a classification rating</a> in South Korea, raising hopes Nintendo might be ready to reveal a firm release date soon, and Eurogamer's Ed Nightingale liked what he saw of the game earlier this year, calling it the "best example of Switch 2's varied control capabilities", even if you <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/metroid-prime-4-is-the-best-example-of-switch-2s-varied-control-capabilities-but-you-might-want-to-work-on-your-thighs">might want to prepare your thighs</a>.
</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/metroid-prime-4-still-launching-this-year-says-nintendo-as-delay-speculation-intensifies]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marvel Tōkon: Fighting Souls PS5 Closed Beta announced for September]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/08/04/marvel-tokon-fighting-souls-ps5-closed-beta-announced-for-september/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/marvel-t%C5%8Dkon-fighting-souls-ps5-closed-beta-announced-for-september.1261329/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>A PS5 Closed Beta for <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/marvel-tokon-fighting-souls">Marvel </a><span dir="auto"><span dir="auto">Tōkon: Fighting Souls has been announced for 5th-7th September.</span></span></p>
<p><iframe title="MARVEL Tōkon: Fighting Souls PS5 Closed Beta Announce Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/qpYZUnPFqbc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>For those who get in on the closed beta, Marvel <span dir="auto"><span dir="auto">Tōkon: Fighting Souls will have six playable characters, online matches with a shared communal space where you can also enter a spectator mode. Of course, you’ll also want to brush up your skills in a training tutorial and there will be a little more to sample beyond that as well.</span></span></p>
<p>The six playable characters include Iron Man, Doctor Doom, Ms Marvel, Storm, Captain America and Star-Lord. There’s a Japanese anime-infused style to their designs here, and we get to see some of the colour variants like a green Captain America, and special attacks that include a big triple-barrel gun for Star-Lord and Iron Man’s Hulkbuster suit unleashing a Super Saiyan-style beam attack.</p>

<p>The closed beta announcement comes a few days after Arc System Works Game Director Kazuto “Pachi” Sekine gave a little beginners guide introduction to the game’s fighting mechanics.</p>
<p><iframe title="MARVEL Tōkon: Fighting Souls Beginner's Guide" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/v1c9TcMIWfA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Marvel <span dir="auto"><span dir="auto">Tōkon: Fighting Souls</span></span> is a tag fighter but it is pushing the boundary to be a 4v4 system. There are different ways to approach it. You can use one fighter with the other three in the team being assists, or swap through each character to work out the different styles that they have.</p>
<p>The game is a big collaboration between Sony, Marvel and Arc System Works, who have developed some of the most celebrated fighting games of the past decade including Dragon Ball FighterZ and Guilty Gear Strive.</p>
<p>Looking back at Dragon Ball FighterZ, in <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2018/01/29/dragon-ball-fighterz-review/">our glowing review</a>, Dave wrote,&nbsp;“By shattering some boundaries, Dragon Ball FighterZ has combat that’s more than worth getting into, but also a diverse roster and some phenomenal presentation. The Story Mode could have been improved if it were more streamlined, but it’s a mere blemish on an otherwise spectacular game.”</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/08/04/marvel-tokon-fighting-souls-ps5-closed-beta-announced-for-september/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bloodborne Emulation Improvements Deliver 60 FPS on 4GB VRAM GPUs Like the RX 580]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/bloodborne-60-fps-4gb-vram-rx-580/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/bloodborne-emulation-improvements-deliver-60-fps-on-4gb-vram-gpus-like-the-rx-580.1261326/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Bloodborne's emulation on PC with the ShadPS4 emulator has continued to improve in the past few months, so much so that the PlayStation 4 exclusive is now playable with few issues even on a dated 4 GB VRAM GPU like the RX 580.</p>



<p>A new video shared on YouTube by ProteinGaming shows the popular game by FromSoftware running on a fresh version of the excellent PlayStation 4 emulator with a few mods at 60 FPS, 768p resolution on the RX 580 GPU. Some of the improvements recently implemented in the <a href="https://github.com/shadps4-emu/shadPS4/actions/runs/16673907836">emulator</a> made running the game smoothly on a GPU with low VRAM possible, fixing the VRAM leaking issues that also caused stability issues on GPUs with higher VRAM. As such, Bloodborne is now more playable than ever across many different system configurations.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Bloodborne PC VRAM Leaks Fixed! - SHADPS4 0.10.1 60FPS RX 580 4GB" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_QKwj34IF6E?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>The latest official version of the ShadPS4 emulator that made playing Bloodborne on PC a reality is version <a href="https://wccftech.com/shadps4-0-10-0-major-new-feature-bloodborne/">0.10.0</a>. This version of the emulator packed <span>many improvements, which improved the emulation of several titles, including the FromSoftware game and The Last Guardian, another PS4 exclusive that has yet to be ported </span>to PC. In addition to emulation improvements, Bloodborne is receiving plenty of love from modders who have introduced many improvements to the game, including&nbsp;<a href="https://wccftech.com/bloodborne-remaster-improved-pointlights/">enhanced visuals</a>&nbsp;that wouldn't look amiss in a proper remaster.</p>



<p>More information on the ShadPS4 emulator can be found on its <a href="https://shadps4.net/">official website.</a></p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/bloodborne-60-fps-4gb-vram-rx-580/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Titan Quest II Early Access Review – Return of a legend]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/08/04/titan-quest-2-early-access-review/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/titan-quest-ii-early-access-review-%E2%80%93-return-of-a-legend.1261314/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Titan Quest II starts with a literal Greek tragedy. You arrive with the Spartans, the iconic warrior nation, at the height of their power, but it doesn’t take long before fate and the Gods intervene, striking them down with mystical fire and reducing them to nothing. Their ambition angered the goddess, and they paid the ultimate price. Yet, for all of this death and destruction, Titan Quest II begins with hope.</p>
<p><iframe title="Titan Quest II | Early Access Release Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ikmiyR8rutw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>You begin your journey on Proti Island, your created character ready to embark on a tale worthy of myth and legend. Here in Early Access, you can choose from a selection of preset character builds and give them a name, but you have to assume that there’ll be a full character creation tool come the final release.</p>


<p>My Greek hero, Domocles, boasting olive skin and a hefty beard, began the game as all newly made characters should: barely clothed, with a puny sword strike and the ability to dodge. Fortunately, as soon as you beat up a few nearby pots, you immediately begin to build up your inventory, helping you protect yourself from the dangers that are coming your way.</p>
<p>This gear isn’t prescribed either, with different runs granting you different loot at different times. And there is so much loot. If there was really this much loot in Ancient Greece, Hercules would never have made it to the Underworld, he’d have been rummaging in his pack every two seconds.</p>

<p>Holding the attack button sees your character continually swing away with their sword, but it’s best to remember to dodge if you want to last more than a few moments here. It’s only a few short moments before you go from being newborn, bashing pots like a well-tanned Link, to going off to hunt a Gryphon, and you’ll have to be ready for an onslaught of crabs, wolves and undead on your way there.</p>

<p>Titan Quest II feels like a classic action RPG. You fight off monsters, collect loot, improve your weaponry and level up as you gain experience. It’s reassuringly familiar, but it’s also presented with such clarity and vision that you can’t help but be swept up within its historic setting and mythological beasts.</p>
<p>I especially love the music. It evokes the ancient setting so well, with its carefully attuned vocals and traditional instrumentation backed by the swells of more conventional Western orchestral strings. It’s packed with drama, nuance, and emotion, and I found myself repeatedly sitting back and listening to it while writing this article.</p>
<p>When you level up, you gain Attribute Points, and Titan Quest’s stats are dealt with in an interesting way, spread across Might, Agility, Vigor, and Knowledge. These go on to &nbsp;affect three further stats, with Fitness, Resolve and Cunning growing depending on where you’ve placed your previous points.</p>

<p>Alongside Attribute Points, you have Masteries, which deal with your skills. Here, you can level up each of your core abilities, but there’s further nuance and depth brought by then applying modifiers to each one, tailoring and specialising your character in a way that will make them truly unique to you.</p>
<p>These might range from upping the damage against wounded enemies, or giving you a chance to inflict Slow on them, and there’s so much to mess around with that you could find yourself falling down a menu-based rabbit hole. Still, we like that, right?</p>
<p>If you want even more specialisation, Titan Quest II will give you more, and once you’ve unlocked them, you have two further sets of abilities to choose from. Once again, this is Mastery, though this time you’re choosing between Earth, Rogue, Storm and Warfare.</p>
<p>Rather than being ancient X-Men, these specialisations funnel you towards spell-casting, fighting from the shadows or becoming a beast on the battlefield, unlocking further abilities within each one. I love the amount of customisation there is, even in Early Access, and I can see players really gelling with the various systems and options.</p>
<p>If you get things wrong, or head down a path towards Rage modifiers that you decide don’t work out for you, you can hit the Respec Mode, and reverse your choices. This isn’t free though, so expect to spend some of your hard-won Gold if you decide to hit reset.</p>

<p>While it clearly shares a great deal with Diablo, Titan Quest 2 has an undeniably different feel, with fewer enemies, at least at the outset, and a more considered approach to combat. It’s more grounded, which is almost amusing when you’re comparing demons and mythical beasts, but I felt that combat, even on the normal difficulty, was tougher here, making everything feel harder won.</p>
<p>If I was being picky, I’d like a little more weight and impact to your strikes, and hopefully that’s something that can be tweaked through Early Access. There’s also a little wonkiness with controller inputs when you’re in the menus that will need sorting out, but as it stands you can remedy everything as long as you’ve got your mouse lying in wait.</p>
<p>Titan Quest II makes a great first impression in Early Access. Its enveloping world, tough but fair combat and deep loot and experience trees, are perfectly weighted to pull you ever deeper into myth and legend.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/08/04/titan-quest-2-early-access-review/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Just Like With Switch 1, Nintendo Warns Against Using Switch 2 In Extreme Heat]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/just-like-with-switch-1-nintendo-warns-against-using-switch-2-in-extreme-heat</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/just-like-with-switch-1-nintendo-warns-against-using-switch-2-in-extreme-heat.1261311/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>AC adapter</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure><a title="Donkey Kong Sweating Switch 2" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/44ebc7c7f82fc/donkey-kong-sweating-switch-2.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure><p>Whenever the weather in Japan reached particularly high temperatures throughout the Switch's lifespan, Nintendo would release a statement reminding everyone that the OG hybrid was not cut out for such conditions. As it turns out, the Switch 2 is no different (thanks for the heads up, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-warns-japanese-players-not-to-play-switch-2-in-extreme-temperatures">Eurogamer</a>).</p>
<p>Japan has been experiencing a huge heatwave in recent weeks, with unprecedented temperatures launching the region to an <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/jul/31/hot-weather-japan-south-korea-record-breaking-heat">all-time high of 41.2 degrees Celsius</a> (around 106 degrees Fahrenheit). Expectedly, not a lot of household tech is designed to work in this heat, and Nintendo has released a <a href="https://x.com/nintendo_cs/status/1951116935409860651">statement</a> via its Japanese customer support Twitter account to clarify that the Switch 2 is no exception.</p>
<p>The statement reminds everyone that the console is best suited to environments between 5-35 degrees Celsius, with anything outside of this range running the risk of a "malfunction" (via Google Translate). "We have seen several days recently where temperatures have exceeded 35°C," the message concludes, "Please be careful when using the console outdoors".</p>

<p>Now, that bracket is nothing new — Nintendo has issued <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2022/07/dont-use-your-switch-in-temperatures-exceeding-35c-warns-nintendo">the exact same advice for the Switch 1</a> in the past — but it's still something to pay attention to as the particularly sweaty summer keeps ticking on.</p>
<p><em>Have you discovered any Switch 2 problems in the summer sun? Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://x.com/nintendo_cs/status/1951116935409860651" rel="noopener" href="https://x.com/nintendo_cs/status/1951116935409860651">x.com</a>, via <a title="External Link: https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-warns-japanese-players-not-to-play-switch-2-in-extreme-temperatures" rel="noopener" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-warns-japanese-players-not-to-play-switch-2-in-extreme-temperatures">eurogamer.net</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-info/69b1d31e4a00cdde809c26b29239ba08 @ 1754304697 --></div></article><div><p>Jim came to Nintendo Life in 2022 and, despite his insistence that The Minish Cap is the best Zelda game and his unwavering love for the Star Wars prequels (yes, really), he has continued to write news and features on the site ever since.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/JimNorman"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/jimnormann.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('JimNorman');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/just-like-with-switch-1-nintendo-warns-against-using-switch-2-in-extreme-heat]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch 2 First-Party Games Are Not Using NVIDIA DLSS Likely Due to Engine Limitations]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-first-party-nvidia-dlss-engine-limitations/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-switch-2-first-party-games-are-not-using-nvidia-dlss-likely-due-to-engine-limitations.1261308/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Nintendo Switch 2 first-party launch titles don't use NVIDIA DLSS, likely due to engine limitations that would require a lot of work to implement.</p>



<p>Speaking during their weekly podcast, the tech experts at Digital Foundry commented on why the Nintendo Switch 2 first-party launch titles like Mario Kart World and Donkey Kong Bananza don't use NVIDIA DLSS, opting, like in the new entry in the Donkey Kong series, for the inferior AMD FSR 1 solution instead. While it's impossible to make a definitive statement, Digital Foundry believes there could be some engine limitations behind this, as the engines that power these games may, for example, not support motion vectors, which NVIDIA DLSS needs. Without engine support, implementing the upscaler would require a lot of work, which Nintendo may not have wanted to do for any reason.</p>



<p>Technical limitations, however, may not be the only reason why the Nintendo Switch 2 first-party launch titles are not using NVIDIA DLSS, as art direction may be playing a part in this as well. Nintendo games usually have cartoony visuals that don't feature complex shapes or patterns, so even if the edges aren't smooth, they aren't terrible either, reducing the need for antialiasing and upscaling. Mario Kart World is the perfect example of this, as the game looks great even without them.</p>



<p>Even so, there's a good chance that even first-party titles will eventually use NVIDIA DLSS. After all, not only is the upscaler mentioned in the Nintendo Switch 2 Welcome Tour, but the Japanese company actively worked with NVIDIA to have the hardware needed to use the upscaler in the system, so they clearly saw its value. Hopefully, it won't take long for them to use it, as a game like the aforementioned Donkey Kong Bananza would clearly have benefited from it, given the image quality delivered with FSR 1.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Why Isn't Nintendo Using Switch 2 DLSS?" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Yu5lfv4uJ0M?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>NVIDIA DLSS is only one of the features that set the Nintendo Switch 2 apart from its predecessor. You can learn more about the system's offerings by reading Chris's <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/nintendo-switch-2-console/">review.</a></p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-first-party-nvidia-dlss-engine-limitations/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Valve point to Mastercard restrictions as the payment firm deny influencing adult game removals]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/valve-point-to-mastercard-restrictions-as-the-payment-firm-deny-influencing-adult-game-removals</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/valve-point-to-mastercard-restrictions-as-the-payment-firm-deny-influencing-adult-game-removals.1261305/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>No delisting for the blame game</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Valve</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Financial service giants Mastercard have denied accusations that they sought to influence the recent removal of adult/NSFW games <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/valve-are-now-removing-a-bunch-of-sex-games-from-steam-to-keep-banks-and-card-companies-happy">from Steam</a> and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/itchio-apologise-for-frustration-and-confusion-after-delisting-thousands-of-nsfw-projects">Itch.io</a>, <a href="https://www.mastercard.com/us/en/news-and-trends/press/2025/august/clarifying-recent-headlines-on-gaming-content.html">claiming</a> that they have "not evaluated any game or required restrictions of any activity on game creator sites and platforms," and that they allow all lawful transactions. It’s a brief and unequivocal statement, but Valve themselves have since suggested it might not be entirely accurate, telling <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/mastercard-deflects-blame-for-nsfw-games-being-taken-down-but-valve-says-payment-processors-specifically-cited-a-mastercard-rule-about-damaging-the-brand/">PC Gamer</a> that Steam’s payment processors objected to the availability of law-abiding adult games by citing one of Mastercard’s specific rules.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>Rule 5.12.7 is <a href="https://www.mastercard.us/content/dam/public/mastercardcom/na/global-site/documents/mastercard-rules.pdf">one of hundreds</a> governing what Mastercard’s customers, merchant partners, and "service providers" – the actual payment processors who use Mastercard’s network – can and can’t do with its tech, and forbids any transaction "that is illegal, or in the sole discretion of the Corporation, may damage the goodwill of the Corporation or reflect negatively on the Marks." In other words, a game doesn’t need to be breaking the law for its sale to break Mastercard’s rules, and Valve claim this is what allowed payment processors – potentially on Mastercard’s behalf – to push for removals.</p>
<p>"Mastercard did not communicate with Valve directly, despite our request to do so," Valve told PCG. "Mastercard communicated with payment processors and their acquiring banks. Payment processors communicated this with Valve, and we replied by outlining Steam’s policy since 2018 of attempting to distribute games that are legal for distribution. Payment processors rejected this, and specifically cited Mastercard’s Rule 5.12.7 and risk to the Mastercard brand."</p>
<p>It’s yet another direction in which blame-laced fingers have been pointed since Steam and Itch, ostensibly under pressure from payment processors, cracked down on games with adult content last month, with many non-sexual games – and especially those with LGBTQ+ themes – getting caught in the cull. Not that these payment firms have been any keener than Mastercard to admit to being a driving force: Stripe, one of the processors that pressured Itch, say <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/major-payment-firm-behind-itch-adult-game-cull-say-they-themselves-face-restrictions-from-another-banking-firm">they themselves were acting under restrictions</a> imposed by unnamed banking partners. That leaves the only organisation to have readily claimed responsibility as, rather miserably, the religious-backed activist group Collective Shout, who are probably pleased as peas that this whole thing went better than their <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/anti-porn-group-who-tried-to-ban-gta-5-claim-credit-for-steams-sex-game-crackdown">previous attempts at misinformation-led game bans</a>.</p>
<p>In the end, of course, Valve folded, though Itch have at least relisted numerous free games that were previously removed, and are <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/itchio-are-seeking-out-new-payment-processors-who-are-more-comfortable-with-adult-material">actively searching for alternative payment processors</a> who aren’t so restrictive about handling transactions for paid games.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/valve-point-to-mastercard-restrictions-as-the-payment-firm-deny-influencing-adult-game-removals]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo raises price of Switch hardware and Switch 2 accessories in the U.S.]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/nintendo-raises-price-of-switch-hardware-and-switch-2-accessories-in-the-u-s-</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-raises-price-of-switch-hardware-and-switch-2-accessories-in-the-u-s.1261302/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-testid="article-base-contributors"><div data-component="contributors"><p><a data-testid="contributor-name" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/author/chris-kerr" data-discover="true">Chris Kerr</a><span data-testid="contributor-title">, <!-- -->Senior Editor, News</span><span data-testid="contributor-title">, <!-- -->GameDeveloper.com</span></p><p data-testid="contributors-date">August 4, 2025</p></div><p><span data-component="icon" data-name="Clock"></span><span>1 Min<!-- --> <!-- -->Read</span></p></div><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Nintendo has </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.nintendo.com/us/whatsnew/nintendo-switch-pricing-update/">raised the price of original Nintendo Switch hardware</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and certain Switch 2 accessories in the United States to account for shifting "market conditions."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The company didn't provide a more specific reason for the price hike, but the news arrived one day after U.S. president Donald Trump imposed additional reciprocal tariffs on a range of countries. That included a 20 percent levy on Vietnam, where Nintendo has transferred most of its hardware production.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The pricing tweaks were implemented on August 3, 2025, and resulted in the following changes on the official Nintendo store in the United States:</span></p><div data-component="basic-list"><ul data-testid="basic-list-unordered"><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Nintendo Switch Lite // Now: $229.99 (Previously: $199.99)</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Nintendo Switch OLED Model // Now: $399.99 (Previously: $349.99)</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Nintendo Switch // Now: $339.99 (Previously: $299.99)</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Joy-Con 2 // Now $94.99 (Previously: $99.99)</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Nintendo Switch 2 Pro Controller // Now: $89.99 (Previously: $84.99)</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Nintendo Switch 2 Dock Set // Now: $124.99 (Previously $199.99)</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Nintendo GameCube Controller // Now: $69.99 (Previously: $64.99)</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Nintendo Sound Clock: Alarm // Now: $109.99 (Previously: $99.99)</span></p></div></li></ul></div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Switch 2 hardware pricing remains unchanged for now, but Nintendo has warned consumers that certain adjustments "may be necessary in the future."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The Switch 2 has </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/the-switch-2-has-sold-over-6-million-units-worldwide">sold-through over 6 million units worldwide in seven weeks</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, with demand for the console exceeding supply in some regions.</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/mark-deloura-joins-gdc-as-executive-director-of-innovation-and-growth" target="_self" data-discover="true">Mark DeLoura joins GDC as executive director of innovation and growth</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Nintendo shared the milestone within its latest fiscal report, where it also revealed that Switch 2 launch title </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Mario Kart World</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> has sold 5.63 million units globally.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Senior Editor, News, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer news editor Chris Kerr is an award-winning journalist and reporter with over a decade of experience in the game industry. His byline has appeared in notable print and digital publications including Edge, Stuff, Wireframe, International Business Times, and&nbsp;</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="http://pocketgamer.biz/">PocketGamer.biz</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. Throughout his career, Chris has covered major industry events including GDC, PAX Australia, Gamescom, Paris Games Week, and Develop Brighton. He has featured on the judging panel at The Develop Star Awards on multiple occasions and appeared on BBC Radio 5 Live to discuss breaking news.</span></p></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/nintendo-raises-price-of-switch-hardware-and-switch-2-accessories-in-the-u-s-]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amid Metroid Prime 4: Beyond Delay Rumors, Nintendo Recommits to 2025 Launch]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/amid-metroid-prime-4-beyond-delay-rumors-nintendo-recommits-to-2025-launch</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/amid-metroid-prime-4-beyond-delay-rumors-nintendo-recommits-to-2025-launch.1261296/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">As fans continue to wait for a final release date, Nintendo has reaffirmed that <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/metroid-prime-4-beyond">Metroid Prime 4: Beyond</a> is still on track for 2025.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">After a long and bumpy development that has stretched much of the past decade, fans are eager to hear when the highly-anticipated Switch and Switch 2 exclusive will arrive. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">But as the months roll on and gossip spreads of the game needing more time than initially expected, Nintendo has now re-stated that Metroid Prime 4: Beyond will still launch before the end of the calendar year.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Indeed, in a news <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/en-ca/whatsnew/fan-expo-canada-attendees-will-have-access-to-play-the-latest-and-upcoming-titles-on-nintendo-switch-2/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">post</a> advertising the company's upcoming preseence at Fan Expo Canada, Nintendo has stated that Metroid Prime 4: Beyond will be playable there ahead of it becoming "available later in 2025."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It's unclear if this hands-on opportunity is a new demo, or the one made available to members of the public who attended the Switch 2's pre-launch tour. Still, it's a positive sign the game and its launch are in Nintendo's sights — and still coming at some point within the next five months.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The statement comes amid online discussion surrounding the fact that Nintendo has not released new details on the game or fresh footage of it for a little while. The last new Metroid Prime 4: Beyond trailer uploaded to the Nintendo of America YouTube account comes from the company's Nintendo Switch 2 full console reveal back in March. Since then, the biggest news about the game's launch has been the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/confused-nintendo-fans-spot-giant-metroid-prime-4-beyond-advert-stating-that-the-game-is-out-now-sparking-hopes-of-an-imminent-release">advertising slip-up that saw the game promoted as being "Out Now" in a billboard on the London Underground</a>. If only!</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Nintendo Direct: Nintendo Switch 2 - Metroid Prime 4 Beyond</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">At the same time, Nintendo leaker <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GamingLeaksAndRumours/comments/1mfxizw/kiwitalkz_gives_one_last_update_on_what_he_knows/?share_id=riXz3o7YuwdEAKqEAIBlG" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">KiwiTalkz</a> had prompted concern among fans that the game was originally due sooner, closer to the Switch 2's launch, but has been held up due to last-minute snags. This, just days after Nintendo's recent third-party focused Partner Direct (where Metroid Prime 4 would not have featured anyway) has contributed to a sense of unease among fans over the game's arrival.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It has been a long wait for a new 3D Metroid game, lengthened further by Nintendo taking the decision to reboot the project's development back in 2019 after an earlier incarnation being made by Bandai Namco did not meet Nintendo's expectations.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Nintendo's current Switch 2 release schedule for the remainder of 2025 includes Drag x Drive (August 14), Kirby and the Forgotten Land — Nintendo Switch 2 Edition + Star-Crossed World (August 28) and Pokémon Legends Z-A (October 16), plus Kirby Air Riders and Metroid Prime 4: Beyond, which do not have set dates.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Tom Phillips is IGN's News Editor. You can reach Tom at tom_phillips@ign.com or find him on Bluesky </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/tomphillipseg.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@tomphillipseg.bsky.social</a></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/amid-metroid-prime-4-beyond-delay-rumors-nintendo-recommits-to-2025-launch]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Virtua Fighter 6's Combat Gameplay First Look Has Old Martial Arts Movie Vibes]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/virtua-fighter-6s-combat-gameplay-first-look-has-old-martial-arts-movie-vibes</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/virtua-fighter-6s-combat-gameplay-first-look-has-old-martial-arts-movie-vibes.1261293/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Virtua Fighter 6 has its first proper gameplay video, and the fighting game continues to look amazing on the graphics front.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Sega has only released <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/virtua-fighter-6s-new-look-wolf-hawkfield-has-more-than-a-whiff-of-ganondorf-about-him-and-impressive-muscle-jiggle-physics">reveal videos</a> and a <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/virtua-fighter-fans-hope-the-new-game-comes-close-to-matching-this-incredible-in-engine-concept-video">tech demo</a> for its upcoming 'New Virtual Fighter Project,' so this new trailer, revealed during the EVO fighting game tournament, shows us just how impressive the visuals and animations are shaping up to be in actual gameplay.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">We see series stalwart Akira, wearing an outfit fans of Donnie Yen’s Ip Man film series will know well, going up against new character Stella on the Training Stage.</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><div data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>◤◢◤◢◤◢◤◢◤◢◤◢◤◢◤◢</p><p>New VIRTUA FIGHTER Project</p><p>Combat Gameplay First Look<br>-Training Stage</p><p>◤◢◤◢◤◢◤◢◤◢◤◢◤◢◤◢</p><p>Check out the latest <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/NewVF?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">#NewVF</a> trailer that just premiered at <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/EVO2025?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">#EVO2025</a>.<br>More info coming at <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/TGS2025?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">#TGS2025</a>.</p><p>Follow the official global VF account… <a href="https://t.co/jPzmsSUKwt" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/jPzmsSUKwt</a></p></div>— VIRTUA FIGHTER (@VF_SEGA) <a href="https://twitter.com/VF_SEGA/status/1952147917000823025?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">August 3, 2025</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">In truth, the gameplay here doesn’t look that far off the eye-catching tech demo that was shown at Nvidia’s CES event in January. At the time, Sega released what it called a “pre-development concept video” for Virtua Fighter 6, but made clear it did not reflect how the upcoming fighting game would look and play when it eventually comes out.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The video, below, shown during Nvidia founder and CEO Jensen Huang’s keynote speech at CES 2025, features incredibly realistic and fluid animations for a fighting game. We see an Akira mirror match with the kind of combat usually reserved for a martial arts movie.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">But this new video, which Sega is calling a ‘Combat Gameplay First Look,’ shows buttery smooth animations and cool transitions, with a slow-motion effect for whiffs that makes Virtua Fighter look much more realistic than its fighting game rivals.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“No infinite juggles, no crazy magic, no stupid invincible ex, no stupid rage art, no spamming rage drive, focus attacks etc. Just pure fighting, I like that,” commented one fan on YouTube.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“VF6 is feeling like those old martial arts films,” added another. “No drive impact, no heat system, no rev system, just straight up hands. I cannot wait for this to drop.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">We do see some sort of debilitating effect in the gameplay, where Stella appears to suffer damage to her face, but overall it’s a very clean, back to basics approach for video game fighting.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/08/04/screenshot-2025-08-04-094427-1754297084498.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Stella emerged victorious over Akira in the first Virtua Fighter 6 gameplay video.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Virtua Fighter 6 is in development at Yakuza / Like a Dragon studio Ryo Ga Gotoku and is without a release window or target platforms. Virtua Fighter hasn’t seen a mainline release in years, leaving mini-game appearances in Ryu Ga Gotoku Studio’s Yakuza games and the 2021 release of Virtua Fighter 5 Ultimate Showdown to tide fans over.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Expect more on the battle system at the Tokyo Game Show in September. There is no release date yet.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is Director, News at IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/virtua-fighter-6s-combat-gameplay-first-look-has-old-martial-arts-movie-vibes]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rumour: Three Games Were Pulled From Nintendo's Direct Partner Showcase, According To Veteran Games Journalist]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/rumour-three-games-were-pulled-from-nintendos-direct-partner-showcase-according-to-veteran-games-journalist</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/rumour-three-games-were-pulled-from-nintendos-direct-partner-showcase-according-to-veteran-games-journalist.1261278/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><section>
<figure><a title="Missing games from partner showcase 25" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/d71a8727a49bd/missing-games-from-partner-showcase-25.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Nintendo</em></figcaption></figure><p>Well, we were all quite excited, we think it's fair to say, about Nintendo's Partner Showcase last week and, in the end, it seemed <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/features/reaction-switch-2-needed-a-partner-showcase-with-pep-this-wasnt-it">a little light on heavy-hitting or exciting stuff in all honesty</a>.</p>
<p>Yep, we expected a little more sugar, a few surprises to whet our appetites on the third-party front, since the initial wave of excitement, for early adopters at least, may be somewhat wearing off.</p>
<p>Now though, Chris Dring, long-serving game industry journalist, and current Editor-In-Chief and Co-Founder of The Game Business (so he proper knows stuff), has taken to his social media with the following, very teasing, little nugget of info. There were three games missing from the showcase, that he knows of (cheers for the head's up, <a href="https://mynintendonews.com/2025/08/02/chris-dring-says-he-knows-3-games-pulled-from-nintendo-direct-partner-showcase/">MyNintendoNews</a>)!</p>

<p>Hmmm. Well now. Of course, there's no indication of what these games were, but they must have been reasonably sizeable, you would think, for folk to have been made aware of them pre-show. It's not like he's been informed of three unmissable highlight reel games that would have been lost in the mix, we shouldn't think, these may have been somewhat substantial, and somewhat more of what the showcase needed in general.</p>
<p>So what were the games do we reckon? Well, pure speculation, but surely Silksong must have been in the works for a peek...surely? And this particular writer refuses to believe they didn' pull a Vanquish Remastered reveal at the last second (I can dream, can't I?).</p>
<hr>
<p><em>What do you reckon the missing games could have been, and which titles could have made it a better showcase all-round? Make sure to let us know!</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://mynintendonews.com/2025/08/02/chris-dring-says-he-knows-3-games-pulled-from-nintendo-direct-partner-showcase/" rel="noopener" href="https://mynintendonews.com/2025/08/02/chris-dring-says-he-knows-3-games-pulled-from-nintendo-direct-partner-showcase/">mynintendonews.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-info/69b1d31e4a00cdde809c26b29239ba08 @ 1754304697 --></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/rumour-three-games-were-pulled-from-nintendos-direct-partner-showcase-according-to-veteran-games-journalist]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Metroid Prime 4 Is Still Slated for Late 2025, Will Be Playable Later This Month in Toronto]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/metroid-prime-4-still-slated-late-2025-playable-later-this-month/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/metroid-prime-4-is-still-slated-for-late-2025-will-be-playable-later-this-month-in-toronto.1261263/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Nintendo has reconfirmed that Metroid Prime 4 is still slated to launch before the end of the year. They also revealed that it will be playable alongside other Nintendo Switch 2 games (Mario Kart World, Donkey Kong Bananza, Street Fighter 6 Years 1-2 Fighters Edition, Hades II, Borderlands 4, and Elden Ring Tarnished Edition) during <a href="https://fanexpohq.com/fanexpocanada/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Fan Expo Canada</a> in Toronto, Ontario. The expo runs from Thursday, August 21, to Sunday, August 24, essentially at the same time as Gamescom, at the Metro Toronto Convention Centre.</p>



<p>It's definitely great news for all those gamers who have been waiting eight long years for Metroid Prime 4, ever since it was announced in June 2017. Its troubled history is well-known: Nintendo had initially handed development to Bandai Namco, only to change their mind and bring it back to historic developer Retro Studios. That inevitably affected the release timeline.</p>



<p>Between Nintendo's confirmation and the <a href="https://wccftech.com/metroid-prime-4-beyond-gets-rated-in-south-korea/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">recent listing on the South Korean rating board</a> (the GRAC), there's good reason to believe Metroid Prime 4 won't be delayed again. If that's the case, a release date announcement could be forthcoming. </p>



<p>Meanwhile, our Nathan Birch was able to <a href="https://wccftech.com/metroid-prime-4-beyond-hands-on-impressions/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">go hands-on with the game</a> during the Nintendo Switch 2 reveal event: </p>



<p><em>The Metroid Prime 4: Beyond demo on offer at the Nintendo Switch 2 event was relatively brief, essentially consisting of the game’s intro and its first boss battle. The demo opens with Samus touching down in the middle of a pitched battle between the Federation Force and those pesky Space Pirates on the remote planet of Tenmaar. For this section of the game, the usual lonely tone of Metroid games is cast aside in favor of lots of action and general activity, as a larger conflict unfolds all around you.</em></p>



<p><em>Metroid Prime 4: Beyond probably won’t change how most fans feel about the series. It’s more of a good thing that we haven’t got a fresh dose of in a long time, and make no mistake, this is going to be the most playable, technically-sound version of Metroid Prime to date. A few easily-tweakable issues aside, the mouse controls work, and 120fps on a Nintendo console is a real thing that’s actually happening. I still have a lot more I need to play, but it seems like Metroid Prime fans have a rewarding bounty coming their way.</em></p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/metroid-prime-4-still-slated-late-2025-playable-later-this-month/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Virtua Fighter Project Gets Fresh Training Stage Trailer]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/new-virtua-fighter-project-gets-fresh-trailer/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-virtua-fighter-project-gets-fresh-training-stage-trailer.1261260/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>At EVO 2025, SEGA shared a brief new look at the upcoming New Virtua Fighter Project. The trailer shows off some combat gameplay set in the training stage. It's only about a minute, but it does look promising, featuring smooth animations and meaty punches and kicks.</p>



<p>The New Virtua Fighter Project was <a href="https://wccftech.com/new-virtua-fighter-game-is-in-development-sega-confirms/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">acknowledged</a> for the first time by SEGA in November 2024, though the actual <a href="https://wccftech.com/new-virtua-fighter-project-century-announced-by-like-a-dragon-series-developer-ryu-ga-gotoku-studio/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">announcement</a> came about a month later, during The Game Awards 2024, when we learned that the game was being crafted by Yakuza developer Ryu Ga Gotoku Studio.</p>



<p>The game was subsequently <a href="https://wccftech.com/new-virtua-fighter-project-pre-development-video-shows-impressive-visuals-and-animations/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">demonstrated</a> with a 'pre-development video' shared at CES 2025 during NVIDIA's keynote. Later in January, Virtua Fighter fans were able to enjoy the <a href="https://wccftech.com/virtua-fighter-5-r-e-v-o-available-on-steam-new-launch-trailer-released/">release</a> of VF5 R.E.V.O. on Steam, with all major consoles (PlayStation 5, Xbox Series S|X, and Nintendo Switch 2) now <a href="https://wccftech.com/virtua-fighter-5-r-e-v-o-is-coming-to-ps5-xbox-series-and-nintendo-switch-2-with-crossplay/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">confirmed</a> to be getting the game with full cross-play enabled. That should tide them over until the new title is available, which could be in a few years' time.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="New VIRTUA FIGHTER Project | Combat Gameplay First Look - Training Stage" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/KkGmeofGSw0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>While the new Virtua Fighter project was arguably the most interesting news to come out from EVO 2025, there were others. Bandai Namco said that Tekken 8 is getting a new DLC character, Armor King, on October 13 for Season 2 Character Pass owners and on October 16 for all users. Additionally, a new fighter named Miary Zo from Madagascar will be released as DLC this winter, along with a new stage called Baobab Horizon.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="TEKKEN 8 — Armor King Gameplay Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/RBjhCpvBtyk?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>The upcoming fighting game Invincible VS, in development at Quarter Up, has been confirmed to feature Omni-Man as a playable character. To be honest, it would have been weirder if he was not available, since he's such a pivotal character of the IP. Invincible VS is targeting a 2026 launch on PC, PS5, and Xbox Series S and X.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Omni-Man Gameplay Trailer | Invincible VS" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/MEYc6HXd-Ic?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>Finally, Arc System Works announced that a PlayStation 5 closed beta test for <a href="https://wccftech.com/marvel-tokon-fighting-souls-gameplay-showcase/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">MARVEL Tokon: Fighting Souls</a> will take place between September 5 and 7, with registration now open <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-us/games/marvel-tokon-fighting-souls/#closed-beta/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">on PlayStation.com</a>. The closed beta test will feature six playable characters, online matches, a spectator mode, and a training tutorial.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe loading="lazy" title="MARVEL Tōkon: Fighting Souls PS5 Closed Beta Announce Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/qpYZUnPFqbc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/new-virtua-fighter-project-gets-fresh-trailer/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Video: Street Fighter 6 Teases Next DLC Fighter And More Outfits In Two New Trailers]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/video-street-fighter-6-teases-next-dlc-fighter-and-more-outfits-in-two-new-trailers</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/video-street-fighter-6-teases-next-dlc-fighter-and-more-outfits-in-two-new-trailers.1261245/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>C. Viper returns this Autumn</p>
</section></header><section>

<p>Following a leak earlier on, Capcom has now officially released the teaser trailer for the next <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/street-fighter-6-years-1-2-fighters-edition">Street Fighter 6</a> DLC character.</p>
<p>The secret agent C. Viper, who originally made her debut in <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/3ds/super_street_fighter_iv_3d_edition">Street Fighter IV</a>, is scheduled to arrive in Street Fighter 6's World Tour, Battle Hub and Fighting Grounds on <strong>Autumn 2025</strong> for all platforms including the Switch 2.</p>
<p>She's part of the game's third year of DLC, which also includes Sagat (out this week), as well as Alex (<strong>Early Spring 2026</strong>) and Ingrid (<strong>Late Spring 2026</strong>).</p>

<p>In addition to this, Capcom has released a new trailer for the next batch of DLC outfits coming to the game.</p>

<p>Apart from these new trailers for Street Fighter 6, one other Capcom announcement at EVO 2025 was a free title update for the <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/capcom_fighting_collection_2">Capcom Fighting Collection 2</a>. It's out this week and will add Ingrid as well as multiple other characters to Street Fighter Alpha 3 UPPER.</p>
<p>You can find out more about this and Street Fighter 6 in our previous coverage on Nintendo Life. There's also a demo for the sixth entry available on the Switch 2.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:182899,185987,183525 @ 1754307534 -->
<p>Have you tried out Street Fighter 6 on the Switch 2 yet? <em>Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section></article><div><p>Liam is a news writer and reviewer across Hookshot Media. He's been writing about games for more than 15 years and is a lifelong fan of many iconic video game characters.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Liam_Doolan"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/liamdoolan.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Liam_Doolan');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/video-street-fighter-6-teases-next-dlc-fighter-and-more-outfits-in-two-new-trailers]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BrokenLore: DON’T WATCH for PS5, Xbox Series, PS4, and Xbox One launches August 18]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/08/brokenlore-dont-watch-for-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-and-xbox-one-launches-august-18</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/brokenlore-don%E2%80%99t-watch-for-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-and-xbox-one-launches-august-18.1261242/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Currently available for PC.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Shochiku [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/shochiku">Shochiku</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Serafini Productions [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/serafini-productions">Serafini Productions</a> will release psychological <a title="Genres > Horror [670 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/horror">horror game</a> <em><a title="Games > BrokenLore: DON'T WATCH [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/brokenlore-dont-watch">BrokenLore: DON’T WATCH</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [10,037 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [7,629 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [28,220 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, and <a title="Platforms > Xbox One [14,107 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a> on August 18, the companies <a href="https://prtimes.jp/main/html/rd/p/000000357.000053064.html" target="_blank">announced</a>. <span id="more-982086"></span></p><p><em>BrokenLore: DON’T WATCH</em> first launched for PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2351330/BrokenLore_DONT_WATCH/" target="_blank">Steam</a> on April 24.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Serafini Productions:</p><blockquote><p><em>BrokenLore: DON’T WATCH</em> is a first-person psychological horror game from the intricate <em>BrokenLore</em> series.</p><p>Shinji is a young hikikomori, trapped inside his small Tokyo apartment. With unpaid rent, mounting bills, and a family that doesn’t understand him, he feels isolated from the world—and from himself.</p><p>His only escape is video games, but even that can’t ease the crushing weight of his anxiety.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>You’ll explore Shinji’s mind as it unravels, but be cautious. Hyakume, a malevolent entity with a hundred eyes, is watching, waiting for the right moment to strike.</p><p>Your PC is the only link to the outside world. But even there, safety is an illusion…</p></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span><a title="Platforms > PlayStation [48,161 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation">PlayStation</a> Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="BrokenLore: Don't Watch - Release Date Trailer | PS5 &amp; PS4 Games" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/-7Qe20TR_gw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/08/brokenlore-dont-watch-for-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-and-xbox-one-launches-august-18]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This Week’s Japanese Game Releases: Mafia: The Old Country, Gradius ORIGINS, more]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/08/this-weeks-japanese-game-releases-mafia-the-old-country-gradius-origins-more</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/this-week%E2%80%99s-japanese-game-releases-mafia-the-old-country-gradius-origins-more.1261236/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch-2">Switch 2</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox">Xbox</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Corpse Party Tetralogy Pack, The House of the Dead 2: Remake, etc.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><em><a title="Games > Mafia: The Old Country [5 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/mafia-the-old-country">Mafia: The Old Country</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [10,037 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [7,629 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [23,824 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a>, and&nbsp;<em><a title="Games > Gradius ORIGINS [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/gradius-origins">Gradius ORIGINS</a></em> for PlayStation 5, Xbox Series, Switch, and PC are the highlights of this week’s Japanese video game releases. <span id="more-982078"></span></p><p>Also due out this week are <em><a title="Games > Corpse Party Tetralogy Pack [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/corpse-party-tetralogy-pack">Corpse Party Tetralogy Pack</a></em> for Switch, and <em><a title="Games > The House of the Dead 2: Remake [5 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/the-house-of-the-dead-2-remake">The House of the Dead 2: Remake</a></em> for Switch and PC.</p><p>Get the full list of this week’s Japanese game releases below. It should be noted that <a title="Companies > Gematsu" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/gematsu">Gematsu</a> will receive a small percentage of money from purchases made through Play-Asia links. You can also save five percent with our multi-use “<strong>GEMATSU2025</strong>” coupon code.</p><h2><span>Physical and Digital</span></h2><ul><li><em><a title="Games > ACA NEOGEO Selection Vol. 5 [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/aca-neogeo-selection-vol-5">ACA NEOGEO Selection Vol. 5</a></em> (<a href="https://www.play-asia.com/aca-neogeo-selection-vol-5-multi-language/13/70il9h?tagid=578221" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Switch</a>)<ul><li>Asian Version (<a href="https://www.play-asia.com/aca-neogeo-selection-vol-5-multi-language/13/70ilcr?tagid=578221" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Switch</a>)</li></ul><!-- AD: content -->
        </li><li><em><a title="Games > ACA NEOGEO Selection Vol. 6 [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/aca-neogeo-selection-vol-6">ACA NEOGEO Selection Vol. 6</a></em> (<a href="https://www.play-asia.com/aca-neogeo-selection-vol-6-multi-language/13/70il9l?tagid=578221" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Switch</a>)<ul><li>Asian Version (<a href="https://www.play-asia.com/aca-neogeo-selection-vol-6-multi-language/13/70ilct?tagid=578221" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Switch</a>)</li></ul></li><li><em>Basureroes: Invasion</em> (<a href="https://www.play-asia.com/basureroes-invasion-multi-language/13/70img9?tagid=578221" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PS5</a>) – Already available worldwide.<ul><li>Limited Edition (<a href="https://www.play-asia.com/basureroes-invasion-limited-edition-multi-language/13/70imgj?tagid=578221" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PS5</a>)</li></ul></li><li><em><a title="Games > Behind the Frame: The Finest Scenery [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/behind-the-frame-the-finest-scenery">Behind the Frame: The Finest Scenery</a></em> / <em><a title="Games > The Star Named EOS [6 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/the-star-named-eos">The Star Named EOS</a></em> (<a href="https://www.play-asia.com/behind-the-frame-and-the-star-named-eos-multi-language/13/70ijrr?tagid=578221" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Switch</a>)<ul><li>Asian Version (<a href="https://www.play-asia.com/behind-the-frame-and-the-star-named-eos-multi-language/13/70io7b?tagid=578221" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Switch</a>)</li></ul></li><li><em>Corpse Party Tetralogy Pack</em> (<a href="https://www.play-asia.com/corpse-party-tetralogy-pack-multi-language/13/70in2f?tagid=578221" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Switch</a>)<ul><li>Limited Edition (<a href="https://www.play-asia.com/corpse-party-tetralogy-pack-limited-edition-multi-language/13/70in2n?tagid=578221" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Switch</a>)</li></ul></li><li><em><a title="Games > FAITH: The Unholy Trinity [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/faith-the-unholy-trinity">FAITH: The Unholy Trinity</a></em> (<a href="https://www.play-asia.com/faith-the-unholy-trinity-multi-language/13/70ihs7?tagid=578221" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Switch</a>) – Already available digitally worldwide.</li><li><em><a title="Games > FANTASY LIFE i: The Girl Who Steals Time [36 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/fantasy-life-i-the-girl-who-steals-time">FANTASY LIFE i: The Girl Who Steals Time</a></em> (<a href="https://www.play-asia.com/fantasy-life-i-the-girl-who-steals-time-nintendo-switch-2-edit/13/70issp?tagid=578221" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Switch 2</a>) – Already available digitally.</li><li><em>Goat Simulator: Remastered</em> (<a href="https://www.play-asia.com/goat-simulator-remastered-multi-language/13/70hlyt?tagid=578221" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PS5</a>) – Already available worldwide.</li><li><em>Gradius ORIGINS</em> (<a href="https://www.play-asia.com/gradius-origin-collection-multi-language/13/70ifsv?tagid=578221" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PS5</a>, <a href="https://www.play-asia.com/gradius-origin-collection-multi-language/13/70ift1?tagid=578221" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Switch</a>) – Launching digitally worldwide.<ul><li>Premium Edition (<a href="https://www.play-asia.com/gradius-origin-collection-premium-box-multi-language/13/70ig4z?tagid=578221" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PS5</a>, <a href="https://www.play-asia.com/gradius-origin-collection-premium-box-multi-language/13/70ig55?tagid=578221" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Switch</a>)</li></ul></li><li><em><a title="Games > Okayu Nyumu! [5 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/okayu-nyumu">Okayu Nyumu!</a></em> (<a href="https://www.play-asia.com/okayu-nyumu/13/70iipv?tagid=578221" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Switch</a>) – Already available digitally.</li><li><em><a title="Games > Operation Night Strikers [4 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/operation-night-strikers">Operation Night Strikers</a></em> (<a href="https://www.play-asia.com/operation-night-strikers/13/70i97z?tagid=578221" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Switch</a>) – Launching worldwide.<ul><li>Special Edition (<a href="https://www.play-asia.com/operation-night-strikers-special-edition/13/70ig33?tagid=578221" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Switch</a>)</li><li>Asian Version (<a href="https://www.play-asia.com/operation-night-strikers-multi-language/13/70isjz?tagid=578221" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Switch</a>)</li></ul></li><li><em>Mafia: The Old Country</em> (<a href="https://www.play-asia.com/mafia-the-old-country/13/70hlxf?tagid=578221" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PS5</a>) – Launching worldwide.<ul><li>North American Version (<a href="https://www.play-asia.com/mafia-the-old-country/13/70hlu9?tagid=578221" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PS5</a>, <a href="https://www.play-asia.com/mafia-the-old-country/13/70hlud?tagid=578221" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Xbox Series</a>)</li><li>European Version (<a href="https://www.play-asia.com/mafia-the-old-country/13/70hluf?tagid=578221" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PS5</a>, <a href="https://www.play-asia.com/mafia-the-old-country/13/70hluj?tagid=578221" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Xbox Series</a>)</li></ul></li><li><em><a title="Games > RoboCop: Rogue City - Unfinished Business [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/robocop-rogue-city-unfinished-business">RoboCop: Rogue City – Unfinished Business</a></em> (<a href="https://www.play-asia.com/robocop-rogue-city-unfinished-business/13/70ilf9?tagid=578221" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PS5</a>) – Already available worldwide.</li><li><em>Yuukyuu no Tierblade for <a title="Platforms > Switch [17,436 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Nintendo Switch</a></em> (<a href="https://www.play-asia.com/yuukyuu-no-tierblade-for-nintendo-switch/13/70if8h?tagid=578221" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Switch</a>)<ul><li>Special Edition (<a href="https://www.play-asia.com/yuukyuu-no-tierblade-for-nintendo-switch-special-edition/13/70if93?tagid=578221" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Switch</a>)</li></ul></li></ul><h2><span>Digital-Only</span></h2><ul><li><em><a title="Games > 1000 Deaths [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/1000-deaths">1000 Deaths</a></em> (PC [<a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1141260/1000_Deaths_Thousand_Deaths/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a>]) – Launching worldwide.</li><li><em>Apex Legends</em> (<a title="Platforms > Switch 2 [294 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch-2">Switch 2</a>) – Launching worldwide.</li><li><em><a title="Games > Death Note: Killer Within [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/death-note-killer-within">Death Note: Killer Within</a></em> (PS5, PS4, PC [<a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2213190/DEATH_NOTE_Killer_Within/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a>]) – Already available worldwide.</li><li><em><a title="Games > Drag x Drive [4 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/drag-x-drive">Drag x Drive</a></em> Global Jam Demo (Switch 2) – Launching worldwide.</li><li><em>ENDLESS Legends II</em> Early Access (PC [<a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3407390/ENDLESS_Legend_2/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a>]) – Launching worldwide.</li><li><em><a title="Games > Fate/hollow ataraxia REMASTERED [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/fate-hollow-ataraxia-remastered">Fate/hollow ataraxia REMASTERED</a></em> (Switch, PC [<a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2396990/Fatehollow_ataraxia_REMASTERED/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a>]) – Launching worldwide.</li><li><em><a title="Games > Fruitbus [5 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/fruitbus">Fruitbus</a></em> (Xbox Series, Switch) – Launching worldwide.</li><li><em>Gradius ORIGINS</em> (Xbox Series, PC [<a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2897590/GRADIUS_ORIGINS/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a>]) – Launching worldwide.</li><li><em><a title="Games > Hello Kitty Island Adventure [8 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/hello-kitty-island-adventure">Hello Kitty Island Adventure</a></em> (PS5) – Launching worldwide.</li><li><em>The House of the Dead 2: Remake</em> (Switch, PC [<a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3376690/THE_HOUSE_OF_THE_DEAD_2_Remake/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a>, <a href="https://www.gog.com/en/game/the_house_of_the_dead_2_remake" target="_blank" rel="noopener">GOG</a>]) – Launching worldwide.</li><li><em>Mafia: The Old Country</em> (Xbox Series, PC [<a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1941540/Mafia_The_Old_Country?snr=1_2108_9__2107" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a>]) – Launching worldwide.</li><li><em>Operation Night Strikers</em> (PC [<a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3099790/Operation_Night_Strikers/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a>]) – Launching worldwide.</li><li><em><a title="Games > Ritual of Raven [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/ritual-of-raven">Ritual of Raven</a></em> (Switch, PC [<a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2066520/Ritual_of_Raven/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a>]) – Launching worldwide.</li><li><em><a title="Games > SHIKIYOKU: Teru Yumemi in the Nightmare" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/shikiyoku-teru-yumemi-in-the-nightmare">SHIKIYOKU: Teru Yumemi in the Nightmare</a></em> (PC [<a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/914720/SHIKIYOKU_Teru_Yumemi_in_the_Nightmare/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a>]) – Launching worldwide.</li><li><em><a title="Games > Slopecrashers [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/slopecrashers">Slopecrashers</a></em> (PS5, Xbox Series, PS4, <a title="Platforms > Xbox One [14,107 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a>, Switch) – Launching worldwide.</li><li><em><a title="Games > Turbo Kid [4 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/turbo-kid">Turbo Kid</a></em> (Switch) – Launching worldwide.</li><li><em><a title="Games > Voyagers of Nera [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/voyagers-of-nera">Voyagers of Nera</a></em> Early Access (PC [<a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2686630/Voyagers_of_Nera/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a>]) – Launching worldwide.</li></ul><p>The PlayStation 5, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [28,220 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, and Switch titles listed above can be purchased through Japanese <a title="Platforms > PlayStation [48,161 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation">PlayStation</a> Network and <a title="Platforms > Nintendo [22,418 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo">Nintendo</a> accounts using prepaid cards:</p><ul><li>PlayStation Store cards (yen): <a href="https://www.play-asia.com/psn-card-1100-yen-playstation-network-japan/13/70dc0b?tagid=578221" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">1,100</a> / <a href="https://www.play-asia.com/psn-card-3000-yen-playstation-network-japan/13/703xk5?tagid=578221" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">3,000</a> / <a href="https://www.play-asia.com/psn-card-5000-yen-playstation-network-japan/13/703xk4?tagid=578221" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">5,000</a> / <a href="https://www.play-asia.com/psn-card-10000-yen-playstation-network-japan/13/703xk3?tagid=578221" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">10,000</a></li><li>Nintendo eShop cards (yen): <a href="https://www.play-asia.com/nintendo-eshop-card-1000-yen-japan-account/13/704a2v?tagid=578221" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">1,000</a> / <a href="https://www.play-asia.com/nintendo-eshop-card-1500-yen-japan-account/13/70cte9?tagid=578221" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">1,500</a> / <a href="https://www.play-asia.com/nintendo-eshop-card-3000-yen-japan-account/13/704a2w?tagid=578221" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">3,000</a> / <a href="https://www.play-asia.com/nintendo-eshop-card-5000-yen-japan-account/13/705239?tagid=578221" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">5,000</a> / <a href="https://www.play-asia.com/nintendo-eshop-card-9000-yen-japan-account/13/70bkw5?tagid=578221" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">9,000</a></li></ul><h2><span>Demos, Betas, Updates, etc.</span></h2><ul><li><em><a title="Games > Capcom Fighting Collection 2 [6 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/capcom-fighting-collection-2">Capcom Fighting Collection 2</a></em> Title Update (PS4, Xbox One, Switch, PC) – Launching worldwide.</li><li><em><a title="Games > Castle Crashers Remastered [7 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/castle-crashers-remastered">Castle Crashers</a></em> Downloadable Content “Painter Boss Paradise” (PC) – Launching worldwide.</li><li><em><a title="Games > Chained Echoes [7 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/chained-echoes">Chained Echoes</a></em> Downloadable Content “Ashes of Elrant” (PS4, Xbox One, Switch, PC) – Launching worldwide.</li><li><em><a title="Games > Granblue Fantasy Versus: Rising [36 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/granblue-fantasy-versus-rising">Granblue Fantasy Versus: Rising</a></em> Downloadable Content Character Wilnas (PS5, PS4, PC) – Launching worldwide.</li><li><em><a title="Games > Street Fighter 6 [50 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/street-fighter-6">Street Fighter 6</a></em> Downloadable Content Character Sagat (PS5, Xbox Series, Switch 2, PS4, PC) – Launching worldwide.</li></ul></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/08/this-weeks-japanese-game-releases-mafia-the-old-country-gradius-origins-more]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tekken 8 DLC character Armor King launches October 16; new fighter Miary Zo launches this winter]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/08/tekken-8-dlc-character-armor-king-launches-october-16-new-fighter-miary-zo-launches-this-winter</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/tekken-8-dlc-character-armor-king-launches-october-16-new-fighter-miary-zo-launches-this-winter.1261227/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Miary Zo to launch alongside Baobab Horizon stage.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><em><a title="Games > Tekken 8 [58 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/tekken-8">Tekken 8</a></em> downloadable content character Armor King will launch on October 13 for Season 2 Character Pass owners and October 16 for all users, <a title="Companies > Bandai Namco Entertainment [6,732 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/bandai-namco-entertainment">Bandai Namco</a> announced. Additionally, brand-new fighter Miary Zo from Madagascar will follow as a downloadable content character this winter alongside the new stage Baobab Horizon. <span id="more-982067"></span></p><p><em>Tekken 8</em> is available now for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [10,037 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [7,629 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [23,824 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1778820/TEKKEN_8/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a>.</p><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>DLC Character Armor King Gameplay Trailer</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><p><iframe title="TEKKEN 8 — Armor King Gameplay Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/RBjhCpvBtyk?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe title="TEKKEN 8 - 「アーマーキング」 ゲームプレイトレイラー" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Em_rQnZ_RUs?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/08/tekken-8-dlc-character-armor-king-launches-october-16-new-fighter-miary-zo-launches-this-winter]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Virtua Fighter New Project ‘Combat Gameplay First Look: Training Stage’ trailer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/08/virtua-fighter-new-project-combat-gameplay-first-look-training-stage-trailer</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/virtua-fighter-new-project-%E2%80%98combat-gameplay-first-look-training-stage%E2%80%99-trailer.1261206/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
        </ul>

    
    <p><span>More details to be announced at Tokyo Game Show 2025.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > SEGA [2,681 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sega">SEGA</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Ryu Ga Gotoku Studio [501 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sega/ryu-ga-gotoku-studio">Ryu Ga Gotoku Studio</a> have released a new gameplay trailer for the new <em>Virtua Fighter</em> project, showcasing a first look at combat in the game’s training stage. <span id="more-982061"></span></p><p>An official title, platforms, and a release date for the new <em>Virtua Fighter</em> project have yet to be announced. More information will be announced at Tokyo Game Show 2025, which will run from September 25 to 28 at Makuhari Messe in Chiba, Japan.</p><p>Watch the trailer below.</p><h2><span>Combat Gameplay First Look: Training Stage</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><p><iframe title="New VIRTUA FIGHTER Project | Combat Gameplay First Look - Training Stage" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/dfG8XdOwPK8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe title="『New VIRTUA FIGHTER』Project 対戦バトルプレイ First Look" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/AGAJUGw_iJo?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/08/virtua-fighter-new-project-combat-gameplay-first-look-training-stage-trailer]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Guilty Gear Strive DLC Character Lucy From Cyberpunk: Edgerunners Can Quickhack Like She’s in Cyberpunk 2077 — Here’s How It Looks in Gameplay]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/guilty-gear-strive-dlc-character-lucy-from-cyberpunk-edgerunners-can-quickhack-like-shes-in-cyberpunk-2077-heres-how-it-looks-in-gameplay</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/guilty-gear-strive-dlc-character-lucy-from-cyberpunk-edgerunners-can-quickhack-like-she%E2%80%99s-in-cyberpunk-2077-%E2%80%94-here%E2%80%99s-how-it-looks-in-gameplay.1261164/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">At the Evo 2025 fighting game tournament, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/guilty-gear-strive">Guilty Gear Strive</a> developer Arc System Works revealed a first look at Lucy from <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/tv/cyberpunk-edgerunners">Cyberpunk: Edgerunners</a>, and confirmed an August 21 release date for the DLC guest character.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Lucy is the final playable character from Strive’s Season Pass 4, and is lifted from the hugely popular Cyberpunk: Edgerunners Netflix anime that followed the release of CD Projekt’s Cyberpunk 2077. And anyone who’s played the game will instantly recognize the hacking mechanic we see in the gameplay trailer, below.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Time pauses as Lucy selects from a number of Quickhacks, such as Algorithm Malfunction, Optics Inhibition, and Energy Siphon, using Cyberdeck Ram in the same limited fashion you do in Cyberpunk 2077.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">We then see Lucy’s opponent afflicted with the hacking debuffs via icons that display above their character. These icons are the same from Cyberpunk 2077, and appear to clear quite quickly.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">So, does Lucy mark the end of DLC for Guilty Gear Stive? Four years after its launch, it seems more is to come. Arc System Works tweeted to say Guilty Gear Strive “will continue… we look forward to your continued support.”</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p data-cy="paragraph" lang="ja" dir="ltr"><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/GGST?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">#GGST</a> will continue...<br>We look forward to your continued support.<br>皆様の応援を引き続きよろしくお願いします！<a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/%E3%82%AE%E3%83%AB%E3%83%86%E3%82%A3%E3%82%AE%E3%82%A2?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">#ギルティギア</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/GuiltyGearStrive?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">#GuiltyGearStrive</a> <a href="https://t.co/lQKiDyIEV3" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/lQKiDyIEV3</a></p>— GUILTY GEAR OFFICIAL (@GUILTYGEAR_PR) <a href="https://twitter.com/GUILTYGEAR_PR/status/1952101221357232187?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">August 3, 2025</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">That message came alongside a video that revealed Strive has had 3.5 million players since launch, and announced Guilty Gear Strive 2.00, coming at some point in 2026. What that means for gameplay is anyone's guess right now. Perhaps of more interest, the video teased two new characters, which fans are speculating are Robo-Ky and Jam Kuradoberi.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is Director, News at IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/guilty-gear-strive-dlc-character-lucy-from-cyberpunk-edgerunners-can-quickhack-like-shes-in-cyberpunk-2077-heres-how-it-looks-in-gameplay]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Of Course Omni-Man Is a Playable Character in Invincible VS — Here’s Our First Look at Gameplay, and Some Info on How He Works]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/of-course-omni-man-is-a-playable-character-in-invincible-vs-heres-our-first-look-at-gameplay-and-some-info-on-how-he-works</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/of-course-omni-man-is-a-playable-character-in-invincible-vs-%E2%80%94-here%E2%80%99s-our-first-look-at-gameplay-and-some-info-on-how-he-works.1261161/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Invincible supervillain Omni-Man is a playable character in fighting game Invincible VS. The announcement came as part of the EVO tournament alongside a first look at gameplay.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Invincible VS is the upcoming 3v3 tag fighting game set in the Invincible universe. It’s developed by Skybound Entertainment’s first in-house game studio, Quarter Up, and already has a number of confirmed playable characters, including Mark Grayson (Invincible), Atom Eve, Thula, Bulletproof, Rex Splode, and Battle Beast. Now we can add Omni-Man to the list.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Here’s the official blurb on Omni-Man:</p><blockquote>A versatile and brutal fighter, Omni-Man is an excellent pick for or against any team composition. His versatile move set offers options at all ranges: he can apply pressure from a distance with his concussive blast, punish reckless advances with anti-air tools, or close the gap in an instant with his sudden and devastating takedowns. Balanced, efficient and relentless, Omni-Man is a top-tier “point” character for players who want to set the pace from the very first hit.</blockquote><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Of course, this isn’t Omni-Man’s first foray into the world of fighting games. He was a popular guest character in the equally gory Mortal Kombat 1, which included some of his iconic scenes as Fatalities.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">So, we now know seven playable characters in <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/invincible-vs"><u>Invincible VS</u></a>. There will be more, of course. But just how many? Based on comments from Invincible creator Robert Kirkman in an interview with IGN at San Diego Comic-Con 2025, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/robert-kirkman-teases-massive-roster-of-playable-characters-for-invincible-vs-thats-a-spoiler-i-might-get-in-trouble-for-that-sdcc-2025">Invincible VS will have a massive roster</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Fresh from his SDCC 2025 panel where <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/robert-kirkman-reveals-battle-beast-as-a-playable-character-in-invincible-vs-with-debut-trailer-sdcc-2025"><u>he announced Battle Beast for Invincible VS</u></a>, Kirkman told IGN that if fans are wondering if a specific character from either the Invincible comic or the Prime Video animated series will be in the game, there’s a “99%” chance they will be.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“There's so much care being put into being true to the Invincible universe,” Kirkman began. “So if you're a fan of the comics or the show and you're like, ‘Oh, there's a fighting game coming, who would I like to be in that fighting game?’ There's a 99% chance they're going to be in the game. I'll just say that. That's a spoiler. I might get in trouble for that. I don't know.”</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Invincible VS Battle Beast Screenshots</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Kirkman continued: “The lineup is going to be absolutely insane. I'm so glad that we announced Battle Beast. You can't do an Invincible fighting game without having Battle Beast be one of the playable characters. There are other characters like that that will more than likely be in the game. So we'll see. We've got a lot of announcements to roll out. There's a really great team working on this and I can't wait for people to see everything is going into it.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Who would you like to see playable in Invincible VS? Let us know in the comments below.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As for when Invincible VS will be released, Kirkman said 2026, which we already knew, but then he added: “Sooner than you may think… But next year. I'm not being specific.” </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Check out IGN's roundup of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/invincible-season-4s-dinosaurus-has-a-voice-actor-robert-kirkman-says-7-9-seasons-needed-to-do-the-complete-comic-arc-jokes-season-5-will-be-out-in-2032-sdcc-2025"><u>everything announced during Robert Kirkman's Invincible panel at SDCC 2025</u></a> for more.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is Director, News at IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/of-course-omni-man-is-a-playable-character-in-invincible-vs-heres-our-first-look-at-gameplay-and-some-info-on-how-he-works]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fatal Fury: City of the Wolves DLC character Ken launches today]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/08/fatal-fury-city-of-the-wolves-dlc-character-ken-launches-today</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fatal-fury-city-of-the-wolves-dlc-character-ken-launches-today.1261128/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Street Fighter collaboration character shadow dropping soon.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><em><a title="Games > Fatal Fury: City of the Wolves [29 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/fatal-fury-city-of-the-wolves">Fatal Fury: City of the Wolves</a></em> downloadable content character Ken from <em>Street Fighter</em> will launch <a href="https://www.timeanddate.com/worldclock/fixedtime.html?iso=20250804T0000" target="_blank">today at 5:00 p.m. PT / 8:00 p.m. ET</a>, <a title="Companies > SNK Corporation [419 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/snk">SNK</a> <a href="https://prtimes.jp/main/html/rd/p/000000830.000028651.html" target="_blank">announced</a>. <span id="more-982057"></span></p><p>Here is his character description, via SNK:</p><blockquote><p><strong>Ken <a title="Companies > Mas [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/mas">Mas</a>ters</strong> (voiced by David Matranga in English, Yuuji Kishi in Japanese)</p><p>A veteran Metro City street fighter who sets his sights on South Town, seeking closure for an incident to which he was wrongfully tied. Burning with determination and a fiery arsenal of unmatched offense, this former US National Fighting Champion eventually crosses paths with the Legendary Wolf himself—and with that, the wheels of fate are set in motion.</p></blockquote><p><em>Fatal Fury: City of the Wolves</em> is available now for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [10,037 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [7,629 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [28,220 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [23,824 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2492040/FATAL_FURY_City_of_the_Wolves/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> and <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/p/garou-city-of-the-wolves-556c5a" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Epic Games Store</a>.</p><p>Watch a new set of trailers below.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <h2><span>DLC Character Ken Gameplay Trailer</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><p><iframe title="FATAL FURY: CotW × STREET FIGHTER｜KEN" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6byynkBnQOM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe title="餓狼伝説CotW×ストリートファイター｜ケン" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Ge4thpfg9gU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><span>DLC Character Ken Animated Trailer</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><p><iframe title="FATAL FURY x STREET FIGHTER｜Animated Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/qFFoHDENmLI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="餓狼伝説 × ストリートファイター | アニメーショントレーラー" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/eOvY5OS4PzY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><span>Message from Chief Producer Yasuyuki Oda</span></h2><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="FATAL FURY: CotW｜Yasuyuki Oda message video" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/4sHKJh_oJF4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/08/fatal-fury-city-of-the-wolves-dlc-character-ken-launches-today]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Best Deals Today: Elden Ring Nightreign, Razer BlackShark V2 X Headset, and More]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/best-deals-for-august-3-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-best-deals-today-elden-ring-nightreign-razer-blackshark-v2-x-headset-and-more.1261113/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">We've rounded up the best deals for Sunday, August 3, below, so don't miss out on these limited-time offers.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Elden Ring Nightreign Deluxe Edition for $39.49</h2><div catalogid="6792e89c-4ffc-4bb4-b5c2-adea8ff25633" id="226312"><div id="226312" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>ELDEN RING NIGHTREIGN PS5 Amazon Exclusive Deluxe Edition</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Elden Ring Nightreign is a great time with friends, and you can save on the Deluxe Edition of the game this weekend at Amazon. This edition of the game includes additional DLC content, featuring additional playable characters and bosses, in addition to a digital artbook and mini soundtrack. Bandai Namco has continued to release new content for Nightreign, so this is a great time to jump in.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">M4 MacBook Air for $799</h2></div><div catalogid="b6924989-d312-445b-871c-20c712a50785" id="225876"><div id="225876" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Apple 2025 MacBook Air 13-inch Laptop with M4 chip</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">This weekend at Amazon, you can save $200 off an M4 MacBook Air. This 13-inch model includes 16GB of Unified Memory and 256GB of SSD storage, making it ideal for multitasking and running intense applications. All 2025 models support Apple Intelligence features as well.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Dragon Quest III HD-2D Remake for $34.99</h2><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/dragon-quest-3-hd-2d-remake-review">Dragon Quest III HD-2D Remake</a> was one of the most enjoyable RPGs of 2024, featuring a gorgeous remade HD-2D world and voice acting. If you haven't had the chance to check this one out yet, Amazon has copies available for only $34.99. The Nintendo Switch version even got a Nintendo Switch 2 update this week, so you can experience the game with higher resolution and frame rates on your new console! This is by far the definitive way to experience this classic, and now is the perfect time to catch up before Dragon Quest I &amp; II HD-2D Remake this Fall.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Nintendo Switch 2 Available at Walmart &amp; Target</h2></div><div catalogid="b6924989-d312-445b-871c-20c712a50785" id="225854"><div id="225854" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Nintendo Switch 2 Console + Mario Kart World Bundle</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">While <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/tech/nintendo-switch-2">Nintendo Switch 2</a> has been quite challenging to find if you didn't secure one at launch, both Target and Walmart have the highly popular console in stock. This is the Mario Kart World bundle, too, which packs in a digital copy of Mario Kart World for $50. The Nintendo Switch 2 is an upgrade to Nintendo Switch in almost every way possible, featuring a 1080p display with a 120Hz refresh rate, improved Joy-Con, and much more.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Xenoblade Chronicles X: Definitive Edition for $46.99</h2></div><div catalogid="32d78f5f-cb50-4f43-84a1-aaecdcc68343" id="225506"><div id="225506" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Xenoblade Chronicles X: Definitive Edition</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Xenoblade Chronicles X: Definitive Edition launched earlier this year, and it's still one of the biggest RPGs you can jump into on any platform. The remaster introduced numerous quality-of-life updates that were much needed, in addition to a brand-new epilogue chapter. We gave the game <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/xenoblade-chronicles-x-definitive-edition-review">a 9/10 in our review</a>, stating, "Xenoblade Chronicles X was already one of the Wii U’s best games, and this Definitive Edition does more than enough to justify another trip to planet Mira."</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Lexar microSD Express 512GB Card Available</h2></div><div catalogid="6792e89c-4ffc-4bb4-b5c2-adea8ff25633" id="226308"><div id="226308" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Lexar 512GB Play PRO microSD Express Card</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">The Nintendo Switch 2 requires microSD Express Cards, so you aren't able to use the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-sd-cards-for-nintendo-switch">standard microSD cards that worked on Nintendo Switch</a>. As a result, microSD Express Cards have been incredibly hard to find, often only having a few minutes worth of stock at a time. Right now, Amazon has the Lexar 512GB Play PRO microSD Express Card in stock, so if you've yet to upgrade your Switch 2 storage, don't wait to do so.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Marvel VS Capcom: Ultimate Complete Works Up for Pre-Order</h2></div><div catalogid="6792e89c-4ffc-4bb4-b5c2-adea8ff25633" id="226313"><div id="226313" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Marvel VS Capcom: Ultimate Complete Works</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Amazon has opened pre-orders for the brand-new Marvel VS Capcom: Ultimate Complete Works hardcover art book from Udon Entertainment. This book contains 336 total pages, with over 140 pages of new artwork to discover. Set to release in December, this is the perfect time to lock in your pre-order.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Wall-E &amp; EVE LEGO Set Up for Pre-Order</h2></div><div catalogid="6792e89c-4ffc-4bb4-b5c2-adea8ff25633" id="226310"><div id="226310" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>LEGO Disney &amp; Pixar Wall-E &amp; EVE Building Set</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">New <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/tech/lego-toys">LEGO sets</a> are always being announced, and this one is no exception. You can now pre-order the LEGO Disney &amp; Pixar Wall-E &amp; Eve set, featuring WALL-E, EVE, M-O, and Hal as buildable characters. Each character has movable heads and arms, so you can pose them however you'd like. </p><h2 data-cy="title2">Razer BlackShark V2 X Headset for $30</h2></div><div catalogid="6792e89c-4ffc-4bb4-b5c2-adea8ff25633" id="226311"><div id="226311" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Razer BlackShark V2 X Gaming Headset</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Amazon has the wired Razer BlackShark V2 X Gaming Headset on sale for only $30 right now. While this is a wired headset, you're not sacrificing on sound quality, as the BlackShark V2 X packs in 50mm Drivers into its lightweight design. If you're looking for a cheap, quality headset to use for Xbox or PC, look no further than this one. However, if you want something more high end, don't hesitate to check out <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/where-to-buy-razer-blackshark-v3-pro-headset">the Razer BlackShark V3 Pro</a>.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">2TB Samsung 990 EVO Plus SSD for $129.99</h2></div><div catalogid="6792e89c-4ffc-4bb4-b5c2-adea8ff25633" id="226309"><div id="226309" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Samsung 990 EVO Plus SSD 2TB</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Amazon has this huge 2TB Samsung 990 EVO Plus SSD listed for $129.99 this weekend, and if you're the owner of a PlayStation 5 or PC, this is a great option for upgrading your storage. Especially for PlayStation 5 owners, 2TB of extra storage is a godsend, as you no longer have to enter the cycle of uninstalling and reinstalling your favorite games to save space.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Final Fantasy VII Rebirth for $34.99</h2></div><div catalogid="b6924989-d312-445b-871c-20c712a50785" id="225853"><div id="225853" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Final Fantasy VII Rebirth - PS5</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/final-fantasy-7-rebirth-review">Final Fantasy VII Rebirth</a> was my favorite game of 2024, and it's available for just $34.99 at Woot this weekend. This is the lowest I've seen the PS5 copies so far, and I cannot recommend picking it up enough. Cloud and the rest of the party leave Midgar to step into the open world of Gaia for the very first time, and there is well over 100 hours of content available for you to complete.</p></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Aug 3, 2025 7:39 pm</p></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/best-deals-for-august-3-2025]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Guilty Gear: Strive DLC character Lucy launches August 21; version 2.00 update launches in 2026]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/08/guilty-gear-strive-dlc-character-lucy-launches-august-21-version-2-00-update-launches-in-2026</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/guilty-gear-strive-dlc-character-lucy-launches-august-21-version-2-00-update-launches-in-2026.1261098/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/arcade">Arcade</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>The mysterious netrunner joins the fray.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><em><a title="Games > Guilty Gear: Strive [93 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/guilty-gear-strive">Guilty Gear: Strive</a></em> downloadable content character Lucy from <em>Cyberpunk: Edgerunners</em> will launch on August 21 for $6.99 / 880 yen, <a title="Companies > Arc System Works [1,317 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/arc-system-works">Arc System Works</a> announced. <span id="more-982046"></span></p><p>The company also released a trailer teasing next chapter of <em>Guilty Gear: Strive</em>—version 2.00—which is planned for release in 2026.</p><p><em>Guilty Gear: Strive</em> is available now for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [10,037 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [7,629 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [28,220 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox One [14,107 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch [17,436 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [23,824 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1384160/GUILTY_GEAR_STRIVE/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a>.</p><p>Watch the new trailers below.</p><h2><span><em>Cyberpunk: Edgerunners</em> DLC Character Lucy Trailer</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><iframe title="GUILTY GEAR -STRIVE- Season Pass 4 Playable Character #4 [Lucy] Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/7sacvUzDV_Q?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe title="GUILTY GEAR -STRIVE- シーズンパス4 第4弾プレイアブルキャラクター『ルーシー』トレーラー" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/bU4sButXYqQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><span>Version 2.00 Update Teaser Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="GUILTY GEAR -STRIVE- : Future Update Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/98NQzzjXnxc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/08/guilty-gear-strive-dlc-character-lucy-launches-august-21-version-2-00-update-launches-in-2026]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>