<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 13:31:16 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokémon Red And Blue: The Kotaku Retro Review]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/pokemon-red-blue-yellow-green-review-game-boy-switch-2000671975</link>
            <guid>1446985</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        <p><span>The </span><i><span>Pokémon </span></i><span>franchise has undergone so many transformations since</span><i><span> Red </span></i><span>and </span><i><span>Green </span></i><span>(</span><i><span>Red </span></i><span>and </span><i><span>Blue</span></i><span> here in the States)</span> <span>launched in 1996 that these inaugural Game Boy games now feel almost like a period piece. The 8-bit visuals and somewhat archaic mechanics date the original games, but what is most fascinating about revisiting them 30 years later is being reminded that the world of </span><i><span>Pokémon </span></i><span>has evolved just as much as any catchable critter does over the course of a playthrough.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><span>Those original Game Boy games feel retro nowadays not just in their pixel art graphics and chiptune sounds, but in the way that the world within the games feels like it’s in a different, earlier era than it is in modern games like </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-legends-za-review-switch-2-bugs-performance-2000637719"><i><span>Legends: Z-A</span></i></a><span> or </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-scarlet-violet-indigo-disk-dlc-review-terapagos-1851100679"><i><span>Scarlet </span></i><span>and </span><i><span>Violet</span></i></a><span>. As video games have become more advanced, the </span><i><span>Pokémon </span></i><span>universe has developed along with it. The Kanto region of </span><i><span>Blue </span></i><span>and </span><i><span>Red </span></i><span>is somewhat technologically advanced with its tiny Poké Ball gizmos capturing even massive monsters in machines, but by and large, this is the most grounded </span><i><span>Pokémon </span></i><span>has ever felt, and likely will ever feel again.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <h2>A simpler time with simpler struggles</h2> <p><span>The Pokédex you fill out with new data as you catch Pokémon hasn’t become a Rotom-possessed phone yet. The sluggish HM mechanic that requires you to teach Pokémon on your team traversal moves hasn’t been phased out in favor of simply riding monsters across large distances. And even the legendary creatures you find in the corners of its world don’t quite feel larger than life yet. It was a simpler time, one that was likely designed without any notion that it would persist for 30 years, expanding beyond a few freak experiments and urban legends into a world with a cosmic design at its center.</span></p> <p><span>Playing </span><i><span>Pokémon Red</span></i><span>, or any variation of those first-generation games, feels like opening a history text book and learning about how rough it was in the old days for those who set out on their </span><i><span>Pokémon </span></i><span>journey in the backseat of their parents’ car with the overhead lights on trying to angle their Game Boy just right. For some of us who grew up in that era, it’s an unsettling reminder that our past has become history, and only with time and by experiencing change firsthand can we learn just how much better we’ve got it now. Yeah, you can remake these games multiple times and let players journey through Kanto with a run button and colorful sprites, but there is a history here that even </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-fire-red-leaf-green-switch-pokemon-direct-price-2000671938"><i><span>FireRed </span></i><span>and </span><i><span>LeafGreen</span></i></a><span> can’t capture by putting players back in Pallet Town on a Game Boy Advance.</span></p>

 <figure id="attachment_2000671979" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000671979"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000671979">© The Pokémon Company</figcaption></figure> <p><span>Unchanged by the </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-games-best-worst-part-scarlet-violet-red-blue-1850084491"><span>decades of Pokémania that would follow</span></a><span>,</span><i><span> Red</span></i><span> and </span><i><span>Blue</span></i><span>’s unassuming nature means the world it offers up feels more mysterious, unknowable, and rewarding to uncover. In revisiting this game for the first time in over a decade, I decided to avoid checking databases like </span><i><span>Serebii</span></i><span> or </span><i><span>Bulbapedia</span></i><span> and just feel my way through it based on memory and vibes. I knew I needed to find a Pikachu in Viridian Forest before I headed out to win my eight gym badges, defeat the villainous Team Rocket, and become a regional champion, but beyond that, I tried to approach the game like I was playing it for the first time with no expectations or party-building goals, trying to recapture that same sense of discovery I felt in the ‘90s, though that’s easier said than done.</span></p>

 <p><span>30 years later, </span><i><span>Pokémon Red</span></i><span> and </span><i><span>Blue </span></i><span>are immaculately designed games that are also burdened by years of iteration that make some of their more archaic parts insufferable to go back to. You can’t run through the small towns and metropolitan cities of Kanto like you can in </span><i><span>Ruby </span></i><span>and </span><i><span>Sapphire</span></i><span>, the party-wide experience shared across your whole team of six is divided into fractions rather than universally given to every monster on your belt, and HMs, while an interesting way to make Pokémon feel like they exist beyond the simple turn-based battles they partake in, weigh down a party with mostly junk attacks that can’t be replaced and that’ll only be used outside of fights to traverse the world.</span></p>  <h2>As games have gotten better, so has the&nbsp;<em>Pokémon </em>world</h2> <p><i><span>Pokémon </span></i><span>has a weird quirk where it likes to add </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-scarlet-violet-photo-mode-selfie-roto-stick-1850834335"><span>quality-of-life updates diegetically</span></a><span>, with new features or fixes like sprinting only arriving because your character is given Running Shoes in </span><i><span>Ruby </span></i><span>and </span><i><span>Sapphire</span></i><span> so they can do more than lightly jog through tall grass where wild Pokémon reside. The series isn’t merely building better games, it’s building a better, more efficient world with each new entry. The trade-off for these quality-of-life improvements is that some of the mystique has gone away as Game Freak has repeatedly pulled back the curtain and fans have made entire subcultures based around seeing what’s under the hood. Every mystery in the </span><i><span>Pokémon </span></i><span>universe has been documented in online databases, each attack interaction has been meticulously cataloged and rolled into the competitive meta, and there’s someone out there who’s learned how to manipulate stats and is ready to tell you why your favorite Pokémon isn’t viable in a hypothetical ranked match you’re not even signed up for.</span></p>

 <p><span>To know </span><i><span>Pokémon </span></i><span>more deeply doesn’t mean to love it less, but I think most people who are </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-ken-sugimori-original-art-red-blue-gold-silver-1850352781"><span>nostalgic for old </span><i><span>Pokémon </span></i><span>games</span></a><span> are less attached to the games themselves than the adventurous wonder they sparked inside of us at a younger age. </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-red-blue-remake-logan-paul-firered-leafgreen-2000657176"><span>Fairweather fans who stopped playing </span><i><span>Pokémon </span></i><span>decades ago beg for another </span><i><span>Red </span></i><span>and </span><i><span>Blue </span></i><span>remake</span></a><span> like any adult pines for nostalgic media that beckons back to a time when the possibilities seemed endless. Even if </span><i><span>Red </span></i><span>and </span><i><span>Blue </span></i><span>are clunky by modern standards, its limitations gave you a lot of space to fill in as you journeyed through Kanto with your best friend by your side.</span></p> <figure id="attachment_2000671985" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000671985"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000671985">© The Pokémon Company</figcaption></figure> <p><span>Over 30 years, </span><i><span>Pokémon </span></i><span>has gone from the adventures you share secrets about with your friends on the playground to a corporate multimedia juggernaut propping up major esports events worldwide, and people have made entire businesses out of selling (or stealing) merchandise and cards where that once sounded like a pipe dream, the kind of thing your parents might jokingly suggest when you got a holographic card. It’s a phenomenon that has spawned over a hundred games, plenty of copycats, and over one thousand monsters. And it all began with </span><i><span>Red </span></i><span>and </span><i><span>Blue</span></i><span>, games whose seemingly timeless longevity has led to decades of iteration that makes them pretty annoying to go back to.</span></p> <p><span>Maybe you can’t go home again, but it’s important to remember where you came from. And even if there’s no turning back the clock, the foundations on which Game Freak and The Pokémon Company built an empire are still magical. Finding the Pokémon you’ve been looking for in random battles still feels special, and seeing them grow and overcome some of the toughest fights evokes feelings of pride in your furry friend and yourself for having overcome those challenges. As frustrating as HMs are, the mental image of my </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-legends-za-mega-dimension-evolution-raichu-x-2000652246"><span>Raichu</span></a><span> lighting up a dark cave with Flash as we try to find the exit makes him feel like more than just stats and a movepool for battles. Though future games would add more personalization, customization, and the ability to have your Pokémon follow you around the overworld, even in those original RPGs, Game Freak already understood that fostering connection between player and Pokémon was the secret sauce that made its games exceptional.</span></p>

 <p><i><span>Pokémon Red</span></i><span> and </span><i><span>Blue </span></i><span>are not the “peak” of the franchise as </span><a href="https://en.wiktionary.org/wiki/genwunner"><span>genwunners</span></a><span> will have you believe, but they’re also not obsolete games only worth revisiting for the people who grew up with them. Every brick Game Freak and The Pokémon Company placed in building a decades-long legacy was on top of those first trips to Kanto. The franchise owes its longevity to the magic of </span><i><span>Red </span></i><span>and </span><i><span>Blue</span></i><span>, and even if parts of the </span><i><span>Pokémon </span></i><span>world look nothing like it anymore, there’s a reason its fundamentals are still the basis of even the series’ most experimental entries 30 years later.</span></p>      </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/pokemon-red-blue-yellow-green-review-game-boy-switch-2000671975]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Is Crimson Desert A Sequel or Prequel To Black Desert Online?]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/crimson-desert-sequel-black-desert-online/</link>
            <guid>1446982</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Crimson Desert is the long-awaited successor to Black Desert Online, and if you played the first one, it’s only natural that you want to know if Crimson Desert is a sequel, a prequel, or something else entirely.</p>



<p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tag/black-desert-online/" id="1332" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Black Desert Online</a> was an immediate hit, selling several hundred thousand copies. Now, in 2026, millions of players have registered, and the MMO has grossed billions. There’s a lot of love for Black Desert Online, which is why its direct connections to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tag/crimson-desert/" id="888" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Crimson Desert</a> are fascinating for both old and new players.</p>







<h2 id="h-is-crimson-desert-a-prequel-to-black-desert-online">Is Crimson Desert A Prequel To Black Desert Online?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>New world. Credit to Pearl Abyss</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>No, despite being initially conceived as a prequel to Black Desert Online, Crimson Desert has dropped any notion of this idea.</strong></p>



<p>There’s your first big question about this story answered: Crimson Desert is not a prequel. Pearl Abyss has mentioned in interviews that the goal was to have Crimson Desert be another MMO, serving as a precursor to Black Desert Online.</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>More Insider Gaming:</strong> <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/crimson-desert-devs-say-premium-price-avoids-microtransactions/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Crimson Desert Devs Say Premium Price Avoids Microtransactions</a></li>
</ul>



<p>Abyss’ vision and scope for the project quickly expanded, which is why Crimson Desert is not a prequel.</p>







<h2 id="h-is-crimson-desert-a-sequel-to-black-desert-online">Is Crimson Desert A Sequel To Black Desert Online?</h2>



<p><strong>Crimson Desert is also not a direct sequel to Black Desert Online, and it’s closer to a spiritual successor than having any direct ties to the original game.</strong></p>



<p>There are many key differences between Crimson Desert and Black Desert Online—including its single-player and multiplayer focus—but the world itself is another big one.</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>More Insider Gaming:</strong> <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/crimson-desert-hands-on-preview-a-little-refining-is-needed-but-has-promise/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Crimson Desert HANDS-ON PREVIEW</a></li>
</ul>



<p>Crimson Desert is set in Pywel, whereas Black Desert Online was separated into several key and distinct regions. Aside from the setting being new, there are also new characters and a fresh narrative—underlining that while the game remains grounded in the same universe, this is a whole new game, and isn’t a sequel or prequel!</p>



<p>The main positive about this creative decision is that if you haven’t played Black Desert Online, you won’t need to play catch-up and can jump right in.</p>



<p>But if you have played Black Desert Online at any point, share your thoughts on the game and what you’re hoping for in Crimson Desert. You can do so via the usual place: The <a href="https://discord.com/channels/1433093283558719611/1433112738133180426" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>If you’re worried about delays or anything similar, you should be reassured by the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/crimson-desert-goes-gold/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Crimson Desert went Gold two months before release</a>.</p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/crimson-desert-sequel-black-desert-online/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Reboot Develop organiser issued bankruptcy order]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/reboot-develop-organiser-issued-bankruptcy-order</link>
            <guid>1446973</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-testid="article-base-contributors"><div data-component="contributors"><a data-testid="contributor-name" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/author/chris-kerr" data-discover="true">Chris Kerr<!-- -->,</a><p><span data-testid="contributor-title">Senior Editor, News</span><span data-testid="contributor-title">, <!-- -->GameDeveloper.com</span></p><p data-testid="contributors-date">February 26, 2026</p></div><p><span data-component="icon" data-name="Clock"></span><span data-testid="article-read-time-text">2 Min<!-- --> <!-- -->Read</span></p></div><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The future of boutique game development conference Reboot Develop has been cast into doubt after organizer Digitalna Avantura was hit with a bankruptcy order over roughly €520,000 in unpaid debts.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.tportal.hr/vijesti/clanak/digitalna-avantura-gamera-damira-durovica-pred-stecajem-zbog-520-000-eura-duga-20260209?ref=gamesmarket.global&amp;meta_refresh=1">As reported by Croatian outlet tportal</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> (via Google Translate), financial agency Fina initiated proceedings against Digitalna Avantura in the Commercial Court of Zagreb after determining the company lacks the assets to cover a repayment.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The court has now called on the creditors of Digitalna Avantura to advance €2,000 by the end of February to cover the costs of initiating bankruptcy.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Digitalna Avantura is owned by Damira Đurovića, who is listed as a founder, director, and representative on the company's latest annual income statement (shared on the Fina website and viewed by tportal).&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Reboot Develop celebrated its 10th anniversary in 2025 in the Croatian city of Dubrovnik. The conference website (</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://rebootdevelopblue.com/">which remains live</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">) said Reboot Develop aimed to increase its attendance to over 2,700 industry professionals from more than 850 companies last year.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ea-makes-layoffs-at-skate-developer-full-circle" target="_self" data-discover="true">EA makes layoffs at Skate developer Full Circle</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">There is no mention of a 2026 event on the event website. That's despite Reboot Develop </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:7326141850128433152/">advertising "super early bird" tickets on its LinkedIn page</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> for a prospective 2026 conference around nine months ago. It's unclear whether those who accepted that offer will be issued refunds.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">At the time, Reboot Develop said the conference was hitting a "capacity ceiling" and implored attendees to secure their spot ahead of Reboot Develop 2026, which was slated to take place from April 20 to April 22, 2026. There has been no mention of the event since.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Meanwhile, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/organiser-of-reboot-develop-issued-with-bankruptcy-order-underlining-fears-over-events-future">GamesIndustry.biz has been in contact with the Dubrovnik Sheraton</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">—which has hosted the conference since 2015—and confirmed the hotel has not been booked to host a 2026 event.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer has reached out to Reboot Develop for comment.&nbsp;</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Senior Editor, News, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer news editor Chris Kerr is an award-winning reporter with over a decade of experience in the game industry. His byline has appeared in notable print and digital publications including Edge, Stuff, Wireframe, International Business Times, and&nbsp;PocketGamer.biz. Throughout his career, Chris has covered major industry events including GDC, PAX Australia, Gamescom, Paris Games Week, and Develop Brighton.&nbsp;</span></p></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/reboot-develop-organiser-issued-bankruptcy-order]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Skate developer Full Circle confirms layoffs, claims commitment to the game's future "remains strong"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/skate-developer-full-circle-confirms-layoffs-claims-commitment-to-the-games-future-remains-strong</link>
            <guid>1446970</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>

  <figure>
      <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Skate-screenshot-showing-a-boarder-doing-tricks-high-above-a-city.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Skate-screenshot-showing-a-boarder-doing-tricks-high-above-a-city.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Skate-screenshot-showing-a-boarder-doing-tricks-high-above-a-city.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Skate-screenshot-showing-a-boarder-doing-tricks-high-above-a-city.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Skate-screenshot-showing-a-boarder-doing-tricks-high-above-a-city.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Skate-screenshot-showing-a-boarder-doing-tricks-high-above-a-city.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Skate-screenshot-showing-a-boarder-doing-tricks-high-above-a-city.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Skate-screenshot-showing-a-boarder-doing-tricks-high-above-a-city.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Skate-screenshot-showing-a-boarder-doing-tricks-high-above-a-city.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>EA/Full Circle</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Skate developer Full Circle - which is part of EA's studio network - has announced "changes to [its] team structure", that will result in layoffs at the company.</p>
<p>Full Circle said it is "transforming" the studio, which will see it "reshaping to better support Skate's long-term future and focus the team on the things that matter most" to players. This transformation, it said, will include layoffs.</p>
<!-- code from Primis - Eurogamer.net - eurogamer.net -->
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<!-- code from Primis -->
<p>"The teammates affected are talented colleagues and friends who helped build the foundation of <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/skate-2025">Skate.</a> Their creativity and dedication are deeply ingrained in what players experience today," <a href="https://www.ea.com/ea-studios/full-circle/news/an-update-from-fullcircle">Full Circle wrote in a blog post</a>, stressing the "decision is not a reflection of their impact and we're committed to supporting them through this transition".</p>
<p>As for Skate, which was released in September and proved especially popular on its first day <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/with-players-stuck-in-lengthy-queues-for-online-only-skate-those-who-made-it-in-are-comparing-its-bouncing-belly-flopping-traversal-to-mario-64">leading to lengthy queues</a>, work will still continue. "We look forward to working with you as we move faster, listen more closely, and deliver consistently for all of you," Full Circle said. "Our commitment to Skate, and to the millions of players who believe in it, remains strong."</p>
<p>The studio did not say how many Full Circle employees are affected by the this week's layoffs. Eurogamer has asked EA for a comment and will update when we know more.</p>
<p>"After an absolute age, EA's wheelie classic is back with great handling and a whole world of slightly jarring niceness," reads our <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/skate-early-access-review">Skate early access review</a>.</p>

        </div>

  
      </article>



  



  <div>
      <p>
        <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/skate-2025">Skate.</a>
      </p>

      <p>
            <span>PS4</span>, 
            <span>PS5</span>, 
            <span>Xbox One</span>, 
            <span>Xbox Series X/S</span>, 
            <span>PC</span>
      </p>





</div>

  <section>
    <span>Related topics</span>

    
  </section>
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/skate-developer-full-circle-confirms-layoffs-claims-commitment-to-the-games-future-remains-strong]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox’s Best Path Forward Is Being Spun off to Be Free of Microsoft, Says Analyst]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/xbox-best-path-spun-off-free-microsoft-says-analyst/</link>
            <guid>1446955</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>The <a href="https://wccftech.com/microsoft-phil-spencer-retires-sarah-bond-resigns-asha-sharma-takes-over-xbox/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sudden leadership change at the helm of <strong>Microsoft Gaming</strong> and <strong>Xbox</strong></a>, with <strong>Phil Spencer</strong> and <strong>Sarah Bond</strong> leaving their roles, has inevitably dominated the gaming industry conversation over the past few days. </p>



<p>While Phil Spencer's retirement was in the air (<a href="https://wccftech.com/phil-spencer-retire-following-next-gen-xbox-launch/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">despite Microsoft denying it just a few months ago</a>) after a long tenure, it was believed that Sarah Bond, who had been president of Xbox since October 2023, would be the natural successor. Bond has instead left the company, and a subsequent report by The Verge <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/sarah-bond-phil-spencer-no-one-liked-everything-is-an-xbox-strategy/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">revealed that she was the main driver behind the controversial 'This Is an Xbox' marketing campaign</a></strong>, which fans didn't take well at all.</p>



<p>Microsoft has instead selected <strong>Asha Sharma</strong>, previously president of CoreAI, as the new CEO of the gaming division. It was another decision that has so far proven controversial; Xbox founder <strong>Seamus Blackley</strong>, who first thought of a Microsoft console and pitched it to Bill Gates over twenty-five years ago, openly <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/xbox-founder-thinks-new-xbox-ceo-will-sunset-division-ai-business/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">shared his opinion that Sharma will be Xbox's caretaker toward the eventual division's shutdown</a></strong> in favor of Microsoft's core businesses (chiefly AI-related).</p>



<p>His concerns are perhaps a little extreme, but certainly not entirely unfounded. <a href="https://alineaanalytics.substack.com/p/game-pass-500k-new-players-for-star?utm_source=post-email-title&amp;publication_id=5141681&amp;post_id=189048025&amp;utm_campaign=email-post-title&amp;isFreemail=true&amp;r=4mhhpq&amp;triedRedirect=true&amp;utm_medium=email" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">In a recent <strong>Alinea Analytics</strong> newsletter</a>, Head of Market Analysis <strong>Rhys Elliott</strong> mused that making games is more of an art than a business for a tech giant, adding that it's a "hits-driven" business with long development timelines. As such, while he believes that Sharma could perhaps do well as an executive <a href="https://wccftech.com/new-xbox-ceo-targeted-supposedly-using-ai-bot-x/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">even without being a gamer</a>, Elliott adds that to really fly,<strong> Xbox should become its own independent entity</strong>: </p>



<p><em>Despite Sharma’s potential, <strong>the most logical long-term move is to spin Xbox off</strong>. It has Activision, Bethesda, and some of the most valuable IP in the business. A standalone Xbox would be free from the burden of matching the ROI of Azure or the ubiquity of Windows. It could return to its roots as a scrappier, game-focused competitor.</em></p>



<p><em>Sharma may well be the person to prepare Xbox for a transition away from Game Pass stagnation and ‘’this is an Xbox!’’, but for the brand to truly reclaim its 25-year legacy, <strong>it needs to stop being a footnote for Satya Nadella and become something of its own</strong>. It’s big enough.</em></p>



<p><em><strong>The best pathway forward, in my eyes, is to set Xbox free</strong>. Not by euthanising it, but by spinning it off. Gaming is in a better place with a strong, independent Xbox.</em></p>



<p>It's hard to imagine right now, but <strong>it could perhaps happen in the future</strong> if Microsoft opts to focus on surer bets than gaming. Of course, right now, it's more of a mental exercise than anything else, but what do you think of the possibility? Vote in the poll below and voice your thoughts in the comments.</p>



<div id="democracy-1535" data-opts="{&quot;ajax_url&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/wccftech.com\/wp-admin\/admin-ajax.php&quot;,&quot;pid&quot;:1535,&quot;max_answs&quot;:0,&quot;answs_max_height&quot;:&quot;500&quot;,&quot;anim_speed&quot;:&quot;400&quot;,&quot;line_anim_speed&quot;:1500}"><p><strong>Would you like to see Xbox going independent from Microsoft?</strong></p></div>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/xbox-best-path-spun-off-free-microsoft-says-analyst/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Today’s Strands #725 Hints and Answers for February 26, 2026]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/todays-strands-725-hints-and-answers-for-february-26-2026/</link>
            <guid>1446946</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tag/strands/" id="3586">Strands </a>is a daily word search puzzle game from <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tag/new-york-times/" id="2981">The New York Times</a>. It is a relatively new game, launched in 2024, in which players seek a common theme among words in a 6×8 letter grid.</p>



<p>Whether it’s your first time playing or you’re a Strands veteran, today’s tips and strategies can help you find words faster. So, if you’ve found yourself stuck with today’s Strands, don’t worry, below you’ll find some&nbsp;<strong>helpful hints and even the answers for Strands Game #725</strong>&nbsp;<strong>for Thursday, February 26, 2026</strong></p>



<p id="block-672014a9-ce75-4ea0-b98d-12b9214dbb53">To play today’s Strands,&nbsp;<a href="https://www.nytimes.com/games/strands" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">head to the game’s website.</a></p>



<p id="block-a3d47262-a89d-4341-93f0-34626756e4b3"><em><strong>IMPORTANT:</strong>&nbsp;The following information includes spoilers on today’s edition of Strands. If you don’t want the answer given to you, stop scrolling.</em></p>



<figure id="block-5f20defe-2f05-4eb9-b880-6af2f94b324d"></figure>







<h2 id="block-e2995432-719e-4ed6-8fad-a1db37670203">How To Play Strands</h2>



<p id="block-da980997-0420-4527-946e-b66c49bf3d07">Strands is a daily word search that challenges you to find words with a common theme. There’s also a Spanagram that reveals the deeper theme behind the words.</p>



<ul id="block-d0bea02d-4b9f-4991-b9db-3b35778ff3bf">
<li>Words that are three letters and under do not count.</li>



<li>Words that reveal the correct theme appear in blue.</li>



<li>The Spanagram turns yellow when found.</li>



<li>Finding three words that don’t fit the theme will reveal a hint to help you find the proper words.</li>
</ul>



<p id="block-5e597b53-af1c-4c06-a00c-6c5a4694e9e0">The goal is to string together as many words as possible. Every letter on the grid gets used! Daily puzzles keep players coming back for more, making it a fun brain exercise and a popular online trend.</p>



<p id="block-cd7aaa7f-9491-4ad0-b994-72d0102c5bed">Strands can only be played on the New York Times website or on the <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/crosswords/apps" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">NYT Games app.</a></p>



<h2 id="block-c6d4979d-f8eb-4473-a011-33019cb8da2c">Strands Hints For Today, February 26, 2026</h2>



<p id="block-23b6a5a9-2c25-47c2-a0ea-e23a99c87abd">The Strands’ answers for Game #725 are all related to being “rude.” In this case, “rude” is less gross or mean-spirited and more argumentative and combative.</p>



<h3 id="block-6777813b-1426-4c21-b507-3024542b4683">General Strands Hints For February 26</h3>



<p id="block-b36e160d-6e5e-4dc8-aae9-5352ee681266">Without giving today’s Strands answers completely away, here are a few helpful hints for today to get you started:</p>



<ul id="block-5c9f7d28-537c-424b-92c3-2a9906b57178">
<li><strong>Hint 1:</strong>&nbsp;Laundry out the dryer always smells so ____ and clean. Also, think OutKast.</li>



<li><strong>Hint 2:</strong> One of the original shows on PTV in Family Guy featured Stewie and Brian. The premise was that Stewie was a “____ bastard.”</li>



<li><strong>Hint 3:</strong>&nbsp;Puppies’ best quality.</li>
</ul>



<p id="block-7fb794eb-0d89-4f8d-a7cf-082d0148b796">Use these clues to narrow down your guesses and increase your chances of solving&nbsp;<strong>Strands #725</strong>&nbsp;<strong>for February 26, 2026.</strong></p>







<h3 id="block-73a1d2f5-fc2b-49b7-9c10-539e38a2b946">Words to Help You Find Strand Hints for February 26, 2026</h3>



<p id="block-0853e28e-417e-4720-9526-9f2808a268be">If you want help getting started without having today’s Strands answer given to you, there are a few starter words worth trying that will help you unlock some in-game hints. A few starter words that may help are:</p>



<ul id="block-2ca8fb79-d1a4-43e4-8764-e4d238a3cc97">
<li>CURE</li>



<li>DENT</li>



<li>PETAL</li>



<li>TALK</li>



<li>SENT</li>
</ul>







<h2 id="h-today-s-strands-answer-for-game-725-on-february-26-2026">Today’s Strands Answer For Game #725 On February 26, 2026</h2>



<figure></figure>



<p id="block-4ee7c8b7-21fe-4613-8d40-bdf10f8881d0">If you’ve tried everything, including using the above hints, and are still stuck, you can find the answers to today’s Strands below. Check out the answers for yesterday’s puzzle <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/todays-strands-724-hints-and-answers-for-february-25-2026/" id="179972">here.</a></p>



<ul>
<li>PERT</li>



<li>CUTE</li>



<li>FRESH</li>



<li>IMPUDENT</li>



<li>SASSY</li>



<li>SAUCY</li>



<li>CHEEKY</li>



<li><strong>SPANAGRAM</strong>: TALKINGBACK</li>
</ul>



<p id="block-0e0094cc-40a6-49a3-a98c-ee90172006ac">If you solved today’s Strands without our answers, congratulations! If not, take note of the best tips above for tomorrow’s puzzle, and check back daily for more hints.</p>



<h2 id="block-44882c9d-d6a6-4e4f-9b1a-8312ae0b3036">When Is The Next Strands Game After #725?</h2>



<p id="block-bc42def5-af74-42a4-abf5-f31a34e53dd6">All New York Times games are&nbsp;<strong>updated daily at 12 am or Midnight in your respective time zone</strong>. Information about the next game is often available in the hours before, giving players a heads-up. The game on&nbsp;<strong>February 27</strong>&nbsp;will be&nbsp;<strong>Strands Game #726.</strong></p>



<h2 id="block-96ac6df0-5b63-4788-9eff-98ceece739ee">What Is Strands?</h2>



<p id="block-cde2c274-bfd9-4d27-a0d9-3ebe6f1ff7f2">Strands is a daily word search puzzle game created by The New York Times. Launched in 2024, Strands challenges players to discover a common theme among words in a 6×8 letter grid. The game’s original concept was developed by Juliette Seive, a research director on The New York Times Games team, with the aim of replicating Wordle’s success. Tracy Bennett serves as the puzzle editor for Strands, overseeing the creation and curation of daily puzzles since its launch.</p>



<hr>



<p id="block-9d1c4fad-eba9-422a-a628-5cb7b00aea3b">For even more Insider Gaming delivered straight to your inbox,&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>






        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/todays-strands-725-hints-and-answers-for-february-26-2026/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Resident Evil Requiem Has a Convoluted Challenge Called 'The Final Puzzle' — and the Race Is Now on to Get It Fully Solved]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/resident-evil-requiem-has-a-convoluted-challenge-called-the-final-puzzle-and-the-race-is-now-on-to-get-it-fully-solved</link>
            <guid>1446943</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle" data-autopogo="true"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/resident-evil-requiem">Resident Evil Requiem</a> includes numerous Easter eggs and unlockable extras, but none seemingly as complex as 'The Final Puzzle.'</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em><strong>Warning! </strong></em><em>Resident Evil Requiem puzzle spoilers follow:</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph">As with other recent Resident Evil games, Requiem includes a list of challenges which add completion points to your playthrough score. At the bottom of the list is the appropriately-named 'The Final Puzzle' — which is proving to be something of a headscratcher.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/resident-evil-requiem/Final_Challenge_Puzzle_Solution">IGN has a work-in-progress guide to The Final Puzzle</a> where significant progress has been made through the challenge's convoluted early stages, which feel more complex than anything seen in any other Resident Evil game to date — and, seemingly, with still some way left to go.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Exactly what the final outcome or reward for the challenge might be remains unknown — but as the game continues its launch around the world, the hunt for answers here will undoubtedly become a major point of community focus.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The game's own description for the challenge offers only the vaguest of hints, to "Let the sweet pair hear the voice." The mechanics of the puzzle, or at least its first part, appear to rely on players picking up or examining a variety of objects throughout the game to determine fragments of a code.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Requiem's trail of clues relies on players picking up a specific severed hand which, if obtained, can also be scanned later on to provide a hidden RNA code in a blood sample analysis machine. Other items also hide their own codes, providing (with a bit more puzzling work) a version of that RNA sequence that can be plugged into a safe that features buttons labelled with a Star, Sun and Moon. </p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><span data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><div data-cy="slideshow-preview"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Resident Evil Requiem Review Screens</h3></div></span></output><p data-cy="paragraph">After that... well, it's here the trail has gone cold, though likely not for long. We'll be keeping an eye on further progress made throughout the next few days, as players uncover further steps. For now, however, it's just fun to see that the game hides this kind of puzzle. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">For a far more granular look at each step to-date, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/resident-evil-requiem/Final_Challenge_Puzzle_Solution">IGN's work-in-progress guide to The Final Puzzle</a> is right here. We've also logged <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/how-long-is-resident-evil-requiem">how long Resident Evil Requiem takes to beat</a>, and tracked <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/resident-evil-requiem-global-release-timings-revealed">Resident Evil Requiem's global release times</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"Like the result of an experiment conducted in an underground Umbrella Corporation lab, Resident Evil Requiem successfully splices two separate strains of survival horror together into the one highly infectious new mutation," IGN wrote in our full <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/resident-evil-requiem-review">Resident Evil Requiem review</a>, which returned a 9/10 score.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Tom Phillips is IGN's News Editor. You can reach Tom at tom_phillips@ign.com or find him on Bluesky </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/tomphillipseg.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@tomphillipseg.bsky.social</a></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/resident-evil-requiem-has-a-convoluted-challenge-called-the-final-puzzle-and-the-race-is-now-on-to-get-it-fully-solved]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine 2 Techmarine Update Out Now — Check Out Patch 12.0]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/warhammer-40000-space-marine-2-techmarine-update-out-now-check-out-patch-120</link>
            <guid>1446937</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle" data-autopogo="true"><p data-cy="paragraph">Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine 2’s long-awaited Techmarine update is out now across all platforms as part of patch 12.0. It adds the new Techmarine class, a new melee weapon, a new Operation, DLCs, and balance updates.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The Techmarine is the big draw here. The new playable class — the first to hit the explosive third-person action game since launch — has a unique Servo-Gun ability that locks onto enemies in a line of sight and automatically fires at them while the Techmarine continues fighting in melee or range. It also has access to the new Omnissian Axe, which can deal massive damage to both a single target with its standard attacks and to surrounding enemies with its finishing heavy attacks.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“We hope you will really like the new class,” game director Dmitry Grigorenko said in <a href="https://community.focus-entmt.com/focus-entertainment/space-marine-2/blogs/356-patch-notes-12-0" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">a post on publisher Focus Entertainment’s website</a>. “We've tried to make sure that this class plays differently from the rest.”</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><span data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><div data-cy="slideshow-preview"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine 2 Techmarine Screenshots</h3></div></span></output><p data-cy="paragraph">A number of changes were made based on feedback from the recent PTS, outlined in the patch notes below. “We've tried to address most of it, but there are some big changes that we didn't have time to implement,” Grigorenko explained. “There will be more improvements and perks reworks in upcoming patches.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Elsewhere, patch 12.0 heralds the addition of Space Marine 2's first voice pack, which costs $4.99. This is <em>not</em> included in the Season Pass (and thus has <a href="https://community.focus-entmt.com/focus-entertainment/space-marine-2/blogs/343-january-community-update#post-6777" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">upset some players who believe it should be part of the premium DLC package</a>). It includes 450 re-recorded voicelines and a unique Space Marine Head cosmetic for each of the following Space Marine chapters: Blood Angels, Space Wolves, and Black Templars.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2026/02/26/spacemarine2-patchnote-12-techmarine-1920x1080-1772103288673.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Image credit: Focus Entertainment.</figcaption></figure></output><h2 data-cy="title2">Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine 2 Techmarine update 12.0 patch notes:</h2><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>NEW FEATURES</strong></p><h3 data-cy="title3">New Class: Techmarine</h3><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>We are introducing a new playable class: the Techmarine! This mighty technician specialises in crowd control and area defense, handling multiple combat tasks simultaneously. This is primarily possible with his Servo-Gun ability. When activated, it locks onto enemies in a line of sight and automatically fires at them while the Techmarine continues fighting in melee or range. Furthermore, the Servo-Gun allows executing Gun Strikes without interrupting other actions.</em>    </p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>🟡 Changes from PTS:</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Fixed “Furious Gun Strike” prestige perk not activating properly.</li><li>"Revive Surge" prestige perk has been replaced with "Indomitable": “You become Invulnerable to Damage while activating Tarantula Sentry Gun”</li><li>“Chained Headshots" prestige perk now correctly increases headshot damage.</li><li>"Volatile Sentry" prestige perk damage boost increased from 40% to 1000%.</li><li>"Replenishing Salvo" perk cooldown reduced from 90 to 75.</li><li>Fixed “Lethal Perimeter” perk, it now correctly reduces the energy per shot for all types of Servo-Guns.</li><li>"Arc Cleave" perk damage bonus decreased from 25% to 20%.</li><li>“Explosive Enfilade” perk now works with Sanctified Wrath equipment.</li><li>"Augmented Tarantula" perk's damage boost increased from 25% to 30%.</li><li>"Augmented Tarantula" perk now correctly increases the turret's ammo.</li><li>"Methodical Destruction" perk now correctly debuffs enemies.</li><li>"Designated target" perk now correctly debuffs enemies.</li><li>"Omnissian Axe Deflection" perk duration increased from 5 to 10 seconds.</li><li>“Explosives Adept” perk damage increased from 20% to 35%.</li><li>"Lethal Perimeter" perk using 50% less energy per shot instead of 20%.</li><li>Servo-gun damage now correctly scales with difficulty.</li><li>Precision Servo-gun damage reduced by 10%.</li><li>Bolter Servo-gun cooldown reduced by 20%.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Game Director’s note:</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>We hope you will really like the new class. We've tried to make sure that this class plays differently from the rest.<br>Thank you for your feedback on him from PTS. We've tried to address most of it, but there are some big changes that we didn't have time to implement. There will be more improvements and perks reworks in upcoming patches.</em></p><h3 data-cy="title3">New Weapon: Omnissian Axe</h3><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>With the Techmarine class, you will also get the chance to try out its signature weapon, the Omnissian Axe! This weapon is capable of dealing massive damage to both a single target with its standard attacks and to surrounding enemies with its finishing heavy attacks. And as a starting heavy attack, you can perform a powerful charge attack that can hit all enemies in its path.</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>🟡 Changes from PTS:</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Improved responsiveness of Omnissian Rush attacks.</li><li>Sweeping Whirl damage increased by 100%.</li><li>The third light attack in the combo now correctly breaks the enemy's guard.</li><li>"Armour Siphon” perk now activates properly.</li><li>Fixed the amount of HP which taken when using the "Iron Surge" perk.</li><li>"Executioner" perk duration increased to 5 seconds.</li><li>Added an energy explosion effect for "Explosive Strike" perk.</li><li>"Mighty Blast" perk second explosion deals correct damage.</li><li>"Expose" perk is now correctly applied.</li><li>"Cleaving Strike" perk no longer triggers environmental hazards explosions.</li></ul><h3 data-cy="title3">New PvE Content: Tarantula Sentry Gun</h3><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Techmarines can also locate and activate Sentry Turrets in PvE missions. These Tarantula-type emplacements offer automatic suppressive fire support against nearby enemies. Sentry Turrets have limited ammo and would go into standby mode after running out of it, but a Tech Marine can re-awaken them to restore their supplies.</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>🟡 Changes from PTS:</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Fixed double HP and damage scaling by difficulties.</li><li>Increased spawn rate of turrets by ~50%.</li><li>Added more potential spawn areas for turrets.</li><li>Increased range of turret outline for better visibility.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Game Director’s note: </em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Rest assured that turrets are still going to be very effective.</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Sentries (along with lots of other cool stuff 😉) will be added in Siege in the next big content update.</em></p><h3 data-cy="title3">New PvE Map: Disruption</h3><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Space Marine forces have been deployed to the Hive City of Avarax. Their initial mission is to reinforce the overwhelmed Cadian defenses against a massive Tyranid swarm. Subsequently, they will join a Dreadnought to eliminate Thousand Sons forces that have penetrated the city's lower levels.</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>New PvE Equipment: Restorative Stimms</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>The Restorative Stimms, a new PvE healing Equipment, has been added, encouraging aggressive playstyles. Upon use, it restores an initial small amount of health, then a large amount of Contested Health over a period of time.</em></p><h3 data-cy="title3">New Customisation Feature: Shared Heads for PvE / PvP Characters</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">Added an option to pick any face for PvE and PvP characters in Armour Customisation. Class restrictions no longer apply (i.e you can equip Assault’s head on the Heavy)</p><h3 data-cy="title3">New Tech Feature: Siege Host Migration</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">Supported Host Migration for Siege Mode: If a server crash occurs, the game will continue on a new server from the last saved state.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">New Feature: VO Selector</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">Added an option to pick and customise voices for PvE and PvP characters. You’ll find the Voice Selector in the “Edit Armour” menu of the Armouring Hall.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">New Battlefield Conditions</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">21 new Battlefield Conditions have been added to expand the variety of daily and weekly Stratagems.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Custom Stratagems Mode for PvE</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">Players can now create private matches with any combination of Battlefield Conditions. This allows players to customize their games, set their own Stratagems or simply enjoy some light-hearted carnage <em>(note that all rewards will be disabled in Custom Stratagems mode).</em></p><h3 data-cy="title3">New Heroic Items</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">Added 3 Heroic Weapons:</p><ul data-cy="list"><li><em>Argent Edge (Combat Knife - Fencing type)</em></li><li><em>Ultima Ratio (Omnissian Axe - Fencing type)</em></li><li><em>Deathwatch (Heavy Bolt Rifle with Grenade Launcher)</em></li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>🟡 Changes from PTS:</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li><em>Argent Edge</em> riposte damage increased by 50%.</li></ul><h3 data-cy="title3">New DLC Content:</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">Included in Season Pass 2:</p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Raven Guard Champion Pack (Assault Champion + Bolt Pistol)</li><li>Carcharodons Chapter Pack (Unlike the other Cosmetic Packs, the Carcharodons Cosmetic Pack does not add a new Heraldry page to unlock the cosmetic items. Instead, the armour pieces will be automatically unlocked and added to your armour sets once you purchase the pack.)</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph">Not included in any Season Pass:</p><ul data-cy="list"><li>3 Custom Heads + VO for PvE/ PvP Characters. (Space Wolves / Blood Angels / Black Templars)</li></ul><h2 data-cy="title2">GAMEPLAY AND BALANCING TWEAKS</h2><h3 data-cy="title3">PvE Perks</h3><p data-cy="paragraph"><u><strong>Tactical</strong></u></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Balanced Distribution</strong>: Both negative and positive effects are increased from 10% to 15%.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Kraken Penetrator Rounds</strong>: All bolter weapons now deal 50% more damage with body shots.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">🟡<strong> Changes from PTS:</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Kraken Penetrator Rounds now correctly apply to bolter rounds only.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Game Director’s note</em>: </p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>We hear your feedback regarding bolters doing too little body damage.</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>This behavior is kind of intentional. The reason is that Space Marine 2’s engagement distances and recoil are extremely low, while average enemy size is rather big. It's very difficult to completely miss your enemies. This is why the only skill element of ranged combat is to aim for the head, and this is why head shots are so important for bolt weapons.</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>That being said, I agree that we've overtuned headshots way too much, especially with how different perks and multipliers stack with each other. We will reduce the gap between body shots and head shots. But it's not going to be as easy as applying this perk by default to everybody. </em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>We need to adjust base damage of all bolter weapons and then adjust damage sensitivity on all enemies and do it case by case. So, a big overhaul is coming in this area rather soon, but do keep in mind that aiming for the head will remain the proper way of using bolters.</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><u><strong>Sniper</strong></u></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Efficient Readiness</strong>: Now the effect lasts 5 seconds after deactivation.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Ambush</strong>: Now forces stagger to the enemies.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Vantage Point</strong>: Added an indication when ready.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><u><strong>Assault</strong></u></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Squad Cohesion</strong>: Effect is increased from 10% to 15%.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Hammer of Wrath</strong>: Is now a Prestige Perk replacing “Commendation”. </p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Commendation</strong>: Removed.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Strong Strike</strong>: New perk, taking the original place of “Hammer of Wrath”: <em>“Hitting an enemy with an attack after a Jump Pack Dash restores Jump Pack Ability Charge by 1. Cooldown 10 seconds.”</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Winged Fury</strong>: Now works with all stances of Power Sword.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Firearms in PvE</h3><p data-cy="paragraph"><u><strong>Bolt Rifle</strong></u></p><p data-cy="paragraph">Base damage is increased by 10% for versions: </p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Drogos Reclamation - Beta (Artificer)</li><li>Ophelian Liberation - Beta (Relic)</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><u><strong>Bolt Carbine (Marksman Version)</strong></u></p><p data-cy="paragraph">Base damage is increased by 11% for versions: </p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Drogos Reclamation Marksman (Artificer)</li><li>Ophelian Liberation Marksman (Relic)</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><u><strong>Inferno Pistol</strong></u></p><p data-cy="paragraph">Gunstrike damage is increased by 22%.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><u><strong>Volkite Pistol</strong></u></p><p data-cy="paragraph">Gunstrike damage is increased by 9%.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><u><strong>Sanctified Wrath Reliquary</strong></u></p><p data-cy="paragraph">Bonus to Melee Damage is increased from 25% to 35%.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Effect duration is increased from 15 to 20 seconds.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Melee in PvE</h3><h3 data-cy="title3">Damage of all Artificer and Relic Balanced type melee weapons was increased by about 15% on average.</h3><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>🟡 Changes from PTS:</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Heroic Chainsword and Power Sword damage increased by 10%.</li></ul><h3 data-cy="title3">PvP</h3><ul data-cy="list"><li>Fixed restoring armour by hitting an enemy for Power Axe. </li><li>Fixed issue with 3rd attack in Power Sword combo dealing too much damage.</li><li>Blindness effect from Shock Grenade is decreased from 2 sec to 1,5 sec.</li></ul><h3 data-cy="title3">Rewards</h3><ul data-cy="list"><li>Siege Mode: Rebalanced rewards for waves completion first 5 waves grant less XP, while later waves grant more XP.</li><li>Stratagems: Hard difficulty Stratagems no longer grant XP. </li></ul><h3 data-cy="title3">Gameplay QoL</h3><ul data-cy="list"><li>Contested health no longer fades away during grab animations</li><li>Rebalanced melee attacks that have multiple attacks: Now they restore contested health with each strike instead of just the first one.</li><li>Slightly adjusted hitboxes of a few melee attacks so they would connect more easily against large enemies.</li><li>Fixed an issue where Bolt Sniper Rifle and Las Fusil would miss their targets at extremely long range. Aim Assist at such distances has also been slightly increased.</li><li>Improved properties of bullet magnetism for Chaos enemy NPC: Chaos Spawns , Rubric Marines, Tzaangors, Terminators. Making them slightly easier to headshot at medium and long ranges.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>🟡 Changes from PTS:</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Jump Pack dash can be used to cancel any player melee animation.</li><li>Improved controls responsiveness after using Jump Pack Dash attacks.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>CUSTOMISATION</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Added and updated a few Champion parts to the Custom Armour Set pieces:<ul data-cy="list"><li>Added Ultramarine Champion Tabard to Tactical</li><li>Added Imperial Fist Champion Tabard to Tactical</li><li>Added robes to Dark Angels Champion Bulwark's chest</li><li>Added Dark Angels Champion shoulder pads to Heavy</li><li>Updated White Scars Champion chest on Tactical to include belt accessories</li><li>Added Black Templars Champion shoulder pads to Heavy</li><li>Added Blood Angels Champion shoulder pads and backpack to Bulwark</li></ul></li><li>Added the option to switch and apply Heroic Weapons skins to other weapons (not applicable to special weapons i.e combi-weapon).</li><li>Lots of minor customisation fixes for both Loyalists and Chaos.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph">🟡 Changes from PTS:</p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Added 4 more shared customisation slots.</li><li>Added missing unlock conditions for Power Axe skins in PvP.</li></ul><h2 data-cy="title2">LEVELS</h2><ul data-cy="list"><li>Lots of minor fixes with level geometry.</li></ul><h2 data-cy="title2">ENEMIES</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Lots of minor fixes with animations.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">GENERAL FIXES</h2><ul data-cy="list"><li>Fixed: The plasma weapon perk "<strong>Fast venting</strong>" reduced the cooling by ~7.5% instead of 15% as announced in the tooltip.</li><li>Fixed a bug with the <strong>Heroic Heavy Bolt Pistol</strong> not interrupting enemy reinforcements with body shots.</li><li>Fixed a bug with the Controller <strong>Aim Assist</strong> strength depending on camera FOV.</li><li>Lots of minor bug fixes.</li><li>Lots of minor localisation bug fixes.</li><li>Lots of minor UI and sound fixes.</li></ul><h2 data-cy="title2">TECH</h2><ul data-cy="list"><li>Crash fixes and general stability improvements.</li><li>Memory optimisations.</li><li>Minor performance improvements.</li><li>Minor loading times optimization.</li><li>General connectivity improvements.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is Director, News at IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/warhammer-40000-space-marine-2-techmarine-update-out-now-check-out-patch-120]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How Long Is Resident Evil Requiem?]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/how-long-is-resident-evil-requiem</link>
            <guid>1446934</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle" data-autopogo="true"><p data-cy="paragraph">Resident Evil Requiem has finally arrived, ready to provide you with hours and hours of survival horror action, in which you can test your mettle as both Grace Ashcroft and Leon S. Kennedy. Much like its modern predecessors, Requiem boasts a reasonably stacked campaign, but just how long is it? Here, we’ll let you know exactly how many hours it took different members of the IGN team to finish the game, and what they prioritised doing with that time.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">How Long is Resident Evil Requiem?</h2><ul data-cy="list"><li>Our fastest player finished the game in <strong>4.5 hours</strong>.</li><li>Our “slowest” player finished the game in <strong>16 hours</strong>.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph">Everyone plays games differently, so read on for more details about how everyone played, how long it took to reach the credits, and how much extra time players spent exploring. Once you've finished the game yourself, be sure to submit your times on our sister website, <a href="https://howlongtobeat.com/game/169267" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>How Long To Beat</u></a>, and see how your time compares!</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><span data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><div data-cy="slideshow-preview"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Resident Evil Requiem Review Screens</h3></div></span></output><h2 data-cy="title2">Jesse Gomez - Senior Video Producer </h2><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Completion Time: 8 hours and 59 minutes on Standard (Modern) / 4 hours and 38 minutes on Insanity.</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph">Shy of just under nine hours, my first playthrough of Resident Evil Requiem consisted of meticulously hunting down every single Mr. Raccoon collectable, reading as many files as I could (I missed just three of the 75 available to find), and relishing in the blood-soaked glory of Leon's vast, yet costly arsenal.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">If I wasn't so engrossed by exploring every nook and cranny of the Rhodes Hill Chronic Care Center and beyond for secrets, I'm sure I could’ve shaved an hour or two off my playtime. For my second playthrough, though, I cut that time practically in half. I dove into a run on Insanity difficulty right after hitting credits and, armed with knowledge of objectives and environment layouts from my first playthrough, I blitzed through it all in just over four hours and a half hours. Such speed does come with some hiccups, though; to Grace's dismay, I did get munched on a few times by the many monstrosities that stalk the care centers' halls. </p><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>Dale Driver -  Associate Director, Video Programming</strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Completion Time: 16 hours on Standard (Modern)</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph">I hit credits 16 hours into my playthrough of Resident Evil Requiem after choosing what I assume to be the “good” ending! I played through the game on the standard modern difficulty; the hardest option available out of the gate that doesn’t demand you deal with Ink Ribbons taking up inventory space.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">I was quite thorough during my playthrough, making sure I got all the antique coins and all the safes' codes, and generally trying not to leave anything behind. When I got to Raccoon City later in the game, I spent a decent amount of time revisiting the classic locations and soaking up the nostalgia. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">I did have an advantage that many first-time players won’t have, which I assume might have cut an hour or two from my playthrough. I’d previously played through the majority of the Rhodes Hill Chronic Care Center section for IGN’s preview of Resident Evil Requiem, so when it came to that section I already knew what I needed to find and where it was hidden. That certainly sped up the early hours for me.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">So far, I’ve only finished the game once, but I definitely plan to dive back in for an Insanity run and see what I missed!</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><h2 data-cy="title2">Tristan Ogilvie - Senior Video Editor + Reviewer</h2><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Completion Time: 10 hours on Standard (Modern)</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph">It took me just over 10 hours to roll credits on Resident Evil Requiem, however that was to arrive at the shorter and what I consider to be the worse of its two possible endings. Man, I hate that ending so much! So, I immediately reloaded my save game to play through the other, better, ending, which added close to another 30 minutes onto my playtime.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">I opted to play Requiem on the Standard (Modern) difficulty setting, mainly because I didn’t want to be restricted to using ink ribbons in order to save my game during Grace’s sections like you are on the Standard (Classic) setting. As the parent of two young kids who are liable to disrupt me at any moment and for no good reason, I need to have the ability to save my game without any restrictions. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">However, I am now playing a second time through on Standard (Classic) and taking my time with it a bit more. I’ve still got a number of small things like notes and Mr. Raccoon bobbleheads to track down, as well as a few areas here and there tucked away in the Rhodes Hill Chronic Care Center that I didn’t fully explore the first time through. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">I’m too much of a coward to tackle the game a third time on the Insanity difficulty setting, however if Capcom ends up adding a Mercenaries mode to Requiem at a later date I’ll come charging back harder than a zombie chef with the smell of blood in his nostrils. </p><h2 data-cy="title2">Matt Purslow - Executive Editor of Features</h2><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Completion Time: 11 Hours on Standard (Modern)</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph">I completed Resident Evil Requiem in exactly 11 hours. And, if you’re planning to do a pretty “regular” playthrough, I expect you’ll clock up a similar playtime. While I didn’t scour every last corner, bookshelf, and drawer for the most fiendishly hidden treasures and lore drops, I was reasonably thorough in my exploration of the Rhodes Hill Chronic Care Center and the locations that await beyond it. I scavenged enough currency to buy a healthy selection of upgrades, ensuring both Grace and Leon were well equipped for the dangers they faced, but by the time credits rolled there were still guns that could be further modified and stats that could be improved. I unlocked some safes, but there are still several left to crack in a second playthrough. I read plenty of documents, and so learned many of the story’s extra details, but there are still mysteries to be solved by finding the papers I missed. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">11 hours is pretty typical for a Resident Evil game, but relatively slender compared to many of today’s massive, RPG-style games, and so a second playthrough is certainly on the cards. I not only plan to gather what I missed, but also play with the opposite perspectives of Requiem’s default set up – I’m excited to see what exploring Rhodes Hill as Grace in third person is like, and taking on Leon’s sections as a first-person shooter. That’ll surely clock up another dozen hours. </p><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>Brian Altano - Executive Producer</strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Completion Time: 12 Hours on Standard (Classic)</strong></p><p data-cy="paragraph">It took me around 12 and a half hours to beat Resident Evil Requiem on the Standard (Classic) difficulty setting, in which Leon can save the game infinitely at pretty much every save station, while Grace needs to find (or craft) limited, finite ink ribbons, just like in the classic Resident Evil games. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">I’m a huge fan of the series and I had a hunch I’d like this game, but I didn’t expect to practically adore it. I found myself exploring every inch of it for secrets, collectibles, easter eggs, and more. Ultimately I missed a few on my first run through the game, but then immediately started a second and third playthrough after initially rolling credits the first time in an effort to find everything. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">There are some really fun post-game options tied to beating the campaign with specific parameters (like finishing it without using a single healing item), plus a couple of other little challenges I’m excited to try. There’s one specific Mr. Raccoon bobblehead I definitely wouldn’t have found without the help of IGN’s guides guru, Brendan Graeber, so if you’re a completionist who doesn’t want to miss anything on your first trek through the story, be sure to give our walkthrough a look. Then there’s the unlockable “Insanity” difficulty that I absolutely can’t wait to repeatedly get my butt kicked in. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">All in all, I’ll probably put about 40 hours into Resident Evil Requiem, a number that will only go up if Capcom decides to add a Mercenaries mode and additional story DLC post launch. I really love this game!</p><span data-cy="poll-view-trigger"></span></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/how-long-is-resident-evil-requiem]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Magic: The Gathering’s TMNT Set Launches Next Week, and Collector Boosters Just Got a Sizable Discount at Amazon]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/magic-the-gathering-teenage-mutant-ninja-turtle-set-launches-next-week-and-collector-boosters-just-got-a-sizable-discount-at-amazon</link>
            <guid>1446931</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Out of the Shadows.</h2></p><div><section data-cy="article-content" data-autopogo="true"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/magic-the-gathering-trading-card-game"><u>Magic: The Gathering</u></a> will kick off its <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/magic-the-gathering-teenage-mutant-ninja-turtles-where-to-buy-updated-2026"><u>Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles set</u></a> this weekend with a prerelease window before launch next week, but the notoriously elusive Collector Boosters are now back in stock at Amazon.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Not only can you find a box in stock (which in itself is a small miracle), <a href="https://zdcs.link/QxeXBb?object_uuid=5ce32472-206e-4759-862f-86cb177f152e&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>but it’s discounted down to $424.93</u></a>. That nets you twelve packs - it's pricey, but potentially worth it.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Save on MTG Collector Boosters For The New TMNT Set</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">For those new to the game, Collector Boosters offer the rarest cards in the Ninja Turtles-themed set, and are ideal for anyone looking for unique art treatments.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Will you get ‘better’ cards? No, not necessarily, but you’re more likely to find cards with higher resale value, hence why they cost an MSRP of $37.99 per pack. For anyone looking to <em>play</em> Magic, the aptly-named Play Boosters are a better bet.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">While Play Boosters aren’t as cheap as they were last week, there are other TMNT products on sale.</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><div data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>Magic: The Gathering's TMNT Collector Booster Box preorders are in stock at Amazon... again! (Out March 6)</p><p>Currently down to $424.93 (was $455.88) <a href="https://t.co/oB0o5M55gO" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://t.co/oB0o5M55gO</a></p><p>This is the best deal we've seen on these since preorders first kicked off, I'd snap them up ASAP <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/ad?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">#ad</a> <a href="https://t.co/qDWQZd496G" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/qDWQZd496G</a></p></div>— IGN Deals (@IGNDeals) <a href="https://twitter.com/IGNDeals/status/2026953676212875374?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">February 26, 2026</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">The <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/magic-the-gathering-next-precon-deck-is-teenage-mutant-ninja-turtle-themed-and-its-already-discounted-just-a-few-weeks-from-launch"><u>newest Commander Deck, ‘Turtle Power’</u></a>, is down to $59, saving you $10 off the MSRP, while <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/magic-the-gathering-teenage-mutant-ninja-turtles-set-launches-next-month-and-the-bundle-is-discounted-already"><u>the Bundle of nine Play Boosters</u></a> is $63.99, down from $69.99. It also includes a promo card and 30 lands from the set.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Draft Night, which includes a series of boosters to play a draft match and a Collector Booster to use as a prize, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/magic-the-gathering-tmnt-draft-night-box-back-in-stock-and-discounted-at-amazon"><u>is down to $94.99 from $119.99</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">For more on Magic’s Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtle crossover, check out <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/tmnt-magic-card-is-a-dream-for-artifact-creature-decks-like-warhammer-40ks-necron-dynasties"><u>a card that pairs nicely with Warhammer 40K Necrons</u></a> (what is Magic in 2026, eh?), and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/magic-the-gathering-tmnt-commander-deck-is-a-video-game-homage-packed-with-classic-characters"><u>our early thoughts on the Commander precon</u></a>, Turtle Power.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Amazon also has a great deal on Play Boosters for the game’s current set, Lorwyn Eclipsed, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/magic-the-gathering-lorwyn-eclipsed-booster-boxes-reach-new-low-price-ahead-of-tmnt-launch"><u>which you can find right here</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Lloyd Coombes is an experienced freelancer in tech, gaming and fitness seen at Polygon, Eurogamer, Macworld, TechRadar and many more. He's a big fan of Magic: The Gathering and other collectible card games, much to his wife's dismay.
</p></section><div><h3 data-cy="title3"><svg data-cy="icon-logo" viewBox="0 0 76 24" title="IGN"><title>IGN Logo</title><path fill="currentColor" stroke="none" d="M5.38 7.65a7.85 7.85 0 0 1 2.26-2.26c.13-1.18.31-2.26.52-3.21a10.605 10.605 0 0 0-6 6c.95-.22 2.03-.39 3.21-.52M16.34 5.36v.02c.9.59 1.67 1.37 2.27 2.27 1.18.13 2.26.31 3.21.52a10.627 10.627 0 0 0-6.02-6.01c.22.95.4 2.02.54 3.2M7.64 18.62c-.9-.59-1.67-1.37-2.27-2.27h-.03c-1.19-.14-2.26-.32-3.19-.54 1.07 2.75 3.26 4.95 6.01 6.02-.22-.95-.39-2.03-.52-3.21M18.64 16.35h-.03c-.59.9-1.37 1.67-2.27 2.27v.03c-.14 1.17-.32 2.25-.54 3.19a10.59 10.59 0 0 0 6.03-6.03c-.94.22-2 .4-3.19.54M10.04 0h3.9c.85 1.85 1.2 4.59 1.3 5.52.04.22.06.43.06.63L12 9.11 8.7 6.15c0-.17.02-.35.05-.55.1-.95.43-3.75 1.29-5.61M8.7 17.83c0 .17.02.35.05.55.1.95.43 3.75 1.29 5.61h3.9c.85-1.84 1.2-4.59 1.3-5.52.04-.22.06-.43.06-.64L12 14.87l-3.3 2.96ZM6.16 8.68c-.17 0-.35.02-.55.05-.95.12-3.75.45-5.61 1.31v3.9c1.84.85 4.59 1.19 5.52 1.3.22.04.43.06.64.06L9.11 12 6.16 8.7ZM24 10.02c-1.86-.86-4.66-1.19-5.61-1.29-.2-.03-.38-.05-.55-.05l-2.96 3.3 2.96 3.3c.2 0 .41-.02.64-.06.93-.11 3.68-.45 5.52-1.3v-3.9Z"></path><path fill="currentColor" stroke="none" d="M42.83 13.9V10h10.45c1.06 0 1.93.86 1.93 1.92v4.63c0 2.38-1.91 4.36-4.33 4.36h-6.69c-4.96 0-8.97-4-8.97-8.94s4.04-8.95 8.98-8.95h10.36v4.11H44.2c-2.67 0-4.86 2.17-4.86 4.84s2.16 4.83 4.86 4.83h6.91v-2.91h-8.27ZM33.86 3h-4.07v16.02c0 1.05.86 1.91 1.91 1.91h2.15V3M74.37 3.01h-2.18v13.81s0 .08-.03.11a.29.29 0 0 1-.24.14c-.09 0-.16-.04-.25-.15L64.83 4.93a4.347 4.347 0 0 0-3.72-2.11h-.07c-2.39 0-4.32 1.93-4.32 4.32v11.88c0 1.05.86 1.91 1.91 1.91h2.17V7.14s.02-.09.04-.13a.29.29 0 0 1 .24-.14c.09 0 .18.03.24.14l6.88 12.07c.76 1.27 2.12 2.05 3.69 2.05h.07c2.39 0 4.32-1.93 4.32-4.32V4.92c0-1.05-.85-1.91-1.91-1.91"></path></svg>Recommends</h3></div></div><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/magic-the-gathering-teenage-mutant-ninja-turtle-set-launches-next-week-and-collector-boosters-just-got-a-sizable-discount-at-amazon]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How Rennsport is building into a racing platform through 2026]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/02/26/rennsport/</link>
            <guid>1446904</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Rennsport really didn’t get off to the greatest start for a racing game, but its developers are determined to put things right with a newly revealed roadmap for 2026, an AI overhaul and modding tools in the works, and a new mantra of “Double the content –&nbsp;Half the price” to get the ball rolling.</p>
<p>Stepping into the simulation racing genre is a tall task, as you need to try and cater to the varying preferences and demands of a keen and deeply invested audience, but for its launch in November 2025, Rennsport simply came up short. Not enough cars, not enough tracks, a slim set of single player championships, and AI that would launch itself through fast corners, seemingly without braking, and end up cartwheeling through the sky.</p>
<p>The first level that they’re pulling is to reset the expectations and value within the game. The Deluxe Edition price is being slashed by 45% and will now feature the first three paid DLC packs released through 2026 –&nbsp;the Endurance Classics Part 1, Touring Classics Part 1 and now also a September DLC. Current Deluxe Edition owners will have further in-game items given to them as compensation for the price they previously paid.</p>



<p>But all owners will benefit from the free updates from March through May, adding the Hyundai N Vision 74 and Porsche 718 Cayman GT4, iconic tracks like Laguna Seca, Sebring International and a community-derived Kuala Lumpur Street Circuit, and updated and new single player championships, and further improvements through the game’s multiplayer features. The capper to all of this will be the reworked AI arriving in May, a ground-up rebuild of this element in the game.</p>

<p>We got to go hands on with some of this new content at an event in Munich, spending the most time in the game with the Porsche 911 GT1 ’98 and Circuit Des 24 Heures Du Mans, both of which are featured in the Endurance Classics DLC. I’m someone that loves Le Mans and endurance racing as a sport, and this combination (admittedly with the current layout instead of that of the late 90s) was a joy to experience. Isn’t it always?</p>

<p>The rest of the DLC pack will feature the Porsche’s counterpart in the Mercedes-Benz CLK-LM, as well as the older Porsche 956 and current Peugeot 9X8 Evo. May will follow this up with a classic touring car bundle, the iconic Mercedes-Benz 190E and other cars able to take to the Hockenheimring Classic layout.</p>
<p>They’re good additions… free and paid, and the impact should hopefully be pretty swift for the multiplayer side of the game. The various added single player championships, though, will be beholden to the reworked AI coming in May.</p>
<p>The new AI wasn’t available for us to race against just yet, but the approach they are taking was outlined by Lead Gameplay Programmer Rikard Häggström. Instead of leaning into a machine learning approach to programmatically find the fastest racing line and learn to race, the AI is given the optimal racing line to try and follow, but then given situational awareness of other cars –&nbsp;visualised in the demo with laser beams zapping everything of note –&nbsp;to let them try to react more organically. They will also be driving with the same throttle, brake and steering inputs players have, and while there’s a slightly simplified physics model that they use compared to players, there won’t be any “cheating” mechanisms. While it’s expected in May, this could change depending on how development progresses.</p>
<div id="attachment_469268"><p id="caption-attachment-469268">The Kuala Lumpur circuit is a community-created track coming to Rennsport soon</p></div>
<p>The cherry on top, though, could be the modding support that will be added through 2026 and the years to follow. Modding and the ability for fans to add in additional cars, tracks and more to games, has been a major part of various PC racing games, but never really on console. Rennsport is looking to change that with an in-game asset store and manager to go alongside a growing suite of modding tools.</p>
<p>For this year, the focus is all about track modding tools. Built around Unreal Engine 5, the available tools are already robust, but will be combined with Rennsport’s in-house tools for better manipulating the tracks. The very first access to this will be in June for select creators, before expanding with a closed beta in August and a wider release potentially by the end of the year. From there, the modding focus will shift to gameplay and cars, over the next few years.</p>

<p>It’s ambitious for a number of reasons, not least that the most popular mods are now often supported via Patreon and other monetisation methods. To draw those talents to Rennsport, there’s the possibility that Competition Company’s in-game mod browser will also have to act like a shop and not just a platform for discovery. Needless to say there’s a lot of details still to be figured out with how to implement all of this, but it’s a fascinating direction to take, especially with console gamers in mind.</p>
<p>Rennsport is far from the only game to have had a rocky launch and need to pull off a recovery drive to get back to relevance. There’s earnest ambition behind this racing game, though, and a determination to improve the fundamentals while also broadening the horizons for the future.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/02/26/rennsport/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Wordscapes Daily Puzzle Hints Today—Answers For Thursday, February 26]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/wordscapes-daily-puzzle-hints-today-answers-for-thursday-february-26/</link>
            <guid>1446895</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Wordscapes is a popular word game where players solve a crossword using anagrams, and it also features a Daily Puzzle, which is not the easiest to solve at times.</p>



<p>If you are one of the players who is struggling with the latest&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tag/wordscapes/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Wordscapes</a>&nbsp;Daily Puzzle, then don’t worry, as Insider Gaming has all the hints and answers for the puzzle featured on Thursday, February 26.</p>



<p><em><strong>IMPORTANT:</strong>&nbsp;The following information includes spoilers on today’s edition of the Wordscapes Daily Puzzle. If you don’t want the answer given to you, stop scrolling.</em></p>







<h2 id="h-how-to-play-wordscapes">How to Play Wordscapes</h2>



<figure></figure>



<p>Wordscapes is a relatively easy game to play, but it can become increasingly challenging as you advance. In the game, players are presented with a crossword puzzle to solve using an anagram. The anagram is displayed below the crossword, and players must swipe across the letters to form words.</p>



<p>The game features over 6,000 crossword puzzles for players to solve. More points can be unlocked by finding hidden words, and each level also comes with a beautiful landscape background. The game is available for free download on both the&nbsp;<a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.peoplefun.wordcross&amp;hl=en_IN" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Google Play Store</a>&nbsp;and the&nbsp;<a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/wordscapes-word-puzzle-game/id1207472156" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">iOS App Store</a>.</p>



<h2 id="h-wordscapes-daily-puzzle-clues-feb-26">Wordscapes Daily Puzzle Clues (Feb. 26)</h2>



<p>Here are hints for all the Wordscapes Daily Puzzle answers for February 26, 2026, to make your puzzle a bit easier.</p>



<h3 id="h-across">Across&nbsp;</h3>



<ol>
<li>Comparing two strange or unusual things</li>



<li>The positive opinion that you have of yourself</li>



<li>A person who uses deceitful methods to avoid a debt.</li>



<li>A supreme being, the creator. </li>



<li>A female deer. </li>



<li>Graphic violence in movies or video games. </li>



<li>A poem that glorifies a person or a thing. </li>



<li>A monster from Shrek. </li>
</ol>



<h3 id="h-down">Down</h3>



<ol>
<li>To avoid something by moving quickly. </li>



<li>To do something again. </li>



<li>A man’s best friend. </li>



<li>Something you do with a motorcycle (past tense).</li>



<li>Something that is strange or unusual.</li>



<li>The colour of blood. </li>



<li>A rock containing valuable minerals like metals. </li>



<li>A thin straight piece of wood or metal. </li>
</ol>



<h2 id="h-all-wordscapes-daily-puzzle-answers-feb-26">All Wordscapes Daily Puzzle Answers (Feb. 26)</h2>



<p>Here are all the answers for Wordscapes Daily Puzzle on February 26, 2026, if the hints were not enough for you.</p>



<h3 id="h-across-nbsp">Across&nbsp;</h3>



<ol>
<li>ODDER</li>



<li>EGO</li>



<li>DODGER</li>



<li>GOD</li>



<li>DOE</li>



<li>GORE</li>



<li>ODE</li>



<li>OGRE</li>
</ol>



<h3 id="h-down">Down</h3>



<ol>
<li>DODGE</li>



<li>REDO</li>



<li>DOG</li>



<li>RODE</li>



<li>ODD</li>



<li>RED&nbsp;</li>



<li>ORE</li>



<li>ROD</li>
</ol>



<h2 id="h-when-is-the-next-wordscapes-daily-puzzle">When is the Next Wordscapes Daily Puzzle?</h2>



<p><strong>The next daily puzzle will be updated at 12 AM local time, with the next, for February 27, arriving tomorrow.</strong></p>







<p>What are your thoughts on today’s Wordscapes Daily Puzzle? Did you find it difficult or easy? Leave your thoughts down in the comments, and join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more word games, check out&nbsp;hints and answers for&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/todays-contexto-1257-hints-answer-for-february-26-2026/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">today’s Contexto #1257</a>, and take a look at&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nyt-mini-crossword-february-26-hints/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">hints for today’s NYT&nbsp;Mini Crossword</a>.</p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/wordscapes-daily-puzzle-hints-today-answers-for-thursday-february-26/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Skate developers Full Circle lay off an unspecified number of staff, claim this'll somehow help them "better support" the game]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/skate-developers-full-circle-lay-off-an-unspecified-number-of-staff-claim-thisll-somehow-help-them-better-support-the-game</link>
            <guid>1446865</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>It's a "transforming" and a "reshaping" that happens to involve talented people losing their jobs</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/ea-skate-layoffs-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/ea-skate-layoffs-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/ea-skate-layoffs-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/ea-skate-layoffs-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/ea-skate-layoffs-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/ea-skate-layoffs-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/ea-skate-layoffs-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/ea-skate-layoffs-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/ea-skate-layoffs-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>EA</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>The team behind Electronic Arts-published early access skateboarding game <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/skate-2025">Skate</a> have announced that they're laying off an unspecified number of staff. Well, I say that, Full Circle have actually announced that they're "transforming as a studio", which happens to entail "making changes to our team structure" which impact some folks' jobs.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>"We’re reshaping Full Circle to better support Skate’s long-term future and focus the team on the things that matter most to you - and making those things great," is another way they put it in a short <a href="https://www.ea.com/ea-studios/full-circle/news/an-update-from-fullcircle">blog post</a>. As for the affected devs, the studio noted that they're "talented colleagues and friends who helped build the foundation of Skate", adding that "this decision is not a reflection of their impact and we’re committed to supporting them through this transition."</p>
<p>As for Skate, which only arrived in early access as of September last year, the plan is for the remaining staff to keep on grinding, while being able to "move faster, listen more closely, and deliver consistently". How having less hands on deck is supposed to make any of that easier, I don't know.</p>
<p>In their <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/3354750/view/502850552192829278">most recent update</a> on plans for the game, put out late last week, Full Circle announced that they'll be changing how they present info about when new additions are coming - making clear which ones are actively in development and which are just being loosely explored/discussed with no set timeline for arrival.</p><p>"We’re doing this to be clear about where things stand - and about how we work," the studio wrote. "The further out something is on the roadmap, the more room it has to shift, or sometimes, be shelved altogether. But we’d rather show you what we’re thinking, even while it’s shifting, than wait until everything is locked. That’s how we want to approach Early Access with you. For example, Open World Collection was on the last roadmap. We’ve taken it off for now so we can focus on more social features – specifically Meetups and Turn-Based Competitive Modes – which we know are high on your wishlist."</p>
<p>Solidarity to those affected by these layoffs at Full Circle. If you're looking for an interesting read about Skate, J.C. Rodriguez's <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-sanitisation-of-skate-reminds-me-how-far-counterculture-has-fallen-and-how-hard-it-can-be-to-stay-inspired">feature from November</a> about the game and where it sits in the wider landscape of skateboarding culture is well worth a look.</p>

        </div>

      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/skate-developers-full-circle-lay-off-an-unspecified-number-of-staff-claim-thisll-somehow-help-them-better-support-the-game]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Space Marine 2 Techmarine Update Patch Notes—New Class, Weapon, Map and More]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/space-marine-2-techmarine-update-patch-notes-new-class-weapon-map-and-more/</link>
            <guid>1446862</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Space Marine 2’s update 12.0 is live now, introducing the new Techmarine class, more PvE content, a weapon, a new map, and so much more. </p>



<p>Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine 2 is on schedule with their <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/warhammer-40000-space-marine-2-year-2-roadmap-released/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Year 2 roadmap</a>, with the new class, missions, and cosmetics arriving with Patch 12 in Q1 2026 as announced. Many details of this update were revealed in the PTS (public test server) patch notes, and it is now officially live. </p>







<h2 id="h-what-s-new-in-the-space-marine-2-techmarine-update-12-0">What’s New in the Space Marine 2 Techmarine Update 12.0? </h2>



<p>Space Marine 2 update 12.0’s highlight is the new playable class, Techmarine. This class features a technician with expertise in crowd control and defense. A lot of changes have been made to the class as part of the PTS update, including fixes and balancing adjustments. The Techmarine class also features a new weapon, the Omnissian Axe, which can deal damage to single enemies as well as surrounding crowds. </p>



<p>Then players can look forward to the Tarantula Sentry Gun as part of PvE content in this update, with Techmarines able to activate Sentry Turrets in PvE missions. The new PvE Map is called Disruption, and it takes the Space Marines to the Hive City of Avarax, where they have to “reinforce the overwhelmed Cadian defenses against a massive Tyranid swarm.”</p>



<p>The latest update for Space Marine 2 introduces several new features for players. These include new PvE equipment, Restorative Stims, and Shared Heads for both PvE and PvP characters, enhancing customization options. Additionally, a new Tech feature, Siege Host Migration, has been added, along with a VO Selector. </p>



<p>The update brings 21 new battlefield conditions, a Custom Stratagems Mode for PvE, and Heroic Items. Players can also look forward to fresh DLC content from the Raven Guard Champion Pack, gameplay and balancing tweaks, new custom armor set pieces, and various fixes. Interested readers can check out the patch notes below to learn more. </p>



<h2 id="h-all-space-marine-2-techmarine-update-12-0-patch-notes">All Space Marine 2 Techmarine Update 12.0 Patch Notes</h2>



<p><strong>NEW FEATURES</strong></p>



<h3>New Class: Techmarine</h3>



<p><em>We are introducing a new playable class: the Techmarine! This mighty technician specialises in crowd control and area defense, handling multiple combat tasks simultaneously. This is primarily possible with his Servo-Gun ability. When activated, it locks onto enemies in a line of sight and automatically fires at them while the Techmarine continues fighting in melee or range. Furthermore, the Servo-Gun allows executing Gun Strikes without interrupting other actions.</em>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Changes from PTS:</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Fixed “Furious Gun Strike” prestige perk not activating properly.</li>



<li>“Revive Surge” prestige perk has been replaced with “Indomitable”: “You become Invulnerable to Damage while activating Tarantula Sentry Gun”</li>



<li>“Chained Headshots” prestige perk now correctly increases headshot damage.</li>



<li>“Volatile Sentry” prestige perk damage boost increased from 40% to 1000%.</li>



<li>“Replenishing Salvo” perk cooldown reduced from 90 to 75.</li>



<li>Fixed “Lethal Perimeter” perk, it now correctly reduces the energy per shot for all types of Servo-Guns.</li>



<li>“Arc Cleave” perk damage bonus decreased from 25% to 20%.</li>



<li>“Explosive Enfilade” perk now works with Sanctified Wrath equipment.</li>



<li>“Augmented Tarantula” perk’s damage boost increased from 25% to 30%.</li>



<li>“Augmented Tarantula” perk now correctly increases the turret’s ammo.</li>



<li>“Methodical Destruction” perk now correctly debuffs enemies.</li>



<li>“Designated target” perk now correctly debuffs enemies.</li>



<li>“Omnissian Axe Deflection” perk duration increased from 5 to 10 seconds.</li>



<li>“Explosives Adept” perk damage increased from 20% to 35%.</li>



<li>“Lethal Perimeter” perk using 50% less energy per shot instead of 20%.</li>



<li>Servo-gun damage now correctly scales with difficulty.</li>



<li>Precision Servo-gun damage reduced by 10%.</li>



<li>Bolter Servo-gun cooldown reduced by 20%.</li>
</ul>



<h3>New Weapon: Omnissian Axe</h3>



<p><em>With the Techmarine class, you will also get the chance to try out its signature weapon, the Omnissian Axe! This weapon is capable of dealing massive damage to both a single target with its standard attacks and to surrounding enemies with its finishing heavy attacks. And as a starting heavy attack, you can perform a powerful charge attack that can hit all enemies in its path.&nbsp; &nbsp;</em>&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Changes from PTS:</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Improved responsiveness of Omnissian Rush attacks.</li>



<li>Sweeping Whirl damage increased by 100%.</li>



<li>The third light attack in the combo now correctly breaks the enemy’s guard.</li>



<li>“Armour Siphon” perk now activates properly.</li>



<li>Fixed the amount of HP which taken when using the “Iron Surge” perk.</li>



<li>“Executioner” perk duration increased to 5 seconds.</li>



<li>Added an energy explosion effect for “Explosive Strike” perk.</li>



<li>“Mighty Blast” perk second explosion deals correct damage.</li>



<li>“Expose” perk is now correctly applied.</li>



<li>“Cleaving Strike” perk no longer triggers environmental hazards explosions.</li>
</ul>



<h3>New PvE Content: Tarantula Sentry Gun</h3>



<p><em>Techmarines can also locate and activate Sentry Turrets in PvE missions. These Tarantula-type emplacements offer automatic suppressive fire support against nearby enemies. Sentry Turrets have limited ammo and would go into standby mode after running out of it, but a Tech Marine can re-awaken them to restore their supplies.</em></p>



<p><strong>Changes from PTS:</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Fixed double HP and damage scaling by difficulties.</li>



<li>Increased spawn rate of turrets by ~50%.</li>



<li>Added more potential spawn areas for turrets.</li>



<li>Increased range of turret outline for better visibility.</li>
</ul>



<h3>New PvE Map: Disruption</h3>



<p><em>Space Marine forces have been deployed to the Hive City of Avarax. Their initial mission is to reinforce the overwhelmed Cadian defenses against a massive Tyranid swarm. Subsequently, they will join a Dreadnought to eliminate Thousand Sons forces that have penetrated the city’s lower levels.</em></p>



<p><strong>New PvE Equipment: Restorative Stimms</strong></p>



<p><em>The Restorative Stimms, a new PvE healing Equipment, has been added, encouraging aggressive playstyles. Upon use, it restores an initial small amount of health, then a large amount of Contested Health over a period of time.</em></p>



<h3>New Customisation Feature: Shared Heads for PvE / PvP Characters</h3>



<p>Added an option to pick any face for PvE and PvP characters in Armour Customisation. Class restrictions no longer apply (i.e you can equip Assault’s head on the Heavy)</p>



<h3>New Tech Feature: Siege Host Migration</h3>



<p>Supported Host Migration for Siege Mode: If a server crash occurs, the game will continue on a new server from the last saved state.</p>



<h3>New Feature: VO Selector</h3>



<p>Added an option to pick and customise voices for PvE and PvP characters. You’ll find the Voice Selector in the “Edit Armour” menu of the Armouring Hall.&nbsp;</p>



<h3>New Battlefield Conditions</h3>



<p>21 new Battlefield Conditions have been added to expand the variety of daily and weekly Stratagems.</p>



<h3>Custom Stratagems Mode for PvE</h3>



<p>Players can now create private matches with any combination of Battlefield Conditions. This allows players to customize their games, set their own Stratagems or simply enjoy some light-hearted carnage&nbsp;<em>(note that all rewards will be disabled in Custom Stratagems mode).</em></p>



<h3>New Heroic Items</h3>



<p>Added 3 Heroic Weapons:</p>



<ul>
<li><em>Argent Edge (Combat Knife – Fencing type)</em></li>



<li><em>Ultima Ratio (Omnissian Axe – Fencing type)</em></li>



<li><em>Deathwatch (Heavy Bolt Rifle with Grenade Launcher)</em></li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Changes from PTS:</strong></p>



<ul>
<li><em>Argent Edge</em>&nbsp;riposte damage increased by 50%.</li>
</ul>



<h3>New DLC Content:</h3>



<p>Included in Season Pass 2:</p>



<ul>
<li>Raven Guard Champion Pack (Assault Champion + Bolt Pistol)</li>



<li>Carcharodons Chapter Pack (Unlike the other Cosmetic Packs, the Carcharodons Cosmetic Pack does not add a new Heraldry page to unlock the cosmetic items. Instead, the armour pieces will be automatically unlocked and added to your armour sets once you purchase the pack.)</li>
</ul>



<p>Not included in any Season Pass:</p>



<ul>
<li>3 Custom Heads + VO for PvE/ PvP Characters. (Space Wolves / Blood Angels / Black Templars)</li>
</ul>



<h3>GAMEPLAY AND BALANCING TWEAKS</h3>



<h3>PvE Perks</h3>



<p><strong><u>Tactical</u></strong></p>



<p><strong>Balanced Distribution</strong>: Both negative and positive effects are increased from 10% to 15%.</p>



<p><strong>Kraken Penetrator Rounds</strong>: All bolter weapons now deal 50% more damage with body shots.</p>



<p><strong>Changes from PTS:</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Kraken Penetrator Rounds now correctly apply to bolter rounds only.</li>
</ul>



<p><strong><u>Sniper</u></strong></p>



<p><strong>Efficient Readiness</strong>: Now the effect lasts 5 seconds after deactivation.</p>



<p><strong>Ambush</strong>: Now forces stagger to the enemies.</p>



<p><strong>Vantage Point</strong>: Added an indication when ready.</p>



<p><strong><u>Assault</u></strong></p>



<p><strong>Squad Cohesion</strong>: Effect is increased from 10% to 15%.</p>



<p><strong>Hammer of Wrath</strong>: Is now a Prestige Perk replacing “Commendation”.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Commendation</strong>: Removed.</p>



<p><strong>Strong Strike</strong>: New perk, taking the original place of “Hammer of Wrath”:&nbsp;<em>“Hitting an enemy with an attack after a Jump Pack Dash restores Jump Pack Ability Charge by 1. Cooldown 10 seconds.”</em></p>



<p><strong>Winged Fury</strong>: Now works with all stances of Power Sword.</p>



<h3>Firearms in PvE</h3>



<p><strong><u>Bolt Rifle</u></strong></p>



<p>Base damage is increased by 10% for versions:&nbsp;</p>



<ul>
<li>Drogos Reclamation – Beta (Artificer)</li>



<li>Ophelian Liberation – Beta (Relic)</li>
</ul>



<p><strong><u>Bolt Carbine (Marksman Version)</u></strong></p>



<p>Base damage is increased by 11% for versions:&nbsp;</p>



<ul>
<li>Drogos Reclamation Marksman (Artificer)</li>



<li>Ophelian Liberation Marksman (Relic)</li>
</ul>



<p><strong><u>Inferno Pistol</u></strong></p>



<p>Gunstrike damage is increased by 22%.</p>



<p><strong><u>Volkite Pistol</u></strong></p>



<p>Gunstrike damage is increased by 9%.</p>



<p><strong><u>Sanctified Wrath Reliquary</u></strong></p>



<p>Bonus to Melee Damage is increased from 25% to 35%.</p>



<p>Effect duration is increased from 15 to 20 seconds.</p>



<h3>Melee in PvE</h3>



<h3>Damage of all Artificer and Relic Balanced type melee weapons was increased by about 15% on average.</h3>



<p><strong>Changes from PTS:</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Heroic Chainsword and Power Sword damage increased by 10%.</li>
</ul>



<h3>PvP</h3>



<ul>
<li>Fixed restoring armour by hitting an enemy for Power Axe.&nbsp;</li>



<li>Fixed issue with 3rd attack in Power Sword combo dealing too much damage.</li>



<li>Blindness effect from Shock Grenade is decreased from 2 sec to 1,5 sec.</li>
</ul>



<h3>Rewards</h3>



<ul>
<li>Siege Mode: Rebalanced rewards for waves completion first 5 waves grant less XP, while later waves grant more XP.</li>



<li>Stratagems: Hard difficulty Stratagems no longer grant XP.&nbsp;</li>
</ul>



<h3>Gameplay QoL</h3>



<ul>
<li>Contested health no longer fades away during grab animations</li>



<li>Rebalanced melee attacks that have multiple attacks: Now they restore contested health with each strike instead of just the first one.</li>



<li>Slightly adjusted hitboxes of a few melee attacks so they would connect more easily against large enemies.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where Bolt Sniper Rifle and Las Fusil would miss their targets at extremely long range. Aim Assist at such distances has also been slightly increased.</li>



<li>Improved properties of bullet magnetism for Chaos enemy NPC: Chaos Spawns , Rubric Marines, Tzaangors, Terminators. Making them slightly easier to headshot at medium and long ranges.</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Changes from PTS:</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Jump Pack dash can be used to cancel any player melee animation.</li>



<li>Improved controls responsiveness after using Jump Pack Dash attacks.</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>CUSTOMISATION</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Added and updated a few Champion parts to the Custom Armour Set pieces:
<ul>
<li>Added Ultramarine Champion Tabard to Tactical</li>



<li>Added Imperial Fist Champion Tabard to Tactical</li>



<li>Added robes to Dark Angels Champion Bulwark’s chest</li>



<li>Added Dark Angels Champion shoulder pads to Heavy</li>



<li>Updated White Scars Champion chest on Tactical to include belt accessories</li>



<li>Added Black Templars Champion shoulder pads to Heavy</li>



<li>Added Blood Angels Champion shoulder pads and backpack to Bulwark</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li>Added the option to switch and apply Heroic Weapons skins to other weapons (not applicable to special weapons i.e combi-weapon).</li>



<li>Lots of minor customisation fixes for both Loyalists and Chaos.</li>
</ul>



<p>Changes from PTS:</p>



<ul>
<li>Added 4 more shared customisation slots.</li>



<li>Added missing unlock conditions for Power Axe skins in PvP.</li>
</ul>



<h3>LEVELS</h3>



<ul>
<li>Lots of minor fixes with level geometry.</li>
</ul>



<h3>ENEMIES</h3>



<p>Lots of minor fixes with animations.</p>



<h3>GENERAL FIXES</h3>



<ul>
<li>Fixed: The plasma weapon perk “<strong>Fast venting</strong>” reduced the cooling by ~7.5% instead of 15% as announced in the tooltip.</li>



<li>Fixed a bug with the&nbsp;<strong>Heroic Heavy Bolt Pistol</strong>&nbsp;not interrupting enemy reinforcements with body shots.</li>



<li>Fixed a bug with the Controller&nbsp;<strong>Aim Assist</strong>&nbsp;strength depending on camera FOV.</li>



<li>Lots of minor bug fixes.</li>



<li>Lots of minor localisation bug fixes.</li>



<li>Lots of minor UI and sound fixes.</li>
</ul>



<h3>TECH</h3>



<ul>
<li>Crash fixes and general stability improvements.</li>



<li>Memory optimisations.</li>



<li>Minor performance improvements.</li>



<li>Minor loading times optimization.</li>



<li>General connectivity improvements.</li>
</ul>



<p>The update 12.0 patch notes were found through Focus Entertainment’s new <a href="https://community.focus-entmt.com/focus-entertainment/space-marine-2/blogs/356-patch-notes-12-0" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">blog post</a>. </p>







<p>In other news, Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine 3 is <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/warhammer-40000-space-marine-3-is-in-development/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">officially in development</a>. What are your thoughts on the Space Marine 2 Techmarine update? Leave your thoughts down in the comments, and join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/wolfenstein-3-casting-call-reveals-early-plot-details/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Wolfenstein 3’s casting call revealing early plot details</a>.&nbsp;Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/space-marine-2-techmarine-update-patch-notes-new-class-weapon-map-and-more/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EA makes layoffs at Skate developer Full Circle]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ea-makes-layoffs-at-skate-developer-full-circle</link>
            <guid>1446859</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-testid="article-base-contributors"><div data-component="contributors"><a data-testid="contributor-name" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/author/chris-kerr" data-discover="true">Chris Kerr<!-- -->,</a><p><span data-testid="contributor-title">Senior Editor, News</span><span data-testid="contributor-title">, <!-- -->GameDeveloper.com</span></p><p data-testid="contributors-date">February 26, 2026</p></div><p><span data-component="icon" data-name="Clock"></span><span data-testid="article-read-time-text">1 Min<!-- --> <!-- -->Read</span></p></div><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">EA has laid off an undisclosed number of workers at </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Skate</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> developer Full Circle.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The news comes around five months after the title made its early access debut with the promise of becoming an "ever-growing, ever-evolving skateboarding sandbox."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/skate-tops-15-million-players-in-under-three-weeks">Skate</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/skate-tops-15-million-players-in-under-three-weeks"> attracted over 15 million players in under three weeks</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, but EA said it must reshape Full Circle to better support the free-to-play title.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"These shifts mean making changes to our team structure, and some roles will be impacted. The teammates affected are talented colleagues and friends who helped build the foundation of </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Skate.</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> Their creativity and dedication are deeply ingrained in what players experience today. This decision is not a reflection of their impact and we’re committed to supporting them through this transition," </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.ea.com/games/skate/skate/news/an-update-from-fullcircle">said the company in a short blog post</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Our work on </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Skate</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> continues. We look forward to working with you as we move faster, listen more closely, and deliver consistently for all of you. Our commitment to skate., and to the millions of players who believe in it, remains strong."</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/new-york-sues-valve-over-loot-boxes" target="_self" data-discover="true">New York sues Valve over loot box-driven gambling</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">It's currently unclear how many people have been impacted by the layoffs. Game Developer has reached out to EA for comment.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Skate</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> currently has a 'mixed' rating on Steam from over 58,000 user reviews. </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://steamdb.info/app/3354750/charts/">According to SteamDB estimates</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, the game peaked at 134,901 concurrent players on Steam during its launch window.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">It appears that </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Skate</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> was unable to sustain that early momentum, however, with the title failing to surpass 4,000 concurrent players over the past month.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">EA is currently in the process of being </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/saudi-arabia-is-taking-ea-private-alongside-other-investors">taken private by an investor consortium</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> that includes Saudi sovereign wealth fund, PIF. If the deal goes through, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/saudi-arabia-will-own-93-4-percent-of-ea-after-buyout">PIF will own 93.4 percent of the U.S. publisher</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Senior Editor, News, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer news editor Chris Kerr is an award-winning reporter with over a decade of experience in the game industry. His byline has appeared in notable print and digital publications including Edge, Stuff, Wireframe, International Business Times, and&nbsp;PocketGamer.biz. Throughout his career, Chris has covered major industry events including GDC, PAX Australia, Gamescom, Paris Games Week, and Develop Brighton.&nbsp;</span></p></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ea-makes-layoffs-at-skate-developer-full-circle]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>