<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 14:34:47 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dynasty Warriors Origins – Nintendo Switch 2 Review]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/01/16/dynasty-warriors-origins-nintendo-switch-2-review/</link>
            <guid>1408234</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
			
			<p>The Musou games and their ‘1v1000’ gameplay style are practically a foundational piece for video game civilisation at this point. Ever since the original Dynasty Warriors game appeared on the PlayStation, they’ve pushed the technical boundaries of each platform, filling your screens with Yellow Turban Warriors, four-digit kill counts, and screen-filling carnage at every turn. Now it’s the turn of the <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/nintendo-switch-2">Nintendo Switch 2</a>, though <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/01/13/dynasty-warriors-origins-review-the-best-musuo-game-ever/">Dynasty Warriors: Origins</a> is not the first Musou game to arrive on this generation of handheld.</p>
<p><iframe title="DYNASTY WARRIORS: ORIGINS - Gameplay Features (Nintendo Switch 2)" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rjBwUY3uPrU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Koei Tecmo and Omega Force have worked alongside Nintendo for a considerable length of time, with their collaboration on the Legend of Zelda spin-off Hyrule Warriors ensuring that this is a team that are thoroughly versed in Nintendo’s hardware. Most recently, that’s seen <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/11/04/hyrule-warriors-age-of-imprisonment-review/">Hyrule Warriors: Age of Imprisonment</a> arrive on Switch 2, and it’s clear that many of the lessons learned from that release have been carried over to this port of Dynasty Warriors Origins.</p>


<p>Dynasty Warriors: Origins immediately impresses with the quality of its cutscenes. Fully voiced in either Japanese or English, these look excellent, whether CG or in-engine, and they run at a consistent frame rate as well, which you can’t always guarantee on Nintendo’s less powerful hardware. The in-engine versions give you a good look at the character models, and they’re surprisingly close to those you’ll see on <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/playstation-5">PS5</a> and <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/xbox-series-x">Series X</a>, albeit with a hint more anti-aliasing shimmer around character’s hair. They set the tone for an experience that feels very close to the one available across other platforms.</p>


<p>Omega Force look to have made smart decisions with the transition to Switch 2, rather than just a wholesale downgrade which seems to be the current approach for a number of companies. That, in and of itself, makes this one of the most consistent and impressive Switch 2 ports we’ve seen so far.</p>
<p>There’s two key graphical settings here, and it’s nice to see Koei Tecmo letting Switch 2 players make some decisions about the game’s visual setup. In this case, that means opting for either a locked 30fps or letting Origins run with an unlocked, variable frame rate, and it’s an intriguing choice.</p>
<p>There is certainly some extra fluidity when playing with a variable frame rate, and that wiggle room means that, at times, Dynasty Warriors: Origins can feel more reactive. However, that also means that the frame rate can alter depending on the situation, and with more warriors on screen, there’s definitely increased stress and strain on the engine. The frame rate doesn’t drop to a point where it feels like stuttering, but if you’re aware of it, you’ll probably want to opt for the locked 30fps, as it’s simply more consistent.</p>
<p>Interestingly, the place where it feels like the most graphical concessions have been made is in the open world. This top-down overworld has definitely lost some detail, and you can make the frame rate occasionally drop when you’re running around and spinning the camera about. Still, as a slower, non-action section of the game, it doesn’t detract from the experience at all. This is all true whether in docked or handheld mode, but, unusually, the handheld mode actually feels more detailed, particularly in cutscenes and the open world. There’s none of the obvious resolution downgrading that I’m used to seeing, and it makes Origins an excellent experience when you’re out and about.</p>

		
		<div id="gallery-1"><dl>
			<dt>
				<a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/01/16/dynasty-warriors-origins-nintendo-switch-2-review/origins-switch-2-docked-1/" data-slb-active="1" data-slb-asset="899304067" data-slb-internal="467884" data-slb-group="467875"></a>
			</dt>
				<dd id="gallery-1-467884">
				Origins Switch 2 Docked 1
				</dd></dl><dl>
			<dt>
				<a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/01/16/dynasty-warriors-origins-nintendo-switch-2-review/origins-switch-2-undocked-1/" data-slb-active="1" data-slb-asset="132204702" data-slb-internal="467883" data-slb-group="467875"></a>
			</dt>
				<dd id="gallery-1-467883">
				Origins Switch 2 Undocked 1
				</dd></dl><dl>
			<dt>
				<a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/01/16/dynasty-warriors-origins-nintendo-switch-2-review/origins-switch-2-undocked/" data-slb-active="1" data-slb-asset="631408797" data-slb-internal="467882" data-slb-group="467875"></a>
			</dt>
				<dd id="gallery-1-467882">
				Origins Switch 2 Undocked
				</dd></dl><dl>
			<dt>
				<a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/01/16/dynasty-warriors-origins-nintendo-switch-2-review/origins-switch-2-docked/" data-slb-active="1" data-slb-asset="216204520" data-slb-internal="467881" data-slb-group="467875"></a>
			</dt>
				<dd id="gallery-1-467881">
				Origins Switch 2 Docked
				</dd></dl><br><dl>
			<dt>
				<a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/01/16/dynasty-warriors-origins-nintendo-switch-2-review/origins-switch-2-docked-3/" data-slb-active="1" data-slb-asset="806276320" data-slb-internal="467880" data-slb-group="467875"></a>
			</dt>
				<dd id="gallery-1-467880">
				Origins Switch 2 Docked 3
				</dd></dl><dl>
			<dt>
				<a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/01/16/dynasty-warriors-origins-nintendo-switch-2-review/origins-switch-2-undocked-3/" data-slb-active="1" data-slb-asset="1024453956" data-slb-internal="467879" data-slb-group="467875"></a>
			</dt>
				<dd id="gallery-1-467879">
				Origins Switch 2 Undocked 3
				</dd></dl>
			<br>
		</div>

<p>Dynasty Warriors: Origins served as a reset for the series, and it managed to update and revise the classic Musou experience for the modern day, tightening up the combat and beefing up the storytelling while layering RPG-like progression across the top of it. All of that feels just as good here in the Switch 2 release.</p>
<p>The question mark that lingers over Dynasty Warriors: Origins is the addition of a fictional central character, complete with amnesia, a mystical quest, and a newfound supernatural element. For a series that remains grounded in history – albeit a hyper-stylised, caricature of this period of Chinese history – it was an interesting pivot, but one that fits with the shift in tone towards an action-RPG. If anything, I found it gave me more agency and more permanence than previous Dynasty Warriors games, giving me a place within the narrative and setting that matched my own, external viewpoint.</p>
<p>Alongside the more in-depth combat and RPG-like progression, Dynasty Warriors: Origins stand out feature is its audio. The quality of both the English and the Japanese dub is good, but it’s the orchestral soundtrack with its louder, more bombastic moments during battles that really help to set the tone for a journey that feels as grand and epic as you could hope for.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/01/16/dynasty-warriors-origins-nintendo-switch-2-review/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Review: Dynasty Warriors: Origins (Switch 2) - A Super-Solid Port Of Fantastic Reboot]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/nintendo-switch-2/dynasty-warriors-origins</link>
            <guid>1408231</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><section>
<figure><a title="Dynasty Warriors: Origins Review - Screenshot 1 of 7" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/161468/large.jpg"></a><figcaption>Captured on Nintendo Switch 2 (Handheld/Undocked)</figcaption></figure><p>Wading into <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/dynasty-warriors-origins">Dynasty Warriors: Origins</a> on Switch 2, I'm keenly aware that there's been a lot of conversation about the game's frame rate on Nintendo's console in the run-up to release.</p>
<p>Yes, it's not a super-sweet 60fps as on some other platforms, and yes, that is a shame. However! Anyone who fancies a little Musou madness but isn't jumping in as a result of this fact is genuinely shooting (or slicing) themselves in the foot, as this is a genuinely brilliant series refresh that looks and plays great on Switch 2, in both docked and handheld modes.</p>
<p>I've already played this one through on a PS5 Pro when it released in January 2025, and taking everything into consideration, I've got zero hesitation in fully recommending this Switch 2 port as heartily as that 60fps version. How so when they've halved the frame digits? Well, playing portably is a big selling point with a game that suits dipping in and out of for a quick blast this well, so I'm way more likely to stick at it on Switch, and that frame rate drop honestly makes little real-world difference. This is one of those 30fps situations where once you've spent 10 minutes readjusting, it's all good. It feels smooth and responsive at all times.</p>
<figure><a title="Dynasty Warriors: Origins Review - Screenshot 2 of 7" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/161469/large.jpg"></a><figcaption>Captured on Nintendo Switch 2 (Handheld/Undocked)</figcaption></figure>
<p>Indeed, even though Koei Tecmo has gone and thrown in a "variable" unlocked frame rate toggle for you to mess with, honestly, I recommend just leaving this off to enjoy a consistently smooth and fully exhilarating ride without any little niggling stutters that this toggle introduces at points. You don't need niggles distracting you from the story or the '1 VS 1000' battles here either, as what Dynasty Warriors: Origins brings to the table is a grand refocusing of the usual Warriors caper that makes for a very exciting and stylish reboot.</p>
<p>Now that we've got the most pressing issue out of the way — now that we know there's no awful image blurring or crippling stutters — I can get down to praising it freely for all the very many things that it does so well.</p>
<p>Anyone who knows me knows I love Musou, and thankfully we've had a few absolute belters of late, most recently in the form of the stellar <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/hyrule-warriors-age-of-imprisonment">Hyrule Warriors: Age of Imprisonment</a>. This game, though, sees the <strong>Romance of the Three Kingdoms</strong> core of the franchise <em>finally</em> get some much-needed TLC.</p>
<p>I'll never agree that a Musou game, even the older ones, are actually all that repetitive or simplistic, as they're often attacked as being. I'll defend them for what they are at all times, and the repetition and trance-like whipping through enemies that they bring to the table has always been a source of great personal gaming comfort. But it did need a kick up the arse. That much I can accept. Dynasty Warriors: Origins <em>is</em> that kick up the arse. And it's a good one. A real 'toe-poker'.</p>
<figure><a title="Dynasty Warriors: Origins Review - Screenshot 3 of 7" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/161470/large.jpg"></a><figcaption>Captured on Nintendo Switch 2 (Handheld/Undocked)</figcaption></figure>
<p>Here, for the first time in the series, you play as a nameless travelling wanderer, who I'll admit is a bit of a bland and boring avatar overall. But it's for good reason. You see, the narrative approach taken is to slow the whole thing down, and to give you a little breathing space amidst all the events, character introductions and storylines of the Romance of the Three Kingdoms saga. To do this, we have no more switching around a huge catalogue of protagonists, instead sticking with this one, very upgradeable, main avatar.</p>
<p>Yes, you do get to muck around with some other characters in side missions and at specific moments — and there's more of this on the way in the game's DLC, which launches alongside this Switch 2 port — but what sticking with one character for the main duration does is ground us in a fixed perspective, making the constant introductions of important historical figures and political events easier to keep a foothold in. I didn't get lost along the way. I remembered people when they returned to the fray, and this helps enormously with the game's overall narrative, which settles on a part of the overall Romance saga, rather than trying to blow through way too much history all at once, as has been the case in the past.</p>
<figure><a title="Dynasty Warriors: Origins Review - Screenshot 4 of 7" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/161471/large.jpg"></a><figcaption>Captured on Nintendo Switch 2 (Handheld/Undocked)</figcaption></figure>
<p>I won't spoil any of the plot or surprises, but this refocusing works really well. This is absolutely my favourite game in the main franchise in terms of both its narrative and its slightly darker and more brutal vibe. It also introduces some nice RPG aspects, now that we've only got one main character to worry about, and these add more depth than ever. There's a range of 10 weapons to level up and master, unlocking new battle moves and skills for each one as you go. It all feels much more personal and the sense of progression, given the narrower scope and roster, is more keenly felt as a result.</p>
<p>The combat's main draw, pre-release at least, was the sheer number of enemies that are now present on the screen. On the PS5 it properly wowed me, even though I'm used to battering my way through these enormous Musou crowds.</p>
<p>On Switch 2, and especially when you're playing in handheld, the wow factor has not been diminished one iota. Indeed, it honestly feels like a new benchmark for portable play with the sheer scope of what's going on, unfettered by technical issues, on your screen. The enemies are absolutely everywhere, and so it's lucky you've got a ton of cool new tricks and skills to beat the snot out of them with, innit.</p>
<figure><a title="Dynasty Warriors: Origins Review - Screenshot 5 of 7" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/161472/large.jpg"></a><figcaption>Captured on Nintendo Switch 2 (Docked)</figcaption></figure>
<p>Starting with a trusty sword, you'll soon find yourself picking up gauntlets, lances, and a whole bunch of other weapons that all excel in different scenarios. The lance, as an example, is a cracker for clearing huge crowds, whilst the gauntlets are my go-to for juggling boss fools in the air like the clueless children they really are.</p>
<p>Each weapon feels unique, and given that the enemy AI here is the best I've seen from the series — you'll actually need to use your perfect dodges and parries! — you really do get a chance to dig in and try them all out to find which ones work best and where.</p>
<p>And that's all before you add the series' signature screen-shaking musou attacks to the equation. Yes, they're just as satisfying as ever to pull off, and watching hundreds of wee guys fly into the air in unison just never fails to make me feel much better about my life. It is what it is.</p>
<figure><a title="Dynasty Warriors: Origins Review - Screenshot 6 of 7" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/161461/large.jpg"></a><figcaption>Captured on Nintendo Switch 2 (Docked)</figcaption></figure>
<p>Over the course of the main campaign's five chapters, and through a whole bunch of side skirmishes and missions that are spread out across the game's dinky mini-world map (it's one of those nice ones you get to walk around), the story is also woven at a nice pace, providing enough of a backdrop to keep you going, whilst the combat continues to drop just the right amount of new gear, new moves, and new tactics along the way to keep you invested.</p>
<p>You now also have a bunch of larger-scale tactical options on a drop-down menu that work on a cooldown timer. These allow you to dramatically change the tide of battle (a big boost to overall morale) by allowing you to call catapult barrages, volleys of fiery arrows, and chariot charges. There's also a few points along the way where your main character will need to choose sides and run with a particular crew. This not only makes things more absorbing in the moment, but adds plenty of replayability with multiple endings and a 'true' ending to unlock.</p>
<figure><a title="Dynasty Warriors: Origins Review - Screenshot 7 of 7" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/161462/large.jpg"></a><figcaption>Captured on Nintendo Switch 2 (Handheld/Undocked)</figcaption></figure>
<p>Honestly, with the story switching between the main Romance saga thrust and our new hero's amnesia issues (I know, cheesy, but it works), you'll feel way more involved than you might expect for the genre, and the combat is addictive in the extreme, meaning replays for those alternative endings are all but guaranteed.</p>
<p>In terms of negatives, well, the loading times are a little longer in starting a mission, and the cutscenes that bookend battles and other moments as you wander the map can introduce a little bit of 30fps stutter. It's very minimal, and it's only during cutscenes, but it's there. Related to this, try as I might, I just couldn't get on with the variable graphics mode at all; you can really feel it as the camera moves around, so let's hope that gets improved down the line.</p>
<p>Other than that, though, and other than some horrendous English voice acting which you should switch out for Japanese with English subs <em>immediately,</em> Dynasty Warriors: Origins on Switch 2 is every bit as good as on other platforms, which is very good indeed! It also feels like a bit of a watershed moment, I have to say, as someone who has reviewed a whole lot of action games on both Switch consoles. This game, and especially in portable, feels a little magical in just how good it looks and feels whilst delivering enormous and incredibly good-looking battles to the palm of your hand.</p>
</section><section id="conclusion"><h2>Conclusion</h2>
<p>Dynasty Warriors: Origins on Switch 2 is a super-solid port of a fantastic reboot for the franchise. The shift to focus on one protagonist and improvements in storytelling across the board result in a gripping adventure that delivers huge enemy numbers to slice and dice through, whilst also being careful not to lose players in a mess of historical names and events.</p>
<p>30fps is a bit of a shame, but this <em>is</em> a super smooth and responsive 30fps — the good sort — making for a game that lands on Switch 2 in fine form and with plenty to offer hardened Musou and action fans alike.</p></section>

</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/nintendo-switch-2/dynasty-warriors-origins]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lego Zelda Ocarina of Time Set Seemingly Leaked for March]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/lego-zelda-ocarina-of-time-set-leak-march</link>
            <guid>1408228</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>It looks as though a new Lego <em>Zelda </em>set has been leaked for March, and if you're a fan of seminal Nintendo 64 adventure <em>Ocarina of Time</em>, then this set should make you very happy indeed.</p><p>As spotted by Redditor <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Legoleak/comments/1qe6y4h/zelda_77093_the_final_battle_ocarina_of_time/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">BrickTap</a>, the set will seemingly be called "The Final Battle: <em>Ocarina of Time</em>", and, as the name suggests, it'll depict the climactic fight between Link and Ganondorf at the conclusion of the 1998 classic.</p><p>If the leak is correct, then the set will contain just over 1000 pieces and will feature minifigures for Link, Zelda, and Ganondorf, as well as a brick-built Ganon, Link's Megaton Hammer, and his indispensable fairy buddy Navi, as well as a set of recovery heart items.</p><figure role="group">
<article>
  
      
  

  </article>

<figcaption>This is apparently what the new <em>Zelda </em>Lego set will look like. Image courtesy of user BrickTap on Reddit.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Assuming BrickTap's information is solid, then The Final Battle: <em>Ocarina of Time </em>will be launching on March 1st and will set you back $130 (that's €120 or £100 if you're in Europe or the UK).</p><p>That might sound like a lot for what seems to be a relatively small set, but it works out at around 0.13 cents per piece, which, while slightly more expensive than the <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/lego-pokemon-fan-favorites-revealed" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="20154363-2140-41d8-aed8-9ac66d983fc8" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">recently-revealed <em>Pokemon</em></a><em> </em>Lego set, still doesn't seem too bad.</p><p>The <em>Zelda </em>set also seems to be more expensive on a per-piece basis than many original Lego products, but it does look like the <em>Ocarina of Time </em>scene contains a lot of custom elements, so that could well be what's driving the price up.</p><p>This is, at any rate, far from Nintendo's only foray into the Lego world. There's the aforementioned <em>Pokemon </em>partnership, of course, but you can also grab Lego sets for properties like <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/lego-animal-crossing" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="25704771-aecd-4ebf-b2a8-3f90af39a5ca" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow"><em>Animal Crossing</em></a><em> </em>and <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/first-ever-lego-mario-kart-sets" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="d55c03af-b288-4bcc-a242-7dec1b9f0687" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow"><em>Mario</em></a>.</p><figure role="group">
<article>
  
      
  

  </article>

<figcaption>The new Lego <em>Zelda </em>set isn't Nintendo's only string in this particular bow.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Nintendo hasn't officially announced The Final Battle: <em>Ocarina of Time</em> yet (<a href="https://www.lego.com/en-gb/categories/adults-welcome/article/legend-of-zelda-set-2026" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">in full, at least</a>), but if the leak is correct, there will probably be an official reveal soon. Stay tuned for more.</p></div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/lego-zelda-ocarina-of-time-set-leak-march]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon Goes After Bose, Now Selling the Bluetooth Micro Speaker at a New Record Low]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/amazon-goes-after-bose-now-selling-the-bluetooth-micro-speaker-at-a-new-record-low-2000660305</link>
            <guid>1408222</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Good music can instantly lift your mood and the overall vibe of any space. Those shopping for a portable Bluetooth speaker today should consider grabbing the 2nd-generation Bose SoundLink Micro speaker, while it’s going for less than $100 at Amazon.</p>
<p>The retailer is <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6762/">currently offering this mini yet mighty device at a 23% discount, which drops its $129 price to just $99</a>. Delivery is free, and the offer applies to all color options. Pick black if you’re looking for something basic, or go for the stunning pink version if you want something that can make a statement! The discount ends soon, though. If you’ve been on the lookout for a solid speaker, we highly recommend acting before it’s too late.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6762/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Packs a Solid Punch</h2>
<p>As the name suggests, this speaker is truly portable. The pocketable size, paired with the upgraded strap, makes it easy to carry around anywhere with ease; slide it into your pocket, attach it to your backpack, or just hold it in your hand as it delivers rich sound. It won’t add unnecessary weight, which is essential if you’re trying to travel light. Durability comes from its rugged design, plus an IP67 design that makes it dust, water, shock, and rust proof. Whether it’s a party on the beach, fun by the poolside, or just a solo session in the rain, the weather conditions won’t interfere with your listening session.</p>



<p>Of course, portability doesn’t mean a compromise on the sound quality. SoundLink Micro Speaker delivers crisp sound and impressive bass for all your tracks, from energy-filled songs to podcasts and even guided meditation sessions. The Bose app takes the experience even further by letting you tweak bass, treble, and mid-level to your liking. The app can also be used to control volume and create shortcuts. What’s more, you’ll also have the option of linking two SoundLink Micro speakers (2nd Gen) together for larger sound, which is great when you want to entertain a crowd. In this setup, you can choose between Stereo mode and Party mode. The former balances out the audio from each speaker, while the latter plays the same sound at once from any paired compatible Bose speaker.</p>
<p>Battery life is another strong selling point here. A single charge gets you up to 12 hours of continuous listening, which is more than enough to keep the party going all night long. Additionally, the extended range of up to 30 feet and increased bandwidth improve connectivity and make it easy to move around freely with your connected device, instead of feeling tied to the speaker.</p>
<p>This speaker normally retails for $129, but you can snap it up for just $99 today. All colors are discounted, so you have options to choose from. Just be sure to grab it as soon as you can, as we’re not expecting the discount to last long.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6762/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/amazon-goes-after-bose-now-selling-the-bluetooth-micro-speaker-at-a-new-record-low-2000660305]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Julian Gerighty Leaving Massive To Work at Battlefield Studios]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/julian-gerighty-leaving-massive-to-work-battlefield/</link>
            <guid>1408219</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Massive Entertainment has shared a message on social media confirming that Julian Gerighty, executive producer on The Division franchise, is stepping down and transitioning to a new role at Battlefield Studios. This takes Gerighty from Ubisoft to Electronic Arts, moving from one shooter series to another.</p>



<p>Gerighty has been at Ubisoft for more than fifteen years and recently appeared in interviews talking about the future of The Division, making bold promises about The Division 3.</p>



<h2 id="h-the-division-s-executive-producer-is-moving-on">The Division’s Executive Producer is Moving On</h2>



<p>In a recent post on social media, Massive Entertainment shared the message:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>Today, we want to share that Julian Gerighty, Executive Producer on the Tom Clancy’s The Division franchise is heading off to a new adventure at Battlefield Studios. While we’ll miss him, his mark will live on at Massive and we’ll continue to bring hte world he’s been part of creating to our players for years to come.</p>



<p>Julian, your legacy is part of this studio and remember: once an Agent, always an Agent.</p>



<p>For our players, don’t worry. Our teams who built this world with Julian are still here, carrying it forward with an ambitious, unchanged commitment for the future with The Division 2, The Division 2: Survivors, The Division Resurgence, and The Division 3</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Days ago, Gerighty spoke on The Division 3, stressing it’s shaping up to be ‘a monster’ and suggesting it will have the same impact on the industry as the first Division game, released back in 2016.</p>










        <div>
                  <p>
                    Grant's passion for gaming started on the Amstrad CPC when he wasn't even old enough to walk properly. Now, he's a multi-platform expert gamer with an undying love for the…                  </p>
                  <p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/author/grant-taylor-hill/">
                    More from Grant Taylor-Hill                  </a>
                </p></div>
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/julian-gerighty-leaving-massive-to-work-battlefield/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Division Boss Julian Gerighty Leaves For Battlefield: "Don't Worry," Ubisoft Says]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-division-boss-julian-gerighty-leaves-for-battlefield-dont-worry-ubisoft-says/1100-6537452/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>1408213</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6537452">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Massive Entertainment has <a href="https://x.com/UbiMassive/status/2012157010784186856" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">announced</a> that Julian Gerighty, the executive producer for The Division at Ubisoft, is leaving the company to join Battlefield Studios.</p><p>"While we'll miss him, his mark will live on at Massive and we'll continue to bring the world he's been part of creating to our players for years to come," Ubisoft said.</p><p>Ubisoft also told fans, "don't worry" about Gerighty leaving. "Our teams who built this world with Julian are still here, carrying it forward with an ambitious, unchanged commitment for the future of The Division 2, The Division 2: Survivors, The Division Resurgence, and The Division 3," the developer said.</p><p>Gerighty <a href="https://x.com/jgerighty/status/2012156450039033939" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">released his own statement </a>on his departure, writing, "It's time for me to hang up my go bag (keeping the watch) as I go on another grand adventure."</p><p>He added: "The Division future burns bright, and I can't wait for you to discover what the teams have been working on. Long live The Division and Godspeed!"</p><p>Gerighty co-directed The Division and The Division 2, and was creative director on Star Wars Outlaws. In 2023, he was <a href="https://news.ubisoft.com/en-us/article/18oNmwEFQzGDu0TYVOAcJN/julian-gerighty-appointed-executive-producer-for-the-division-brand" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">promoted to become executive producer of the entire The Division series</a>, and under his watch, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ubisoft-cancels-the-division-heartland-but-the-division-3-is-still-coming/1100-6523480/" data-ref-id="1100-6523480">The Division: Heartland was canceled. </a> <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-division-3-release-date-trailer-story/1100-6537326/" data-ref-id="1100-6537326">The Division 3</a> is coming up next, and Gerighty recently said it's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-division-3-is-gearing-up-to-be-a-monster-says-series-executive-producer/1100-6537293/" data-ref-id="1100-6537293">shaping up to be a "monster." </a></p><p>It's not immediately clear what Gerighty's role at EA and Battlefield Studios will be. The company launched the highly successful Battlefield 6 in 2025. It was the<a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/2025-best-selling-games/2900-6281/#1" data-ref-id="2900-6281"> No. 1 best-selling game in the US through November</a>. Its Season 2 update was recently <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/battlefield-6s-season-2-delay-adds-more-challenges-cosmetics-and-double-xp-to-season-1/1100-6537406/" data-ref-id="1100-6537406">delayed to mid-February.</a></p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-division-boss-julian-gerighty-leaves-for-battlefield-dont-worry-ubisoft-says/1100-6537452/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[There Will Be Quite The Sideline Shuffle In Madden NFL 27]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/there-will-be-quite-the-sideline-shuffle-in-madden-nfl-27/1100-6537451/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>1408210</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-main">

      
                    
  
              <header id="masthead"><nav></nav></header>      
                            <div id="site-wrapper" role="main">
          <div id="default-content">
        
          <p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p>
  
    <article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6537451">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">When Madden NFL 27 arrives later this year, there will be nine new coaches roaming the sidelines for the 32 teams. Technically, a few of these won't necessarily be new altogether, as John Harbaugh goes from the Baltimore Ravens <a href="https://www.espn.com/nfl/story/_/id/47616292/sources-john-harbaugh-giants-expected-barring-setbacks" rel="nofollow ">to New York Giants</a> after being fired from the former. But undoubtedly, there will be at least a handful of first-timers with the amount of vacancies--equating to over a third of all organizations.</p><p dir="ltr">EA Sports has incorporated features like Coach DNA and Coach Speak into the Madden NFL series, so your team's coach can affect your in-game experience. They also have their own playsheets, too. So, for fans of the Ravens or Pittsburgh Steelers (Mike Tomlin stepped away), they should expect notable differences with whomever their teams hire when Madden NFL 27 launches. Harbaugh and Tomlin were also two of the longest-tenured coaches in the NFL, starting in 2008 and '07, respectively.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="313892110" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6466045,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;EA%20Sports%20Madden%2026%20-%20Official%20Reveal%20Trailer&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:119,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/ea-sports-madden-26-official-reveal-trailer\/2300-6466045\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466045\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466045\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466045\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6466045&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6466045,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6537451&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;madden-nfl-26&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;football-american,simulation,sports,team-based&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;playstation-5,xbox-series-x,pc,nintendo-switch-2&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;electronic-arts&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;franchise&quot;:&quot;madden-football&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;franchiseRoot&quot;:&quot;madden-football&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6466045},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6466045\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;Publisher Asset&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4506864-11.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/5kRygbcv.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1749052680,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="5kRygbcv" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> EA Sports Madden 26 - Official Reveal Trailer</p>
      </div>
<p dir="ltr">Here are all of the NFL teams that will have a new coach in Madden NFL 27:</p><ul><li dir="ltr">Baltimore Ravens</li><li dir="ltr">Pittsburgh Steelers</li><li dir="ltr">New York Giants - John Harbaugh</li><li dir="ltr">Atlanta Falcons</li><li dir="ltr">Tennessee Titans</li><li dir="ltr">Las Vegas Raiders</li><li dir="ltr">Arizona Cardinals</li><li dir="ltr">Miami Dolphins</li><li dir="ltr">Cleveland Browns</li></ul><p dir="ltr">Madden NFL 27 hasn't been officially announced yet. EA has mixed up when the reveal occurs with each installment in the long-running sports franchise. For example, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ea-sports-announces-madden-nfl-26-college-football-26-release-dates-and-preorders/1100-6531104/">Madden NFL 26 was unveiled in April 2025</a> alongside College Football 26. Meanwhile, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/madden-nfl-25-is-over-10-years-old-but-madden-25-could-also-be-announced-this-week/1100-6523470/">Madden NFL 25</a> wasn't announced until May 2024.</p><p dir="ltr">One thing that is almost certain: Madden NFL 27 will come out sometime this August. Every installment of this decade has arrived in that same month.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article>

    
  

        
  
</div>
                      <meta itemprop="seamless-content-list-items" data-list-items="[{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534941&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/2026-upcoming-games-release-schedule\/1100-6534941\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6537415&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/resident-evil-showcase-how-to-watch-start-times-and-what-to-expect\/1100-6537415\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6537395&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/forza-horizon-6-release-date-may-have-leaked-ahead-of-developer-direct\/1100-6537395\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6537407&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/god-of-war-tv-series-finds-its-kratos-with-sons-of-anarchy-actor\/1100-6537407\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6537422&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/tomb-raider-series-gives-first-look-at-sophie-turner-as-lara-croft\/1100-6537422\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6537410&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/what-to-do-first-in-animal-crossing-3-0-first-day-checklist\/1100-6537410\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6537436&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/amazons-big-mmo-that-started-strong-is-shutting-down\/1100-6537436\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6537405&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/ubisoft-is-sending-out-compensation-to-rainbow-six-siege-players-over-hack\/1100-6537405\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6537360&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/sophie-turner-discusses-tomb-raider-tv-show-and-her-intense-training-for-it\/1100-6537360\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6535971&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/arc-raiders-echoes-of-victory-ridge-quest-guide\/1100-6535971\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6537438&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/gog-boss-says-we-may-get-fewer-games-if-regulators-force-devs-to-maintain-them-forever\/1100-6537438\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6537026&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/arc-raiders-paving-the-way-quest-guide\/1100-6537026\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6537310&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/arc-raiders-prescriptions-of-the-past-quest-guide\/1100-6537310\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6537380&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/rockstar-union-court-case-potentially-reveals-first-gta-6-online-details\/1100-6537380\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6537354&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/evangelion-eva-unit-02-razer-collection-preorder-guide\/1100-6537354\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6536018&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/arc-raiders-celestes-journals-quest-guide\/1100-6536018\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6537265&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/arc-raiders-communication-hideout-quest-guide\/1100-6537265\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6535922&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/all-arc-raiders-quests-full-mission-list\/1100-6535922\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6537230&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/arc-raiders-eyes-in-the-sky-quest-guide\/1100-6537230\/&quot;}]">
            </div>
              
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/there-will-be-quite-the-sideline-shuffle-in-madden-nfl-27/1100-6537451/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["I had in my mind that The Elder Scrolls 6 was going to be like The Empire Strikes back," says former Bethesda designer once tipped to become the proj]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/the-elder-scrolls-6-could-have-been-like-star-wars-the-empire-strikes-back</link>
            <guid>1408204</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>

  <figure>
      <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/luke-2.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/luke-2.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/luke-2.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/luke-2.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/luke-2.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/luke-2.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/luke-2.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/luke-2.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/luke-2.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Eurogamer / Disney</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>The person allegedly once earmarked for the role of lead designer of The Elder Scrolls 6, Kurt Kuhlmann, has said that if they had their way, the game would have been like the beloved Star Wars movie The Empire Strikes Back.</p>
<p>His idea - he who spent 20 years working at <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/companies/bethesda-game-studios">Bethesda Game Studios</a> on nearly every Elder Scrolls game, including being co-lead designer of Skyrim - was the elven supremacists the Thalmor, the game's baddies, would temporarily win, Kuhlmann told <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/the-elder-scrolls/bethesdas-former-elder-scrolls-loremaster-on-why-he-left-starfields-communication-breakdowns-and-how-he-wanted-the-elder-scrolls-6-to-be-the-empire-strikes-back/">PCGamer</a>. Evil would triumph and there'd be something of a cliffhanger, and you'd get a chance at revenge in the next instalment, The Elder Scrolls 7.</p>
<p>"I had in my mind that TES6 was going to be like The Empire Strikes Back," Kuhlmann said. The player might have "secretly saved the day" by rescuing an heir to the throne, say, preserving hope for another day, "but overall it looks like the Thalmor are on the march". It would be a welcome change from the 'chosen one' storyline The Elder Scrolls games always use, he believed.</p>
<figure>
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>

</figure><p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MX9UuAt6FqI" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></p><p>Bethesda Game Studios boss <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/personas/todd-howard">Todd Howard</a> allegedly verbally offered Kuhlmann the lead designer role on TES6, Kuhlman said, when work finished on Skyrim. The studio's plan then was apparently to make <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/fallout-4-walkthrough-and-guide-4019">Fallout 4</a> and return to the famed fantasy series afterwards. But this didn't come to be. <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/fallout-76">Fallout 76</a> diverted the studio's attention and then <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/starfield-main-story-walkthrough-9352">Starfield</a> preoccupied it for several years afterwards, meaning it would be 11 years before Bethesda Game Studios returned properly to the next Elder Scrolls game.</p>
<blockquote><em>"It wasn't just my expectation - I had been told that that was going to happen"</em></blockquote>
<p>Kuhlmann, who'd been a lead systems designer on Starfield in the meantime, was ready for his call-up. "I was obviously one of the old-timers there and had a lot of experience," he said. "Bruce [Nesmith] and I had been the co-leads on Skyrim. I think most people would call it a successful project, so I thought that it wasn't unreasonable for me to think that I could be a successful lead on TES6. It wasn't just my expectation - I had been told that that was going to happen. And they made the decision, no, you're not going to be the lead."</p>
<p>Bethesda apparently offered him a different role on the project instead - "an important role", Kuhlmann said Howard called it. "But what I wanted and what he wanted were different at that point," he said. There was no indication Howard remembered the alleged verbal promise made years earlier and no reference was ever made to it. This, coupled with the ways in which the studio had changed during the development of Starfield, as it ballooned across multiple studios, contributed to Kuhlmann's decision to leave Bethesda Game Studios in 2023.</p>
<!-- code from Primis - Eurogamer.net - eurogamer.net -->
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<!-- code from Primis -->
<p>Nevertheless, Kuhlmann - once considered the loremaster of Elder Scrolls - acknowledges that leading the Elder Scrolls today is a different proposition to leading the studios back in 2011. "The role of lead on TES 6 is very different from the role of lead on Skyrim," he said. He also doesn't think his Empire Strikes Back idea would ever have flown with the team. Ending on a loss and a cliffhanger? "That's not a good way to end a game and say, yeah, we'll see you in 10, 15 years."</p><p>The Elder Scrolls 6 is now, blessedly, properly under way, having been announced ridiculously early back at an E3 in 2018, before Starfield was anywhere near made. <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-elder-scrolls-6-is-still-a-long-way-off-says-todd-howard-but-development-is-his-everyday-thing">Todd Howard said last November that the game was still "a long way off"</a>, but it sounds like a lengthy pre-production process is done and <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/even-todd-howard-wishes-elder-scrolls-6-development-went-a-little-faster-but-says-its-progressing-really-well">the majority of the studio is working on it</a>. I can't wait to play it in 2030. Stop it, Bertie, stop it.</p>

        </div>

  
      </article>



  



  <section>
        


    

      <details>
        <summary>
See 1 more              <span></span>

        </summary>

        
      </details>
  </section>

  <section>
    <span>Related topics</span>

    
  </section>
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/the-elder-scrolls-6-could-have-been-like-star-wars-the-empire-strikes-back]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mystery Product Code Sparks Rumours Of A New Switch 2 Model]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/01/mystery-product-code-sparks-rumours-of-a-new-switch-2-model</link>
            <guid>1408189</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Already?!</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure data-uuid="77b92cc095aa2"><a title="Switch 2" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/77b92cc095aa2/switch-2.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Damien McFerran / Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure><p>Right folks, get ready to file this one under either "huh?!" or "hmmm....", because an unusual discovery on Nintendo's official website has got folks chatting about a potential new Switch 2 model.</p>
<p>The discovery comes via Bluesky user <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/dootsky.re/post/3mcgz3nkmzl2i">dootsky</a>, who notes that a new product code labelled 'OSM' can be uncovered on the <a href="https://accounts.nintendo.com/portal/console">Nintendo Account Portal page</a>. They state that requesting the OSM product code returns an image of the Switch 2, while folks over on <a href="https://www.resetera.com/threads/potential-new-switch-2-model-osm-discovered-on-nintendos-internal-website.1407796/">ResetEra</a> claim that any other code results in an error message.</p>

<p>So what does this mean? Are we due a new Switch 2 model already? Well no, hold your horses.</p>
<p>In a <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/dootsky.re/post/3mcj5zjxbqs2e">follow-up post</a>, dootsky quite rightly states that the original Switch models – i.e. the Lite, OLED, etc – all had similar product codes: HAE, HAD, HDH, and HEG. The BEE product code for the Switch 2 shares no similarities with OSM.</p>
<p>That's not to rule out a new model <em>entirely</em>, but dootsky makes it clear that we shouldn't jump to any conclusions just yet. For one, today (16th January) marks one year since the Switch 2 was officially revealed to the world, so can we really expect a new model anytime soon..? Our gut says no.</p>
<p>Still, it's interesting nevertheless. It's obviously <em>something</em> – Nintendo doesn't just come up with new product codes for no reason – but just what it could be is anybody's guess right now.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:196263,196160 @ 1768573808 -->
<p><em>What do you make of all this? Could this product code relate to a new Switch 2 model, or is it something else entirely? Let us know with a comment.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://bsky.app/profile/dootsky.re/post/3mcgz3nkmzl2i" rel="noopener" href="https://bsky.app/profile/dootsky.re/post/3mcgz3nkmzl2i">bsky.app</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-info/d41d8cd98f00b204e9800998ecf8427e @ 1768573265 --></div></article><div><p>Nintendo Life’s resident horror fanatic, when he’s not knee-deep in Resident Evil and Silent Hill lore, Ollie likes to dive into a good horror book while nursing a lovely cup of tea. He also enjoys long walks and listens to everything from TOOL to Chuck Berry.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Olliemar28"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/ollie-nl.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Olliemar28');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/01/mystery-product-code-sparks-rumours-of-a-new-switch-2-model]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Seven Deadly Sins: Origin Has Been Delayed to March]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/seven-deadly-sins-origin-delayed-march</link>
            <guid>1408186</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Developer and publisher Netmarble has announced a delay for <em>The Seven Deadly Sins: Origin</em>, which means you'll no longer be getting your hands on the free-to-play anime RPG in January.</p><p>As revealed in <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/3679080/view/490461848218371595" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">a post on Steam</a>, <em>The Seven Deadly Sins: Origin </em>will now be arriving in March. No more specific release date than that was given, though, so we still don't know exactly when you'll be able to play the game.</p><p>Netmarble says that the feedback it received during the game's recent beta period showed that more work was still needed on various key systems like UI, combat, and core controls, and so in order to deliver a more "polished experience", <em>The Seven Deadly Sins: Origin </em>will take another couple of months.</p><figure role="group">
<article>
  
      
  

  </article>

<figcaption><em>The Seven Deadly Sins: Origin </em>is going to take a little longer to arrive.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>If you want to know exactly what's changing with those extra couple of months, Netmarble has handily provided an <a href="https://7origin.netmarble.com/en/news/3/59" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">incredibly exhaustive rundown</a> of what the devs are doing to address user feedback.</p><p>The list includes refinements to various combat systems, improvements to the "convenience" of exploring <em>The Seven Deadly Sins: Origin</em>'s world, and lots of quality-of-life improvements and visual enhancements as well.</p><p>If you're not familiar with <em>The Seven Deadly Sins: Origin</em>, it is, as you've probably already surmised, an action RPG based on the popular <em>Seven Deadly Sins </em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/seven-deadly-sins-origin-is-open-world-take-on-anime" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="7c891282-93f2-45f2-b26d-54a896d4fd01" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">manga and anime series</a>.</p><p>The game, which will utilize gacha mechanics (because of course it will), casts you as Prince Tristan of Liones, who must embark on a journey through the land of Britannia to "restore order to a world thrown into chaos by the collision of time and space".</p>
<p>You'll be able to check out <em>The Seven Deadly Sins: Origin </em>when it launches sometime this March on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3679080/The_Seven_Deadly_Sins_Origin/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">PC</a>, <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-us/games/the-seven-deadly-sins-origin/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">PlayStation 5</a>, and mobile devices. Stay tuned for more on this, including a new release date, as soon as we get it.</p></div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/seven-deadly-sins-origin-delayed-march]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I love fantasy RPG Soulframe’s cosy start screen even though it could be a creepy piece of habit-forming design]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/i-love-fantasy-rpg-soulframes-cosy-start-screen-even-though-it-could-be-a-creepy-piece-of-habit-forming-design</link>
            <guid>1408183</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Soulframe-start-menu.png?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Soulframe-start-menu.png?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Soulframe-start-menu.png?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Soulframe-start-menu.png?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Soulframe-start-menu.png?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Soulframe-start-menu.png?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Soulframe-start-menu.png?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Soulframe-start-menu.png?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Soulframe-start-menu.png?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>YourStonedSavior / Digital Extremes</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
I continue to have a soft spot for <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/soulframe">Soulframe</a>, the new, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/you-can-now-buy-dark-fantasy-action-rpg-soulframe-rather-than-begging-for-a-code-and-it-has-a-steam-page">sort-of-early access</a> fantasy <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-rpgs">RPG</a> from <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/warframe">Warframe</a> developers Digital Extremes, despite the fact that the lore writing is often wyrd to the point of giving me a concussion. Especially when it creeps into studio press announcements. For example, here is a snippet from the developer’s <a href="https://forums.soulframe.com/topic/8378-farewell-to-2025-looking-ahead-to-2026/">summary of Soulframey doings</a> in the year 2025: “Together, we stepped into sap-dreams and freed Bromius from rotting roots. We Bestitched with a certain witch and crept into the crypts of The Circade.” ...Right then! I expect you shall be tending to your ravens next.
</p>
<p>
Still, don’t let that turn you off. There’s a lot of gentle craft beneath the plus-plus-ultra world-building. Soulframe is a game that often comes alive in the quieter moments. Take, for example, the login screen, which I’ve just realised could be a hidden creature collection game.
</p><!--more-->
<p>
When you login into Soulframe, you’re shown your character sleeping in the undergrowth like some questing knight fallen under the spell of a forest witch. Delicacies of sunlight and shadow play about your slumped shoulders and exquisite armour – a really lovely advertisement for the game’s costume design, which is as posh as you’d expect from the people who spent a decade making neat suits for Warframe. Beside you doze various woodland animals. Press a button to resume play, and your character will awaken and disturb the creatures, who disappear gracefully off-screen. 
</p>
<p>
It’s a sweet touch because it’s mildly perverse. Start playing the game, and you’ll ruin Bambi’s slumber time! It’s also reminiscent of what happens when you idle at the start menu when playing <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/shadow-of-the-colossus">Shadow of the Colossus</a>. The view cuts to Wander asleep with his back to the last shrine you saved at, then follows his horse Agro out on a tour of the landscape. There’s a simple point being made here about passivity and nonhuman animal agency, perhaps.
</p>

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Shadow of the Colossus (PS4, idle menu)" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rNo4kOCHSEQ?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Shadow of the Colossus (PS4, idle menu)</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rNo4kOCHSEQ?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/rNo4kOCHSEQ?autoplay=1" title="Shadow of the Colossus (PS4, idle menu)">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rNo4kOCHSEQ" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>


<p>
The twist with Soulframe is that, according to <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/SoulFrame/comments/1q9mnv5/is_there_a_way_to_increase_the_number_of_animal/">much fan speculation</a>, at least, the dozing animals are actually a login bonus. You’ll see more of them if you log in every day. I can offer limited corroboration of the expanding menagerie, based on <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/soulframe-has-the-bones-of-a-great-action-rpg-but-im-enjoying-it-partly-because-it-feels-too-late-to-enjoy-warframe">infrequent time with the Prelude builds</a>, but I haven’t had confirmation from Digital Extremes that it's actually a feature. In any case, I suspect it’s the kind of thing they’d rather leave mysterious.
</p><p>
In general, I dislike anything in a videogame that seems designed to kindle compulsive play. I find generic, Polly-wanna-cracker login bonuses both predatory and self-sabotaging. You decide to fire up a game, and the game immediately reminds you that it wants to monopolise your time – immersive! Fun! I much prefer stuff like the above, which at least doesn’t openly present itself as an engagement-farming machine. Even if that makes it a more effective engagement-farming machine.
</p>
</div>

      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/i-love-fantasy-rpg-soulframes-cosy-start-screen-even-though-it-could-be-a-creepy-piece-of-habit-forming-design]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why Do We Do This to Ourselves?]]></title>
            <link>https://remapradio.com/articles/why-do-we-do-this-to-ourselves/</link>
            <guid>1408180</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
			<div>
					
					
					

					<article>
	
	<div>
		<p>I was <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Double_Doink?ref=remapradio.com"><u>at the double doink</u></a>, a football event so infamous it has its own Wikipedia page. That moment stuck with me, sat on my fucking <em>chest</em>, for a week. Skunk-like, a stench that lingered. I let myself have hope, I let myself believe. And I was rewarded with a football paralysis demon. What a fool. What a dope. I lost sleep over that experience for days.</p><p>Who lets a football kick do that to them? </p><p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gz3Stx1N14Y&amp;ref=remapradio.com"><u>I was what I thought I was</u></a>. </p><p>A loser.&nbsp;A <em>Bears</em> fan.</p><p>Sports is irrational. You have no influence on the outcome. You can tell yourself you’re watching because you love incredible athletics—but it’s a lie. The team you root for was likely pre-determined by the region you grew up in. Like family, you have no say in the matter. Plenty of people are born into families they’d happily trade in for another. Sports is the same way. Ongoing devotion to a family, or a sports team, is often a mixture of faith and ironic detachment. &nbsp;</p><p>I do not remember when I started <em>caring</em> about the Bears, which is different than when I started <em>watching</em> the Bears, or being <em>around</em> the Bears. I was around the Bears young, due to my father’s career in sports equipment. I pulled up field goal nets before they outlawed it for strangers. I was smuggled into the Bears locker rooms inside empty laundry baskets. I have been, in some for another, watching the Bears my whole life. I hosted a party at my college apartment for their Super Bowl appearance in 2006. As a kid, I’d hang out with my dad while the games were on the TV. I’m <em>sure</em> I cheered when they scored. I think. Probably. But I can’t <em>remember</em>.&nbsp;</p><p>But when did I start to <em>care</em>?</p><figure><figcaption><span>The night of the doink. </span></figcaption></figure><p>There was no single moment, but there was a person: my wife. She was, from the moment I met her, a diehard. Even funnier, she was, like me, born in Wisconsin—born in Packers territory!—and converted. She made that choice when she was older. My birth in Wisconsin was a quirk of circumstance; my mom and dad were Illinois people. It was never a question what team we were invested in.</p><p>Every week, my wife wanted to watch the Bears. My dad watched the games, but he didn’t lose his mind the way she did. He wasn’t doing shots during touchdowns the way she was. He wasn’t ditching me for a bar down the street on a Sunday to watch the game.</p><p>She loved the Bears and I loved her. But to better understand her, I came to realize over time that I had to understand the Bears. </p><p>I downloaded podcasts. Started playing fantasy football. </p><p>Understanding became caring.</p><p>Caring creates belief. Belief makes shared ties of fate and emotion around a single desire: for the Chicago Bears to defy history, to defy expectation, to defy science. For the Chicago Bears to <em>win</em>.</p><p>My friend and I have a tradition with our youngest daughters where, when the Bears score a touchdown, we pick them up and swing them around. It always cracks me up when they wander over and ask “Why haven’t we been swing around today?” The answer is simple, of course: today, like most days, the Bears suck. Those same Chicago goddamn Bears especially sucked in the first half of their trilogy of matchups against the Green Bay Packers this season, punctuated by these two sweet young girls walking down the stairs when they realized the Bears had scored a field goal. Points! It’s time to be picked up and swung around by the Dads!</p>
		<div>
	<h2><svg role="img" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" height="1em" viewBox="0 0 448 512"><!--! Font Awesome Free 6.4.2 by @fontawesome - https://fontawesome.com License - https://fontawesome.com/license (Commercial License) Copyright 2023 Fonticons, Inc. --><path d="M144 144v48H304V144c0-44.2-35.8-80-80-80s-80 35.8-80 80zM80 192V144C80 64.5 144.5 0 224 0s144 64.5 144 144v48h16c35.3 0 64 28.7 64 64V448c0 35.3-28.7 64-64 64H64c-35.3 0-64-28.7-64-64V256c0-35.3 28.7-64 64-64H80z"></path></svg>  Library, Zeal or Foundation tier</h2>
	<p>Subscribe at  Library, Zeal or Foundation tier(s) or above to access "Why Do We Do This to Ourselves?". You'll also get access to the full back catalog of that tier's content.</p>
	<p><a href="https://remapradio.com/signup/">Sign up now</a>
	<small>Already have an account? <a href="https://remapradio.com/#/portal/signin/">Sign in</a></small>
</p></div>
	</div>
</article>

				</div>
			<div id="notifications">
	<p>You’ve successfully subscribed to Remap</p>
	<p>Welcome back! You’ve successfully signed in.</p>
	<p>Great! You’ve successfully signed up.</p>
	<p>Success! Your email is updated.</p>
	<p>Your link has expired</p>
	<p>Success! Check your email for magic link to sign-in.</p>
</div>
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://remapradio.com/articles/why-do-we-do-this-to-ourselves/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rust Exec Reacts To Amazon Killing New World: ‘Games Should Never Die’]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/new-world-mmo-servers-rust-facepunch-amazon-2000660558</link>
            <guid>1408174</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><em>New World</em> was once the crown jewel in Amazon’s rising gaming ambitions. Developed in-house, the MMO initially exploded in popularity on Steam and seemed to have decent legs in the notoriously competitive genre. Less than five years later, it’s officially being killed. Servers will go offline in January 2027. The news has prompted a reaction from many who are tired of big games vanishing so quickly after launch, including an executive at <em>Rust</em> maker Facepunch Studios.</p> <p><span>“25m, final offer Amazon Games,” the London-based company’s COO, Alistair McFarlane, wrote in response to the news <a href="https://x.com/Alistair_McF/status/2011890710468071708">on X</a>. “Games should never die,” he added, before going on to juxtapose Amazon’s approach to online games with Facepunch’s. “As with everything we do at Facepunch, empower the community.” when someone asked what the<em> Rust</em> maker buying <em>New World</em> would look like. “Give them control, make servers publicly hostable. A game will live forever in the hands of a dedicated community.”</span></p>

 <p>The writing for <em>New World</em> has been on the wall since last fall. Despite recently releasing new updates and seasonal content changes appearing to come and go as planned, Amazon <a href="https://kotaku.com/new-world-amazon-mmo-shutting-down-servers-2026-layoffs-new-content-2000639761">announced in late October</a> that the game would be going on life support with no meaningful additions planned in the future. The servers would remain open and operating “through 2026” to allow the community “<span>time to continue their adventures in Aeternum.”</span></p>

 <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">Games should never die.</p> <p>— Alistair McFarlane (@Alistair_McF) <a href="https://twitter.com/Alistair_McF/status/2011894052128768316?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 15, 2026</a></p></blockquote>  <p>While Amazon is technically holding up that end of the bargain, remaining fans probably weren’t expecting the tech giant to kick the new year off with a full-blown death sentence. “We want to thank the players for your dedication and passion. We are grateful for the time spent crafting the world of Aeternum with you,” an <a href="https://www.newworld.com/en-us/news/articles/the-future-of-new-world-aeternum-what-to-expect">unattributed blog post</a> that went up on the game’s website this week reads. “Together we built something special. While we are saddened to say goodbye, we’re honored that we were able to share so much with the community.”</p>

 <p><em>New World</em> is no longer for sale but anyone who already owns it can still re-download the game and play until January 31, 2027. Will there be any refunds? Of course not. Can you still buy premium in-game currency for real money? Strangely, yes. “Beginning July 20, 2026, players will no longer be able to purchase Marks of Fortune or anything else in game,” reads the new FAQ. Why not unlock everything and make all cash transactions in the game free? No idea.</p>

 <p>All of this stems from <a href="https://kotaku.com/amazon-layoffs-lord-rings-mmo-tomb-raider-2000639620">Amazon’s wider pivot</a> away from internal game development, with mass layoffs last fall that included not only the end of <em>New World</em> but seeming cuts to other projects including a <em>Lord of the Rings</em> MMO. The company hasn’t confirmed if that project is dead or still being shopped around to other outside development partners. Amazon is also set to publish the upcoming<em> Tomb Raider</em> games, including this year’s <em>Tomb Raider: Legacy of Atlantis</em>, a remake of the original game.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/new-world-mmo-servers-rust-facepunch-amazon-2000660558]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Lego Zelda Leaks, Depicting The Final Battle From Ocarina Of Time]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/lego-zelda-ocarina-of-time-ganon-battle-leak-2000660556</link>
            <guid>1408168</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p id="featured-image">
                              <figure id="attachment_featured" aria-describedby="featured-caption">
                                                                          <figcaption id="featured-caption">
                    <span>The box art for the new Lego Zelda set.</span> © Reddit / Kotaku
                  </figcaption>
                </figure>
                                                      </p><div>
              
              <p>Following on from 2024’s original Lego&nbsp;<em>Zelda</em> build, <a href="https://kotaku.com/nintendo-lego-legend-zelda-great-deku-tree-set-price-1851503670">the Great Deku Tree</a>, leaks have revealed the forthcoming follow-up, the <a href="https://kotaku.com/zelda-lego-ocarina-time-n64-ganon-price-date-2000642945">previously teased set</a> called The Final Battle: Ocarina of Time, due to release at the beginning of March.</p> <p>This repeats the pattern, given the original collab between Lego and Link leaked in 2023, and then was <a href="https://kotaku.com/lego-zelda-tears-of-the-kingdom-deku-youtube-copyright-1850136690">pretty much confirmed as real</a> by Nintendo rapidly firing off copyright takedown notices. It’ll be interesting to see if the Japanese giant attempts the same pointless endeavor this time with the leaked images, or whether the fact that the new set is seemingly due in less than a couple of months means it’ll have the sense to consider this the beginning of its promotional campaign.</p> <p>Posted to Reddit’s dedicated forum for such matters, /Legoleak, user BrickTap shared two images to that my eye look like they’re from a fairly clumsily put-together internal slideshow. The images reveal the build number, title, release date and pricing.</p>

   <p>So for $129.99 (considerably less than the Great Deku, which was $300), the 1003-piece set features the climactic battle of&nbsp;<em>Ocarina of Time</em>, with Link, Zelda and Ganondorf minifigs, as well as an enormous brick-built Ganon dual-wielding mighty swords. Also featured are a Triforce, Megaton Hammer, and even some recovery hearts should Link’s fight meet complications.</p>

 <p>The second image reveals a hidden secret in the first, what looks like a ruined piece of castle opening up to reveal minifig Ganondorf’s throne.</p> <p>I do think it looks a little paltry. Less than half the brick count (hence less than half the price) of the previous&nbsp;<em>Zelda</em> build, this really does seem to be primarily about constructing a large Ganon, with the rest of the scene being really rather underwhelming. It’s primarily a flat base with a couple of bits of broken castle poking out, and really seeming to lack in fun extra details or interesting terrain. I do like how Link is leaping, but the brown/gray dirge of the majority of the diorama seems a shame. Forgivable maybe at $60, but a hard sell at $130.</p> <p>If the details are correct, the set will go on sale March 1.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/lego-zelda-ocarina-of-time-ganon-battle-leak-2000660556]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Escape from Tarkov Devs Want Your Help Picking Collaborations]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/escape-from-tarkov-collaboration-devs-ask-for-help/</link>
            <guid>1408165</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>In a post on social media, Battlestate Games has asked for <strong>your help </strong>picking upcoming collaborations and crossovers with other projects. This isn’t a request that’s exclusive to <strong>games</strong>, as the team asked for opinions on ‘games <strong>or</strong> projects’ that could be a ‘great fit’ for Escape from Tarkov.</p>



<p>It was recently suggested that an Escape from Duckov collaboration might be incoming, which honestly writes itself. But there’s a whole world of brands out there that would make perfect sense for an Escape from Tarkov collaboration.</p>







<h2 id="h-what-brands-do-you-want-in-escape-from-tarkov">What Brands Do You Want in Escape from Tarkov?</h2>



<p>Nikita Buyanov, the head of the studio at Battlestate Games, posted a message <a href="https://x.com/nikgeneburn/status/2012116918694752296" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">on social media</a> asking fans for help:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>recently the team and I have been discussing potential collaborations with other projects, and I’d love to hear your thoughts. What game or project do you think would be a great fit for EFT for a collab with?</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Escape from Tarkov, the pioneering extraction shooter that has been evolving for a decade, has typically steered clear of the typical collaboration topics that live-service games so regularly explore. It’s not a game known for skin packs, crossover bundles, or LTMs, which is something fans have been appreciative of over the years.</p>



<p>However, that looks set to change now that Escape from Tarkov is a ‘1.0’ title and is exploring more ways to monetize and expand.</p>



<p>Days ago, it was suggested by Team Soda and Bilibili that an <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/escape-from-duckov-tarkov-collaboration-coming/">Escape from Duckov x Escape from Tarkov crossover</a> is on the horizon. This would make brilliant sense, as both games are extraction shooters that mirror each other closely, but what other brands could surface or enter the space?</p>



<p>Fans were quick to make suggestions on social media under Buyanov’s post.</p>



<p>One suggested more alignment with similar games, like ARC Raiders and Gray Zone Warfare. Another suggested STALKER makes sense, but there might be something political preventing Russian and Ukrainian developers from joining forces.</p>



<p>In one comment, a user poked fun at Escape from Tarkov’s more prolific problems, writing: ‘Collab with Riot Games and add Vanguard anti-cheat.’</p>



<p>It’s unlikely we’ll see Escape from Tarkov become the next Fortnite when it comes to collaborations, but it’s cool to imagine the potential.</p>







<p>What crossover would you like to see hit the Escape from Tarkov universe? Let us know what you’re thinking on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/resident-evil-5-voice-actor-hints-at-possible-30th-anniversary-announcement/">a big Resident Evil announcement might be coming soon</a></p>


        <div>
                  <p>
                    Grant's passion for gaming started on the Amstrad CPC when he wasn't even old enough to walk properly. Now, he's a multi-platform expert gamer with an undying love for the…                  </p>
                  <p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/author/grant-taylor-hill/">
                    More from Grant Taylor-Hill                  </a>
                </p></div>
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/escape-from-tarkov-collaboration-devs-ask-for-help/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon Has Some Brilliant Deals on Magic Booster Boxes Today, Including the Excellent Edge of Eternities Set]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/magic-the-gathering-amazon-sale-including-edge-of-eternities-avatar-spider-man-and-more</link>
            <guid>1408162</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle" data-autopogo="true"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/magic-the-gathering-trading-card-game"><u>Magic: The Gathering</u></a> is set to have another <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/magic-the-gathering-full-release-schedule-updated-2026">big year in 2026</a>, but there's no harm in looking back at the best of 2025 as well right now, especially with the latest discounts available on booster boxes and more. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">My favorite deal in Amazon's latest MTG sale is on the <a href="https://zdcs.link/aA8leb?object_uuid=909374ef-0098-4816-a3af-1eaaf3327728&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Edge of Eternities Booster Box</a>, featuring 30 packs, which has dropped to just $139.99 today. That's just $1 off its best price ever ($139.98), and a brilliant offer to kick off the year with.</p><div id="226402"><div><p><span data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><div id="226402" data-cy="solo-product-card"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Edge of Eternities - Play Booster Box (30 Packs)</h3></p></div></span></p></div><h2 data-cy="title2">Amazon Has Big Discounts on Magic: The Gathering Today</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">However, that's not all. You can also find some of the most recent 2025 Universes Beyond sets, like Avatar: The Last Airbender, and Marvel's Spider-Man, at low, low prices right now as well. That includes Spidey's Play Booster Box, which is available for just over $110. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">That's a pretty big discount compared to the almost $210 asking price back when preorders kicked off last year, just about $100, in fact. Avatar only came out in November, and you can already pick up its Play Boosters for even less than Edge of Eternities, and now just $134.99 at Amazon.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">You can also score the Collectors versions of these Universes Beyond sets as well, both of which have seen tidy price drops since last year, and are your best bet of finding the rarest cards from each set.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://zdcs.link/9l3ejx?object_uuid=909374ef-0098-4816-a3af-1eaaf3327728&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Play Boosters</a> are now the standard way to crack open Magic packs, having replaced both Set and Draft Boosters. But if you're on the hunt for rare cards, <a href="https://zdcs.link/Qp7A2Y?object_uuid=909374ef-0098-4816-a3af-1eaaf3327728&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Collector Boosters</a> are the best option.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">These packs are more expensive, but are much more likely to include various foil treatments, extended arts, and all sorts. There are usually 5 Commons, 4 Uncommons, 5 Rare or Mythic Rare cards, a Land and a Token, but the rub here is that 6 of the included cards have a 'booster Fun frame' and 12-13 of them are foil.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In terms of 2026 sets, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/magic-the-gathering-trading-card-game"><u>Magic's</u></a> highly anticipated <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/magic-the-gathering-lorwyn-eclipsed-where-to-buy-2026"><u>Lorwyn Eclipsed set</u></a> is getting closer as well, but we can already expect another trip to New York not long after in March. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">On that note, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/amazon-just-discounted-magics-teenage-mutant-ninja-turtles-set-to-its-lowest-price-ever">Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles Booster Box preorders</a> are also discounted right now at Amazon (out March 23), down to the lowest price so far at $148.20 (and down from $209.70).</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In other TCG news, there are also some great deals on Pokémon cards right now at Amazon and TCGplayer, including a great deal on the most recent expansion's ETB, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-mega-evolution-phantasmal-flames-elite-trainer-box">Mega Evolution - Phantasmal Flames</a>. It's down to its lowest price ever at Amazon after its market price took a mighty tumble over the New Year, dropping almost 50% in a matter of weeks.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Unsurprisingly, stock is still running low on Amazon for a lot of Pokémon cards, even from last year, and even upcoming MTG sets like Lorwyn and TMNT. That said, sites like <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/magic-the-gathering-edge-of-eternities-where-to-buy">TCGplayer</a> still have a solid supply, and in some cases, better prices too, so are definitely worth checking out while on your hunt for cheap boosters.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Robert Anderson is Senior Commerce Editor and IGN's resident deals expert on games, collectibles, trading card games, and more. You can follow him <a href="https://x.com/robertliam21" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@robertliam21</a> on Twitter/X or <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/robertliam21.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Bluesky</a>.</p></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Jan 16, 2026 11:57 am</p></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/magic-the-gathering-amazon-sale-including-edge-of-eternities-avatar-spider-man-and-more]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Code Vein II character trailer – Zenon Gryfgote]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/01/code-vein-ii-character-trailer-zenon-gryfgote</link>
            <guid>1408159</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>The scientist who conquered the sun,</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Bandai Namco Entertainment [6,823 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/bandai-namco-entertainment">Bandai Namco</a> has released a new trailer for <em><a title="Games > Code Vein II [12 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/code-vein-ii">Code Vein II</a></em> introducing character Zenon Gryfgote. <span id="more-1019791"></span></p><p>Valentin Voda is “unbridled intellectual curiosity,” “a man of extraordinary talent,” and “the scientist who conquered the sun.” His quote reads, “Never fear… I’ll forge your potential into hope. Put your best foot forward and don’t give into despair.”</p><p><em>Code Vein II</em> is due out for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [11,201 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [8,573 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [25,272 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2362060/CODE_VEIN_II/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> on January 30, 2026.</p><p>Watch the trailer below.</p><h2><span>Character Trailer: Zenon Gryfgote</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><iframe title="CODE VEIN II – Zenon Gryfgote Character Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/375gRvPc1ak?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe title="『CODE VEIN II』ゼノン・グリフゴート（CV:子安武人）|キャラクタートレーラー" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wgLH0icOt-4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/01/code-vein-ii-character-trailer-zenon-gryfgote]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Arknights Endfield passes 35m pre-registered players ahead of launch this month]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/arknights-endfield-passes-35m-pre-registered-players-ahead-of-launch-this-month</link>
            <guid>1408153</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>

  <figure>
      <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arknights-endfield-key-art-jpg.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arknights-endfield-key-art-jpg.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arknights-endfield-key-art-jpg.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arknights-endfield-key-art-jpg.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arknights-endfield-key-art-jpg.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arknights-endfield-key-art-jpg.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arknights-endfield-key-art-jpg.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arknights-endfield-key-art-jpg.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arknights-endfield-key-art-jpg.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Hypergryph</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Arknights Endfield has surpassed 35,000,000 pre-registered players ahead of its release on the 22nd January.</p>
<p>This news comes alongside a new launch trailer for the game, which can be viewed below. These 35 pre-registered players not only get to sign up for the game early, but have collectively earned a series of milestone-based rewards for the playerbase once the game releases.</p>
<p>These include in-game credits, a free five-star operator, and some gacha currency used to pull for in-game characters. The pre-launch community for Arknights Endfield also managed to pass a social media milestone previously, which means a five star weapon and additional gacha currency.</p>

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Arknights: Endfield Official Release Trailer: Back to Endfield" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/oJ00ggFb8A0?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Arknights: Endfield Official Release Trailer: Back to Endfield</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/oJ00ggFb8A0?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/oJ00ggFb8A0?autoplay=1" title="Arknights: Endfield Official Release Trailer: Back to Endfield">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>You can watch the new Arknights Endfield trailer here!<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oJ00ggFb8A0" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>


<p>Arknights Endfield, for those who don't know, is a blend between a squad-based action RPG and a base/factory management system. You collect and enhance a gaggle of distinct characters to use in combat scenarios, while in the background you build and expand a growing hub of facilities to aid you as the game progresses. Think, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/genshin-impact">Genshin Impact</a> meets Factorio for an over-generalised idea of what's on offer here.</p><p>It's been in development for a good while, being a spinoff from Hypergryph's 2019 game Arknights. Having first released a trailer for the game back in 2022, the game has been steadily gaining a wave of intrigued players thanks to ongoing beta tests and drip-fed trailers. The result of which being that staggering number of pre-registered players.</p>
<p>Is Arknights Endfield your cup of tea? Let us what you think below!</p>

        </div>

  
      </article>



  



  

  <section>
    <span>Related topics</span>

    
  </section>
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/arknights-endfield-passes-35m-pre-registered-players-ahead-of-launch-this-month]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ubisoft claims Assassin's Creed: Black Flag music reuploads were due to "technical issues", and nothing more...]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/ubisoft-claims-assassins-creed-blag-flag-music-reuploads-were-due-to-technical-issues-and-nothing-more</link>
            <guid>1408150</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>Arrr you sure about that?</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
      <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Screenshot-from-Assassin's-Creed-Black-Flag-showing-a-pirate-with-a-feather-adorned-hat.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Screenshot-from-Assassin's-Creed-Black-Flag-showing-a-pirate-with-a-feather-adorned-hat.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Screenshot-from-Assassin's-Creed-Black-Flag-showing-a-pirate-with-a-feather-adorned-hat.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Screenshot-from-Assassin's-Creed-Black-Flag-showing-a-pirate-with-a-feather-adorned-hat.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Screenshot-from-Assassin's-Creed-Black-Flag-showing-a-pirate-with-a-feather-adorned-hat.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Screenshot-from-Assassin's-Creed-Black-Flag-showing-a-pirate-with-a-feather-adorned-hat.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Screenshot-from-Assassin's-Creed-Black-Flag-showing-a-pirate-with-a-feather-adorned-hat.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Screenshot-from-Assassin's-Creed-Black-Flag-showing-a-pirate-with-a-feather-adorned-hat.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Screenshot-from-Assassin's-Creed-Black-Flag-showing-a-pirate-with-a-feather-adorned-hat.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Ubisoft</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>That music which was reuploaded for Assassin's Creed: Black Flag was apparently just due to "technical issues", so stop reading too much into it, ok.</p>
<p>Earlier this week, Ubisoft set tongues wagging when it <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/assassins-creed-black-flag-remake-music-upload">reuploaded a sizable selection of sea shanties from Assassin's Creed 4: Black Flag</a> over on its YouTube music channel. Many assumed this was all because a remake of the studio's piratical Assassin's Creed adventure is on the cards.</p>
<!-- code from Primis - Eurogamer.net - eurogamer.net -->
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<!-- code from Primis -->
<p>However, apparently an impending Black Flag remake - which these days feels like the world's worst kept shared secret - has absolutely nothing to do with it, or so Ubisoft claims. Rather, the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/post/Ugkx_qiROkA8vcnQk_a-1BH_gW4gTLnDetS0">studio has cited</a> "technical issues" as the reason for the shanties' sudden appearance on YouTube.</p>
<p>Here's Ubisoft's full statement: "Hi there music lovers! We encountered some technical issues with a few of our videos, which we had to reupload. Apologies for the trouble, and hope you enjoy the music."</p>
<p>Needless to say, though, many are unconvinced with the company's response. "Technical issues in the Animas that calls for a resync in Assassin's Creed Black Flag," reads one reply, while another adds: "yeah suuuuuuure." Another user is quite blunt, and has called this reasoning by Ubisoft "b******t".</p>
<figure>
 


<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>YouTube/Eurogamer</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Now, like I have said, we are all basically just waiting for Ubisoft to confirm that yes, Black Flag is getting a remake. We all are 99.9 percent sure it is happening. Back in August of last year, voice actor Matt Ryan - who portrayed Edward Kenway in Assassin's Creed: Black Flag - <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/assassins-creed-black-flag-actor-threatened-with-legal-action-following-remake-slip-up">claimed legal action was brought against him by Ubisoft</a> after cheekily hinting at its existence at a convention.</p>
<p>Then, just a couple of months ago in November, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/long-rumoured-assassins-creed-black-flag-remake-could-set-sail-before-april">the company's financial reports stated an unannounced title was due to be released during the fourth quarter of this financial year</a>. That would be before April.</p>
<p>And, if <em>all that </em>wasn't enough to convince you this remake is real, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/assassins-creed-black-flag-remake-spotted-again-ahead-of-the-game-awards">a PEGI listing for Black Flag Resynced was spotted</a> in December. It really does seem to be a case of when, not if this remake is coming. But that music was <em>definitely </em>about technical issues…</p>

        </div>

  
      </article>



  



  

  <section>
    <span>Related topics</span>

    
  </section>
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/ubisoft-claims-assassins-creed-blag-flag-music-reuploads-were-due-to-technical-issues-and-nothing-more]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Roborock’s Wet-Dry Vac Is 40% Off, Now Selling Close to Cost as It Launches on Amazon]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/roborocks-wet-dry-vac-is-40-off-now-selling-close-to-cost-as-it-launches-on-amazon-2000660299</link>
            <guid>1408126</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Tackling a true deep-cleaning day with just an upright vacuum is going into battle woefully outgunned. Even if it gets the surface stuff out of your carpets and most of the really big crumbs and dust bunnies off of your hard-surfaced floors, you’re probably left staring at stubborn dried food stains on the hardwood and enough pet hair still in the carpets to make a life-sized model of your pet.</p>
<p>Your first look at the Roborock F25 Ultra might have you thinking it’s just a somewhat-larger stick vacuum, and not much of an improvement over what you have now. Look again – the F25 Ultra is a wet-dry vacuum cleaner and high-temperature steam mop that is, quite plainly, one of the very best floor cleaning machines we’ve seen. It’s also carrying over its big sale price from the holidays – <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6761/">right now at Amazon the Roborock F25 Ultra is 38% off, dropping its price from $799 to $499</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6761/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>No Mess Too Tough</h2>
<p>It’s hard to tell which is the biggest selling point for the F25 Ultra — its vacuuming performance with a mighty 22,000Pa of suction and 33 Newtons of downward pressure, its ability to deep-clean hard-surfaced floors with 187° Fahrenheit hot water and 356°F steam to destroy both stubborn stains and bacteria, its cutting-edge AI enhancements, or the fact that it cleans itself quickly and thoroughly without human intervention.</p>
<p>We’ll just call it a draw among all of them, and add in the fact that the F25 Ultra works its substantial cleaning magic in a single pass. You can work your standard vacuum and an old-school mop back and forth until you break a sweat and not come anywhere close to the cleaning result of one pass of the Roborock F25 Ultra. And the F25 Ultra doesn’t clean debris so much as it actively hunts it — rather than the standard headlight that most vacuums have, the F25 Ultra uses a powerful blue LED light to reveal even tiny particles in dark places that you would otherwise miss, and it can be folded down by a full 180 degrees to lie perfectly flat, and be driven by the Roborock app to run beneath furniture without causing you to get down on your hands and knees.</p>



<h2>Smart Automatic Adjustments</h2>
<p>Roborock’s DirTect technology enables the F25 Ultra to monitor the dirt levels it encounters and adjust accordingly, so the really stubborn stuff gets the full power of the machine, while lighter tasks get a lighter touch to help extend the already significant life of the rechargeable battery — up to 60 minutes of runtime with a full charge.</p>
<p>When it’s time for the Roborock F25 Ultra to go back to its charging station, it gives itself a very thorough cleaning. That same ultra-hot steam is used to clean the mop roller and destroy bacteria, along with 194°F hot water. A quick bath and recharge later, the F25 Ultra is ready for the next mess, no matter how big or gross.</p>
<p>Your deep-cleaning chore day becomes far easier and far more effective when you upgrade to the Roborock F25 Ultra and turn it loose on every flooring surface in your home. Amazon’s practically begging you to make the switch from your standard vacuum and mop to the F25 Ultra, with a $300 discount that’s still running right now.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6761/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/roborocks-wet-dry-vac-is-40-off-now-selling-close-to-cost-as-it-launches-on-amazon-2000660299]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Resident Evil 5 Voice Actor Hints at Possible 30th Anniversary Announcement]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/resident-evil-5-voice-actor-hints-at-possible-30th-anniversary-announcement/</link>
            <guid>1408123</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Resident Evil 5’s voice actor is teasing a new announcement coming this March, during the franchise’s 30th Anniversary. </p>



<p>Capcom’s next big title, Resident Evil Requiem, arrives next month on February 27, 2026. The developers just provided us with another trailer, showcasing <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/resident-evil-requiem-showcase-reveals-new-leon-gameplay/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Leon Kennedy’s gameplay</a> in the process. However, after this title, what’s next for the franchise might be revealed during the 30th Anniversary event in March. </p>







<h2 id="h-resident-evil-5-s-sheva-alomar-teasing-something-for-march-2026">Resident Evil 5’s Sheva Alomar Teasing Something for March 2026</h2>



<p>Spotted on r/<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GamingLeaksAndRumours/comments/1qdt1yu/eva_la_dare_va_from_sheva_alomar_re5_is_teasing/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">GamingLeaksAndRumours</a>, the voice actor for Karen Dyer from Resident Evil 5, Sheva Alomar, has posted a cryptic video on their official <a href="https://x.com/KarenShevaEva/status/2011868483194392926" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">X</a> account (formerly Twitter). The video’s caption states that “got a few fun things lined up for March. Stay Tuned!. Additionally, the video itself has another caption that reads “When you know something, but can’t share it with the world…yet.” </p>



<figure></figure>



<p>Fans from the community have already started making all kinds of speculation from this post, with many hoping that this could be a tease for a possible Resident Evil 5 Remake. At the same time, there are also speculations that Alomar will star in another Resident Evil movie, with Resident Evil: Death Island’s writer, Makoto Fukami, mentioning in a 2023 <a href="https://www.fangoria.com/resident-evil-death-island-writer-would-love-to-take-the-carnage-to-antarctica/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Fangoria</a> interview that he would “love to bring back characters like Barry Burton or Sheva Alomar.” </p>



<p>Additionally, there was <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/resident-evil-5-remake-not-in-development-its-claimed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a claim</a> from last year that stated Resident Evil 5 Remake was not in development. Whatever this announcement is, players will have to wait until Resident Evil’s 30th Anniversary to know for sure, and all players are hoping that more games are announced this year. </p>







<p>In other news, PlayStation was recently seen promoting a strange Resident Evil rip-off, ‘<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/playstation-promote-resident-evil-rip-off-ebola-village/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ebola Village</a>‘. Additionally, Requiem’s director has stated that the upcoming title is “<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/resident-evil-requiem-is-almost-like-having-two-games-says-director/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">almost like having two games</a>“. What do you think Resident Evil 5’s voice actor is teasing for this March? Leave your thoughts down in the comments, and join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hytale-is-adding-dinosaurs-mining-sound-changes-and-more/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Hytale adding dinosaurs, changes to mining sounds, and more in the next patch</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/resident-evil-5-voice-actor-hints-at-possible-30th-anniversary-announcement/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Arknights: Endfield tops 35 million pre-registrations; new trailers]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/01/arknights-endfield-tops-35-million-pre-registrations-new-trailers</link>
            <guid>1408120</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Free-to-play 3D RPG due out on January 22.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Genres > Free-to-Play [501 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/free-to-play">Free-to-play</a> 3D <a title="Genres > RPG [17,948 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg">RPG</a> <em><a title="Games > Arknights: Endfield [12 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/arknights-endfield">Arknights: Endfield</a></em> has surpassed 35 million pre-registrations, publisher <a title="Companies > GRYPHLINE [23 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/hypergryph-network-technology/gryph-frontier/gryphline">GRYPHLINE</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Mountain Contour [12 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/hypergryph-network-technology/mountain-contour">Mountain Contour</a> announced. The official launch trailer, a new Operator story trailer, and a new gameplay trailer were also released. <span id="more-1019598"></span></p><p>The launch trailer features cinematic animations set against the original song “We Are Empire” by rock band STARSET, while the “New Horizons” gameplay trailer highlights the game’s vast industrial landscapes, specialized operators, and unfolding mystery.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via GRYPHLINE:</p><blockquote><p><em>Arknights: Endfield</em> is the latest entry set in the popular <em>Arknights</em> universe, and has already garnered more than 35 million pre-registrations worldwide. To celebrate the milestone, all community rewards and special gifts revealed during the livestream will be available for players to claim starting on launch day.</p><p><em>Arknights: Endfield</em> introduces a new frontier storyline and a world built around exploration, strategic real-time combat, and base-building. Players command squads of up to four Operators, combining skills, elemental synergies, and coordinated tactics across fast-paced encounters. The story follows the Endministrator (Endmin)—a legendary guardian awakened from a ten-year hibernation to lead Endfield Industries from their orbital headquarters, the OMV Dijiang.</p></blockquote><div id="carousel_1019600"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div><!-- AD: content -->
        <blockquote><p>On Talos-II, players harness the Automated Industrial Complex (AIC), a system used to architect integrated production networks and power grids across the wilderness. As the Endmin, players must manage these facilities while defending the Civilization Band from organized raider clans and investigate the origins of their self-commissioned “Zeroth Directive”. </p><p><em>Arknights: Endfield</em> leverages the latest graphical technologies, including native 120 frames per second support, realistic snow-stepping, environmental puddle reflections, and more. Players can also toggle NVIDIA DLSS Super Resolution and Frame Generation independently. The title includes plug-and-play support for both PlayStation (DualSense and DualShock) and Xbox controllers with haptic feedback for a premium, tactile experience.</p></blockquote><p><em>Arknights: Endfield</em> is due out for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [11,201 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > PC [25,272 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via the official launcher and <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/p/arknightsendfield-f0f167" target="_blank">Epic Games Store</a>, iOS via <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/arknights-endfield/id6752642477" target="_blank">App Store</a>, and Android via <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.gryphline.endfield.gp" target="_blank">Google Play</a> on January 22.</p><p>Watch the trailers and an archive of today’s launch live stream below. View a new set of screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/arknights-endfield/january-16-2026/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>Launch Trailer: Back to Endfield</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><p><iframe title="Arknights: Endfield Official Release Trailer: Back to Endfield" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/oJ00ggFb8A0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe title="『アークナイツ：エンドフィールド』正式リリースPV：Back to Endfield" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/EGZpPrCd7iI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Korean</strong></p><p><iframe title="「명일방주: 엔드필드」 정식 출시 PV - Back to Endfield" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/qZijew4BVvs?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Traditional Chinese</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="《明日方舟：終末地》公測PV：Back to Endfield" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Vof0M3X34EY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><span>Operator Story: “The Five: Sparks that Shatter the Darkness”</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Arknights: Endfield Operator Story [The Five: Sparks that Shatter the Darkness]" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/UPpeeft1-8o?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="『アークナイツ：エンドフィールド』オペレーターファイル [群像：暗闇に灯る炎]" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_69N6wbEZkU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Korean</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="「명일방주: 엔드필드」 오퍼레이터 스토리 [군상: 어둠 속에 피어난 불씨]" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Y-doiIMTO1E?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Traditional Chinese</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="《明日方舟：終末地》幹員敘事 「群像：暗夜星火」" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_WfnTjgIigw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><span>New Horizons Trailer: The Mission</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Arknights: Endfield New Horizons Trailer [The Mission]" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/tN80M6IEMo0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="『アークナイツ：エンドフィールド』旅立ちPV「使命」" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/WyeCPKCe3vg?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Korean</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="「명일방주: 엔드필드」 여정의 시작 PV 「사명」" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NeNZRhphoHY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Traditional Chinese</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="《明日方舟：終末地》啟程PV「使命」" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/xckBGk28ueM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><span>Official Release Special Program</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Arknights: Endfield Official Release Special Program" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/dz2g_D52NR0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="『アークナイツ：エンドフィールド』リリース予告特別番組" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/RoxNYCzJep8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Korean</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="「명일방주: 엔드필드」 정식 출시 미리보기 특별 방송" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/a2NirKiYTzg?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Traditional Chinese</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="《明日方舟：終末地》公測前瞻特別節目" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Db-bDoIe-xY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/01/arknights-endfield-tops-35-million-pre-registrations-new-trailers]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Greatness Of Earthbound Reminded Me Why I Never Want To Conquer My Backlog]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/earthbound-backlog-nintendo-switch-online-finishing-games-2000659900</link>
            <guid>1408108</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><span>In the middle of 2025, I decided to take a step back from the grind of playing the latest releases and carve out time for something I’d wanted to get around to for years: </span><a href="https://intothespine.com/2025/12/31/stories-of-2025/"><i><span>Earthbound</span></i></a><span>. I had just gotten my </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/nintendo-switch-2-review-metroid-prime-4-pokemon-2000656188"><span>Switch 2</span></a><span> and<!--StartFragment --><span>—</span><!--EndFragment -->knowing I would enjoy a lengthy honeymoon phase in which my brand new console would be all I’d want to play<!--StartFragment --><span>—</span><!--EndFragment -->decided to boot up the legendary SNES role-playing game thanks to </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/tag/nintendo-switch-online"><span>Nintendo Switch Online</span></a><span>. And I’m so glad I did, because playing </span><i><span>Earthbound </span></i><span>for the first time was one of the most joyful experiences of 2025! There are likely dozens more surprises like it waiting for me in my constantly growing backlog.</span></p> <p><span>Unlike a lot of other folks, I’m really content with the restless state of my backlog. I relish the fact, for example, that I will never entirely conquer it. How, for every two games I triumphantly finish, three more will appear in the blink of an eye. Like a boss battle or random encounter that you’re meant to lose, I eventually gave up on the notion of quashing my backlog, and I think I’m much happier as a result.</span></p>

 <p><span>Games are wonderful things. Unlike many other mediums, they drop you into the world and perspective of their characters. They are these utterly dazzling and transportive experiences, and can range from space operas to </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/red-dead-redemption-2-the-kotaku-review-1829984369"><span>melancholic westerns</span></a><span> and everything in between. I can be a squid-kid and compete in the equivalent of professional paintballing or venture through the harrowing nightmares of a </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/bloodborne-fromsoftware-rpg-goty-ps5-the-doll-1849659930"><span>gothic town descended into madness</span></a><span>. And if all else fails, I can be some plumber who has somehow found the bandwidth to do it all and then some.</span></p>

 <p><span>I love how varied and surprising exploring these virtual worlds can be. I love booting a game up and disappearing into it. I love the way I get to embody a character in games, especially in the ones that let me sculpt my own. Why would I rush that? Why should any of us try to zoom to the end of these experiences? Shouldn’t we collectively stop and take in the vistas and skyboxes of these immaculately constructed fictions? Plumb every last cave and jump behind every proverbial (or literal) waterfall in search of treasure and adventure? I want to make the most of my time with video games, not min-max it.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <figure id="attachment_2000659915" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000659915"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000659915">©Nintendo</figcaption></figure> <p><span>My backlog is lined with games that hold these promises and so much more. I mentioned space operas because–and this always shocks folks–I’ve never played the entire </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/mass-effect-5-n7-day-bioware-blog-teaser-url-krogan-2000642122"><i><span>Mass Effect</span></i></a><span> trilogy. I missed the first game on account of its exclusivity back in the day, and only hopped onboard the bandwagon with the second entry. One day, I hope to experience the first title, and I’m sure that’ll send me down a path that’ll see me revisit the entirety of the trilogy. I cannot wait to embark on that tremendous adventure with fresh eyes and a new appreciation for the entirety of that cast’s arcs. I’m also in no rush to see that day.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <p><span>Likewise, I’ve yet to finish </span><i><span>Baldur’s Gate 3</span></i><span>, and I’m in no rush to see it to its end, either. I’ve never played </span><i><span>Demon’s Souls</span></i><span> or the latter two </span><i><span>Dark Souls</span></i><span> games to completion. Early </span><i><span>Final Fantasy</span></i><span> games and basically any RPG that launched before the year 1997 are a blind spot for me. Foundational titles of PC gaming, like the </span><i><span>Half-Life</span></i><span> series and </span><i><span>Myst</span></i><span>, still elude me, and I never really “got” </span><i><span>The Sims</span></i><span> despite all the hype around it.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <p><span>I hope to get around to these games and so many more. I’ve also got a lifetime to get to ’em. Why spoil the fun by imposing challenges on myself to see as much of them as quickly or efficiently as possible? Why spoil the magic rather than live comfortably alongside it for as long as I can? What is the actual material harm of letting a backlog grow? As far as I can tell, none. On the flip side though, voraciously consuming any and every game that has ever made some kind of impression on me just sounds miserable. It minimizes what can otherwise be life-affirming, or even life-changing, experiences with art. It also just spoils the potential fun of a lifetime of games.</span></p>

 <p><span>So take this as a PSA, if you must. Slow down. Savor your video game backlog. Preserve its magic for as long as you can. Oh, and play </span><i><span>Earthbound</span></i><span>, if you haven’t. You’ll thank me later.</span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/earthbound-backlog-nintendo-switch-online-finishing-games-2000659900]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ubisoft’s Avatar Game Is So Much Better Than Fire And Ash]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/ubisofts-avatar-game-is-so-much-better-than-fire-and-ash-2000659445</link>
            <guid>1408105</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>I consider myself a pretty big <em>Avatar</em> sicko. I can name multiple characters from the franchise. I’ve read some of the comics and played the games. I enjoyed 2009’s <em>Avatar</em> when I saw it in a big theater all those years ago. I liked 2022’s <em>Way of Water</em> even more! And yet, I<a href="https://kotaku.com/avatar-3-fire-and-ash-reviews-rotten-tomatoes-score-spongebob-squarepants-2000654602"> walked out of <em>Avatar: Fire and Ash</em> in December 2025</a> supremely disappointed. So, in a desperate attempt to feel something good about <em>Avatar</em>, I booted up Ubisoft’s 2023 open-world <em>Avatar</em> game, <em>Frontiers of Pandora</em>, and gave it another shot, and you know what, it’s so much better than <em>Fire and Ash.&nbsp;</em></p> <p><a href="https://kotaku.com/avatar-frontiers-of-pandora-impressions-review-ubisoft-1851077773">I played <em>Frontiers of Pandora</em> back when it first launched on consoles and PC around a year after <em>Way of Water</em></a>. At the time, I found the game’s narrative to be threadbare and its gorgeous jungle landscape mostly devoid of stuff to do, so after I wrote about it for the site, I mostly set the game aside. Fast forward to a late night in December 2025, feeling down about how much I didn’t like <em>Fire and Ash</em>, and I decided to return to Pandora using Ubisoft’s game.</p>

 <p>Okay, the truth is that I didn’t just return in the hopes that the game would make me feel good about <em>Avatar</em> again. I was also curious to check out <a href="https://kotaku.com/avatar-frontiers-pandora-cheap-third-person-new-game-1851786644">the big free update for the game</a> that Ubisoft released last month that added a third-person mode, alongside a new paid expansion featuring a new area. I’ve yet to play the new expansion, which stars a character from the main game fighting back against the evil RDA and their Navi allies from the Ash clan. I’ve been too busy getting lost in the world of <em>Frontiers of Pandora.</em></p>

  <h2>Pushing through <em>Frontiers of Pandora</em>‘s bad opening section</h2> <p>The first 10 hours or so of <em>Frontiers of Pandora</em> are bad. You’re stuck in one location, the quests are forgettable, and for a good chunk of that time, you don’t even have access to your Ikran, a flying dragon-like mount. Bleh! Boo! Bad. But, after pushing through it over the last few weeks, I’ve discovered there’s so much to like about <em>Frontiers of Pandora</em> once you’re past that crappy start.</p>

 <p>The biggest discovery was that beyond the jungle biome found at the start, <em>Frontiers of Pandora</em>‘s other biomes are vast and varied. One of my biggest gripes with <a href="https://kotaku.com/avatar-3-fire-and-ash-trailer-fire-clan-james-cameron-1851787146"><em>Fire and Ash</em></a> was that it felt like <em>The </em><em>Way of Water Part 2</em> and didn’t offer many new places to gawk at. <em>FoP</em> doesn’t have that problem. The vast plains you enter later in the game are incredible. Super long draw distances and massive alien trees bent over by the unrelenting wind offer up totally different vibes compared to the jungle biome of the game’s earlier section.</p>

 <figure id="attachment_2000659865" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000659865"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000659865">©Ubisoft</figcaption></figure> <p>And then, hours later, and after some quests that actually address the complicated relationship between the Navi and their human allies that make up the resistance, I visited a new biome. It is covered in mist and feels like an alien version of the forests found in the Pacific Northwest. Even hunting in this biome feels different, with strange swarms of bugs ready to descend on every carcass if you let it sit around too long without harvesting. I also found a scared and withdrawn Navi clan of former healers that is the most interesting in the game.</p>

 <p>And unlike the Ash clan featured in the latest film, they aren’t just evil warmongers, but instead are complicated beings trying to remember their place in the world while afraid of what happens if they return.</p> <p>I’m reaching the end of <em>Frontiers of Pandora,</em> and I’m not sad at all. I’m actually excited as I have two past DLCs to dive into, each adding new regions, and then I have the recently released <em>From the Ashes</em> standalone expansion to play after all that. And if all of that content can be even half as cool as what I’ve discovered on my return to Pandora, I’ll be more than satisfied that I came back to this game that had remained buried on my backlog.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/ubisofts-avatar-game-is-so-much-better-than-fire-and-ash-2000659445]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marvel Rivals Season 6 Battle Pass—Price, Rewards, & Is It Worth It?]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-season-6-battle-pass-price-rewards/</link>
            <guid>1408102</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>A new season has arrived in Marvel Rivals, headlined by the addition of Deadpool, and there’s a new Battle Pass to consider purchasing in Season 6.</p>



<p>Battle Passes in Marvel Rivals include a wide array of cosmetic rewards, and Insider Gaming has the breakdown of everything included in the Season 6 pass, alongside the price and a verdict of whether it’s worth buying.</p>







<h2 id="h-how-much-is-the-marvel-rivals-season-6-battle-pass">How Much is the Marvel Rivals Season 6 Battle Pass?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Plenty to unlock. Image via NetEase</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>The Marvel Rivals Season 6 Battle Pass is priced at 990 Lattice, which equates to around $9.99, but there are other options available.</strong></p>



<p>For 2100 Lattice, you receive an immediate 2800 Chrono Tokens to unlock rewards and receive an additional 20% Chrono Tokens Acquisition bonus for the duration of the season to increase the amount you earn for each quest completed.</p>



<p>You can purchase the Battle Pass through currency earned in-game, and, once unlocked, it’s permanently available, so you can work through it at your own pace.</p>



<h2 id="h-all-rewards-in-marvel-rivals-season-6-battle-pass">All Rewards in Marvel Rivals Season 6 Battle Pass</h2>



<p><strong>The Marvel Rivals Season 6 Battle Pass has 12 pages stacked with rewards, including costumes that can’t be obtained anywhere else, two of which are included in the free pass.</strong></p>



<p>Without splashing out on the pass, a free costume is available for Storm and Blade, while purchasing the pass unlocks rewards for the likes of Venom, Winter Soldier, Invisible Woman, and Mantis.</p>



<p>For a full breakdown of all the rewards in the Season 6 Battle Pass, take a look at the table below.</p>



<figure><table><thead><tr><th data-align="center">Reward</th><th data-align="center">Character</th><th data-align="center">Chrono Tokens Cost</th><th data-align="center">Free/Luxury Pass</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td data-align="center">Space Corsair Costume</td><td data-align="center">Venom</td><td data-align="center">N/A</td><td data-align="center">Luxury</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Space Corsair Emote</td><td data-align="center">Venom</td><td data-align="center">200</td><td data-align="center">Free</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Space Corsair Spray</td><td data-align="center">Venom</td><td data-align="center">200</td><td data-align="center">Free</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Deadpool Nameplate</td><td data-align="center">N/A</td><td data-align="center">200</td><td data-align="center">Free</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Space Corsair Nameplate</td><td data-align="center">N/A</td><td data-align="center">200</td><td data-align="center">Free</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Space Corsair MVP</td><td data-align="center">Venom</td><td data-align="center">200</td><td data-align="center">Luxury</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">x100 Unstable Molecules</td><td data-align="center">N/A</td><td data-align="center">200</td><td data-align="center">Luxury</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Venom Spray</td><td data-align="center">Venom</td><td data-align="center">200</td><td data-align="center">Free</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Luminous Legend Spray</td><td data-align="center">Star-Lord</td><td data-align="center">200</td><td data-align="center">Free</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Luminous Legend Nameplate</td><td data-align="center">N/A</td><td data-align="center">200</td><td data-align="center">Free</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">100x Units</td><td data-align="center">N/A</td><td data-align="center">200</td><td data-align="center">Free</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Luminous Legend Emote</td><td data-align="center">Star-Lord</td><td data-align="center">200</td><td data-align="center">Luxury</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">100x Lattice</td><td data-align="center">N/A</td><td data-align="center">200</td><td data-align="center">Luxury</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Luminous Legend Costume</td><td data-align="center">Star-Lord</td><td data-align="center">400</td><td data-align="center">Luxury</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Wolverine Winter Soldier Nameplate</td><td data-align="center">N/A</td><td data-align="center">200</td><td data-align="center">Free</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Winter Soldier Spray</td><td data-align="center">Wolverine</td><td data-align="center">200</td><td data-align="center">Free</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Winter Soldier Emote</td><td data-align="center">Wolverine</td><td data-align="center">200</td><td data-align="center">Free</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">100x Unstable Molecules</td><td data-align="center">N/A</td><td data-align="center">200</td><td data-align="center">Free</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Winter Soldier MVP</td><td data-align="center">Wolverine</td><td data-align="center">200</td><td data-align="center">Luxury</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">100x Units</td><td data-align="center">N/A</td><td data-align="center">200</td><td data-align="center">Luxury</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Winter Soldier Costume</td><td data-align="center">Wolverine</td><td data-align="center">400</td><td data-align="center">Luxury</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">100x Units</td><td data-align="center">N/A</td><td data-align="center">200</td><td data-align="center">Free</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">100x Unstable Molecules</td><td data-align="center">N/A</td><td data-align="center">200</td><td data-align="center">Free</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Blade Soray</td><td data-align="center">Blade</td><td data-align="center">200</td><td data-align="center">Free</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Vampire Slayer Spray</td><td data-align="center">Blade</td><td data-align="center">200</td><td data-align="center">Free</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Vampire Slayer Nameplate</td><td data-align="center">N/A</td><td data-align="center">200</td><td data-align="center">Free</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Vampire Slayer Emote</td><td data-align="center">Blade</td><td data-align="center">200</td><td data-align="center">Luxury</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Vampire Slayer Costume</td><td data-align="center">Blade</td><td data-align="center">400</td><td data-align="center">Free</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">100x Lattice</td><td data-align="center">N/A</td><td data-align="center">200</td><td data-align="center">Free</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">King of Clubs Nameplate</td><td data-align="center">N/A</td><td data-align="center">200</td><td data-align="center">Free</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">King of Clubs Spray</td><td data-align="center">Moon Knight</td><td data-align="center">200</td><td data-align="center">Free</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">King of Clubs MVP</td><td data-align="center">Moon Knight</td><td data-align="center">200</td><td data-align="center">Luxury</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">King of Clubs Emote</td><td data-align="center">Moon Knight</td><td data-align="center">200</td><td data-align="center">Luxury</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">100x Units</td><td data-align="center">N/A</td><td data-align="center">200</td><td data-align="center">Luxury</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">King of Clubs Costume</td><td data-align="center">Moon Knight</td><td data-align="center">400</td><td data-align="center">Luxury</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Gallery Card</td><td data-align="center">N/A</td><td data-align="center">200</td><td data-align="center">Free</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">100x Units</td><td data-align="center">N/A</td><td data-align="center">200</td><td data-align="center">Free</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Bucky Spray</td><td data-align="center">Winter Soldier</td><td data-align="center">200</td><td data-align="center">Free</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Elsa Bloodstone Nameplate</td><td data-align="center">N/A</td><td data-align="center">200</td><td data-align="center">Free</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Bucky Nameplate</td><td data-align="center">N/A</td><td data-align="center">200</td><td data-align="center">Free</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Bucky Emote</td><td data-align="center">Winter Soldier</td><td data-align="center">200</td><td data-align="center">Luxury</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">100x Unstable Molecules</td><td data-align="center">N/A</td><td data-align="center">200</td><td data-align="center">Luxury</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Bucky Costume</td><td data-align="center">Winter Soldier</td><td data-align="center">400</td><td data-align="center">Luxury</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">100x Unstable Molecules</td><td data-align="center">N/A</td><td data-align="center">200</td><td data-align="center">Free</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Galactic Gladiator Spray</td><td data-align="center">Mantis</td><td data-align="center">200</td><td data-align="center">Free</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Galactic Gladiator Nameplate</td><td data-align="center">N/A</td><td data-align="center">200</td><td data-align="center">Free</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Galactic Gladiator Emote</td><td data-align="center">Mantis</td><td data-align="center">200</td><td data-align="center">Luxury</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Galactic Gladiator MVP</td><td data-align="center">Mantis</td><td data-align="center">200</td><td data-align="center">Luxury</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">100x Lattice</td><td data-align="center">N/A</td><td data-align="center">200</td><td data-align="center">Luxury</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Galactic Gladiator Costume</td><td data-align="center">Mantis</td><td data-align="center">400</td><td data-align="center">Luxury</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">King of Wakanda Emote</td><td data-align="center">Black Panther</td><td data-align="center">200</td><td data-align="center">Free</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">King of Wakanda Spray</td><td data-align="center">Black Panther</td><td data-align="center">200</td><td data-align="center">Free</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">100x Lattice</td><td data-align="center">N/A</td><td data-align="center">200</td><td data-align="center">Free</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">100x Units</td><td data-align="center">N/A</td><td data-align="center">200</td><td data-align="center">Luxury</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">King of Wakanda Nameplate</td><td data-align="center">N/A</td><td data-align="center">200</td><td data-align="center">Luxury</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">King of Wakanda MVP</td><td data-align="center">N/A</td><td data-align="center">200</td><td data-align="center">Luxury</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">King of Wakanda Costume</td><td data-align="center">Black Panther</td><td data-align="center">400</td><td data-align="center">Luxury</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Censer of the Contemplator</td><td data-align="center">N/A</td><td data-align="center">200</td><td data-align="center">Free</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">100x UInstable Molecules</td><td data-align="center">N/A</td><td data-align="center">200</td><td data-align="center">Free</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Queen of Wakanda Spray</td><td data-align="center">Storm</td><td data-align="center">200</td><td data-align="center">Free</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Queen of Wakanda Nameplate</td><td data-align="center">N/A</td><td data-align="center">200</td><td data-align="center">Free</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Queen of Wakanda Emote</td><td data-align="center">Storm</td><td data-align="center">200</td><td data-align="center">Free</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Queen of Wakanda MVP</td><td data-align="center">Storm</td><td data-align="center">200</td><td data-align="center">Free</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Queen of Wakanda Costume</td><td data-align="center">Storm</td><td data-align="center">400</td><td data-align="center">Free</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">100x Lattice</td><td data-align="center">N/A</td><td data-align="center">200</td><td data-align="center">Free</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Prism Parade Spray</td><td data-align="center">Invisible Woman</td><td data-align="center">200</td><td data-align="center">Free</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Prism Parade Emote</td><td data-align="center">Invisible Woman</td><td data-align="center">200</td><td data-align="center">Free</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">100x Lattice</td><td data-align="center">N/A</td><td data-align="center">200</td><td data-align="center">Luxury</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Prism Parade Nameplate</td><td data-align="center">N/A</td><td data-align="center">200</td><td data-align="center">Luxury</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Prism Parade MVP</td><td data-align="center">Invisible Woman</td><td data-align="center">200</td><td data-align="center">Luxury</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Prism Parade Costume</td><td data-align="center">Invisible Woman</td><td data-align="center">400</td><td data-align="center">Luxury</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Gallery Card</td><td data-align="center">N/A</td><td data-align="center">200</td><td data-align="center">Free</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<h2 id="h-is-the-marvel-rivals-season-6-battle-pass-worth-it">Is the Marvel Rivals Season 6 Battle Pass Worth it?</h2>



<p><strong>Unfortunately, the Season 6 Battle Pass in Marvel Rivals is arguably the weakest to be introduced since launch, and, unless you’re in love with one of the premium skins, it’s an easy one to skip.</strong></p>



<p>The characters featured, including Venom, Wolverine, Winter Soldier, and Invisible Woman, all have better costumes already available in the game, so it’s hard to justify splashing out on the pass.</p>



<p>Not having a Deadpool skin included is a major disappointment, considering how high the excitement levels have been for his addition, and you’d be better off saving your Lattice for a different purchase.</p>







<hr>



<p>What do you think about the Marvel Rivals Season 6 Battle Pass? Share your thoughts in the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord</a>.</p>



<p>For more Marvel Rivals, take a look at <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marevel-rivals-season-6-twitch-drops/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">all the Twitch Drop rewards for Season 6</a>, and check out the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-season-6-balance-changes-all-buffs-nerfs/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">latest buffs and nerfs</a>.</p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-season-6-battle-pass-price-rewards/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ace Combat 7 has sold over 7,000,000 copies, seven years after its launch]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/ace-combat-7-has-sold-over-7-million-copies</link>
            <guid>1408096</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Ace Combat 7, the brilliant flight sim combat game from Bandai Namco, has sold over 7,000,000 copies since releasing in January, 2019.</p>
<p>Announced on <a href="https://www.facebook.com/AceCombatAmericas/posts/pfbid0VEYNcQBYWdbVAVUWUveoHHYvaLMwcktQQXmQbK8ZdCWu8ue9dHyohimfTvfgjv6Bl">official Ace Combat social media accounts</a>, the milestone came with a message of gratitude from director Kazutoki Kono. It reads: "We are deeply grateful that so many players have continued flying with us for so long. We look forward to meeting you again in the next skies."</p>
<p>In addition, a collection of free wallpapers were linked to Ace Combat fiends looking to relive their time in those skies from the comfort of their various devices. These are sourced from a wide variety of Ace Combat games too, so if you're like me you can decorate your phone with an Ace Combat 5 background. Rest in piece Chopper.</p>

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="ACE COMBAT 8: WINGS OF THEVE Announcement Trailer" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/JQYx_867ua0?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>ACE COMBAT 8: WINGS OF THEVE Announcement Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/JQYx_867ua0?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/JQYx_867ua0?autoplay=1" title="ACE COMBAT 8: WINGS OF THEVE Announcement Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Watch the Ace Combat 8 trailer here!<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JQYx_867ua0" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>


<p>This milestone comes <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/after-a-seven-year-wait-bandai-namcos-classic-aerial-combat-series-will-return-in-2026-with-ace-combat-8">as Ace Combat 8: Wings of Thieve is on the horizon</a>. Announced during The Game Awards 2025, this title is set to release on PC and consoles in 2026. It's also set to feature an "emotionally charged" narrative as well as multiplayer modes, so it's one to look out for.</p><p>Ian Higton took a look at Ace Combat 7's VR capabilities back when it first released back in 2019, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/ace-combat-7-in-vr-is-phenomenal-if-you-have-the-stomach-for-it">and came away impressed, though somewhat disappointed in its limited scope</a>. He wrote: "VR implementation for the full Ace Combat 7 experience would have made it a PSVR system seller for sure but even so, if you're a VR enthusiast, I'd say this experience is worth the price of the full game."</p>

        </div>

  
      </article>



  



  

  <section>
    <span>Related topics</span>

    
  </section>
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/ace-combat-7-has-sold-over-7-million-copies]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A New, Gothic Title From 'Eternal Darkness' Creator Has Re-Emerged]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/01/a-new-gothic-title-from-eternal-darkness-creator-has-re-emerged</link>
            <guid>1408090</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>It looks... okay?</p>
</section></header><div><section>

<p>Denis Dyack, the former president of Silicon Knights and director of games such as <a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/games/ps1/blood_omen_legacy_of_kain">Blood Omen: Legacy of Kain</a> and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gamecube/eternal_darkness_sanitys_requiem">Eternal Darkness: Sanity's Requiem</a>, has revealed the latest look at <strong>Deadhaus Sonata</strong>, a new 'spiritual successor' to Blood Omen.</p>
<p>Originally announced back in 2018, there are no target platforms at the moment, but a <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1142050/Deadhaus_Sonata/">Steam</a> page is now live with more information on its Early Access release. Dyack has previously stated that Deadhaus Sonata will be coming to consoles, but given the sheer amount of time it's been in the works, we can't say for certain if this includes the Switch or Switch 2.</p>
<p>Looking at the gameplay footage, it looks... okay? It's hard to really parse exactly what's going on. There's a lot of hack and slash action being showcased, but there's quite a busy UI to go along with it, and we're not quite sure how everything functions. Early descriptions state that tarot cards can be used to customise your build, while loot is tied to your actions and performance, rather than being completely random.</p>
<p>Still, it's nice to be shown gameplay at all in this day and age, and we're certain Dyack will reveal more in the coming months.</p>
<p>Here's the official Steam description:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Step into Malorum, a dark and crumbling world where the lines between life and death no longer hold. Deadhaus Sonata invites you to embrace the undead, master supernatural powers, and carve your place within a realm shaped by ancient forces, political intrigue, and the choices of its players. Play alone or join up to six players in cooperative play as you face the living and uncover the secrets that shape this fallen realm.</p>
</blockquote>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/retro/related-articles:186876,133576 @ 1768570921 -->
<p><em>What are your thoughts on Deadhaus Sonata so far? Reckon it's worth keeping an eye on? Let us know with a comment.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=F57BmeaZyYc" rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=F57BmeaZyYc">youtube.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/retro/related-info/c4ee4a74802e4936355ac9e8d0cf4994 @ 1768571753 --></div></article><div><p>Nintendo Life’s resident horror fanatic, when he’s not knee-deep in Resident Evil and Silent Hill lore, Ollie likes to dive into a good horror book while nursing a lovely cup of tea. He also enjoys long walks and listens to everything from TOOL to Chuck Berry.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Olliemar28"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/ollie-nl.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Olliemar28');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/01/a-new-gothic-title-from-eternal-darkness-creator-has-re-emerged]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Asus now claims it’s not dropping the RTX 5070 Ti amid memory shortages]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/863297/asus-pr-mess-rtx-5070-ti-end-of-life-statements-memory-shortages</link>
            <guid>1408087</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p>The RTX 5070 Ti will probably still be very hard to find on retail shelves.</p></div><div><div><p>The RTX 5070 Ti will probably still be very hard to find on retail shelves.</p><div><p><span><span>by</span> <!-- --> <span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"></span></span></p><p><span><time datetime="2026-01-16T12:05:26+00:00">Jan 16, 2026, 12:05 PM UTC</time></span></p></div></div><div><p><cite>Photo by Tom Warren / The Verge</cite></p></div></div></div><div><div><div><p><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span id="follow-author-standard_article_details-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTY0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span></span><span>Tom Warren</span></span></span></p> <p><span>is a senior editor and author of <a href="https://www.theverge.com/notepad-microsoft-newsletter"><i>Notepad</i></a>, who has been covering all things Microsoft, PC, and tech for over 20 years.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>The GPU market is turning into a mess again. Asus <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/863000/asus-nvidia-rtx-5070-ti-5060-ti-supply-rumors">told Hardware Unboxed earlier this week</a> that it was winding down production of its RTX 5070 Ti, but the PC maker is now walking back that claim and blaming “incomplete information” from its own Asus PR representatives.</p><p>“The GeForce RTX 5070 Ti and GeForce RTX 5060 Ti 16 GB have not been discontinued or designated as end-of-life (EOL),” says an <a href="https://press.asus.com/news/statements/asus-rtx-5070ti-5060ti-statement/">Asus statement</a>. “Asus has no plans to stop selling these models.”</p><p>That’s quite the opposite of what <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/863000/asus-nvidia-rtx-5070-ti-5060-ti-supply-rumors">Asus told Hardware Unboxed</a>, with the YouTube channel reporting that Asus “explicitly told us this model is currently facing a supply shortage and, as such, they have placed the model into end-of-life status.”</p><div><p>Here’s the full timeline, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yteN21aJEvE">from Hardware Unboxed</a>, of how this mess unfolded:</p></div><div><blockquote><p>• We request RTX 5070 Ti samples from Asus (and other partners)<br>• An Asus PR rep looks into it, comes back and says they cannot provide 5070 Tis due to supply constraints, saying their models are “end of life.”<br>• We ask Asus to clarify whether the RTX 5070 Ti is end of life. They confirm it’s end of life.<br>• We reach out to retailers to see whether they can purchase RTX 5070 Ti stock for their stores, to fact check Asus’ claims. They say there is no supply.<br>• Given we have received an on the record statement from Asus and confirmed the supply constraints with retailers, we publish a video with this information.<br>• Nvidia says all GeForce SKUs are being shipped.<br>• Asus reaches out to clarify that Nvidia told Asus that the RTX 5070 Ti is not end of life, but that Asus are “streamlining some models.”<br>• We publish that statement.<br>• Asus reaches out again to provide another statement (the third statement we’ve received from Asus), now saying the 5070 Ti is not discontinued or end of life. This directly contradicts the original statement.<br>• We immediately request RTX 5070 Ti samples now that the cards are not discontinued or end of life. We haven’t heard back yet.</p></blockquote></div><p>A global shortage of conventional DRAM and NAND is putting the pressure on RAM and GPU prices, and we’re starting to see a lack of GPU stock or higher pricing. Asus blames fluctuations in supply for both the RTX 5070 Ti and RTX 5060 Ti 16GB models due to the ongoing memory supply constraints that have affected production output. “As a result, availability may appear limited in certain markets, but this should not be interpreted as a production halt or product retirement,” says Asus.</p><p>Nvidia told us yesterday that it was still producing RTX 5070 Ti GPUs and continues “to ship all GeForce SKUs and are working closely with our suppliers to maximize memory availability.” Just how many RTX 5070 Ti and 5060 Ti 16GB models will be available in the future is anyone’s guess. Perhaps they’ll be as limited in the real world as Nvidia’s own Founders Edition models, which are very rarely ever in stock.</p><div><p><span><strong>Follow topics and authors</strong> from this story to see more like this in your personalized homepage feed and to receive email updates.</span></p><ul><li id="follow-author-article_footer-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTY0"><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span><span>Tom Warren</span></span></span></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li></ul></div></div></div><div><form><div><h2>The Verge Daily</h2><p><span>A free daily digest of the news that matters most.</span></p></div></form></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/news/863297/asus-pr-mess-rtx-5070-ti-end-of-life-statements-memory-shortages]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>