<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 13:09:33 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Final Fantasy VII Rebirth update 1.040 slashes more bugs]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/06/04/final-fantasy-vii-rebirth-update-1-040-slashes-more-bugs/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/final-fantasy-vii-rebirth-update-1-040-slashes-more-bugs.889020/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/06/04/final-fantasy-vii-rebirth-update-1-040-slashes-more-bugs/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p><a href="http://thesixthaxis.com/tag/square-enix">Square Enix</a> has released a new <a href="http://thesixthaxis.com/tag/final-fantasy-vii-rebirth">Final Fantasy VII Rebirth</a> update which is now available to download on PS5. It’s important to note that this patch doesn’t deliver any new content to the JRPG sequel and is mainly aimed at bug fixes.</p>
<p><iframe title="FINAL FANTASY VII REBIRTH Final Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Q56cRDseTGQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>According to Square, Final Fantasy VII Rebirth update 1.040 “will apply fixes to several bugs, as well as improving the stability and functionality of the overall game.”</p>
<p>You can find a quick rundown of what’s included in the latest patch below. In the meantime, check out <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/02/22/final-fantasy-7-rebirth-review/">Nic’s glowing review</a> in which he scored the game a resounding 9/10, saying: “Final Fantasy VII Rebirth is a beautifully crafted experience that fans old and new will absolutely love. It almost goes too far in correcting the first game’s linearity with broad open areas stuffed with things to do, but there’s also key additions to the combat, and the story running through this middle chapter is masterfully retold. Really the biggest problem you’ll have once the credits roll is knowing that it will be far too many years before we can finish the trilogy.”</p>
<p>Anyway, onto those patch notes!</p>

<h3>Final Fantasy VII Rebirth Update 1.040 Patch Notes</h3>
<ul>
<li>Fixes to bugs that would very occasionally prevent game progress under specific conditions.</li>
<li>Fixes that allow the player to acquire photo frames if a bug occurs that would prevent their acquisition after fulfilling the relevant unlock conditions.</li>
<li>Fixes to bugs that are triggered under specific circumstances in battle.</li>
<li>Fixes to a bug where information was not shown on screen when selecting to play Stage 2 of the Gambit Gears mini game on Hard Mode.</li>
<li>Fixes to several display-related bugs.</li>
<li>Improvements to the overall game stability.</li>
</ul>
<p>These aren’t the only improvements that have been made to the game since its launch earlier this year.&nbsp;Gamers who choose to play in Performance Mode will now have the choice of ‘Sharp’ or ‘Soft’ visuals. At launch, there were complaints that the image quality in Performance Mode was too soft, thanks to the significant drop in the dynamic resolution bracket compared to the Quality Mode. It seems that Square Enix has now added an optional sharpening filter or upscaling technique to help.</p>
<p>Publisher Square Enix is said to be making major changes to the way its creates blockbuster hits. This comes after a recent financial report which showed huge losses for the company after its abandonment of cancelled projects to the tune of $140,000,000. As a result, Square will be more selective in which games its chooses to greenlight.</p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://www.square-enix-games.com/en_US/documents/notice-regarding-updates-final-fantasy-vii-rebirth">Square Enix</a></em></p>


<!-- AI CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pax Dei Early Access Q&A – Mainframe Talks Improvements from the Wilderness Alpha, Monetization and Much More]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/pax-dei-early-access-qa-mainframe-talks-improvements-from-the-wilderness-alpha-monetization-and-much-more/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pax-dei-early-access-q-a-%E2%80%93-mainframe-talks-improvements-from-the-wilderness-alpha-monetization-and-much-more.889017/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/pax-dei-early-access-qa-mainframe-talks-improvements-from-the-wilderness-alpha-monetization-and-much-more/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p><a href="https://wccftech.com/mainframe-industries-reveals-pax-dei-a-sandbox-mmo-coming-to-pc-and-cloud-gaming-platforms/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Pax Dei</a>, the sandbox MMORPG in development at Iceland-based studio Mainframe Industries, has found a publishing partner in New Tales, the French team that helped publish the free-to-play collectible card game Waven.</p>
<p>Together, Mainframe and New Tales announced that Pax Dei will debut in early access in exactly two weeks, on Tuesday, June 18. Pre-purchase is available starting today on the <a href="https://playpaxdei.com/en-us" target="_blank" rel="noopener">official website</a>, with various Founder's Packs options, and the game will be playable via Steam or the dedicated Pax Dei launcher.</p>
<p>Mainframe doesn't shy away from the fact that the game is still very much in Alpha and, as such, in 'heavy' development. It will stay in early access for at least a year, during which major changes will be introduced. At times, full wipes of character progress may even take place. The first big post-launch update will introduce markets and a gold economy to Pax Dei.</p>
<p>I recently had the opportunity to interview Sulka Haro, co-founder and Chief Product Officer at Mainframe, to discuss the game's current state and its future throughout early access.</p>

<p><iframe title="Pax Dei | Early Access Announcement" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/m9kbu7qtYR4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p><strong>When I <a href="https://wccftech.com/mainframe-ex-ccp-remedy-ceo-the-industry-is-headed-towards-cloud-native-games/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">talked</a> to Thor four years ago, he told me the original goal was to make a cloud-native game Cloud native. It was meant to run directly on cloud servers, but that seems to be gone now. Can you speak to this fundamental change?</strong></p>
<p>We still very much want to publish the game across all platforms, including mobile devices, and see streaming as a critical part of that rollout. 5 years ago, it looked like the game streaming platforms were on a steep rise, and we were assuming there would be a widely available ecosystem for distributing games using streaming available by the time we ship the game. This ended up not happening due to a variety of things and we still have a game we’d like to grant access to, so we’re launching on PC first. But as said before, there are plans to expand the available platforms later.</p>
<p><strong>Will Pax Dei be available to play on GeForce NOW and/or other cloud services? If so, when?</strong></p>
<p>We fully intend to bring the game out to a much wider selection of distribution platforms. As a matter of fact, we’ve announced back in January that we’re working on making Pax Dei available on GeForce Now. Not in June, though! Let’s get this PC launch out of the way first.</p>
<p><strong>Will there be support for Steam Deck?</strong></p>
<p>There’s no official support at this time.</p>
<p><strong>During the Wilderness Alpha, I noticed the lack of proper controller support. Is it coming at the early access launch or later?</strong></p>
<p>We’re actively working on improving the controller access. We don’t have a locked-down ETA for it at this point, but we do want to have this available before too long.</p>
<p><strong>The combat felt quite barebones, especially due to the stiff animations. Are you looking to improve that?</strong></p>
<p>Absolutely. The combat system in the Early Access build has already been improved quite a bit in terms of responsiveness, but we can see how we still have to work a lot to get the combat to the level we aspire. We just did a planning session with the whole team and did agree that combat improvements is one of the focus areas for the rest of the year.</p>
<p><strong>Is there a set amount of active combat abilities that players will have at their disposal?</strong></p>
<p>Each one of the weapons (and shields) has a special ability, which we’re improving all the time. Additionally, we’re adding more spells to a larger selection of gear. If you only played the game for a short period of time in the Alpha, you may never get your hands on the spell gear - as you play in PvE, you can find Relics, which unlock recipes for wearables and wieldables that grant you spells, most of which are in form of active combat abilities.</p>
<p><strong>Other MMOs have class-specific special resources (rage/energy/mana, etc.). Will you add something like that to Pax Dei? What about Ultimate abilities?</strong></p>
<p>Our game doesn’t have classes - we use the gear you’re using to effectively create the classes. So when you go raiding, you’ll want to choose gear that matches the role you want to play (which in turn grants you spells once you’ve found some Relics). This system eliminates the need for class-specific resources - we use stamina to gate the spells and abilities you get from the gear. Not related, we are planning to introduce a second resource by the end of the year that will, to some degree, have a similar role in the game.</p>
<p><strong>Previously, you said that magic would be rather rare in the game. Is that still the case? Do you have to work hard to find magic spells?</strong></p>
<p>When you start the game, you have no access to magic. As you progress in the game, you can find Relic, which unlock recipes that allow manufacturing gear that grants you spells and abilities when worn or wielded. The relics for more powerful spells are quite challenging to find, and as the Relics are consumed as part of the crafting process, magic items indeed are not common, and the powerful spells will be quite rare.</p>
<p><strong>Is all gear going to be tradeable? Could you conceivably lend high-end gear to a newbie to make them competitive right away?</strong></p>
<p>Yes, we don’t gate trading and/or using items with character progression. Having said that, new characters will not have progressed in the skills and will not be able to effectively use advanced gear, and of course, a new player is unlikely to have the player skills needed to maximize the use potential of the gear. What this means in practice is that a twinked new player will be immediately useful to you but will not be as powerful as an experienced player with a character that’s in the skill cap in the progression.</p>
<p><strong>In terms of PvE, you talked about the dungeon. Is there a limit to player numbers in dungeons? How does instancing work for dungeons? Could you find other groups there?</strong></p>
<p>Each dungeon has a maximum capacity of players that can be in the same instance at a time. The number is based on the dungeon size &amp; performance requirements to ensure the gameplay experience in the dungeon is pleasant. The instances are not made specifically for a party, so you can find other groups in the dungeons, and new instances are created as needed if the dungeon is full. There’s a system related to the instances in Pax Dei that looks at which instance your party &amp; clan members are and automatically picks the instance with your friends if multiple instances are active. The system also has a different “soft” and “hard” caps for the player routing to give it room to do this social matching to maximize the probability you always end up in the correct instance. This same system also applies to the open world areas of the game, where if a Heartland or Wildland reaches the soft cap, it gets instanced, after which we prioritize the instance for you based on where your friends are.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/PvP-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>

<p><strong>Will PvP work in dungeons, allowing fights between different groups?</strong></p>
<p>Currently, no - we do not want to create significant PvE content in the game that’d be locked behind PvP flags, so players who do not want to participate in PvP don’t feel like we’re forcing them to PvP. Having said that, we are working on an expansion to the PvP system, which will allow players to flag themselves for PvP in a manner that will also work in dungeons. We’ll tell more about this later.</p>
<p><strong>You spoke about potential rewards for PvP, so what are people getting from PvP activities except for loot from the defeated foes?</strong></p>
<p>Currently, PvP is enabled in Lyonesse, a central area in the world accessible from the four Provinces that feature the buildable areas. Entering the area flags you for PvP. The risk/reward related to entering Lyonesse is about the resources you can find in the area - for example, Pure Iron, which is very good for advanced gear manufacturing, is relatively common in Lyonesse (and very rare outside of the area).</p>
<p><strong>I believe Clan Wars were also mentioned somewhere in the presentation slides. Is that feature coming during the early access phase?</strong></p>
<p>We are indeed working on an expansion to the PvP system, and yes, this will launch during the Early Access. The system is not tied directly to the Clans - the PvP organizations are independent of the Clan memberships of the players. We’re assuming some Clans might choose to go all in on PvP and have the PvP organization and the clan memberships match 1:1, but this is up to the players, and we’re sure there will be interesting mixing of clans across the different organizations.</p>
<p><strong>How would those work? Will there be sieges and stuff like that?</strong></p>
<p>We do want to pull off sieges eventually, but in the short term the PvP will be skirmish based. We’ll tell everyone more once we have a better idea of when the features are going to ship to players!</p>
<p><strong>Will there be some bigger PvP-enabled area than Lyonesse at some point?</strong></p>
<p>The entire world will eventually be PvP-enabled. Having said that, the players who do not want to PvP will not be forced to do so and the plots you’re building are sacrosanct and protected by the Divine Peace, so no destruction will come to the villages players are building currently.</p>
<p><strong>You've listed Churches and Feudal System as upcoming Pax Dei features. How do those systems work? What about Altars and Miracles?</strong></p>
<p>The altars will enable new gameplay through Grace, a new resource attainable from the altars used for Miracles and churches are built… around the altars. Grace will also allow anointing Knights, who are PvP flagged across the entire world, which forms the basis of the Feudal System. We’ll tell more about this when we’re a bit closer to shipping these features.</p>
<p><strong>You said transitions to other provinces will require load times. Is there no way to make it seamless at some point?</strong></p>
<p>Currently, when you play the game, it’s pretty rare to get to a loading screen during a typical play session as the 100 square kilometer provinces already provide a huge area for exploration. At this moment, there are practical limits to level sizes, and 100 square kilometers is already pushing it when it comes to seamless travel in the world. We’ll probably look into this at some point, but at the moment we think our time is better spent on other things like improving the combat feel and adding the new game systems discussed earlier.</p>
<p><strong>Can you move between different instances, perhaps to find friends?</strong></p>
<p>At the moment we don’t have a feature for the players to move between instances. We’ll probably add this eventually, but at the moment this is not critical as the way we’ve implemented the instancing areas means players very rarely experience areas that need instancing and when they do, we have the matchmaking system that places layers into the instance with their friends, so it’s extremely unlikely that you’ll ever experience a moment where you’d need to hop between instances.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/Village-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>

<p><strong>What options will there be to reach distant players with fast travel?</strong></p>
<p>At the moment, the only fast travel option is the ability to return home. We’re likely to keep the fast travel in the world very, very restricted, as we want distance to matter in the game. There will be features to make travel more pleasant (mounts will definitely appear in the game eventually).</p>
<p><strong>Regarding character customization, will you add more faces and cosmetic options?</strong></p>
<p>Absolutely.</p>
<p><strong>In the Pax Dei Wilderness Alpha, even with <a href="https://wccftech.com/dlss-3-is-coming-to-horizon-forbidden-west-dragons-dogma-2-like-a-dragon-infinite-wealth-pax-dei-and-more/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DLSS 3</a> enabled on a PC equipped with an RTX 4090 GPU, the game stuttered every few hundred meters. Will you solve that problem in time for the early access launch?</strong></p>
<p>We’ve made several improvements to the content loading, and you should see significant improvement in reducing those stutters in the Early Access build. The stutters were caused by a multitude of issues not related to the GPU, and the work on these, with the help of some of the profiling data we gathered during the Alpha, has paid off very well. We have a few remaining issues, which we’ll address as part of upgrading to a newer version of the Unreal Engine later this year.</p>
<p><strong>What other improvements have you made to Pax Dei since the last Alpha test?</strong></p>
<p>We’ve made a ton of changes that improve the combat responsiveness. Almost everything that can be touched regarding balancing (from combat to recipes) has been touched. We (finally) have rebinding support. There’s literally a few hundred bugs that have been fixed since the Alpha 2 And other things… we’ll soon be publishing extensive release notes that cover a lot of this in detail.</p>
<p><strong>I know you're using Unreal Engine 5 with Lumen and Nanite. Will you keep updating it as Epic releases new versions?</strong></p>
<p>That is the plan, yes. We’re currently using UE 5.2.1 and have already started working on the upgrade all the way to UE 5.4. We’ll ship the Early Access build with the current engine version and are hoping the first bigger update to the game a few months after the launch will already be using a newer engine version.</p>
<p><strong>You've hinted that the game could eventually require an active subscription to play. However, only three of the oldest MMOs (EVE Online, World of Warcraft, and Final Fantasy XIV) still use that business model. Aren't you worried you might alienate many people unwilling to pay a monthly fee?</strong></p>
<p>The final business model for Pax Dei is not decided yet. In Pax Dei, you’re building your home in the “real” world. Whatever gets built on a given player’s plot must always be maintained - that’s costly (not to mention technically challenging). We also need a system to free up land once players leave the game (or become ‘inactive’). This system will be crucial in keeping the world alive, full of activity and opportunities to meet friends, and avoid having areas of the game become ghost towns. Coupling this with monetization seems to be a well-understood and generally accepted model - in the existing Pax Dei community, at least.</p>
<p>We have yet to fully determine the exact shape and form (and price!). this will take. The good old-fashioned subscription model is certainly something we’re looking at. Still, we are also considering other options, with an eye on balancing the simplicity of usage while allowing players to choose how they want to engage with the game. We also indicated we intended to offer a free tier, allowing players to discover the game before committing to it.</p>
<p>We’re committed to being transparent with our model and we’ll keep our players updated on our progress, with an increasing amount of details and with space to experiment and adjust based on sensitivities and data.</p>
<p><strong>What are the odds you'll expand Pax Dei to consoles after the early access phase?</strong></p>
<p>The funding theory behind Mainframe was to make a game playable on every screen. We’re not excluding anything. That said, let’s get things right on PC first!</p>
<p><strong>Thank you for your time.</strong></p>

				

			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mutant Year Zero: Zone Wars is the year’s goofiest tabletop skirmish game]]></title>
            <link>https://www.polygon.com/tabletop-games/24168167/mutant-year-zero-zone-wars-review</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mutant-year-zero-zone-wars-is-the-year%E2%80%99s-goofiest-tabletop-skirmish-game.889014/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.polygon.com/tabletop-games/24168167/mutant-year-zero-zone-wars-review<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>If you buy something from a Polygon link, Vox Media may earn a commission. See our <a href="https://www.polygon.com/pages/ethics-statement" target="_blank">ethics statement</a>.</p><div>
  <p id="8KK5pH">Skirmish wargaming — traditional miniatures wargaming with a smaller footprint and fewer minis — is having a moment. Used to be there were just a few flavors available, but a new crop of games is suddenly giving all kinds of different energies. Grimdark <em>Necromunda</em>, futuristic <em>Infinity</em>, and stalwart <em>Malifaux</em> are all still around, of course. Their action remains brutal, and their rulesets fairly complex. Meanwhile, newcomers <em>Cyberpunk Red: Combat Zone </em>and <em>Fallout: Factions</em> are becoming more established thanks to dynamic sculpts, bright colors, and most importantly, far more simplified rules. There’s also <em>Star Wars: Shatterpoint </em>and <em>Halo: Flashpoint</em>, more civilized games clearly built for brisk, competitive play. </p>
<p id="2Y5ZbW">Now comes Free League Publishing’s <em>Mutant Year Zero: Zone Wars</em>, launching today with a<em> </em>new <em>Core Set</em>. It feels like this one is bringing some much-needed comic relief. </p>
<p id="lnGiQO">First launched as <em>Mutant</em> in 1984, the Swedish tabletop role-playing universe has been many things over the years. Funcom’s <a href="https://www.polygon.com/2018/9/13/17854952/mutant-year-zero-pc-xbox-one-ps4-tactical-rpg-xcom"><em>Mutant Year Zero: Road to Eden</em></a> refocused the franchise on its goofiest characters, human-and-animal hybrids with bizarre special abilities. It also helped that one of the main characters looks like an up-armored Howard the Duck. All the while, Free League has been working diligently in the background to keep <a href="https://freeleaguepublishing.com/shop/mutant-year-zero/">the modern version of the TTRPG</a> in circulation around the world.</p>
<p id="KXe1oO"><em>Zone Wars</em> smartly puts our duck friend back on the cover, and this time he’s the linchpin of a powerful band of Stalkers, mutant soldiers who enter the dangerous, irradiated Zone to scavenge for artifacts. It’s a simple premise that opens the door to clever scenario-based gameplay and the potential for linked campaigns.</p>
<p>  <figure>
  <span>
    
    <span data-original="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25473018/mutant_year_zero_zone_wars_minis.jpg">
      
        <picture data-cid="site/picture_element-1717506039_84_19258" data-cdata="{&quot;asset_id&quot;:25473018,&quot;ratio&quot;:&quot;*&quot;}">
  


  <source srcset="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9cANjOsaERtp5lHOXZhJYPISafs=/0x0:3000x2000/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x2000):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25473018/mutant_year_zero_zone_wars_minis.jpg 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/eo1TZFcB6L-lXREbsK7-5sZ6ytA=/0x0:3000x2000/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x2000):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25473018/mutant_year_zero_zone_wars_minis.jpg 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/vCach-m3n2ae67Fro137g4SubmU=/0x0:3000x2000/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x2000):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25473018/mutant_year_zero_zone_wars_minis.jpg 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/86CeaB4SZmeUWZdfmISX09YLE9k=/0x0:3000x2000/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x2000):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25473018/mutant_year_zero_zone_wars_minis.jpg 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/woy5FbPPQbJjofuQAnvnaJ7AVjQ=/0x0:3000x2000/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x2000):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25473018/mutant_year_zero_zone_wars_minis.jpg 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xNknOkqHN3fg_Gz0rszQ4mIcPsI=/0x0:3000x2000/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x2000):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25473018/mutant_year_zero_zone_wars_minis.jpg 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ewObvD74tP0-n9RGUmp8OOVuIZs=/0x0:3000x2000/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x2000):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25473018/mutant_year_zero_zone_wars_minis.jpg 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/TrV0B18xpTYnqKmdpPUSwSHCh-E=/0x0:3000x2000/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x2000):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25473018/mutant_year_zero_zone_wars_minis.jpg 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3270fk5UBX9DgnLHIVBnwiXV3T8=/0x0:3000x2000/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:3000x2000):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25473018/mutant_year_zero_zone_wars_minis.jpg 1920w" sizes="90vw" type="image/webp">




</picture>

      
    </span>
    
  </span>
  
    <span>
      
        <figcaption>All 10 miniatures come pre-painted with a high-contrast paint, but you’re going to need to put in some work to strip it off if you want to paint them up. The custom plastic pack-in included inside the box gives the whole package a polished feel.</figcaption>
      
      
        <cite>Photo: Charlie Hall/Polygon</cite>
      
    </span>
  
</figure>


</p>
<p id="YmtnF4">The most surprising part of this package isn’t the manual. That’s because the rules have been built by Andy Chambers, co-designer of the original <em>Necromunda</em>, and they are rock-solid and easy to understand. No, the most surprising part is the completeness of this starter set, which includes a few short stacks of unit and ability cards, loads of cardboard terrain, bits and custom dice, but also pre-assembled and pre-shaded monochrome miniatures. Setup took me all of 20 minutes, and just about 30 minutes later I had already grokked most of the mechanics.</p>
<p id="mWANTe">Gameplay is nuanced and engaging, but never tedious. <em>Zone Wars</em> has just enough complexity to keep you on your toes. You’ll need to keep track of where your miniatures are facing, for instance, and charging straight away into melee isn’t always the best move, even when your team has the advantage in numbers. Meanwhile, if you keep your distance it can be hard to level a kill shot. That’s because these little buggers are all pretty resilient!</p>
<p id="V2yCaP">Deal enough damage to a given character, and they’ll become broken. After tipping them on their side, the only available action you can take with them on their turn is recovery. But to recover, you’ll need a special item or a friend nearby to come to your aid. Then the only way forward is to roll some dice, combining attributes of the rescuer and the rescued to tally up the results. If they succeed, the broken character leaps to their feet with full health — only to become bloodied. If they go down again, though, they’re absolutely out of the match.</p>

<p id="yxZP9K">The result is a lighthearted game of tactical <em>Whac-a-Mole</em>, filled with endearing critters with charming attributes taking devastating hits. But when they go down in a hail of bullets and feathers, they invariably leap heroically back to their webbed feet, makeshift guns blazing. I know of no other game where a moose-man can run antlers-first into an insect-man to score the winning point.</p>
<p id="CVeGV1">The best part is that even in a linked campaign with multiple missions — of the type offered in the game’s first expansion, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Free-League-Psionics-Expansion-Miniatures/dp/B0CV81X9RB/?tag=polygon05-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank" has-subtag="true" data-cdata="{&quot;rewritten_url&quot;:&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Free-League-Psionics-Expansion-Miniatures/dp/B0CV81X9RB/?ascsubtag=___pl__p_23932208__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder\u0026tag=polygon05-20&quot;,&quot;subtag_max_length&quot;:99,&quot;subtag_delim_length&quot;:3,&quot;subtag_key&quot;:&quot;ascsubtag&quot;,&quot;subtag_data&quot;:{&quot;ascsubtag&quot;:&quot;___pl__p_23932208__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder&quot;,&quot;tag&quot;:&quot;polygon05-20&quot;},&quot;encode_subtag&quot;:false}"><em>Mutant Year Zero: Zone Wars - Robots &amp; Psionics</em></a> — death isn’t really an issue. Even if your favorite character does go down for a second time in the heat of battle, they’ll absolutely be back for the next game. Because if there’s one thing funnier than doming Howard the Duck at range with a scavenged laser rifle, it’s doing it again... and again... and again over the course of a multi-session campaign. </p>
<p id="iBr4Uu"><small><em>Mutant Year Zero: Zone Wars Core Set</em></small><small> and </small><small><em>Mutant Year Zero: Zone Wars - Robots &amp; Psionics</em></small><small> are available now. The products were reviewed using a retail copy provided by Free League Publishing. Vox Media has affiliate partnerships. These do not influence editorial content, though Vox Media may earn commissions for products purchased via affiliate links. You can find </small><a href="https://www.polygon.com/pages/ethics-statement"><small>additional information about Polygon’s ethics policy here</small></a><small>.</small></p>
<hr id="88oQTx">



  
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dragon Ball: Sparking Zero Leak Teases Special Edition & Pricing]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-leak-teases-special-edition-pricing/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-leak-teases-special-edition-pricing.889011/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-leak-teases-special-edition-pricing/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>In <a href="https://x.com/billbil_kun/status/1797968974560518366" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a new post</a> on Twitter/X, consistently reliable leaker @billbil_kun claimed that Dragon Ball: Sparking Zero is getting an Ultimate Edition.</p>



<p>The post also adds that this special edition will be available in physical format, and that it should have a price tag of $109.99. There were no further details about a release window, or other potential editions. </p>



<p>However, the leaker did reiterate that Dragon Ball: Sparking Zero is coming to Summer Game Fest 2024. Insider Gaming can corroborate that the game will be at Summer Game Fest, with retailers ready to put pre-order information live. </p>



<p>It’s unclear if the devs will reveal more information during the event. Summer Game Fest 2024 will premiere later this week on June 7, and it will feature <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/summer-game-fest-2024/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">2 hours of game showcases</a>. </p>



<figure><div>
<blockquote data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>🚨 EDITION &amp; PRICE REVEAL 🚨</p><p>DRAGON BALL: Sparking! ZERO Ultimate Edition<br>(Also available in physical disc)</p><p>Price: 109.99$</p><p>More details on Summer Game Fest 2024 <a href="https://t.co/9RMl0AwBkr">pic.twitter.com/9RMl0AwBkr</a></p></div>— billbil-kun (@billbil_kun) <a href="https://twitter.com/billbil_kun/status/1797968974560518366?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 4, 2024</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>



<p>Bandai Namco announced Dragon Ball: Sparking Zero <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/every-new-game-announced-at-the-game-awards/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">at The Game Awards 2023</a>. Last March, the devs also revealed a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/bandai-namco-reveals-dragon-ball-sparking-zero-roster-and-features/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">promising roster of fighters</a> and key features. That included some big changes, such as a movement boost and new fighting mechanics.</p>



<p>It’s unclear which platforms the Ultimate Edition is coming to, as well as the potential components it will include. However, such editions frequently add exclusive figures, original soundtracks, art books, and more. Such content would certainly help justify the leaker’s claimed price tag. </p>



<p>Billbil-kun has successfully leaked a variety of gaming information. That includes the recent <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/astro-bot-officially-announced-at-playstation-state-of-play/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Astro Bot game announcement</a> from PlayStation’s State of Play event.</p>



<p>Dragon Ball: Sparking Zero will be available on PC via Steam, PlayStation 5, and the Xbox Series X|S. At this time, Bandai Namco has not confirmed anything about the Dragon Ball: Sparking Zero Ultimate Edition or its pricing.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more of the latest gaming industry news, you can read about Prime Video announcing a new live action <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/like-a-dragon-yakuza-series-amazon/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Like a Dragon: Yakuza adaptation</a>, and sign up to receive the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/newsletter/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming newsletter</a>.</p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GTA 6 Trailer At Summer Game Fest Is Not Happening]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-6-trailer-at-summer-game-fest-is-not-happening/1100-6523913/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gta-6-trailer-at-summer-game-fest-is-not-happening.889008/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-6-trailer-at-summer-game-fest-is-not-happening/1100-6523913/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6523913">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>The big Summer Game Fest showcase takes place this Friday, June 7, and people are naturally wondering what they should expect in terms of reveals and announcements. Geoff Keighley, who organzes the show, has now offered some insight into what won't be on hand at the briefing.</p><p><a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/heres-what-we-know-wont-be-at-summer-game-fest" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">As reported by IGN</a>, Keighley confirmed there will be no <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/grand-theft-auto-6-everything-we-know/1100-6503729/" data-ref-id="1100-6503729">Grand Theft Auto VI</a> trailer during Summer Game Fest. It's been more than six months since the first GTA VI trailer was released in December 2023, so some people believed it might be time for the next trailer or any other information. Apparently that's not going to happen, though, and GTA fans will have to wait a while longer.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FZ2Clscn0Jg" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/FZ2Clscn0Jg" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>Keighley also said there won't be Kingdom Hearts 4 news or any reveals for Ken Levine's new game, Judas. Beyond Good &amp; Evil 2 also won't show up, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/dont-expect-a-just-one-more-thing-at-summer-game-fest-live/1100-6523883/" data-ref-id="1100-6523883">nor will there be a big "one more thing" announcement to cap off the event.</a></p><p>In terms of what will be on display during Summer Game Fest, Keighley said there will be announcements regarding updates to existing games, including Palworld and Kingdom Come: Deliverance II. New trailers for Monster Hunter Wilds and Batman: Arkham VR will be on display as well. As for brand-new announcements, Keighley said Blumhouse Games will have something to reveal, while the showcase will debut the first footage of the Among Us animated series.</p><p>Summer Game Fest 2024 takes place place on Friday, June 7 at 2 PM PT / 5 PM ET. The show will now take the spot formerly held by E3, the long-running video game trade show once seen as the premier event in gaming, which was <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/e3-is-permanently-canceled/1100-6519882/">permanently canceled</a> last year.</p><p>Following Summer Game Fest will be the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/xbox-games-showcase-airs-june-9-followed-by-mystery-event/1100-6523072/" data-ref-id="1100-6523072">Xbox Games Showcase event on June 9, with a Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 reveal event</a> to follow immediately after. Then on June 10, Ubisoft will host its <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ubisoft-forward-2024-how-to-watch-start-times-and-what-to-expect/1100-6523848/" data-ref-id="1100-6523848">Ubisoft Forward event with news on Assassin's Creed Shadows, XDefiant, and Star Wars Outlaws.</a></p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What do Apple and Google’s direct-to-consumer changes really mean for game developers?]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamesindustry.biz/what-do-apple-and-googles-direct-to-consumer-changes-really-mean-for-game-developers</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/what-do-apple-and-google%E2%80%99s-direct-to-consumer-changes-really-mean-for-game-developers.889005/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamesindustry.biz/what-do-apple-and-googles-direct-to-consumer-changes-really-mean-for-game-developers<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        

        <p>FastSpring also shares advice on how studios can best adopt direct-to-consumer payment solutions</p>

    </div><div>



            <p>The direct-to-consumer payment landscape for mobile game developers is changing. Rapidly. Courts and regulators in both the EU and the US have taken issue with Google and Apple's app store monopolies, which means in the near future, mobile game developers may no longer have to mandatorily surrender a 30% cut on all in-game purchases.</p>
<p>Traditionally, selling in-game items or virtual currency through an external webshop has generally been allowed without additional fees by Apple and Google, so long as you don’t embed payments directly inside your mobile game, or steer players with calls-to-action inside the game to buy items from an external webshop.</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/david-nachman.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption>David Nachman, FastSpring</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Recent regulatory and legal pressure has forced Apple and Google to make concessions on embedded payments. However, these concessions have come with prohibitively high fees that negate most of the financial value of direct-to-consumer. This has spurred lawsuits from app and game publishers like Epic, Spotify, and others, which will further increase pressure. Other game publishers are still in wait-and-see mode as these lawsuits play out.</p>
<p>That said, direct-to-consumer is still a viable growth strategy for mobile game publishers, and there are many excellent examples of success to learn from including Warner Bros' Game of Thrones Conquest, Scopely’s Marvel Strikeforce, and the Supercell store.</p>
<p>How can developers monetise their mobile games with direct-to-consumer today? Well, that's a little more complicated. The freedom of monetizing with direct-to-consumer comes with the complexities of global payment methods, currency localisation, and local sales tax/VAT compliance, all of which need to be scrupulously observed to ensure you don't fall foul of the law. This is where the convenience of a direct-to-consumer payments specialist like FastSpring comes in, saving you not only time but considerable money, too. While it focuses on your payments (and, importantly, fraud prevention), you can stay focused on making great games.</p>
<blockquote><p>"The freedom of monetizing with direct-to-consumer comes with the complexities of global payment methods, currency localisation, and local sales tax compliance</p></blockquote>
<p>"Video game publishers have numerous options when it comes to direct-to-consumer payment providers, making it challenging to determine the best choice," admits David Nachman, CEO of FastSpring. FastSpring is a Merchant of Record (MoR) payment provider, which mean it's a trusted third-party firm that assumes responsibility for processing your payments, and sales tax compliance worldwide. It has almost two decades of experience providing payment solutions to publishers unsure about how best to navigate the complexities of global payments and sales tax compliance.</p>
<p>"Our solution seamlessly integrates payments either directly within video games or on a publisher's webshop. Our comprehensive service facilitates payments through multiple global processors to ensure optimal approval rates, offers a wide variety of payment methods around the globe, manages all global sales tax and VAT compliance automatically, offers robust video game-specific fraud prevention, provides dedicated customer support, and much more."</p>
<p>Nachman says that whilst there's been a lot of progress with lawsuits like Epic v. Google – for which FastSpring was called upon to provide evidence – there's still a lot for developers and publishers to consider even without looming app store rule changes around direct-to-consumer.</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Screenshot-2024-06-03-at-7.08.19AM.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption>FastSpring can help developers go direct-to-consumer</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Because of its 19 years of experience as an all-in-one payments provider, FastSpring considers itself uniquely placed to "allow video game publishers to spend more time making great games and less time selling them." Thanks to its specialized knowledge of local payment methods, video game-specific fraud prevention, and tax compliance, FastSpring has even helped game developers and publishers break into new markets.</p>
<p>"Marketplaces serve as excellent platforms for reaching new audiences for games, while simultaneously offloading the complexities of payment processing and tax compliance. Game studios simply upload their game to the marketplace and receive their earnings monthly," Nachman explains, acknowledging that a lot of game studios use the familiar method of selling their games through Steam, the PlayStation, Xbox, and Nintendo online stores, and/or mobile app stores.</p>
<p>"But for game publishers considering a move beyond marketplaces to direct-to-consumer sales, FastSpring is a great choice because we offer many of the payment and tax compliance benefits of a marketplace thanks to our comprehensive all-in-one platform and Merchant of Record model.</p>
<p>"Like a marketplace, the MoR model offloads the burdens of payment processing and tax compliance. However, it does so within an experience directly embedded in your game or on your webshop, and at a significantly lower cost than marketplaces."</p>
<p>As for publishers already selling directly to their players? FastSpring can still help there, too; its global payments coverage enables studios to expand into all-new markets "or as a redundant provider in their existing payment stack to leverage FastSpring’s high approval rates, or simply as a failover option."</p>
<blockquote><p>"FastSpring is a great choice because we offer many of the payment and tax compliance benefits of a marketplace"</p></blockquote>
<p>While FastSpring is ready to help with direct-to-consumer strategies today, Nachman said FastSpring is still committed to the fight for open commerce in mobile with embedded payments and steering allowed without additional fees in the future.</p>
<p>When the Google vs Epic ruling came down last December, Nachman was quick to respond, stating he and FastSpring were "ecstatic that game developers will have more choice in how they bring their games to market." He called it "a major win" that he suspected would "have a huge impact on gamers across the industry" and enable devs "to deliver better games and pricing for their players." And it's this commitment to consumer choice and developer freedoms that FastSpring champions most.</p>
<p>"At FastSpring, we support open computing and believe that people should have choice when installing games and software on their phones," Nachman explains. "We also believe that game developers should have choice over the payment solutions they support in their games.</p>
<p>"Apple and Google have been responding to the recent lawsuits and regulations by updating their terms to 'comply' but these changes so far have resulted in a great big juicy nothing-burger," Nachman adds. The recent app store term changes – which include a 28% fee for transactions that happen outside of the app and a limited ability to load apps outside the respective app stores – include "mind-bending gotchas" that essentially negate any material benefit for players or game developers.</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Screenshot-2024-06-03-at-7.07.43AM.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption>Supercell operates its own store</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>It's because of this that Nachman expects, in the short term, to see game companies start aggressively pushing the line in their direct-to-consumer strategies with mobile games "now that weaknesses have emerged", along with further lawsuits protesting the recent app store terms changes.</p>
<p>In the mid-to-long term, he opines that ongoing lawsuits may force even more changes to app store terms and conditions that are more in line with rulings and regulations.</p>
<p>"One thing we can confidently predict is that Apple and Google will keep fighting to protect their global duopoly, and everyone else will keep fighting for choice," Nachman insists.</p>
<p>To learn more about FastSpring’s global payments and subscription management platform, get in touch <a href="https://fastspring.com/solutions/gaming/" rel="sponsored" target="_blank">via the website</a>.</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PSVR 2 PC adapter to launch on August 7]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamesindustry.biz/psvr-2-pc-adapter-to-launch-on-august-7</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/psvr-2-pc-adapter-to-launch-on-august-7.889002/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamesindustry.biz/psvr-2-pc-adapter-to-launch-on-august-7<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        

        <p>The device will give access to Steam's VR library from PlayStation's headset</p>

    </div><div>



            <p>Sony is set to launch a PC adapter for its PlayStation VR 2 headset this August.</p>
<p>Scheduled for release on August 7, the adapter will give PSVR 2 players access to Steam's library of VR titles, which includes Half-Life: Alyx, Fallout 4 VR, and more.</p>
<p>The adapter will be available from PlayStation's own store and "select retailers," Sony said, and will have a $59.99 / €59.99 / £49.99 price tag.</p>
<p>In order to have access to Steam's VR library from a PSVR 2, players will also need a DisplayPort cable compatible with DisplayPort 1.4 (that needs purchasing separately), a Steam account, and a PC meeting the minimum requirements detailed in <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2024/06/03/playstation-vr2-players-can-access-games-on-pc-with-adapter-starting-on-august-7/">Sony's blog post</a>.</p>
<p>"PSVR 2 was designed from the ground up specifically for PS5 – so you'll notice that some key features, like HDR, headset feedback, eye tracking, adaptive triggers, and haptic feedback (other than rumble), are not available when playing on PC," Sony's principal product manager Yasuo Takahashi clarified in the announcement.</p>
<p>He added: "While the most immersive way to experience PSVR 2 gaming remains on PS5, we hope players will enjoy the ability to play an expanded lineup of VR games on PC using the same headset."</p>
<p>The PSVR 2 launched on February 22, 2023 and <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/psvr-2-sold-just-shy-of-600000-units-in-six-weeks">sold just shy of 600,000 units in six weeks</a>. The virtual reality headset hasn't been a breakaway success, with reports in March 2024 pointing to <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/sony-reportedly-stops-psvr-2-production-to-clear-the-current-backlog">Sony halting production</a> in order to clear its current backlog of unsold devices.</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Like A Dragon: Yakuza' Live-Action Series Hits Amazon Prime Video This October]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gameinformer.com/news/2024/06/04/like-a-dragon-yakuza-live-action-series-hits-amazon-prime-video-this-october</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/like-a-dragon-yakuza-live-action-series-hits-amazon-prime-video-this-october.888999/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gameinformer.com/news/2024/06/04/like-a-dragon-yakuza-live-action-series-hits-amazon-prime-video-this-october<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p>Amazon has announced <em>Like a Dragon: Yakuza</em>, a live-action television series adaptation of Ryu Ga Gotoku Studios and Sega's long-running Like a Dragon (formerly Yakuza) series. It will be a story centered on series mainstay Kazuma Kiryu and will follow his life in 1995 and 2005 across six episodes.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The first three episodes drop Oct. 25 and the last three episodes hit Amazon Prime Video on Nov. 1, and, according to&nbsp;<a href="https://variety.com/2024/tv/news/like-a-dragon-yakuza-live-action-series-sega-game-prime-video-1236024275/"><em>Variety</em></a>, the series will be subbed and dubbed in 30 languages.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The logline for the series describes it as a story set in two time periods – 1995 and 2005 – and follows the life, childhood friendships, and repercussions of the decisions of Kazuma Kiryu, a Yakuza warrior with a strong sense of justice, duty, and humanity. If you're familiar with the series, given the time periods at play here, it sounds like <em>Like a Dragon: Yakuza</em> could be loosely adapting the storyline of Yakuza 1.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Take Masaharu (<em>100 Yen Love</em>) is directing the series alongside Takimoto Kengo (<i>Kamen Rider</i>), and stars Takeuchi Ryoma (various&nbsp;<em>Kamen Rider&nbsp;</em>movies and series) as Kazuma Kiryu. You can see him in the image below:</p>












<article data-embed-button="image_browser_uploader" data-entity-embed-display="view_mode:file.body_default_rendered" data-entity-type="file" data-entity-uuid="e428a1da-2e12-4759-895e-e02d4a81a896" data-langcode="en" data-entity-embed-display-settings="[]">





</article><p><em>Variety&nbsp;</em>reports <em>Like a Dragon: Yakuza</em> will "depict the lives of fierce yet passionate gangsters and people living in a huge entertainment district,&nbsp;Kamurochō, a fictional district modeled after the violent Shinjuku ward's&nbsp;Kabukichō, that acts as the backdrop of the gameplay." Amazon says the series "showcases modern Japan and the dramatic stories of these intense characters, such as the legendary Kazuma Kiryu, that games in the past have not been able to explore."&nbsp;</p>

<p>Ryu Ga Gotoku Studios studio head and series executive producer Yokoyama Masayoshi told&nbsp;<em>Variety&nbsp;</em>the following:&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Since the day I first put pen to paper on the original Yakuza script, I've never once thought about revisitng any of my work on the series. It's because I understand all too well the challenges and hardships that come with remaking a finished title. However, if I were ever sent to the past through some kind of cosmic joke, this is the experience I'd want to create. If I had to go through the wringer anyhow, I'd want to make the most engaging versions of&nbsp;Kamurochō and Kazuma Kiryu I could - and this show has it all.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"While the games let you experience their world through the subjective lens, this adaptation will be the ultimately objective way to enjoy the show. I have no doubt fans of the series will be drawn to how it brings the games to life and adds new surprises. Newcomers, I'm sure, will find themselves invested simply in the gritty realism of the show."&nbsp;</p>

<p><em>Like a Dragon: Yakuza </em>hits Amazonz Prime Video starting on Oct. 25 and will finish on Nov. 1 this year.&nbsp;</p>

<p>News of this series follows the release of <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/product/like-a-dragon-infinite-wealth">Like a Dragon: Infinite Wealth</a>, the eighth mainline installment in the video game series, back in January. You can read&nbsp;<a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/review/like-a-dragon-infinite-wealth/passing-the-torch"><em>Game Informer's&nbsp;</em>Like a Dragon: Infinite Wealth review here</a>. After that, read&nbsp;<a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/feature/2022/11/24/the-future-of-ryu-ga-gotoku-studio"><em>Game Informer's&nbsp;</em>exclusive interview with the leads behind the Like a Dragon series</a> to learn about the future of Ryu Ga Gotoku studio while visiting its offices.&nbsp;</p>

<hr><p><em>Are you excited about Like a Dragon: Yakuza? Let us know in the comments below!</em></p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dig into Magical Delicacy, a delicious Metroidvania-lite, when it’s served next month]]></title>
            <link>https://www.destructoid.com/dig-into-magical-delicacy-a-delicious-metroidvania-lite-when-its-served-next-month/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=dig-into-magical-delicacy-a-delicious-metroidvania-lite-when-its-served-next-month</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dig-into-magical-delicacy-a-delicious-metroidvania-lite-when-it%E2%80%99s-served-next-month.888996/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.destructoid.com/dig-into-magical-delicacy-a-delicious-metroidvania-lite-when-its-served-next-month/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=dig-into-magical-delicacy-a-delicious-metroidvania-lite-when-its-served-next-month<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p data-characters="243" data-injectable="true" data-video="true">Publisher Whitethorn Games has revealed when fans can get their hungry hands on Skaule’s upcoming main course of a Metroidvania-lite, <em>Magical Delicacy</em>. The game will be available on July 16, offering a new, wholesome twist on the genre. </p> <p data-characters="616" data-current-count="616" data-injectable="true">In just over a month, you’ll be able to get cooking with <em>Magical Delicacy</em> on PC, Nintendo Switch, Xbox One, and Xbox Series X/S from day one. You can even get the game on Xbox Game Pass the same day, meaning there are plenty of places you can settle down to consume its meaty gameplay. The story reminds me very much of <em>Kiki’s Delivery Service</em> as protagonist Flora, a young witch, arrives in the town of Grat to develop her magical skills. As we all know, though, training as a witch is never straightforward, and Grat has several mysteries to get caught up in and a colorful cast of characters to meet. </p>
 <h2 id="h-players-will-collect-recipes-and-ingredients-build-their-dream-kitchen-and-serve-the-local-townsfolk-in-magical-delicacy" data-injectable="false">Players will collect recipes and ingredients, build their dream kitchen, and serve the local townsfolk in <em>Magical Delicacy</em></h2> <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"><p> <iframe title="Magical Delicacy Release Date | PC, Nintendo Switch, Xbox" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Mn-5KMaEJuw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe> </p></figure> <p data-characters="420" data-current-count="720" data-injectable="true">While we don’t know how Flora comes to Grat, once there, she settles down and sets up shop to deliver potions and home-cooked meals to the local townsfolk. <em>Magical Delicacy</em> is a Metroidvania-lite, borrowing some <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/10-best-metroidvania-games-you-can-play-now/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">elements from the genre</a>, such as unlocking tools for gradual progression, while using others, such as 2D platforming and NPC relationships, to help build out the overarching story and linear questline. </p>
 <p data-characters="432" data-current-count="432" data-injectable="true">The core gameplay revolves around cooking and gathering ingredients. Some can be purchased, while others must be foraged from around Grat. As you progress, you’ll unlock new potions and recipes that will open up new areas of the town and access to new townsfolk. Some of these recipes will require kitchen upgrades, but you’ll get to build it as you play until it feels like your ideal countryside cottage cooking area. </p>
 <p data-characters="382" data-current-count="382" data-injectable="false"><em>Magical Delicacy</em>‘s cooking system isn’t a simple one-button affair. It’s pretty complex and allows for experimentation as you figure out what to cook for every individual you meet. As you move through the story, new ingredients, processes, and recipes only make it more in-depth, but based on the trailer, it seems to replicate cooking in the kitchen fairly well. </p> <p data-characters="444" data-current-count="826" data-injectable="true">Whitethorn Games boasts that, much like a good soup, there’s more to Grat than meets the eye. While cooking and serving the townsfolk is one objective, you’ll lose yourself in others, including meeting ancient figures of legend or old masters of their craft who have long been forgotten. It sounds to me like Flora will help modern-day townsfolk understand more about Grat’s past in a similar way to how you did in <em><a href="https://www.destructoid.com/reviews/review-spirittea/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Spirittea</a></em>. </p>
 <p data-characters="540" data-current-count="540" data-injectable="false">What I believe is special about <em><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2231190/Magical_Delicacy/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Magical Delicacy</a></em> is that it takes what is often the heart of a family’s day, sitting around a table together to talk about their day and share a meal, and turns it into an entire game. Flora may cook multiple meals, but it’s the cooking that brings the townsfolk out of their shells and helps you, as the player, understand and appreciate Grat. Just like in real life, food can help you integrate with a small community because it’s a great leveler. After all, everyone’s got to eat. </p>

<hr>
<p><i data-stringify-type="italic"> Destructoid is supported by our audience. When you purchase through links on our site, we may earn a small affiliate commission.&nbsp;</i><i data-stringify-type="italic"><a href="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-stringify-link="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" data-sk="tooltip_parent">Learn more</a></i> </p>

</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mech Engineer's demo is for people who love hateful interface design]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/mech-engineers-demo-is-for-people-who-love-hateful-interface-design</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mech-engineers-demo-is-for-people-who-love-hateful-interface-design.888981/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/mech-engineers-demo-is-for-people-who-love-hateful-interface-design<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>



            <p>
If you heard loud swearing last night in the Watford area it may have been one of two things: 1) me cussing out my (borrowed) Steam Deck while stealthily accessing the wifi from outside a closed public library, as I don't currently have broadband at home, or 2) me subsequently trying to make head or tail of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/mech-engineer">Mech Engineer</a>, in which you take charge of a mobile undersea metropolis and send squads of painstakingly assembled robosoldiers to semi-auto-battle squidgy alien fauna. 
</p>
<p>
Engineering a mech is a Herculean labour whose completion eludes today's puny scientists, and Mech Engineer doesn't aim to make life easier, whatever its putative status as a "means of fun". Mech Engineer is a game with an attitude problem, frankly. I realised this on in-game day two, when the interface coughed up a bunch of damage reports presented as pieces of paper, which I then had to crumple up and toss away individually.
</p>
<!--more-->
<p>
That interface! There's an innocent 30 seconds initially when you think it's just badly designed. But then you realise that it is a creature of foul and labyrinthine purpose. Broadly, it consists of a Dwarf Fortressy grid-based world map, where you can shunt your city about and send mech squads on missions, with tabs for researching new components, fabricating them, and assembling them into conveniently coffin-sized Gundams you can then fill with pilots. There's a calendar which lets you advance to the next day. Reading those sentences back, it sounds practically transparent. Like XCOM but with extra robots, right? Wrong! Mech Engineer is nothing like XCOM. It is like tying your shoelaces with a pair of scissors. It is like doing jigsaw puzzles in a cesspit after the death of the sun.
</p>
<p>
When I mentioned Mech Engineer to Graham he said it reminded him of MicroProse's older interface 'em ups, in which the thrill arises from the quasi-analog, high-fidelity obfuscatoriness of the simulation itself. I subsequently went away and discovered that yes, MicroProse is Mech Engineer's publisher. I do not have the benefit of Graham's greatly advanced years and accompanying experience of recreational inconvenience, but to me Mech Engineer feels almost like a parody of MicroProse's games on par with <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/space-warlord-organ-trading-simulator">Space Warlord Organ Trading Simulator</a>. 
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Mech Engineer 1.0 Launch Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6RT8ijnoUak?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Mech Engineer 1.0 Launch Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6RT8ijnoUak?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/6RT8ijnoUak?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6RT8ijnoUak" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>
The interface is a sour quagmire of analog dials, submarine-style viewports, wireframe graphs and incomprehensible LED readouts, laid out in violent contradiction of present day notions of "flow", with several ways of flipping between screens that compete for your attention constantly, on-screen buttons in place of keyboard controls, a habit of miniaturising the most important elements, and a relentless desire to overcomplicate every little interaction. Again, you might think it to be poorly made, but it's very obviously a labour of love. Each individual fitting has a just-so exactness, from the monochrome firing range simulator through the authentically papery bestiary and landscape illustrations, to the sheer range of alarm SFX and mechanical reports that blare from the guts of the beast as you tootle about pressing the wrong bits and getting your pilots slaughtered.  
</p>
<p>
The actual mech engineering is in-depth and seems engrossing. For instance: you have to construct, test and ignite a mech's reactor before slotting it into the chassis, which feels vaguely cathartic - like putting the cherry on a carefully optimised cake's worth of delicately thinned-out armour plating, optional energy shields, and chonky Gatling guns that can themselves be tweaked and whittled to satisfaction. Battle, meanwhile, is fairly hands-off and visually reminiscent of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/duskers">Duskers</a>: you give your squad waypoints and fiddle with things like spacing while they shoot at Space Invaders in real-time on a scratchy radar display, until they run out of ammo or crumple under the stress. 
</p>
<p>
Your pilots have animated portraits, and my word, they are an unsightly bunch even before you feed them to the extra-terrestrials - not so much an army of Doomguys as a cluster of chatbot gargoyles gawping at you from the abyss. Again, there's a just-so feel to it all that hooks my curiosity even as I whinny in anguish, uninstall the demo in a frenzy, and race back to the library at midnight to download something gentler, like <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/i-made-the-witchy-cottage-of-my-dreams-in-tiny-glade">Tiny Glade</a>. Mech Engineer! How I loathe you, especially as I've just realised that <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-rally-point-putting-mech-engineer-on-trial-and-error">Sin wrote you up three years ago</a> - honestly, it sounds like the only thing that has really changed in the meantime is that you can now <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1428520/Mech_Engineer/">buy the full thing on Steam</a>.</p>




        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hypercharge Unboxed Sells 40,000 Copies in 4 Days on Xbox]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/hypercharge-unboxed/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hypercharge-unboxed-sells-40-000-copies-in-4-days-on-xbox.888978/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/hypercharge-unboxed/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>Hypercharge Unboxed by Digital Cybercherries Limited is out now on Xbox Series X/S and Xbox One.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If you have ever seen a reel or a TikTok of a game where a bunch of toys are causing chaos with weapons in the middle of a toy store, then you know about Hypercharge Unboxed. The 2020 multiplayer and offline shooter is now officially available through the Xbox store. The game is an indie project that has been developed by a team of 6 people and was first available only through <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/523660/HYPERCHARGE_Unboxed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Steam</a>. Commendably, Hypercharge Unboxed has sold more than 40,000 copies within 4 days of its release on the Xbox Store, as per Jake Lucky on X (formerly Twitter).&nbsp;</p>



<figure><div>
<blockquote data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">The viral game where you play as action figures in a toy store is officially out on Xbox, selling over 40,000 copies in it's first 4 days, a dream accomplished for the lead of this indie dev project <a href="https://t.co/KFjo6tkfBx">pic.twitter.com/KFjo6tkfBx</a></p>— Jake Lucky (@JakeSucky) <a href="https://twitter.com/JakeSucky/status/1797666996135555270?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 3, 2024</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>



<p>Talking about the game, the story revolves around an ancient line of action figures that allows humans to retain their childhood memories with their toys through a magical power called Hypercore. In this first and third-person shooter, you get to play as action figures as you fight against hordes of weaponized toys and save the Hypercore from a villainous faction called Major Evil.&nbsp;</p>



<figure>
<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>



<figure></figure>
</figure>



<p>Moreover, Hypercharge Unboxed features online as well as offline co-op for up to 2-4 players with cross-platform play. The player needs to team up to gather resources, stronger weapons, and mysteries between the waves of enemies to progress. There are two editions of the game available on the Xbox Store. The <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/hypercharge-unboxed/9ngk4zhkbc8x" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Standard Edition</a> provides the base game at the price of $29.99. The second version is the <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/hypercharge-complete-edition/9PPMRSZ3CS7P/0010" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Complete Edition</a> of the game, which includes the contents of the standard edition along with a Supporter Pack and Breaker &amp; Mightus pack. These packs include the following: Breaker action figure, Migtus action figure, Classic Hypercharge action figure, Roadwarrior action figure, more than 18 skins, and weapon materials.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What are your views on Hypercharge Unboxed? Let us know in the comments. </p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read&nbsp;about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/newsletter/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">GAME shutting down its reward scheme</a>, and don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/newsletter/">subscribe to the Insider Gaming Newsletter</a>.<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/league-of-legends-source-code-stolen-from-riot-games/?relatedposts_hit=1&amp;relatedposts_origin=42839&amp;relatedposts_position=0&amp;relatedposts_hit=1&amp;relatedposts_origin=42839&amp;relatedposts_position=0&amp;relatedposts_hit=1&amp;relatedposts_origin=42839&amp;relatedposts_position=0"></a></p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MultiVersus Tournament Player Sees Their Main Character Pulled From the Game Mid-Bracket, Wins Anyway]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/multiversus-tournament-player-sees-their-main-character-pulled-from-the-game-mid-bracket-wins-anyway</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/multiversus-tournament-player-sees-their-main-character-pulled-from-the-game-mid-bracket-wins-anyway.888975/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/multiversus-tournament-player-sees-their-main-character-pulled-from-the-game-mid-bracket-wins-anyway<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>A <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/multiversus">MultiVersus</a> players had to react fast after the developer pulled their main character out of the game in the middle of a tournament.</p><p>A post on the MultiVersus X/Twitter account signaled the removal of Iron Giant from the recently released brawler due to various issues with the character, which players believe include overpowered combos and an infinite chain grab. Garnet was added to the Preview Rotation in response.</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Thank you MVPs for alerting us about the current issues surrounding Iron Giant. We have decided to bring him back into the shop for maintenance. During this time, you will not be able to play with him, but we are working diligently and will update you next week on his status. In…</p>— MultiVersus (@multiversus) <a href="https://twitter.com/multiversus/status/1797780234680569867?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">June 3, 2024</a></blockquote> <p>Fair enough, you’d think. But for one MultiVersus player the removal of Iron Giant couldn’t have come at a worse time. As revealed in an <a href="https://x.com/NickSF_SSB/status/1797790657047863488" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">X/Twitter post by @NickSF_SSB</a>, co-owner of No Style eSports, a player going by the name of ‘FlaSHFReeeze’ was in the middle of a bracket when their main, Iron Giant, was pulled from the game. Cue bemused conversation between the two players. Brilliantly, FlaSHFReeeze switched character and won the set anyway, proving that fighting game players always need a backup in case of emergency.</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">He still won the set tho <a href="https://t.co/ZpsFR7Tlyz" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/ZpsFR7Tlyz</a></p>— NS | NickSF 🔜 Solar Flare &amp; Sunrise 2024 (@NickSF_SSB) <a href="https://twitter.com/NickSF_SSB/status/1797797020012511410?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">June 4, 2024</a></blockquote> <p>This week, developer Player First Games said <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/multiversus-dev-bringing-back-some-missing-features">a number of missing features are on their way back to MultiVersus</a>. After close to a year long hiatus, the Warner Bros. brawler featuring Gizmo from Gremlins, Rick and Morty, Lebron James, Batman, Arya Stark, Bugs Bunny, Shaggy, Tom and Jerry, Jason, and more <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/multiversus-relaunch-draws-many-players-and-many-complaints"><u>returned in May 2024 to many players and many complaints</u></a>.</p><p>"Some of the missing settings and features from the open beta are incoming," wrote game director Tony Huynh on <a href="https://x.com/Tony_Huynh/status/1796903400497684726?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>X/Twitter</u></a>. "Team colors, end of game stats, swapping side and neutral attack, adjustable input buffer settings, etc."</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div><h3>MultiVersus Joker Reveal</h3></div></output><p>Huynh then said the team didn't have time to add these features during Multiversus's offline period. "Many of these features are currently implemented and are in testing and we had planned, but were left out due to time as we had to rebuild every screen and feature again to support our new netcode and Unreal Engine 5 switch," he explained.</p><p>No timeframe for the features was given, though as Huynh said more information is coming soon, the actual release may not be imminent.</p><p><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[XDefiant leaker claims two Assassin’s Creed maps could be coming soon]]></title>
            <link>https://www.destructoid.com/xdefiant-leaker-claims-two-assassins-creed-maps-could-be-coming-soon/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=xdefiant-leaker-claims-two-assassins-creed-maps-could-be-coming-soon</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/xdefiant-leaker-claims-two-assassin%E2%80%99s-creed-maps-could-be-coming-soon.888972/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.destructoid.com/xdefiant-leaker-claims-two-assassins-creed-maps-could-be-coming-soon/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=xdefiant-leaker-claims-two-assassins-creed-maps-could-be-coming-soon<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p data-characters="259" data-injectable="true" data-video="true"><em>XDefiant</em> is Ubisoft’s attempt at creating a <em>Call of Duty</em> killer, but the company has so much more locked away in its IP vault. That’s why it should be no surprise that a leaker has discovered mentions of maps themed around <em>Assassin’s Creed</em>. </p> <p data-characters="321" data-current-count="321" data-injectable="false"><em>CoD</em> is well-known for its weird and wacky crossovers these days, so it’s not a huge shock that <em>XDefiant</em> aims to follow that pattern too. It’s easier when you own a lot of IP as well, as Ubisoft does, so getting them into your game is much easier and doesn’t require negotiations with the rights owners. </p> <p data-characters="296" data-current-count="617" data-injectable="true">According to Rogue, an <em>XDefiant</em> dataminer, two <em>Assassin’s Creed</em> maps should appear in the game at some point in the future, with the leaker posting a clip featuring sounds from the maps, while also stating that they had found a “good amount of things related to” the locations. </p>
 <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"></figure> <p data-characters="410" data-current-count="710" data-injectable="true">It would definitely be interesting to see what those maps would look like, with all of the <em>Assassin’s Creed</em> maps set well in the past. Whether we would see locations from history or maps based on the more modern-day story that is expected to feature in <em>Assassin’s Creed: Infinity</em>. Other leaks have suggested that a new faction called The Brotherhood could also be linked to the long-running series.</p>
 <p data-characters="322" data-current-count="322" data-injectable="false">Of course, it’s worth remembering that these are leaks and rumors, and haven’t been confirmed by Ubisoft. Therefore, it’s worth taking all of this information with a pinch of salt until we get official word from the developers. Still, it’s hard not to let your imagination run wild at the thought. </p>
<hr>
<p><i data-stringify-type="italic"> Destructoid is supported by our audience. When you purchase through links on our site, we may earn a small affiliate commission.&nbsp;</i><i data-stringify-type="italic"><a href="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-stringify-link="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" data-sk="tooltip_parent">Learn more</a></i> </p>

</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ikea is hiring UK workers for its new store in Roblox]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/ikea-is-hiring-uk-workers-for-its-new-store-in-roblox</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ikea-is-hiring-uk-workers-for-its-new-store-in-roblox.888966/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/ikea-is-hiring-uk-workers-for-its-new-store-in-roblox<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>



            <p>Swedish store and home of flatpack furniture Ikea is hiring 10 people from the UK and Ireland to assist with the running of a virtual store in Roblox.</p>
<p>As spotted by <a href="https://www.thegamer.com/ikea-hiring-roblox-players-run-virtual-in-game-store/">TheGamer</a>, this virtual store is part of a "Careers Done Different" campaign, which Ikea hopes will demonstrate possible career paths available within the company.</p>
<p>Successful candidates will be able to serve meatballs in the store's bistro, and help patrons choose furniture in the showroom. As for pay, Ikea is offering an hourly wage of £13.15/€14.80 for this obviously fully remote, limited contract position.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="PlayStation upsets VR fans as it kicks off this year's not-E3 hype cycle" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ev55ao9pf4M?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>PlayStation upsets VR fans as it kicks off this year's not-E3 hype cycle</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ev55ao9pf4M?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/ev55ao9pf4M?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Newscast: PlayStation upsets VR fans as it kicks off this year's not-E3 hype cycle<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ev55ao9pf4M" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>"With us, you have the opportunity to move departments, flex your skill and get promoted," the application's <a href="https://thecoworker.co.uk/">website</a> reads. "At Ikea, career progression is unique because you can grow in any direction. We believe in recruiting people based on our values rather than simply ticking all the right boxes on a CV."</p>
<p>To apply, those interested will need to answer a range of questions including the deeply insightful: "How do you feel about being turned into pixels?" Applicants will also need to think about what they would do if the bistro ran out of pixelated hot dogs during their shift.</p>
<figure data-count="2" role="group">
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Ikea-Roblox.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
</figure>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Roblox-Ikea.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
</figure>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Ikea</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>It is not just Ikea that is using Roblox to expand its reach. <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/netflix-unveils-digital-theme-park-nextworld-on-roblox">Netflix is also coming to Roblox</a>, with the streaming giant recently revealing its "digital theme park" on the gaming platform, known as Nextworld. This will essentially acts as a hub where players can access areas, characters and games based on Netflix properties, such as Stranger Things and One Piece.</p>
<p>For more on Roblox, our Chris Tapsell recently spoke with the studio's head Stefano Corazza about concerns the game exploits children. You can <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/roblox-studio-boss-children-making-money-on-the-platform-isnt-exploitation-its-a-gift">read the full interview here</a>.</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Suda51 says he doesn't know if we'll ever see No More Heroes' Travis Touchdown again]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/suda51-says-he-doesnt-know-if-well-ever-see-no-more-heroes-travis-touchdown-again</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/suda51-says-he-doesnt-know-if-well-ever-see-no-more-heroes-travis-touchdown-again.888960/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/suda51-says-he-doesnt-know-if-well-ever-see-no-more-heroes-travis-touchdown-again<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Untitled-111.jpg?width=1200&amp;height=1200&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Grasshopper Manufacture</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
Legendary game designer Goichi "Suda51" Suda has said he doesn't know if the world will ever see No More Heroes or its star Travis Touchdown again, following the launch of 2021's climactic No More Heroes 3.
</p>
<p>
Speaking to Eurogamer ahead of his appearance at MomoCon 2024 last month, No More Heroes creator and director Suda acknowledged that the rights to the No More Heroes series remain with Japanese game publisher Marvelous rather than his own studio Grasshopper Manufacture.
</p>
<p>
"Honestly, not even I know that," Suda51 told Eurogamer, when asked if No More Heroes and Travis Touchdown would ever return. "Of course I'd love to see him again, but to be honest it's simply not my call to make."
</p>
<figure>
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<figcaption>Hotel Barcelona announcement trailer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ytZ1cfKMaJE" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>
No More Heroes 3 was designed as a game to cap off the series so far, with Marvelous otherwise focused on its own franchises, such as Rune Factory, Story of Seasons and Daemon X Machina.
</p>
<p>
Suda51, meanwhile, is currently busy building <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/heres-our-first-look-at-hotel-barcelona-a-horror-themed-side-scroller-from-swery-and-suda51">Hotel Barcelona, a collaboration between his Grasshopper Manufacture studio and Hidetaka "Swery" Suehiro</a>, of Deadly Premonition fame. 
</p>
<p>
"A long time ago, before Covid, we did an event in Shibuya where Swery was a guest. We just kinda started talking about doing a collaboration of some sort," Suda51 said of how work on Hotel Barcelona began. "The idea came up, Swery liked it, and he basically brought it all the way to development, and well, now it's a thing.
</p>
<p>"Swery is acting as both director and producer and is doing most of the work; I just kinda started it up with him at beginning. But Swery is having a lot of fun making it, and I'm having a lot of fun giving input here and there, etc. I'm extremely happy to be involved as co-creator."</p>
<p>Fans of Grasshopper's earlier work at least have two other launches to look forward to: remasters of both <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/lollipop-chainsaw-repop-now-a-remaster-not-a-remake-developer-says">Lollipop Chainsaw</a> and <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/shadows-of-the-damned-remaster-announced">Shadows of the Damned</a>.</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Final Fantasy VII Rebirth Glitch Lets You Reach Midgar, Fort Condor, Village of the Gi]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/final-fantasy-vii-rebirth-glitch-fort-condor/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/final-fantasy-vii-rebirth-glitch-lets-you-reach-midgar-fort-condor-village-of-the-gi.888957/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/final-fantasy-vii-rebirth-glitch-fort-condor/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Final Fantasy VII Rebirth features some rather interesting out-of-bounds secrets that can only be experienced by taking advantage of a certain glitch.</p>
<p>As reported by @deltasyn on X/Twitter, the glitch showcased by M_Two on <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mRFqVpMLLIE" target="_blank" rel="noopener">YouTube</a>, which involves the blue Chocobo, which can normally only be ridden in the Nibel Region, allows players to reach some normally impossible to reach locations, such as <a href="https://x.com/deltasyn/status/1797036281618202684">Midgar</a>, <a href="https://x.com/deltasyn/status/1797521060021334380">Fort Condor</a> and the <a href="https://x.com/deltasyn/status/1797798352790184378" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Village of the Gi</a>. While the former two aren't particularly interesting, the latter is far more interesting, as it features some objects that could have some lore and story implications.</p>
<p>On a related note, a new Final Fantasy VII Rebirth patch went live earlier today. The 1.040 patch fixes a variety of bugs, including several unspecified display-related bugs, and improves overall game stability. Full patch notes can be found on the Square Enix <a href="https://www.square-enix-games.com/en_US/documents/notice-regarding-updates-final-fantasy-vii-rebirth">official website.</a></p>
<p>Final Fantasy VII Rebirth is now available on PlayStation 5. Learn more about the game by checking out Kai's <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/final-fantasy-vii-rebirth/">review.</a></p>
<p><em>If there’s one word to describe&nbsp;Final Fantasy VII Rebirth, it would be ambitious. Tetsuya Nomura, Kazushige Nojima, and the rest of Creative Business Unit I at Square-Enix have turned what is merely the remainder of Final Fantasy VII’s Disc One upon leaving Midgar into a 100-hour-long epic. Moments of distracted exploration throughout the massive wide-open environments are often bookended with more linear story segments that balance comedy and somber moments. Players will feel more intimately engrossed with the story of those chosen by the planet and routinely have their fond memories of playing the original tickled with delight.</em></p>

				

			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MSI Announces a Mid-Gen Refresh for The Claw]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/msi-claw/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/msi-announces-a-mid-gen-refresh-for-the-claw.888954/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/msi-claw/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>MSI Claw 8 AI Plus confirmed with a larger battery and screen, as the previous device received Fallout collaboration during Computex 2024.</p>



<p>MSI had a panel today at the Computex 2024 event, announcing a mid-gen refresh for their handheld console, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/msi-claw-us-release-date/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The Claw</a>. As per <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/computing/msi-claw-8-ai-plus-first-look/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Digital Trends</a>, the device is getting an upgraded model called the MSI Claw 8 AI Plus. Interestingly, just like the recently announced <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/rog-ally-x-launch-specifications/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">ROG Ally X</a>, the new model will also feature an 80 Whr battery, a substantial upgrade over the previous model. The most exciting upgrade comes towards its processor, as it will be ditching the existing Meteor Lake chips for Intel’s upcoming Lunar Lake series of processors.&nbsp;</p>



<figure><div>
<blockquote data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Date : June 4 – June 7 2024 <br>Time : 9:30 am – 5:30 pm <br>Venue : Taipei Nangang Exhibition Center, Hall 1, 4F, <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/M0806?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#M0806</a><br>MSI sincerely invites you to dive into the AI Era of Computing and witness our groundbreaking hardware and software innovations at COMPUTEX 2024. <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MSIxComputex2024?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#MSIxComputex2024</a> <a href="https://t.co/7eEVz8JAJz">pic.twitter.com/7eEVz8JAJz</a></p>— MSI (@msitweets) <a href="https://twitter.com/msitweets/status/1796074292666339738?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">May 30, 2024</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>



<p>Furthermore, the report also reveals that we will see an upgrade in the memory and storage of the Claw 8 AI Plus. The RAM will be upgraded to 32GB LPDDR5x, capable of reaching 8.5gbps. The upcoming device will now have upgradeable storage, featuring a 1TB M.2 2280 SSD. The MSI Claw 8 AI Plus will also sport a larger 8-inch screen with a similar resolution and refresh rate, 1080p at 120Hz. These are the only details disclosed about the device thus far. Additional information, such as pricing, availability, and other specifications, shall be available soon.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In addition, the original MSI Claw has received a new limited edition model in collaboration with Fallout. The theme will be inspired by the Vaults, Pip-Boys, and robots from the game, offering fans a chance to immerse themselves even more during their Fallout sessions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What do you think about the MSI Claw 8 AI Plus? Let us know in the comments.&nbsp;</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read&nbsp;about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/game-reward-ending-shut-down/">GAME shutting down its reward scheme</a>, and don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/newsletter/">subscribe to the Insider Gaming Newsletter</a>.</p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bungie Warns Of Known Issues Ahead Of Destiny 2: The Final Shape Release]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/bungie-warns-of-known-issues-ahead-of-destiny-2-the-final-shape-release/1100-6523909/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/bungie-warns-of-known-issues-ahead-of-destiny-2-the-final-shape-release.888951/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/bungie-warns-of-known-issues-ahead-of-destiny-2-the-final-shape-release/1100-6523909/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6523909">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>With not long to go now before <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/destiny-2/" data-ref-id="5000-463450">Destiny 2</a> comes back online for the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/destiny-2-the-final-shape-raid-launch-time-and-everything-we-know/1100-6522790/" data-ref-id="1100-6522790">Final Shape launch</a>, Bungie has warned of <a href="https://www.bungie.net/7/en/News/article/finalshapeknownissues" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a few known issues</a> that will launch with the new content. With issues that will potentially impact progression, audio playback, and other elements of the game, here's what Destiny 2 players need to know.</p><p>Most importantly, players who are taking on the Final Shape campaign in a fireteam should avoid joining missions in progress or swapping characters mid-campaign to ensure progress is correctly recorded.</p><p>Bungie also warns that the game won't currently work with 3D audio, and any players with 3D audio enabled won't get any sound from the game. Players are advised to disable 3D audio settings, including Windows Sonic for Headphones or Dolby Atmos, until this is fixed.</p><p>A number of other minor issues that will launch with the game include placeholder art appearing instead of final pieces, and some small errors in descriptions for items and abilities. Check out the full list below.</p><p>The Final Shape will launch after an <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/destiny-2-the-final-shape-requires-25-hour-downtime-massive-install-sizes/1100-6523838/" data-ref-id="1100-6523838">extended downtime</a> at 10 AM PT / 1 PM ET today, June 4, though players can preload the new expansion while the game is down. After the expansion is live, progress on known issues will continue to be updated through the <a href="https://www.bungie.net/7/en/user/ZendeskAuth?brand_id=360002414611&amp;locale_id=1&amp;return_to=https%3A%2F%2Fhelp.bungie.net%2Fhc%2Fen-us%2Farticles%2F27062192032404&amp;timestamp=1717485651" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Top Issues</a> page. Bungie also encourages players to report issues with the new content through its <a href="https://www.bungie.net/en/Forums/Topics?pNumber=0&amp;tg=Help&amp;tSort=3&amp;tType=0&amp;d=0&amp;lang=en" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Help Forum</a> if they encounter any with the new content.</p><h2>The Final Shape Known Issues</h2><ul><li>Players progressing through The Final Shape campaign<strong> in a fireteam</strong> should avoid joining missions in-progress or swapping characters during the campaign to ensure progress is correctly recorded.</li><li>PC players with <strong>3D audio enabled</strong> will not get any audio output from the game.  <ul><li>As a temporary workaround, players with Windows Sonic for Headphones, Dolby Atmos, or any other 3D audio setting enabled in their Windows Spatial Sound settings should switch the setting to Off when playing the game.</li></ul></li><li>The "<strong>Leaving The Final Shape Campaign</strong>" pop-up is displaying placeholder art.</li><li>Activating Prismatic Hunter's <strong>Blink Dagger super</strong> while mid-Grapple causes the player to fall.</li><li>The Solar Hunter’s <strong>“Knock ‘Em Down” aspect</strong> does not increase the number of Blade Barrage projectiles.</li><li>The ability description for the Hunter <strong>Arc Staff super</strong> does not mention that the three-attack combo or ground slam attack applies Blind.</li><li>The description for the <strong>Deconstruct perk</strong> does not reflect the recent change made in Update 8.0.0.1. Deconstruct now refills ammo from reserves.</li><li><strong>Vestiges </strong>won't auto-convert into a Memory item if another Memory item is in your inventory. Players must obtain another Vestige after the Memory is used for Vestiges to convert into another Memory.</li><li>Some <strong>old seasonal currencies and items</strong> from Seasons 20-23 will not be automatically removed.</li><li><strong>Khvostov 7G 0X</strong>'s trait "Eyes Up, Guardian" incorrectly states that the ricochet shots deal more damage.</li><li>Players who were tracking <strong>Triumphs that were vaulted</strong> with the launch of The Final Shape cannot untrack them.</li><li>During The Final Shape campaign, if players do not open the final chest in <strong>The Blooming Deep Lost Sector</strong> before the cutscene plays, the loot will be lost.</li><li>When Warlocks pick up a <strong>Stasis Shard with the Glacial Harvest aspect equipped</strong>, they will not be granted healing.</li><li>The <strong>Berserker’s Bladefury super</strong> does not consistently apply Woven Mail to allies on super cast when combined with Into The Fray aspect.</li></ul>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[CI Games hires Tencent and PlayStation veteran to spearhead development]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ci-games-hires-tencent-and-playstation-veteran-to-spearhead-development</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ci-games-hires-tencent-and-playstation-veteran-to-spearhead-development.888948/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ci-games-hires-tencent-and-playstation-veteran-to-spearhead-development<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Lords of the Fallen</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> developer CI Games has named former Tencent director Tom O'Connor as its senior vice president of development.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The Polish studio said O'Connor will "spearhead" its strategic development goals and "help coordinate the company's internal and external studios across CI Games and United Label."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">O'Connor will report to CI Games CEO, Marek Tyminski, who feels his experience will enable the studio to build on the "business optimizations" it has made over the past six months.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"On behalf of the executive leadership team–and the company as a whole–I want to welcome Tom to CI Games," said Tyminski. "He joins at a crucial time as we continue to improve the efficiency and quality of our titles–building on the business optimizations we've made over the last six months–and help execute the company strategy through the growth of our owned IPs going forward."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Those "optimisations" saw the company </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/lords-of-the-fallen-developer-ci-games-cutting-10-percent-of-jobs">lay off 10 percent of its workforce</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> in January 2024 to deliver "business strength and stability." A few months later, CI Games </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ci-games-ceo-lauds-record-annual-revenues-months-after-cutting-10-percent-of-jobs">delivered record annual revenues</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> but </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ci-games-sanctions-another-30-layoffs-in-final-targeted-round-of-redundancies-">decided to cut another 30 jobs</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> in a "final, targeted round of redundancies."</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="CI Games eager to realize multi-project ambitions, but at least one title is in trouble">CI Games eager to realize multi-project ambitions, but at least one title is in trouble</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">CI Games is currently developing multiple projects including two codenamed Project III and Project Survive, the latter of which is seemingly in a spot of bother.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">An investor update published in April revealed an external agency hired to evaluate the project found some deficiencies. "The Agency Report indicates that currently some of the mechanics of the game being developed under the project 'Survive' do not meet the assumptions implied by the documentation of this project," </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://cigames.com/en/ci-games-se-20-2024-results-of-project-survive-analysis/">it reads.</a></span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"The Management Board after an initial analysis of the current status of the project 'Survive' and taking into account the results of the Agency Report, concludes that the game’s release date planned for 2025 is significantly jeopardized."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">O'Connor, who also spent 15 years at PlayStation managing a suite of studios, said he will attempt to hone the company's production frameworks to bring those projects to fruition and take CI Games "to the next level."</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author(s)</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">News Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer news editor Chris Kerr is an award-winning journalist and reporter with over a decade of experience in the game industry. His byline has appeared in notable print and digital publications including Edge, Stuff, Wireframe, International Business Times, and&nbsp;</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="http://pocketgamer.biz/">PocketGamer.biz</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. Throughout his career, Chris has covered major industry events including GDC, PAX Australia, Gamescom, Paris Games Week, and Develop Brighton. He has featured on the judging panel at The Develop Star Awards on multiple occasions and appeared on BBC Radio 5 Live to discuss breaking news.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fallout 2 Fan-Made Remake Will Be an Open-World RPG; Steam Release Planned]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/fallout-2-remake-open-world/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fallout-2-fan-made-remake-will-be-an-open-world-rpg-steam-release-planned.888942/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/fallout-2-remake-open-world/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Fallout 2, the second entry in the series, which has recently seen a surge in popularity thanks to the Amazon Prime Video TV show, is getting remade by a team of dedicated fans in the style of the third and fourth entries in the series.</p>
<p>In a new interview with <a href="https://www.thegamer.com/fallout-2-fan-made-remake-interview-project-arroyo/#project-arroyo-will-be-open-world">The Gamer</a>, Damion Daponte, a freelance video editor who leads the Project Arroyo development team of over 100 modders, revealed some details on the project. The project is attempting to remake the second entry in the series as an open-world role-playing game using Fallout 4's engine. As the original game wasn't big enough, the team will also expand the world and offer a condensed-down version of San Francisco to explore.</p>
<p>The Fallout 2 fan-made remake will also rework some of the mechanics of the original, such as random encounters, which are not needed in an open-world RPG, bring back the classic Pip-Boy, and feature some assets lifted from New Vegas, which provided a better look at the New California Republic. Fallout 4's Power Armor will also be back in the remake, as the developer feels the way it works in the game makes more sense compared to how it functions in Fallout 3 and New Vegas.</p>
<p>While a release date for the Fallout 2 Project Arroyo remake has yet to be announced, there's a good chance the fan-made remake will be released on Steam. <em>"It’s just a platform that everyone has,"</em> Daponte said, <em>"it’s easier to access, easier to update, easier to install - it’s more efficient. We would have to figure out all the specificities, making it so you have Fallout 2 and Fallout 4 and all of its DLC to make sure there are no legal issues. But we’re still looking into it.”</em></p>
<p>More information on the Fallout 2 fan-made remake can be found on <a href="https://discord.com/invite/xDcqEb3jgt" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Discord</a>. You can also check out a quick comparison between the original and Project Arroyo in the video below.</p>
<p><iframe title="FALLOUT 2 REMAKE - Remake vs Original Comparison [Project Arroyo]" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/AwJlcesILvY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>The original Fallout 2 is now available on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/agecheck/app/38410/">Steam</a> and <a href="https://www.gog.com/en/game/fallout_2">GOG.</a></p>

				

			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Team Fortress 2 Steam Reviews Drop to ‘Mostly Negative’ as Players Plead With Valve to Do Something About Bots]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/team-fortress-2-steam-reviews-drop-to-mostly-negative-as-players-plead-with-valve-to-do-something-about-bots</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/team-fortress-2-steam-reviews-drop-to-%E2%80%98mostly-negative%E2%80%99-as-players-plead-with-valve-to-do-something-about-bots.888936/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/team-fortress-2-steam-reviews-drop-to-mostly-negative-as-players-plead-with-valve-to-do-something-about-bots<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>The <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/team-fortress-2">Team Fortress 2</a> community has come together in an attempt to brute force developer Valve into fixing a bot problem that has plagued the hero shooter for years.</p><p>Disgruntled players of the near 17-year-old shooter, which remains one of the most-played games on Steam, have taken to user reviews to let their feelings be known about bots. This review campaign has caused Team Fortress 2’s recent reviews user rating to plummet to ‘mostly negative’, with pretty much all the comments complaining about bots.</p><p>“It's time Valve does something about the bots,” reads one review from a user with over 630 hours on Team Fortress 2. “The game has been overrun with people willing to doxx, DDOS, and SWAT anyone who takes action against the problem.”</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/06/04/tf2-1717495240265.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption>Team Fortress 2 is one of the oldest supported video games on the market. Image credit: Valve.</figcaption></figure></output><p>“The current state of this game is borderline unplayable,” reads another review from a user with over 950 hours. “It is CRIMINAL that Valve has done nothing against this issue, and have continued to profit off of this game.”</p><p>“Valve, you've got a gem of a game here that has left a mark on the internet culture for longer than I can remember,” reads another review, this time from a user with over 700 hours of game time. “We're tired of bots running rampant across the casual matchmaking. We want you to step in, we don't want another update, we don't want any cosmetics, we want you to #FixTF2.”</p><p>Team Fortress 2 is one of the oldest actively supported video games on the market, and remains popular enough to place within the top 10 games on Steam based on concurrent player numbers. However, some players have said this active player count is misleading, with cheater bots filling servers instead. Idle bots, meanwhile, farm Team Fortress 2 for free item drops. Some believe Team Fortress 2 has tens of thousands of bots idling in private servers, contributing towards the impressive player count on Steam.</p><p>Frustrating the Team Fortress 2 player base further is the apparent silence from Valve over the issue. The company continues to support the game with events, the latest of which ends on June 30, tournaments, and bug fixes. In April, <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/valve-updates-team-fortress-2-to-64-bit-boosting-performance-of-the-17-year-old-fps">Valve updated Team Fortress 2 to finally add 64-bit support</a>. But there is no fresh word on the bot problem from the company.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>"For the past five years, Team Fortress 2 has become nearly unplayable.</p></div><p>The community has organized an online #FIXTF2 campaign and set up a <a href="https://save.tf/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">website</a> that includes a petition with nearly 200,000 signatures. “For the past five years, Team Fortress 2 has become nearly unplayable,” the campaign website reads. “The game’s official servers have been overrun by hordes of cheating aimbots while Valve has remained steadfast in their refusal to adequately tackle the problem. This lack of developer interference has thrown the game into a state of turmoil with seemingly no end in sight.</p><p>“Despite being aware of the bot crisis, Valve has instead directed their focus towards other ventures, leaving TF2 with insufficient support in its grave time of need. From the outside, Valve appears to be more concerned with generating millions in revenue every month via in-game microtransactions, rather than maintaining a product that should work as expected.</p><p>“There’s no putting it lightly, Team Fortress 2 is in an unacceptable state, and Valve’s apathy in dealing with the issue is nothing short of appalling.”</p><p>Valve currently operates Steam, the Steam Deck handheld, various virtual reality initiatives, and on the video game front competitive shooter Counter-Strike 2, MOBA Dota 2, as well as the Half-Life, Team Fortress, and Left 4 Dead franchises. Valve is reportedly working on a brand new MOBA shooter called <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/deadlock-rumored-title">Deadlock</a>, which it has yet to announce but has suffered significant leaks in recent weeks.</p><p><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Test Drive Unlimited Solar Crown Preview – the first truly social racer?]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/06/04/test-drive-unlimited-solar-crown-preview-the-first-truly-social-racer/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/test-drive-unlimited-solar-crown-preview-%E2%80%93-the-first-truly-social-racer.888927/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/06/04/test-drive-unlimited-solar-crown-preview-the-first-truly-social-racer/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
			
			<p>With a freshly announced <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/05/30/test-drive-unlimited-solar-crown-release-date-confirmed-for-september/">release date in September</a>, the long wait for a new Test Drive Unlimited is coming to an end. Test Drive Unlimited Solar Crown will invite players to visit Hong Kong Island for a unique driving and racing experience.</p>
<p><iframe title="Test Drive Unlimited Solar Crown - Release Date Trailer | PS5 Games" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8GUCrMPJgkE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>You see, Solar Crown is as much about the racing as it is the social aspects. Most racing games only give a cursory nod to your avatar’s customisation with a bundle of race suits to wear, but Solar Crown doesn’t just let you change how you look when in the cockpit and on the podium, it invites you to step out of the car at various times. There’s the lobby of the Solar Hotel – a fictional spire built into the real-world setting – and there’s both open and private areas to the hubs for the Streets and the Sharps, the two rival car racing gangs of the city. You’ll even walk around car dealerships, the workshop where you can upgrade your car, and more.</p>


<p>Starting by picking a Nissan 370Z as my starter car, the handling is fun and accessible by default. Of course, racing game experts will want to switch to having fewer assists, letting more of a car’s natural tendencies come through as you push it to the ragged edge in a race. KT Racing promise individualised handling and characteristics for all of the more than 100 cars that will be in the game at launch, and I look forward to more time with the game to see how they’ve pulled this off.</p>
<p>After picking that first car, though, players will have to be willing to embrace a tangibly slower pace to the progression. Where modern Forza Horizon games will fling so many cars at you to the point that they become almost meaningless, Solar Crown wants to make everything feel earned and desirable. Getting a new car should be exciting, it should be something that you want to drive and master, to upgrade to the max over time as you look to rise up the rankings and the leaderboards.</p>


<p>Through upgrades, parts changes, and driving presets, cars will be adaptable. Of course, you can soup things up to become a street racing demon with slicker tyres, engine upgrades and more, but there’s plenty of off-road areas to explore on Hong Kong Island, and you could make that street car happier on gravel and dirt paths. Alternatively, save up and buy a truck or SUV, which can handle the bumpy uneven terrain much more easily.</p>
<p>Of course, modern gaming sensibilities have shifted over the last 15 years, and so KT Racing has a tightrope to walk to make Solar Crown still feel rewarding to those used to more instantaneous gratification. While they want you to play for many, many hours to earn enough cash to buy a Pagani Zonda, for example, they won’t gate-keep the applicable hypercar races quite so hard, with a lower-priced option available to take part while you save up. And there will also be car-specific events, such as the race we encountered that demanded we first go and grab a cheap and cheerful 500 Abarth to take part.</p>
<p>While you might have to wait to take a car into competition or to show off to your friends that you’ve managed to buy it, that doesn’t mean you can’t try it out. At any time you can visit one of the various opulent car dealerships, each dedicated to a particular country or region, and test drive one of the cars they have there – it’s in the title, after all. This gives you a tight two-minute window to see what a car is all about, and see if it’s actually the car you want to save up for and buy.</p>

<p>One gaming trend that Solar Crown <em>is</em> following is the shift to always online shared spaces and seasons of live content. For one thing, each race you look to take part in is preceded by some matchmaking to try and combine AI with real racers, and there will be other players doing their own thing on the island as you roam, or in the social areas that you wander around with your avatar. Each season will have a competition for players to take part in, looking to rise up the ranks from bronze, silver and up through to the Solar Court, which grants access to a special featured car – an ultimate flex to demonstrate their racing prowess. The very best player will be crowned as the Solar King or Solar Queen – one per region and per platform.</p>
<p>KT Racing has been inviting a select few fans and community members to check out the game and give feedback over the past year, and that’s led to some tweaks and changes that will be ready for the game’s launch. A much-requested feature, you will now have a personal garage space that lets you view up to six of your cars, inspect them in private and get in physically before choosing to join the open world – the slightest disappointment is that you can’t drive out of the garage at this point. For this demo, it also felt like the game was just a little bit too restrained early on, forcing me to repeat races and hunt down speed traps to earn the experience needed to level up and unlock both car upgrades and a new set of races. Our demo wasn’t that of the full game, but getting the early game flow right is the high-wire act that KT Racing will have to get just right for the final release.</p>

<p>On the whole, I feel that Test Drive Unlimited Solar Crown is coming together rather well. There’s so many more individual touches that show the different attitude and tone that it has to other open-world racing games, which will make it a breath of fresh air compared to the competition. I can’t wait to revisit Hong Kong Island in just a few months time.</p>


<!-- AI CONTENT END 1 -->

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The gorgeous Dungeons of Hinterberg getting a demo this week]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/the-gorgeous-dungeons-of-hinterberg-getting-a-demo-this-week</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-gorgeous-dungeons-of-hinterberg-getting-a-demo-this-week.888924/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/the-gorgeous-dungeons-of-hinterberg-getting-a-demo-this-week<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Dungeons-of-Hinterberg_jJfy4Xi.jpg?width=1200&amp;height=1200&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Microbird Games</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
The Dungeons of Hinterberg team has announced a demo for its upcoming Austrian-based Zelda-like adventure.
</p>
<p>
This demo will allow players to explore dungeons - including one described as "gravity-defying" - visit the Glacier Overworld and meet new characters during a full in-game day cycle.
</p>
<p>
The game's first playable demo will go live later this week, on 8th June, over on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1983260/Dungeons_of_Hinterberg/">Steam</a>, where you can also add it to your wishlist.
</p>
<figure>
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<figcaption>Dungeons of Hinterberg launches 18th July.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GqR5xbRUoe8" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>
Dungeons of Hinterberg has caught the attention of many members of the Eurogamer team. After taking part in a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/dungeons-of-hinterberg-has-stolen-my-heart">hands-off demo at Summer Games Fest</a> last year, our Chris Tapsell already felt the game looked "brilliant". He then managed to actually go <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/what-weve-been-playing-indie-preview-special-edition">hands-on with it earlier this year at GDC</a>, and his praise remained. "This game plays like a dream vacation - it's a delight," he wrote. 
</p>
<p>
These feelings were echoed by our Donlan, who has also been hands on with Dungeons of Hinterberg already. In his feature <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/dungeons-of-hinterberg-is-about-a-holiday-which-is-why-everything-feels-so-important">Dungeons of Hinterberg is about a holiday - which is why everything feels so important</a>, he expressed his delight at the game's art style, puzzles and world.
</p>
<p>
"There are hubs and areas to explore dotted with fast travel, but while I love uncovering treasure chests and new dungeons, there's a pleasure found purely in the fiction of where you are," he wrote. "Yesterday I climbed a hill and found a little restaurant at the top. It meant far more to me than any RPG trinket would. I took lots of screenshots and felt like I was on holiday, like I was exploring a place that I wouldn't get to stay in long term, and so I had to make the most of it. Wonderful stuff."
</p>
<p>
<a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/austrian-zelda-like-dungeons-of-hinterberg-gets-release-date">Dungeons of Hinterberg is set for full release next month</a>, on 18th July. It will be available across Xbox Series X/S and Steam, including a day one release on Game Pass.

</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Yakuza TV show is coming out on Amazon Prime in October]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-yakuza-tv-show-is-coming-out-on-amazon-prime-in-october</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-yakuza-tv-show-is-coming-out-on-amazon-prime-in-october.888921/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-yakuza-tv-show-is-coming-out-on-amazon-prime-in-october<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>



            <p>Amazon will air a live-action TV series based on Sega's <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/video-game-franchises/yakuza">Yakuza</a> games in October this year, says the streaming service. Like A Dragon: Yakuza will be a six-part series following characters in the criminal underbelly of Kamurocho, set to straddle between two time periods: 1995 and 2005. The series "showcases modern Japan and the dramatic stories of these intense characters, such as the legendary Kazuma Kiryu, that games in the past have not been able to explore,” said Amazon, who are releasing it through Prime Video, just like their <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/well-whaddya-know-therell-officially-be-a-season-two-of-amazons-very-popular-fallout-tv-show">Fallout series</a>.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>Exactly what the plot of the show will be remains to be seen. But it will follow "the life, childhood friends and the repercussions of the decisions of a fearsome and peerless Yakuza warrior with a strong sense of justice, duty, and humanity," according to <a href="https://variety.com/2024/tv/news/like-a-dragon-yakuza-live-action-series-sega-game-prime-video-1236024275/">Variety</a>. That sounds like our boy Kiryu for sure. </p>
<p>Work on the TV show was first announced <a href="https://variety.com/2020/film/news/yakuza-movie-sega-video-game-1234781210/">back in 2020</a>. And word later came out about the <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/yakuzagames/comments/14lfd0z/ryoma_takeuchi_and_kento_kaku_to_play_kiryu_and/">actors and directors</a> involved. Hard-punching bastion of justice Kiryu Kazama will be played by Ryoma Takeuchi, for example, who played the protagonist in Kamen Rider Drive. I've not seen any Kamen Rider, so I'm not qualified to tell you if this actor is good at channelling the indignant stiffness of a deeply annoyed statue. But that is what is required of him.</p>
<p>The series is being directed by Take Masaharu and Takimoto Kengo, and the original writer of the first game's script, Masayoshi Yokoyama, is on board as an executive producer. He suggests he was reluctant at first but decided to get involved. “Since the day I first put pen to paper on the original Yakuza‘s script," he said, "I’ve never once thought about revisiting any of my work on the series. It’s because I understand all too well the challenges and hardships that come with remaking a finished title. However, if I were ever sent to the past through some kind of cosmic joke, this is the experience I’d want to create.”</p>
<p>We are quite fond of the Yakuza series here in the treehouse. Ed was into <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/like-a-dragon-infinite-wealth">Like A Dragon: Infinite Wealth</a> when it came out earlier this year. "It's a wonderful, happy <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/spawn-point-the-best-jrpgs-for-total-beginners">JRPG</a> and it will never fail to brighten my day," he said in <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/like-a-dragon-infinite-wealth-review">his review</a>. "Thank goodness for Yakuza."</p>
<p>One of my favourite scenes in Yakuza is when Kiryu sees some chumps <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Gl25uwGLATc">throwing rocks at a puppy</a>. The father figure of Tokyo catches a rock in mid-air, inches from the dog's face. Then proceeds to destroy the goons in the only way he knows how. If the TV show adapts this one scene, I will be satisfied.</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Crash Team Racing “Modded” Version Now Supports Online Multiplayer Mode and PC Compatibility]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/crash-team-racing-modded-version-now-supports-online-multiplayer-mode-and-pc-compatibility/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/crash-team-racing-%E2%80%9Cmodded%E2%80%9D-version-now-supports-online-multiplayer-mode-and-pc-compatibility.888918/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/crash-team-racing-modded-version-now-supports-online-multiplayer-mode-and-pc-compatibility/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Well, a modding team has done something intriguing to witness as they integrate multiplayer and PC compatibility into the original Crash Team Racing.</p>
<p>It's surprising what the modding community can do for titles, especially when it comes to reviving them and adding new features. The latest project by a modding team focuses on bringing an online mode into the game. In a demo of the title, the players in the actual game were connected through a worldwide network, with each player in a completely different country. Surprisingly, there weren't any sort of latency issues, and the game ran perfectly.</p>
<p><iframe title="OnlineCTR - The PS1 Crash Team Racing Online Experience (Launch Trailer)" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Fxhz0EMHlCE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Apart from the online play mode, the modded Crash Team Racing also supports "unofficial" compatibility with the PC platform, and the modding team utilizes DuckStation, the PS1 emulator, to do so. Moreover, the title runs at a stable 60 FPS, ensuring smooth gameplay despite being a "tuned" version of a game that was released almost two decades ago. In terms of the experience itself, the modded title allows you to pair up with up to 8 players with multiple tracks and characters similar to the original game.</p>
<p>Well, if you are interested in checking out "Online Crash Team Racing," you can visit the dedicated website <a href="https://www.online-ctr.com/">here</a>. In&nbsp;order to play it on PC, you'll need to have the DuckStation emulator installed as well. Playing the title is a nostalgic experience, and with the multiplayer feature, it's definitely worth trying out.</p>
<p>PC players might be especially interested since they were unfortunately left out of <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/crash-team-racing-nitro-fueled/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Crash Team Racing Nitro-Fueled</a>, the remastered version launched in 2019 for PlayStation 4, Xbox One, and Nintendo Switch.</p>

			<p>News Source: <a href="https://www.dsogaming.com/news/modders-bring-crash-team-racing-to-pc-with-60fps-and-online-multiplayer-support/" target="_blank">DSOGaming</a></p>	

			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[League of Legends Patch 14.12 – Details, Release Date and What to Expect]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/league-of-legends-14-12/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/league-of-legends-patch-14-12-%E2%80%93-details-release-date-and-what-to-expect.888915/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/league-of-legends-14-12/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>League of Legends Patch 14.12 is scheduled to go live on June 12, 2024, marking the halfway point for the 24 planned patches throughout the year.</p>



<p>Patch 14.12 is said to focus on metagame balance, meaning that many of the game’s champions should see some significant changes. First, it should be mentioned that some of these details are subject to change as they are currently being tested in the League of Legends PBE staging realm, but generally, they will be the changes coming to the game.</p>



<h2 id="h-patch-14-12-changes">Patch 14.12 Changes</h2>



<h3 id="h-champion-changes">Champion Changes</h3>



<h4 id="h-aatrox">Aatrox</h4>



<p><strong>Base Stats</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Health regen growth reduced: 1.0 &gt;&gt;&gt; 0.5</li>



<li>Armor growth increased: 4.45 &gt;&gt;&gt; 4.8</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>E: Umbral Dash</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Healing changed: 18-24% &gt;&gt;&gt; 16%</li>



<li>Healing now scales with 0.9% bonus HP</li>



<li>Healing is no longer increased to 20-36% during R</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>R: World Ender</strong></p>



<ul>
<li><s>Bonus healing increased: 40-80% &gt;&gt;&gt; 50-100% (25-45% live)</s></li>



<li><s>Bonus AD reduced: 20-45% &gt;&gt;&gt; 20-40%</s></li>
</ul>



<h4 id="h-akali">Akali</h4>



<p><strong>Base Stats</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Base MR reduced: 37 &gt;&gt;&gt; 32</li>
</ul>



<h4 id="h-akshan">Akshan</h4>



<p><strong>Passive: Dirty Fighting</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Base damage changed: 10-165 &gt;&gt;&gt; 15-150</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>E: Heroic Swing</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Base damage reduced: 25-85 &gt;&gt;&gt; 15-75</li>



<li>AD ratio changed: 17.5% bonus AD &gt;&gt;&gt; 15% total AD</li>
</ul>



<h4 id="h-corki">Corki</h4>



<p><strong>Base Stats</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Base AD reduced: 55 &gt;&gt;&gt; 52</li>



<li>Attack speed growth increased: 2.3% &gt;&gt;&gt; 2.8%</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Q: Phosphorous Bomb</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Base damage increased: 50-250 &gt;&gt;&gt; 70-270</li>



<li>AP ratio increased: 70% &gt;&gt;&gt; 100%</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>E: Gatling Gun</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Base damage reduced: 100-300 &gt;&gt;&gt; 100-280</li>



<li>Resist reduction reduced: 12-24 &gt;&gt;&gt; 12-20</li>
</ul>



<h4 id="h-naafiri">Naafiri</h4>



<p><strong>Passive: We Are More</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Packmate’s base AD increased: 6-30 &gt;&gt;&gt; 12-32</li>



<li>Pacckmate’s bonus AD ratio increased: 4.5% &gt;&gt;&gt; 5%</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Q: Darkin Daggers</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Cooldown reduced: 11-7 seconds &gt;&gt;&gt; 9-7 seconds</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>E: Eviscerate</strong></p>



<ul>
<li><s>Cooldown reduced: 10-8 seconds &gt;&gt;&gt; 8 seconds flat</s></li>
</ul>



<h4 id="h-skarner">Skarner</h4>



<p><strong>Base Stats</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Base health reduced: 650 &gt;&gt;&gt; 610</li>



<li>Health growth increased: 102 &gt;&gt;&gt; 105</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Passive: Threads of Vibration</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Health damage changed: 7-10% max HP &gt;&gt;&gt; 5-11% max HP</li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-items">Items</h3>



<h4 id="h-lord-dominik-s-regards">Lord Dominik’s Regards</h4>



<ul>
<li>Cloak of Agility replaced by Noonquiver in recipe</li>
</ul>



<h4 id="h-noonquiver">Noonquiver</h4>



<ul>
<li>Additional Long Sword added to recipe, cost unchanged</li>



<li>AD reduced: 25 &gt;&gt;&gt; 20</li>
</ul>



<h4 id="h-scout-s-slingshot">Scout’s Slingshot</h4>



<ul>
<li>Second Dagger added to recipe</li>



<li>Cost reduced: 900 &gt;&gt;&gt; 800</li>
</ul>



<h4 id="h-statikk-shiv">Statikk Shiv</h4>



<ul>
<li>Pickaxe added to recipe, cost unchanged</li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-runes">Runes</h3>



<h4 id="h-first-strike">First Strike</h4>



<ul>
<li>Base gold reduced: 15 &gt;&gt;&gt; 10</li>
</ul>



<h2 id="h-when-does-lol-patch-14-12-go-live">When Does LoL Patch 14.12 Go Live?</h2>



<p>League of Legends patch 14.12 is set to go live on June 12, 2024. Here are the times for the update:</p>



<ul>
<li>3 AM PT (NA)</li>



<li>5 AM GMT (EUW)</li>



<li>3 AM CET (EUNE)</li>



<li>8 AM KST (Korea)</li>
</ul>



<p>What do you think of League of Legends 14.12? Let us know in the comments below!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read&nbsp;about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/game-reward-ending-shut-down/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">GAME shutting down its reward scheme</a>, and don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/newsletter/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">subscribe to the Insider Gaming Newsletter</a>.</p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Prime Video announce Like a Dragon: Yakuza, arriving this October]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/06/04/prime-video-announce-like-a-dragon-yakuza-arriving-this-october/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/prime-video-announce-like-a-dragon-yakuza-arriving-this-october.888912/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/06/04/prime-video-announce-like-a-dragon-yakuza-arriving-this-october/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Amazon’s Prime Video is following up their smash hit Fallout series with another video game adaption based on Sega’s Yakuza series. Because reasons the title has been reversed and the series is call Like a Dragon: Yakuza, rather than Yakuza: Like a Dragon which is the title of the 2020 video game.</p>
<p>There series will span six episodes and is a crime drama directed by Take Masaharu (“100 Yen Love”) and Takimoto Kengo (“Kamen Teacher”) and Takeuchi Ryoma will star as Kiryu Kazuma.</p>


<p>“The series’ story is set in two time periods, 1995 and 2005, and follows the life, childhood friends and the repercussions of the decisions of a fearsome and peerless Yakuza warrior with a strong sense of justice, duty, and humanity,” say Amazon.</p>

<p>“I have poured out my heart, soul, and the experience that I have garnered over 35 years into ‘Like a Dragon: Yakuza’,” said director Take.</p>

<p>“The unfettered appeal for Japanese content from within Japan and other parts of the world has been growing exponentially. While Prime Video Japan continues to offer a variety of content across genres, adapting an internationally popular game franchise that has such deep resonance and layered characters presents a unique charm and makes for an extremely compelling watch,” said James Farrell, head of international originals, Amazon MGM Studios.</p>
<p>There series will be released in two batches of three episodes with the first landing on October 25th 2024 and the remaining episodes following a week later on November 1st.&nbsp; It’s not explicitly stated but it seems this will be a Japanese langauge series but will come with subtitles and dubs for over thirty languages.</p>
<hr>
<h3>Yakuza: Like a Dragon Guides &amp; more from TheSixthAxis</h3>
<ul>
<li>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2020/11/04/yakuza-like-a-dragon-review/">Yakuza: Like a Dragon Review</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2020/11/06/yakuza-games-best-worst-ranking-like-a-dragon/">Every Yakuza game ranked from worst to best</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2020/11/11/yakuza-like-a-dragon-quick-xp-and-levelling-guide/">Yakuza: Like a Dragon – quick XP and levelling guide</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/?p=368990&amp;preview=true">Yakuza: Like a Dragon – how to improve friendship bonds</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/?p=368742&amp;preview=true">Yakuza: Like a Dragon – all mini-games and where to find them</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/?p=368665&amp;preview=true">Yakuza: Like a Dragon starting jobs guide</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/?p=368667&amp;preview=true">Yakuza: Like a Dragon – all female jobs and skills</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/?p=368670&amp;preview=true">Yakuza: Like a Dragon – all male jobs and skills</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/?p=368761&amp;preview=true">Yakuza: Like a Dragon – find all Kappa Statues</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/?p=368731&amp;preview=true">Yakuza: Like a Dragon – find all Missing Cats</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2020/11/08/tokyo-in-video-games-yakuza-persona/">Tokyo in video games: a brief history</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://variety.com/2024/tv/news/like-a-dragon-yakuza-live-action-series-sega-game-prime-video-1236024275/">Variety</a></em></p>


<!-- AI CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Final Fantasy 9 Remake Development is “Very Far Along”, Leaker Claims; Said to be a Multi-platform Title]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/final-fantasy-9-remake-development-is-very-far-along-leaker-claims-said-to-be-a-multi-platform-title/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/final-fantasy-9-remake-development-is-%E2%80%9Cvery-far-along%E2%80%9D-leaker-claims-said-to-be-a-multi-platform-title.888909/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/final-fantasy-9-remake-development-is-very-far-along-leaker-claims-said-to-be-a-multi-platform-title/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Development on the rumored Final Fantasy 9 Remake is progressing well, and Square Enix might very well release the game before April 2025.</p>
<p>At least, that's what known SEGA/Atlus leaker 'Midori' said on X some hours ago. Last month, after <a href="https://wccftech.com/final-fantasy-ix-remake-faithful-modest-budget/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">various claims</a> from other leakers, 'Midori' <a href="https://wccftech.com/final-fantasy-ix-remake-is-happening-confirms-leaker-unlike-ffx/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">said</a> that the remake is indeed happening. No additional details were shared last month, but the leaker (known for his SEGA/Atlus leaks), has now provided more information about the remake. According to 'Midori', the remake was initially outsourced to a different development, but development has shifted as publisher Square Enix wasn't satisfied. Although the leaker can't confirm a release date for the remake, development on the title is now "very far along", and could be released before the end of Square Enix's current fiscal year (which runs through March 31, 2025).</p>
<p>"According to conversations, the title was originally outsourced to another developer, but SQEX was not satisfied and development shifted", the leaker wrote on X.</p>
<p>'Midori' <a href="https://x.com/MbKKssTBhz5/status/1797838848011227419" target="_blank" rel="noopener">added</a>, "Development of this title is now very far along, but I do not have any firm information on the scope of this title or a firm release period right now. This title could release before the end of this fiscal year, but I am not certain right now."</p>
<p>While it's possible that Final Fantasy 9 Remake, which is said to be released as a multi-platform title, will be present at the Xbox Showcase this Sunday, the leaker advises to keep expectations in check as he isn't sure that this is the case.</p>
<div data-md="221" data-hveid="CBEQAA" data-ved="2ahUKEwiOsYbV1sGGAxUA_rsIHWaCDK8QnKEBKAB6BAgWEAA">
<p>"There are plans for new information on some SQEX titles at the Xbox Showcase. I don’t know if this title will be at the showcase. So it is good to keep expectations low right now. And this is a title that is currently planned for release on multiple platforms", the leaker also said on X.</p>
</div>

<p>Personally, we would love to see a remake of 2000's Final Fantasy 9, which was released for the original PlayStation, and is considered one of the best entries in the franchise.</p>

				

			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This Kar98k Warzone attachment makes hip fire 100% accurate, but there’s a catch]]></title>
            <link>https://www.destructoid.com/this-kar98k-warzone-attachment-makes-hip-fire-100-accurate-but-theres-a-catch/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=this-kar98k-warzone-attachment-makes-hip-fire-100-accurate-but-theres-a-catch</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/this-kar98k-warzone-attachment-makes-hip-fire-100-accurate-but-there%E2%80%99s-a-catch.888906/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.destructoid.com/this-kar98k-warzone-attachment-makes-hip-fire-100-accurate-but-theres-a-catch/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=this-kar98k-warzone-attachment-makes-hip-fire-100-accurate-but-theres-a-catch<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p data-characters="253" data-injectable="true" data-video="true">When you think of shooting accurately with a sniper rifle, you automatically think about scoping in, steadying your scope, and firing. If you use this <em>Warzone</em> attachment, however, you can hit perfect shots without aiming down the sight of your Kar98kn. </p> <p data-characters="196" data-current-count="196" data-injectable="false">As shown in a video by SkillIssue– on Reddit, adding the CS15 Scarlet Box Laser to your <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/best-kar98k-loadout-in-mw3-warzone/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Kar98k</a> makes it incredibly accurate when hipfiring, downing enemies with one shot even at long range. </p> <figure data-current-count="496" data-injectable="true"></figure>
 <p data-characters="304" data-current-count="304" data-injectable="false">Unfortunately, this does come with a little bit of a catch, as you need to be standing completely still to get the incredible advantage that this attachment provides. Still, if you can take the time to stop and line up your shot, it will hit it with mindboggling accuracy and could be very, very useful. </p> <p data-characters="224" data-current-count="528" data-injectable="true">Of course, the downside to standing still is that you’re an easier target to hit, as a moving target requires good aim and some tracking. In this case, just make sure you get your shot off first, and you should be ok. </p>
 <p data-characters="389" data-current-count="389" data-injectable="false">This news comes off the back of the revelation that the <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/secret-buff-in-warzone-season-4-makes-the-crossbow-a-must-use-one-shot-kill-weapon/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Crossbow is not a one-shot down</a> anywhere on the body, making it incredibly powerful too. With this pair of one-shot weapons, you may find yourself dropping a lot more often than you were before. We’ve included SkillIssue’s Kar98k loadout below, and you can also check out our <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/best-warzone-crossbow-loadout-class-and-attachments/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Crossbow loadout</a> if you fancy trying it out. </p> <h2 id="h-warzone-kar98k-hip-fire-loadout" data-injectable="false"><em>Warzone</em> Kar98k hip-fire loadout</h2> <ul data-found-items="5" data-current-count="589" data-injectable="false"> <li><strong>Muzzle: </strong>Sonic Suppressor</li> <li><strong>Barrel: </strong>Prazisionsgewehr&nbsp;762 Long Barrel</li> <li><strong>Laser: </strong>CS15 Scarlet Box</li> <li><strong>Stock: </strong>No Stock</li> <li><strong>Ammunition: </strong>7.92 High Grain Rounds</li> </ul>
<hr>
<p><i data-stringify-type="italic"> Destructoid is supported by our audience. When you purchase through links on our site, we may earn a small affiliate commission.&nbsp;</i><i data-stringify-type="italic"><a href="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-stringify-link="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" data-sk="tooltip_parent">Learn more</a></i> </p>

</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Like A Dragon: Yakuza TV series on Amazon Prime later this year]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/like-a-dragon-yakuza-tv-series-on-amazon-prime-later-this-year</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/like-a-dragon-yakuza-tv-series-on-amazon-prime-later-this-year.888903/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/like-a-dragon-yakuza-tv-series-on-amazon-prime-later-this-year<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>



            <p>
Amazon will release a new live-action TV series based on Sega's Yakuza games later this year.
</p>
<p>
Like a Dragon: Yakuza will be exclusive to Prime Video and release globally on 25th October.
</p>
<p>
Japanese actor and model Ryoma Takeuchi (who cameoed in Detective Pikachu, among other roles) will take on the lead role of Kazuma Kiryu, while Masaharu Take (The Naked Director) will direct.
</p>
<figure>
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<figcaption>Like a Dragon: Infinite Wealth opening movie<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=J5_RjgvQQBo" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>
The series will span two time periods - 1995 and 2005 - and will follow "the life, childhood friends, and repercussions of the decisions of Kazuma Kiryu, a fearsome and peerless Yakuza warrior with a strong sense of justice, duty, and humanity". 
</p>
<p>
This hints it'll be, perhaps, based on the first game in the series, which takes place in 2005 following events 10 years before.
</p>
<p>
"I am truly honoured to be given the opportunity to play the role of Kazuma Kiryu, a beloved character and the game series," said Takeuchi. "I strongly felt that I was willing to put my life on the line. Audience will enjoy the show's human drama and conflict that unfolds around Kazuma Kiryu. Moreover, please take a look Kiryu's intense fighting scenes with the Dragon tattoo on his back."
</p>
<p>
Take said he has "poured out [his] heart, soul, and the experience that [he has] garnered over 35 years into Like a Dragon: Yakuza", noting 2024 is fittingly the year of the dragon.
</p>
<p>
"Since the day I first put pen to paper on the original Yakuza's script, I've never once thought about revisiting any of my work on the series," said Masayoshi Yokoyama, head of Ryugagotoku studio and executive producer on the TV series. "It's because I understand all too well the challenges and hardships that come with remaking a finished title. However, if I were ever sent to the past through some kind of cosmic joke, this is the experience I'd want to create."
</p>
<p>
He added: "While the games let you experience their world through the subjective lens, this adaptation will be the ultimately objective way to enjoy the show. I have no doubt that fans of the series will be drawn to how it brings the games to life and adds new surprises."
</p>
<p>
The TV series is yet another indication of the success of the series, which has <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/sega-sammy-reports-best-financial-performance-for-a-decade-despite-european-studio-disappointment">sold 21.3m units in total</a>. The most recent game, this year's <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/like-a-dragon-infinite-wealth-hits-1m-sales-in-first-week">Infinite Wealth, sold 1m units in its first week</a> and was the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/like-a-dragon-infinite-wealth-is-series-biggest-steam-launch-to-date">series' biggest Steam launch ever</a>.



</p>
<p>
Ironically enough, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/yakuza-was-flat-out-rejected-by-sega-in-its-first-proposal-says-series-creator">Sega "flat out rejected" the first proposal for the game</a>, presuming it wouldn't attract mass audiences.

</p>
<p>
Yet the TV series is likely to do just that, especially following the success of Amazon's Fallout series. <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/amazons-fallout-tv-show-was-watched-by-65m-people-in-its-first-two-weeks">Fallout was watched by 65 million people</a> in its first 16 days of release and has already been <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/amazons-fallout-show-officially-renewed-for-second-season">renewed for a second season</a>.



</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Just Cause developer announces layoffs and studio closures, including one office open less than a year]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/just-cause-developer-announces-layoffs-and-studio-closures-including-one-office-open-less-than-a-year</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/just-cause-developer-announces-layoffs-and-studio-closures-including-one-office-open-less-than-a-year.888900/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/just-cause-developer-announces-layoffs-and-studio-closures-including-one-office-open-less-than-a-year<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>



            <p>Just Cause developer Avalanche is shutting two of its five offices, one of which had been open for less than 12 months.</p>
<p>Last night, the company announced it will close down its New York and Montreal studios. As a result of these closures, 50 employees will be laid off, equating to roughly nine percent of Avalanche's overall workforce.</p>
<p>In a <a href="https://avalanchestudios.com/stories/statement-nymr">statement</a> shared on Avalanche's website, the studio called these closures an "exceptionally difficult decision", but one it believed "necessary to ensure a stable and sustainable future for the company".</p>
<figure>
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<figcaption>Is the closure of Hi-Fi Rush and Redfall's studios a sign Xbox Game Pass publishing is failing?<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6Dx4fu4H6us" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>"Our focus is now on supporting all Avalanchers through this challenging time," it continued. "We're grateful for the invaluable contributions of those leaving and remain committed to creating incredible gaming experiences for our players."</p>
<p>Avalanche opened its New York office in <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/avalanche-opens-new-york-studio">2011</a>, while the <a href="https://avalanchestudios.com/stories/avalanche-studios-group-expands-to-montreal">Montreal office only opened in October last year</a>, following the acquisition of Monster Closet Games. At this time, the company called this acquisition "a fantastic way to start our new chapter".</p>
<p>Avalanche is sadly one of many studios to suffer layoffs and closures this year. According to an archive tallying layoffs across the industry, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games-industry-layoffs-surpass-10000-for-2024-so-far">more than 10,000 people have been laid off from their jobs</a> across the video game industry in 2024 alone. Others impacted include <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/microsoft-to-lay-off-1900-people-across-xbox-and-activision-blizzard">Microsoft</a>, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/sony-laying-off-900-playstation-employees-london-studio-to-close-in-its-entirety">Sony</a>, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/square-enix-impacted-by-unknown-number-of-layoffs-across-us-and-european-offices">Square Enix</a>, and this is merely scratching the surface.</p>
<p>
For more on this topic, be sure to read Chris Dring's feature: <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/what-is-going-on-with-the-video-games-industry">What is going on with layoffs in the video games industry?</a></p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox Games Showcase Might Feature a Shadow-Dropped 1st Party Game; Xbox Portable Likely to Be Teased]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/xbox-games-showcase-might-feature-a-shadow-dropped-1st-party-game-xbox-portable-likely-to-be-teased/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/xbox-games-showcase-might-feature-a-shadow-dropped-1st-party-game-xbox-portable-likely-to-be-teased.888897/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/xbox-games-showcase-might-feature-a-shadow-dropped-1st-party-game-xbox-portable-likely-to-be-teased/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>With Sony's State of Play over and a Nintendo Direct possibly coming later this month, all eyes are focused on Microsoft's Xbox Games Showcase, which is slated to go live on Sunday, June 9, at 10 AM Pacific Time.</p>
<p>Speculation is already running rampant among Xbox fans, and today, Spanish leaker eXtas <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mCFmKwQIo0Q" target="_blank" rel="noopener">has added extra fuel with some rumors from his own sources.</a> To start with, he said that a first-party Xbox game will be shadow-dropped during the showcase.</p>
<p>This means it will be released in some capacity right away. It could be a beta, a demo, or a full release. The most likely game to be shadow-dropped is Towerborne, the side-scrolling fantasy action game once known as <a href="https://wccftech.com/xbox-exclusive-project-belfry-2d-action-ghibli-vanillaware/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Project Belfry</a>. Developed by Stoic (the makers of <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/the-banner-saga-3/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The Banner Saga</a>), Towerborne is set in a post-apocalyptic (but colorful) world where the so-called Aces are all that stands between the monsters and the safety of the titular tower.</p>
<p>Players will be able to fight solo with NPC companions or with other players in a group of four. That's also the number of fighting styles available in the game, with unique moves available for War Clubs, Gauntlets, Dual Daggers, and Swords &amp; Shields. The world map will continue to evolve over time with seasonal content to keep players engaged.</p>
<p>eXtas also said that Microsoft might share a teaser about the long-rumored Xbox Portable console. Rumors on Xbox handhelds <a href="https://wccftech.com/xbox-handheld-release-this-year/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">intensified</a> in the last few months, and even Microsoft Gaming CEO Phil Spencer <a href="https://wccftech.com/xbox-handheld-discussed-once-again-by-microsofts-phil-spencer/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">seemed</a> to tease something of the sort in an interview at GDC 2024.</p>
<p>As for the rest of the Xbox Games Showcase, it's worth reminding earlier rumors, such as <a href="https://wccftech.com/doom-the-dark-ages-announcement-rumor-xbox-games-showcase-medieval-world/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DOOM: The Dark Ages</a> from id Software and <a href="https://wccftech.com/gears-6-might-appear-at-xbox-showcase-people-arent-ready-for-how-good-it-looks/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Gears 6</a> from The Coalition. The Perfect Dark reboot, in development at The Initiative and Crystal Dynamics, was also <a href="https://wccftech.com/perfect-dark-will-be-shown-next-month-recent-rumors-might-have-been-outdated-says-insider/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">rumored</a> to be featured at the upcoming show.</p>
<p>Other likely candidates for an appearance include Avowed, Ara: History Untold, Indiana Jones and the Great Circle, and Microsoft Flight Simulator, all of which should get release dates since they are 2024 games. Looking at the 2025 lineup, we might also see Clockwork Revolution, State of Decay 3, South of Midnight, and Fable.</p>

				

			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Expectations for us are high': New PlayStation CEOs outline their vision of the future]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/-expectations-for-us-are-high-new-playstation-ceos-outline-their-vision-of-the-future</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/expectations-for-us-are-high-new-playstation-ceos-outline-their-vision-of-the-future.888894/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/-expectations-for-us-are-high-new-playstation-ceos-outline-their-vision-of-the-future<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Sony Interactive Entertainment's new CEOs have </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://sonyinteractive.com/en/news/blog/an-exciting-future-at-sony-interactive-entertainment/">pitched their vision of the future</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and claim employees must prepare to evolve and adapt in a market increasingly driven by "digital transformation."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">It's a period of significant change at SIE. Former president Jim Ryan has been </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/sony-has-appointed-two-playstation-ceos-to-replace-jim-ryan">replaced by two CEOs</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> in the form of Hermen Hulst and Hideaki Nishino.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The double appointment was part of a broader plan to implement a new, multi-pronged business structure that will see Nishino take charge of SIE Platform Business Group while Hulst oversees SIE Studios Business Group.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">In their new roles, Hulst will be responsible for first-party content development and publishing, while Nishino will lead the teams tasked with creating the experiences and technology within PlayStation products. Third-party publisher and developer relations will also be his responsibility.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Those who survived the </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/sony-reevaluating-playstation-studios-and-cutting-900-jobs">recent layoffs at PlayStation Studios</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> are being asked to usher in a new era of "profitability" and "growth" in a shifting environment that's being shaped by emerging technologies.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="PlayStation leaders hope new structure will foster creativity and drive growth">PlayStation leaders hope new structure will foster creativity and drive growth</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Hulst and Nishino feel the new structure will "foster greater creativity and innovation" as Sony searches for new ways to grow its business, but stressed "expectations for us are high."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Play and storytelling are fundamental to society. People are exploring new ways to interact with games just as the passionate creators within our studios and our development partners craft incredibly rich stories and immersive new ways to play and build communities," reads an email penned by the two CEOs.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"The inspiring technical talent within our engineering teams drive the creation of cutting-edge hardware and services, empowering game developers with the very best tools and ensuring gamers have the very best experiences. We are one SIE and all of us are essential to delivering these amazing experiences and share in our continued success.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Expectations for us are high and we aim to drive improving profitability. Technology has fundamentally changed the way we make and play games and more people are gaming than ever before. Digital transformation has changed the way we engage with our customers and the way we work. We recognize the world is evolving and we must prepare ourselves for growth in this environment."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Both CEOs claim it's an " exciting time" to be making video games and implored staff to continue their journey as "trailblazers" under the Sony banner. They also promised more regular communication between SIE leaders and employees.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Two distinct Business Groups will enable us to have more rigor and clarity across our lines of business as SIE continues to grow and evolve," continues the email. "As we step into our new roles, we will take time to deepen our understanding about various aspects of the business. In the coming weeks you will receive information about a future Town Hall, and moving forward, we plan to communicate with you regularly."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://sonyinteractive.com/en/news/blog/an-exciting-future-at-sony-interactive-entertainment/">You can read the full email on the Sony Interactive website</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author(s)</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">News Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer news editor Chris Kerr is an award-winning journalist and reporter with over a decade of experience in the game industry. His byline has appeared in notable print and digital publications including Edge, Stuff, Wireframe, International Business Times, and&nbsp;</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="http://pocketgamer.biz/">PocketGamer.biz</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. Throughout his career, Chris has covered major industry events including GDC, PAX Australia, Gamescom, Paris Games Week, and Develop Brighton. He has featured on the judging panel at The Develop Star Awards on multiple occasions and appeared on BBC Radio 5 Live to discuss breaking news.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tactical Breach Wizards is refreshingly unlike XCOM despite wearing the same tactical underwear]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/tactical-breach-wizards-is-refreshingly-unlike-xcom-despite-wearing-the-same-tactical-underwear</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/tactical-breach-wizards-is-refreshingly-unlike-xcom-despite-wearing-the-same-tactical-underwear.888888/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/tactical-breach-wizards-is-refreshingly-unlike-xcom-despite-wearing-the-same-tactical-underwear<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/tactical-breach-wizards-wishlisted-2024-1.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Suspicious Developments</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            
<p>We’ll never know exactly what sort of fiction Tom Clancy would have written if he was less interested in the calibre of specific bullets and their effiency at dismantling burgeoning socialist governments, and more so in the specific sigils required to blast a riot cop through a third story window. While charity shops across the land mourn this devasting loss to their paperback shelves to this very day, we do at least have a glimpse into what such a literary venture may have looked like. Oh, did you like that door? Was it your <em>favourite</em> door? Soz, pal. <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-best-strategy-games-on-pc">Strategy</a> game <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/tactical-breach-wizards">Tactical Breach Wizards</a> just hexed right through it with a new demo as part of Steam Next Fest. I’ve played it, and it’s very exciting stuff, not least for how differently it plays than what I’d expected.</p>

<p>Tactical Breach Wizards comes from Suspicious Developments, founded by former game journo and RPS contributor <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/authors/tom-francis">Tom Francis</a>. All these disclaimers are enough to make me hopeful that someone will someday pay me, Nic Reuben, to write the legally distinct Little Shop Of Horrors management sim of my dreams, but I digress (call me). The studio’s previous work includes <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/gunpoint">Gunpoint</a> and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/heat-signature">Heat Signature</a>. Both are well-loved, but thankfully, neither look to infringe on my concept for the legally distinct Little Shop Of Horrors management sim of my dreams (call me.)</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Tactical Breach Wizards gameplay trailer - Act 2" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/1hlPsGeUdcs?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Tactical Breach Wizards gameplay trailer - Act 2</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/1hlPsGeUdcs?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/1hlPsGeUdcs?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1hlPsGeUdcs" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>The first thing I’d like to make absolutely clear about Tee-Bee-Dubs, if only for my past self who tends to form unwieldy assumptions based on singular screenshots, is that it has nothing to do with <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/xcom-enemy-unknown">XCOM</a> 2012 or its progeny. Ok, so ‘nothing to do’ might be a bit of a stretch. It still offers turn-based, grid-aligned tactics. Your team still boasts contrasting and complimentary skills. Also, there’s still cover, although you have to actively duck behind it. In terms of how it actually feels to play, though, it’s miles away from XCOM’s lengthy, ultra-deadly skirmishes of attrition. I’m using XCOM as an example here, but Wizard’s sleekly designed, eminently solvable, room-by-room discrete puzzles mean it stands proudly and refreshingly apart from the glut of XCOM’s grandkids we’ve had in the intervening…12 years! If anyone needs me I’ll be reconstituting myself from the salt sachet of dust I currently reside in.</p>
<figure>

</figure>
<p>Here, you’re less concerned about a stray Muton headbutting your beloved sniper to death (I have played other tactics games I swear), and more about cleanly and efficiently solving whatever configuration of bastards and windows the current room throws at you, in as few moves as possible. Any actions taken are effectively just plans, as you can both redo turns and scry possible enemy responses. You don’t commit to things until you thwack that end turn button like you’re furiously wishlisting the legally distinct Little Shop Of Horrors management sim of my dreams (call me.) All this is just a taster to the main event, though. An amuse-bouche to the amusement of boofing bods rudely out of windows.</p>
<p>You know you’re in for a cracking time when, alongside scores for speed and efficiency, the results screen bookending each room tallies up your total, and I quote, defenestrations. In TBW’s implied quest to throw absolutely everything that breathes through glass, some abilities are more efficient than others, but even basic attacks all feature some sort of knockback. And, wouldn’t you know it, these compact room-levels are effectively just window delivery systems. When a room has no windows, you know Mr. Francis is incredibly serious. I’m not yet sure from the chunk of demo I played if there’s any evolution on these currently windows-only environmental hazards, but that’d be neat, wouldn’t it? Not that I don’t like windows. I would have had to quickly abandon the game in disgust if I didn’t.</p>
<p>There will be some evolutions though, no doubt. Each level gives you a chance to flesh out the skills of your wizards with perk points. There’s a host of other lovely details I’d like to quickly cram in, right down to the incredibly minor. The graphics settings have cute names like ‘practical peach blizzards’ and such. The bit on the menu screen for patch notes currently says ‘fixed: demo didn’t exist’. I love this sort of thing. It’s the kind of minor attention to detail that promises similar love elsewhere, nice little pre-gags to warm you up, like arriving at the pub to find there’s a shot already waiting for you on the bar. It’s also just a very funny game in general, although there’s plenty of hints towards a more involved story as your progress. At this point, it’d take a serious hex to stop me diving into the full game when it releases, as if by magic, at some unspecified point in the future. Hopefully, sooner than the legally distinct Little Shop Of Horrors management sim of my dreams (call me.)</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Content Warning has sold 2.2 million units | News-in-brief]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamesindustry.biz/content-warning-has-sold-22-million-units-news-in-bref</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/content-warning-has-sold-2-2-million-units-news-in-brief.888885/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamesindustry.biz/content-warning-has-sold-22-million-units-news-in-bref<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>


<p>The resource for people who make and sell games.</p>

  

  <p>GamesIndustry.biz is owned by Gamer Network Limited.</p>
  <p>© 2024 Gamer Network Limited, 1-6 Grand Parade, Brighton, BN2 9QB, United Kingdom. Registered under company number 03882481.</p>
  <p>All rights reserved. No part of this website or its content may be reproduced without the copyright owner's permission.</p>


  <nav>
    <ul>
          <li>
            


    <a href="https://www.facebook.com/gamesindustry" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-icon="facebook" data-type="facebook" aria-label="Check us out on Facebook">
          <span role="img" aria-label="Check us out on Facebook"></span>

    </a>

          </li>
          <li>
            


    <a href="https://twitter.com/GIBiz" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-icon="x-twitter" data-type="twitter" aria-label="Check us out on X">
          <span role="img" aria-label="Check us out on X"></span>

    </a>

          </li>
          <li>
            


    <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/gamesindustrybiz" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-icon="linkedin" data-type="linkedin" aria-label="Check us out on LinkedIn">
          <span role="img" aria-label="Check us out on LinkedIn"></span>

    </a>

          </li>
          <li>
            


    <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/feed" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-icon="rss" data-type="rss" aria-label="Subscribe to our RSS feed" type="application/rss+xml">
          <span role="img" aria-label="Subscribe to our RSS feed"></span>

    </a>

          </li>
          <li>
            


    <a href="https://mastodon.social/@GIbiz" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-icon="mastodon" data-type="mastodon" aria-label="Check us out on Mastodon">
          <span role="img" aria-label="Check us out on Mastodon"></span>

    </a>

          </li>
    </ul>
  </nav>
      </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Worldwalker Games goes into hibernation]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamesindustry.biz/worldwalker-games-goes-into-hibernation</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/worldwalker-games-goes-into-hibernation.888882/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamesindustry.biz/worldwalker-games-goes-into-hibernation<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        

        <p>"Nobody is shutting us down. We are going into hibernation because we are done with this project," clarified co-owner Nate Austin</p>

    </div><div>



            <p>Wildermyth developer Worldwalker Games will be on a hiatus for the foreseeable future.</p>
<p>In a post shared on <a href="https://x.com/wildermyth/status/1795872859232813087">social media</a>, the studio's co-owner Nate Austin shared that active development on the 2021 RPG is now complete and players shouldn't expect new content. The team will continue supporting Wildermyth with bug fixes, and the console port is still on the cards.</p>
<p>He clarified that the studio's hibernation is not a reflection of poor performances or other troubles, but simply what was planned all along now that the project is over.</p>
<p>Austin however added that Worldwalker will be "saying farewell to many of [its] team members."</p>
<p>"Wildermyth has been wonderful, but nothing goes on forever," Austin said. "We wanted to ship [DLC] Omenroad, and having done that we're ready to move on. This was the plan, and it doesn't have anything to do with how well Omenroad is going."</p>
<p>He added: "We're an independent studio, which means we're not answerable to investors. Nobody is shutting us down. We are going into hibernation because we are done with this project."</p>
<p>He concluded by saying that he's "pretty sure" that the team will "eventually find something else to pour [their] passion into, and that it'll be communicated to players "when the time comes"</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Like a Dragon: Yakuza getting Amazon live-action series, releasing this fall]]></title>
            <link>https://www.destructoid.com/like-a-dragon-yakuza-getting-amazon-live-action-series-releasing-this-fall/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=like-a-dragon-yakuza-getting-amazon-live-action-series-releasing-this-fall</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/like-a-dragon-yakuza-getting-amazon-live-action-series-releasing-this-fall.888879/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.destructoid.com/like-a-dragon-yakuza-getting-amazon-live-action-series-releasing-this-fall/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=like-a-dragon-yakuza-getting-amazon-live-action-series-releasing-this-fall<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p data-characters="201" data-injectable="true" data-video="true">Following the massive success of <em>Fallout</em> on Prime Video, Amazon is heading back into the world of video games for another blockbuster series, with <em>Like a Dragon: Yakuza</em> set to release later this year. </p> <p data-characters="303" data-current-count="303" data-injectable="false">Made up of six episodes, the Amazon original series is directed by Masaharu Take and stars Ryoma Takeuchi, known for his role as Shinnosuke Tomari in <em>Kamen Rider Drive</em>. The series will feature six episodes, split into two parts, with the first released on October 25 and the second on November 1, 2024. </p> <p data-characters="261" data-current-count="564" data-injectable="true">The big announcement took place in Tokyo, Japan on June 4, with both Take and Takeuchi in attendance. Amazon stated that <em>Like a Dragon: Yakuza</em> will be “a live-action adaptation with an original story based on SEGA’s global hit game franchise.”</p>
 <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"><figcaption>Masaharu Take directs while Ryoma Takeuchi stars. Image via Amazon</figcaption></figure> <p data-characters="434" data-current-count="734" data-injectable="true">In a press release, lead Ryoma Takeuchi said he was “truly honored to be given the opportunity to play the role of Kazuma Kiryu,” and told fans to look forward to “intense fighting scenes with the Dragon tattoo on his back.” Director Masaharu Take echoed these thoughts, explaining that he has “poured [his] heart, soul, and the experience that [he] has garnered over 35 years into <em>Like a Dragon: Yakuza.</em></p>
 <p data-characters="565" data-current-count="565" data-injectable="true">Masayoshi Yokoyama, who wrote the script for the first <em>Yakuza</em> game is also onboard, serving as an executive producer on the series. “Since the day I first put pen to paper on the original <em>Yakuza</em>‘s script, I’ve never once thought about revisiting any of my work on the series,” he stated. “It’s because I understand all too well the challenges and hardships that come with remaking a finished title. However, if I were ever sent to the past through some kind of cosmic joke, this is the experience I’d want to create.”</p>
 <p data-characters="430" data-current-count="430" data-injectable="true">The release of <em>Like a Dragon: Yakuza</em> will see Amazon dip back into the world of gaming following the monumental success of <em><a href="https://www.destructoid.com/fallout-tv-show-sparks-a-surge-in-popularity-for-the-games-on-steam/">Fallout</a></em>. The series based on Bethesda’s iconic franchise was a massive success, setting a new record for the most watched title ever among adults 18-34 in the first 16 days of release, and sits just behind <em>The Lord of the Rings: The Rings of Power</em> for the company’s most successful launch ever. </p>
 <p data-characters="171" data-current-count="171" data-injectable="false">While we don’t know too much about the story of <em>Like a Dragon: Yakuza</em> just yet, we expect to hear more and see our first glimpses of the show throughout the summer. </p>
<hr>
<p><i data-stringify-type="italic"> Destructoid is supported by our audience. When you purchase through links on our site, we may earn a small affiliate commission.&nbsp;</i><i data-stringify-type="italic"><a href="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-stringify-link="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" data-sk="tooltip_parent">Learn more</a></i> </p>

</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>