<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 11:34:31 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Subnautica 2 and InZoi publishers announce voluntary layoff program "amid the era of AI transformation"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/subnautica-2-and-inzoi-publishers-announce-voluntary-layoff-program-amid-the-era-of-ai-transformation</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/subnautica-2-and-inzoi-publishers-announce-voluntary-layoff-program-amid-the-era-of-ai-transformation.1352290/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Krafton also freezing hires for anything save original IP and AI-related roles</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Collector-Leviathan-close-up-from-vlog.png?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Collector-Leviathan-close-up-from-vlog.png?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Collector-Leviathan-close-up-from-vlog.png?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Collector-Leviathan-close-up-from-vlog.png?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Collector-Leviathan-close-up-from-vlog.png?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Collector-Leviathan-close-up-from-vlog.png?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Collector-Leviathan-close-up-from-vlog.png?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Collector-Leviathan-close-up-from-vlog.png?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Collector-Leviathan-close-up-from-vlog.png?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Krafton / Rock Paper Shotgun</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/subnautica-2">Subnautica 2</a> and InZoi publishers Krafton have launched a voluntary redundancy program in what appears to be a bid to shed ballast and winnow out unbelievers as they reorganise around the usage of generative AI.</p>
<p>As reported by <a href="https://www.businesskorea.co.kr/news/articleView.html?idxno=256319">Business Korea</a> and passed along by <a href="https://automaton-media.com/en/news/krafton-launches-voluntary-resignation-program-for-employees-as-it-transforms-into-an-ai-first-company/">Automation Media</a>, the redundancy program follows a quarter of record profits. Krafton will dole out severance packages in tiers, with people who've been there one year or less getting six months salary, while those who've been there for over 11 years get 36 months.</p>
<p>According to a company spokesperson, "the core purpose is to support members in proactively designing their growth direction and embarking on new challenges both inside and outside the company amid the era of AI transformation."</p>
<p>Krafton <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/krafton-to-undergo-complete-reorganization-as-it-positions-itself-as-an-ai-first-company">announced plans to refocus on generative AI for game development</a> in late October. These refocussings include splurging $20.8 million / 30 million Korean won on retraining the workforce to use generative AI tools, while implementing some kind of automated management system.</p><p>They're also going to spend $69.7 million/100 billion won on a new GPU cluster - that is, a frosty warehouse full of computers with phat graphics cards that pool their might to complete difficult tasks, like patterning a dataset to produce a mean Piña Colada recipe without exhorting the end user to drink sawdust.</p>
<p>Krafton have also announced a hiring freeze across all roles save for those related to developing new intellectual properties or doing things with fancy chatbots, as detailed by CFO Bae Dong-geun in an earnings call on 4th November. The emphasis will be on individual staff being more productive, instead. </p>
<p>"Excluding organizations developing original intellectual property (IP) and AI-related personnel, we have frozen hiring company-wide," Dong-geun said, adding that "rather than reducing costs through AI First, individual productivity must increase at the company-wide level, so we are stopping hiring for now, and we will organize and disclose later whether there will be changes to the five-year franchise IP strategy announced earlier this year."</p>
<p>This week, Epic's Tim Sweeney gave <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/epic-boss-tim-sweeney-is-right-to-call-genai-a-political-topic-its-a-mechanism-of-class-war">an "optimistic" defence of generative AI</a> in response to Eurogamer's unimpressed <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/arc-raiders-best-guns-tier-list">Arc Raiders</a> review, arguing that "when tech increases productivity, competition leads to building better games rather than employing fewer people." It sort of feels like Krafton timed these announcements to wind him up.</p><p>Generative AI aside, Krafton are slap-bang in the middle of a legal war with ousted Unknown Worlds founders over the quality and release timing of Subnautica 2. I think Brendy and I have basically written a whole book on the subject by now. Here's <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/subnautica-2-studio-unknown-worlds-are-now-suing-their-former-execs-for-stealing-docs-and-sharing-them-with-the-press">the last news article we wrote</a>, in which Unknown Worlds accuse their old bosses of leaking things to the press.</p>

        </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/subnautica-2-and-inzoi-publishers-announce-voluntary-layoff-program-amid-the-era-of-ai-transformation]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Red Dead Redemption rating suggests remaster on the way to PS5, Xbox Series X/S, and Switch 2]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/new-red-dead-redemption-rating-suggests-remaster-on-the-way-to-ps5-xbox-series-xs-and-switch-2</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-red-dead-redemption-rating-suggests-remaster-on-the-way-to-ps5-xbox-series-x-s-and-switch-2.1352284/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>Undead Nightmare also included.</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
      <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/rdr_mQMeOOY.png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/rdr_mQMeOOY.png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/rdr_mQMeOOY.png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/rdr_mQMeOOY.png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/rdr_mQMeOOY.png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/rdr_mQMeOOY.png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/rdr_mQMeOOY.png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/rdr_mQMeOOY.png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/rdr_mQMeOOY.png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Rockstar Games/Digital Foundry</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Red Dead Redemption has been <a href="https://www.esrb.org/ratings/40987/red-dead-redemption/">rated by the ESRB</a> for PS5, Xbox Series X/S, and <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/platforms/switch-2">Switch 2</a>, suggesting a remaster is very much on the way.</p>
<p>As you'd expect, the game has been rated M, due to blood and gore, intense violence, strong language and sexual content, and more.</p>
<p>The description also notes gun fights with enemies will include zombies, suggesting the Undead Nightmare expansion will also be included.</p>

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Red Dead Redemption: The Story So Far - Red Dead Redemption 2 Story Recap" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/IjTBe-q45XE?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Red Dead Redemption: The Story So Far - Red Dead Redemption 2 Story Recap</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/IjTBe-q45XE?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/IjTBe-q45XE?autoplay=1" title="Red Dead Redemption: The Story So Far - Red Dead Redemption 2 Story Recap">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Red Dead Redemption: The Story So Far - Red Dead Redemption 2 Story Recap<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IjTBe-q45XE" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>


<p>Rumours of a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/red-dead-redemption-remaster-rumours-swirl">Red Dead Redemption remaster have been swirling for the last couple of years</a>. Originally released on the PS3, Red Dead Redemption is available on the PlayStation Store in its PS4 version - that's playable on PS5, but not fully optimised. Similarly, the original Xbox 360 version of the game is playable on current consoles via backwards compatibility.</p>
<p>This new rating suggests a native current gen version will be on the way. While the ESRB rating doesn't include a release date, its existence suggests it could be available soon.</p>
<p>Back in the summer, rumours circled of a next gen update for <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/red-dead-redemption-2-walkthrough-guide-4975">Red Dead Redemption 2</a> - alongside a Switch 2 port. It's unclear if the sequel is also on the way, or if the two games have been confused in rumours.</p><p>Either way, Take Two CEO <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/red-dead-redemption-2-reportedly-set-for-switch-2-as-take-two-boss-praises-nintendos-console">Strauss Zelnick praised the Switch 2</a> in a financial briefing back in May. "Historically being a third-party in the Nintendo business has been a bit challenging," he said. "I think Nintendo's been very forthcoming in addressing that, and we're stepping up too because we have great optimism for the platform."</p>

        </div>

  
      </article>



  



  

  <section>
    <span>Related topics</span>

    
  </section>
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/new-red-dead-redemption-rating-suggests-remaster-on-the-way-to-ps5-xbox-series-xs-and-switch-2]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Forestrike Review]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/11/13/forestrike-review/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/forestrike-review.1352278/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="gp-content-wrapper">

	<article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/Article">

		<meta itemprop="mainEntityOfPage" itemtype="https://schema.org/WebPage" itemscope="" content="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/11/13/forestrike-review/">
		<meta itemprop="headline" content="Forestrike Review">			
		
		<meta itemprop="author" content="Aran Suddi">			
		<meta itemprop="datePublished" content="2025-11-13">
		<meta itemprop="dateModified" content="2025-11-13">
		
		
			
		
								
		
			

																		
		<div itemprop="text">
			
			<p>There’s a deeply rooted part of the human psyche that plans and anticipates the worst things you can imagine. What if, while you’re stood in line waiting for the self checkout, or are sat in a cafe, a fight suddenly breaks out? What would you do?Suddenly you are daydreaming as you imagine the guy in front suddenly charging at you, but you move out of the way so he collides into the person behind you who was about to hit you with a stick. In your head, you can visualise these scenarios and outcomes as much as you want, but in reality you’d only have one shot. Forestrike takes that scenario of imagining fights and puts it in video game form.</p>
<p><iframe title="Forestrike | Gameplay Overview | The Fight Starts November 17" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/hdWREMaGhJo?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>In Forestrike, you play as Yu, who is an apprentice of the ability called Forestrike. The Order of Forestrikers used to be vast, but now it is just you and a handful of old masters imparting their knowledge to you as you go on a quest to save the Emperor and the Empire. The gameplay of Forestrike is built around a roguelite form, where each run offers different abilities to build up Yu to face the different combat puzzles ahead. And while it has all the appearance of a martial arts battler, Forestrike really is at its heart a puzzle game with combat elements.</p>



<p>As you progress through a run, Yu is put into different single scene situations with different enemy types being presented to you. This could range from two enemies up to around six. Yu’s own skills depend on which of the five masters you choose to follow for a run. Taigun, for example, is a master who values using enemy movements against them, encouraging a playstyle where you dodge and have enemies attack each other. Nodai, meanwhile, is much more focused on taking the tactical fight to the enemy, with his path offering a key block ability, and Ogai has the power of the storm on her side, and following her allows you to evade attacks and strike from behind.</p>

<p>While your chosen master gives you the bulk of the abilities on a run, you can pick up techniques from the other masters as you move along the paths, generally if you beat them in a fight. Some abilities will provide additional bonuses with dodging, better blocks, or ways to disarm enemies and cause more damage to them. All of them are reliant on your planning and execution, and that is where Forestrike comes in.</p>

<p>Unlike the majority of roguelikes, Forestrike allows you to practice a fight an unlimited number of times using the Forestrike power. When you foresee, you can test out different tactics to take out the enemies you are facing before they take you down. It doesn’t matter if you fail during this, because this is just Yu planning his attack in his mind. You are encouraged to find a tactic and practice it a few times before triggering the actual fight, because if you lose the real fight the run ends and you have to start again without any of your upgrades and abilities.</p>
<p>Some of the fights are relatively simple and may only need one or two practice runs, while others will need a lot of goes before going for the real attack. Even then, success is no guarantee, because a slight deviation from a plan can spell disaster. A misstep here or a rushed attack there may mean you suddenly need to think on your feet to salvage a fight, your best laid plan going right out the window. At other times you will face an impossible fight no matter what, whether that’s down to not having enough health or the wrong mix of abilities to progress. It can be really frustrating to reach those points, as you know the run is over no matter what you do.</p>

<p>Forestrike’s story is pretty run of the mill with a few little mysteries thrown in, but this is ultimately the struggle of a small group of rebels fighting against a powerful foe and their forces. I did like the music in the game as it has that martial arts feel to it, and the pixel art does convey the fight scenes pretty well.</p>
<p>A major issue I had while playing on Switch 2 was the game kept crashing at different times back to the home screen. A day one patch is planned that targets stability and performance, but Forestrike already had the foresight to save between each level, so runs aren’t cut short by crashes.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

			
		</div>

		
				
	<div id="gp-summary">
		<p>Summary</p><p>
		Forestrike is an entertaining blend of puzzle game and martial arts brawler, allowing you to experiment with different tactics. The different masters also provide variety with ability combinations that make each run unique. Running into some impossible fights that you simply can't beat and the crashing issue on Switch 2 do take some of the shine off the experience, though.	</p></div>
		

	<div id="gp-review-results">

									<div id="gp-good-points">
						<p>Good</p>
						<ul>
														
								<li><i></i>Provides an interesting puzzle set up</li>
														
								<li><i></i>Runs can be varied due to the different masters</li>
														
								<li><i></i>The Forestrike ability lets you try out different tactics</li>
													</ul>
					</div>
				
									<div id="gp-bad-points">
						<p>Bad</p>
						<ul>
														
								<li><i></i>Game crashes when playing on Switch 2, thankfully without losing progress</li>
														
								<li><i></i>You can be led to impossible situations</li>
													</ul>
					</div>
							
			</div>

					
	
						
			
			

			
						
		<div>

			<h3>Related stories from TSA			
			</h3>
			
				
				
		</div>

	
		
					
 
	
	
				
	</article>

</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/11/13/forestrike-review/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[It Still Isn’t Time for a Steam Deck 2, But Valve Has a ‘Pretty Good Idea’ of What It’s Going to Be]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/it-still-isnt-time-for-steam-deck-2-but-valve-has-pretty-good-idea-of-what-its-going-to-be/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/it-still-isn%E2%80%99t-time-for-a-steam-deck-2-but-valve-has-a-%E2%80%98pretty-good-idea%E2%80%99-of-what-it%E2%80%99s-going-to-be.1352275/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>It's been two years since Valve <a href="https://wccftech.com/steam-deck-oled-announced-reservations/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">introduced the Steam Deck OLED</a>, a revision of the handheld gaming device originally released on the market in February 2022. Back then, fans of the device had already been clamoring for a proper, more powerful new iteration, but Valve had just <a href="https://wccftech.com/steam-deck-2-might-not-arrive-until-2025-2026/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">said</a> that a Steam Deck 2 wouldn't be released until 2025 or 2026 because the technology they were looking for <a href="https://wccftech.com/steam-deck-2-0-doesnt-exist-because-technology-is-not-there-yet-valve-is-working-on-games-designed-for-deck/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">was simply not yet available</a>.</p>



<p>The Steam hardware family is officially set to expand early next year with the launch of the Frame headset, the new Steam Machine, and the new Steam Controller; however, there's no new Deck in sight yet. IGN <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/valves-next-gen-steam-machine-and-steam-controller-the-big-interview" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">asked Valve once again</a>, and Software Engineer Pierre-Loup Griffais reiterated that it still isn't time yet, although the company now has a good idea of what it's going to be. </p>



<p><em>Obviously the Steam Deck's not our focus today, but the same things we've said in the past where we're really interested to work on what's next for Steam Deck… the thing we're making sure of is that it's a worthwhile enough performance upgrade to make sense as a standalone product. We're not interested in getting to a point where it's 20 or 30 or even 50% more performance at the same battery life. We want something a little bit more demarcated than that. So we've been working back from silicon advancements and architectural improvements, and I think we have a pretty good idea of what the next version of Steam Deck is going to be, but right now there's no offerings in that landscape, in the SOC landscape, that we think would truly be a next-gen performance Steam Deck. </em></p>



<p>It sounds like we'll have to wait until the latter half of 2027, in all likelihood, which could put the new Deck in direct competition with the PlayStation handheld that Sony is working on. <a href="https://wccftech.com/playstation-6-handheld-specks-leaked-outperform-xbox-ally-x/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">According to rumors</a>, it's expected to offer a performance level similar to the base PlayStation 5 console. </p>



<p>Given that both devices will be powered by AMD technology, they could end up with similar performance if they are released near each other at a comparable price. Of course, there are too many unknowns at this point, which is expected given that these devices are a couple of years away. Still, keep following Wccftech to remain updated on the latest leaks, rumors, and news.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/it-still-isnt-time-for-steam-deck-2-but-valve-has-pretty-good-idea-of-what-its-going-to-be/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Maybe hold off a bit longer on reinstalling your Fallout 4 mods, as Bethesda have two anniversary update patches planned]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/maybe-hold-off-a-bit-longer-on-reinstalling-your-fallout-4-mods-as-bethesda-have-two-anniversary-update-patches-planned</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/maybe-hold-off-a-bit-longer-on-reinstalling-your-fallout-4-mods-as-bethesda-have-two-anniversary-update-patches-planned.1352272/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Issues with Creations and other gremlins need squashing</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fallout-4-anniversary-update-bethesda-two-patches-planned-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fallout-4-anniversary-update-bethesda-two-patches-planned-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fallout-4-anniversary-update-bethesda-two-patches-planned-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fallout-4-anniversary-update-bethesda-two-patches-planned-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fallout-4-anniversary-update-bethesda-two-patches-planned-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fallout-4-anniversary-update-bethesda-two-patches-planned-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fallout-4-anniversary-update-bethesda-two-patches-planned-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fallout-4-anniversary-update-bethesda-two-patches-planned-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fallout-4-anniversary-update-bethesda-two-patches-planned-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Bethesda</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Ah, it's gotten a bit worse. Bethesda are planning to release two patches to <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/fallout-4">Fallout 4</a> in order to rectify issues with its anniversary edition, meaning that the potential's there for more havoc to be played with mods. Though, outside of fixes for issues with the revamped Creations menu, it looks like a lot of the contents of these patches may end up being console-specific fixes, so there's a chance any extra PC disruption's relatively minimal.</p>
<p>I'd certainly hope it's less of a palaver than the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/fallout-4s-script-extender-has-already-gotten-its-anniversary-update-as-bethesda-battle-creation-issues">update's initial arrival</a>, which many modders have been quick to get on top of and push updates for their works.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>"We’re actively investigating issues you’re encountering with the latest Fallout 4 update and Anniversary Edition launch," the latest <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/377160/view/617683464289779908?l=english">Steam post</a> from Bethesda reads. "You should now see faster load times of the Creations menu, game menu, and redemption of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/creation-club">Creation Club</a> items."</p>
<p>There's a hotfix coming to the game early next week, which the studio say will put the "issue causing creations that rely on DLC to not work" to bed, as well as a couple of problems specific to Xboxers and PlayStationeers. That ain't it, though. The hotfix'll be followed by two patches, the first arriving the week of November 24th, and the second being more loosely timetabled to rock up in the first half of December.</p><p>Bethesda haven't specified what'll be in either patch yet, with the exception of a boost to local Creations storage on Xbox. Maybe there'll only be one or two tweaks for us PC folk, but the studio not delineating these further patches as console-only suggests there'll at least be something PC-related in 'em. Here's hoping any tweaks are minimal, but even then, such is the nature of game updates that it can only take one bit of code moving or changing to throw a mod out of whack.</p>
<p>So, maybe leave any uber-modded returns to early next year if you want to play it safe in terms of avoiding any headaches.</p>

        </div>

      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/maybe-hold-off-a-bit-longer-on-reinstalling-your-fallout-4-mods-as-bethesda-have-two-anniversary-update-patches-planned]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Football Manager 26 update 2 has been detailed]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/11/13/football-manager-26-update-2-has-been-detailed/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/football-manager-26-update-2-has-been-detailed.1352251/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Sports Interactive has released Football Manager update 2 on the Steam Public Beta track to test it before it is pushed out to the whole community. This second patch for Football Manager 26 will contain 200 fixes, though not all are listed, including bug fixes, UI improvements, and the addition of being able to use the space bar to navigate messages.</p>
<p><iframe title="Football Manager 26 | First Look Reveal" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_cDQi5kwuHQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<h2>Football Manager 26 update 2 patch notes</h2>
<ul>
<li>Added legacy preference option to continue through messages via the space bar.&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Numerous tile/card polish and alignment fixes.&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Numerous further fixes to translations.&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Substantial amount of other crash and stability fixes (some specific ones listed below).&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Fixed a crash when adding Club Affiliation via the Pre-Game Editor (PGE).&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Fixed a crash when user tries to move players or staff using the In-Game Editor (IGE).&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Fixed an issue in IGE where Transfer and Wage Budget edits wouldn’t take effect.&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Fixed an issue where Move to Club/Move to Other Club wouldn’t work for free agents using the IGE.<wbr></li>
<li>Fixed a soft lock when selecting off of the Move to Other Club list on the IGE.&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Fixed a crash on M1/Intel Macs when attempting to start a match.&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Further fixes to Matches freezing during single player and online matches.&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Fixed slowdown in match when on 2D overview screen.&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Scroll bar will now save state when leaving and returning to a tile/card.&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Added Save Team Selection and Clear Squad/Subs options within Tactics.&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Fixed “Auto-size all Columns” leaving a large space to the right of the table.&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>“Sort Attributes Using English Language Sorting” preference will now function correctly.&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Japan – Match Rules – Fixed foreign player limits having incorrect rules set.&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>England – Fixed rare issue where season wouldn’t begin due to incorrect scheduling of the National League Playoff Final.&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>USA – Updated Designated Player path rule to better reflect real life.&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Fixed an issue preventing user being able to sort by Role Ability in Player Selector during a match.&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Star Ratings widget has been added within Squad Planner.&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Body language of players will now correctly update during meetings.&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Global Search bar now closes when a hyperlink is pressed.&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Fixed an issue where club badges would be switched in Cup Final news items when venue was neutral.&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Acting on Opposition Instruction advice will now function correctly.&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Fixed an issue where Recruitment Focus would display as completed if cancelled.&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Fixed an issue where some clubs would be shown to have 0 people on the season ticket waiting list.&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Fixed an issue where NXGN award wouldn’t be handed out.&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Fixed an issue preventing the Place of Birth field to populate during manager creation.&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Fixed save game prompt appearing on screen causing an overlap during the Portal tutorial.&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Fixed an issue where clubs in Saudi Arabia wouldn’t renew player contracts often enough.&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Fixed issue where the ‘i’ profile preview would appear for non-players who shouldn’t be accessible.&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Agent feedback will now correctly display when prompted if user asks within “Ask Agent About Market Interest” dialogue option.&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Realigned columns of Interested Clubs within Player Offers.&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Fixed issue preventing user to return to the start screen if they deleted all managers present within the Manager Profiles tab.&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Realigned Career Milestones.&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Refined ‘Player Change in Registration’ card to fix cutoffs.&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Fixed issue where a message would open by default if user selected one of the Messages tabs.&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>‘Arrange Friendly’ will now appear as intended when opening Fixture Schedule for the first time.&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Pre-Match Lineups will now hide Form if there isn’t any data to show.&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Future Transfers filter within Transfer History will now function as intended.&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Change/Withdraw Transfer Offer action buttons will now function correctly immediately after user makes an offer.&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Management Style box during manager creator flow will now correctly store previous role and how well known you were for it.&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Mentality will now display correctly if updated within Match Tactics.&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Reworked the positional familiarity colouring on the player position map.&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>The icon for ‘Really Good’ morale will now display properly.&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Team Priorities card will now function correctly.&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>The Fixtures card will now properly distinguish between those that scored/missed during a penalty shootout.&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>AI Club Fixtures will now display correctly if user is unemployed.&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Fixed issue displaying head coaches name during UEFA Women’s CL pre-match lineup graphic.&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Finances &gt; Summary will now display correctly for teams without FFP.&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Recruitment &gt; Player Database – Selecting a Role will now highlight the correct Key Attributes.&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Fixed the Ability and Potential columns not populating with any data in the Recruitment Focus General Info view&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Newly promoted teams should now receive a more reasonable wage budget reflecting new division and current financial state.&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Agreed Playing Time column will now populate with correct data.&nbsp;<wbr></li>
<li>Multi-Select on “Available for U21/U18 match” portal item will now function correctly.</li>
</ul>

<p>In our Football Manager 26 review, I said, <em>“Football Manager 26 is the first step of a new era, and as we’re seeing with some of the biggest clubs in the country, any new era comes with the challenge of rebuilding and both setting and meeting expectations. Football Manager 26 can get better with updates, but I doubt that this entry will be the one to make the most of the switch to the new engine, overhauled UI and new features. It might take one or two more years for this rebuild to really meet its potential.”</em></p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/3551340?emclan=103582791475288538&amp;emgid=630068363265048766">Steam</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/11/13/football-manager-26-update-2-has-been-detailed/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ARC Raiders update 1.2.0 is called North Line, adds the Stella Montis map]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/11/13/arc-raiders-update-1-2-0-is-called-north-line-adds-the-stella-montis-map/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/arc-raiders-update-1-2-0-is-called-north-line-adds-the-stella-montis-map.1352248/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Embark Studios has released the 1.2.0 update for Arc Raiders, naming it North Line, which brings along the new Stella Montis map. Stella Montis is a facility that has lots of blocked up tunnels, but players are being tasked with digging deep into these tunnels to find out what was blocked off and why. In addition to the new map, Arc Raiders update 1.2.0 has fixed issues including players falling through terrain, an issue around missions not completing, and also introduced some balance changes. The full notes are below.</p>
<p><iframe title="The North Line Update | ARC Raiders" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/O9JeiBAAey4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>




<ul>
<li>Map <wbr>Stella Montis</li>
<li>ARC Matriarch and Shredder</li>
<li>Community Unlock Event</li>
<li>New Gameplay Items</li>
<li>New Quests</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li>Reduced character movement latency on server to improve the “desync” problem where it looks like you get damaged even after behind cover.<wbr></li>
<li>Fixed an issue that prevented players from completing quests involving multiple objectives or item collections within a single round.<wbr></li>
<li>Fixed various achievements not working correctly. Players will need to redo some achievements with only one objective item (e.g. “Destroy the Queen”) while achievements with multiple objectives will only need parts of them completed again.<wbr></li>
<li>Reduced delay between shooting at ARC and seeing impact effects on the target.<wbr></li>
<li>Fixed various locations where players could fall through the terrain.</li>
</ul>


<p>Wolfpack<wbr></p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Value: From 3,000 to 5,000 Coins<wbr></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Crafting:&nbsp;<wbr></p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Before: 2 Refined Explosives + 2 Sensors<wbr></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Now: 3 Refined Explosives + 2 ARC Motion Cores<wbr></p>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p>ARC Motion Core &amp; ARC Circuitry<wbr></p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Unlock:<wbr></p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Before: Refiner LVL 3<wbr></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Now: Refiner LVL 2<wbr></p>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p>Crafting:<wbr></p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Before: 6 ARC Alloy<wbr></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Now: 8 ARC Alloy<wbr></p>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Launcher Ammo<wbr></p>

<ul>
<li>
<p>Value: From 100 to 200 Coins (This doubles trader cost for launcher ammo)<wbr></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Crafting (6 ammo):&nbsp;<wbr></p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Before: 5 Metal Parts + 1 Crude Explosives<wbr></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Now: 4 Metal Parts + 1 Refined Explosives<wbr></p>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Spotter Relay<wbr></p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Value: From 5,000 to 2,000 Coins<wbr></p>
</li>
</ul>

<p>Reduced XP per Damage from 3 to 2 for:<wbr></p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Bastion<wbr></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Bombardier<wbr></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Rocketeer<wbr></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Leaper<wbr></p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Reduced XP for Looting ARC parts:<wbr></p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Bastion: From 500 to 250<wbr></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Bombardier: From 500 to 300<wbr></p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Increased XP for Looting ARC parts:<wbr></p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Rocketeer thruster: From 200 to 500<wbr></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Leaper leg: From 200 to 500<wbr></p>
</li>
</ul>


<ul>
<li>
<p>Fixed various achievements not working correctly. Players will need to redo some achievements with only one objective item (e.g. “Destroy the Queen”) while achievements with multiple objectives will only need parts of them completed again.<wbr></p>
</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li>Fixed an issue where weapons were automatically slung when throwing grenades.<wbr></li>
<li>Fixed an issue where weapons were sometimes hidden when using deployables.<wbr></li>
<li>Improved camera behavior to prevent clipping through walls and objects while jumping.<wbr></li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li>Fireball enemies will no longer get stuck on security gates and will pursue the player accordingly.<wbr></li>
<li>Fixed a bug where the Surveyors fleeing behavior could move it out of playable area.<wbr></li>
<li>Fixed a bug which caused some enemies to take more fire damage than intended.<wbr></li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li>Added a System Default option for voice chat input and output devices to follow your operating system’s default.<wbr></li>
<li>Breathing audio has been adjusted for better balance between players with and without helmets. Breathing sounds are also less audible over distance.<wbr></li>
<li>Added different audio effects to Scrappy while wearing various helmet cosmetics.<wbr></li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li>
<p>Fixed an issue where party members would initially appear with the base appearance.<wbr></p>
</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li>
<p>The Dam Battlegrounds<wbr></p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Fixed locations in The Dam where players could fall through the terrain.<wbr></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Fixed some collision issues on The Dam where players could get stuck.<wbr></p>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p>Buried City<wbr></p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Fixed various flickering and clipping issues in Buried City.<wbr></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Fixed some locations where players could get stuck in the subway stations in Buried City.<wbr></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Fixed locations in Buried City where players could fall through the terrain.<wbr></p>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p>Spaceport<wbr></p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Sealed one of the rooms in Spaceport’s Departure Building, making it require breaching to access. The loot inside was adjusted to fit the effort required to enter.<wbr></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Fixed an issue where certain doors could not be breached from the inside in the Launch Tower.<wbr></p>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p>Blue Gate<wbr></p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Fixed an issue where players could get trapped in the Blue Gate Control Room.<wbr></p>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p>Hatches<wbr></p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Fixed an issue where successfully entering a raider hatch did not grant immunity to damage and knockbacks.<wbr></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Increased interaction distance for raider hatches.<wbr></p>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li>Reduced character movement latency on server to improve the “desync” problem where it looks like you get damaged even after behind cover.<wbr></li>
<li>Reduced delay between shooting at ARC and seeing impact effects on the target.<wbr></li>
<li>Adjusted blueprint drop rates from Raider Containers.<wbr></li>
<li>Interacting with Probes, Husks, Raider Caches, etc. now counts towards looting container objectives.<wbr></li>
<li>Fixed a bug where players would sometimes become unable to perform any actions if they were downed while holding a carriable object and then revived.<wbr></li>
<li>Fixed an issue where you could not loot or knock out DBNO players on steep slopes.<wbr></li>
<li>Field crafting selection now stays on the same item after crafting.<wbr></li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li>
<p>Vaulting is now smoother.<wbr></p>
</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li>Added an inventory item menu option for splitting stacks.<wbr></li>
<li>Removed Thumb Mouse Button from the Escape action in menus to prevent unintended back navigation when that button is bound to Push-to-Talk.<wbr></li>
<li>Added a confirmation message after submitting a player report to clearly indicate that the report was received.<wbr></li>
<li>Certain enemy salvage items will no longer auto-assign to Quick Slots when looted (e.g. Wasp Driver), preventing unwanted quick slot fills.<wbr></li>
<li>Prevent showing blocked Discord users in the social screen when the Discord integration is on.<wbr></li>
<li>Changed the styling of some UI input hints.<wbr></li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li>Fixed an issue where the Blaze Grenade Trap could deal more damage then intended.<wbr></li>
<li>Reduced Tick attachment time for the Anti-Tick Field augment passive from 1 second to 0.5 seconds.<wbr></li>
<li>Fixed an issue where a prompt would get stuck while fighting off Ticks at the same time as the Anti-Tick Field passive being active.<wbr></li>
<li>Smoke clouds from items are now always visible at the same range as players.<wbr></li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the Trigger ‘Nade explosions could bypass the brief invulnerability when entering DBNO, causing instant elimination. Invulnerability now correctly applies on downing.<wbr></li>
<li>Fixed a bug allowing players to use the Snap Hook to go out of bounds in the Spaceport bunker.<wbr></li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li>
<p>Fixed an issue where firing while standing close to walls could cause bullets to veer sideways instead of following the crosshair.<wbr></p>
</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li>Fixed an issue that prevented players from completing quests involving multiple objectives or item collections within a single round.<wbr></li>
<li>The Greasing Her Palm quest in Spaceport now includes more thrusters that will complete the objective.</li>
</ul>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news?emclan=103582791471145455&amp;emgid=632320262484787237">Steam</a></em><wbr></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/11/13/arc-raiders-update-1-2-0-is-called-north-line-adds-the-stella-montis-map/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Marvel Cosmic Invasion Trailer Highlights The Hero-Swapping Tag-Team Feature]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/11/new-marvel-cosmic-invasion-trailer-highlights-the-hero-swapping-tag-team-feature</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-marvel-cosmic-invasion-trailer-highlights-the-hero-swapping-tag-team-feature.1352245/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>On your left</p>
</section></header><section>

<p>We are drawing ever closer to the release of Dotemu and Tribute Games' next side-scrolling beat 'em up, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/marvel-cosmic-invasion">MARVEL Cosmic Invasion</a>, on <strong>1st December</strong>, and the devs have returned to give us another deep dive into some gameplay.</p>
<p>While the <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/11/marvel-cosmic-invasion-devs-showcase-every-fighter-in-the-upcoming-beat-em-up">last video of this ilk</a> was all about the diverse character roster, this fresh peek gives us our best look yet at the tag-team-style 'Cosmic Swap' ability, which lets you sub in a new hero at the tap of a button.</p>
<p>We had spotted a bit of this arcade-inspired feature in previous trailers, but it's nice to have the minds behind the game run us through its intricacies.</p>
<p>"Gameplay-wise, the Cosmic Swap is an amazing tool," Game Director Frederic Gemus explains in the vid, "because it not only helps you address different situations with different characters, but also enables you to extend your combos by swapping mid-way and creating these amazing-looking combat sequences, or even just call in an assist so your teammate can take care of an enemy while you're taking care of another one."</p>
<p>It sounds like there's a good layer of depth to it all, too. Whether you want to tackle an enemy from a different angle or plan ahead to achieve a slick combo, the Cosmic Swap ability looks like it'll be something that we'll be using <em>a lot</em> in each and every playthrough.</p>
<p>Marvel Cosmic Invasion arrives digitally on Switch and Switch 2 next month for <strong>£26.99 / $29.99</strong>.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:193485,192883 @ 1763033353 -->
<p><em>Will you be checking this one out in December? Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section></article><div><p>Jim came to Nintendo Life in 2022 and, despite his insistence that The Minish Cap is the best Zelda game and his unwavering love for the Star Wars prequels (yes, really), he has continued to write news and features on the site ever since.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/JimNorman"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/jimnormann.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('JimNorman');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/11/new-marvel-cosmic-invasion-trailer-highlights-the-hero-swapping-tag-team-feature]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why is superhero comedy Dispatch a million-selling success story? It could be that weekly release schedule]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/why-is-superhero-comedy-dispatch-a-million-selling-success-story-it-could-be-that-weekly-release-schedule</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/why-is-superhero-comedy-dispatch-a-million-selling-success-story-it-could-be-that-weekly-release-schedule.1352242/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Or it could just be a good game, but that's BORING</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/dispatch_xP1iqG3.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/dispatch_xP1iqG3.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/dispatch_xP1iqG3.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/dispatch_xP1iqG3.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/dispatch_xP1iqG3.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/dispatch_xP1iqG3.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/dispatch_xP1iqG3.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/dispatch_xP1iqG3.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/dispatch_xP1iqG3.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>AdHoc Studio</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>The final episode of swish and salacious Telltale-style caped tellydrama Dispatch released yesterday. It's been a surprise hit - according to the gabbling labcoats at GameDiscoverCo, AdHoc's superhero workplace comedy is approaching two million sales. Reasons given for this range from the appealing but uninvestigated - there's a Galactus-sized untapped audience for narrative single player games, and all the publishers are absolute spanners for doubling down on live service projects instead - to the boring - people are still keen on superheroes, especially sociopathic and disgusting superheroes that cut against archetypes from the more pompous Marvel films, and Dispatch is simply <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/telltale-and-the-boys-make-mostly-beautiful-love-in-dispatch-a-slick-and-surprisingly-tactical-superhero-comedy">a very well-made game</a>. </p>
<p>Good games sell? What a <em>gauche</em>, back-of-napkin excuse for industry analysis. There must be a more arcane and clever-sounding explanation for Dispatch's meteoric fortunes. Ah yes, here we go: speaking to GameDiscoverCo, AdHoc's CEO and exec producer Michael Choung has suggested that it's partly down to the weekly episodic release schedule.</p><!--more-->
<p>"We're really just borrowing a rhythm that's worked for decades on television," he <a href="https://newsletter.gamediscover.co/p/how-did-narrative-hit-dispatch-hit">told the site</a>. "That weekly cadence hits a sweet spot where anticipation builds, but not long enough to fade." That's it. That's the whole quote. Still, it has given me Thoughts. </p>
<p>One is that I can now no longer tolerate the thought of episodic schedules at all. After years of streaming TV platforms, I am now only capable of watching shows all in one go, while crying into bowls of lukewarm salsa. The thought of getting to episode 5 and having to wait multiple diurnal cycles for episode 6 is a source of torment. Anything could happen between episodes! I might start watching something else instead! A piano might fall on me! I might be forced to spend time with my own thoughts! A month between episodes? You might as well ship it after our sun goes supernova.</p><p>Another more developed thought is that I want to go back and compare the formal structure of episodic narrative artworks, from Star Trek to Telltale's Walking Dead games, thinking about how the release tempo affects, for example, the writing of relationships and the choice and structure of cliffhangers. Monthly episodes surely need to be more like standalone releases; within that, what kinds of narrative event are best for nurturing suspense and speculation over a 30 day interval? If I dangle the prospect of killing off a major character, is that a better fit for a weekly rollout? Sorry, these are questions of craft TV writers have been writing books about for decades.</p>
<p>A third thought is that all of this is a far cry from the Telltale days of multiple-month gaps between episodes. Episode 1 of The Walking Dead: Season 2 came out in December 2013. Episode 2 came out in March 2014. Incredible! Just imagine how many pianos could fall on you in three whole months. Telltale was <a href="https://www.vg247.com/the-rise-and-fall-of-telltale-games">notoriously mismanaged</a>, with parallel, staggered projects and changes of direction creating a culture of crunch; I'm not sure how much that dictated the longer gaps between episodes, but the studio was clearly operating at the brink of capacity, for a lot of the time.</p>
<p>A fourth thought is simply that I need to go back and finish Dispatch. I reviewed the first couple of episodes, but then a week went by in which I stumbled upon new anime series Sanda and decided to rewatch Monthly Girls' Nozaki-kun (no high velocity piano encounters, at least). Still, I can just about remember enough of episodes 1 and 2 to grasp the stakes going into episode 3. IIRC, there are two romance interests, both Problematic, and a man with flammable BO wants to kick my head in.</p>

        </div>

      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/why-is-superhero-comedy-dispatch-a-million-selling-success-story-it-could-be-that-weekly-release-schedule]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Horizon Steel Frontiers, an MMORPG twist on Sony's series about plinking robo-animals with arrows, is coming to PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/horizon-steel-frontiers-an-mmorpg-twist-on-sonys-series-about-plinking-robo-animals-with-arrows-is-coming-to-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/horizon-steel-frontiers-an-mmorpg-twist-on-sonys-series-about-plinking-robo-animals-with-arrows-is-coming-to-pc.1352239/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>From Guild Wars publishers NCSoft</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/horizon-steel-frontiers-mmorpg-ncsoft-revealed-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/horizon-steel-frontiers-mmorpg-ncsoft-revealed-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/horizon-steel-frontiers-mmorpg-ncsoft-revealed-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/horizon-steel-frontiers-mmorpg-ncsoft-revealed-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/horizon-steel-frontiers-mmorpg-ncsoft-revealed-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/horizon-steel-frontiers-mmorpg-ncsoft-revealed-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/horizon-steel-frontiers-mmorpg-ncsoft-revealed-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/horizon-steel-frontiers-mmorpg-ncsoft-revealed-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/horizon-steel-frontiers-mmorpg-ncsoft-revealed-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>NCSoft</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Start setting up tripwires and stretch your bow strings, a <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/horizon-forbidden-west">Horizon</a> MMORPG dubbed Horizon Steel Frontiers has been <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/ncsofts-project-skyline-rumoured-to-be-horizon-mmo-in-the-works-for-pc-and-unreal-engine-5">fully revealed</a> by Sony and developers NCSoft. As ever, it's all about slapping up and taming big metal bears, birds and the like, this time as a custom character in a world filled with other players who're also in the robo-hunting business.</p>
<!--more-->

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="[Horizon Steel Frontiers] Announcement Video" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/bN-NNgWIyIQ?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>[Horizon Steel Frontiers] Announcement Video</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/bN-NNgWIyIQ?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/bN-NNgWIyIQ?autoplay=1" title="[Horizon Steel Frontiers] Announcement Video">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bN-NNgWIyIQ" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>


<p>As Guerilla Games studio director Jan-Bart van Beek says in the reveal video above, Steel Frontiers has been "built specifically for mobile" by <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/guild-wars">Guild Wars</a> publishers NCSoft, but is also coming to PC via the South Korean studio's launcher <a href="https://purple.plaync.com/download">Purple</a>.</p>
<p>Set in a region dubbed The Deadlands inspired by Arizona and New Mexico, the game'll see your custom Nora, Tenakth, Utaru, or Oseram "sharing the frontier with thousands of other players, sometimes working together to take down machines, sometimes competing with rival tribes, or fighting over resources". Sounds quite Monster Huntery, as you'd expect.</p><p>Executive producer Sung-Gu Lee says giving massive machine hunts the MMO treatment's been the key focus for Steel Frontiers. "We’ve added unique, original gameplay elements to the process of taking down giant machines," he explains. "For example, after destroying a specific part of a machine you can quickly approach and climb onto it using a Pullcaster, set traps on the damaged part, and inflict status effects. During battle, you can even pick up weapons dropped by the machine, carry them on your mount and use them in subsequent fights. At the heart of giant machine hunts are two core values: cooperation and strategy. Players must take on their roles, act strategically, and work together seamlessly. These combat mechanics truly shine in large-scale battles, offering the scale and dynamism that only an MMORPG can provide."</p><p>

The footage shown off thus far looks pretty graphically swanky regardless of the stated mobile-first focus, and contains a lot more big swords than I remember from my time playing <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/horizon-zero-dawn">Zero Dawn</a>. To be fair, I did spend 90% of that whacking things to death with Aloy's spear in a fashion I imagine led the game to sigh deeply while it gazed at the array of ranged weapons and gizmos I could be using if I didn't want to be flung at the scenery whenever I failed to dodge point blank swipes fast enough.

</p><p>Speaking of Aloy, she's nowhere to be seen in the video, so we'll have to see how or if the game works in any references to the metal-named huntress. As of right now, Steel Frontiers also doesn't have a release date. Alongside <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/sony-fire-arrows-alleging-nonsense-and-deliberate-corporate-water-muddying-at-tencent-as-horizon-lawsuit-rumbles-on-2">yelling at Tencent in court</a>, Sony and Guerilla have <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/guerrilla-confirm-their-rumoured-online-horizon-game-is-indeed-real">previously confirmed</a> they've got a new mainline Horizon entry in the works, as well as an online Horizon game of their own.</p>
</div>

      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/horizon-steel-frontiers-an-mmorpg-twist-on-sonys-series-about-plinking-robo-animals-with-arrows-is-coming-to-pc]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Guerrilla affirms it's working on new games in the Horizon franchise as NCSoft MMO skips PS5]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/guerrilla-affirms-its-working-on-new-games-in-the-horizon-franchise-as-ncsoft-mmo-skips-ps5</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/guerrilla-affirms-its-working-on-new-games-in-the-horizon-franchise-as-ncsoft-mmo-skips-ps5.1352233/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>

  <figure>
      <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/A-female-with-tribal-markings-on-her-face-on-the-back-of-a-machine-beast-in-Horizon-MMO.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/A-female-with-tribal-markings-on-her-face-on-the-back-of-a-machine-beast-in-Horizon-MMO.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/A-female-with-tribal-markings-on-her-face-on-the-back-of-a-machine-beast-in-Horizon-MMO.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/A-female-with-tribal-markings-on-her-face-on-the-back-of-a-machine-beast-in-Horizon-MMO.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/A-female-with-tribal-markings-on-her-face-on-the-back-of-a-machine-beast-in-Horizon-MMO.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/A-female-with-tribal-markings-on-her-face-on-the-back-of-a-machine-beast-in-Horizon-MMO.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/A-female-with-tribal-markings-on-her-face-on-the-back-of-a-machine-beast-in-Horizon-MMO.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/A-female-with-tribal-markings-on-her-face-on-the-back-of-a-machine-beast-in-Horizon-MMO.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/A-female-with-tribal-markings-on-her-face-on-the-back-of-a-machine-beast-in-Horizon-MMO.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>NCSoft</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>An upcoming and newly announced game in PlayStation's Horizon series is skipping PS5.</p>
<p>Last night, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/horizon-zero-dawn">Horizon Zero Dawn</a> and Forbidden West developer Guerilla officially announced the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/horizon-mmo-reportedly-in-the-pipeline">series' long-rumored MMORPG</a>, known as Horizon Steel Frontiers. Steel Frontiers is coming from NCSoft, though Guerrilla has collaborated with the studio, and is a cross-platform release… for mobile and PC.</p>
<!-- code from Primis - Eurogamer.net - eurogamer.net -->
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<!-- code from Primis -->
<p><a href="https://hsf.plaync.com/en-us/conts/teaser#main">Steel Frontiers is described</a> as a "fierce survival adventure", in which players take on the role of machine hunters in a region known as Deathlands. The team promises "large-scale raids" and an "advanced combat system".</p>
<p>Along with the announcement, a trailer was shared for Horizon Steel Frontiers, which you can see further below in this article. However, while plenty have said the upcoming game looks actually pretty good, many have lamented that such a well known PlayStation series is getting a game that will not be released on PlayStation consoles.</p>
<p>"It's a huge miss that this is skipping consoles," reads one comment on the trailer's YouTube announcement. Another adds: "I hope this comes to console soon because if not that’s CRIMINAL!!!"</p>
<p>Comments on X are similar. "Guys we want this on PlayStation too" and "how about starting by releasing this on PS5 as well? It looks awesome and I'd love to play it... On PS5!" are two such replies to Guerrilla's post.</p>

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="[Horizon Steel Frontiers] Announcement Video" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/bN-NNgWIyIQ?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>[Horizon Steel Frontiers] Announcement Video</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/bN-NNgWIyIQ?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/bN-NNgWIyIQ?autoplay=1" title="[Horizon Steel Frontiers] Announcement Video">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>
[Horizon Steel Frontiers] Announcement Video. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bN-NNgWIyIQ" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>


<p>In a <a href="https://x.com/Guerrilla/status/1988826301608661461?s=20">follow up post on X</a>, Guerrilla said it had "loved" working with NCSoft on Horizon Steel Frontiers, and the team is "beyond excited to be able to hunt machines together in the world of Horizon". The developer added Guerrilla itself is "still busily working on more ways for you to do just that", teasing "more on that to come".</p><p>While the studio is yet to officially reveal a third mainline entry in the Horizon series, Guerrilla previously confirmed <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/guerrilla-casually-confirms-horizon-forbidden-west-sequel">another game with Aloy at the forefront is in the pipeline</a>. In addition, a film adaptation based on the Horizon series is also in the works.</p>
<p>"Just imagine Aloy's beloved origin story set in a vibrant far future world filled with the giant machines brought to you for the first time on the big screen," <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/horizon-zero-dawn-and-helldivers-2-are-getting-film-adaptations">PlayStation's Asad Qizilbash announced back in January of this year</a>.</p>
<p>For more on the Horizon series, earlier this year Aloy actress Ashly Burch spoke to Eurogamer about her thoughts on AI, and why <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/horizon-zero-dawn-developer-replacing-all-actors-with-robots-not-going-to-happen-says-aloy-voice-actress">she believes Guerrilla replacing all actors with robots is "not going to happen"</a>.</p>

        </div>

  
      </article>



  



  <section>
        


    

      <details>
        <summary>
See 1 more              <span></span>

        </summary>

        
      </details>
  </section>

  <section>
    <span>Related topics</span>

    
  </section>
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/guerrilla-affirms-its-working-on-new-games-in-the-horizon-franchise-as-ncsoft-mmo-skips-ps5]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Silent Hill f gets a fresh update that addresses combat concerns by introducing a much easier Casual option]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/silent-hill-f-gets-a-fresh-update-that-addresses-combat-concerns-by-introducing-a-much-easier-casual-option</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/silent-hill-f-gets-a-fresh-update-that-addresses-combat-concerns-by-introducing-a-much-easier-casual-option.1352227/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>

  <figure>
      <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Silent_Hill_f_ending_Header.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Silent_Hill_f_ending_Header.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Silent_Hill_f_ending_Header.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Silent_Hill_f_ending_Header.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Silent_Hill_f_ending_Header.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Silent_Hill_f_ending_Header.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Silent_Hill_f_ending_Header.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Silent_Hill_f_ending_Header.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Silent_Hill_f_ending_Header.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Konami</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/silent-hill-f">Silent Hill f</a> has received a fresh update that adds a new Casual difficulty option for combat, among other changes to make it easier.</p>
<p>While Konami hasn't detailed the specifics of Casual difficulty, it is presumably easier than the existing Story option. It's selectable when starting a new game, or will be an option after reaching the Game Over screen multiple times.</p>
<p>Other tweaks to make the game easier include faster stamina replenishment, fewer enemies in some encounters, and less damage taken on Hard action difficulty.</p>
<p>The update further adds an option to skip certain sections on New Game+, which won't impact branching paths or endings. Considering some story details are saved for later playthroughs, this change will make experiencing the full game a lot easier - as Eurogamer's Matt Wales explained in his piece on <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/silent-hill-f-is-the-first-game-in-four-decades-to-convince-me-new-game-plus-is-worth-my-time">Silent Hill f's New Game+</a>.</p>
<div>
<div data-domain="twitter.com"><blockquote><p dir="ltr" lang="en">Thank you to all SILENT HILL f players for your patience. Today we've released a patch that adds a new casual difficulty and addresses feedback we've received, including reducing the amount of forced combat areas, speeding up NG+ runs, and bug fixes such as Sakuko's diary in NG+. <a href="https://t.co/kCiz4DoDft">https://t.co/kCiz4DoDft</a></p>— Al Yang (@QQBert) <a href="https://twitter.com/QQBert/status/1988831306864538009?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 13, 2025</a></blockquote></div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>

<p>Though the game has been widely praised, Silent Hill f has been criticised for its combat encounters. In our <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/silent-hill-f-review">Eurogamer review of Silent Hill f</a>, Vikki Blake described the combat as "clumsy", which makes it "extraordinarily difficult to do any real exploration of the world".</p>
<p>As such, this new Casual difficulty should appease those critics somewhat, and allow more players to experience the story.</p>
<p>Below are the full patch notes.</p>
<blockquote><h3>PC (Steam / Epic Games Store / Microsoft Store / GOG)</h3>
<p><strong>New Features</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Added Action Difficulty: Casual</li>
<p>- The Casual action difficulty will be playable when starting a game from "New Game" on the main menu or from a New Game+ save file.</p>
<p>- For players on the Story action difficulty or higher, the Casual action difficulty will be selectable upon reaching the Game Over screen multiple times.</p>
<li>Added Optional Skip Feature for Select Sections of New Game+</li>
<p>- Upon completing the "Go through the door" objective after solving the mural puzzle on New Game+, the game will display the option to skip. The game will resume at the scene where Hinako awakens at the corridor of the Dark Shrine for the second time with the "Proceed" objective if skipped.</p>
<p>- Items from the skipped sections will not be collected.</p>
<p>- "Thankful to Be Here," "Grateful for a Worthy Foe," and "Clear Skies" do not unlock on a playthrough that uses the skip feature.</p>
<li>The skip feature does not impact branching paths or endings.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>System Changes</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Hinako's stamina replenishes slightly faster</li>
<li>Unskippable combat encounters are reduced across multiple sections</li>
<li>Fewer enemies are placed across multiple sections</li>
<li>Hinako's line when an enemy is defeated plays at a slightly later time</li>
<li>Hinako takes slightly less damage on the Hard action difficulty</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Bug Fixes</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Fixed bug where Shu duplicates in the cutscene that plays when heading from Sennensugi Shrine to Rinko's house during the "Head to Rinko's house" objective</li>
<li>Fixed bug where interaction icons do not display on the hall leading to the room with the naginata during the "Enter the inner room" objective</li>
<li>Fixed bug where the Sakuko-like entity stops moving in combat during the "Defeat the Sakuko-like entity" objective</li>
<li>Fixed bug where the Fog Monster stops moving and halts progress during the "Chase after the Fog Monster" objective</li>
<li>Fixed bugs across multiple levels where events do not progress despite meeting the required conditions</li>
<li>Fixed bugs across multiple levels where specific enemies remain outside of the combat area and cannot be defeated</li>
<li>Fixed bugs across multiple levels where clumps of flesh do not spawn</li>
<li>Fixed bug where some notes from "Sakuko's Diary" could not be obtained on New Game+</li>
<li>Fixed bug where Hinako may become unresponsive to player input after dodging</li>
<li>Fixed bug where Hinako dies upon loading an autosave file if Hinako died during an autosave</li>
<li>Fixed bug where the "View Endings" option does not display on the title screen after finishing the first playthrough (may require loading New Game+ data to fix)</li>
<li>Fixed bug where Indirect Lighting and Reflections revert to On during cutscenes even when set to Off in the Graphics menu</li>
<li>Fixed bug where the cursor moves without player input when playing on the controller</li>
<li>*Various other minor bugs have been fixed, including bugs related to audio, hitboxes, text errors, loading, and graphics.</li>
</ul>
<h3>PS5 / Xbox Series X/S</h3>
<p><strong>New Features</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Added Action Difficulty: Casual</li>
<p>- The Casual action difficulty will be playable when starting a game from "New Game" on the main menu or from a New Game+ save file.</p>
<p>- For players on the Story action difficulty or higher, the Casual action difficulty will be selectable upon reaching the Game Over screen multiple times.</p>
<li>Added Optional Skip Feature for Select Sections of New Game+</li>
<p>- Upon completing the "Go through the door" objective after solving the mural puzzle on New Game+, the game will display the option to skip. The game will resume at the scene where Hinako awakens at the corridor of the Dark Shrine for the second time with the "Proceed" objective if skipped.</p>
<p>- Items from the skipped sections will not be collected.</p>
<p>- "Thankful to Be Here," "Grateful for a Worthy Foe," and "Clear Skies" do not unlock on a playthrough that uses the skip feature.</p>
<li>The skip feature does not impact branching paths or endings.</li>
<li>Added Motion Blur option to the Graphics menu</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>System Changes</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Hinako's stamina replenishes slightly faster</li>
<li>Unskippable combat encounters are reduced across multiple sections</li>
<li>Fewer enemies are placed across multiple sections</li>
<li>Hinako's line when an enemy is defeated plays at a slightly later time</li>
<li>Hinako takes slightly less damage on the Hard action difficulty</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Bug Fixes</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Fixed bug where Shu duplicates in the cutscene that plays when heading from Sennensugi Shrine to Rinko's house during the "Head to Rinko's house" objective</li>
<li>Fixed bug where interaction icons do not display on the hall leading to the room with the naginata during the "Enter the inner room" objective</li>
<li>Fixed bug where the Sakuko-like entity stops moving in combat during the "Defeat the Sakuko-like entity" objective</li>
<li>Fixed bug where the Fog Monster stops moving and halts progress during the "Chase after the Fog Monster" objective</li>
<li>Fixed bugs across multiple levels where events do not progress despite meeting the required conditions</li>
<li>Fixed bugs across multiple levels where specific enemies remain outside of the combat area and cannot be defeated</li>
<li>Fixed bugs across multiple levels where clumps of flesh do not spawn</li>
<li>Fixed bug where some notes from "Sakuko's Diary" could not be obtained on New Game+</li>
<li>Fixed bug where Hinako may become unresponsive to player input after dodging</li>
<li>Fixed bug where Hinako dies upon loading an autosave file if Hinako died during an autosave</li>
<li>Fixed bug where the "View Endings" option does not display on the title screen after finishing the first playthrough (may require loading New Game+ data to fix)</li>
<li>Fixed bug where the cursor moves without player input when playing on the controller</li>
<li>*Various other minor bugs have been fixed, including bugs related to audio, hitboxes, text errors, loading, and graphics.</li>
</ul></blockquote>

        </div>

  
      </article>



  



  

  <section>
    <span>Related topics</span>

    
  </section>
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/silent-hill-f-gets-a-fresh-update-that-addresses-combat-concerns-by-introducing-a-much-easier-casual-option]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[From the desk of the Editorial Director of Rock Paper Shotgun: "Ahoy hoy"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/from-the-desk-of-the-editorial-director-of-rock-paper-shotgun-ahoy-hoy</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/from-the-desk-of-the-editorial-director-of-rock-paper-shotgun-ahoy-hoy.1352218/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Awfully nice treehouse you got here</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/julian-benson-welcome-image---less-bum-more-ears.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/julian-benson-welcome-image---less-bum-more-ears.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/julian-benson-welcome-image---less-bum-more-ears.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/julian-benson-welcome-image---less-bum-more-ears.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/julian-benson-welcome-image---less-bum-more-ears.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/julian-benson-welcome-image---less-bum-more-ears.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/julian-benson-welcome-image---less-bum-more-ears.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/julian-benson-welcome-image---less-bum-more-ears.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/julian-benson-welcome-image---less-bum-more-ears.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Rock Paper Shotgun</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Hello. My name is Julian Benson and, as you will have gathered from the headline, I am the new Editorial Director of Rock Paper Shotgun.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>While this is my announcement post, in truth, I've already been here a couple of weeks. However, I didn't want to draw too much attention to myself as I worked through the treehouse, mapping out its dimensions on gridpaper.* I have had some successes in puzzling out the workings of this ancient structure – for instance, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/if-only-more-games-ended-like-hardspace-shipbreaker">finding out how articles are posted</a>. Though, there are many rooms still to uncover, so I may remain in the background a little as I get situated. The bashing of furniture and snarls coming from behind the door marked  'Comment Moderation' suggest I should leave that one till last. But I did want to put my head above the treehouse's parapet – the crenellations are an architectural nod to its earlier days as RPS Towers and Castle RPS – and let you know who I am and why I'm here.</p>
<p>Back in 2012, when I was still working as a volunteer for long-departed gaming site Beefjack (alongside James, coincidentally), I reached out to Jim to pitch an article about transcribing games into musical notation. <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/music-to-my-thumbs-transcribing-braid">The resulting article</a> was more ambitious than my writing ability could sustain, but I'll never forget the depth with which RPS's commenters engaged with and challenged my ideas. In all the years since, it was a level of discussion I've rarely seen at the other sites I've written for. Still, it would be more than a decade before I could return to RPS's pages outside of the Sunday Papers.</p>
<p>In the intervening years, I've worked for sites such as TechRadar Gaming, GAMINGbible, and Kotaku UK, as well as RPS's other other fanzine, PCGamesN. It was only when I returned to freelance in 2023, appearing in Edge, The Guardian, and GQ, that <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/authors/julian-benson">I could once again write on RPS</a>. Even a decade later, it still carries the thrill of that first feature.</p><p>As long as I've been writing about videogames I've been reading RPS, and there is no publication that has had a greater impact on how I talk about games and see their role in our lives. Part of the magic of this site is that it is a place where writers and readers will afford a game equal attention, whether it was made by a single developer or built by thousands. It is a magic conjured by a team of passionate writers, and equally passionate readers, who care about games and how they fit into culture – which is to say, alongside other artforms, neither above nor below them. So when the opportunity to join the team arose, I seized it.</p>
<p>That RPS is a space where this discussion can take place is only because of the hard work of the many members of the team who came before, a line stretching back to the site’s founders. Though I want to acknowledge in particular the size of the shoes Graham has left behind. Each of his boots are big enough to comfortably fit a Clarks outlet in the toe and a Doc Martens warehouse in the heel. Over 12 years, he and the team established and maintained the direction and voice of RPS, making it into the place I have the opportunity to lead today. The footsteps he and the others left are clear and I'm going to try my best to follow them and keep them in sight whenever we strike out into the new.</p>
<p>In the months since Graham's departure, the team has done an excellent job of running RPS. Selfishly, their capability makes my job of proving I can be of some use much harder. Now that I'm here I can't wait to lend a hand wherever I can.</p>
<p>I find the title of 'Editorial Director' to be uncomfortably grand, but it does capture my responsibility: I will be working hard to support this talented team do their best work, and for you, the readers, I will be the point of contact when you want to discuss the direction of the site. I'm not on social media but you can email me or reach out through the comments whenever you need.</p><p>To give you a sense of our current plans, at the moment we are hard at work putting together all the pieces that will see out the end of 2025: Advent Calendars, Selection Boxes, and larger pieces, such as this year's RPS 100, which has seen some significant upsets in the voting since last year's edition – my love of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/orcs-must-die">Orcs Must Die!</a> will not be denied. And we will also be asking for your opinion, too, with a return of the RPS 100: Reader's Edition, which we plan to run through December.</p>
<p>We will have other announcements to make in 2026, I just need to find a way to get Graham's massive shoes out of my office so I can reach the desk…</p>
<p>So for now, I will say 'Hello! I am thrilled to be here'.</p>
<p>*I also used the time honing my Horace-drawing abilities. You can tell me if that time was spent fruitfully.</p>

        </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/from-the-desk-of-the-editorial-director-of-rock-paper-shotgun-ahoy-hoy]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marvel Rivals Season 5 Balance Changes—All Buffs & Nerfs]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-season-5-buffs-nerfs-balance-patch/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/marvel-rivals-season-5-balance-changes%E2%80%94all-buffs-nerfs.1352215/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>A new season is deploying in Marvel Rivals with the launch of Season 5, which naturally comes alongside a fresh balance patch with buffs and nerfs, and we’ve got all the details.</p>



<p>Season 5 in Marvel Rivals features all the tweaks we’ve come to expect with the seasonal transition of the title, including a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-season-5-team-up-changes/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">shake-up to Team-Up Abilities</a>, and tweaks are made to specific heroes to ensure they all remain viable.</p>



<p>For a breakdown of all the buffs and nerfs present in Marvel Rivals for the Season 5 launch, we’ve got all the information you need.</p>







<h2 id="h-all-marvel-rivals-season-5-buffs-amp-nerfs">All Marvel Rivals Season 5 Buffs &amp; Nerfs</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Tweaks. Image via Netease</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Season 5 sees potentially the biggest balance changes of all, and remarkably, there’s not a single nerf at launch. Instead, a host of characters are receiving buffs.</strong></p>



<p>For Vanguards, stand-out changes include Peni Parker’s Cuber-Webs now providing the same Healing Over Time and Movement Boost to ally players as she receives, while Magneto’s Metal Bulwark and Iron Bulwark have had their cooldowns seperated, although the shield value is reduced from 250 to 200.</p>



<p>In the DPS scene, Mister Fantastic’s Bonus Health has been tweaked to provide an addition of 350 Maximum Health and a one-time heal of 350, which is removed upon exiting his inflated state, while Squirrel Girl’s Burst Acorn damage has been increased to 110 from 100.</p>



<p>Finally, two Strategists have seen their base health increased, with Cloak &amp; Dagger and Loki receiving the boost, while Invisible Woman can now deploy a shield in front of her.</p>



<p>Here’s a full list of all the characters affected with buffs and nerfs in Season 5.</p>



<p><strong>Buffs</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Angela</li>



<li>Peni Parker</li>



<li>Magneto</li>



<li>Captain America</li>



<li>Groot</li>



<li>Hulk</li>



<li>The Thing</li>



<li>Hawkeye</li>



<li>Phoenix</li>



<li>Mister Fantastic</li>



<li>Storm</li>



<li>Spider-Man</li>



<li>The Punisher</li>



<li>Wolverine</li>



<li>Adam Warlock</li>



<li>Cloak &amp; Dagger</li>



<li>Invisible Woman</li>



<li>Loki</li>



<li>Rocket Raccoon</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Nerfs</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>None</li>
</ul>







<h2 id="h-full-marvel-rivals-version-20251114-season-5-balance-post-patch-notes">Full Marvel Rivals Version 20251114 Season 5 Balance Post Patch Notes</h2>



<p>Take a look at the full details of the latest balance patch below, as shared on the <a href="https://www.marvelrivals.com/balancepost/20251112/41667_1270634.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">official Marvel Rivals website</a>.</p>



<h4>Angela</h4>



<p>The Hand of Heven sharpens her edge, bringing even (slightly) greater threat to the battlefield.<br>– Increase Movement Speed of Assassin’s Charge accelerated dash state from 16m/s to 18m/s.<br>– Increase Heven’s Retribution (Ultimate Ability) spear Health from 600 to 800.</p>



<h4>Captain America</h4>



<p>Steve Rogers steps up as the ultimate team player!<br>– Freedom Charge (Ultimate Ability) New Effect: Allies within its path gain a 30% boost to Ultimate Energy charge efficiency.</p>



<h4>Groot</h4>



<p>The gentle giant gets tougher!<br>– Ironwood Wall New Effect: Gain Unstoppable status when within 15m of Awakened Ironwood Walls.</p>



<h4>Hulk</h4>



<p>The Green Goliath’s protection game goes gamma!<br>– Gamma Burst New Effect: Each direct hit reduces Indestructible Guard cooldown by 1s.</p>



<h4>Magneto</h4>



<p>Max amplifies his shielding frequency for both self and allies.<br>– Separate the cooldowns of Metal Bulwark and Iron Bulwark. Now, activating one won’t send the other on cooldown.<br>– Reduce Metal Bulwark and Iron Bulwark shield value from 250 to 200.</p>



<h4>Peni Parker</h4>



<p>SP//dr’s pilot takes teamwork to the next level!<br>– Allies in Peni’s Cyber-Webs now receive the same Healing Over Time and a Movement Boost effects as her. Movement Boost for allies is 25%, Healing is 15/s. Ally excess healing converts into Bonus Health, up to 25.</p>



<h4>The Thing</h4>



<p>Ben Grimm doubles down on defense and offense.<br>– Embattled Leap: Remove Damage Reduction from single leap target, now grants 20% Damage Reduction to all allies within 5m of his landing point. Reduce Damage Reduction to self from 25% to 20%.<br>– Battle Blitz: Remove Damage Reduction from self. Now applies 20% Vulnerability to all enemies within 5m of his landing point.<br>– Reduce Stone Haymaker base Damage from 90 to 55 and remove 50 Bonus Health gained during ability activation. New Effects: Deal bonus Damage equal to 8% of enemies’ max Health per hit. Gain Bonus Health equal to damage dealt (up to 100).</p>



<h3>DUELIST</h3>



<h4>Hawkeye</h4>



<p>Clint’s precision packs a slightly bigger punch!<br>– Increase Archer’s Focus maximum Bonus Damage from 75 to 90.</p>



<h4>Mister Fantastic</h4>



<p>Reed Richards gets even stretchier and tougher.<br>– Reflexive Rubber can now be used during Inflated state after reaching 100 Elasticity.<br>– Remove the 350 Bonus Health on entering Inflated state; now gain 350 Maximum Health and a one-time heal of 350, which is removed upon exiting the Inflated state.</p>



<h4>Phoenix</h4>



<p>Jean Grey’s cosmic fire burns brighter:<br>– Adjust Cosmic Flames maximum falloff at 30m from 60% to 75%.</p>



<h4>Spider-Man</h4>



<p>Peter Parker’s web-slinging offense gets a slight lift.<br>– Reduce Web-Cluster energize time from 2.5s to 2s.<br>– Increase Amazing Combo Damage from 60 to 70.</p>



<h4>Squirrel Girl</h4>



<p>Doreen’s nutty offense gets a boost.<br>– Increase Burst Acorn Damage from 100 to 110.</p>



<h4>Storm</h4>



<p>Ororo empowers her allies with even greater force.<br>– Increase Weather Control – Thunder’s Damage Boost to allies from 10% to 12%.<br>– Increase Goddess Boost – Thunder’s Damage Boost to allies from 12% to 15%.</p>



<h4>The Punisher</h4>



<p>Frank Castle loses his Team-Up Anchor bonus, but gains raw power.<br>– Increase base health from 275 to 300.<br>– Adjust Adjudication maximum falloff at 40m from 70% to 85%.<br>– Increase pellets fired per Deliverance round from 14 to 16.</p>



<h4>Wolverine</h4>



<p>Logan’s claws get deadlier, especially against Vanguards.<br>– Increase Savage Claw’s Percentage Damage for each point of Rage from 0.045% to 0.057%.<br>– Increase Vicious Rampage’s Percentage Damage for each point of Rage from 0.045% to 0.057%.<br>– Reduce Feral Leap cooldown from 15s to 12s.</p>



<h3>STRATEGIST</h3>



<h4>Adam Warlock</h4>



<p>Adam’s cosmic control and ultimate impact are enhanced.<br>– Increase soul flight speed from 6m/s to 12m/s.<br>– Reduce Karmic Revival (Ultimate Ability) Energy cost from 4700 to 4500 and increase ally detection radius from 30m to 35m.</p>



<h4>Cloak &amp; Dagger</h4>



<p>The dynamic duo’s durability increases.<br>– Increase base health from 250 to 275.</p>



<h4>Invisible Woman</h4>



<p>Susan Storm’s power and survivability are up.<br>– Increase Orb Projection hit damage from 25 to 30; projectile maximum range from 30m to 35m, and projectile speed from 120m/s to 150m/s.<br>– Increase Force Physics length from 30m to 35m.<br>– Guardian Shield New Effect: If no Guardian Shield is present, pressing the recall key now deploys a shield in front of Invisible Woman.</p>



<h4>Loki</h4>



<p>The Trickster God gets trickier and tougher.<br>– Increase base health from 250 to 275.<br>– Adjust Mystical Missile’s damage falloff at 3m from 50% to 80%. New Effect: Now heals directly hit allies for an extra 10 Health.</p>



<h4>Rocket Raccoon</h4>



<p>Rocket’s support and firepower are slightly tuned up.<br>– Reduce B.R.B. cooldown from 45s to 40s.<br>– Increase Repair Mode maximum count from 5 to 7 and projectile speed from 60m/s to 80m/s.<br>– Increase Bombard Mode Projectile Speed from 150m/s to 180m/s.</p>



<hr>



<p>Are there any characters that should have been nerfed for the start of Season 5 in Marvel Rivals? Let us know your thoughts in the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord</a>.</p>



<p>For more Marvel Rivals, take a look at all the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-season-5-twitch-drops/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Twitch Drops available to earn in Season 5</a>, and find out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-season-5-roadmap-reveals-date-for-rogue-release/">when Rogue is releasing in the ga</a><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-season-5-roadmap-reveals-date-for-rogue-release/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">m</a><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-season-5-roadmap-reveals-date-for-rogue-release/">e</a>.</p>




    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-season-5-buffs-nerfs-balance-patch/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[As Xbox boss responds to Valve's new hardware, fellow Microsoft employee jokes it looks like those "rumoured" Series S leaks]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/as-xbox-boss-responds-to-valves-new-hardware-fellow-microsoft-employee-jokes-it-looks-like-those-rumoured-series-s-leaks</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/as-xbox-boss-responds-to-valves-new-hardware-fellow-microsoft-employee-jokes-it-looks-like-those-rumoured-series-s-leaks.1352209/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>

  <figure>
      <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Phil-Spencer-from-Xbox-overlaid-on-Valve's-Steam-Machine.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Phil-Spencer-from-Xbox-overlaid-on-Valve's-Steam-Machine.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Phil-Spencer-from-Xbox-overlaid-on-Valve's-Steam-Machine.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Phil-Spencer-from-Xbox-overlaid-on-Valve's-Steam-Machine.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Phil-Spencer-from-Xbox-overlaid-on-Valve's-Steam-Machine.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Phil-Spencer-from-Xbox-overlaid-on-Valve's-Steam-Machine.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Phil-Spencer-from-Xbox-overlaid-on-Valve's-Steam-Machine.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Phil-Spencer-from-Xbox-overlaid-on-Valve's-Steam-Machine.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Phil-Spencer-from-Xbox-overlaid-on-Valve's-Steam-Machine.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Eurogamer</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Xbox boss <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/personas/phil-spencer">Phil Spencer</a> has commented on Valve's freshly announced hardware, stating "gaming moves forward when players and developers have more ways to play and create, especially across open platforms".</p>
<p>Writing on social media, the exec praised "open platforms" for this forward momentum. "Expanding access across PC, console, and handheld devices reflects a future built on choice, core values that have guided Xbox's vision from the start," <a href="https://x.com/XboxP3/status/1988677531801944496">Spencer said</a>.</p>
<!-- code from Primis - Eurogamer.net - eurogamer.net -->
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<!-- code from Primis -->
<p>Rounding out his thoughts and congratulating Valve on its hardware announcements, Spencer closed: "As one of the largest publishers on Steam, we welcome new options for players to access games everywhere."</p>
<p>Elsewhere on social media, a fellow Xbox employee in the form of senior social media manager Josh Stein remarked that Valve's new hardware looked kind of like the "rumoured" Xbox Series S designs from back in 2019.</p>
<p>"All hail the cube," <a href="https://x.com/steinekin/status/1988671218099339775">Stein joked</a>.</p>
<figure>
 


<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Eurogamer via X</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>While this may be quite a humorous coincidence, Valve has said the announcement of its Steam Machine stemmed from the company's own PC gaming experience. It is <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/we-dont-work-back-from-whats-happening-in-other-spaces-valves-new-steam-hardware-stems-from-its-pc-gaming-experience-not-what-console-makers-playstation-and-xbox-are-doing">not coming from what fellow console makers such as Xbox were planning</a>.</p>
<p>Speaking to our Will Judd on the new hardware's announcement, Valve said: "We typically just work back from our own experience playing PC games and what we wish was possible to do and what we hear our users say as well."</p><p>Valve's new Steam hardware will be released next year, though release dates are currently unknown. If you're hoping to get your hands on it all, know that <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/will-it-be-easy-to-buy-a-steam-machine-valve-confirms-its-continually-improving-how-it-distributes-hardware-ahead-of-the-release-of-its-new-hardware-launches">Valve will continue to self-distribute hardware just as it did with the Steam Deck</a>.</p>
<p>For more, be sure to check out all of Eurogamer's previews on Valve's upcoming gear - <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/tech-steam-machine-preview-a-powerful-customisable-mini-pc-for-couch-gaming">Steam Machine preview: a powerful, customisable mini PC for couch gaming</a>, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/tech-steam-frame-preview-a-long-awaited-standalone-vr-headset-that-runs-steam-games-on-arm">Steam Frame preview: a long-awaited standalone VR headset that runs Steam games on ARM</a> and <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/tech-steam-controller-preview-a-smart-touch-centric-gamepad-that-also-packs-in-traditional-controls">Steam Controller preview: a smart, touch-centric gamepad that also packs in traditional controls</a>.</p>

        </div>

  
      </article>



  




  <section>
    <span>Related topics</span>

    
  </section>
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/as-xbox-boss-responds-to-valves-new-hardware-fellow-microsoft-employee-jokes-it-looks-like-those-rumoured-series-s-leaks]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Steam Machine Pricing Will Be ‘Really Competitive’ with Building a Similar PC Yourself, Says Valve]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/steam-machine-pricing-will-be-really-competitive-with-building-a-similar-pc/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/steam-machine-pricing-will-be-%E2%80%98really-competitive%E2%80%99-with-building-a-similar-pc-yourself-says-valve.1352203/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>Following Valve's <a href="https://wccftech.com/valve-unveils-steam-frame-steam-machine-steam-controller-launch-early-2026/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">trio of hardware announcements</a> (the Steam Machine, the Steam Frame, and the Steam Controller), the biggest question users were left with was pricing. However, <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/valves-next-gen-steam-machine-and-steam-controller-the-big-interview" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">speaking to IGN</a>, Valve's Hardware Engineer Yazan Aldehayyat did not shy from sharing a few things about the pricing of the Steam Machine, stating that it will be very competitive with building a PC with similar hardware. </p>



<p><em>If you're trying to make a PC that has similar features and similar performance, I think the Steam Machine is going to be a really competitive price to that and provide really good value to it. The affordability piece you mentioned is one of the reasons why we think a Steam Machine makes a lot of sense right now. So it's just something that we thought about every time we made a hardware decision, a feature decision, is to make sure that we keep it as approachable, as affordable as possible.</em></p>



<p>Let's take another look at the specifications, then.</p>



<figure><table><thead><tr><th>Category</th><th>Specification</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td><strong>I/O</strong></td><td></td></tr><tr><td>Displays</td><td><strong>DisplayPort 1.4:</strong><br>- Up to 4K @ 240Hz or 8K@60Hz<br>- Supports HDR, FreeSync, daisy-chaining<br><strong>HDMI 2.0:</strong><br>- Up to 4K @ 120Hz<br>- Supports HDR, FreeSync, CEC</td></tr><tr><td>USB</td><td>- Two USB-A 3.2 Gen 1 (front)<br>- Two USB-A 2.0 High speed (back)<br>- One USB-C 3.2 Gen 2 (back)</td></tr><tr><td>Networking</td><td>Gigabit ethernet</td></tr><tr><td>LED Strip</td><td>17 individually addressable RGB LEDs for system status and customization</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Size &amp; Weight</strong></td><td></td></tr><tr><td>Size</td><td>152 mm tall (148 mm without feet), 162.4 mm deep, 156 mm wide</td></tr><tr><td>Weight</td><td>2.6 kg</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Software</strong></td><td></td></tr><tr><td>Operating System</td><td>SteamOS 3 (Arch-based)</td></tr><tr><td>Desktop</td><td>KDE Plasma</td></tr><tr><td><strong>General</strong></td><td></td></tr><tr><td>CPU</td><td>Semi-custom AMD Zen 4 6 Cores /12 Threads<br>- Up to 4.8 GHz, 30W TDP</td></tr><tr><td>GPU</td><td>Semi-custom AMD RDNA3 28 Compute Units<br>- 2.45GHz max sustained clock, 110W TDP</td></tr><tr><td>RAM</td><td>16GB DDR5 + 8GB GDDR6 VRAM</td></tr><tr><td>Power</td><td>Internal power supply, AC 110-240V</td></tr><tr><td>Storage</td><td>Two models, both with a high-speed microSD slot:<br>- 512GB NVMe SSD<br>- 2TB NVMe SSD</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Connectivity</strong></td><td></td></tr><tr><td>Wi-Fi</td><td>2x2 Wi-Fi 6E</td></tr><tr><td>Bluetooth</td><td>Bluetooth 5.3 with a dedicated antenna</td></tr><tr><td>Steam Controller</td><td>Integrated 2.4 GHz Steam Controller wireless adapter</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<p>Valve claims it arrived at these hardware specifications after carefully analyzing the Steam hardware survey, with the goal of enabling 4K@60Hz performance in all Steam games (through upscaling). However, Digital Foundry <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2rv83LgXiN0" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">noted</a> that in their early test at Valve, Cyberpunk 2077 ran at 1440p@60FPS upscaled to 4K, but dropped to 30 frames per second as soon as they enabled ray traced reflections and sun shadows. The folks at DF estimate the performance of the Steam Machine to be positioned somewhere between an Xbox Series S and a PlayStation 5, possibly closer to the latter.</p>



<p>The Xbox Series S is now <a href="https://wccftech.com/xbox-series-xs-price-increase-europe/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">priced at $379.99</a> (in its 512GB model), while the PlayStation 5 (digital edition) <a href="https://wccftech.com/playstation-5-price-increased/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">costs $499.99</a>. Both consoles received price hikes this year, mainly due to the tariffs. Still, if Valve really wants to break into the living room this time around, it needs to be competitive with them, not just with a PC, which is notoriously more expensive. At the very least, it should cost less than the PlayStation 5 Pro (currently priced at $749.99), being far less powerful on paper. </p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/steam-machine-pricing-will-be-really-competitive-with-building-a-similar-pc/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marvel Rivals Season 5 Roadmap Reveals Date For Rogue Release]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-season-5-roadmap-reveals-date-for-rogue-release/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/marvel-rivals-season-5-roadmap-reveals-date-for-rogue-release.1352197/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Marvel Rivals is set to switch over into a new season with the launch of Season 5, with two new characters joining the battlefield, and the roadmap for the season has revealed when Rogue will be playable.</p>



<p>Rogue is one of two new additions to the Marvel Rivals character roster in Season 5, alongside her partner, Gambit. However, while Remy LeBeau will be available from the start of Season 5 on November 14, players will have to wait a little bit longer for Rogue’s arrival.</p>







<h2 id="h-rogue-joins-marvel-rivals-on-december-12">Rogue Joins Marvel Rivals on December 12</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Lots to come. Image via NetEase</figcaption></figure>



<p>NetEase has shared an <a href="https://x.com/MarvelRivals/status/1988683430242943375" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">official roadmap</a> for the content coming in Season 5, which reveals the release date for several new costumes, the start of the Anniversary Event, where players can earn up to $25 worth of currency for free, and the launch of the 18-vs-18 Conquest Annihilation game mode.</p>



<p>However, the biggest news of all confirms just how long the first half of the season will last, as it’s revealed that Season 5.5 will begin on December 12.</p>



<p>We don’t yet know all of the content that will be launching at the start of Season 5.5, but we do know the mid-point in the season will mark the arrival of Rogue.</p>







<p>Given the time of the year Season 5.5 launches, it’s expected that a Holiday Event to cover Christmas and the New Year will be on the cards at some point, while Season 6 will launch in January 2026.</p>



<hr>



<p>What do you want to see added to Marvel Rivals in 2026? Let us know your wishlist in the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord</a>.</p>



<p>For more Marvel Rivals, check out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-season-5-team-up-changes/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">all the changes to Team-Up Abilities in Season 5</a>, and take a look at <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-teases-deadpool-elsa-bloodstone-as-next-characters/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">teasers for the next batch of heroes in Season 6</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-season-5-roadmap-reveals-date-for-rogue-release/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NCSOFT Says Horizon Steel Frontiers Could Launch as Early as Next Year, and Its Early Reception Has Been Great]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/ncsoft-says-horizon-steel-frontiers-could-launch-as-early-as-next-year/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ncsoft-says-horizon-steel-frontiers-could-launch-as-early-as-next-year-and-its-early-reception-has-been-great.1352185/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>This morning, South Korean developer NCSOFT (Lineage, Aion, Throne and Liberty) took the stage at G-Star 2025 to <a href="https://wccftech.com/horizon-steel-frontiers-is-a-full-fledged-mmorpg-for-pc-and-mobile/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">announce</a> the long-rumored Horizon Steel Frontiers MMORPG. The game, which is targeting a launch on PC and mobile, is a collaboration between the studio and franchise holder Guerrilla Games.</p>



<p>The announcement provided a few initial and fairly vague details, such as the region (the Deadlands, modeled after Arizona and New Mexico) the game will take place in, the fact that players will cooperate to take down machines but also compete for resources and fight against rival tribes, and the tweaks made to the combat system. The developers claim there will be new mechanics, such as climbing onto a damaged machine part with the Pullcaster to set traps and inflict status effects, picking up weapons dropped during battle, carrying them on your mount, and using them at a later time. Perhaps the biggest difference shown in the debut Horizon Steel Frontiers gameplay, though, is the addition of greatswords. Whereas Aloy only ever used a spear for melee while heavily favoring bows, it looks like this game will allow proper melee combat with parries and counterattacks.</p>



<p>What neither the announcement video nor the official press release mentioned was any launch window. However, NCSOFT executives spoke about it two days ago during the company's <a href="https://irsvc.teletogether.com/ncsoft/ncsoft.php?c=ncsoft&amp;y=3230" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Q3 2025 earnings call</a>. They were confident that it could launch in 2026 or early 2027 and also boasted of having received acclaim from those who had already played it.</p>



<p><em>Internally, the development has progressed pretty significantly, so we think that based on the development progress, it would be available to be launched either next year or early two years from now, but we need to discuss the specifics with the IP holder. What I want to emphasize is that significant progress has been made in development, so with refinement, we will be able to release this title, too. Everyone gave us a round of applause after viewing the demonstration and playing the game firsthand.</em></p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="[Horizon Steel Frontiers] Gameplay Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9qwAulK6db4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>Of course, with game development becoming increasingly complex, especially for an MMORPG, I would say there's a solid chance we'll see it in 2027. Still, that NCSOFT thinks it could launch as early as next year suggests we could at least be able to try the game in pre-release testing events throughout 2026.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/ncsoft-says-horizon-steel-frontiers-could-launch-as-early-as-next-year/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Utawarerumono: Shiro e no Michishirube latest information broadcast set for November 22]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/11/utawarerumono-shiro-e-no-michishirube-latest-information-broadcast-set-for-november-22</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/utawarerumono-shiro-e-no-michishirube-latest-information-broadcast-set-for-november-22.1352182/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
        </ul>

    
    <p><span>Utawarerumono: Lost Flag sixth anniversary broadcast to follow.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > AQUAPLUS [218 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/yukes/aquaplus">AQUAPLUS</a> will host the “<em><a title="Games > Utawarerumono: Shiro e no Michishirube [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/utawarerumono-shiro-e-no-michishirube">Utawarerumono: Shiro e no Michishirube</a></em> Official Broadcast: Latest Information Special” on <a href="https://www.timeanddate.com/worldclock/fixedtime.html?iso=20251122T0600" target="_blank">November 22 at 15:00 JST</a>, the company <a href="https://blog.aquaplus.jp/archives/11982" target="_blank">announced</a>. You will be able to watch it on <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=M6httGZ3aNA" target="_blank">YouTube</a>. <span id="more-1006666"></span></p><p>The broadcast will feature the latest information on <em>Utawarerumono: Shiro e no Michishirube</em>, which is due out for unannounced platforms in 2026 in Japan. Presenters include Kentaro Tone (Oshtor voice actor), Yuuko Minaguchi (Shunya voice actor), and Yuuya Uchida (Mikazuchi voice actor).</p><p>After that broadcast ends, AQUAPLUS will host the “<em><a title="Series > Utawarerumono [21 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/series/utawarerumono">Utawarerumono</a>: Lost Flag</em> Official Broadcast: 6th Anniversary Special” on <a href="https://www.timeanddate.com/worldclock/fixedtime.html?iso=20251122T0800" target="_blank">November 22 at 17:00 JST</a>, featuring the latest information on the mobile game with presenters Kentaro Tone (Haku / Oshtor voice actor), Yuuya Uchida (Mikazuchi voice actor), Kazuya Nakai (Akuta voice actor), and Ryouka Yuzuki (Eruru voice actor). You will be able to watch it on <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=csJm411WzUA" target="_blank">YouTube</a>.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/11/utawarerumono-shiro-e-no-michishirube-latest-information-broadcast-set-for-november-22]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Square Enix Switch 2 Launch Title Scores A Limited-Time Discount]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/11/square-enix-switch-2-launch-title-scores-a-limited-time-discount</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/square-enix-switch-2-launch-title-scores-a-limited-time-discount.1352176/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Don't miss this Bravely Default eShop sale</p>
</section></header><section>
<figure data-uuid="3dd507bdaf4be"><a title="Bravely Default" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/3dd507bdaf4be/bravely-default.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Square Enix</em></figcaption></figure><p>We're now roughly six months into the life of the Switch 2, and we're starting to see multiple third-party launch titles go on sale on the eShop.</p>
<p>Following price cuts to titles such as CDPR's <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/cyberpunk-2077-ultimate-edition">Cyberpunk 2077</a> and Capcom's <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/street-fighter-6-years-1-2-fighters-edition">Street Fighter 6</a>, Square Enix is now offering <strong>20% off</strong> its role-playing game <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/bravely-default-flying-fairy-hd-remaster">Bravely Default: Flying Fairy HD Remaster</a> in select locations. So, if you've been holding off, now might be the time to finally add it to your digital library. This sale reduces it from the regular price of <strong>$39.99 / £33.99</strong> to just <strong>$31.99 / £27.19</strong>, and ends next week.</p>
<p>Square Enix is also celebrating this sale by sharing the following "prequel scenario" featuring Tiz (illustration by Naoki Ikushima, scenario by Keiichi Ajiro):</p>
<figure data-uuid="3cbf4455c94d7"><a title="Bravely Default" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/3cbf4455c94d7/bravely-default.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Square Enix</em></figcaption></figure>
<p><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/3ds/bravely_default">Bravely Default</a> originally made its debut on the 3DS, and this updated version comes loaded with not only the main adventure but also brand new minigames utilising Joy-Con 2 mouse mode. The game was also updated on Switch 2 last month, with various fixes, adjustments and improvements.</p>

<p>If you haven't already tried it out on Nintendo's new hardware, be sure to take a look at our review - we called it a solid refresh for the 3DS gem.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"Bravely Default: Flying Fairy HD Remaster is a solid update of one of Square’s finest modern turn-based RPGs. Its combination of a flexible job system, dynamic combat, and unexpectedly interesting story makes for an adventure that no fans of the JRPG genre will want to miss out on, especially any such fans that enjoyed Team Asano’s more recent work on the Octopath Traveler duology."</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Square Enix also rolled out a Switch and Switch 2 demo this week for the upcoming RPG <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/octopath-traveler-0">Octopath Traveler 0</a>.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:193754,192397,183379 @ 1763033320 -->
<p>Have you tried out this game on the Switch 2 yet? Will you be taking up this offer? <em>Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section></article><div><p>Liam is a news writer and reviewer across Hookshot Media. He's been writing about games for more than 15 years and is a lifelong fan of many iconic video game characters.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Liam_Doolan"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/liamdoolan.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Liam_Doolan');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/11/square-enix-switch-2-launch-title-scores-a-limited-time-discount]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Horizon Steel Frontiers Is a Full-Fledged MMORPG for PC and Mobile]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/horizon-steel-frontiers-is-a-full-fledged-mmorpg-for-pc-and-mobile/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/horizon-steel-frontiers-is-a-full-fledged-mmorpg-for-pc-and-mobile.1352173/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>Three years after <a href="https://wccftech.com/horizon-mmo-game-reportedly-in-the-works-supposedly-made-by-sony-and-ncsoft/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the first rumors on the project</a>, NCSOFT has now unveiled Horizon Steel Frontiers at G-Star 2025. This is a full-fledged MMORPG for PC (via the South Korean studio's PURPLE platform) and mobile (iOS and Android) based on Guerrilla Games' popular action/adventure franchise.</p>



<p>The announcement video features comments from Jan-Bart van Beek, now Studio Head at the Dutch developer, and also the person who came up with the original concept of Horizon. Van Beek says this is a version of the world that's meant to be played 'anywhere and at any time' (on mobile devices), and adds that Guerrilla was able to playtest the game and feels amazing about it, as it sports a unique identity that also fits with the universe. The Guerrilla Games Studio Head also seemed to hint that there will be PvP in addition to PvE:</p>



<p><em>You're sharing the frontier with thousands of other players, sometimes working together to take down machines, other times competing with rival tribes or fighting over resources. That mix of cooperation and competition creates moments that you could never script. At the heart of Horizon's story is the search for the balance between humanity, nature, and technology. And sometimes that's harmony, sometimes that's conflict, but it always creates a world filled with mystery and beauty.</em></p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="[Horizon Steel Frontiers] Announcement Video" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/bN-NNgWIyIQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>In the video, Sung-gu Lee, the Executive Producer of Horizon Steel Frontiers at NCSOFT, talked about tweaking the franchise's signature combat for an MMORPG:</p>



<p><em>Our main focus is designing a new combat experience tailored for an MMORPG. In Horizon Steel Frontiers, we’ve added unique, original gameplay elements to the process of taking down giant machines. For example, after destroying a specific part of a machine, you can quickly approach and climb onto it using a Pullcaster, set traps on the damaged part, and inflict status effects. During battle, you can even pick up weapons dropped by the machine, carry them on your mount, and use them in subsequent fights.</em></p>



<p><em>At the heart of giant machine hunts are two core values: cooperation and strategy. Players must take on their roles, act strategically, and work together seamlessly. These combat mechanics truly shine in large-scale battles, offering the scale and dynamism that only an MMORPG can provide.</em></p>



<p>Horizon Steel Frontiers will take place in a new area of the post-apocalyptic United States, known as the Deadlands, which is inspired by the landscapes of New Mexico and Arizona.</p>



<p>More details will undoubtedly follow. Meanwhile, you can find the official website <a href="https://hsf.plaync.com/en-us/conts/teaser" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">at this URL</a>.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/horizon-steel-frontiers-is-a-full-fledged-mmorpg-for-pc-and-mobile/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Solo Leveling: KARMA G-STAR 2025 trailer, opening movie]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/11/solo-leveling-karma-g-star-2025-trailer-opening-movie</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/solo-leveling-karma-g-star-2025-trailer-opening-movie.1352170/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/mobile/smartphone">Smartphone</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>The untold 27-year war.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Netmarble [49 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/netmarble">Netmarble</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Netmarble Neo [4 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/netmarble/netmarble-neo">Netmarble Neo</a> have released the G-STAR 2025 trailer and opening movie for <a title="Genres > Roguelite [306 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/roguelite">roguelite</a> <a title="Genres > Action RPG [1,854 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg/action-rpg">action RPG</a> <em><a title="Games > Solo Leveling: KARMA [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/solo-leveling-karma">Solo Leveling: KARMA</a></em>. <span id="more-1006659"></span></p><p>The opening animation is produced by A-1 Pictures, the same studio that handles production of the <em>Solo Leveling</em> anime series.</p><p><em>Solo Leveling: KARMA</em> will be available for <a title="Platforms > PC [24,781 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a>, iOS, and Android. A release date has yet to be announced.</p><p>Watch the footage below.</p><h2><span>G-STAR 2025 Trailer</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><iframe title="Official Solo Leveling: KARMA G-STAR 2025 Trailer – First Reveal!" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/vjOwu_1NCIc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe title="『俺だけレベルアップな件：KARMA』G-STAR 2025公式PV初公開！" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/0ZsaVZQ9kMM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Korean</strong></p><p><iframe title="나 혼자만 레벨업: 카르마, G-STAR 2025 공식 PV 공개!" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rsh2GD85nHM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><span>Opening Movie</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="First Reveal of the Solo Leveling: KARMA Opening!" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/xfvGregm0tc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="『俺だけレベルアップな件：KARMA』 OP 初公開！ ​" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/egxyaU9oTkY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Korean</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="나 혼자만 레벨업: 카르마 오프닝 최초 공개!" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/EVQJNW_yWuU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><span>G-STAR 2025 Day 1: Live Creator Showdown <a title="Games > Session: Skate Sim [8 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/session-skate-sim">Session</a>s</span></h2><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="[🔴LIVE] Live Creator Showdown Sessions🎮Solo Leveling: KARMA | G-STAR 2025 DAY 1" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wEoO0z0ly7c?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/11/solo-leveling-karma-g-star-2025-trailer-opening-movie]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokémon Unite Is Discontinuing Aeos Coins In Its December Game Update]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/11/pokemon-unite-is-discontinuing-aeos-coins-in-its-december-game-update</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pok%C3%A9mon-unite-is-discontinuing-aeos-coins-in-its-december-game-update.1352167/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Taking place alongside the introduction of "License Journeys"</p>
</section></header><section>
<figure data-uuid="1019b97439709"><a title="Pokemon Unite" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/1019b97439709/pokemon-unite.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: The Pokémon Company</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>The free-to-play MOBA <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/pokemon_unite">Pokémon Unite</a> has experienced all sorts of updates since arriving on the Switch eShop and mobile devices in 2021, but this latest announcement appears to have <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/PokemonUnite/comments/1ovrgay/aeos_coins_are_gone/">a lot of the community talking</a> about the title's future.</p>
<p>In an in-game notification, it's been revealed as of <strong>4th December 2025</strong>, Aeos coins will no longer be distributed. Nintendo Life can confirm the following in-game message. Here's the part of this notice focused on Aeos coins:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>As of <strong>December 4, 2025</strong>, Aeos coins will no longer be distributed, and the Unite Battle Comittee will no longer offer Unite licenses in exchange for Aeos coins. If you would like to obtain Unite licenses via Aeos coins, please do so by that date.</p></blockquote><div><figure data-videoid="RLc1VHm8D80" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/RLc1VHm8D80?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><div><iframe id="ytRLc1VHm8D80" title="YouTube Video" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/RLc1VHm8D80?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/RLc1VHm8D80?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed43f22fnmxpgo&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>838k</span></a></p>
</div></figure></div><blockquote>
<p>Aeos coin boost cards will become unusable starting December 4, 2025. We plan to allow remaining ones to be exchangeable for Aeos coins. This will be implemented at a later date.</p>
<p>After December 4, 2025, the Unite Battle Committee will, however, continue to offer Unite licenses in exchange for Aeos gems.</p>
<p>Aeos Coin Exchange</p>
<p>An Aeos Coin Exchange will become available December 4, 2025. Here, players will be able to exchange previously earned Aeos coins for license points or various items.</p>
<p>Aeos coins and the Aeos Coin Exchange will remain in-game <strong>until May 2026</strong>.</p>
</blockquote>
<figure data-uuid="e08376960df62"><a title="Pokemon Unite" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/e08376960df62/pokemon-unite.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Nintendo Life / The Pokémon Company</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>This discontinuation of Aeos coins will take place alongside the introduction of License Journeys on the same date (4th December 2025). These will give players a new way to obtain Licenses in Unite by playing the game and accumulating License points. These can be obtained as battle pass rewards, from random boxes, or as rewards from future events. Here's a bit more about this new feature:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"Typically, each time the player selects a Unite license to work toward, they'll choose from five available licenses. However, there will also be times players can choose from all the Unite licenses in the game. Unite licenses for newly released Pokémon may also become available via License Journeys at the same time they're released in the shop."</p>
</blockquote>
<p>2025 marks the fourth anniversary of Pokémon Unite. Over the years it's been expanded with new playable Pokémon, maps, modes and much more, and is also playable on the Switch 2.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:172506,134585,118735 @ 1763033360 -->
<p>If we hear anything else, we'll let you know. What are your thoughts about this update? <em>Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section></article><div><p>Liam is a news writer and reviewer across Hookshot Media. He's been writing about games for more than 15 years and is a lifelong fan of many iconic video game characters.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Liam_Doolan"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/liamdoolan.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Liam_Doolan');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/11/pokemon-unite-is-discontinuing-aeos-coins-in-its-december-game-update]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Several’ Tier 1 Counter-Strike 2 Events Won’t Happen in 2026, It’s Confirmed]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/several-tier-1-counter-strike-events-not-happening/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/%E2%80%98several%E2%80%99-tier-1-counter-strike-2-events-won%E2%80%99t-happen-in-2026-it%E2%80%99s-confirmed.1352164/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>In a recent post on social media, the CEO of PGL, Silviu Stroie, confirmed that ‘several’ high-tier Counter-Strike 2 tournaments won’t take place in 2026. This is because an announcement pathway wasn’t followed, which unfortunately violates Valve’s tournament operation requirements.</p>



<p>The post on social media confirmed that <strong>none of the Starladder events </strong>in 2026 will take place, and two of the three Fissure events in 2026 have also been struck from the schedule.</p>







<h2 id="h-cs2-events-slashed-from-the-schedule">CS2 Events Slashed From the Schedule</h2>



<p><a href="https://x.com/ssilviu/status/1988490449951015313" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The post</a> from Silviu Stroie, CEO of PGL, reads:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>Several CS2 Tier 1 events in 2026 won’t take place, as they missed the deadline for announcing the additional details. None of the Starladder CS2 Tier 1 events in 2026 will take place. The same applies to two of the three Fissure CS2 Tier 1 events in 2026 (Playground 4 and Playground 5). So far, there has been no Starladder announcement for any Tier 1 event in 2027.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>In one of the most important comments under the post, a user wrote, ‘How can this happen? Like, if you know that this is a requirement, there’s like a 0% chance of missing the deadline if it’s your main business.’</p>



<p>Valve’s tournament operation requirements demand that organizers provide ‘additional information’ within a certain timeframe after an initial announcement. That deadline was missed by some, and therefore, these tournaments will not be allowed to go ahead.</p>







<p>Neither of the organizers impacted by this confirmation have provided a statement to say what’s happening, but Stroie also mentioned that no Starladder events have been announced (at Tier 1) going into 2027, which is cryptic to say the least. This was later refuted by Starladder, as the company revealed that ‘the next Tier-1 Starladder event comes in October 2027’.</p>



<p>Are you bothered about the loss of these events, or do you feel that there are already enough Counter-Strike tournaments lined up? Let me know on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tarkov-twitch-drops-campaign-confirmed/">Escape from Tarkov has a new Twitch Drops campaign</a></p>




    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/several-tier-1-counter-strike-events-not-happening/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Escape from Tarkov Twitch Drops Campaign Confirmed for Launch]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/tarkov-twitch-drops-campaign-confirmed/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/escape-from-tarkov-twitch-drops-campaign-confirmed-for-launch.1352161/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>This weekend, Escape from Tarkov hits a 1.0 state after a <strong>decade </strong>in testing and development. It’s a monumental time to be a fan of the spearhead extraction shooter, and the release comes as the genre is experiencing something of a boom, spurred onwards by the recent arrival of ARC Raiders.</p>



<p>Battlestate Games confirmed that Escape from Tarkov will have a new Twitch Drops campaign that’s kicking off to celebrate the launch of the game on November 15, this coming Saturday.</p>







<h2 id="h-tarkov-twitch-drops-coming">Tarkov Twitch Drops Coming</h2>



<p>From November 15 to December 6, Tarkov fans will be able to watch their favorite streamers exploring the new 1.0 update that brings the game into an entirely new world. The drops will reward players with different reward crates, containing some loot that could be considered highly exclusive:</p>



<ul>
<li>Hideout Targets</li>



<li>Tarko Figuring</li>



<li>Nikita’s PMC Voice</li>
</ul>



<p>There’s a split between the rewards coming to the Escape from Tarkov Twitch Drops campaign, and that’s between <strong>free </strong>and <strong>paid-for </strong>rewards. If you dish out subscriptions during the event, you’ll unlock even more content in Escape from Tarkov:</p>



<ul>
<li>5 Subs – Cap, M-2 Brown &amp; Secure Container</li>



<li>3 Subs – PMC Dogtag (Twitch)</li>



<li>1 Sub – Hideout Decor</li>
</ul>



<figure></figure>







<p><a href="https://www.escapefromtarkov.com/news/id/361" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">It was stressed</a> that the split is timed differently, too. The free drops run until November 28, while the paid rewards will stay live until December 6.</p>







<p>More content will be added, per a graphic published by Battlestate Games, so expect plenty of rewards to flow going into Escape from Tarkov’s 1.0 release – provided you watch those streaming the game. The 1.0 update is highly anticipated and will bring a new map, story, and many other quality-of-life improvements and upgrades.</p>



<p>Are you looking forward to Escape from Tarkov’s 1.0 release? Let me know what you’re thinking on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/escape-from-tarkov-pve-platform-change-coming/">Tarkov’s PvE platform might have a big change coming</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/tarkov-twitch-drops-campaign-confirmed/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ARC Raiders North Line Update Release Time—Stella Montis Unlock]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/north-line-update-release-time-arc-raiders/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/arc-raiders-north-line-update-release-time%E2%80%94stella-montis-unlock.1352155/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>ARC Raiders has a new supersized update inbound called North Line, and it introduces a new map, new ARC enemies, weapons, quests, and more. It will be made accessible via a community event that requires all users to contribute to a project to bust open a tunnel leading to the new map, Stella Montis.</p>



<p>Many are wondering when the North Line update will be released. It’s coming out today, but the release time for the update isn’t clear. Read on to learn what we know about the ARC Raiders North Line update release times.</p>







<h2 id="h-when-is-north-line-releasing-on-arc-raiders">When is North Line Releasing on ARC Raiders?</h2>



<p><strong>The North Line update for ARC Raiders will be released today, November 13, at 09:30 AM GMT / 04:30 AM ET / 01:30 AM PT.</strong> This timing convention is to allow for a unified launch of the update across all platforms and territories.</p>



<p>Fans of the post-apocalyptic extraction shooter will be able to enjoy some of the trappings of the North Line update when it drops, but the bulk of it will come after <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/new-arc-raiders-map-open-breaking-new-ground/">the Breaking New Ground event</a> has been completed.</p>



<p>This is where players must contribute Metal Parts, Fabric, Chemicals, Plastic Parts, and Rubber Parts to the centralized project to open up the tunnels to Stella Montis. Here, players will be able to explore a new path in ‘Staking Our Claim’, digging deep into Stella Montis, facing new ARC threats, and preparing for the <strong>next </strong>major ARC Raiders update – Cold Snap.</p>







<p>There’s a busy roadmap ahead, and Embark Studios has promised to support ARC Raiders for the next decade, so expect plenty more maps, modes, weapons, and more to be added in the coming months to make way for that lifecycle.</p>



<p>Are you enjoying ARC Raiders? Let me know what you’re thinking about the game on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/escape-from-tarkov-pve-platform-change-coming/">Escape from Tarkov might be facing a drastic change</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/north-line-update-release-time-arc-raiders/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Escape from Tarkov’s PvE Platform Might Have a Drastic Change Coming]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/escape-from-tarkov-pve-platform-change-coming/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/escape-from-tarkov%E2%80%99s-pve-platform-might-have-a-drastic-change-coming.1352152/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Escape from Tarkov is finally being ‘released’ this week after a decade in alpha and beta stages. It brings an end to years of development that have culminated in Escape from Tarkov being the most popular extraction shooter ever made. It’s a paradigm shift of a title that’s evolving into a 1.0 state this coming Saturday.</p>



<p>In a recent interview, the head of the studio at Battlestate Games, Nikita Buyanov, suggested that a drastic balancing mechanic might be put into play for Escape from Tarkov’s PvE platform.</p>







<h2 id="h-they-might-wipe-the-pve-flea-market">They Might Wipe the PvE Flea Market</h2>



<p>Nikita suggested in a recent interview with Pestily that the team at Battlestate Games might wipe the Flea Market <strong>specifically on the PvE platform </strong>when 1.0 drops. Pestily addressed the Flea Market being ‘filled with stuff’ that PvE players have collected over many months, impacting the mode’s economy.</p>



<p>Nikita said:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>We will see. Maybe we will wipe the Flea Market, for example.</p>



<p>Nobody said that we can’t do that. We can wipe the Flea Market, and nobody will say anything to us, because the Flea Market is just a sub-system that we can wipe.</p>
</blockquote>



<figure><div><blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>I laughed out loud at this clip <a href="https://twitter.com/nikgeneburn?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@nikgeneburn</a>.  Glad you are keeping your humor!</p><p>In <a href="https://twitter.com/Pestily?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@Pestily</a>'s interview today, Nikita says they might wipe the flea for PvE to keep people from snowballing with 1.0…</p><p>BUT…. if this is all you guys have planned It's not enough, you are going to… <a href="https://t.co/VZCegXIYsE">pic.twitter.com/VZCegXIYsE</a></p></div>— Airwingmarine (@Airwingmarine1) <a href="https://twitter.com/Airwingmarine1/status/1988718220728234146?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 12, 2025</a></blockquote></div></figure>



<p><br>Escape from Tarkov players focused on <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tarkov-pve-players-need-to-wipe-for-full-release-quest/">PvE will need to wipe their accounts</a> to access the new story being introduced with 1.0. This story will finally allow players to <strong>escape from Tarkov</strong>, presenting them with a branching campaign with multiple endings.</p>



<p>This is bad news for the PvE players (like myself) who have spent the last year racking up a phenomenal stash and building the strongest character they’ve ever made, simply because PvE <strong>doesn’t automatically wipe</strong>.</p>







<p>The economy that has been created because of that is a little skewed, so pushing for a reset of this kind might be a neat balancing tactic.</p>



<p>Do you think that Battlestate Games should better balance the PvE platform? Let me know on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/death-stranding-isolations-anime-disney-kojima/">a Death Stranding anime is coming</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/escape-from-tarkov-pve-platform-change-coming/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>