<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2025 19:56:05 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Says The eShop Is Better On Switch 2, But Offers Vague Answer About Stick Drift]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/switch-2-stick-drift-joy-con-eshop-fix-better-nintendo-1851774614</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-says-the-eshop-is-better-on-switch-2-but-offers-vague-answer-about-stick-drift.1154664/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/switch-2-stick-drift-joy-con-eshop-fix-better-nintendo-1851774614<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Nintendo claims that it has built better, nicer controllers to help avoid <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/joy-con-drift-is-becoming-a-real-problem-on-the-switch-1836417809&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/joy-con-drift-is-becoming-a-real-problem-on-the-switch-1836417809">stick drift</a></span> on the Switch 2, and that it’s made the new console’s eShop snappier and easier to use. But the company’s answers haven’t fully convinced me that we shouldn’t be worried as we approach the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/nintendo-switch-2-price-release-date-specs-1851773502&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/nintendo-switch-2-price-release-date-specs-1851773502">Switch 2's launch on June 5.</a></span></p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="195670" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="This Stylish Noir-Punk Side-Scroller Is Like Celeste With Guns" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="184" data-playlist="195670,196181,196230" data-current="195670"><div><p>This Stylish Noir-Punk Side-Scroller Is Like Celeste With Guns</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195670/195670_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195670/195670_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195670/195670_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195670/195670_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21167.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>In a roundtable interview with press about the upcoming console, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/nintendo-switch-2-price-release-date-specs-1851773502&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/nintendo-switch-2-price-release-date-specs-1851773502">Nintendo Switch 2</a></span> producer Kouichi Kawamoto was asked about the console’s eShop and he made it clear that using the digital storefront should be a great experience, like it was back on the Wii. </p><p> “Maybe this is a little bit controversial, but in terms of applications on the Wii, I probably booted the Wii shopping channel the most out of any application,” said Kawamoto, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.gamesradar.com/games/switch-2s-producer-made-requests-in-great-detail-and-great-amounts-to-make-sure-the-eshop-is-as-good-as-the-wii-shop-channel/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.gamesradar.com/games/switch-2s-producer-made-requests-in-great-detail-and-great-amounts-to-make-sure-the-eshop-is-as-good-as-the-wii-shop-channel/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">as reported by <em>Eurogamer</em></a></span> who attended the roundtable event. <em>Kotaku</em> wasn’t invited. </p><p> “So when it comes to the eShop, I wanted to make sure that it was a smooth experience, that the scrolling of the list doesn’t stop, that it’s very smooth, pages load fast. These are all requests that I made to the team in great detail and great amounts.” </p><p>Switch 2 technical director Tetsuya Sasaki says that the team worked really hard to “make Mr. Kawamoto happy,” including the various people who worked on the console’s network service, server apps, software, and more.</p><p>This sounds great, and is a much-needed improvement over the old Switch. Trying to navigate that console’s eShop is about as fun as pulling teeth. Things take forever to load, menus are unresponsive, and the shop is filled with garbage. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/nintendo-eshop-switch-slop-clones-unpacking-scam-ai-art-1851722248&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/nintendo-eshop-switch-slop-clones-unpacking-scam-ai-art-1851722248">And while it sounds like you’ll still have to navigate through awful slop</a></span> to buy games you care about, at least you can speed by the crap you don’t care about faster on <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/switch-2-backwards-compatibility-list-start-up-issues-1851774297&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/switch-2-backwards-compatibility-list-start-up-issues-1851774297">Switch 2</a></span>. Lovely. </p><p>Of course, the topic of stick drift also came up during the roundtable. Since basically day one, the Switch has suffered from Joy-Con sticks drifting and becoming hard to use as a result.<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/nintendo-switch-joy-con-drift-fix-repair-center-replace-1848828886&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/nintendo-switch-joy-con-drift-fix-repair-center-replace-1848828886"> This has led to a lot of costly repairs for Nintendo</a></span> and damaged the console’s reputation. So I was really hoping for a better answer when Nintendo was asked about this big problem and if the Switch 2 would avoid it. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-addresses-joy-con-drift-in-switch-2-says-new-console-will-have-better-wireless-connectivity&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-addresses-joy-con-drift-in-switch-2-says-new-console-will-have-better-wireless-connectivity" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">That’s not what we got.</a></span></p><p>“As you may have witnessed and felt, the new Joy-Con 2 controllers for the Nintendo Switch 2 have been really designed from the ground up from scratch, and they have been designed to have bigger movement and smoother movement,” said Switch 2 hardware design lead Tetsuya Sasaki.</p><p>So the controllers are better and totally new. That’s nice. But it doesn’t answer the question. You’d like to think, after all the headaches Nintendo dealt with during the Switch’s lifespan, that stick drift would be a big priority for the company on its next console. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/nintendo-switch-2-release-date-joycon-drift-repair-1850825084?_gl=1*d5lrqg*_ga*MTc0MjY2NTg1OS4xNzQwMzc1OTc4*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTc0MzY5OTc4NC41OC4wLjE3NDM2OTk3ODQuNjAuMC4w&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/nintendo-switch-2-release-date-joycon-drift-repair-1850825084?_gl=1*d5lrqg*_ga*MTc0MjY2NTg1OS4xNzQwMzc1OTc4*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTc0MzY5OTc4NC41OC4wLjE3NDM2OTk3ODQuNjAuMC4w">And this answer, along with some patents, seems to indicate that it is working to make sure the issue doesn’t return for Switch 2.</a></span> But for now, we’ll have to wait until Switch 2 arrives in June to see if the new and improved Joy-Cons avoid the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/valve-hopes-to-avoid-thumbstick-drift-on-the-steam-deck-1847313237&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/valve-hopes-to-avoid-thumbstick-drift-on-the-steam-deck-1847313237">dreaded drift</a></span>. </p><p> .<br></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Last of Us Part 2 on PC Struggles To Beat PS4 Performance in Some Ways]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/last-of-us-part-2-on-pc-struggles-beat-ps4/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/last-of-us-part-2-on-pc-struggles-to-beat-ps4-performance-in-some-ways.1154661/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/last-of-us-part-2-on-pc-struggles-beat-ps4/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Digital Foundry has published an in-depth technical review for The Last of Us Part II Remastered on PC, which was released earlier today. While it has been regarded as an improvement over the woeful release of The Last of Us Part I on PC, it’s still <strong>not as good as it could be</strong>.</p>



<p>In some aspects, The Last of Us Part II on PC performs worse – or not as well as you’d expect comparatively – than the base PlayStation 4, which was released in 2013. For instance, Digital Foundry found that a GPU with more than three times the compute power of the base PS4 wasn’t able to consistently double the performance of The Last of Us Part II on PlayStation 4.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-in-the-weeds">In The Weeds</h2>



<p>Digital Foundry’s comprehensive technical review of The Last of Us Part II Remastered on PC is pretty insane. It’s fifteen minutes long, and it takes the time to dive into absolutely every aspect of the game, from frame rates and load speeds, and from texture clarity to settings optimisation.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="The Last of Us Part 2 PC Review - We're Disappointed - Analysis + Optimised Settings" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Z0IoZxiv1i0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>







<p>The team mentioned that the game’s usage of GPU resources is ‘a bit inordinate’, comparing the figures between a base PS4 and an RTX 3060 GPU. The PC GPU should be able to walk rings around the PlayStation 4’s tech, but that’s not what’s happening with this game, as DF explains:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>We should be looking at a GPU that is around 3.5 times <strong>more </strong>performant in compute, even at a non-boosted clock. Yet the RTX 3060 cannot fully double the PS4’s performance in this game at the closest equivalent settings.</p>



<p>This is a very large outlier in our history of examining PC ports.</p>



<p>Whether or not that’s justified is up to the jury, but that means you as a user will have to adjust your expectations accordingly. You really don’t want to drop below those PS4 settings, as I see it, as you’re getting a visual experience worse than a 12-year-old console at that point.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>DF also revealed that stuttering and framerate drops were fairly common, and at one point, they reveal that the game would lock up without any prior warning before leaping back into life a few seconds later. They also detected issues with shadows popping in at odd times – even on maxed-out settings. </p>



<p>These issues weren’t present on the PS4 Pro backwards-compatible version of the game on PS5.</p>



<p>Have you played The Last of Us Part II Remastered on PC yet? Let me know if you’re having issues in the comments or on the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/warzone-hits-highest-peak-viewer-count-since-2022/">Warzone’s viewer count is soaring</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Grand Theft Auto 5 Enhanced Comes to Xbox Game Pass for PC in 2 Weeks]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/grand-theft-auto-5-enhanced-comes-to-xbox-game-pass-for-pc-in-2-weeks</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/grand-theft-auto-5-enhanced-comes-to-xbox-game-pass-for-pc-in-2-weeks.1154655/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/grand-theft-auto-5-enhanced-comes-to-xbox-game-pass-for-pc-in-2-weeks<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">A triumphant return to Microsoft's gaming service.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Microsoft will bring Rockstar Games’ <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/grand-theft-auto-v">Grand Theft Auto 5</a> to Xbox Game Pass and GTA 5 Enhanced to Game Pass for PC on April 15.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">This striking addition to the Wave 1 April 2025 lineup was announced in an <a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2025/04/03/grand-theft-auto-v-game-pass-gtav-enhanced-april-15/?ocid=Announce_soc_omc_xbo_tw_Photo_lrn_4.3.1" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Xbox Wire post</u></a>, revealing that the service’s biggest new title of the month is only a few weeks away from dropping. It’s an especially enticing reveal, as the PC Game Pass version of GTA 5 comes with that all-new Enhanced update Rockstar dropped in early March.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“No matter what version you’re playing, everyone will have access to <em>Oscar Guzman Flies Again</em>, the latest update where you can take to the skies — taking control of the McKenzie Field Hanger in Grapeseed,” an official description from Xbox explained. “Play new arms trafficking missions, fly new aircraft, and more.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Its arrival in two Tuesdays will mark a triumphant return to Game Pass after Rockstar’s open-world masterpiece was previously removed from the service. However, while the addition will mark the title's first time on PC Game Pass, it’s not all sunshine and rainbows as far as many die-hard GTA fans are concerned.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/gta-online-on-pc-is-finally-catching-up-with-console-versions"><u>GTA 5 Enhanced arrived on PC March 4</u></a> as a free update, bringing access to all the latest vehicles, performance upgrades in Hao’s Special Works, animal encounters, and visual bumps. It was a promising addition that also resulted in GTA 5 becoming <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/rockstars-grand-theft-auto-5-enhanced-now-the-worst-user-reviewed-gta-on-steam"><u>Rockstar’s worst-reviewed title on Steam</u></a> as players latched onto account migration issues that kept them from bringing their GTA Online profiles over to the new version.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">If you’re a newcomer to Los Santos, then you likely won’t have much to worry about. If you’re returning to the world of GTA 5 Online and looking to migrate your account over to that shiny new Enhanced upgrade, you might find yourself out of luck. For now, it appears the issues with account migration are still ongoing.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Every Celebrity in GTA 5 and GTA Online</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Meanwhile, we’re still waiting for any news about <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/grand-theft-auto-vi"><u>Grand Theft Auto 6</u></a>. Our last GTA 6 update ensured that <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/gta-6-release-date-still-set-for-fall-2025-take-two-ceo-insists-we-feel-really-good-about-it"><u>Rockstar intended to deliver its next open-world trend-setter sometime this fall</u></a>, though we’re <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/when-will-gta-6-trailer-2-come-out-take-two-boss-says-its-better-to-provide-marketing-materials-relatively-close-to-the-release-window"><u>still waiting on that elusive release date</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">While Rockstar works out the kinks ahead of GTA 5’s return to Game Pass, you can read up on <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/microsoft-reveals-xbox-game-pass-april-2025-wave-1-lineup"><u>the rest of the Wave 1 April 2025 titles coming to Xbox Game Pass</u></a>. You can also read up on how Rockstar is supporting the modding community by <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/rockstar-owned-modding-team-working-on-official-grand-theft-auto-5-enhanced-conversion-tool"><u>granting them access to official tools</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Michael Cripe is a freelance contributor with IGN. He's best known for his work at sites like The Pitch, The Escapist, and OnlySP. Be sure to give him a follow on Bluesky (@mikecripe.bsky.social) and Twitter (@MikeCripe).</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild and Tears of the Kingdom Are Getting Achievements on Nintendo Switch 2]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/the-legend-of-zelda-breath-of-the-wild-and-tears-of-the-kingdom-are-getting-achievements-on-nintendo-switch-2</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-legend-of-zelda-breath-of-the-wild-and-tears-of-the-kingdom-are-getting-achievements-on-nintendo-switch-2.1154652/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/the-legend-of-zelda-breath-of-the-wild-and-tears-of-the-kingdom-are-getting-achievements-on-nintendo-switch-2<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Build the legend all over again.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Both The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild and Tears of the Kingdom are getting Nintendo Switch 2 versions for the new console. Alongside the in-game upgrades, Nintendo's adding a number of additional features through the new Zelda Notes option in its Nintendo Switch App, including achievements.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The Nintendo Switch App (formerly known as the Nintendo Switch Online App) will get an update adding Zelda Notes, a game-specific service exclusive to the Nintendo Switch 2 versions of both Breath of the Wild and Tears of the Kingdom.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">This app was <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/how-nintendo-switch-2-will-improve-switch-1-games">shown off in the Nintendo Switch 2 Direct</a>, allowing players to use GPS-style navigation to reach landmarks in the Zelda games. For achievements, the app will track your play data and allow players to earn in-app medals based on their records. These account for opening chests, earning rupees, and more.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">In the Achievements section, Nintendo lists categories such as "Quests and Adventures Cleared," "Shrines of Light Cleared," "Locations Visited," "Lightroots Unlocked," and others. Alongside tracking those numbers, the app will also let you see how you match up with other players on a global scale.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">While the achievements seem geared towards completion, it's interesting to see Nintendo experiment with these options. Granted, they exist in a phone app rather than on the Switch 2 console by itself, but I am curious to see whether other games get similar treatments in the future.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Other features of the Zelda Notes app include a Daily Bonus option for helpful resources, a Voice Memories section which adds more story and lore to the world as you explore, and an Autobuild Sharing tool. These do seem like handy tools, and especially geared towards people playing through this Zelda duology for the second time on their Nintendo Switch 2.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild - Nintendo Switch 2 Edition Screenshots</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The Nintendo Switch 2 has a launch date set for June 5, 2025. Both Breath of the Wild and Tears of the Kingdom will have Switch 2 editions at launch, alongside a slew of other games both new and refreshed. Previews dropped this morning for some of the launch window games for the Nintendo Switch 2, including <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/mario-kart-world-for-nintendo-switch-2-first-hands-on-preview">Mario Kart World</a>, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/donkey-kong-bananza-first-hands-on-preview">Donkey Kong Bananza</a>, and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/we-played-nintendo-switch-2-first-hands-on-preview">general hands-on impressions of the console</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">If you're looking for everything announced at the Direct for this upcoming console, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-direct-everything-announced">be sure to check out our recap of all the Nintendo Switch 2 Direct news here</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Eric is a freelance writer for IGN.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mario Kart World Video Suggests There Are 84 Characters, Including Costume Variants]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/mario-kart-world-video-suggests-there-are-84-characters-including-costume-variants/1100-6530608/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mario-kart-world-video-suggests-there-are-84-characters-including-costume-variants.1154646/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/mario-kart-world-video-suggests-there-are-84-characters-including-costume-variants/1100-6530608/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6530608">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Following the announcement of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/mario-kart-9-release-date-trailer-news/1100-6528874/" data-ref-id="1100-6528874">Mario Kart World</a> this week for the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/switch-2-release-date-specs-display-price/1100-6520278/" data-ref-id="1100-6520278">Switch 2</a>, Nintendo showed off even more gameplay footage during a Treehouse Live event, and more information about the game has come to light.</p><p>Social media user BearUNLV clipped a segment from the broadcast that shows the Mario Kart World character-select screen. There are three rows of four characters on one page for a total of 12, with seven tabs shown at the bottom of the screen. If each tab has 12 characters, this suggests there are a whopping <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/every-mario-kart-9-racer/2900-6141/" data-ref-id="2900-6141">84 characters in Mario Kart World</a>.</p><p>A <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@ign/video/7488860529600285998?_r=1&amp;_t=ZT-8vEQLcI9xSV" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">subsequent video from IGN runs through</a> the characters and costumes, featuring 60 in all, including costume variants like Gondolier Luigi and Yakuta Peach. The IGN video features five tabs as opposed to seven tabs in the official Nintendo video.</p><p>For comparison, Mario Kart 8 Deluxe for Switch had 36 characters, including those featured in the base game and through DLC. It hasn't been explicitly confirmed as of yet if Mario Kart World does indeed have 84 characters; since we haven't seen the full roster, it's unknown. But Mario Kart World appears to be aiming to be a bigger Mario Kart game overall, so a larger character roster wouldn't be a surprise.</p><p>The new Mario Kart World video also suggests the game will have at least 28 tracks spread across seven Cups, along with 24 vehicles. Interestingly, it looks like Mario Kart World has fully formed vehicles; players seemingly no longer select individual parts to assemble a car.</p><p>One major lingering question that remains unanswered for Mario Kart World is if the game will have DLC characters and courses like Mario Kart 8 Deluxe did.</p><p>Another video from the event showed the stage DK Spaceport, which includes a segment at the end that recreates the classic 1981 arcade game Donkey Kong. As you can see in the video below, racers have to dodge barrels that a giant DK is tossing down at them right at the race's finish. With up to 24 players competing at a time--the most ever for the Mario Kart series--things may get pretty chaotic.</p><div data-embed-type="tweet" data-src="https://x.com/Stealth40k/status/1907857457340448811" data-has-image="true"><blockquote data-conversation="none" data-mce-disable-toolbar="true"><p dir="ltr">At the end of the DK Spaceport stage in Mario Kart World, they've recreated the arcade classic. <br>A very cool ending to a track, especially when you have that many racers at once trying to dodge barrels. <a href="https://t.co/WSf0z52RO4" rel="nofollow ">pic.twitter.com/WSf0z52RO4</a></p>  — Stealth (@Stealth40k) <a href="https://twitter.com/Stealth40k/status/1907857457340448811?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 3, 2025</a></blockquote>              </div><p>Mario Kart World appears to be a larger-scale Mario Kart game with a price tag to follow--<a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-game-prices-reach-staggering-80/1100-6530563/" data-ref-id="1100-6530563">it will cost $80</a>. That's $10-$20 more than the current going-rate for AAA games. Price increases are <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/will-tariffs-increase-switch-2s-price-why-the-console-and-games-are-so-expensive/1100-6530591/" data-ref-id="1100-6530591">necessary for the overall sustainability of the video game industry</a>, one retailer has said.</p><p>For more on Mario Kart World, which is a launch title for the Switch 2, be sure to check out <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/mario-kart-world-hands-on-the-conservative-switch-2-gets-a-bold-sequel/1100-6530583/" data-ref-id="1100-6530583">GameSpot's hands-on preview of Mario Kart World.</a></p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch 2's C Button Was A "Very Last-Minute Request"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-c-button-was-a-very-last-minute-request/1100-6530609/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-switch-2s-c-button-was-a-very-last-minute-request.1154643/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-c-button-was-a-very-last-minute-request/1100-6530609/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6530609">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/switch-2-release-date-specs-display-price/1100-6520278/" data-ref-id="1100-6520278">Nintendo Switch 2's</a> C button was a late addition, with a new interview stating it was added following a "very last-minute request."</p><p dir="ltr">The <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-quietly-confirmed-the-switch-2s-c-button-in-nintendo-today-promo/1100-6530447/" data-ref-id="1100-6530447">Nintendo Switch 2 Joy-Con 2's mysterious C button</a> sparked debate ahead of the Switch 2 Nintendo Direct, where it was revealed to be a dedicated button for the console's Discord-like <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2s-c-button-is-all-about-video-and-voice-chat/1100-6530539/" data-ref-id="1100-6530539">GameChat feature</a>. In a series of developer <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/us/whatsnew/ask-the-developer-vol-17-gamechat-part-1/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">interviews</a> posted on Nintendo's website diving into various aspects of the Switch 2's creation, Sumikazu Ono, a member of Nintendo's entertainment planning and development department, said the C button came as a result of making sure the GameChat feature was easy to use.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="1040229294" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6465857,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Nintendo%20Switch%202%20%E2%80%93%20Official%20System%20Overview%20Trailer&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:330,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/nintendo-switch-2-official-system-overview-trailer\/2300-6465857\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465857\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465857\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465857\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6465857&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6465857,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6530609&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;nintendo-switch-2&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6465857},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6465857\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;Publisher Asset&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4469338-11.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/P7d0cUEb.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1743603600,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="P7d0cUEb" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> Nintendo Switch 2 – Official System Overview Trailer</p>
      </div>
<p dir="ltr">He said he thought the idea of having to pause the game and go to the home screen, find the right menu, make a chat room, and then return to the game (the way basically every other modern video game console does it) was "bothersome." That resulted in the idea of the C button.</p><p dir="ltr">"So we asked for a special button to be added while the hardware design was in progress," Ono said. "It was a very last-minute request, just before the controller molds were about to be made."</p><p dir="ltr">Ono said he thinks GameChat's ease of use, as well as the fact that the Switch 2 comes with a built-in microphone, will result in more players trying voice chat for the first time.</p><p dir="ltr">"We knew a lot of players would eventually stop using this feature if it wasn't easy to understand, so we worked hard to ensure it could be used easily to play with friends and family without any fuss," he said.</p><p dir="ltr">In the interview, Ono described GameChat as one of the Switch 2's "defining features," and that its origins came from trying to capture the vibe of a "student lounge" where people can gather not just to play games but also hang out.</p><p dir="ltr">"Until now, online play for Nintendo games has meant everyone coming together to play the same game," Ono said. "But more than anything, we wanted to create a space where people would naturally gather, whether it's to play the same game together, or different games, or even just to watch."</p><p dir="ltr">GameChat will technically require a Nintendo Online subscription to use, but can be accessed for free until March 2026, around nine months after the Switch 2 releases in June 2025.</p><p dir="ltr">In a previous developer interview, Nintendo said the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-switch-could-have-had-magnetic-joy-cons-like-switch-2/1100-6530577/" data-ref-id="1100-6530577">Switch 2's magnetic Joy-Con 2's were originally an idea for the first Switch</a>, but the idea was shelved following a meeting with late Nintendo President Satoru Iwata where he gave feedback on the prototype.</p><p dir="ltr">The <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-launches-june-5/1100-6530537/" data-ref-id="1100-6530537">Nintendo Switch 2 will launch on June 5 for $450</a>, with <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-preorder-guide-mario-kart-world-bundle/1100-6530531/" data-ref-id="1100-6530531">preorders, including a Switch 2 bundle with Mario Kart World, going live April 9</a>. Nintendo announced a number of new first-party games coming exclusively to Switch 2, including <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/donkey-kong-bananza-hands-on-red-faction-gorilla/1100-6530581/" data-ref-id="1100-6530581">Donkey Kong Bonanza</a> and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/switch-2-upgrades-of-zelda-breath-of-the-wild-and-tears-of-the-kingdom-revealed/1100-6530550/" data-ref-id="1100-6530550">Switch 2 versions of games like Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dragon Age creator's Stray Gods studio unveils demonic deckbuilder Malys]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/dragon-age-creators-stray-gods-studio-unveils-demonic-deckbuilder-malys</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dragon-age-creators-stray-gods-studio-unveils-demonic-deckbuilder-malys.1154640/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/dragon-age-creators-stray-gods-studio-unveils-demonic-deckbuilder-malys<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>Kickstarter campaign coming soon.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/malys-crop.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Summerfall Studios</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
If you found yourself bopping along in admiration to 2023's Stray Gods: The Roleplaying Musical, you might be interested to hear Dragon Age creator David Gaider's Summerfall Studios has announced its follow-up game. It's a "demonic roguelite deckbuilder" called Malys, and a Kickstarter campaign is coming soon.
</p>
<p>
Malys casts players a Noah, a former-priest-turned-demon-hunter, who's on a mission of vengeance to exorcise the infernal forces running rampant in a festering night-time city. "Expose, endure, and expel evil from the innocent possessed," teases Summerfall. "Confront your past, forge precarious alliances, and uncover the truth."
</p>
<p>
At the centre of all this demonic mayhem is the titular Malys, a being of "extraordinary cunning and power" and Noah's primary target. As players hunt the demon down, they'll deploy their deck of arcane tricks, finding unique combinations and strategies to withstand the city's horrors and expose the rot within. And if death wins out, they can always try, and try again.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Nintendo Switch 2 Hands-On Preview: Mario Kart World Impressions &amp; More!" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9CF8nQGolWY?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Nintendo Switch 2 Hands-On Preview: Mario Kart World Impressions &amp; More!</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9CF8nQGolWY?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/9CF8nQGolWY?autoplay=1" title="Nintendo Switch 2 Hands-On Preview: Mario Kart World Impressions &amp; More!">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Eurogamer goes hands-on with Switch 2.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9CF8nQGolWY" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
Malys is written by Gaider - perhaps best known as the lead writer on BioWare's original Dragon Age trilogy - and it's promising to deliver a "unique take on a familiar genre, pushing the boundaries of roguelite storytelling and delivering a satisfyingly moody experience".
</p>
<p>
And that's pretty much all we know so far. <a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/summerfallstudios/malys-exorcise-demons-on-your-hunt-for-an-ancient-evil?ref=t828fa">Malys' crowdfunding campaign</a> starts later this month, and Summerfall says the Kickstarter will enable it to "work closely" with backers to "ensure Malys is the best game it can be". The game itself is planned to release on PC this year.
</p>
<p>
Eurogamer's Ed Nightingale called Summerfall's Stray Gods "fascinating but flawed" in his <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/stray-gods-a-roleplaying-musical-review-greek-melodrama-fails-to-reach-lofty-expectations">three star review</a>, but it was interesting enough that Malys should be worth keeping an eye on.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Report Reveals The ESA Expects Trump’s Tariffs To Have A “Detrimental Impact On The Video Game Industry”]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/new-report-reveals-the-esa-expects-trumps-tariffs-to-have-a-detrimental-impact-on-the-video-game-industry/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-report-reveals-the-esa-expects-trump%E2%80%99s-tariffs-to-have-a-%E2%80%9Cdetrimental-impact-on-the-video-game-industry%E2%80%9D.1154610/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/new-report-reveals-the-esa-expects-trumps-tariffs-to-have-a-detrimental-impact-on-the-video-game-industry/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Immediately after Donald Trump announced his proposed tariffs that will go into effect this coming Saturday, April 5, and then a second wave on Wednesday, April 9, there was speculation across the video game industry as to how this would impact games.</p>
<p>So far, the sentiment is that these tariffs will have a huge impact on the video game industry, and the latest report from <a href="https://www.gamefile.news/p/esa-trump-tariffs">Game File</a> reveals that the Entertainment Software Association (ESA) expects the tariffs to have "<em>a real and detrimental impact on the video game industry.</em>"</p>
<p>Game File spoke to Aubrey Quinn, senior vice president at the ESA, who said that gaming hardware, for example, will be hit on multiple fronts, not just from the tariffs levied against countries like Vietnam, China, and Cambodia.</p>
<p>"<em>Any one product that a consumer would buy is likely to be subject to many of the tariffs announced, all compounded on top of one another,</em>" said Quinn.</p>
<p>It was already speculated that the tariffs on Vietnam and Cambodia, in particular, could potentially impact the pricing of the <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2s-price-could-go-even-higher-due-to-trumps-tariffs/">Nintendo Switch 2</a>, but Quinn's point is that there's more to gaming hardware that comes from other countries beyond Vietnam and Cambodia, which means that the base 10% tariff levied against all imports to the United States will only add on to the already high tariffs on specific countries.</p>
<p>Quinn did add, though, that the ESA remains "<em>optimistic that there will be a solution that doesn’t damage U.S. industries, ours included, and doesn’t hurt U.S. consumers</em>."</p>
<p>As we previously <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-is-selling-a-cheaper-region-locked-nintendo-switch-2-in-japan/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reported</a>, Niko Partners analyst Daniel Ahmad believes that Nintendo won't raise the price of its new console anytime soon, at least on the specific question of the pricing for the Nintendo Switch 2.</p>
<p>At the time of writing, we could still see things shift with these tariffs for the better, with the potential still remaining for a deal to be reached with exemptions for certain products, a lower tariff, or no tariffs at all being levied. Those deals, however, will take some time to set up with each impacted country, and in the meantime, we could still see the video game industry take a serious hit.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Genki has a magnetic battery for the Switch 2 and a better Joy-Con charging dock]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/642869/genki-nintendo-switch-2-accessories-cases-shells-magnetic-battery</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/genki-has-a-magnetic-battery-for-the-switch-2-and-a-better-joy-con-charging-dock.1154607/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/news/642869/genki-nintendo-switch-2-accessories-cases-shells-magnetic-battery<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/andrew-liszewski">Andrew Liszewski</a> <span>is a senior reporter who’s been covering and reviewing the latest gadgets and tech since 2011, but has loved all things electronic since he was a kid.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>With every new portable console comes a mountain of new third-party accessories. We’ve already seen <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/642514/nintendo-switch-2-usb-c-camera-hori-piranha-plant-privacy">Hori’s Piranha Plant alternative</a> to the Switch 2’s USB-C camera, but Genki has announced a larger lineup of accessories designed to help protect the portable console while you’re playing away from home, plus some clever ways to keep it and its Joy-Con controllers charged.</p><p>The <a href="https://www.genkithings.com/products/joy-station-pre-order">$49.99 Genki Joy-Station</a> looks like a sleek way to avoid the annoying juggling act of keeping more than two Joy-Cons charged, with some additional, well thought-out functionality. The Joy-Cons attach to two delta-shaped grips turning each pair into standalone controllers. Two Joy-Cons can be simultaneously charged using a USB-C cable while attached to the grips – useful for those times when you want to play and the Joy-Cons are nearly dead – but they also charge when the grips are reattached to the charging base.</p><p>Thanks in part to a larger screen, the Switch 2’s battery life is estimated to be between two and 6.5 hours per charge. You can extend that using <a href="https://www.genkithings.com/products/energy-pack-pre-order">Genki’s $69.99 Energy Pack</a> which is designed to conveniently magnetically attach to the back of the console and charge it at up to 30W speeds. The 10,000mAh Energy Pack is Qi2 compatible so you can also use it to wirelessly charge your phone, but the Switch 2 isn’t, so the battery instead connects to the console’s top USB-C port using a short included cable.</p><p>For gamers wanting added protection while they’re playing the Switch 2, <a href="https://www.genkithings.com/products/attack-vector-pre-order?variant=42025271623754">Genki’s Attack Vector is a $49.99 three-piece dock-compatible protective shell</a> that can be upgraded with a screen cover for an extra $10. Its most compelling feature is that it comes with three different sizes of sweat-resistant grips including a slim option designed for travel and a chunky option for maximum grip.</p><p>The $29.99 (or $39.99 with an optional screen cover) <a href="https://www.genkithings.com/products/force-field-2-pre-order?variant=42025278701642">Force Field 2 shell</a> is a cheaper alternative to the Attack Vector featuring a swing open design so you can detach and reattach the Switch 2’s Joy-Cons without having to fully remove it. It’s also dock-compatible, and allows for full use of the Switch 2’s folding stand.</p><p>If you’re simply looking for a way to keep the Switch 2 safe from dirt and scratches while it’s stuffed in a bag, <a href="https://www.genkithings.com/products/sleeper-case">Genki’s $42.99 Sleeper Case</a> features a hidden zipper and a soft wool finish inside and out wrapped around a sturdy shell the company describes as both “crushproof” and “virtually indestructible.”</p><p>Genki has also introduced a $19.99 Switch 2 screen protector called the <a href="https://www.genkithings.com/products/aegis-shield-pre-order">Aegis Shield</a>, and the <a href="https://www.genkithings.com/products/mimic-chest-pre-order">Mimic Chest</a>: a $19.99 plastic case sold in three-packs that each hold 12 game cartridges. All of the accessories are available for preorder now and expected to ship sometime in May or June 2025. If you want them all, <a href="https://www.genkithings.com/products/pre-order-genki-accessory-pack-for-switch-2?variant=42025332637770">Genki also sells the collection as a bundle</a> with either the Force Field 2 shell for $184.99 or the Attack Vector for $199.99.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marathon News Being Teased By Bungie]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/marathon-news-being-teased-by-bungie/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/marathon-news-being-teased-by-bungie.1154601/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/marathon-news-being-teased-by-bungie/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>More details and news about Bungie’s upcoming extraction shooter Marathon could be coming sooner rather than later. </p>



<p>On Thursday afternoon, the official Marathon Twitter <a href="https://x.com/MarathonTheGame/status/1907840558544072722" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">account posted</a> a “glitching” teaser video while updating its header image. Not long after that, the official PlayStation account also updated its header image to something Marathon related. </p>



<p>Other aspects of the game’s online presence such as its Steam page, Facebook, and YouTube were also updated. Lastly, a MIDA profile had been created on Twitter as well.</p>







<p>That has led to plenty of speculation that fans are only days away from getting more information of the relatively unknown reboot of the classic Bungie franchise.</p>



<p>To add fuel to the fire, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/why-bungies-marathon-wasnt-at-state-of-play/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Jeff Grubb reported</a> back in February that Marathon wasn’t a part of that month’s PlayStation State of Play because PlayStation was planning a standalone event for the game. At the time, he said that April was the target for such a showing.</p>







<p>“I think April [is] when we probably hear from them about Marathon,” he said. “And it would be its own thing separate from a State of Play.”</p>



<p>As of publishing, neither PlayStation nor Bungie have officially confirmed anything regarding when more Marathon news will be announced. Based on the teases, however, it should be only a matter of time.</p>



<p>When do you think Bungie will give the next look at Marathon? Let us know down below, and join the discussion in the official Insider Gaming forums.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read about the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/with-verdansk-return-call-of-dutys-player-count-jumps-200/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">player count boost Call of Duty is receiving</a> with the return of Verdansk in Season 3. &nbsp;And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for the Insider Gaming newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Warzone Hits Highest Peak Viewer Count Since 2022]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/warzone-hits-highest-peak-viewer-count-since-2022/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/warzone-hits-highest-peak-viewer-count-since-2022.1154595/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/warzone-hits-highest-peak-viewer-count-since-2022/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Call of Duty Warzone is back at the top of the streaming charts as Verdansk comes storming into the game once again. In 2021, Verdansk was removed rather unceremoniously from Warzone, being replaced with Caldera – a decision that many fans were disappointed with.</p>



<p>Even if it’s a flash in the pan, the return of Verdansk has proven the power of nostalgia – at the time of writing, more than 336,000 people were watching Call of Duty Warzone on Twitch. The last time the game had numbers that high was in <strong>November 2022</strong> when Warzone 2.0 was released.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-up-the-charts">Up the Charts</h2>



<p>Warzone is currently the most popular game on Twitch, which is a position it hasn’t occupied for many years. It was in 2022 that the previous peak was set, as 615,000 people tuned in to see what was new in Warzone 2.0, the release that came with Modern Warfare II.</p>



<p>Presently, more than 336,000 <a href="https://twitchtracker.com/games/512710" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">are watching Warzone on Twitch</a> – and the number is growing. Before this, Warzone had struggled to push beyond the 280,000 mark, even during groundbreaking events and new map releases.</p>



<p>As I write this, 11,000 channels are streaming Warzone gameplay, which is <strong>almost </strong>hitting that November 2022 peak. It seems everyone wants a piece of the Verdansk pie on streaming platforms – and this is before we even start talking about YouTube. On <strong>that </strong>platform, streamers like TimTheTatman are currently broadcasting to as many as 40,000 viewers.</p>



<p>It’s safe to say that, all in all, across the suite of streaming platforms, a good 500,000 – 750,000 people are watching Warzone gameplay in some way, shape, or form.</p>



<p>Many doubted that Verdansk would herald a return to form for Warzone, but if streaming figures are anything to go by, it’s looking <strong>very </strong>good for the battle royale title.</p>



<p>Are you playing in Verdansk? Let me know what you think of the map’s return on the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/">Insider Gaming forum</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/new-falcons-roster-priestahh-arcitys/">the Vegas Falcons have finalised their new roster</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Verdansk Return Leads To Call of Duty’s Player Count Rising 200%]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/with-verdansk-return-call-of-dutys-player-count-jumps-200/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/verdansk-return-leads-to-call-of-duty%E2%80%99s-player-count-rising-200.1154592/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/with-verdansk-return-call-of-dutys-player-count-jumps-200/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>It seems that people are just a little bit excited for the start of Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 Season 3 and the return of Verdansk in Warzone. After just the first few hours since the start of the season, player count for Call of Duty on Steam has risen over 200%.</p>



<p>As of writing, Call of Duty currently sits with 111,377 players <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/1938090/charts/#3m" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">on Steam</a>. That represents a 207.8% increase from its numbers prior to the start of the season. It also marks the first time Call of Duty has been over 100,000 concurrent players on Steam since early February when 102,000 players were on at once on February 2.</p>







<p>While not the be all, end all for numbers, Steam’s player counts are often a solid indication of the performance for a game. With numbers rising as high as they have on the platform, it could be safe to assumed that early numbers on console are just as strong, if not stronger.</p>



<p>The question then becomes whether these numbers will continue, or if players will tune out again after seeing what the return of Verdansk has to offer. Either way, the game has a ways to go to match the 160,000+ average player count it saw in its first month after release. Since then, the average count has dropped by double digits each month as of the end of March.</p>



<p>Do you think Call of Duty’s player count will stay elevated with Season 3? Let us know down below, and join the discussion in the official <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/threads/1812/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read about the change coming to the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/change-made-to-madden-26-broadcast-team/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">EA Sports Madden NFL 26 broadcast team</a>&nbsp;when the game launches later this year. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for the Insider Gaming newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo’s Switch 2 era comes at a price]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/games/642868/nintendo-switch-2-price-console-games-accessories</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo%E2%80%99s-switch-2-era-comes-at-a-price.1154574/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/games/642868/nintendo-switch-2-price-console-games-accessories<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/jay-peters">Jay Peters</a> <span>is a news editor covering technology, gaming, and more. He joined The Verge in 2019 after nearly two years at Techmeme.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Just about everything with the Nintendo Switch 2 is more expensive than the original Switch. </p><p>It’s perhaps not unexpected that the console itself costs more money than the first Switch. That device launched more than eight years ago, after all. But following yesterday’s big Switch 2 Direct, there has been a lot of sticker shock as people have seen just how much Nintendo is charging for the console and its games, including multiple titles with a price tag of just under $80. (And some of those games are just improved versions of years-old Switch titles.)</p><p>Based on hands-on reports from my colleagues, the Switch 2 seems like another <a href="https://www.theverge.com/nintendo/642420/nintendo-switch-2-hands-on-preview">excellent device</a>, with upgrades like an improved <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/642793/nintendo-switch-2-dlss-support-nvidia-ray-tracing">Nvidia processor</a> and a bigger screen with support for HDR and 120fps framerates. Nintendo games like <a href="https://www.theverge.com/nintendo/642432/mario-kart-world-hands-on-nintendo-switch-2"><em>Mario Kart World</em></a> and <a href="https://www.theverge.com/games/642699/donkey-kong-bananza-hands-on-preview-switch-2"><em>Donkey Kong Bananza</em></a> seem like they’re shaping up well, too.</p><p>But if you’re looking to buy a Switch 2 for yourself – pre-orders in the US start <a href="https://www.theverge.com/tech/24342715/nintendo-switch-2-preorder-price-release-date-availability-how-to-buy">on April 9th</a> – you’re going to have to pay up. (And, depending on the impact of President Trump’s newly-announced tariffs, the Switch 2 could cost <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/642459/switch-2-price-donald-trump-tariffs-china-vietnam-cambodia">even more</a>.)</p><p>Here are some comparisons of console, accessory, and game costs between the Switch and Switch 2. </p><div><p id="console"><h4><strong>Console</strong></h4></p></div><div><ul><li><span>Switch:</span><ul><li><span>Switch Lite: $199</span></li><li><span>Switch: $299</span></li><li><span>Switch OLED: $349</span></li></ul></li><li><span>Switch 2:</span><ul><li><span>Switch 2: $449.99</span></li><li><span>Switch 2 + <em>Mario Kart World</em> bundle: $499.99 (which is available for a limited time through fall 2025)</span></li></ul></li></ul></div><div><p id="games"><h4>Games</h4></p></div><div><ul><li><span>Switch (typically): $59.99</span></li><li><span>Switch 2: seems to be between $69.99 and $79.99</span><ul><li><span>Nintendo’s suggested retail price for <em>Donkey Kong Bananza</em> is $69.99, while <em>Mario Kart World</em>’s is $79.99.</span></li><li><span>Wal-Mart lists <a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fbrowse%2Fswitch-2-hardware-and-software%2F0%2F0%3F_refineresult%3Dtrue%26_be_shelf_id%3D7433688%26search_sort%3D100%26facet%3Dshelf_id%253A7433688%26povid%3Dets_switch2_pov%26nrtv_cid%3Dq6408wp3nhonf%26clickid%3DQTFXQTy2wxyKT9I2Qh2KvSx-Uksyj3SByXfazY0%26irgwc%3D1%26sourceid%3Dimp_QTFXQTy2wxyKT9I2Qh2KvSx-Uksyj3SByXfazY0%26veh%3Daff%26wmlspartner%3Dimp_376373%26affiliates_ad_id%3D565706%26campaign_id%3D9383%26sharedid%3D" rel="sponsored">various prices</a> for Nintendo’s Switch 2 games, including:</span><ul><li><span><em>The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild – Nintendo Switch 2 Edition</em>: $69.00</span></li><li><span><em>The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom – Nintendo Switch 2 Edition:</em> $79.00</span></li><li><span><em>Kirby and The Forgotten Land - Nintendo Switch 2 Edition + Star Crossed World:</em> $79.00</span></li><li><span><em>Super Mario Party Jamboree - Nintendo Switch 2 Edition + Jamboree TV</em>: $79.99</span></li></ul></li></ul></li></ul></div><div><p id="accessories"><h4>Accessories</h4></p></div><div><ul><li><span>Switch:</span><ul><li><span>Joy-Con: $79.99</span></li><li><span>Pro Controller: $69.99</span></li></ul></li><li><span>Switch 2:</span><ul><li><span>Joy-Con 2: $89.99</span></li><li><span>Pro Controller: $79.99</span></li><li><span>Camera: $49.99</span></li></ul></li></ul></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marvel Rivals season 2 invites you to party it up with Emma Frost, features a very Dalek-sounding Ultron]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/marvel-rivals-season-2-invites-you-to-party-it-up-with-emma-frost-features-a-very-dalek-sounding-ultron</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/marvel-rivals-season-2-invites-you-to-party-it-up-with-emma-frost-features-a-very-dalek-sounding-ultron.1154571/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/marvel-rivals-season-2-invites-you-to-party-it-up-with-emma-frost-features-a-very-dalek-sounding-ultron<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Seriously, he says exterminate and everything!</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/marvel-rivals-season-2.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>NetEase</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Anyone up for a little shindig? <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/companies/netease">NetEase</a> clearly are, as <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/marvel-rivals">Marvel Rivals</a>' second season is all about the Hellfire Gala, a fun little party gone wrong hosted by Emma Frost. As you'll no doubt be aware, Emma Frost isn't in the game currently, making her the first of the new characters to join this season, which kicks off next week, April 11th. 
</p>
<!--more-->
<p>
The Hellfire Gala is actually a story from the comics, set on Krakoa, a living island where mutants live, with the whole gimmick of this season being that everyone and anyone is invited for a big ole party.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Season 2: Hellfire Gala Official Trailer | Krakoa Welcomes You April 11! | Marvel Rivals" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/thyG51IdChc?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Season 2: Hellfire Gala Official Trailer | Krakoa Welcomes You April 11! | Marvel Rivals</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/thyG51IdChc?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/thyG51IdChc?autoplay=1" title="Season 2: Hellfire Gala Official Trailer | Krakoa Welcomes You April 11! | Marvel Rivals">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=thyG51IdChc" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>
That gets rudely interrupted by the second new character of the season (who'll be coming a bit later), Ultron, who crashes the party by saying that man and mutant "will be exterminated." Here's the thing I can't get over though: he really sounds like a bloody Dalek. That choice to have him say "exterminated" can't be a coincidence, right? He just sounds like a Dalek that's trying to deepen its voice so that it sounds a bit tougher. Not quite the sultry tones of the likes of James Spader.
</p>
<p>
You can also spot a number of characters in new costumes you'll inevitably spend way too much money on, like Wolverine in a white tux, Storm with some vividly blue hair, Magneto cosplaying as a Space Marine, amongst a few other mutant and non-mutant characters.
</p>
<p>A <a href="https://youtu.be/LOuv0tO_aLI?si=_lYN36-L8wO5KKcp">new Dev Vision</a> was shared today too, offering some more details on what lies ahead for the game. For one, from season 3 onwards, a new hero will debut every month, which just sounds like overkill if you ask me. There's also mission adjustments coming, new colour options for popular costumes, the ability to gift costumes to friends, new team-ups, and a bunch of adjustments. You can check out the video for specifics!</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stealth Tips For Becoming The Sneakiest Godlike In Avowed]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/avowed-stealth-build-divine-thorn-shadowing-beyond-1851774452</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/stealth-tips-for-becoming-the-sneakiest-godlike-in-avowed.1154568/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/avowed-stealth-build-divine-thorn-shadowing-beyond-1851774452<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>This isn’t <em>Skyrim</em>, so why do so many of us want to play the same build—a one-hit stealth archer—in <em>Avowed</em>? Well, because it’s downright fun! Who doesn’t want to slink through the tall grass, line up <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/avowed-best-bow-the-long-touch-map-guide-rpg-1851766965&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/avowed-best-bow-the-long-touch-map-guide-rpg-1851766965">the perfect bow shot</a></span>, and wipe the floor with a Xaurip or Sparrowhawk after letting loose a single arrow? Here’s the thing, though: The stealth mechanics in <em>Avowed </em>leave something to be desired, but we have a few tips that should help you one-up the competition and leave enemies wondering where you went if you haven’t murdered them already.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196394" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="The Week In Games: Killing Your Heroes, And More New Releases" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="97" data-playlist="196394,195922,196345" data-current="196394"><div><p>The Week In Games: Killing Your Heroes, And More New Releases</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196394/196394_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196394/196394_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196394/196394_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196394/196394_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21942.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><h2 id="h273633"><a id=""></a><em>Avowed </em>gives you an absolutely broken stealth attack</h2><figure id="" data-id="dbc640ca3422eee28ee1895c7c9d55e5" data-recommend-id="image://dbc640ca3422eee28ee1895c7c9d55e5" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="The player uses Divine Thorn to attack an enemy." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="The player uses Divine Thorn to attack an enemy." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Obsidian / Brandon Morgan / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="dbc640ca3422eee28ee1895c7c9d55e5" data-recommend-id="image://dbc640ca3422eee28ee1895c7c9d55e5" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="The player uses Divine Thorn to attack an enemy." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Most of the enemies you encounter in <em>Avowed </em>prove to be pushovers—unless you’re playing on the “Path of the Damned” difficulty. If you are, well, good luck in finding any sort of fun from the experience (<strong>Editor’s Note</strong>: I’ve been playing on Path of the Damned and it’s been a friggin’ blast). </p><p>You can walk right over most of the game’s enemies as long as you’re <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/avowed-obsidian-best-sword-last-light-of-day-guide-1851767297&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/avowed-obsidian-best-sword-last-light-of-day-guide-1851767297">wielding a solid sword</a></span> or whipping out a magic spellbook to toasting them to death with Fan of Flames. But they have something you don’t, and that’s numbers. To whittle away at the crowd, stealth!</p><p><strong>Read More:</strong> <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/avowed-obsidian-best-sword-last-light-of-day-guide-1851767297&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/avowed-obsidian-best-sword-last-light-of-day-guide-1851767297"><em>Avowed</em>’s Best Sword Might Be The Best Weapon In The Whole Game</a></span></p><p>Thanks to your godlike powers, you can sneak up behind unaware enemies in the game and usually one-hit kill them with Divine Thorn, or take their health down substantially at the very least. </p><p>Divine Thorn is a unique spell-like melee attack that summons a blue-and-purple blade around your fist that looks wildly similar to the energy sword in <em>Halo</em>. In a swift animation, you thrust the blade into the enemy’s back, launching them forward in a burst of magical…powder? Well whatever this spectral blade does to them, they’re done and gone, leaving you with one less enemy to fight.</p><p><strong>Read More:</strong> <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/avowed-best-bow-the-long-touch-map-guide-rpg-1851766965&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/avowed-best-bow-the-long-touch-map-guide-rpg-1851766965"><em>Avowed</em>’s Best Bow Is Bought From A Posh Shop Right At The Start</a></span></p><p>This power has its limits though. Don’t try to stealth kill one-hit bosses or some of the more powerful enemies in <em>Avowed</em>, and they’re less likely to fall and more likely to turn around and right-hook you.</p><h2 id="h273634"><a id=""></a>Stealth tips and tricks for the sneakiest of players</h2><p><br>There are a lot of ways to combine different class abilities and equipment to create a cool stealth build in <em>Avowed</em>. Stick to these tips to make the most out of your sneaky character.</p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li><strong>Don’t try to stealth-kill a bear or other large beast</strong>; it doesn’t appear to work the same way as with smaller creatures. You can one-hit stealth-kill a bipedal, humanoid-ish enemy using Divine Thorn, so long as they’re weak enough for your attack to wipe their health bar entirely.</li><li><strong>Invest in Dexterity and Perception</strong>; Dex will make you speedier while Perception will up your Critical Hit Chance as well as your Maximum Range for ranged weapons.</li><li><strong>Grab Shadowing Beyond from the Ranger class at Level 5</strong>; this will let you vanish into thin air and is a perfect combo with Divine Thorn.</li><li><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/avowed-best-bow-the-long-touch-map-guide-rpg-1851766965&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/avowed-best-bow-the-long-touch-map-guide-rpg-1851766965">Snag the game’s best bow from Dawnshore</a></span>: The Long Touch.</li><li> While you can use the tall grass to hide your approach, it’s not a requirement. <strong>So long as you remain crouched and behind enemies, you’ll remain in stealth until you alert an enemy guard</strong>. I was wearing heavy armor and could still stealth-kill Xaurips with relative ease.  <br></li><li>No one is watching you play (unless you’re streaming to the masses). Don’t hesitate to lower the game’s difficulty to Story or Easy to deal additional damage, especially when stealth-attacking enemies, to help clear zones quickly and efficiently.</li><li>Don’t be afraid to fall back if you get spotted;it’s called a tactical retreat, not running away.</li></ul><hr><p><br><em>Avowed </em>is available now on Xbox Series X/S and Windows PCs. And you can play it on Xbox Game Pass if you’re an active subscriber and don’t feel like dropping $70 on another RPG this year!  </p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch 2 Has 10x The Graphics Performance Of The Original, Nvidia Says]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-switch-2-has-10x-the-graphics-performance-of-the-original-nvidia-says/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-switch-2-has-10x-the-graphics-performance-of-the-original-nvidia-says.1154565/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-switch-2-has-10x-the-graphics-performance-of-the-original-nvidia-says/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-107940">

    <header>
        

        

    </header>

    


    <div>
        
<p>The Nintendo Switch 2 is a more powerful console than the Nintendo Switch, but, according to Nvidia, it’ll feature ten times the graphics power of the original.</p>



<p>In a post on its website going over Nintendo’s latest console, Nvidia discussed DLSS and 4K gaming coming to a Nintendo platform for the first time. The post goes over how Tensor Cores will help improve “AI-powered graphics” while adding that RT Cores will “enhance in-game realism with dynamic lighting and natural reflections.” Nvidia also says that variable refresh rate and G-Sync for the console’s screen result in “ultra-smooth, tear-free gameplay.”</p>



<p>These features, <a href="https://blogs.nvidia.com/blog/nintendo-switch-2-leveled-up-with-nvidia-ai-powered-dlss-and-4k-gaming/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">the company says</a>, will give the new system “10x the graphics performance of the Nintendo Switch”, providing “smoother gameplay and sharper visuals.”</p>







<p>The Nintendo Switch 2 <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-switch-2-features-officially-revealed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">features a 1080 LCD screen</a> that supports up to 120 frames per second (FPS) and HDR in handheld mode. When docked, the system supports 4K output at 60 FPS. One game that doesn’t seem to have 60 FPS on the system, however, is CyberPunk 2077 as CD Projekt Red’s RPG <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/cyberpunk-2077-on-nintendo-switch-2-runs-at-40-fps-costs-70/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">runs at 40 FPS</a> when docked.</p>



<p>Do you believe the Nintendo Switch 2 is going to have 10x the graphics performance of the original Switch? Let us know down below, and join the discussion in the official <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/threads/1811/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read about the change coming to the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/change-made-to-madden-26-broadcast-team/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">EA Sports Madden NFL 26 broadcast team</a>&nbsp;when the game launches later this year. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for the Insider Gaming newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-season-2-confirms-emma-frost-and-ultron/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-season-2-confirms-emma-frost-and-ultron/">
                                Marvel Rivals Season 2 Confirms Emma Frost and Ultron                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Marvel Rivals Season 2: Hellfire Gala’s trailer has confirmed the arrival of Emma Frost and Ultron. Here are more details. </p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/gta-5-returns-to-xbox-game-pass-this-month/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/gta-5-returns-to-xbox-game-pass-this-month/">
                                GTA 5 Returns To Xbox Game Pass This Month                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Microsoft has announced that Grand Theft Auto (GTA) 5 will be returning to Xbox and PC Game Pass later this month.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-switch-2-price-complains/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-switch-2-price-complains/">
                                Nintendo Switch 2 Livestream Comments Are 99% Spam of “Drop The Price”                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>The first Nintendo Treehouse livestream for the Nintendo Switch 2 is live now and fans have voice their frustration over the consoles and games prices.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/cyberpunk-2077-on-nintendo-switch-2-runs-at-40-fps-costs-70/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/cyberpunk-2077-on-nintendo-switch-2-runs-at-40-fps-costs-70/">
                                Cyberpunk 2077 On Nintendo Switch 2 Runs At 40 FPS, Costs $70                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>CD Projekt Red has confirmed that Cyberpunk 2077 on Nintendo Switch 2 will cost $70 when it releases on June 5.</p>
                    </div>

                                                    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mario Kart World Preview – Can Nintendo revolutionise the karting world again?]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/04/03/mario-kart-world-preview-can-nintendo-revolutionise-the-karting-world-again/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mario-kart-world-preview-%E2%80%93-can-nintendo-revolutionise-the-karting-world-again.1154544/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/04/03/mario-kart-world-preview-can-nintendo-revolutionise-the-karting-world-again/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Where can Mario Kart go after the sublime <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2017/04/20/mario-kart-8-deluxe-review/">Mario Kart 8</a>? That’s the question that we were wondering for the past 7 years, especially as Nintendo stuffed their deluxe best-seller with more and more tracks. The answer is <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/mario-kart-world">Mario Kart World</a>, an open-world spin on the traditional karting format that seriously mixes things up.</p>
<p><iframe title="Mario Kart World – Nintendo Direct | Nintendo Switch 2" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/3pE23YTYEZM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Right off the bat, Mario Kart World feels like putting on a pair of old slippers. It’s an utterly familiar feeling Mario Kart experience from the start, but it doesn’t take long to start spotting the bustle of new additions and extra features.</p>


<p>It starts with the character selector. There’s just a huge number of characters to choose from and their various costumes –&nbsp;these you unlock, it seems, by grabbing food items from roadside diners and then chowing down mid-race, which also transforms your look at that time. Of course you have staples like Mario, Peach, Yoshi, Waluigi, but the character list goes so far down the Mario universe as to just have Cow as a driver, which is as brilliant as it is barmy.</p>
<p>Get on track and you can literally just race it as though it’s Mario Kart 8, but there’s finer details to keep an eye out for. You can still pick up two items at once, but you no longer needing to hold and item behind you for protection as this now happens automatically. You also have the ability to grind on rails, which is trickier than it might look to pull off, wall-ride and more.</p>

<p>There’s some new transformations as well, with the karts all now having a boat or jetski mode to go with the road racing and glider modes.</p>

<p>We’ve played a handful of races with the game’s Grand Prix mode, but it’s not quite like the racing that you know from Mario Karts past. Where the point-to-point races of previous games were rare treats, here that aspect is folded into the main events. The demo build at the hands-on events picked randomly from the Grand Prix side of the game, and each time we found ourselves first racing cross-country until we reached the actual circuit that is home to the race. There’s no new race start at this point, the journey to the race track is as much a part of the race as the actual final circuit, and you might have 1 lap at that circuit, you might have three, or potentially more.</p>
<p>There’s just a huge amount of variety to this new structure, and it will be fascinating to see how it comes together. Will custom races let you get that classic feel? Or will things constantly keep on remixing?</p>

<p>But what if you love those point-to-point races and just want them to be even bigger and more challenging? Knockout Tour is one long cross-country race, with checkpoints to blaze a trail towards and the final four drivers to reach that point being eliminated. From twenty-four racers at the start, it will chop the field down to just four by the time you’re racing for the win. It ramps up the pressure in a very different way, and the sheer number of players, the volume of pickups going off makes for some seriously topsy-turvy moments as you tumble from 5th to 19th and the cusp of getting completely knocked out as you come to the next time gate.</p>
<p>It’s a lot of fun, though, and shows that there’s wide open avenues for Nintendo still to explore with their biggest game franchise. There’s also no doubt tons about this game that is still yet to be revealed, with a Nintendo Direct dedicated to Mario Kart World coming on 17th April.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[South of Midnight Review]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/south-of-midnight-review</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/south-of-midnight-review.1154532/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/south-of-midnight-review<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">In an early chapter of South of Midnight, our protagonist Hazel is coming to grips with her newfound powers - it’s an important tone-setter, because it’s representative of what developer Compulsion Games is trying to do throughout a concise 12-hour runtime. Mythical creatures straight out of folklore from the American South drive a human story that stands as a fantastic example of how the local can be universal, with the grand tapestry of that region's culture and history wrapped around an otherwise fairly straightforward action-adventure game. While there are plenty of aspects of South of Midnight that aren’t necessarily groundbreaking, it’s all uplifted by a clear and well-executed artistic vision that makes it one the more memorable Xbox console exclusives of this generation.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Hazel’s ability to manipulate the magical threads of an ethereal realm is both the weapon she uses to defeat otherworldly demons in combat and the tool she relies on to piece together the tragic pasts of her neighbors and forebears in her hometown of Prospero. It’s a fictional place, but one that’s deeply rooted in the very real experience of the South – traces of its dark history litter the dilapidated houses after a treacherous flood, contrasting with the remnants of communities that struggled to survive in those harsh conditions. These touches provide the rich context South of Midnight is working within while also unraveling a larger story about the pain, guilt, and trauma many of us experience in our own family lives.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">From a gameplay perspective, South of Midnight is rather simple – you’re ushered through fairly linear levels that alternate between platforming and combat encounters, with a few secrets hidden off the beaten path like journal entries from the locals that enrich the story and extra upgrades for your powers and health. If you’ve scaled cliffsides in Uncharted, God of War, or Tomb Raider, its frequent climbing sections will feel pretty familiar – but with the authentic sights and sounds of the American South at the forefront, the detailed vistas, ramshackled towns, or rushing rivers create a strong sense of place. With Hazel’s weaving powers, you’ll zip through air, clear paths forward, or summon ethereal objects depending on what obstacles are in front of you. There isn’t really much to <em>figure out</em> per se, although there is an enjoyable momentum as you’re funneled from one fight to the next, or when you’re trying to outrun evil spirits chasing you down in the lengthy platforming sequences that cap off every major chapter.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Combat itself is contained in distinct arenas across each level, with the idea being that Haints – the demonic manifestations of peoples’ pain and sorrow – plague all of Prospero, and Hazel is the one who can cleanse that corruption. It’s a comfortable, if predictable, cadence that doesn’t really wear thin since it’s judicious about when you actually have to fight. This helps South of Midnight not feel repetitive, and I genuinely looked forward to each combat encounter. Similar to the platforming, these fights aren’t really pushing any boundaries, but Hazel's attack combos and spells have a certain chunkiness that I really enjoyed. That’s especially true when firing off her stun weaves and grappling strand to stack damage, then leaving a burst behind with a perfect dodge. Cycling through a shortlist of fun abilities like that makes the basics satisfying.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>It’s everything around South of Midnight’s competent foundation that makes it truly stand out.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Haints come in various forms that give encounters enough variety. Some are swift and pesky, while others are hulking beasts that tunnel underground and cause massive area-of-effect damage. They’re mixed and matched throughout, and things like Hazel’s puppet named Crouton, who can temporarily control enemies, add an interesting wrinkle when thinking about which targets to prioritize. There are a few boss fights to heighten the stakes with a bit of spectacle as well, but they mostly tend to highlight the formulaic nature of combat by relying on derivative versions of mechanics that are used elsewhere.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">South of Midnight’s foundation is perfectly competent, but it’s everything else around it that makes it truly stand out, grabbing you with its painterly character designs and striking stop-motion animation style. That unconventional choice helps special moments pop during cutscenes, although it isn’t really noticeable in the action – and if you find it too jarring, you can optionally disable the stop-motion effect altogether. Even without it, the details in characters’ faces, their expressiveness, and the superb voice acting feel like the real reward chapter after chapter. The specific accents and vernacular come across authentically, to the point where I didn’t think twice about them since it all sounded so familiar to me as someone who was born in the region. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Southern gothic folklore hasn’t really been explored in games like this, and South of Midnight showcases how rich it is by bringing these tales to life in ways we rarely see. Mythical creatures embody the pain and suffering of townsfolk, melding broader urban myths with the struggles of specific characters throughout the story. A figure like Florida’s legendary alligator Two-Toed Tom shows up as a boss, while the shapeshifting Rougarou from Cajun tales takes a form I hadn’t heard of before – and Alabama’s Huggin’ Molly has on a fascinating reinterpretation. It’s the sort of amalgamation of folklore that’s wonderful to see as someone who is familiar with some of it, but done in a way that’s still inviting for the uninitiated.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">South of Midnight acknowledges the region’s real history in subtle and effective ways as well, recognizing that remnants of slavery and the Reconstruction era persist in our modern world, and that trauma can carry across generations. Passing by abandoned houses along the bayou with eviction notices from greedy landgrabbers reminds you of the rough and unfair economic conditions many of these communities face. It’s woven into its main themes about the complicated dynamics of family – the best and worst parts that can come from blood relations. With her weaving powers, Hazel can peer into the past through visions recreated using the threads that make up The Grand Tapestry – the flow of all life and memory. You’ll see a mother risking life and limb to escape abuse and give their child a fighting chance; A man ashamed of his brother who takes drastic measures to separate himself, only to live with regret forever; A kid who called out to a mythical creature in desperation to escape his abusive father. </p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>It brings Southern folklore to life in ways we rarely see.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">From tragic displays of unconditional love to the horrors of the abuse our own kin can inflict on us, South of Midnight focuses on the idea of family being something we either embrace or reckon with, told in a way that’s inseparable from its setting. Through it all, Hazel is desperately chasing any possible thread to find her mother after that devastating flood at the start, but is still willing to lend a helping hand to the spirits that have endured in the afterlife. As you uncover the hard work her mom puts in as a social worker, it shows that a little empathy can go a long way.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">There’s a lot I love about the stories in South of Midnight – I do wish they were more elegant or told with more finesse, however. The larger plot is missing some necessary connective tissue at times, and it’s easy to lose track of why Hazel’s journey leads from one thing to another. Characters and narrative threads are sometimes introduced as quickly as they’re resolved through story beats that feel segmented in ways that aren’t entirely clear. There are parts of Hazel’s life I’m still wondering about that get brought up as important pieces to the story, and I wish I could have tied those loose ends together before the credits rolled.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">South of Midnight Review - Screenshots</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">It gets the big picture right, though, and in its exploration of a region as wide-ranging as the American South, there’s an earnest interpretation. While it is also a heavily religious place, the story is more interested in the spirituality that gives rise to these folktales. And it’s not all swamps and basins out there, it’s not just Bourbon street in New Orleans, or a politically hostile place for marginalized folks – those are all part of it, for sure. But I like that we have a story that shows that <em>people live there</em>, and they struggle in ways that are both universal and unique to the region. South of Midnight also understands that <em>hurt people hurt people</em>, and knows it’s not an excuse for the terrible things that pain may drive people to do – it’s a bit of a trope when stories talk about mental health nowadays, but there’s still truth to it, and South of Midnight has its own take by focusing on this concept with regards to family. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Perhaps my favorite touch, however, is how South of Midnight uses its fantastic soundtrack to tie everything together thematically. With a mix of bluegrass, blues, jazz, and American folk tunes that weave in harmonizing choirs, church organs, or banjos and fiddles, it’s a showcase of how important music has been throughout the region’s history. Big story moments are built up through songs written as if a narrator was walking you through what the characters felt and experienced in their life, and they’re queued up at just the right time to propel you forward as you’re playing. It got me in my feelings at times, because there’s not much I love more than a fantastic soundtrack used as an effective storytelling device.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Many of us from the South have a complicated relationship with it. Born in Mississippi and adopting parts of the culture and vernacular as my family and I moved throughout the country, it’ll always have a special place in my heart. I appreciate having a game that helped me reconnect with those roots in a way that was whimsical and harrowing in equal measure, and that’s the sort of value South of Midnight has beyond just being a good action-adventure game – it’s worth playing for a little virtual tour of the South you wouldn’t see otherwise.</p></section><div data-cy="verdict"><h3 data-cy="title3">Verdict</h3><p data-cy="article-verdict-paragraph">South of Midnight is a straightforward but well-executed action-adventure game on the surface, with a simple but satisfying mix of combat and platforming. It’s focused, filling out its 12-hour runtime nicely without ever dragging or relying on unnecessary padding. Beyond those basics, however, is a certain heart and artistry that elevates the whole package, inviting you to peer into the deep American South through its folklore, nature, and culture. It might not be the most profound exploration of family life, but it’s delivered in ways that feel authentic. From its striking art style to the evocative tunes that bring big story moments together, Hazel’s journey is a captivating one no matter where you come from.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rune Factory: Guardians of Azuma for Switch, PC delayed to June 5]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/rune-factory-guardians-of-azuma-for-switch-pc-delayed-to-june-5</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/rune-factory-guardians-of-azuma-for-switch-pc-delayed-to-june-5.1154529/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/rune-factory-guardians-of-azuma-for-switch-pc-delayed-to-june-5<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Now launching alongside Switch 2 version.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>The Switch and <a title="Platforms > PC [22,805 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> (<a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2864560/Rune_Factory_Guardians_of_Azuma/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a>) versions have been delayed by one week from May 30 to June 5 to launch alongside the <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/rune-factory-guardians-of-azuma-coming-to-switch-2-on-june-5">newly announced</a> Switch 2 version, publisher <a title="Companies > Marvelous [1,338 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/marvelous">Marvelous</a> announced. <span id="more-955859"></span></p><p>Get the latest details below.</p><blockquote><p>The latest entry in the popular <a title="Genres > Action [2,634 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a>–<a title="Genres > RPG [17,123 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg">RPG</a> and life-<a title="Genres > Simulation [697 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/simulation">simulation</a> series will now launch alongside the <a title="Platforms > Switch [16,914 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Nintendo Switch</a> 2 version simultaneously. Players will experience the Eastern territory of Azuma for the first time, a land of Japanese-inspired visuals and unique twists on familiar gameplay elements from the <em><a title="Series > Rune Factory [24 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/series/rune-factory">Rune Factory</a></em> franchise. Those playing on Nintendo Switch 2 will experience the title in a higher resolution with improved frame rates, along with Joy-Con 2 mouse controls for village building.</p><p>The company also announced that those who have pre-ordered the Nintendo Switch version of <em><a title="Games > Rune Factory: Guardians of Azuma [9 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/rune-factory-guardians-of-azuma">Rune Factory: Guardians of Azuma</a></em> will be able to play on the new platform with the <em>Nintendo Switch 2 Edition</em> upgrade pack. Details regarding the upgrade pack will be available at a later date.</p><p>Additionally, <a title="Companies > Marvelous USA [14 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/marvelous/marvelous-usa">Marvelous USA</a> today revealed the <em>Rune Factory: Guardians of Azuma</em> “<a href="https://marvelous-usa.com/product/rune-factory-guardians-of-azuma/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Earth Dancer Accessory Set</a>,” a limited box set containing the original soundtrack consisting of 56 tracks across two CDs, a 160-page art book, an Azuma-inspired folding fan, and a plush Woolby keychain together in a custom outer box. Limited quantities of this special set will be available for pre-order soon exclusively on the Marvelous USA Online Store for an MSRP of $49.99.</p></blockquote></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Switch 2's Main Menu Isn't That Different From The One On Nintendo Switch]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/switch-2s-main-menu-isnt-that-different-from-the-one-on-nintendo-switch/1100-6530604/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/switch-2s-main-menu-isnt-that-different-from-the-one-on-nintendo-switch.1154523/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/switch-2s-main-menu-isnt-that-different-from-the-one-on-nintendo-switch/1100-6530604/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6530604">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>A single image of the main menu of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/" data-ref-id="5005-154">Nintendo Switch 2</a> has emerged, and it looks more like an iteration than an evolution of the original <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/nintendo-switch/" data-ref-id="5005-124">Nintendo Switch's</a> menu.</p><p>To find this image, you need to look at the Nintendo webpage titled <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/us/gaming-systems/switch-2/featured-games/switch-2-edition/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">"About Nintendo Switch 2 Edition games."</a> Scroll down to the section on "How to purchase an upgrade pack," and the image showing people how to navigate to the Switch 2's eShop gives us our first look at the UI. At a glance, it's quite similar to the menu you see after hitting the home button on Nintendo Switch. There's a gallery of game art in the middle, from which Switch 2 games like <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/mario-kart-world/" data-ref-id="5000-658545">Mario Kart World</a> are presumably launched. Above, you can see the time of day, Wi-Fi connectivity, and battery charge remaining.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1849/18498836/4470505-switch2editions-eshop.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4470505" data-ratio="0.56166666666667" data-width="600" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1849/18498836/4470505-switch2editions-eshop.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4470505"></a><figcaption>This is the first official image of the Switch 2's main menu from Nintendo.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1849/18498836/4470505-switch2editions-eshop.jpg"></figure><p>At the bottom of the screen, players can see which Joy-Cons are connected and a row of icons. Some of these icons are very similar to those on Switch 1, specifically the Nintendo Switch Online, Album, Controllers, System Settings, and Sleep Mode ones. The Nintendo eShop icon has been redesigned to a darker shade of orange, and ones that could be for features like Virtual Game Cards, GameChat, and GameShare appear alongside it. There's also an unknown icon represented by a green sheet of paper. This could be a redesigned News icon or something else entirely.</p><p>While there are some small but notable icon changes, the Switch 2's main menu, for the most part, takes most of its cues from the home screen design on Switch 1. That means we might be unlucky when it comes to potentially getting improvements like game folders or more menu themes, but we'll have to wait and learn more from Nintendo before we'll know for sure.</p><p>Nintendo Switch 2 will release on June 5. You should check out <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-preorder-guide-mario-kart-world-bundle/1100-6530531/" data-ref-id="1100-6530531">GameSpot's preorder guide for Switch 2</a> if you plan to pick one up on launch day.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                        
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/107508578270426893025?rel=author">Tomas Franzese</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Design opportunities for devs from our time trying out the Nintendo Switch 2]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/design-opportunities-for-devs-from-our-time-trying-out-the-nintendo-switch-2</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/design-opportunities-for-devs-from-our-time-trying-out-the-nintendo-switch-2.1154520/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/design-opportunities-for-devs-from-our-time-trying-out-the-nintendo-switch-2<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The age of the Nintendo Switch 2 is nigh. After a </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/console/-redesigned-from-the-ground-up-the-nintendo-switch-2-will-launch-on-june-5">fast and furious Nintendo Direct </a></span><span data-testid="content-text">on April 2, the Kyoto publisher ushered an assembly of press and influencers into an event space in midtown Manhattan, all eager for a chance to learn the ins and outs of the mysterious new console.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The company's fierce secrecy about the new console has left not just players, but developers wondering what new major advancement the company wants to put front-and-center. The Nintendo Switch was a massive hit for Nintendo not just because of the detachable Joy-Con controllers, but also because of the portability. The Switch 2, it turns out, trades hardware innovation for online social multiplayer features built right into the console.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">But some tech advancements—and the "mouse" gameplay mode supported by the new JoyCons—open some doors for creative developers to break ground on games for the console. Of the games we saw at the New York event, it was titles like </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Metroid Prime 4: Beyond</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Sid Meier's Civilization VII, </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Donkey Kong Bananza</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> that showed the greatest potential for developer inspiration.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="The Joy-Con &quot;mouse&quot; mode can bring more PC games to console">The Joy-Con "mouse" mode can bring more PC games to console</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Switch 2 producer Kouichi Kawamoto explained in an "</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.nintendo.com/us/whatsnew/ask-the-developer-vol-16-nintendo-switch-2-part-1/">Ask a Dev</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">" blog post posted by Nintendo yesterday that Joy-Con mouse control mode came about after he was playing games on PC and mused that the Joy-Con itself might work well as a control device rarely used on consoles. "Switch 2 was originally designed to support a wider range of games by improving the system's processing speed, so with that in mind, I thought it'd be better to be able to play interesting games that require a mouse," he said.</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/dredge-wasn-t-originally-going-to-be-a-narrative-game-but-then-it-became-one-of-2023-s-best" target="_self" data-discover="true">Dredge wasn't originally going to be a narrative game, but then it became one of 2023's best</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">He also credited a theory from former Nintendo R&amp;D general manager Gunpei Yokoi called "lateral thinking of withered technology," which states that that new products can be created by using widely-used technology no longer seen as "cutting edge" for new and unusual functions.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">In a group Q&amp;A held at Nintendo's New York preview event, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.latercera.com/">La Tercera</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> writer Axel Frederick asked Kawamoto about the fact that most places players use the Nintendo Switch like the couch, a comfy chair, or the bed, aren't ideal environments for mouse control. "We have made adjustments so that you can control the mouse on your pants," Kawamoto responded.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">There weren't any chances to drag the Switch 2 Joy-Con across my trousers (probably for the better...), but there was time to experiment with the click-based controls. Maybe it was my lowered expectations, but it was surprising that flipping a Joy-Con on its side and using the R/L buttons as a "left click" and the ZR/ZL buttons as a "right click" felt satisfying. I endeavored to keep my expectations in check—this feature isn't earth-shattering. It is at the end of the day, a humble computer mouse.</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/how-star-wars-outlaws-poker-style-mini-game-helped-to-define-its-tone" target="_self" data-discover="true">How Star Wars Outlaws' poker-style mini-game helped to define its tone</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">That said, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Metroid Prime 4</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Civilization VII</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> showed surprising ways that "humble" can form an intoxicating brew. </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Prime 4</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">'s base controls are similar to those seen in </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Metroid Prime Remastered</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, updating the original GameCube twin-stick scheme for one that supports motion controls centered on the "lock on" feature initiated by pushing the left trigger button. In a quick back-and-forth test, using the mouse to aim Samus' Power Cannon felt smoother than switching to traditional Joy-Con motion aiming.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">It's the "back-and-forth" where some of the magic happens. In </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Metroid Prime 4</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, players can switch control schemes just by turning the Joy-Con from one position to another. In literal seconds, they can swap from mouse, to twin-stick with motion controls, to mouse again.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Switch 2 director Takuhiro Dohta explained to Game Developer that developers who don't want players to accidentally switch control modes can turn off this feature and make it a more menu-driven choice. He danced away from explaining precisely how it worked, but alluded to the gyroscope and accelerometer sensors being other "unique" features developers can take advantage of.</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/the-comedy-first-approach-to-thank-goodness-you-re-here" target="_self" data-discover="true">'We write good stuff in the pub:' the comedy first approach to Thank Goodness You're Here</a></p><p>Image via Nintendo.</p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">If the Joy-Cons are capable of such subtle switches (possibly with the help of the gyroscope and accelerometer, if we're trying to pick apart Dohta's answer), it might open the door to designers who can think of reasons to make players switch between conventional Joy-Con usage and "mouse mode" on a regular basis.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Kawamoto said he was delighted to hear that we were "surprised" by the feature during play, so if nothing else, Nintendo thinks that surprising players with the capabilities of the Joy-Con is fertile territory for games like </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Metroid Prime 4: Beyond</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Next let's talk about </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Civilization VII</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">. At first this is an obvious no-brainer. Turn-based strategy games on PC (and already on consoles) can now have proper mouse controls on the Nintendo Switch 2. In 2006 this would have been revolutionary, in 2025 it'd be fine to ask "is that it?"</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>But</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">. Checking out the game and chatting with Firaxis Games executive producer Dennis Shirk, I was struck by two surprising facts: first, the aforementioned positive clicking sensation really sings in a turn-based environment. Many players will find the physical sensation of clicking a Nintendo Switch 2 mouse to be more favorable than your average PC mouse.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Second, as Shirk pointed out in our conversation, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>the Switch 2 mouse has more buttons than your average PC mouse</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">. Shirk explained that at Firaxis and among hardcore Civilization players, it's generally understood that the the most devoted players use custom mice with mappable macro commands on the side for more efficient empire-building.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The Switch 2 mice aren't as modular or precisely designed as an </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://rog.asus.com/us/mice-mouse-pads/mice/wireless/rog-spatha-x-model/">Asus ROG Spatha X</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, but Firaxis is staring down a funnel of new </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Civilization VII</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> console players who will learn how to play the game on a more complex device. "We're actually pleasantly surprised how absolutely versatile it was," he said. "The flexibility that offers our traditional PC players to play on the go is an instant win."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">It's a neat opportunity for developers porting mouse-friendly games to console to see what new tools they can offer players that they couldn't before. I can imagine that a game like </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://theroottreesaredead.com/">The Roottrees are Dead</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> now has a far more natural home on console than it would have before.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Shirk said Firaxis developers working on the Switch 2 port were surprised by how many kinds of surfaces the mouse controls worked on (including the aforementioned pants). In Dohta's response to Frederick during the group Q&amp;A, he said that playing multiplayer wheelchair basketball game </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Drag X Drive</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> by rubbing the controllers on their laps was the "preferred" way of playing the game.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">On the topic of </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Drag X Drive—</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">I can't recommend it as a good case study for using both Joy-cons in mouse mode. Dohta explained that the demo stations set up for the preview weren't an ideal play scenario because both mice were situated on a table in front of the player. The game is meant to mimic operating a wheelchair, and moving the mice forward and backward on your lap is a more natural motion than on a full table.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">When I tried the demo tables for myself, it was awkward and unpleasant, leaving the game feeling like a hollow successor to </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Arms_(video_game)">Arms</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> as a multiplayer tech demo that didn't necessarily birth a genre or franchise. It made me wish Nintendo had opted for a single-player puzzle game of some sort with this mechanic, because a multiplayer game that isn't exceptionally unique will fade fast, and players will be less likely to experiment with "dual-mouse" layout.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Other journalists I spoke with agreed with Dohta that the table setup may have made for a less favorable impression. But even with proper seating, I'm worried dual mice design is a dead-end. It should be a major opportunity for some new kind of gameplay, but the history of the Nintendo Switch shows that for third-party developers, games on Switch need to be portable to other platforms. And you can't port a "dual mice" game anywhere, not even a PC.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">If the Switch 2's only major addition was the mouse functionality, I'd be more worried about the console's prospects. But with the overwhelming online multiplayer tools the device is built around, I'm less worried about the console's creative prospects hanging on this one thread.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="DLSS and improved processing power open the door for gorgeous (if not radically different) games">DLSS and improved processing power open the door for gorgeous (if not radically different) games</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">It's common to hear from developers that, as the Nintendo Switch reaches the end of its lifespan, it's become harder to port games with increasing graphical fidelity, often trading heavily on performance and load times just to achieve functionality. Those teams are likely to feel unleashed with the Nintendo Switch 2, as developers like CD Projekt Red and FromSoftware are leading the way in porting games like </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Cyberpunk 2077</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Elden Ring</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> to the device. Neither port is likely to be as technically impressive as their PC and PS5/Xbox brethren, but the Switch 2's mobility and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.nintendo.com/us/gaming-systems/switch-2/tech-specs/">specs</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> (which outpace Valve's Steam Deck in many respects) are impressive.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Supergiant Games creative director Greg Kasavin was on hand with </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Hades II</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, grinning from ear to ear as he watched players try his game out on the next-generation Switch. "We knew we'd be making this game for the Switch 2 before we even knew there was a Switch 2," he said, explaining that the Switch 2 doesn't offer any significant upgrades over other console versions, but it does deliver a better visual experience than the Switch version. "A lot of it is just kind of the raw satisfaction of a higher definition display," he said.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">On the first-party side Nintendo is touting </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Donkey Kong Bananza</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> as an example of the "new kinds of gameplay" enabled by the Switch 2 hardware. "In </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Donkey Kong Bananza</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, you can experience the exhilaration of being able to destroy anything you want in the game without restrictions," said Kawamoto in Nintndo's "Ask a Dev" series, also pointing to </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Mario Kart World</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">'s "open world" linking all the racetracks together as benefits of the console's improved processing power.</span></p><p>Image via Nintendo.</p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Mario Kart World's</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> open world lobby is fine, but it's more interesting for its social play implications than its technical novelty. It's the Knockout Tour mode that brings the technology to life. Knockout Tour is a battle royale-like experience as the massive 24-player lobbies can vote on a number of race circuits that they play through uninterrupted. Players start the race in one course, then are steadily eliminated, with the top racers making it all the way through five maps.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Is that kind of gameplay possible on another platform? Maybe, but credit to Nintendo, many other kart racers have hit the market since the last </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Mario Kart</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> game and none of them attempted this kind of feature.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Donkey Kong Bananza</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> is something of a head scratcher. It's a charming return for Nintendo's simian sidekick (yes I'm calling him a sidekick now they haven't made new </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Donkey Kong Country</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> games in years), giving him a chance to fill a roll filled by Mario in </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Super Mario Odyssey</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> on the Nintendo Switch: the role of the family-friendly action game hero available with the console on day one.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Developers curious about </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Bananza</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> should maybe look at it as a study in layered level design. Players are able to destroy most of the terrain in the large maps, and Nintendo has populated the world with cave systems and hidden treasures that reward players pounding at rocks like a toddler in a playground. It's impressive that the game contains well-constructed linear areas that players can navigate from all ends as well as deeply-dug secrets. A Nintendo demo rep and I chatted back and forth about how it compared to the sensation of snooping out secrets in other open-world games.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">But beyond the "Donkey Kong" charm of it all (and it is very charming, the voice going "ooooh ba-na-NA whenever you picked up a banana was an instant win), the chunky digging spaces didn't feel that remarkable considering the amazing destructible voxel worlds of games like </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Minecraft</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Teardown</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, or the jaw-dropping verticality of </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">. I suppose it's significant that </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Bananza</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> pulls off a similar type of gameplay with higher-fidelity graphics, but it doesn't feel like the kind of game to inspire a generation of fast-followers.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">So what does feel exciting? The Switch 2 supports NVIDIA's DLSS thanks to a custom-made processor from the video card manufacturer. Inverse's Shannon Liao quizzed the Switch 2's hardware leadership about its use of the frame generation technology and what possibilities it offered for first-and-third party developers. "We do use DLSS upscaling technology, and that's something we'll continue to use as we develop games," said Dohta, adding that its inclusion can help developers design games that output to resolutions as humble as 1920x1080 and as potent as 4K with HDR.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">That caught my attention. I finally caught the bug for frame generation after a recent stint with </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>God of War: Ragnarok</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> on the Steam Deck. Frame generation can help developers push the boundaries of what framerates their games can pull off, and while it may not look as authentic on a large display it's a force multiplier for games played in portable mode. Not every game needs to run higher than 60fps, but many franchises under Microsoft's umbrella, from Halo, to Call of Duty, to Forza Horizon, and beyond, are best enjoyed with the smoothest possible frame rates. Will DLSS help Microsoft </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/microsoft-signs-binding-contract-to-bring-call-of-duty-to-nintendo-platforms">make good on its promise</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> to the FTC that it would bring Call of Duty to Nintendo?</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Possibly. For now, if you're hoping to debut a smooth-as-butter game on the Nintendo Switch 2, NVIDIA's AI-driven frame generation tech may help you hit those desired performance levels.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Should developers prioritize the Switch 2?">Should developers prioritize the Switch 2?</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">In my heart of hearts, I hope the Joy-Con mouse function ushers in a quiet revolution of exceptional strategy games for the Nintendo Switch 2. It occurs to me now that Microsoft has reason to port </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Age of Empires II</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> to a platform, continuing the life of a game I spent hours on at the ripe old age of 9. If your game is more fun with a mouse than a controller, this feature is an opportunity to build a new audience beyond the world of PC.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Beyond that, it'll be up to FromSoftware to show the game development community what the Switch 2 has to offer that other consoles can't. It was the only studio to show up with a bona fide Nintendo Switch 2 exclusive: a gothic PvPvE game called </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>The Duskbloods</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">. Frustratingly, the company didn't reveal more than a highlight reel of in-engine footage that showed off some stunning art direction and tantalizing gameplay, but failed to detail which of the Switch 2's new features it would lean heavily on.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Coming into the preview, I confess I was worried that Nintendo couldn't free itself from the Nintendo Switch's groundbreaking asset: the portability. Since its launch, the unique features of the Joy-Con controllers have faded in relevance, with motion controls and gyroscopes not driving widely-used game mechanics. The bestselling Switch games of the last year include titles ranging from </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Balatro </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">to </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Hogwarts Legacy</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> to </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Hello Kitty Island Adventure</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">. (With free-to-play mainstays like </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Fortnite </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">regularly on the most-downloaded list).</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Depending on the day, the kinds of the games on the eShop top charts might not look that different than the kind seen on the Steam Top Selling list. If any other portable hardware maker surpassed Nintendo in its ease of use, it could eat away at what made the Switch so special.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">For now, GameChat is convincing me that Nintendo has a strategy beyond "The Nintendo Switch, but better." It takes pressure off the humble mouse feature, which no longer has to lift a console's worth of unique game genres.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Of all the Switch 2's many improvements, it's the one that makes me daydream of what kinds of new and unique games the console could support.</span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Titanfall 3 Isn’t Dead, And Will Be Revealed At The Game Awards 2025 [Rumor]]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/titanfall-3-isnt-dead-and-will-be-revealed-at-the-game-awards-2025-rumor/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/titanfall-3-isn%E2%80%99t-dead-and-will-be-revealed-at-the-game-awards-2025-rumor.1154487/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/titanfall-3-isnt-dead-and-will-be-revealed-at-the-game-awards-2025-rumor/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>According to two reliable leakers for news about Apex Legends, the long-awaited Titanfall 3 is not dead, and it is currently in the works at Respawn.</p>
<p><a href="https://x.com/YOROTSUKI_/status/1907780125996745064">Yorotsuki</a> and <a href="https://x.com/Osvaldatore/status/1907780126626164993">Osvaldatore</a>, two leakers with a solid reputation for Apex Legends leaks, took to X to reinvigorate players' hopes that Titanfall 3 is not lying in a ditch somewhere (or the digital equivalent on EA's servers).</p>
<p>Yorotsuki was a little clearer than Osvladatore, claiming that Respawn is working on the game and that it will be revealed during The Game Awards 2025 showcase set for December 2025. Osvladatore simply posted a graphic of the game's alleged logo.</p>
<p>The Titanfall franchise is arguably one of the best franchises in video game history that got dealt the worst hand possible. The first Titanfall game definitely wasn't perfect, but it brought a new and exciting flavor to the FPS genre that was dominated by Call of Duty and Battlefield.</p>
<p>Then, Titanfall 2 stepped everything up, and if EA hadn't aided in Titanfall 2 being overshadowed by Battlefield 1 launching right beside it in EA's effort to keep up with Call of Duty launching its annual release, Infinite Warfare, in 2016, then there's a solid chance Titanfall 2's story ends differently.</p>
<p>It still has what is regarded as one of the best single-player campaigns, not just in a first-person shooter, but in any game in gaming's history. And the rise and sustained popularity of Apex Legends continues to be proof that there's no other franchise that has mastered movement in a first-person shooter quite like what Respawn was able to accomplish with Titanfall.</p>
<p>That's just a part of what has made Titanfall 3 a topic its fans bring up nearly as often as Bloodborne fans cry out for a sequel or remake. It's also why Respawn's chief executive officer and one of the original creatives behind Titanfall, Vince Zampella, has had to answer questions about Titanfall 3 time and again.</p>
<p>Even though Zampella has previously <a href="https://wccftech.com/titanfall-3-id-love-it-but-it-has-to-be-the-right-thing-at-the-right-time-says-respawn-ceo/">stated that the studio is not working on Titanfall 3</a>, the reality of the video game industry, of which EA is no exception, is that things can change on a dime. Just last month, another multiplayer FPS game Respawn was<a href="https://wccftech.com/respawn-cancels-another-unannounced-multiplayer-fps/"> incubating was canceled</a>, so it's entirely possible that the cancelation of that project has led to Titanfall 3 being kicked up again, which is where today's rumor comes from.</p>
<p>There are plenty of unknowns here, but crazier things have happened during The Game Awards than a franchise that's beloved by millions coming back from the dead.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Alright, Dune: Awakening, your in-game radio that plays music from the '90s Dune games has won me over]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/alright-dune-awakening-your-in-game-radio-that-plays-music-from-the-90s-dune-games-has-won-me-over</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/alright-dune-awakening-your-in-game-radio-that-plays-music-from-the-90s-dune-games-has-won-me-over.1154484/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/alright-dune-awakening-your-in-game-radio-that-plays-music-from-the-90s-dune-games-has-won-me-over<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Alright folks, quiz time: what's the single best feature in the GTA series? I'll give you a second. Got your answer done? If you wrote anything but the in-game radio, you'd be dead wrong, obviously it's listening to boppin' tunes as you crash into lamp posts for the umpteenth time, there's nothing else it could be. I love an in-game radio, and as it turns out, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/dune-awakening">Dune: Awakening</a> of all games will include one (didn't know they had radio on Arrakis).
</p>
<!--more-->
<p>
Best of all though is the fact that the in-game radio will <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1172710/view/546731472820633915">actually feature music from the original Dune games</a>, the pair of games released in 1992, Dune and Dune 2: Battle for Arrakis. I'd also like to highlight that the soundtrack for the first one even has its own name, Dune: Spice Opera, which is just lovely. It even received a remaster last year apparently, so you'll have some crispy tunes to enjoy as you travel the desert planet (sadly, co-composer Stéphane Picq passed away just this February).
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Dune: Awakening - Awaken to the Music of the Classic Dune Games" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/AUzTovhSb9U?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Dune: Awakening - Awaken to the Music of the Classic Dune Games</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/AUzTovhSb9U?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/AUzTovhSb9U?autoplay=1" title="Dune: Awakening - Awaken to the Music of the Classic Dune Games">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AUzTovhSb9U" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>
There's apparently three channels to peruse on the Communinent as it's been dubbed, like Harvester Radio, a station catered to the "commoner workforce." This one will be where you'll be able to listen to music, but also get some tips for survival and even ads, apparently. They're everywhere these days! There's also official Harkonnen and Atreides channels, though maybe stay away if you're susceptible to propaganda.
</p>
<p>
The in-game radio is fun, but including music from the original Dune games is just such a lovely touch. Most people obviously think of the newer films, the OG David Lynch version, and of course the books themselves, so it's a cute way of acknowledging another aspect of the sci-fi series' history. I'm not big on MMOs generally, but this might be enough to get me to give it a go at the very least.

</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>